<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Steps outlined for improving finance sector]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_001_65416231ed50d203d2ca1a95.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中国最高领导层提出了增强国家金融竞争力的措施，强调要全面加强金融监管、完善金融体系周二在北京闭幕的为期两天、定调的中央金融工作会议强调，国家将始终不渝维护金融稳定货币政策稳健，更加注重跨周期、逆周期调节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央总书记习近平在会议上发表重要讲话，指出当前和未来一段时期的金融部门计划。除国家主席、中央军委主席习近平外，党的其他核心领导成员也出席了会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国首次召开全国金融工作会议1997年召开了一次会议，最近一次会议是2017年召开的第五次会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 金融业是国家经济的命脉，是国家核心的重要组成部分会议纪要指出，在强调金融体系对2012年以来我国经济社会整体发展的有力支撑的同时，政策制定者也指出了当前金融体系发展中存在的各种矛盾和问题。金融领域相互交织、相互影响，一些问题依然突出，不少经济金融风险隐患依然存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们指出，金融服务质量和金融服务助推作用实体经济还有待完善，金融违规和腐败问题依然存在，金融监管和治理力度还不够。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 会议强调，要坚持和加强党的全面领导力。 ——中央财经委员会领导金融工作，指出我国必须以建设金融强国为目标，推动金融高质量发展，深化供给侧结构性改革。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摘要指出，金融业要为经济社会发展提供高质量服务，包括营造良好的货币金融环境，加强对重大战略、关键领域和薄弱环节的一流金融服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 加大金融支持力度，促进科技创新、先进制造、绿色发展、中小微企业发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创新驱动发展、区域协调发展、保障国家粮食和能源安全等战略。加强科技金融、绿色金融、普惠金融、金融与养老、数字技术的融合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 着力建设现代金融机构和市场体系，会议纪要表示，促进资金流向实体经济，优化融资结构，更好发挥资本市场枢纽作用，推动注册制进一步发展。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 国家将多元化股权融资，提高上市公司质量，培育一流投行和机构，推动债券市场高质量发展，支持国有大型金融机构做强做优&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 同时，政策制定者将对中小金融机构实行严格的准入标准和监管要求，要求它们注重因地制宜开展特色经营。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 会议提出，在保障国家金融经济安全的同时，推进金融业高水平开放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 强调要统筹推进金融业高水平开放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;推动境内机构“走出去”，稳步扩大机构开放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国将进一步便利跨境投融资摘要称，吸引更多外资金融机构和长期资本来华投资经营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 决策者承诺增强上海国际金融中心的竞争力和影响力，同时巩固和发展上海国际金融中心。提升香港国际金融中心地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 会议强调全面加强金融监管，有效防范和化解金融风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国家还将建立摘要称，建立防范和化解地方债务风险的长效机制，将优化中央和地方债务结构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 房地产领域，会议强调，要加强房地产企业监管，完善资本监管，加强房地产融资宏观审慎监管，平等对待不同所有制企业合理融资需求。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 总结称，中国将加强外汇市场管理，继续保持人民币汇率在合理均衡水平上基本稳定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xuwei@chinadaily。 com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Remains of Li Keqiang to be cremated on Thursday]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_001_65416234ed50d203d2ca1a96.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 李克强同志遗体将于周四在北京火化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李克强曾任十七届、十八届、十九届中央政治局常委中国共产党中央委员会委员、原国务院总理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 被誉为优秀中国共产党员，久经考验的忠诚共产主义战士，杰出的无产阶级革命家、政治家、党的领导人&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他的遗体已于周五乘坐专机从上海运至北京。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为了哀悼他的逝世，天安门广场将于周四下半旗致哀。 #39;安门广场、新华门、北京人民大会堂、外交部，各省、自治区、直辖市党委、政府所在地，香港特别行政区、澳门特别行政区、边境口岸、海港、入境机场以及中国驻外使领馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Reduced to rubble]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_001_65416237ed50d203d2ca1a97.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/001/20231101_001_03_195014.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦居民走过建筑物周一，在持续不断的巴以冲突中，加沙地带中部努塞拉特难民营被以色列轰炸摧毁。参见故事，第 12 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi underlines intl scientific, technological innovation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_001_6541623aed50d203d2ca1a98.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;习近平主席日前回信古巴神经科学家瓦尔德斯索萨，强调各国要通过科技创新共同促进和平与发展。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 习近平赞赏巴尔德斯-索萨致力于加强古中特殊友好关系，积极推动中国对外科研合作。他对古巴科学家及其团队取得的多项突破表示祝贺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，国际科技合作是大势所趋，是共建“一带一路”的根本出发点和着力点，他10年前就提出，要探索各国共同发展新路，走出一条“幸福之路”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平表示，中国加快同“一带一路”沿线国家科技交流和知识共享，不断改善创新环境，聚集创新资源。上个年代。习近平表示，科技创新合作快速推进，成果显着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈到中古关系，习近平表示，中古传统友谊是老一辈领导人共同培育的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年以来，两国就共同构建中古命运共同体达成重要共识。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 总统表示，衷心希望新时期两国不断深化科技及各领域合作，为两国人民带来更多福祉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 位于四川省成都市的中古转化神经技术前沿研究联合实验室主任瓦尔德斯-索萨近日致信习近平，介绍该实验室在中国的研究进展。这位科学家还重申致力于促进中古友谊，为推动全球一带一路合作作出贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mojingxi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Shenzhou XVI crew return after &#39;very cool journey&#39;]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_001_6541623ced50d203d2ca1a99.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/001/20231101_001_05_161014.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;景海鹏少将，周二，神舟十六号载人航天飞行任务指挥员在内蒙古自治区东风着陆点从返回舱走下后挥手致意。景和他的团队成员朱阳柱上校和桂海潮教授完成了为期五个月的天宫空间站任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile /2023-11-01/001/20231101_001_05_178014.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;神舟十六号飞船返回舱周二在东风着陆点着陆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;神舟十六号船员返回地球周二上午，结束了一项历史性的、为期五个月的任务，其中还包括中国第一位民用宇航员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 飞船的再入舱搭载着任务指挥官景海鹏少将、朱大校杨珠和桂海潮教授经过近12个小时的返程飞行，于上午8时11分在内蒙古自治区戈壁滩东风着陆点着陆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 经过室外安全检查，地面回收小组打开钟形太空舱的舱门，对宇航员的情况进行了初步检查。健康。井坐在太空舱内，通过无线电告诉北京地面控制人员，他的团队已经安全着陆，并且“感觉很好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随后，宇航员被抬出太空舱，放在太空舱前的椅子上。 ，并在直播节目中与记者分享了自己的经历。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 景表示，能够“回到祖国”，他们感到很兴奋。天宫空间站内的轨道停留是一次“非常酷的旅程”。他说，任务期间，队友们表现出色，彼此相处融洽，共同兑现了对祖国和人民的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 朱，中国航天第一人太空工程师表示，他们协调配合，成功完成了各项任务。 “中国的空间站永远值得期待” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我国第一位民用航天员、第一位太空有效载荷专家桂民海说，任务的每一天都是忙碌而难忘的。他还表示，期待未来重返空间站，继续自己的科学探索。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 采访结束后，宇航员被转移到专用车辆中，对他们的健康状况进行详细评估。他们于周二下午乘飞机返回北京，随后被送往位于城市西北部的中国航天员中心开始为期数月的医学隔离、健康观察和休养。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 神舟十六号航天员已于5月30日抵达天宫，这是中国第十一次载人航天飞行，也是第五次载人空间站飞行任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第四次航天飞行，使他成为中国最有经验的宇航员。这也是以朱为代表的我国第三代航天员首次航天飞行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 景、朱都是解放军航天员师，桂是航天员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在启程回国之前，景琰的团队将空间站移交给了北京航空航天大学航天学院航天器与运载火箭技术系博士生导师。任务指挥员唐洪波大校、唐胜杰中校、蒋新林中校组成的神舟十七号机组人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 神舟十六号机组人员在天宫号与飞船之间进行物资整理和转运，于8点离开空间站：周一下午 37 点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 出发后，他们拍摄了以地球为背景的空间站照片。经过一些轨道机动后，飞船于周二早上重新进入地球大气层。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在接下来的六个月里，天宫号将由神舟十七号机组人员驾驶，他们于周四晚上抵达空间站.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhaolei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - YOUNG RECRUITS DRAWN TO THE GIG ECONOMY]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_001_6541623fed50d203d2ca1a9a.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/001/20231101_002_02_61455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;金华的演出市场，浙江、河北唐山提供灵活就业机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/001/20231101_002_02_36455.png &quot; />;&lt;p>;上海闵行区就业促进中心在线直播招聘会。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11- 01/001/20231101_002_02_84455.png&quot; />; &lt;p>;张志楠的父母希望她成为家乡江西赣州的一名公务员或教师，但21岁的她最近找到了一个所谓的—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “零工”，在上海的一家物流公司。是一个流行术语，指没有长期承诺的自由职业。大多数零工工人都是兼职或小时工。他们还可以决定工作频率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张的工作要求她每天工作 8 小时，持续 30 天。她说，她还没有长期的职业规划，但希望尝试不同的职业，让自己的生活变得“自由简单”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她是 39 名找到此类工作的人之一。 9月下旬，上海闵行区吴泾镇零工就业市场开业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天，来自时尚零售、酒店服务、快递、家政、物流、机械加工等行业的12家企业参加了零工就业市场。 32个职位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 吴泾演出市场是继8月启动颛桥镇演出市场之后，该区第二个举办的演出市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 定期举办招聘会&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 闵行区就业促进中心主任陈铁民表示， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “今年上半年需求大幅增长，现在出现了这种性质的就业机会。”占总数的30%以上。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国家统计局数据显示，截至2021年底，我国灵活就业人数已达2亿人，其中1990年以后出生的人达1亿人。业内人士预测，到2036年，这一数字将翻一番。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年，五部委发文旨在加强零工市场，更好支持多渠道灵活就业，帮助零工就业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在上海，有关部门7月份发文，要求加大对零工市场的支持力度，完善零工求职招聘服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 闵行区零工就业市场已举办五场线下招聘活动，已有224家企业招聘超过3600人打零工。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年春天大学毕业后，一直在江西物流和餐饮行业打零工的张女士表示，做这种工作的想法在她的同龄人中很普遍。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们开玩笑说我们的生活就像 USB 闪存驱动器一样。我们越来越喜欢决定自己的日程安排，并通过更独立地工作来激发我们的创造力。”大学学的是金融专业的张女士说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她说，自己搬到上海并不是为了钱，而是为了能有更多元化的工作选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “为了工作，我不想失去时间和精力方面的自由。在我职业生涯的这个阶段，我不会选择压力大、需要高度投入的工作。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说，她和她的同龄人认为一份耗费全身心力、需要大量加班的工作对他们来说并不理想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “与过去几代人不同，我们更有可能将工作视为生活的一部分，并且热衷于尝试不同的生活方式。” ”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“而且，为了避免给自己施加压力，为未来存钱，我从来没有深入考虑过结婚或生孩子的问题。如果我能在支出和收入之间取得平衡，我会很高兴。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;更多的空闲时间&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自生活服务平台58同城的数据显示使用其模块寻找零工工作的用户中约有三分之二出生于 1995 年之后，其中一半以上的用户拥有学士学位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “收入不再是唯一因素衡量零工工作或兼职工作。乐趣和个人成长变得同样重要，”张说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 31 岁的上海环境评估工程师刘子熙一年前终止了与前雇主的合同，然后加入了零工经济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她现在在她是多家公司的所在地，她的工作包括撰写环境评估报告。刘女士说，这种新的工作形式报酬与她以前的工作一样多，但她现在有了更多的业余时间，因为她不再通勤上班。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我现在可以更灵活地安排时间。” ，因为我可以随时随地写工作报告。我也不再需要下班后在受欢迎的餐厅排队，因为我可以在其他顾客到来之前到达那里，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海民普人力资源集团总经理吴波表示，年轻人普遍思想自由，对未来的担忧较少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，5月份上海市出台对在本市从事灵活就业的外地居民办理社会保险的政策，让群众选择零工更有保障。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 吴说，新经济和新业态的发展也为零工市场创造了多种就业机会供申请人选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 十年前，许多年轻人通常从事数字产品工作他补充说，工厂，但现在他们更喜欢送餐工作或驾驶网约车。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这种新的工作形式回报更高，工人享有高度的灵活性。如果这些天他们缺钱，他们可以工作更长的时间。如果他们想花更多时间在自己身上，他们就到此为止。”吴说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国范围内更大的流动性和日益先进的信息技术也使许多人能够在一个城市的零工经济中工作很短一段时间，然后再转移到其他地方，吴说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴说。他补充说，他的公司在抖音、快手等短视频平台上的账号拥有超过200万粉丝，这些渠道让零工招聘信息很容易接触到来自不同领域的人们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “有些人被某种特定类型的工作所吸引，从家乡来到上海。他们从工作中赚到一定数量的钱，然后再前往下一个目的地。”吴说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 现在年轻人的父母也与他们的前辈不同，他们对孩子找到稳定、高薪的工作寄予厚望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 沉巍巍，53 岁，儿子今年从上海大学毕业，他说：“像我儿子这样的千禧一代现在正在加入劳动力队伍。他们大多是家里的独生子，他们成长的时代物质条件比前几代人要好得多。我不希望赚大钱，而是希望儿子过上健康、有意义、自己喜欢的生活。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 沉的儿子在一家广告公司实习，目前还没有业内人士表示，COVID-19大流行的影响也是零工经济崛起的一个重要因素。近年来，兼职在线工作和共享员工开始流行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;成本降低&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;零工就业的持续势头不仅仅是这是求职者和雇主观念转变的结果，他们认为此类工作使就业过程更容易并降低成本，特别是在旅游和物流等具有季节性需求的行业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 人力资源奢侈品牌路易威登(L​​ouis Vuitton)一位不愿透露姓名的曹经理表示，该公司在中国的化妆品和服装仓库近80%的工人都是兼职员工。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹说，每年的 6 月 18 日和 11 月 11 日购物节期间，该公司需要约 2,000 名兼职工人数周来处理激增的订单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在一些食品工厂，零工工人的比例现在正在上升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于上海浦东区的上海烧万盛食品厂的人力资源经理冯晓霞表示，该厂主要生产手工馒头，40%的员工工厂里的员工都是零工，主要从事包装等非核心岗位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与通常持续三四个月的传统兼职相比，零工可能只需要一个她说，“公司现在线上线下都有销售，如果线上接到大订单，可能会暂时需要工人。”但由于我们的订单不稳定，我们无法雇佣大量的全职工人。”冯说，并补充说，由于疫情的持久影响，对零工的青睐从去年开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海黄浦区当局推出了在线零工市场平台，为零工提供了机会互联网、新能源、人工智能等新经济产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平台自6月上线以来，已处理求职者与企业聊天超过245万条。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; 黄浦区人力资源和社会保障局局长周雷表示，零工更多面向年轻人，尤其是大学毕业生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 黄浦区就业促进中心副主任陈轩表示， “一些新经济、新业态，比如直播营销、在线设计开发、云客服等，不需要员工呆在固定的办公空间，灵活的工作制度更适合。”&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 对于一些年轻人，尤其是大学毕业生来说，零工就业为他们提供了“缓冲”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海工业大学招生就业办公室主任景晓峰表示，近年来，一些大学生面临的一个困难是，受疫情影响，他们缺乏企业实习经验。 ”，对自己的职业发展感到困惑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说，零工在某种程度上让他们有机会初步进入职场，体验企业氛围，为自己未来的职业生涯找到方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhouwenting@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - After leaving my position, I no longer wake at night fretting about the time]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_002_65416242ed50d203d2ca1a9b.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;肖松友，29岁，上海人&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年2月，我终于辞掉了四年的工作。如果我在过去三年中由于 COVID-19 大流行而无法在大部分时间里在家工作，我就会更早离开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我辞职是因为我没有这样做知道如何在中型互联网公司做好工作。我本来是被雇来制作宣传内容的，但后来老板要我制作科技内容，要求我多学习一些技术。然而，我对这个学科没有兴趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当我受雇时，我就到别处找工作。这些工作大多数的月薪为 10,000 元至 20,000 元（1,372 美元和 2,734 美元），但工作量大、工作时间长，甚至周末也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我不想生活就是这样，所以我继续我的工作，这对我来说已经很令人失望，但很轻松。它涉及远程工作，但我认为我没有做出任何贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我在郊区与一个陌生人租了一套公寓。到市中心上班需要 90 分钟。两年前，我要求每周休息三天，工资减少20%，公司同意了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 离职后我还算平静。职场新人通常要遵守规则，但工作几年后，我不愿意接受公司的一切要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 失业好几个月了，我不知道该怎么办。没有因为没有工作而感到失去自豪感。唯一改变的是我不再获得报酬。我对此已经做好了准备，所以我并不担心。如果我能找到一些零工工作来赚钱，它们可能是全职工作的一个很好的替代方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在过去的几个月里，我靠我的积蓄和经营播客的收入生活，这拥有超过11万粉丝，但我不会把它当作一份全职工作，因为我觉得工作绝不能仅仅作为赚钱的手段。它一定也很有趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当我做以前的工作时，我经常半夜醒来问 Siri 现在几点了，因为我需要知道我还能睡多久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 现在，我不再担心半夜起床的时间了。早上起床后，我喜欢在阳台上享受阳光，和我的植物说话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 自从辞职后，我做了很多我很久以来想做的事情。我去了江苏南京，参观了书店和动物园。我还在马来西亚呆了一个月，像当地人一样生活，充分利用我的签证有效期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我可能会开始找工作，但只找我擅长的工作。我不能保证我会在某个岗位上呆多久。我发现人们现在工作的时间越来越短，他们不再害怕工作之间的“窗口期”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，虽然人们过去通常会为了更高的薪水而换工作，他们现在愿意接受一份薪水相同甚至更低的新工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 原因包括不需要加班，以及有机会在新行业工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;肖松友与周文婷交谈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - YOUNG RECRUITS DRAWN TO THE GIG ECONOMY]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_002_65416242ed50d203d2ca1a9c.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/002/20231101_002_02_61455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;金华的演出市场，浙江、河北唐山提供灵活就业机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/002/20231101_002_02_36455.png &quot; />;&lt;p>;上海闵行区就业促进中心在线直播招聘会。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11- 01/002/20231101_002_02_84455.png&quot; />; &lt;p>;张志楠的父母希望她在家乡江西赣州当一名公务员或教师，但21岁的她最近找到了一个所谓的—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “零工”，在上海的一家物流公司。是一个流行术语，指没有长期承诺的自由职业。大多数零工工人都是兼职或小时工。他们还可以决定工作频率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张的工作要求她每天工作 8 小时，持续 30 天。她说，她还没有长期的职业规划，但希望尝试不同的职业，让自己的生活变得“自由简单”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她是 39 名找到此类工作的人之一。 9月下旬，上海闵行区吴泾镇零工就业市场开业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天，来自时尚零售、酒店服务、快递、家政、物流、机械加工等行业的12家企业参加了零工就业市场。 32个职位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 吴泾演出市场是继8月启动颛桥镇演出市场之后，该区第二个举办的演出市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 定期举办招聘会&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 闵行区就业促进中心主任陈铁民表示， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “今年上半年需求大幅增长，现在出现了这种性质的就业机会。” accounting for more than 30 percent of the total,&amp;quot; Chen said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; National Bureau of Statistics data show that 200 million people were involved in flexible employment in China by the end of 2021, including 100 million born after 1990. Industry insiders predict the former figure will double by 2036.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last year, five ministries issued a document aimed at strengthening the gig market to better support multichannel flexible employment and help those looking for gig jobs find work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Shanghai, the authorities released a document in July, requiring stronger support for the gig market, and improved gig job search and recruitment services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Minhang, five offline recruitment activities have been held at gig job markets, and 224 enterprises have recruited more than 3,600 individuals for gig jobs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang, who has had gig jobs in the logistics and catering industries in Jiangxi since graduating from college in the spring, said the idea of doing such work is commonplace among her peers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We joke that we live like USB flash drives. We increasingly prefer to determine our own schedules and stimulate our creativity by working more independently,&amp;quot; said Zhang, who studied finance at college.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said she did not move to Shanghai for money, but for a more diversified choice of jobs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For my work, I don&amp;#39;t want to lose freedom in terms of time and effort. I won&amp;#39;t choose a high-pressure job that requires a high degree of commitment at this stage of my career,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang said she and her peers consider a job that is all-consuming and involves a lot of overtime work is not ideal for them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Unlike past generations, we&amp;#39;re more likely to regard work as just a part of life, and we&amp;#39;re keen to taste different lifestyles,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Also, to avoid putting pressure on myself to save money for the future, I&amp;#39;ve never thought deeply about marriage or having children. I will be happy if I can strike a balance between spending and earning.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;More spare time&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data from life services platform 58.com show that about two in three of those using its module to find gig jobs are born after 1995, and more than half of these users hold bachelor&amp;#39;s degrees.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Income is no longer the sole factor to gauge a gig job or part-time work. Fun and personal growth have become equally important,&amp;quot; Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Zixi, 31, an environmental assessment engineer in Shanghai, ended her contract with her previous employer a year ago, before joining the gig economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She now operates from home for several companies, and her work includes writing environmental assessment reports. Liu said this new form of work pays just as much as her previous job, but she now has more spare time, as she no longer commutes to work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I can now arrange my time much more flexibly, as I can write my work reports anywhere, anytime. I also no longer have to line up at popular restaurants after work, because I can get to them before other customers start arriving,&amp;quot; Liu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Bo, general manager of Shanghai Minpu Human Resources Group, said young people are generally free-spirited and have few worries about the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that in May, Shanghai introduced a policy to provide social insurance to residents from other areas of the country who are engaged in flexible employment in the city, adding that the policy gives people a better sense of security in choosing a gig job.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Development of the new economy and fresh business formats has also created a variety of job openings in the gig market for applicants to choose from, Wu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A decade ago, many young people typically worked in digital products factories, but now they prefer food delivery jobs or driving ride-hailing vehicles, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Such new forms of work are more rewarding, and workers enjoy a high degree of flexibility. If they run short of money these days, they can work for longer hours. If they want to spend more time on themselves, they just call it a day,&amp;quot; Wu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Greater mobility nationwide and increasingly advanced information technology also allow many people to work in the gig economy in a city for just a short period, before they move on to other locations, Wu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that his company&amp;#39;s accounts on short-video platforms such as Douyin and Kuaishou have more than 2 million followers, and such outlets make it easy for gig job recruitment information to reach people from different areas of the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Some people attracted to a particular type of work travel to Shanghai from their hometowns. They make a certain amount of money from the job before moving on to their next destination,&amp;quot; Wu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Parents of young people today are also different from their predecessors, who had high hopes of their children finding stable, high-paid jobs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Weiwei, 53, whose son graduated from university in Shanghai this year, said: &amp;quot;Millennials such as my son are now joining the workforce. They are mostly the only child in their family, and they grew up in a time of much better material conditions than previous generations. Instead of making big money, I hope my son will live a healthy and meaningful life that he enjoys.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen&amp;#39;s son, who works as an intern at an advertising company, has yet to feel the desire to find a better-paid job.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Industry insiders said the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic were also an important factor in the gig economy&amp;#39;s rise. In recent years, part-time online work and sharing employees have become popular.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Lower costs&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gig employment&amp;#39;s continued momentum is not solely the result of changing philosophies among job seekers, but also employers, who feel that such jobs make the employment process easier and reduce costs, especially in industries with seasonal demands, such as travel and logistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A human resources manager at luxury brand Louis Vuitton, who only wanted to be identified as Cao, said nearly 80 percent of the workers at the company&amp;#39;s cosmetics and clothing warehouses in China are part-time employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the annual June 18 and Nov 11 shopping festivals, the company needs some 2,000 part-time workers for several weeks to handle surging orders, Cao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At some food factories, gig workers now comprise a rising proportion of the workforce as employers seek to better control costs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Feng Xiaoxia, a human resources manager at Shanghai Shaowansheng Food Plant in the city&amp;#39;s Pudong district, which mainly produces handmade steamed bread, said 40 percent of the employees at the plant are gig workers who are mainly used in noncore positions, such as packaging.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared with traditional part-time jobs, which usually last three or four months, a gig job may only require a worker for one or two days, she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The company now sells online and offline, so if a large order is received online, workers may be needed temporarily. But as our orders are not stable, we cannot afford to employ a large team of full-time workers,&amp;quot; Feng said, adding that the preference for gig workers began last year due to the lasting effects of the pandemic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The authorities in Shanghai&amp;#39;s Huangpu district have launched an online gig market platform, providing opportunities in the internet, new energy, and artificial intelligence industries, among other new economies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the platform launched in June, it has handled more than 2.45 million chats between job seekers and enterprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Lei, director of Huangpu District Human Resources and Social Security Bureau, said gig jobs are aimed more toward younger people, especially college graduates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xuan Chen, deputy director of Huangpu District Employment Promotion Center, said, &amp;quot;Some new economies and formats, such as livestream marketing, online design and development, and cloud customer services, do not require employees to stay in a fixed office space, as flexible working systems can be a better fit.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For some young people, especially college graduates, gig employment offers them a &amp;quot;buffer&amp;quot; in the job market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jing Xiaofeng, director of Shanghai Polytechnic University&amp;#39;s admissions and employment office, said one difficulty for some college students in recent years is that they lack corporate internship experience due to the pandemic, and feel confused about their career development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gig jobs, to some extent, give them the opportunity to initially enter the workplace, experience a corporate atmosphere, and find a direction for their future careers, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhouwenting@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Foreign firms see profitable future in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_003_65416245ed50d203d2ca1a9d.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/003/20231101_003_01_96633.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nearly 90 percent of foreign companies expect their profits to remain stable or increase in China over the next five years, with a large number of them identifying technological innovation as the primary growth opportunity in the Chinese market, according to a survey released by China&amp;#39;s top foreign trade and investment promotion agency on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The study, conducted by the China Council for the Promotion of International Trade and involving 700 foreign companies, found that over 80 percent of respondents were satisfied with China&amp;#39;s business environment in the third quarter of 2023, and about 80 percent anticipate that their profits will remain stable or improve in 2023.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Though the global investment sentiment remains subdued, foreign enterprises have sufficient confidence in investing in China, said Zhang Xin, spokesman for the Beijing-headquartered CCPIT.They are happy with the operational aspects such as market access, process of acquiring business premises, access to essential infrastructure facilities and services, and the resolution of commercial disputes in the country, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Regarding development opportunities, foreign firms have consistently believed that technological innovations are the most significant growth opportunities in the Chinese market for three consecutive quarters,&amp;quot; he said, noting that about half of them have expressed an interest in increasing investment in China&amp;#39;s western region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s peaceful and huge market, as well as its latest move to implement measures to broaden market access for global investors in several key areas, including the relaxation of restrictions on foreign investment in listed companies, will offer multinational corporations more growth opportunities, said Chang Xiuze, a professor of economics at the Academy of Macroeconomic Research in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fueled by China&amp;#39;s pool of talent and industrial upgrade, foreign businesses operating in China, especially manufacturers and service providers, will persist in establishing digitally empowered factories, adding innovation hubs and striving to expand their market share in various sectors, such as automotive, logistics, retail, green technology and high-end manufacturing, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Echoing the sentiment, Sally Loh, president for China of United States-based elevator manufacturing company Otis Worldwide Corp, said the Chinese market is a key contributor to the group&amp;#39;s global performance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We will continue to grow our business in both the new equipment and service segments in China, as this market leads our service digitalization deployment,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;Our innovation, smart manufacturing and talent localization in China are important pillars of our global business.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Foreign direct investment used in China&amp;#39;s manufacturing sector amounted to 262.4 billion yuan ($35.9 billion) between January and September, representing a 2.4 percent increase on a yearly basis, with high-tech manufacturing seeing a growth of 12.8 percent year-on-year, data from the Ministry of Commerce showed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In terms of development aspirations, foreign companies surveyed by the CCPIT expressed the hope that the Chinese government will take steps to ensure the stability of the country&amp;#39;s supply and industrial chains, enhance its industrial support capabilities and clustering effects, and bolster the continuity and stability of policies that assist businesses in times of need.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Jinping, former director of the department of foreign economic relations at the Development Research Center of the State Council, said that for many global business leaders, there has been a significant shift in traditional perceptions about the business environment in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;They no longer simply expect the government to provide good services. Rather, they now seek government support to facilitate their innovation activities and gain access to sectors previously restricted to them,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the beginning of this year, numerous multinational company executives have repeatedly shown strong interest in coming to China. They have engaged in discussions with business partners and held meetings with Chinese officials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, Commerce Minister Wang Wentao met with Tim Cook, CEO of US tech giant Apple Inc, and Severin Schwan, board chairman of Swiss healthcare company Roche Holding AG in Beijing in mid-October, encouraging multinational companies to share the benefits of the Chinese market and achieve mutual development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhongnan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Medal for peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_003_65416248ed50d203d2ca1a9e.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/003/20231101_003_02_57633.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A member of the 13th Chinese peacekeeping contingent to South Sudan receives a UN peace medal on Saturday at the Chinese engineering camp in the Super Camp of the United Nations Mission in South Sudan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Breaking the language barrier]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/01/content_003_6541624aed50d203d2ca1a9f.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-01/003/20231101_003_03_40633.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Two contestants bid each other an emotional goodbye on Monday after the finals of the 16th Chinese Bridge Competition in Kunming, Yunnan province. The competition is aimed at promoting Chinese language proficiency among foreign students. It has attracted more than 1.5 million young people from over 160 countries and regions around the world since its inception in 2002.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>