<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Strive for revitalization of northeast]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_001_64fe25a5ed50d203d2c9c0a9.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席提出的东北振兴最新愿景，为东北地区成为国家战略支柱、更好应对人口外流等挑战指明了方向分析人士称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在召开座谈会时勾画了地区振兴愿景周四在黑龙江省省会哈尔滨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 听取辽宁、吉林、黑龙江、内蒙古自治区党委书记和郑善杰汇报。国家发展和改革委员会主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平五年前在辽宁沉阳主持过类似的研讨会。去年，他还在沉阳主持了关于东北地区振兴的高层会议。东北地区是中国的粮食生产基地之一，也是传统制造业强国，但经济增速放缓，人口外流。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，东北地区资源丰富、产业基础雄厚、区位优越、发展潜力巨大，当前面临新的重大机遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，推动中国现代化道路，还需要进一步强化战略支撑作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 实现东北全面振兴，实体经济是基础，科技创新是关键，产业升级是方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平并呼吁，加快传统制造业数字化、网络化、智能化转型，积极发展新能源、新材料、先进制造、电子等新兴产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张飞，副总裁中国改革发展研究院院长表示，习近平在这次座谈会上强调要发展产业，因为东北地区制造业的升级转型不仅对东北地区、对整个民族具有里程碑意义。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; “四十年来，东北地区GDP占全国的比重不断下降。但该地区仍然拥有较多的顶尖大学和良好的产业结构，未来发展潜力巨大。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习主席再次强调本地区在保障我国粮食安全中的重要作用，表示本地区的首要责任是充当国家粮食安全的“压舱石”。稳定粮食生产供应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平总书记指出，要始终把保障国家粮食安全放在第一位，加快推进农业农村现代化，全面增强粮食生产能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说，2022年，东北省份粮食产量占全国的20%以上，区域作用更加凸显。乌克兰危机导致全球粮食安全恶化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在过去每次视察该地区时都强调了该地区在中国粮食安全中的作用周四，他表达了对地区开放迈出更大步伐的期待，表示地区要稳步扩大开放加强规章制度、管理标准，提高通关能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 留住和吸引人才，减轻家庭抚养子女负担，保持适度水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据吉林省、辽宁省、黑龙江省有关部门公布的统计数据，2022年这三个省份的人口均出现负增长，其中常住人口数均为负增长。减少了86万人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国人民大学区域经济学教授张克云表示，该地区推动产业升级、应对老龄化社会的努力可能会对全国产生影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “如果该地区能够拿出有效的解决方案来应对挑战，它很可能在国家层面上率先提出解决方案，并继续成为国家高质量发展的支柱。” ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Army unit urged to improve training, combat readiness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_001_64fe25a8ed50d203d2c9c0aa.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/001/20230911_001_02_154831.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平主席，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平周五视察时受到中国人民解放军陆军第78集团军代表的迎接。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;习近平主席要求解放军陆军第78集团军不断提高训练和作战能力，切实履行好党和人民赋予的任务。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平要求集团军坚持党的强军强军思想贯彻新时代战略，不断创新集团军管理和作战方式，全面加强部队建设&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他在集团军视察时作出指示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平在汇报部队发展和作战战绩时，对部队取得的成绩表示肯定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他要求集团军加强军事行动准备，重点抓好关键战术训练加强新​​型作战能力建设，推动联合作战作战部队和硬件融合发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平要求集团各单位党的建设不断深入开展&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说，军人在对抗夏季影响该国北部和东北部省份的暴雨和洪水方面发挥了重要作用。他表示，广大军人坚决捍卫人民群众生命财产安全，恪尽职守。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhaolei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China ready to advance sci-tech cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_001_64fe25abed50d203d2c9c0ab.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;习近平主席表示，中国愿同各国一道，为科技发展营造开放、公平、公正、非歧视的环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平在贺信中向周日在上海开幕的2023浦江创新论坛致贺信。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 信中，他表示，中国将坚定奉行互利共赢的发展战略习近平表示，中国愿以更加开放的心态、更广泛的举措，继续推动国际科技交流与合作。构建具有全球竞争力的开放创新生态系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 希望浦江创新论坛坚持创新主题，激发创新理念，传播创新思想，增强创新精神，为推动浦江创新发展作出新贡献。推进国际科技合作，增进人类共同福祉” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 本次论坛由科技部和上海市人民政府共同主办，论坛主题为“开放创新生态：创新驱动全球互联互通”，论坛将持续到周一。今年的主宾国是巴西，主宾省是湖北。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦也向论坛发来贺信，他在信中表示，今年“主题要求“我们就快速发展的科技进步和开放生态系统提供的无数可能性深化合作”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 卢拉表示，他看到巴西和中国科技园合作的巨大潜力上海市委书记陈吉宁表示，经过多年努力，上海建设国际化大都市正在实现质的飞跃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科技创新中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周六在论坛间隙发布的今年理想城市报告显示，上海排名第四，仅次于新加坡、深圳和波士顿。教育、人才、科技等综合表现较高。该报告是在对全球 20 个创新中心的高端科学家进行调查后得出的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周六在论坛期间举行的女科学家峰会上发布的另一份报告显示，女性研究人员的数量上海科研人员从2016年的7.03万人增加到2021年的9.83万人，占全市科研人员总数的28.49%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 赵春岭，宽体客机常务副总设计师中国商飞公司，是上海顶尖的女研究员之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据赵介绍，中国第一架自主研发的窄体客机C919已经飞行了522小时截至8月底，已实现商业运营，安全载客25,448人次。截至8月，国产支线客机ARJ21已在134个城市安全完成超过800万人次的旅客出行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wang_ying@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - &#39;BOOT CAMP&#39; RECRUITS SHED EXCESS KILOS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_001_64fe25aded50d203d2c9c0ac.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/001/20230911_002_01_24643.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;健飞达人成员Go Change现在，减肥训练营加盟店，在广东惠州上集体课。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11 /001/20230911_002_01_41643.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;来自吉林省长春市的崔红在市内训练营的帮助下减重了50公斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile .chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/001/20230911_002_01_42643.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;健飞达人Go Change Now在惠州举办沙滩排球比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈淑玲长期以来一直在想尽一切办法减肥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 近两年来，她已经两次报名参加减肥“新兵训练营”。项目在东莞举行，距离她在广东省深圳的家大约一小时车程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 每次，陈都会花几周时间接受军事演习形式的训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “我的一位前同事向我提到了这个计划，我在决定加入之前检查了它，” 28岁的国际贸易公司工作人员说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在报名参加训练营之前，一直比较运动的陈女士经常自己跑一个小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “但是，当我与朋友交往时，我往往会吃得过多。我还认为自己锻炼效果不太好。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于觉得自己有点胖，陈女士想通过运动来减肥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021年，她曾到训练场查看设施和进场方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “场地设施齐全，地板上有防滑垫。”厨师是广东人，所以我觉得食物对我来说是很能接受的。此外，教练还承诺不会让我节食太严格。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为一名资深锻炼者，陈清楚地知道自己想要什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在发现其他几个项目的锻炼设备较差或管理不善后，她排除了这些项目。 “优先考虑安全很重要，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021年，陈在工作间隙，在考虑了这样的项目的利弊后，她在东莞培训机构呆了两个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她锻炼身体是为了全天三到四个小时。 “日程安排得很满，所以我从不感到无聊，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈尽力遵守训练指示。当她觉得自己无法进行某些锻炼时，她说培训师帮助她找到了替代方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她在培训中心养成了健康的生活方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该计划&amp;# 39;s的学员只能吃工厂提供的清淡口味的健康食品。禁止外卖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “即使你有虚弱的时候，想恢复原来的习惯，你也必须遵守规则，因为这个地方有很好的监控，”陈说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 高强度的锻炼制度阻止了她在社交活动中带食物，也帮助她比以前更早睡觉和起床。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈花费了 6,000 元（822 美元）两个月的经历，期间她减掉了15公斤多一点。她认为这笔钱花得值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她很满意，从去年9月到今年1月进行了第二轮训练，期间减掉了10公斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “疫情期间，我不想做饭，也不想宅在家里。培训中心似乎是一个不错的去处，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;会员人数不断增长&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;越来越多的中国年轻人报名参加健身培训课程，以保持更好的体形。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩俊成瘦身训练营特许经营健飞达人 Go Change Now 的联合创始人，在过去十年中其会员人数不断增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “全国约有 1,500-2,000 个训练营，其中 80%其中一次可容纳 100 多名会员，” “有些人对自己的生活不满意，想找到提高自己的出路，而另一些人则需要缓解工作压力，”韩说，他的营地拥有约 4000 名成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些营地最早出现在一线城市，加入成本至少要2万元。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 抖音、快手等平台上流行的直播促销活动导致更多的培训设施在较小的城市和农村地区建立，导致费用大幅降低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “有些营地的收费只有3000到4000元，” 2003年开始做健身教练的韩先生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 许多家长在假期里把超重的孩子送到韩老师那里接受指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “孩子们没有确切地意识到培训对他们有何影响，但有些人表现出了接受我给他们的指示的迹象，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管他让孩子们进行了多次练习，但他的一些孩子在家里又养成了不良的饮食习惯，从而抵消了这些练习的有益效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 因此，为了给孩子们提供更好的生活方式，韩老师萌生了举办夏令营的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了定期锻炼之外，还请了老师来讲解营养、提供心理咨询。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; “我们于 2011 年开设了三个露营地，共有约 1,500 名儿童参加。训练营进行得非常顺利，之后孩子们的体重也没有增加。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于这些积极的成果让孩子们的父母想要加入营地，韩将他的业务从深圳扩展到了海南省三亚市以及其他大约20个城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;p>; 每节课持续 28 天，其中一些在管理更好的学校进行。费用从8000元到20000元不等，具体取决于所提供的服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 加入营地需要经过详细的医院检查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “高血压患者需要监测血压早餐前、训练期间和睡前观察任何变化，”韩说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “对于患有糖尿病的人，营养师会提供指导，并测量他们的血糖水平。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着参与者增强体力，锻炼也会随之进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩说，大约有20%的成员回来接受更多培训。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们中的一些人喜欢留在这里，甚至带着朋友一起来，”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;数据分析&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国人民解放军总医院第一医学中心的研究人员分析了来自 519 个国家的约 1580 万名参与者的数据。美年大健康医疗集团在全国243个城市运营健康体检中心。该组织总部位于上海。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据中国体重指数分类，研究对象中 34.8% 超重，14.1% 肥胖。符合资格的参与者年龄在 18 岁或以上，其中 52.8% 是男性。超过 41% 的中国男性超重或肥胖，而中国女性的超重或肥胖比例为 27.7%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与超重相关的并发症在 50 至 54 岁的男性和 65 至 69 岁的女性中达到顶峰。肥胖相关健康问题的发病高峰期为男性35岁至39岁，女性70岁至74岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京协和医院内分泌科教授吴雪艳，说男性更容易肥胖有几个原因，通常与家庭或工作压力有关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了缓解压力，男性经常采取不健康的生活方式，例如饮酒和暴饮暴食，吴说，补充说，长期睡眠不足或不规律会导致男性肥胖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国北方超重或肥胖的人数多于南方，其中内蒙古自治区（37.1%）山东省（37.1%）、河北省（36.6%）位列前三。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 清华大学玉泉医院内分泌免疫科副主任李步满表示，由于不良饮食和久坐的生活方式，现代以腹部肥胖为特征的代谢综合征患者数量显着增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;寄予厚望&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 众多市场主体都将目光投向了训练营业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 海乐菲连锁健身中心负责人周登红表示，去年，Hilefit连锁健身中心开设了约7300个训练营，迎来了约3万名学员。健身房的团体课。周补充说，今年营地的数量预计将增加20%以上，&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个营地提供大约八节课，持续一个小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“重点精准的身体测量、个性化的科学健身计划、全面的饮食指导，”周说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “报名的人都在寻求一种积极的集体锻炼氛围，以锻炼身体。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大约 60% 的参与者参加了训练营他说，一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 深圳健身训练营教练方兵每天为 4 到 12 名学生上两到三节课。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “大多数都是有锻炼经验的白领。他们对于保持健康的需要有非常强烈的意识，并且非常自律，”方说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 其中许多人加入训练营也是为了社交。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “他们觉得一起锻炼、交朋友互相观看更有趣”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “饮食和其他日常生活习惯，”方说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他在大约300个训练营中提供了关于燃烧脂肪和增肌等问题的指导，他的大多数成员从一开始就支持他。 “这些天我并没有真正寻找新成员，因为我目前的成员占据了我大约 98% 的精力，”他说道。 ”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 方认为他的工作很有意义，因为他的许多会员都感谢他改善了他们的体质和健康。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这激励我不断推广运动和健康的理念。健康，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 参加东莞训练营的陈女士表示，这两次经历让她结交了志同道合的朋友，并保持了更健康的生活习惯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们经常鼓励她当我们锻炼时，彼此继续前进，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈说，对于那些想要参加训练营的人来说，告诉教练他们的健康状况很重要，因为大多数超重的人可能会遇到锻炼困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “如果你很少或从不锻炼，突然采取高强度的训练计划是不明智的，”陈说。 “留意你的心率和饮食很重要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈说，她将来会抽出时间参加类似的训练营。 ” “为什么不呢？对我来说，这将是一次很好的假期经历，可以放松身心，保持健康。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;yangfeiyue@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Condolences, aid pouring in for quake-hit Morocco]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_001_64fe25b0ed50d203d2c9c0ad.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/001/20230911_001_05_93831.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;摩洛哥皇家人员周六，武装部队从摩洛哥马拉喀什市西南部塔菲加特村的废墟中打捞出一具尸体。周五，北非国家发生了 6.8 级地震。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 摩洛哥马拉喀什 -北非国家周五发生强烈地震，造成 2000 多人死亡，国际社会周六和周日纷纷向摩洛哥表示慰问和援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国家主席习近平周六向摩洛哥表示慰问。# 39;国王穆罕默德六世对毁灭性地震表示感谢。习近平在贺电中表示，惊悉地震造成我国重大人员伤亡和财产损失，我谨代表中国政府和中国人民，对地震造成的重大人员伤亡和财产损失表示深切哀悼。摩洛哥内政部称，此次6.8级地震至少造成2012人死亡，大部分发生在马拉喀什和震中附近的五个省份。周六晚上报道。该部表示，至少有 2,059 人受伤，其中 1,404 人伤势严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界卫生组织表示，摩洛哥有超过 30 万人受到这场灾难的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周六摩洛哥宣布哀悼三天，周日，穆罕默德国王呼吁全国各地的清真寺为死者祈祷。根据军方的一份声明，他还命令武装部队动员专门的搜救队，并建立一家外科野战医院。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯对遇难者表示哀悼据他的发言人称，他生活在地震中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “秘书长向遇难者家属表示最诚挚的慰问，并祝愿伤者早日康复，”发言人斯蒂芬·杜雅里克 (Stephane Dujarric) 在周六的一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 包括法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙、德国总统弗兰克-瓦尔特·施泰因迈尔和俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京在内的全球领导人也表示哀悼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 地震灾区的许多人在露天度过了第二个夜晚。救援人员面临着到达高阿特拉斯山脉受灾最严重村庄的挑战，这是一座崎岖的山脉，那里的定居点往往很偏远，许多房屋已变成废墟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周六，红十字会中国政府宣布将向摩洛哥红新月会提供20万美元现金紧急人道主义援助，用于救援行动，并将随时了解摩洛哥救灾需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - &#39;BOOT CAMP&#39; RECRUITS SHED EXCESS KILOS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_002_64fe25b0ed50d203d2c9c0ae.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/002/20230911_002_01_24643.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;健飞达人成员Go Change现在，减肥训练营加盟店，在广东惠州上集体课。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11 /002/20230911_002_01_41643.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;来自吉林省长春市的崔红在市内训练营的帮助下减重了50公斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile .chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/002/20230911_002_01_42643.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;健飞达人Go Change Now在惠州举办沙滩排球比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈淑玲长期以来一直在想尽一切办法减肥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 近两年来，她已经两次报名参加减肥“新兵训练营”。项目在东莞举行，距离她在广东省深圳的家大约一小时车程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 每次，陈都会花几周时间接受军事演习形式的训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “我的一位前同事向我提到了这个计划，我在决定加入之前检查了它，” 28岁的国际贸易公司工作人员说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在报名参加训练营之前，一直比较运动的陈女士经常自己跑一个小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “但是，当我与朋友交往时，我往往会吃得过多。我还认为自己锻炼效果不太好。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于觉得自己有点胖，陈女士想通过运动来减肥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021年，她曾到训练场查看设施和进场方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “场地设施齐全，地板上有防滑垫。”厨师是广东人，所以我觉得食物对我来说是很能接受的。此外，教练还承诺不会让我节食太严格。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为一名资深锻炼者，陈清楚地知道自己想要什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在发现其他几个项目的锻炼设备较差或管理不善后，她排除了这些项目。 “优先考虑安全很重要，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021年，陈在工作间隙，在考虑了这样的项目的利弊后，她在东莞培训机构呆了两个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她锻炼身体是为了全天三到四个小时。 “日程安排得很满，所以我从不感到无聊，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈尽力遵守训练指示。当她觉得自己无法进行某些锻炼时，她说培训师帮助她找到了替代方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她在培训中心养成了健康的生活方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该计划&amp;# 39;s的学员只能吃工厂提供的清淡口味的健康食品。禁止外卖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “即使你有虚弱的时候，想恢复原来的习惯，你也必须遵守规则，因为这个地方有很好的监控，”陈说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 高强度的锻炼制度阻止了她在社交活动中带食物，也帮助她比以前更早睡觉和起床。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈花费了 6,000 元（822 美元）两个月的经历，期间她减掉了15公斤多一点。她认为这笔钱花得值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她很满意，从去年9月到今年1月进行了第二轮训练，期间减掉了10公斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “疫情期间，我不想做饭，也不想宅在家里。培训中心似乎是一个不错的去处，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;会员人数不断增长&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;越来越多的中国年轻人报名参加健身培训课程，以保持更好的体形。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩俊成瘦身训练营特许经营健飞达人 Go Change Now 的联合创始人，在过去十年中其会员人数不断增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “全国约有 1,500-2,000 个训练营，其中 80%其中一次可容纳 100 多名会员，” “有些人对自己的生活不满意，想找到提高自己的出路，而另一些人则需要缓解工作压力，”韩说，他的营地拥有约 4000 名成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些营地最早出现在一线城市，加入成本至少要2万元。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 抖音、快手等平台上流行的直播促销活动导致更多的培训设施在较小的城市和农村地区建立，导致费用大幅降低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “有些营地的收费只有3000到4000元，” 2003年开始做健身教练的韩先生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 许多家长在假期里把超重的孩子送到韩老师那里接受指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “孩子们没有确切地意识到培训对他们有何影响，但有些人表现出了接受我给他们的指示的迹象，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管他让孩子们进行了多次练习，但他的一些孩子在家里又养成了不良的饮食习惯，从而抵消了这些练习的有益效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 因此，为了给孩子们提供更好的生活方式，韩老师萌生了举办夏令营的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了定期锻炼之外，还请了老师来讲解营养、提供心理咨询。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; “我们于 2011 年开设了三个露营地，共有约 1,500 名儿童参加。训练营进行得非常顺利，之后孩子们的体重也没有增加。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于这些积极的成果让孩子们的父母想要加入营地，韩将他的业务从深圳扩展到了海南省三亚市以及其他大约20个城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;p>; 每节课持续 28 天，其中一些在管理更好的学校进行。 Charges range from 8,000 yuan to 20,000 yuan, depending on the services provided.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A detailed hospital examination is required to join a camp.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;People with hypertension have their blood pressure monitored before breakfast, during training and before bedtime to observe any changes,&amp;quot; Han said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For those with diabetes, a nutritionist provides guidance, and their blood sugar levels are measured.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As the participants build up their strength, the workouts are intensified.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Han said that some 20 percent of his members return for more training.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;A number of them like staying here and they even bring their friends along,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Data analyzed&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Researchers from the Chinese PLA General Hospital&amp;#39;s First Medical Center analyzed the data of about 15.8 million participants from 519 health check centers operated by Meinian One-Health Healthcare Group in 243 cities nationwide. The group is headquartered in Shanghai.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Based on the Chinese body mass index classification, 34.8 percent of those studied were overweight and 14.1 percent were obese. The eligible participants were 18 or older and 52.8 percent of them were male. Just over 41 percent of Chinese men were overweight or obese, compared with 27.7 percent of Chinese women.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Complications associated with overweight peaked among males from the ages of 50 to 54, and among females from 65 to 69. The prevalence of obesity-related health problems peaked from the ages of 35 to 39 in males and from 70 to 74 in females.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Xueyan, a professor at Peking Union Medical College Hospital&amp;#39;s endocrinology department, said men are more prone to obesity for several reasons that are usually related to stress at home or at work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To relieve stress, men often resort to unhealthy lifestyles such as drinking alcohol and overeating, Wu said, adding that insufficient or irregular sleep for a long period can lead to obesity among males.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More people are overweight or obese in the north of China than in the south, with the Inner Mongolia autonomous region (37.1 percent), Shandong province (37.1 percent) and Hebei province (36.6 percent) ranking in the top three in this respect.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Buman, deputy director of Tsinghua University Yuquan Hospital&amp;#39;s endocrinal immunology department, said that due to poor diet and sedentary lifestyles, the number of people with metabolic syndrome, which is characterized by abdominal obesity, has risen significantly in modern times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;High hopes&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many market players have set their sights on the training camp business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last year, the Hilefit gymnasium chain opened about 7,300 training camps and welcomed some 30,000 trainees, said Zhou Denghong, an official in charge of the gym&amp;#39;s group class. The number of camps is expected to rise by more than 20 percent this year, Zhou added,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Each camp offers about eight classes, which last for an hour.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The emphasis is placed on precise body measurements, a personalized scientific fitness plan, and comprehensive dietary guidance,&amp;quot; Zhou said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Those who sign up are seeking a positive collective workout atmosphere in which to get in shape.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About 60 percent of the participants join the camps more than once, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fang Bing, a fitness training camp instructor based in Shenzhen, gives two or three classes for four to 12 students every day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Most of them are white-collar workers with previous workout experience. They have a very strong awareness of the need to stay fit, and are extremely self-disciplined,&amp;quot; Fang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many of these people also join the camps for social interaction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;They feel it is more fun to work out together and make friends to watch one another&amp;#39;s diets and other daily routines,&amp;quot; Fang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He has provided instruction on issues such as fat-burning to muscle building at about 300 camps, and most of his members have been with him from the start. &amp;quot;I don&amp;#39;t really look for new members these days, because those I currently have take up about 98 percent of my energy,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fang considers his job rewarding, as many of his members thank him for improving their physique and health.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This motivates me to keep promoting the concept of exercise and health,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen, who joined the boot camp in Dongguan, said the two experiences enabled her to make like-minded friends and maintain a healthier routine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We often encourage each other to keep going when we work out,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said it is important for those wanting to join boot camps to tell the trainers about their health conditions, as most people who are overweight may experience difficulty in exercising.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;If you seldom or never exercise, it is unwise to suddenly take up a demanding training schedule,&amp;quot; Chen said. &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s important to keep an eye on your heart rate and what you eat.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said she will take time off to join similar boot camps in the future. &amp;quot;Why not? It will be a nice vacation experience for me to relax and stay fit,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;yangfeiyue@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China eyes more ties with Central Asia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_003_64fe25b3ed50d203d2c9c0af.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; President Xi Jinping said that China-Central Asia cooperation &amp;quot;has much to achieve and will achieve much&amp;quot; under the new circumstances.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi made the comment in a congratulatory message sent to the 10th China-Central Asia Cooperation Forum, which opened on Saturday in Xiamen, Fujian province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This year marks the 10th anniversary of the Belt and Road Initiative being proposed, and the China-Central Asia Summit was convened in May, marking a milestone in two-way interactions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi emphasized that China and the five Central Asian countries &amp;mdash; Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan &amp;mdash; have taken the lead in jointly advancing the construction of the Belt and Road Initiative and their relations &amp;quot;have entered a new era&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Elaborating on the forum, he noted that since its founding, its scale and influence have expanded gradually.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through the forum, China and Central Asian countries seek common cooperation and shared development. It has greatly enhanced mutual understanding and traditional friendship and written a new chapter in good-neighborly friendship and common progress, Xi wrote.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi expressed his hope that all parties will take the forum as an opportunity to strengthen mutual learning, deepen cooperation in jointly developing the Belt and Road Initiative, and promote more fruitful results in developing relations between China and Central Asian countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The theme of the forum this year is advancing friendly relationships and deepening mutually beneficial cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than 400 guests attended the forum organized by the Good-Neighborliness, Friendship and Cooperation Commission of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization and Fujian provincial people&amp;#39;s government.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Yueyue, vice-chairwoman of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&amp;#39;s Political Consultative Conference and chairwoman of the commission, read out Xi&amp;#39;s letter at the forum.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She noted that the event is a tangible measure to implement leaders&amp;#39; consensus made at the China-Central Asia Summit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Leaders, officials and scholars said that Xi&amp;#39;s letter has &amp;quot;injected confidence and strength&amp;quot; into efforts for furthering friendly relations and deepening mutually beneficial cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Uzbek Deputy Prime Minister Zulaykho Mahkamova said that Xi &amp;quot;has laid out a promising prospect for the development of relations between China and Central Asian countries and will certainly help all parties to carry out fruitful cooperation&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We are full of confidence about China-Central Asia cooperation,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Ming, secretary-general of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, noted that last year, China and the five Central Asian countries announced the joint decision of building a China-Central Asia community with a shared future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;With the progress of China-Central Asia cooperation and the buildup of relevant mechanisms, we look forward to achieving more practical results and bringing tangible benefits to the people of the region,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Teachers key for building stronger nation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_003_64fe25b6ed50d203d2c9c0b0.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; President Xi Jinping has urged teachers across China to work for and contribute to the building of a stronger nation and help realize the goal of national rejuvenation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi, who is also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks in a letter sent to representatives of outstanding teachers attending a symposium on Saturday in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sunday marked Teachers&amp;#39; Day this year. In his letter, Xi sent greetings to teachers and all those working in the education sector across the country on behalf of the CPC Central Committee.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He noted that for a long time, teachers in the country, as represented by the outstanding members, have prepared a significant number of capable individuals who can take on important responsibilities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi said that China has seen plenty of excellent teachers, and they have demonstrated the distinctive ethos of the country&amp;#39;s educationists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He expressed his hope for teachers nationwide to carry forward the high ideals of educationists, and make new and greater contributions to building China into a stronger country and to realizing the goal of national rejuvenation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Premier Li Qiang also issued instructions to mark the occasion, and called for efforts to build the ability of teachers and improve the teachers&amp;#39; education system with Chinese characteristics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi&amp;#39;s letter has drawn wide acclaim from teachers and others working in the nation&amp;#39;s education sector.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After listening to the letter, which was read out at the symposium, Gu Mingyuan, a 93-year-old senior professor at the Beijing Normal University, said the letter &amp;quot;fully reflects the great importance the CPC Central Committee attaches to education &amp;quot;and to the building of a teaching community where senior teachers mentor their successors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Long Qingbo, head of the education bureau of Huishui county, Guizhou province, said that Xi&amp;#39;s letter made him realize that an excellent teacher should &amp;quot;sow the seeds of wisdom in the hearts of students, so that every student has a chance to excel in life&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Early birds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_003_64fe25b9ed50d203d2c9c0b1.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/003/20230911_003_03_44986.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Athletes from Hong Kong arrive on Saturday at the Hangzhou Xiaoshan International Airport in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province, for the Asian Games. They were among the first participants to arrive for the Games that will be held from Sept 23 to Oct 8.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Li urges G20 to strengthen coordination]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_003_64fe25bced50d203d2c9c0b2.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-11/003/20230911_003_04_85986.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Premier Li Qiang addresses the 18th G20 Summit on Saturday in New Delhi, India.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Premier Li Qiang has called on Group of 20 countries to adhere to solidarity and cooperation, and strengthen coordination of macroeconomic policies to deliver confidence in and impetus for economic growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li made the statement while attending the two-day 18th G20 Summit, which concluded on Sunday in the Indian capital, New Delhi.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The summit was chaired by Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, which holds the rotating presidency of the G20 this year. Leaders and representatives from G20 members as well as those of invited countries and international organizations attended the meeting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The premier noted at the inaugural meeting of the summit on Saturday that the destiny of humanity is interdependent, and countries should respect one another, seek common ground while shelving differences and live together in peace.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the face of major crises and common challenges, no one can prosper alone, and only unity and cooperation can lead humanity to the right path, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li urged the G20 members to adhere to the group&amp;#39;s original aspiration of unity and cooperation, shoulder the responsibility of peace and development and effectively strengthen coordination of macroeconomic policies to boost the confidence in and momentum of global economic growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We need to firmly promote economic globalization and jointly safeguard the stable and unimpeded global industrial and supply chains, working as partners in promoting global openness and cooperation,&amp;quot; Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We need to collectively safeguard the green home of the Earth, promote green and low-carbon development, protect the marine ecological environment and work as partners in promoting global sustainable development,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li emphasized the need to resort to unity rather than division, cooperation rather than confrontation, and inclusiveness rather than exclusion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will unswervingly deepen reform and expand opening-up to promote high-quality development and advance Chinese-style modernization, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The premier assured the leaders at the meeting that China enjoys bright development prospects and will inject more impetus into global economic recovery and sustainable development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We are willing to join hands with all parties to make greater efforts and contributions for our common Earth, common home and common future of humanity,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While addressing the third phase of the summit on Sunday, Li said the most pressing issue at present is development. G20 members should put development at the center of macro policy coordination, establish more pragmatic cooperation mechanisms and take practical actions to support developing countries in better addressing development challenges such as poverty reduction, financing, climate change, and food and energy security.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the summit, the African Union was made a permanent member of the G20. In addition, the summit adopted the G20 New Delhi Leaders&amp;#39; Declaration, in which the leaders highlighted the role of the G20 as the premier global forum for international economic cooperation, called for its continued operation in the spirit of multilateralism, and pledged to act in concrete ways through partnerships.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The leaders committed to accelerating strong, sustainable, balanced and inclusive growth, speeding up the full and effective implementation of the United Nations&amp;#39; 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and stepping up actions to address development and climate challenges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They vowed to &amp;quot;improve access to medical countermeasures and facilitate more supplies and production capacities in developing countries to prepare better for future health emergencies&amp;quot;. They also pledged to &amp;quot;promote resilient growth by urgently and effectively addressing debt vulnerabilities in developing countries&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;scale up financing from all sources for accelerating progress on&amp;quot; the Sustainable Development Goals.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next G20 Summit will be held in Brazil next year, according to the leaders&amp;#39; declaration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li concluded his six-day overseas trip, which took him to Indonesia and India, and flew back to Beijing late on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Premier calls on Europe to provide fair business environment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/11/content_003_64fe25bfed50d203d2c9c0b3.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Premier Li Qiang has called for abandoning the practice of politicizing economic issues, urging European countries to provide a fair, just and nondiscriminatory business environment for Chinese companies in their markets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li made the statement while holding a series of bilateral meetings with leaders of European countries and the European Union in New Delhi, India, on the sidelines of the G20 Summit on Saturday and Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During his meeting with United Kingdom Prime Minister Rishi Sunak on Sunday, Li said both countries should uphold open cooperation and maintain and expand common interests.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He urged the UK to oppose politicizing economic issues and trade, and strive to build an open world economy, safeguard the multilateral trading system with the World Trade Organization at its core, and ensure the stable and smooth operation of global industrial and supply chains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Both sides should properly handle differences, uphold the spirit of inclusiveness and mutual learning, and respect each other&amp;#39;s core interests and major concerns, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sunak said the UK respects China&amp;#39;s history and culture and attaches great importance to China&amp;#39;s role in the international system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The UK is willing to engage in constructive and frank dialogue with China, strengthen practical cooperation in the fields of economy, trade and technology, among others, properly handle differences, jointly address global challenges such as climate change, and build a stable and mutually beneficial UK-China relationship, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When meeting with Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni, Li underlined the need for China and Italy to expand bilateral trade for mutual development, and strengthen communication and coordination within the G20 to jointly safeguard the security and stability of global industrial and supply chains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will further open up its market to create more opportunities for high-quality Italian products to enter, Li said. He expressed the hope that Italy will provide a fair, just and nondiscriminatory business environment for Chinese companies to invest and do business in the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meloni said that Italy is willing to strengthen exchanges and dialogues with China under the bilateral framework, promoting further deepening of cooperation between the two countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While meeting with President of the European Commission Ursula von der Leyen on Saturday, Li warned against politicizing economic issues or using security as an excuse to block economic cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that win-win cooperation is the foundation of China-EU relations. As two major forces in a multipolar world and two engines for global development, China and the EU should further unite and cooperate to counter the uncertainties of the world with a stable bilateral relationship, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to work with the EU to hold the China-EU Leaders&amp;#39; Meeting later this year, deepen mutual trust, properly handle differences through communication and consultation, and jointly make more positive contributions to global peace and development, said the premier.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He pointed out that risk prevention and cooperation are not contradictory to each other, and interdependence should not be equated with insecurity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that China is willing to strengthen communication and cooperation with the EU for reliable and stable economic and trade ties, the premier expressed the hope that the EU will uphold the principles of market economy and fair competition, maintain an open trade and investment market, and provide a fair, transparent and nondiscriminatory environment for Chinese enterprises to invest and do business in Europe.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Von der Leyen spoke positively about the fruitful exchanges between the EU and China this year, saying the EU is willing to enhance dialogue and cooperation with China in various fields and jointly address global challenges such as climate change.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li also met with European Council President Charles Michel in New Delhi on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>