<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Mutual trust highlighted at security forum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_001_654014c4ed50d203d2ca1945.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/001/20231031_001_01_97613.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;代表出席第十届北京周一香山论坛。论坛开幕式在北京国际会议中心举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国军队愿与各方携手努力，通过完善架构、加强安全合作，不断深化安全问题互信。中国军方高级官员周一表示，“要加强治理，加强合作”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中央军委副主席张又侠将军在第十届北京香山论坛上发表主旨演讲时表示，面临着世界风云变幻，各国应坚持合作共赢、和谐共同发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他呼吁各国通过对话协商解决争端，并表示任何国家都不能要把自己的意志强加于人，把自己的利益凌驾于别国之上，以牺牲别国的利益来确保自己的安全，或者在重大敏感问题上刻意挑衅他国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 99个官方代表团成员、19个国家的国防部长、14个国家的国防军司令等1800余人出席。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 全世界有良知的人们都希望和平发展、合作共赢，但个别国家却始终奉行零和思维，奉行弱肉强食的丛林法则。他警告说，“我们必须对激化矛盾、助长对抗、作出战略误判的行为保持高度警惕”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张强调，面对全球性挑战，没有人能够独善其身。他呼吁各国共同应对能源、粮食危机以及因战争冲突加剧的全球产业链不稳定等多重危机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张说，习近平主席提出的安全倡议，为共同安全、持久和平提供了正确方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在博鳌亚洲论坛2022年年会开幕式上，习主席提出这一倡议，强调秉持共同、综合、合作、可持续的安全观，尊重各国主权和领土完整，坚持不干涉内政。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 强调相互尊重、合作共赢。表示“一带一路”为实现全球长治久安提供了中国方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，相互尊重是共同安全的基本前提，命运与共。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他概述了需要相互尊重的几个关键方面：主权和领土完整、核心利益和重大关切、各国人民选择的发展道路和社会制度、各国合理的安全关切。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;在谈到台湾问题时，张重申台湾问题事关中国核心利益，一个中国原则是国际社会的普遍共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，无论是谁、以何种方式企图将台湾从中国分裂出去，都将遭到中国军队的坚决拒绝和震慑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 军方高官强调，中国始终是台湾的基石数据显示，中国已与150多个国家开展军事交往，是140多个国家和地区的重要贸易伙伴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国将继续履行大国责任，积极参与维和、军控、反恐、气候变化等领域安全治理工作，加强新兴领域安全问题沟通，积极参与全球安全规则制定，发挥作用他说，在维护世界和平方面发挥了建设性作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;责任与全球安全合作，印度尼西亚国防部副部长穆罕默德·海林德拉 (Muhammad Herindra) 表示，没有一个国家能够单独应对网络安全和全球气候变化等挑战，因为这些挑战影响到我们所有人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 警告单边主义现在构成威胁为了全球和平，他敦促所有国家努力回到加强国家独立和领土完整的道路上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尼日利亚国防部长穆罕默德·巴达鲁·阿布巴卡尔强调，在日益动荡的全球环境中，大国对国际法的支持比以往任何时候都更加重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，遵守和推广国际法可以为预防冲突、保护人权和维护全球稳定建立框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jianchanglong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi calls for fully leveraging the strength of women]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_001_654014c7ed50d203d2ca1946.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席周一强调，妇女在建设强国、推进民族复兴中发挥着不可替代的作用，要激发妇女为中华民族伟大复兴贡献智慧和力量。 ”周四。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平表示，妇联要始终同党密切配合把党中央决策部署转化为具体任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，牢固的亲情、价值观和传统对于子女健康成长、整体健康发展具有重要意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社会各界表示，妇女工作不仅关系到自身发展，还关系到各个家庭、全社会、国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 要动员妇女在弘扬传统文化中发挥独特作用。习近平指出，要加强对青少年婚育家庭观的引导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还强调，要维护妇女儿童合法权益，促进性别平等和妇女儿童全面发展是中国现代化建设的重要内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各级妇联要积极行动，解决影响和侵害妇女儿童利益的突出问题，关注留守儿童等弱势群体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，妇联是联系妇女同党和政府的桥梁和纽带，要深入了解基层妇女群众的关切和需要，提供更多有利资源。和服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mojingxi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Flying Tigers veterans saluted for &#39;profound friendship&#39;]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_001_654014caed50d203d2ca1947.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/001/20231031_001_03_114613.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;人们向 Harry Moyer 唱歌美国飞虎队老兵（右三）周一在北京庆祝他的 103 岁生日。莫耶和他的同胞梅尔·麦克马伦（左二）在第二次世界大战中与中国人民并肩作战，抗击日本侵略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 飞虎队老兵哈利·莫耶——二战中与中国人民并肩抗击日本侵略的美国志愿飞行员——周一在北京迎来了他的 103 岁生日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他正在随主要由飞虎队退伍军人及其家属组成的代表团访问中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席于 ​​9 月给莫耶写了一封回信、飞虎队老兵梅尔·麦克马伦和中美航空遗产基金会主席杰弗里·格林。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平在信中表示希望将飞虎队精神传承给下一代。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 周一上午，美国代表团成员，包括与习近平通话的三人，前往位于北京丰台区的中国人民抗日战争博物馆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们出席了纪念美国第14空军参战80周年的重大活动。该小组继承了美国志愿军于 1941 年开始的工作，该志愿军被广泛称为“飞虎队”，该组织于 1942 年 7 月解散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 活动开始前，莫耶步行而不是坐在轮椅上为活动做准备，浏览了会场外的图片库，里面有飞虎队的档案图片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京市朝阳实验小学的30名小学生站在通往会场的道路两侧敬礼退伍军人的英雄事迹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “给我五个！”莫耶非常高兴地回答了其中一位学生的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在纪念活动上致辞时，中国全国人大常委会副委员长何伟表示：最高立法机构对莫耶说，“两年前的同一天，你驾驶飞机庆祝生日……”昨天你登上了长城。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我谨代表中方祝贺你生日，祝你身体健康。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 莫耶在整个二战期间都是一名战斗机飞行员。结束了地中海战区的战斗，他来到了四川成都的机场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 飞虎队的任务贺军表示，这次来支援中国的行动“是中美并肩作战、共同反侵略的辉煌篇章”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是一个重要的鼓舞源泉”为两国互信、建设稳定健康的中美关系提供指导” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 活动上，中美航空遗产基金会主席格林回忆了习主席的信，并引用了习主席的部分话：“希望精神”飞虎队的精神将在中美两国人民中代代相传”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格林补充道，“习主席在给我们的信中向美国人民证明了”中国不忘老朋友”。他补充说，没有什么比“接受这一点并理解这一点”更重要的了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 出席周一活动的还有飞虎队退伍军人的孩子、孙子和曾孙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; “我希望美国的每个人都能看到这一点。 ……当我们都回家时，我们会和朋友们聊天。他们会和他们的朋友交谈，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 纪念活动的组织者、中国人民对外友好协会会长杨万明承诺，他的组织将邀请美国学生参加“飞虎队青年领袖计划”访华并派中国学生代表团赴美交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “让飞虎队点燃的中美人民友谊火炬代代相传”。杨说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 麦克马伦是另一位给习主席写信的飞虎队老兵，他也是战争期间攻击日本船只的 B-24 轰炸机的炮手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他和活动结束后，代表团成员参观了博物馆，他仔细观看了博物馆内与战争相关的陈列品，如头盔、报纸、弹药样品等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在回答有关战争的问题时麦克马伦说，“我认为他们知道自己在做正确的事。”周一下午，在与包括莫耶、麦克马伦和格林在内的代表团成员在大剧院举行的会议上，麦克马伦说，他们秉承了飞虎队的精神。人民大会堂副院长韩正表示，飞虎队伟大事迹是“两国人民用生命和鲜血结成的深厚友谊”的典范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当今世界，“许多重大挑战仍需要中美两国共同面对”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国要坚持相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢，为世界和平与发展作出更大贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Medical team draws up plans for astronauts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_001_654014cded50d203d2ca1948.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 每次中国航天员升空或返回地球，几乎所有参与其中的航天工作者都希望自己精心磨练的技能能够为任务的成功做出贡献。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，一些训练有素的专业人士总是希望他们的专业知识永远不会被需要。他们是载人航天医疗保障队负责处理航天员健康突发事件的医生和护士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2003年10月神舟五号——我中心的医疗专家参加了每次载人飞行任务的现场医疗保障工作，并且出色地完成了本职工作。”着陆场系统副总指挥、北京总部医疗保障组组长顾建文在中国西北部戈壁滩的酒泉卫星发射中心接受中国日报专访时表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;顾先生说，二十年来，他所在医疗中心神经外科、骨科、普外科、心血管内科、胸外科、呼吸内科、消化内科等科室的近3000名医生和护士为载人航天飞行提供了紧急卫生援助&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在每一个新船员的发射阶段，我们都被要求待命——”从运载火箭升空前15分钟到升空后3分钟。当航天器返回地球时，我们负责首先检查机组人员的身体状况，然后进行初步体检。” ”这位也是国内顶级神经外科医生的主任说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一支由15名高级医疗人员组成的团队，配备齐全的急救药品和医疗设备，负责为抗击疫情提供支持。神舟十六号、神舟十七号机组成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 顾说，该团队已针对烫伤、烧伤、撞击伤、冻伤等 29 种可能需要医疗干预的紧急情况进行了准备，并补充说，已制定了具体的预案和准备。神舟十七号机组人员针对每种可能的情况进行了刻苦训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任务指挥员唐洪波大校、唐胜杰中校、蒋新林中校——周四上午从酒泉发射中心起飞，当天晚些时候抵达天宫空间站。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 神舟十六号航天员——任务指挥员景海鹏少将、朱扬柱大校、桂海潮教授——已完成近五个月在天宫的全部任务，预计周二返回地球。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “考虑到东风着陆点附近有森林和水体，我们的专家已不仅进行了关键的医疗手术，还进行了高强度的体育锻炼。他们甚至学会了基于直升机的快速部署机动，”顾说。 “我们有信心、有能力履行我们的职责，并将始终为我们的宇航员提供最好的医疗服务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在谈到未来的任务时，这位神经外科医生表示，他的中心已经开始对宇航员的医疗支持进行探索性研究。中国计划的载人月球探险和更深入太空的载人探险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“未来，当我们的宇航员飞向月球和火星时，他们将如何适应那里的环境以及他们将如何照顾他们的神经、内分泌、代谢、消化和其他重要系统——这些是我们目前关注的问题，”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhaolei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - YOUNG ENTREPRENEURS TAKING TO WORLD OF AI]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_001_654014d0ed50d203d2ca1949.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/001/20231031_002_01_27668.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/001/20231031_002_01_32668.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 13年打造的人工智能平台-old 上个月在广东深圳首次亮相后，迅速在中学生中疯传。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; AI-Button，由今年进入八年级的中学生邱雨沫创立的平台&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着美国OpenAI公司开发的聊天机器人ChatGPT席卷科技界，邱使用大语言模型—— ChatGPT 的一项关键技术——第一次开发她的学习平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 许多技术行业专家认为，以 ChatGPT 为基础的人工智能革命正在推动一种新的创业形式，被描述为“更小、更快、更便宜、更经济”。更奇怪”作者：Nathan Baschez，美国日报初创公司 Every Inc. 联合创始人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与邱一样，来自中国的年轻人，尤其是 20 世纪 90 年代和 2000 年代出生的年轻人，越来越多地投身人工智能创业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 2010年出生的邱女士，6岁时就开始编程。一年后，她编写了一款电脑游戏，这引发了她对开发复杂软件的兴趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “直到ChatGPT开始腾飞之后，我才感受到了其中带来的机遇。”通过新一代人工智能，我意识到这些技术可以改变世界，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ChatGPT 正在推动人工智能革命，高盛的一份研究报告称，这场革命有可能给全球经济带来彻底的变化，并可能带来 7% 的增长，即近 7 万亿美元，在未来十年的全球 GDP 中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在这一趋势的推动下，一种新形式的人工智能初创公司已经出现。在中国，与以往此类创业公司需要明星创始人、巨额融资和数十名员工不同，ChatGPT的出现为所有创业者提供了一个新的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，邱组建了一个学生团队来自她的中学和邻居的帮助她。团队成员有的负责测试和优化，有的负责推广工作，还有的负责对外联络与合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 受到科技巨头腾讯控股推出的在线公益项目的启发，邱和她的团队合作伙伴鼓励学生使用 AI-Button。学生可以发起和参与公益项目并从中获得收益，这些收益可以用于平台上的学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 所有团队成员每周都参加会议，以确保取得进展。经过几个月的开发和产品优化，AI-Button终于成为一个成熟的项目，并开始接受用户注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我第一次意识到，没有人可以做所有事情，但每个人都可以做某事，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 来自 Every Inc 的 Baschez 在一份报告中表示，这个新时代的人工智能初创企业都是从小规模开始的。 “他们使用开源和云计算来快速启动并执行重复性任务。多亏了人工智能，他们将在更长时间内保持较小的规模，而最成功的公司将只需要少数员工就能取得惊人的成果。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他的评论得到了 Midjourney 示例的支持，Midjourney 是一个使用人工智能从文本描述生成图片的系统。 Midjouney 团队一开始只有 11 名全职员工，其中有 4 名尚未毕业且没有在顶尖大学就读的学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Baschez 说，“更重要的是，这种新型员工的组织可以尝试新的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“进入门槛已经比以往任何时候都低，但现在人工智能足以设计界面、编写代码和执行营销活动，我们将看到一系列全新的实验上线。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;项目启动&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国，妙芽相机是一款人工智能驱动的数字产品，在线生成自画像，于 7 月在微信上以小程序形式推出，距离由 6 名出生于 80 年代末和 90 年代初的中国软件专业人士组成的团队概念化并开发了该产品仅五个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 要使用妙芽相机获取人工智能肖像，用户只需支付 9.90 元（1.40 美元）并上传至少 20 张近期肖像即可获得数字克隆。然后，他们将克隆人变成不同类型的肖像，例如证件照、商务照或中国古代风格的肖像。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 用户可以训练人工智能，使肖像更加逼真。行业专家表示，这是人工智能的逻辑结果，生成模型利用从示例中学到的知识来创造新的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在高峰时段，有超过 6,000 人在线等待使用该产品。有些人甚至要等待15个小时以上才能获得数字克隆。推出一个月内，秒芽相机就被市场观察人士视为人工智能生成内容（AIGC）的潜在颠覆者，该市场是由于 ChatGPT 的到来而产生的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; AIGC 使用人工智能算法和图像生成器是清华大学2012届毕业生中的领头人，他说： 39;的市场表现远远超出了他的预期。他将这一成功部分归功于 AIGC 的新浪潮，大量消费者期待使用 ChatGPT 相关技术的应用程序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我认为 AIGC 和互联网的商业逻辑是根本不同。互联网商业本质上是信息流、渠道和平台。但人工智能时代的本质可以比作建造工厂。指向市场需求的技术更容易被客户接受。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京社科院高级研究员王鹏表示，当ChatGPT带来进一步的技术进步时，更多的中国消费者将愿意接受此类技术，从而导致应用程序进一步成功&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 生活方式平台小红书进行的一项民意调查发现，72%的年轻用户更喜欢用妙芽相机制作的个人资料照片，而不是大型专业人像摄影连锁店天真蓝拍摄的照片。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 王说：“更重要的是，AIGC正在降低创业门槛。美国可能已经在与 ChatGPT 的 AIGC 竞赛中处于领先地位，但中国现在与美国站在同一起跑线上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，这也意味着中国 AI 企业家正在快速追赶&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;发展热潮&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵志云，中国科学技术信息研究所所长，科技部下属的技术部表示，美国和中国在全球大规模人工智能模型（ChatGPT 背后的关键技术）的开发方面处于领先地位，贡献了全球 80% 的模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国的大型人工智能模型正在蓬勃发展，多个技术领域同时取得突破。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 领先的自然语言处理产品和服务初创公司北京泛语科技有限公司董事长周宇表示，由于风险很高，中国和美国的初创公司似乎采取了不同的开发方式。驱动生成式人工智能的大语言模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “美国初创公司的创始人更加注重底层技术的研发和突破性创新。美国在硬件和深度学习框架方面处于世界领先地位。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国的人工智能初创企业更注重应用，这些初创企业更擅长将技术应用于各个行业，并将不同的应用商业化。”他们在打造个性化产品和创新方面也更加灵活，尤其是在小众领域，从而给年轻一代更多的机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国青年创业就业基金会的一份报告称，19世纪的年轻人-23岁年龄段是中国年轻创业者的主要群体。其中近 70% 的人以不到 10 万元（13,680 美元）的资金创办了一家公司。超过一半的企业经历了利润和亏损的波动，但其中70%的企业在三年内开始盈利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国劳动和社会保障研究院的另一份报告称，数字化的快速发展经济的发展吸引了大量的年轻人，特别是35岁以下的年轻人创业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这种创业主要得益于数字技术降低了创业的准入门槛，并提供了良好的条件。就业条件。报告称，数字经济的快速发展带动了年轻人的新就业形态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，35岁以下的小程序用户占比超过73%报告称，年轻一代已成为中国数字经济发展不可或缺的力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 香港商汤科技联合创始人陈宇恒中国AI上市先锋，诞生于20世纪90年代。他见证了中国互联网和人工智能的发展，也见证了ChatGPT如何引发国家的人工智能热潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2013年从清华大学毕业后不久，他和几位朋友创立商汤科技。陈从创业公司的三号员工成长为香港联交所第一家上市人工智能企业的联合创始人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 商汤科技最初专注于计算机视觉，后来扩展到包括自动驾驶在内的更多业务领域&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在ChatGPT引发的人工智能热潮中，该公司大展技术实力。今年8月，其大语言模型SenseChat经主管部门批准，正式开放注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 商汤科技投入大量资源研发InternLM，这是与上海人工智能实验室等国内多家领先研究机构合作开发的预训练大语言人工智能模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈说： “我很幸运能随着人工智能的发展而成长，但我现在也需要跟上时代的变化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：hengyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - YOUNG ENTREPRENEURS TAKING TO WORLD OF AI]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_002_654014d0ed50d203d2ca194a.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/002/20231031_002_01_27668.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/002/20231031_002_01_32668.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 13年研发团队推出的人工智能平台-old 上个月在广东深圳首次亮相后，迅速在中学生中疯传。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; AI-Button，由今年进入八年级的中学生邱雨沫创立的平台&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着美国OpenAI公司开发的聊天机器人ChatGPT席卷科技界，邱使用大语言模型—— ChatGPT 的一项关键技术——第一次开发她的学习平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 许多技术行业专家认为，人工智能革命以 ChatGPT 为基础，正在推动一种新的创业形式，被描述为“更小、更快、更便宜、更经济”。更奇怪”作者：Nathan Baschez，美国日报初创公司 Every Inc. 联合创始人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与邱一样，来自中国的年轻人，尤其是 20 世纪 90 年代和 2000 年代出生的年轻人，越来越多地投身人工智能创业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 2010年出生的邱女士，6岁时就开始编程。一年后，她编写了一款电脑游戏，这引发了她对开发复杂软件的兴趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “直到ChatGPT开始腾飞之后，我才感受到了其中带来的机遇。”通过新一代人工智能，我意识到这些技术可以改变世界，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ChatGPT 正在推动人工智能革命，高盛的一份研究报告称，这场革命有可能给全球经济带来彻底的变化，并可能带来 7% 的增长，即近 7 万亿美元，在未来十年的全球 GDP 中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在这一趋势的推动下，一种新形式的人工智能初创公司已经出现。 In China, unlike previous such startups that needed star founders, huge amounts of financing, and dozens of employees, the advent of ChatGPT offers a new chance for all entrepreneurs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, Qiu formed a team of students from her middle school and those in the neighborhood to help her. Some team members were in charge of testing and optimization, some were responsible for promotion work, while others helped with external liaison and cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Inspired by online public welfare projects launched by tech giant Tencent Holdings, Qiu and her partners encouraged students to use AI-Button. Students can initiate and take part in public welfare projects and receive benefits from them, which can be used for learning on the platform.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; All the team members attended weekly meetings to ensure progress was made. After several months of development and product optimization, AI-Button finally became a mature project and registration began for users.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For the first time, I realized that no one can do everything, but everyone can do something,&amp;quot; Qiu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Baschez, from Every Inc, said in a note that AI startups in this new age begin small. &amp;quot;They use open source and cloud computing to get off the ground quickly and perform recurring tasks. Thanks to AI, they will stay smaller for much longer, and the most successful will achieve staggering results with only a handful of employees,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His comments are supported by the example of Midjourney, a system that uses AI to generate pictures from text descriptions. The Midjouney team at his beginning comprised only 11 full-time employees, with four of them students who had yet to graduate and were not studying at leading universities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Baschez said, &amp;quot;More important, this new type of organization can try out fresh ideas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The entry barrier is already lower than ever, but now that AI is good enough to design interfaces, write code, and execute marketing campaigns, we&amp;#39;re going to see a whole new set of experiments come online.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Program launches&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In China, Miaoya Camera, an AI-powered digital product that generates self-portraits online, launched as a mini program on WeChat in July, just five months after the launch team of six Chinese software professionals, who were born in the late 1980s and early 1990s, conceptualized and developed the product.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To obtain an AI portrait by using Miaoya Camera, users pay 9.90 yuan ($1.40) and upload at least 20 recent portraits to get a digital clone. They then turn the clone into different types of portraits, such as ID photos, business photos, or those in an ancient Chinese style.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Users can train the AI to make the portraits more lifelike. Industry experts said this is the logical outcome of AI, where a generative model takes what it learns from examples to create something new.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During peak times, more than 6,000 people wait online to use the product. Some even wait for more than 15 hours to obtain a digital clone. Within a month of its launch, Miaoya Camera was viewed by market observers as a potential disruptor of the AIGC, or artificial intelligence-generated content, niche market arising from the arrival of ChatGPT.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; AIGC uses AI algorithms and technologies to generate high-quality content, including articles, blog posts, product descriptions and social media updates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Yueguang, leader of a group of students who graduated from Tsinghua University in 2012, said the portrait generator&amp;#39;s market performance is way beyond his expectations. He attributes part of this success to the new wave of AIGC, with a large number of consumers looking forward to applications that use ChatGPT-related technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I think the business logic of AIGC and the internet is fundamentally different. Business on the internet is essentially about information flow, channels and platforms. But the essence of the AI era can be compared with building a factory. Technologies that point to market demand are more easily accepted by customers,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Peng, a senior researcher at the Beijing Academy of Social Sciences, said that when ChatGPT delivers further technological advances, more Chinese consumers will be willing to embrace such technologies, resulting in further success for applications such as Miaoya Camera.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A poll carried out by the lifestyle platform Xiaohongshu found that 72 percent of young users preferred a profile photo created by Miaoya Camera to one taken by Tianzhenlan, a major professional portrait photography chain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said: &amp;quot;More important, AIGC is lowering the threshold for entrepreneurship. The US may have taken the lead in the AIGC race with ChatGPT, but China now stands on the same starting line with the US.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that this also means that Chinese AI entrepreneurs are catching up fast with their US counterparts in the new AIGC era.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Development booms&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Zhiyun, head of the Institute of Scientific and Technical Information of China, which is affiliated with the Ministry of Technology, said the US and China have led global development of large-scale AI models, the key technology behind ChatGPT, contributing to 80 percent of them across the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Development of China&amp;#39;s large AI models is booming, with breakthroughs being made in several technical areas at the same time,&amp;quot; Zhao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Yu, chairman of Beijing Fanyu Technology Co, a leading natural language processing products and services startup, said that as the stakes are high, Chinese and US startups appear to be taking different approaches to developing large language models that drive generative AI.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Founders of US startups put more emphasis on the research and development of underlying technology and groundbreaking innovations. The US is a world leader in terms of hardware and deep learning frameworks,&amp;quot; Zhou said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Chinese AI startups focus more on applications, and those launching these startups are better at adapting technology to various industries, and commercializing different applications. They are also more flexible in creating personalized products and innovations, especially in niche sectors, thus giving the younger generation more opportunities.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A report by the China Foundation for Youth Entrepreneurship and Employment said those in the 19-23 age bracket in China comprise the main group of young entrepreneurs. Nearly 70 percent of them started a company with less than 100,000 yuan ($13,680). More than half have experienced fluctuations in profits and losses, but 70 percent of them began making a profit within three years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another report, from the Chinese Academy of Labour and Social Security, said rapid development of the digital economy has attracted a large number of young people, especially those under the age of 35, to start a business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Such entrepreneurship is mainly due to digital technologies that lower the entry barrier to starting a business and offering good employment conditions. As a result, rapid development of the digital economy has helped drive a new form of employment for young people, the report said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, those younger than 35 account for more than 73 percent of mini-program developers on major social media platforms, the report said, adding that the younger generation has become an indispensable force for the development of the digital economy in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Yuheng, a cofounder of SenseTime, a Hong Kong-listed Chinese AI pioneer, was born in the 1990s. He has witnessed the development of the internet and AI in China, and the way in which ChatGPT has triggered the nation&amp;#39;s AI boom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shortly after graduating from Tsinghua University in 2013, he and several friends founded SenseTime. Chen rose from being No 3 employee at the startup to cofounder of the first listed AI business on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; SenseTime started by focusing on computer vision, before expanding into more business areas, including autonomous driving technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company is flexing its technological muscle amid the AI boom triggered by ChatGPT.In August, SenseChat, its large language model, officially opened to the public for registration after being approved by the authorities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; SenseTime devoted numerous resources to researching and developing InternLM, a pre-trained large language AI model developed in collaboration with several leading domestic research institutions, including the Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said, &amp;quot;I am fortunate to grow with the development of AI, but I now also need to keep up with these changing times.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at chengyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Renewable energy capacity grows robustly]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_003_654014d3ed50d203d2ca194b.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s installed renewable energy capacity saw robust growth during the first nine months of this year amid the country&amp;#39;s efforts to advance its green transition, according to the National Energy Administration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Renewable energy capacity additions rose 93 percent year-on-year to 172 million kilowatts during the first three quarters, accounting for 76 percent of the country&amp;#39;s total newly added installations, the NEA said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Solar power installation during the reporting period rose 145 percent year-on-year to 128.94 million kW, followed by wind power of 33.48 million kW, said Wang Dapeng, deputy head of the administration&amp;#39;s new energy and renewable energy department, during a news conference in Beijing on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As part of China&amp;#39;s efforts to speed up the construction of solar and wind power generation facilities in the Gobi Desert and other arid regions, construction has begun on all of the first large-scale wind and solar power bases, a project launched at the end of 2021 that comprises a total of around 100 gigawatts of wind and solar power capacity in desert areas, the administration said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The bases are mainly in the Xinjiang Uygur, Inner Mongolia and Ningxia Hui autonomous regions, and in Qinghai, Gansu and Shaanxi provinces, which all possess abundant wind and solar resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Construction has also begun on the second group of bases, comprising more than 30 million kW of wind and solar power capacity in desert areas, while the project list for the third group has been officially issued for implementation, it added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Luo Zuoxian, head of intelligence and research at the Sinopec Economics and Development Research Institute, said China has been making huge strides in shifting from its dependence on coal to the use of renewables for power generation, a boon to achieving the country&amp;#39;s carbon goals and tackling climate change.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The installed capacity of renewable energy, which has surpassed that of thermal power, is on track to account for half of the country&amp;#39;s total installed capacity, from the current 49.6 percent, as renewable energy like solar and wind power has been playing an increasingly prominent role in ensuring the country&amp;#39;s energy supply, Luo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The steady growth of renewables was accompanied by accelerated investment in related infrastructure projects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Energy investment in China maintained rapid growth in the first three quarters, with total investment in key energy projects under construction and those planned to begin within the year reaching nearly 1.5 trillion yuan ($205 billion) during the first eight months, up 20.7 percent compared with the same period in the previous year, said Dong Wancheng, deputy director of the development and planning department of the NEA.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Investment in nonfossil energy projects accounted for more than 40 percent of the total national energy investment, Dong said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhengxin@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Building links]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_003_654014d6ed50d203d2ca194c.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/003/20231031_003_02_43600.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina pays a toll on Saturday as she passes through a tollbooth of the Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Tunnel, located at the estuary of the Karnaphuli River in Chittagong, Bangladesh. The expressway, a part of which is underwater, was built by China Communication Construction Co. It opened to vehicular traffic on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Palace Museum&#39;s new gallery sheds light on imperial printing history]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_003_654014d8ed50d203d2ca194d.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/003/20231031_003_03_60600.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Wang Xudong (left), director of the Palace Museum, attends the opening ceremony of the museum&amp;#39;s new gallery displaying printing woodblocks in Beijing on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A gallery displaying printing woodblocks opened at the Palace Museum in Beijing on Monday, the first such exhibition space of its kind since the museum opened to the public in 1925.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Palace Museum, also known as the Forbidden City, was China&amp;#39;s imperial palace from 1420 to 1911.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It houses 1.86 million cultural relics, and about one-third of these are ancient books, documents and related printing woodblocks, making the museum a key venue on the development of Chinese literature.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, these precious relics for academic studies previously lacked a venue in which they could be publicly showcased.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Wang Xudong, director of the museum, the institution now has a collection of about 240,000 printing woodblocks, including 210,000 made within the royal court during the Ming (1368-1644) and Qing (1644-1911) dynasties, which are mainly related to classic literature, records of national affairs and Buddhist sutras.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The opening exhibition of the new gallery, near the Gate of Supreme Harmony, features 32 woodblocks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;These exhibits are of great value for people to understand the politics, culture and printing techniques of that era,&amp;quot; Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Putting them in the context of the history of Chinese classic books and the Qing inner court, we can get more information through in-depth studies, which will inspire us to develop modern culture.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, an exhibited woodblock carved with dragon patterns was made in 1644 shortly after Qing troops seized Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It demonstrates a Qing imperial admonition demanding that princes and high officials strictly stick to their duties and avoid corruption. Related records in historical files and printed notices using this woodblock are also presented alongside it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another exhibited pair of woodblocks, made in the Wanli era (1573-1620) to print a comprehensive collection of Confucian classics and Chinese dynastic history, were important references for Ming scholars and were ordered to be carefully restored by Qing rulers, as indicated by their markings.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some woodblocks were also made to record aspects of the royal lifestyle, with a group used to print landscape pictures of the Chengde Mountain Resort and Emperor Kangxi&amp;#39;s poems lauding its beauty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To give visitors an immersive experience, a part of the gallery is designed as a warehouse, where over 15,000 printing blocks are on the shelves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ji Zhangwei, a researcher at the Palace Museum Library, said that woodblock printing reached its peak during the Ming and Qing dynasties. The royal courts of the two dynasties made a great effort to sponsor printing as an important way to demonstrate national strength and promote cultural development. Pear wood was the most common material to make the blocks at the time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a result of the preservation of these woodblocks, &amp;quot;many precious ancient documents survive to this day&amp;quot;, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, many woodblocks have been lost over the centuries, &amp;quot;so what we see today are only fragments of the whole&amp;quot;, added Ji.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, printing houses and libraries in the Forbidden City were hit by fires several times during the imperial era. There was also a great deal of damage to the collection during the war of 1900, when Beijing fell to foreign invaders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hall of Martial Valor, where the imperial printing house was located, remains to this day, and its surviving woodblocks are generally in good condition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This heritage comprises a crucial example of the world&amp;#39;s ancient printing history,&amp;quot; Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A charity program was announced in July to further conserve, digitize, study and revitalize these literary treasures at the Palace Museum. The effort also involves the China Foundation for Cultural Heritage Conservation and ByteDance, the parent company of short-video platform TikTok. The new gallery is one of the first results of this work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Thanks to the program, the charm of ancient printing arts may be better recognized by the public,&amp;quot; said Liu Yuzhu, head of the foundation. &amp;quot;As a result, more sectors of society may be inspired to participate in the protection of cultural relics.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkaihao@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China to further improve its visa policies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_003_654014dbed50d203d2ca194e.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; The Foreign Ministry said on Monday that China will continue to improve its visa policies and actively create more favorable conditions to boost cross-border travel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The statement came a week after Chinese embassies and consulates in more than 10 countries, including the United States, the United Kingdom, Italy, the Netherlands, South Korea, Singapore and New Zealand, ceased online visa appointments in favor of walk-in visa application services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The new system allows visitors to go directly to Chinese diplomatic missions during their operating hours and apply for a visa. After entering a visa office, the applicants are required to go through security screening, acquire a token number and wait their turn.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Foreign Ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said the new policy has yielded positive results, with the number of visas issued by diplomatic missions rebounding rapidly and the number of foreigners traveling to China rising steadily.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the beginning of this year, China has been improving its visa policies. The Foreign Ministry has been working with other government agencies to roll out measures to ensure smooth channels for foreigners traveling to China and facilitate efforts to achieve high-quality development and high-level opening-up, Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following the decision to manage COVID-19 with measures against Class-B infectious diseases, the ministry directed embassies and consulates to extend office hours, reduce materials required for visa applications, increase staff, issue multipleentry visas when possible and temporarily exempt applicants from registering their fingerprints, so as to make the visa process more efficient, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Green lanes have been added for groups with important and urgent business or humanitarian affairs. Most Chinese embassies and consulates now provide visa appointments down to two working days in advance. There are a few Chinese missions that no longer require an online appointment, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China has also signed visa-exemption agreements with Kazakhstan, Madagascar and other countries this year, increasing the total number of such mutual agreements to 155.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhoujin@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Flying Tigers veterans saluted for &#39;profound friendship&#39;]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/31/content_003_654014dbed50d203d2ca194f.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-31/003/20231031_001_03_114613.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;People sing to Harry Moyer (third from right), a United States Flying Tigers veteran, on his 103rd birthday in Beijing on Monday. Moyer and his compatriot Mel McMullen (second from left) fought in World War II alongside the Chinese people against Japanese aggression.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Harry Moyer, a veteran of the Flying Tigers &amp;mdash; United States volunteer pilots who fought alongside Chinese people against Japanese aggression in World War II &amp;mdash; turned 103 on Monday in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He is visiting China among a delegation composed primarily of Flying Tigers veterans and their family members.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping wrote a reply letter in September to Moyer, fellow Flying Tigers veteran Mel McMullen and Sino-American Aviation Heritage Foundation Chairman Jeffrey Greene.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In his letter, Xi voiced his hope that the spirit of the Flying Tigers will be passed down to the next generation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Monday morning, the US delegation members, including the three with whom Xi corresponded, traveled to the Museum of the War of Chinese People&amp;#39;s Resistance Against Japanese Aggression in Beijing&amp;#39;s Fengtai district.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They attended a major event marking the 80th anniversary of the US 14th Air Force&amp;#39;s participation in the war. That group carried on the work started in 1941 by the American Volunteer Group, widely known as the Flying Tigers, which was disbanded in July 1942.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before the event, Moyer, who walked rather than sitting in a wheelchair prepared for the event, browsed a picture gallery outside the venue featuring archive images of the Flying Tigers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thirty elementary school students from Beijing Chaoyang Experimental Primary School stood on both sides of the path leading toward the venue to salute the veterans&amp;#39; heroic deeds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Give me five!&amp;quot; Moyer said in great delight in response to one of the students.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While addressing the commemorative event, He Wei, vice-chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&amp;#39;s Congress, China&amp;#39;s top legislative body, said to Moyer, &amp;quot;On the very same day two years ago, you flew an airplane to celebrate your birthday&amp;hellip; and yesterday you climbed the Great Wall.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;On behalf of the Chinese side, I would like to congratulate you on your birthday and wish you good health,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Moyer was a fighter pilot throughout World War II. After fighting in the Mediterranean theater, he came to the airfields in Chengdu, Sichuan province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Flying Tigers&amp;#39; action of coming to support China &amp;quot;is a brilliant chapter in the joint fight against aggression, in which China and the US fought side by side&amp;quot;, said He.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It is an important source of inspiration and guidance for the mutual trust between the two countries and for building a stable and healthy China-US relationship,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the event, Greene, the Sino-American Aviation Heritage Foundation chairman, recalled Xi&amp;#39;s letter and quoted some of Xi&amp;#39;s words: &amp;quot;I hope that the spirit of the Flying Tigers will be carried forth from generation to generation among the Chinese and the American people&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Greene added, &amp;quot;In that letter to us, President Xi proved to the American people that &amp;hellip; China does not forget its old friends&amp;quot;. He added that nothing is more important than &amp;quot;accepting that and understanding that&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Also present at the event on Mon-day were children, grandchildren and a great-grandchild of Flying Tiger veterans.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I wish everybody in America can see this. &amp;hellip; When we all go home, we will talk to our friends. They will talk to their friends,&amp;quot; Greene said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Wanming, president of the Chinese People&amp;#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries, organizer of the commemorative event, pledged that his organization will invite US students with the Flying Tigers Youth Leadership Program to visit China and send Chinese student delegations to the US for exchanges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Let the torch of friendship between the Chinese and American people lit by the Flying Tigers be passed from generation to generation,&amp;quot; Yang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; McMullen, the other Flying Tigers veteran who wrote to President Xi, was also a gunner on a B-24 bomber that attacked Japanese ships during the war.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He and the delegation members toured the museum after the event, and he had a good look at the museum&amp;#39;s displays related to the war, such as helmets, newspapers and ammunition samples.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When answering a question about the spirit of the Flying Tigers, McMullen said, &amp;quot;I think they knew they were doing the right thing.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At a meeting with delegation members including Moyer, McMullen and Greene on Monday afternoon at the Great Hall of the People, Vice-President Han Zheng said the Flying Tigers&amp;#39; great deeds were examples of the &amp;quot;profound friendship forged with lives and blood of the two nations&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In today&amp;#39;s world, &amp;quot;many major challenges still need to be faced jointly by China and the US in cooperation&amp;quot;, Han said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two countries should adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence and win-win cooperation and make greater contributions to world peace and development, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>