<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Sports can help promote world peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_001_6510aa79ed50d203d2c9ce2c.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 全球领导人在杭州亚洲峰会期间认可习近平主席领导的北京最新外交努力，注意到中国对世界和平、团结与繁荣的切实承诺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周六晚开幕的第十九届亚运会是2022年中共二十大闭幕以来我国举办的规模最大、水平最高的综合性国际体育赛事&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 来自亚洲45个国家和地区的12000多名运动员齐聚风景秀丽的浙江省会杭州，众多世界领导人和国际组织代表齐聚一堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在周六举行的奥运会欢迎宴会上，开幕式上，习主席指出，这一天是秋分，是农历秋分，丰收、团圆的日子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “山水相连的命运共同体，我们要以体育促和平，睦邻互利，摒弃冷战思维和集团对抗。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们应该让亚洲成为世界和平的支柱，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，本届运动会报名运动员数量、比赛项目数量均创历史新高，“我们要以体育促团结”。他呼吁“为亚洲共同发展、开放融合之路开辟更广阔前景”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们要以体育促进包容，增强文明信心，促进交流与融合。”互学互鉴，重振亚洲文明辉煌”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 学者们表示，中国举办亚运会的目的是通过体育“促进和平、团结、包容”，习近平领导的最新体育外交浙江工业大学马克思主义学院教授肖建中表示，“对中国来说，杭州亚运会不仅是一次重大体育赛事，更是服务这是国内外交的一件大事，也是亚洲文明交流的重要舞台。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周五至周六，习近平在杭州与中国国家领导人举行了多次双边会见。来访的亚洲六国领导人以及亚奥理事会和国际奥委会的负责人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与知名人士的会见是在风景秀丽的旅游胜地西湖的国宾馆举行的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年是习近平提出“亲诚惠容”中国理念十周年，习近平主席周六在同外国领导人会谈时提到了这一原则。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在与柬埔寨国王诺罗敦·西哈莫尼交谈时表示，中柬关系体现了这一原则，并指出中国国王在该地区的外交中致力于与邻国建立睦邻友好和伙伴关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国王赞扬两国之间铁定的兄弟关系，并表示他的国家随时准备与中国在“一带一路”建设上开展合作&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国际奥委会主席托马斯·巴赫周五向习近平表示，“我相信亚运会一定会成功、精彩，促进团结和友谊” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，国际奥委会致力于维护体育非政治化，得到国际社会广泛支持，赞同中方的正确立场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 科威特王储谢赫米沙尔·艾哈迈德·贾比尔·萨巴赫表示，习主席提出的“一带一路”倡议、全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议和全球文明倡议的倡议是“重要的”。 “基于促进人类和平与进步的崇高目标和原则”，科威特坚定支持并积极参与。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 观察人士指出，北京对世界繁荣与和平的一贯追求也可以习近平分别于周五和周六与叙利亚总统巴沙尔·阿萨德和东帝汶总理夏纳纳·古斯芒会谈后发布的两份联合声明中可以看到这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两次声明，中国宣布与叙利亚建立战略伙伴关系，与东帝汶建立全面战略伙伴关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 共建“一带一路”和人类命运共同体，支撑当地生计和“共同推进真正的多边主义”两份声明指出了国际舞台上的共同共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 浙江外国语大学环地中海研究所所长、教授马晓林表示，中方：作为发展中大国和世界第二大经济体，“始终不忘作为亚洲和世界大国的社会责任”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杭州亚运会是这座城市&amp; #39“向世界展示中国形象、促进各国人民面对面交流的最大舞台”他说，自七年前杭州主办 G20 峰会以来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 巴基斯坦主要报纸《国家报》的撰稿人亚西尔·哈比卜·汗 (Yasir Habib Khan) 指出，板球重返亚运会将其纳入杭州赛事“对于这项运动和中国的外交努力来说都是一个关键时刻”，因为巴基斯坦和印度的球队现在可能有机会在奥运会上展开友好的竞争。&lt;/他写道，将板球纳入亚运会“体现了中国致力于利用体育作为国际参与与合作的桥梁”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杭州亚运会他补充说，“这证明了体育在全球舞台上团结各国、打破障碍、打造友谊与合作的共同叙事的力量”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily。 com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - SPOTLIGHT SHINES ON BEIJING&#39;S CENTRAL AXIS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_001_6510aa7bed50d203d2c9ce2d.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/001/20230925_002_01_33048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;什刹海旁的居民下棋北京中轴线沿线的湖泊。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/001/20230925_002_01_34048.png&quot; />;&lt; p>;游客在中山公园参观中轴线黑白老照片展。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09 -25/001/20230925_002_01_35048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;骑行者参观钟楼。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25 /001/20230925_002_01_36048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;正阳门吸引游客。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/ 001/20230925_002_01_37048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;鼓楼外观。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/ 001/20230925_002_01_30048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 刚刚结束的北京中山公园展览中展出的50余幅黑白老照片，让参观者感受到历史文化意义&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些展品还提醒人们需要保护这条路线上的文化遗产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些版画，从 1860 年代到20世纪40年代，是国内外摄影师和机构的作品，包括意大利裔英国摄影师费利斯·贝托（Felice Beato）、中国摄影师赖阿丰、苏黎世平版印刷公司和同盛照相馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盖建中，中山研究中心主任展览联合策展人帕克表示：“这些图像首次作为北京中轴线背景下的原始照片展出。它们无疑将为中国历史图像，特别是与北京城市历史相关的图像的研究和展示提供新的框架和参考体系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，这些照片的最大意义在于重点是它们描绘了中轴线沿线建筑的一些原始状况，这将有助于今后的修复和保护工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 版画是从一万多张中轴线老照片中精选出来的，根据展览展示了中轴线上重点文物古迹的图片，包括永定门、正阳门、国粮坛、太庙、景山等。公园、天坛、钟鼓楼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盖伊说：“我策划这个展览的目的是向参观者展示原版版画。由于展览不需要太豪华或太吸引人，所以我们的展示可能显得有些简单，只有白色的墙壁和相对较少的照片。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中山公园是1924年6月，北京光社在来金玉馆举办了中国第一次摄影展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该社创始人之一陈万里展示了更多他的作品超过60件。展览结束后，他挑选了其中的12幅作品制作成个人相册。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;古色古香&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了举办摄影展，中山公园也是家前往土地粮坛，这是中轴线上15处历史遗址之一，被认为是世界上最古老、存续时间最长的城市轴线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盖说，建设的基础该轴线可以追溯到周朝（约公元前 11 世纪 – 公元前 256 年）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《周礼·诸艺经》记载了中国古代建都的规定，指出这样的城市布局应以祠堂在中轴线左侧、祭坛在右侧为原则。书中还提到，两侧的布局和城市功能的延伸都与中轴线有关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7.8公里的中轴线，是元朝开国元勋忽必烈（1271年）最初勾画的。 -1368），在明朝（1368-1644）和清朝（1644-1911）期间得到进一步发展和完善。盖说，皇宫、寺庙、祭坛、市井的位置安排很巧妙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中轴线是老北京最具代表性、最重要的部分，是古城空间格局的核心。 ， 他加了。术语“空间图案”是指空间图案。指物体的感知结构、位置或顺序，包括物体之间的空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 梁思成，著名纪念碑建筑师，中华民国国徽的设计者。将该轴线描述为世界上最大的南北中轴线。他写道，它横跨整个城市，长约8公里，北京独特而雄伟的秩序源于中轴线的建立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盖说：“因为中轴线是不是一个固定的实体，它是“活的”。包括我自己在内的许多专家曾经将其视为纯粹的建筑遗迹的集合，每一件遗迹都被视为一个历史故事的片段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “但这些历史片段是静态的。它们的意义不在于建筑本身，而在于中轴线现在通过展览和各种其他活动进入了北京居民的生活。这样，这些历史遗迹就与人们的生活紧密地联系在一起了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 公园承担了保护轴线沿线大部分遗产地的作用。天坛、农神庙、太庙、故宫、景山等15处遗址均匀分布在中线两侧。自 1911 年辛亥革命（即孙中山发起的辛亥革命）以来，它们全部向公众开放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “由于这些网站很容易向公众开放，人们能够更好地理解历史、尊重历史，从而增强保护文物的意识。”盖说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 虽然遗产地的人类活动可能对木结构和一些石制文物构成安全挑战，但盖说，这些风险可以通过技术的使用来消除，并补充说，某些区域&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;立法保护&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多年来，北京市政府加强了保护措施，保护中轴线沿线文物，更好地传承历史文化价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年以来，市政府加大中轴线保护力度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去年1月25日，北京市人大常委会通过了《沿线文化遗产保护条例》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京市文物局副局长凌明表示，该条例在轴线上确定受保护的遗产地点，并计划保护它们。提出以保护优先为重点，促进中轴线文化遗产传承利用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 利用该条例组织指导中轴线文化遗产保护、传承与利用活动， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 立法委员、北京建筑大学教授秦红岭表示，中轴线文化遗产保护工作仍面临诸多挑战。例如，此类遗产的继承和利用需要充分利用，但保护仍缺乏坚实的协调机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 保护规则为历史遗产的保护和传承提供了强有力的法律保障。沿轴线文化传承，秦增。即使是在拥有重要历史建筑、城市管理设施和公共建筑的北京古城，游客也络绎不绝——尤其是在假期期间—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京市文化和旅游局的一家网站报道称，去年前六个月，9游客被列入不当行为黑名单，其中包括一名游客翻越景山公园围栏损坏花木的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 规定规定，此类违规行为不可原谅，任何对不可移动文物、对北京中轴线保护区内的古建筑、古树进行处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 违反规定造成公私财物损失的，依法处以罚款，并追究责任人的责任。 ”首都的13座明皇陵墓均受市政府规定保护。在中国，普遍认为地方立法比地方政府规定更有效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，去年5月通过的条例中提到，保护中轴线上的非物质文化遗产意味着需要保护中轴线上的非物质文化遗产。秦补充道，传统民俗不仅体现了北京市民对中轴线的集体记忆，也体现了首都当地人的民俗文化和中国传统建筑工艺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鼓励居住在中轴线保护区内的居民参加文化活动，保存北京历史文化记忆，促进北京历史文化与现代生活的融合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 秦说。旨在提高文化资源利用和传承的公众参与度。她补充道，《中轴线保护条例》章节标题中突出的“公众参与”一词，在以往的遗产保护相关立法中是很少见的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;古代智慧&lt; /b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 过去三个月，中山公园展览的参观人数很少，参观者很少关注精心布置的不同历史时期文化遗址的展示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 模型南北走向的中轴线和两侧的文化遗产位于展览的主区域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 黑白照片，展示在一侧110平方米的展览空间，在聚光灯的照射下，显得格外美观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 46岁的郭庆红是朝阳区京西书院的老师，上个月参观了展览，他说中轴线上的建筑模型给了她灵感。她计划在学校创建这样一个模型，让学生更多地了解中轴线的历史和沿线的文化遗产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在这座繁华的首都，古老的传统常常被掩盖。最新建筑设计中的现代结构。然而，古人的智慧也值得珍惜。让学生了解中轴线的历史及其相关遗产是重新激发对历史遗迹兴趣的一种方式，”郭补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 研究中心主任盖表示，中山公园的展览让参观者深入了解了北京古城的规划和建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这个独特的展览展览也为北京市民真实体验这座城市的历史精髓和中轴线沿线周边环境提供了难得的机会。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xinwen@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Enthralling ceremony opens innovative Games]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_001_6510aa7eed50d203d2c9ce2e.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/001/20230925_001_03_66104.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;女子组获奖者&amp;#周日，在浙江省杭州市第十九届亚运会颁奖典礼上，39;队的轻量级双人双桨赛艇队队员合影留念。中国组合邹嘉琪（左三）和邱秀萍（右三）在赛艇项目决赛中以7分6.78秒的成绩夺得本届奥运会首枚金牌。乌兹别克斯坦队和印度尼西亚队分别获得银牌和铜牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/001/20230925_001_03_197104.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第十九届亚运会周六在浙江省杭州市举行，盛大的开幕式让世界惊叹于中国丰富的文化遗产和卓越的科技的惊人结合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这场长达两个小时的秀以“潮涌亚洲”为主题，将裸眼3D技术、增强现实、人工智能与现实世界无缝融合，给运动员留下了深刻的印象。杭州奥体中心体育场的官员和 5 万名观众，还有全球数十亿观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 亚洲奥林匹克理事会代理主席拉贾·兰迪尔·辛格 (Raja Randhir Singh) 是最先赞扬中国的人之一以及杭州亚运会组委会的精彩演示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们要祝贺组委会……以及中国政府举办了精彩的开幕式，”辛格周日在新闻发布会上说道。 “这是一个盛大的仪式，我们参加过很多次。这是我们见过的最精彩、最美的开幕式之一。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当来自45个国家和地区的运动员在锣鼓声和悠扬的中国民乐中步入会场时，场内座无虚席。体育场内爆发出疯狂的庆祝动作，为每支球队加油助威。华夏文化与亚洲文化交相辉映，凸显了构建人类命运共同体的愿景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 辛格的女儿 Rajeshwari Kumari 正在代表印度参加飞碟射击比赛，她表示，运动员们将铭记这一点。杭州奥运会未来几年。 “他们对开幕式感到非常满意。完成得非常完美。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 圣火台的点亮，首次在国际体育赛事上展现了虚拟与现实的融合，无疑是开幕式最辉煌的时刻” p>; &lt;p>; 数字火炬手随后跑向体育场，与奥运游泳冠军、浙江人、最后的实体火炬手王顺一起跑向体育场点燃圣火台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据主办方介绍，开幕式仪式首次使用绿色、零碳的甲醇点燃圣火台，助力打造首届碳中和亚运会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 使用了9个IMAX大小的高清屏幕屏幕，帮助上演了一场令人眼花缭乱的数字烟花表演，组织者采用了这种方式作为传统烟花表演的环保替代品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据报道，这种氛围是庆祝和令人兴奋的，但以一种更可持续的方式进行致仪式的创意团队。盛典总导演兼总制片人沙晓兰表示，这次活动超出了团队自己的预期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们所做的比我们计划做的更多......技术使我们能够更具表现力。在任何此类规模的国际活动中，这可能是增强现实等技术最伟大的整合。” insidethegames.biz 首席高级记者杰夫·伯克利 (Geoff Berkeley) 表示，这次仪式非常精彩。 “这真是一场奇观，”他说。 “这是一场数字艺术展，绝对精彩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 对于马来西亚摄影师 Luqmanul Arif Abdul Karim 来说，这场仪式是一场视觉盛宴。 &amp;quot;真是太酷了，太棒了。我喜欢这个数字表演，非常具有未来感。我也很喜欢传统文化表演，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 约旦奥委会记者拉德·阿卜杜勒达耶姆表示，中国在开幕式上从来不会让人失望。 “中国每次都给我们带来新的东西。今晚更精彩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;sunxiaochen@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Farewell party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_001_6510aa81ed50d203d2c9ce2f.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/001/20230925_001_04_152104.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;大熊猫小七姬周六，在华盛顿特区史密森尼国家动物园举行的熊猫帕卢扎活动中，它在自己的围栏里打滚。季晓琪将与他的母亲梅香和父亲甜甜根据租赁协议的条款于 12 月返回中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Apartment owners cash in on upcoming holiday trips]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_001_6510aa83ed50d203d2c9ce30.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 国庆假期即将来临，那些临时计划出游的人正忙着预订热门旅游目的地的酒店房间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 为了从抢房热潮中获利，社交媒体用户在平台上大量提供假期期间的公寓出租，价格仅为酒店收费的一小部分，其中许多已售出&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 话题标签“国庆假期住在我家”社交媒体平台上的热门话题，居住在北京、上海、福建省厦门市和湖南省长沙市等热门旅游目的地的人们为旅行者提供额外的房间。周五开始为期八天的假期，恰逢中秋佳节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 专家表示，这种新颖的合租方式不仅能为房主带来额外收入，还能提高声誉。的城市。不过，他们也警告称，其中存在风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据中国铁路运营商中国国家铁路集团称，预计周三起铁路网将发送旅客约1.9亿人次截至 10 月 8 日，2022 年同期出行量为 7200 万人次，2019 年同期为 1.38 亿人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在流行的生活方式分享平台小红书上，有很多网友提出出租公寓的帖子假期期间。帖子通常包含公寓的图片和视频、可用时间段及其位置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与酒店不同，出租房屋的人不会在公寓有人入住时收取任何额外的清洁费用，无需签订合同或协议，也不一定需要承租人的身份证信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 厦门一名25岁的蔡姓男子将自己的公寓出租给了两名前往该地的女子。来自陕西省西安市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们将以每晚 200 元（27 美元）的价格租用 30 平方米的公寓 7 天，而酒店房间的价格很容易超过 500 元蔡说，那段时间一晚一晚人民币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是我第一次在假期出租我的公寓。”我想把它送给一个能保持干净的人，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 蔡和他的潜在客人交换了身份证照片，女人们付给了他200元押金。他已经给了他们进入他公寓的钥匙，并将在他父母的家里度过假期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我的公寓内没有贵重物品，经过对客人的全面检查，发现房间内没有贵重物品。”个人资料表明他们是正派的人，我决定尝试一下，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一位来自长沙的女士在广告中标明，她的公寓内有两间仅供女客人使用的空余房间，因为她将使用主卧室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她的两间客房收费为 188 元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，也有网友对这种私人公寓出租的趋势表示担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是太不安全了。如果人们在你家里安装了摄像头或者把家里弄得一团糟怎么办？”一位用户在评论寻求租户的帖子时问道。还有人说，“你就不怕别人打开你的电脑看里面有什么吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 河南泽金律师事务所律师傅健表示，业主与租客之间没有签订书面协议，身份证信息也没有登记，一旦发生纠纷，业主很难维权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 而且，如果有他表示，如果客人在入住期间发生盗窃或意外事故，业主或多或少都会承担责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他建议业主在出租前了解相关规则和规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zoushuo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - SPOTLIGHT SHINES ON BEIJING&#39;S CENTRAL AXIS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_002_6510aa83ed50d203d2c9ce31.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/002/20230925_002_01_33048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;居民在什刹海旁下棋北京中轴线沿线的湖泊。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/002/20230925_002_01_34048.png&quot; />;&lt; p>;游客在中山公园参观中轴线黑白老照片展。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09 -25/002/20230925_002_01_35048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;骑行者参观钟楼。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25 /002/20230925_002_01_36048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;正阳门吸引游客。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/ 002/20230925_002_01_37048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;鼓楼外观。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/ 002/20230925_002_01_30048.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 刚刚结束的北京中山公园展览中展出的50余张黑白老照片，让参观者感受到历史文化意义&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些展品还提醒人们需要保护这条路线上的文化遗产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些版画，从 1860 年代到20世纪40年代，是国内外摄影师和机构的作品，包括意大利裔英国摄影师费利斯·贝托（Felice Beato）、中国摄影师赖阿丰、苏黎世平版印刷公司和同盛照相馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盖建中，中山研究中心主任展览联合策展人帕克表示：“这些图像首次作为北京中轴线背景下的原始照片展出。它们无疑将为中国历史图像，特别是与北京城市历史相关的图像的研究和展示提供新的框架和参考体系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，这些照片的最大意义在于重点是它们描绘了中轴线沿线建筑的一些原始状况，这将有助于今后的修复和保护工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 版画是从一万多张中轴线老照片中精选出来的，根据展览展示了中轴线上重点文物古迹的图片，包括永定门、正阳门、国粮坛、太庙、景山等。公园、天坛、钟鼓楼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盖伊说：“我策划这个展览的目的是向参观者展示原版版画。 As there was no need for the exhibition to be overly luxurious or visually appealing, our display may have seemed a little basic, featuring only white walls and a relatively small number of photos.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhongshan Park was the venue for the first photographic exhibition in China, which was staged by Beijing&amp;#39;s Light Society in June 1924 at the Laijinyu Pavilion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Wanli, one of the society&amp;#39;s founders, displayed more than 60 of his works. After the exhibition, he selected 12 of these works for a personal photo album.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Ancient setting&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to hosting photographic exhibitions, Zhongshan Park is home to the Altar of Land and Grain, one of 15 historical sites along the Central Axis, which is believed to be the world&amp;#39;s oldest and longest-surviving urban axis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gai said the basis for constructing the axis can be traced to the Zhou Dynasty (c. 11th century &amp;mdash; 256 BC).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Book of Diverse Crafts from the Rites of Zhou, which documents regulations for building a national capital in ancient China, states that the layout of such a city should be based on the location of the ancestral temple to the left of the axis and the altar on the right. The book also mentions that the layout on both sides and the extension of urban functions all relate to the Central Axis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 7.8-kilometer Central Axis, outlined initially by Kublai Khan, founder of the Yuan Dynasty (1271-1368), was further developed and improved during the Ming (1368-1644) and Qing (1644-1911) dynasties. Gai said the location of imperial palaces, temples, altars and marketplaces was ingeniously arranged.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The axis, the most representative and important part of old Beijing, was the core of the ancient city&amp;#39;s spatial pattern, he added. The term &amp;quot;spatial pattern&amp;quot; refers to the perceptual structure, placement, or order of objects, including the space between them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liang Sicheng, a renowned monuments architect who designed the national emblem of the People&amp;#39;s Republic of China, once described the axis as the greatest north-south central axis in the world. He wrote that it stretches across the entire city, running for about 8 km, and that Beijing&amp;#39;s unique and majestic order originates from establishment of the axis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gai said: &amp;quot;Because the axis is not a fixed entity, it is &amp;#39;alive&amp;#39;. Many experts, including myself, once viewed it as a mere collection of architectural relics, with each relic seen as a fragment of a historical story.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;But these fragments of history are static. Their significance lies not in the buildings themselves, but in the fact that the axis now enters the lives of Beijing residents through exhibitions and various other activities. In this way, these historical relics have become closely intertwined with people&amp;#39;s lives.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Parks have taken on the role of preserving most of the heritage sites along the axis. The 15 such sites, evenly located on both sides of the center line, include the Temple of Heaven, the Temple of Agriculture, the Imperial Ancestral Temple, the Forbidden City and Jingshan Hill. They have all been open to the public since the Revolution of 1911, better known as the Xinhai Revolution, which was launched by Sun Yat-sen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;As these sites are easily accessible to the public, people can better understand history, respect it, and thus gain an increased awareness of the need to protect cultural relics,&amp;quot; Gai said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although human activities at the heritage sites may pose safety challenges to wooden structures and some relics made from stone, these risks can be eliminated by the use of technology, Gai said, adding that certain areas of the Forbidden City are currently off limits due to heritage protection work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Legislative protection&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Over the years, the Beijing municipal government has implemented enhanced protection measures to preserve cultural relics along the Central Axis, with the aim of better conveying their historical and cultural value.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 2011, the municipal government has strengthened efforts to protect the axis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On May 25 last year, the Standing Committee of Beijing Municipal People&amp;#39;s Congress passed a regulation on safeguarding cultural heritage along the route.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ling Ming, deputy director of the Beijing municipal cultural heritage bureau, said the regulation defines protected heritage locations on the axis, and plans to conserve them. It proposes promoting the inheritance and use of cultural heritage along the axis by giving priority to protection efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Using the regulation to organize and guide activities related to the protection, inheritance and use of cultural heritage on the axis can address the problems of safeguarding this heritage, Ling added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qin Hongling, a legislator and professor at Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture, said work to protect cultural heritage on the Central Axis still faces many challenges. For example, the inheritance and use of such heritage need to be taken full advantage of, but there is still no solid coordination mechanism for this protection.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The protection rules provide strong legal guarantees for safeguarding and inheriting historical and cultural heritage along the axis, Qin added. Even in the ancient city of Beijing, which boasted significant historical structures, urban management facilities and public buildings, crowds of tourists &amp;mdash; particularly during holidays &amp;mdash; while enjoying the beauty of this ancient architecture, seldom paid attention to the need to protect it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A website managed by the Beijing municipal bureau of culture and tourism reports that in the first six months of last year, nine tourists were added to a blacklist of inappropriate behavior, including one who climbed over fences to damage flowers and trees at Jingshan Park.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regulations state that such breaches are unforgivable, and that any damage to immovable cultural relics, and ancient buildings and trees in the protected area of the Beijing Central Axis should be punished.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Behavior causing loss of public or private property in violation of the regulations should be punished with a fine, and the offender held responsible, the regulations state.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qin said protection of the Central Axis is covered by local legislation approved by the Beijing Municipal People&amp;#39;s Congress, while the Great Wall, the Peking Man heritage site at Zhoukoudian, and the 13 Ming imperial tombs in the capital are protected by municipal government regulations. Local legislation is generally believed to be more effective than local government rules in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, the need to protect intangible cultural heritage on the Central Axis, as stated in the regulation passed in May last year, means that traditional folk customs not only embody the collective memory of the axis among Beijing citizens, but also reflect the folk culture of the capital&amp;#39;s natives and traditional Chinese architectural techniques, Qin added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The regulation also encourages residents living within the protected area of the axis to take part in cultural activities to preserve their memories of Beijing&amp;#39;s historical culture and promote the integration of such culture with modern life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qin said the regulation is aimed at improving public participation in the use and inheritance of cultural resources. The term &amp;quot;public participation&amp;quot;, which features prominently in a chapter title of the central axis protection regulation, has rarely been seen in previous legislation related to conserving heritage, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Ancient wisdom&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Zhongshan Park exhibition only attracted modest attendance over the past three months, with visitors paying little attention to the elegantly arranged displays of cultural sites from different historical periods.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Models of the Central Axis running south to north and of the cultural heritage sites on both sides of it were positioned in the main area of the exhibition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The black-and-white photos, which were displayed on a side wall of the 110-square-meter exhibition space, were aesthetically pleasing under the spotlights.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guo Qinghong, 46, a teacher at the Western Academy of Beijing in Chaoyang district, visited the exhibition last month and said the model of architecture along the Central Axis inspired her. She plans to create such a model at her school for students to learn more about the history of the axis and the cultural heritage situated along it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In this bustling capital city, ancient traditions are often overshadowed by modern structures in the latest architectural designs. However, the wisdom of ancient people also deserves to be treasured. Getting students to learn about the history of the Central Axis and its related heritage is one way of renewing interest in historical sites,&amp;quot; Guo added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gai, the research center director, said the exhibition at Zhongshan Park gave visitors an insight into the planning and construction of the ancient city of Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This unique exhibition also offered a rare opportunity for Beijing citizens to truly experience the historical essence of the city and the surrounding environment along the Central Axis,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xinwen@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Advancing new industrialization seen as key to high-quality growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_003_6510aa86ed50d203d2c9ce32.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s emphasis on advancing new industrialization is expected to provide a solid foundation for high-quality economic growth, improve the resilience and safety of its industrial and supply chains, and boost the country&amp;#39;s core competitiveness globally, experts and company executives said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They called for heightened efforts to enhance independent innovation capabilities and bolster the in-depth integration of cutting-edge digital technologies with the real economy, given that upgrading traditional industries has been high on China&amp;#39;s development agenda.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Their comments came as President Xi Jinping stressed the importance of high-quality development in promoting new industrialization to lay a strong material and technological foundation for Chinese modernization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi, who is also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks in a recent instruction on pushing forward new industrialization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Luo Zhongwei, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences&amp;#39; Institute of Industrial Economics, said, &amp;quot;The key to advancing new industrialization is to accelerate the transformation and upgrading of traditional industries through the adoption of new-generation information technologies, including artificial intelligence, 5G, big data and the internet of things.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More efforts should be made to cultivate strategic emerging industries, such as biotechnology, new energy, new materials, high-end equipment manufacturing and green industry, and foster new growth drivers amid downward economic pressure, Luo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He highlighted that China&amp;#39;s latest push to promote new industrialization and speed up the construction of a modern industrial system underpinned by the real economy will help make the country&amp;#39;s economy more resilient, strengthen its capacity to withstand external risks and shocks, and build the country into a manufacturing powerhouse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan Helin, co-director of the Digital Economy and Financial Innovation Research Center at Zhejiang University&amp;#39;s International Business School, said, &amp;quot;The purpose of pushing forward new industrialization is to ensure the long-term and sustained growth of the Chinese economy.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized the significance of developing the advanced manufacturing sector, which is playing an increasingly key role in bolstering technological innovation, safeguarding the stability of industrial and supply chains, and helping the country gain competitive advantages on the global stage. &amp;quot;It is very crucial to push the manufacturing sector toward higher-end, smarter and greener production,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan called for efforts to beef up research and development investments and tackle bottleneck issues in core technologies in fields such as basic materials and software, precision components and integrated circuits, in order to reinforce the country&amp;#39;s indigenous innovation capabilities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data from the National Bureau of Statistics showed that China&amp;#39;s industrial output &amp;mdash; a gauge of activities in the manufacturing, mining and utilities sectors &amp;mdash; grew by 4.5 percent in August from a year earlier after a 3.7 percent rise in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The high-end manufacturing sector continued to grow at a good clip, as the industrial output last month in integrated circuits and optoelectronic devices jumped 21.1 percent and 29.9 percent year-on-year, respectively.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Dongsheng, founder and chairman of Chinese consumer electronics company TCL Technology Group Corp, said that China&amp;#39;s resolve to advance new industrialization sets the direction for the country&amp;#39;s high-tech manufacturing industry, which has become an important driver of its high-quality development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The manufacturing sector serves as the foundation of the real economy. As key players for propelling technological innovation, enterprises should continue to unswervingly invest in high-tech manufacturing and expand their presence in the upstream industrial chains,&amp;quot; Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China has maintained its position as the world&amp;#39;s largest manufacturing nation for 13 straight years, accounting for nearly 30 percent of global manufacturing output in 2022, according to the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xin Yongfei, head of the Policy and Economic Research Institute at the China Academy of Information and Communications Technology, said that China&amp;#39;s manufacturing industry has maintained recovery momentum, but it is facing some challenges under a complicated international environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;A breakthrough method is to bolster the digital transformation of traditional industries by introducing new production factors, new productivity and new models, so as to change the original development path of manufacturing,&amp;quot; Xin said, adding that China should further enhance the proportion of manufacturing output in the country&amp;#39;s GDP.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Yunjie, chairman and CEO of Chinese home appliance manufacturer Haier Group, said that as the country makes efforts to build itself into a manufacturing powerhouse, more push is needed to promote innovative applications of the industrial internet and fully unleash the value of massive data resources, which is the key to advancing new industrialization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;fanfeifei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Virtual tour]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_003_6510aa89ed50d203d2c9ce33.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/003/20230925_003_02_42856.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A visitor tries interactive technology to view the Tianlongshan Grottoes of Taiyuan, Shanxi province, during an exhibition in Cairo, Egypt. The event, jointly sponsored by the Taiyuan Cultural Heritage Bureau and the China Cultural Center in Cairo, opened on Saturday with 70 experts in attendance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Policy to help promote cross-Strait relations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_003_6510aa8bed50d203d2c9ce34.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; The Communist Party of China is maintaining its strategic dominance in steering cross-Strait relations by rolling out a policy promoting integrated development of the two sides of the Taiwan Strait, thus laying the foundation for future reunification, experts said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will make Fujian province, which faces the island of Taiwan across the sea, a demonstration zone for the integrated development across the Taiwan Strait, according to a circular released earlier this month by the CPC Central Committee and the State Council.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The move is aimed at deepening cross-Strait integrated development and advancing the peaceful reunification of the motherland, with measures in place to offer Taiwan people the same treatment as local residents in Fujian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Zhenguang, a professor of Taiwan studies at Beijing Union University, said it is an important measure by the Party to push its initiatives for cross-Strait relations which have been tense due to the collusion of external and &amp;quot;pro-independence&amp;quot; forces in Taiwan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is necessary to deter &amp;quot;Taiwan independence&amp;quot; acts through activities such as military exercises in the Strait, while it is also crucial to promote cross-Strait exchanges, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Efforts to promote dialogues have been in place since this year, including the visit of former Taiwan leader Ma Ying-jeou to the mainland in April, and the recent document for integrated development aims to push cross-Strait relations in the right direction, Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The establishment of a model region for such integration also serves as an experiment and lays the foundation for the future reunification of the two sides, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xin Qiang, deputy director of the Center for American Studies at Fudan University, said the document shows that the Party continues to deepen the integrated development of the two sides of the Strait, which is a basic policy of the mainland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said it is the wrong belief of some overseas politicians that the policy possibly implies a significant change in Beijing&amp;#39;s Taiwan policy or a reduction in the deterrent force against &amp;quot;Taiwan independence&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the future interference of foreign forces in the Taiwan question, the mainland will maintain strategic initiative, promoting integration of the two sides and cracking down on provocative acts to safeguard the bottom line of the one-China principle, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Kun-yi, a professor of cross-Strait relations at Tamkang University in Taiwan, said that many polls he has done before showed that people from both sides welcome peaceful development and nobody wants war.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the Democratic Progressive Party authorities in Taiwan tended to discredit any peaceful initiatives from the mainland, people in Taiwan understand what is truly beneficial for them, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huang Ching-hsien, director of Taiwan Political Studies Center at Nankai University, said the measures make it more convenient for Taiwan compatriots to study, work and live in the mainland, which indeed puts a lot of pressure on the DPP, which is trying to discredit these efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Taiwan compatriots are well aware of the current development environment in Taiwan, including the high cost of living and difficulty in finding jobs, he said: &amp;quot;They will go to a place that can give them a better life.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyi1@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Furry pal for festive season]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_003_6510aa8eed50d203d2c9ce35.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-25/003/20230925_003_04_59856.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A boy poses for photos on Saturday with a rabbit during the &amp;quot;Meet the Bunnies under the Moon&amp;quot; event at the Lansdowne Centre in Richmond, British Columbia, Canada.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Xi: Sports can help promote world peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/25/content_003_6510aa8eed50d203d2c9ce36.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s tangible commitment to world peace, unity and prosperity were noted by global leaders as they endorsed Beijing&amp;#39;s latest diplomatic efforts led by President Xi Jinping amid the ongoing Hangzhou Asian Games.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 19th Asian Games, which opened on Saturday night, are the largest and highest-level comprehensive international sports event organized by China since the conclusion of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China in 2022.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As more than 12,000 athletes from 45 Asian countries and regions have gathered in scenic Hangzhou, the capital of East China&amp;#39;s Zhejiang province, so have a number of world leaders and representatives of international organizations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the welcoming banquet held on Saturday for the Games&amp;#39; opening, President Xi noted that the day was the autumn equinox, a day of harvest and reunion known as Qiufen on the Chinese lunar calendar.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;As a community with a shared future connected by mountains and rivers as well as cultural affinity, we should use sports to promote peace, pursue good neighborliness and mutual benefit, and reject Cold War mentality and bloc confrontation,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We should make Asia an anchor of world peace,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that the ongoing Games have set a record for the number of registered athletes and events, Xi said, &amp;quot;We should use sports to promote unity.&amp;quot; He called for efforts to &amp;quot;open up broader prospects for the Asian road toward common development, openness and integration&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We should use sports to promote inclusiveness, enhance confidence in our civilizations, pursue exchanges and mutual learning, and renew the glory of Asian civilizations,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scholars said that China&amp;#39;s hosting of the Asian Games aims to use sports &amp;quot;to advance peace, shore up unity and bolster inclusiveness&amp;quot;, and that the latest sports diplomacy led by Xi has been a success.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xiao Jianzhong, a professor at the School of Marxism of Zhejiang University of Technology, said, &amp;quot;For China, the Hangzhou Asian Games not only are a major sporting event, but also serve as an important event for diplomacy rolled out at home, as well as an important stage for exchange among various civilizations in Asia.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From Friday to Saturday in Hangzhou, Xi embarked on a number of bilateral meetings with the visiting Asian leaders of six nations and the heads of the Olympic Council of Asia and the International Olympic Committee.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The meetings with the prominent figures took place at a State guesthouse at West Lake, a scenic tourist destination in Hangzhou.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As this year marks the 10th anniversary of Xi&amp;#39;s proposing the concept of China seeking &amp;quot;amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness&amp;quot; with its neighbors, the president referred on Saturday to this principle during his talks with foreign leaders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking with Cambodian King Norodom Sihamoni, Xi said that China-Cambodia relations epitomize this principle, and he noted China&amp;#39;s commitment to good-neighborliness and partnership with its neighbors in its diplomacy in the region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The king hailed the two-way ironclad, brotherly relations, saying that his country stands ready to work with China on Belt and Road cooperation and build a Cambodia-China community with a shared future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; IOC President Thomas Bach told Xi on Friday, &amp;quot;I believe there will be successful and wonderful Asian Games that will promote the unity and friendship of Asia.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said the IOC is committed to safeguarding the nonpoliticization of sport, which is broadly supported by the world community, and it endorses China&amp;#39;s correct position on this.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Crown Prince of Kuwait Sheikh Mishal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah said President Xi&amp;#39;s proposals to build on the Belt and Road Initiative, Global Development Initiative, Global Security Initiative and Global Civilization Initiative are &amp;quot;based on the noble goals and tenets of promoting the peace and progress of mankind&amp;quot;, which Kuwait firmly supports and actively participates in.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Observers noted that Beijing&amp;#39;s consistent pursuit of world prosperity and peace could also be seen in two joint statements released following Xi&amp;#39;s talks with Syrian President Bashar al-Assad and with Timor-Leste&amp;#39;s Prime Minister Xanana Gusmao on Friday and Saturday, respectively.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the two statements, China announced the establishment of a strategic partnership with Syria and a comprehensive strategic partnership with Timor-Leste.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Co-building the Belt and Road as well as a community with a shared future for mankind, bolstering local livelihoods and &amp;quot;jointly advancing genuine multilateralism&amp;quot; in the international arena are among common points of consensus noted in the two statements.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ma Xiaolin, a professor and director of Zhejiang International Studies University&amp;#39;s Institute for Studies on the Mediterranean Rim, said China, as a major developing country and the world&amp;#39;s second-largest economy, &amp;quot;has never forgotten its social responsibility as a major country in Asia and the world&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hangzhou Asian Games are the city&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;biggest stage to showcase China&amp;#39;s image to the outside world and to promote face-to-face exchanges among people from all countries&amp;quot; since Hangzhou hosted the G20 Summit seven years ago, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yasir Habib Khan, a writer for The Nation, Pakistan&amp;#39;s leading newspaper, noted that cricket&amp;#39;s return to the Asian Games and its inclusion in the Hangzhou events &amp;quot;is a pivotal moment for the sport and for China&amp;#39;s diplomatic endeavors&amp;quot;, as teams of both Pakistan and India now may have the chance to embark on friendly rivalry at the games.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The inclusion of cricket in the Asian Games &amp;quot;showcases China&amp;#39;s commitment to using sports as a bridge for international engagement and cooperation&amp;quot;, he wrote.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Asian Games in Hangzhou serve as &amp;quot;testament to the power of sports to unite nations, break down barriers, and craft a shared narrative of friendship and cooperation on the global stage&amp;quot;, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:52:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>