<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - High-quality growth firmly on the agenda]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_001_6542bc74ed50d203d2ca1b91.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 政策会议强调金融业的战略重要性，中国将加大力度建设强大高效的金融业，为国家高质量发展和现代化建设提供动力专家周三表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周二闭幕的中央金融工作会议概述了增强国家金融竞争力的步骤，表明将加大力度优化金融监管，防范和化解金融危机。他们表示，化解风险，将提振市场信心，并补充说，更多注重细节的政策措施和工具值得等待。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央总书记、国家主席习近平中国国家主席和中央军委主席在为期两天的会议上发表了重要讲话，制定了当前和今后一个时期金融业的计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 高层金融政策制定者的聚会是在中国之后举行的今年早些时候重塑了其金融监管架构。当前，全球地缘政治不确定性不断加大，经济复苏乏力，加上政府债务问题和三年疫情过后房地产市场低迷，交织在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国必须建设足够强大、高效的经济体系”金融业，保障世界第二大经济体金融稳定和高质量发展。在某种程度上，这将决定中国经济未来几十年的前景和全球竞争力。”中国国际经济交流中心首席研究员张燕生表示，“金融业要改革开放，发挥市场在金融资源配置中的决定性作用，这一点至关重要”。推动金融业高质量发展，全面建成高质量经济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 金融是经济的“命脉”。会议领导表示，金融业要解决国民经济运行效率低、经济金融风险隐患、监管治理能力相对薄弱等问题，为经济社会发展提供优质服务。 /p>; &lt;p>; 会议要求，大力营造良好货币金融环境，加强对重大战略、重点领域、薄弱环节的优质金融服务。会议指出，要保持稳健的货币政策，更加注重跨周期、逆周期调节，丰富货币政策工具。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 金融研究所副所长陈道富国务院发展研究中心表示，这次会议发出了一个信号，即加快构建中国特色现代金融体系，推动市场化、法治化改革，党和政府将加快构建中国特色现代金融体系。 #39;的领导力也会受到强调。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他预计新的结构性货币工具可能会推出，让更多的金融资源流向科技创新、先进制造、绿色发展和小规模领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海金融学院副院长刘晓春指出，会议要求扎实发展科技金融、绿色金融、普惠金融、养老金融、数字金融。刘说，这些领域是中国追求经济高质量发展、转变新增长模式的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国人民银行、国家统计局的最新数据央行数据显示，截至9月底，金融机构人民币贷款余额为234.59万亿元人民币（合32.05万亿美元），同比增长10.9%。绿色发展、科创企业、普惠金融等领域贷款增长较快。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 评级机构惠誉博华企业执行董事常海忠表示，央行或将进一步鼓励商业银行和政策性银行会议还强调，要全面加强金融监管，有效防范和化解金融风险，包括“优化中央债务结构”。和地方政府” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国科学院金融研究所副所长张明中国社会科学院银行业研究中心表示，预计地方政府将避免发行大规模债务来为经济增长融资，资金规模大、周转慢、投资回报率低的公益项目融资将更加理性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：liuzhihua@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China launches 40th Antarctic research mission]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_001_6542bc77ed50d203d2ca1b92.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/001/20231102_001_02_126847.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;中国会员&amp;#39第40次南极科考队周三从上海起航。团队将历时5个月，在南极建设我国第五个极地科考站。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国第40次南极科考队周三起航，开启为期5个月的任务据自然资源部称，这将涉及在极地大陆建立一个新的研究站，并研究气候变化对该地区生态系统的影响等任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是该国的南极科考任务将首次由三艘船执行——两艘极地破冰船“雪龙”号、“雪龙2”号以及货船“天惠”号。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两艘破冰船载着来自国内80余家机构的460余名工作人员从上海母港起航，货船满载着施工物资。据中国极地南极局副局长龙伟介绍，新科考站的材料从中国东部江苏省张家港出发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该船队计划于 4 月份返回。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新设施位于罗斯海沿岸，将是继长城站之后中国第五个南极科考站1985年、1989年中山站、2009年昆仑站、2014年泰山站。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 建成后，该研究基地也将成为继长城站、中山站之后的第三个常年站，也是第一个面向太平洋的常年站。龙说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 极地党委书记孙波表示，罗斯海的表面常年大部分时间都处于冰冻状态，是地球上最后保存完好的海洋生态系统之一。中国研究院.这里是世界上大多数企鹅和多种鲸鱼的家园，是南极洲的第一个保护区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Long 说，新的研究站预计在夏季和夏季可容纳 80 人。冬季30号，将在大气环境、海洋基础环境、海洋生态系统等领域的多学科观测、监测和科研工作中发挥关键作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 科考队将在普里兹湾进行综合考察、宇航员海、罗斯海、阿蒙森海以及南极半岛周边海域，深入研究南极洲在全球气候变化中所扮演的角色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此次科学任务还包括国际合作、如与挪威、澳大利亚等国在南极科学前沿领域、恩德比陆地航测等领域开展合作研究，旨在加深对冰海基岩相互作用和冰盖稳定性的认识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 合作还将与美国、英国、澳大利亚、意大利、韩国、俄罗斯、智利等国家开展后勤保障。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Buying frenzy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_001_6542bc7aed50d203d2ca1b93.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/001/20231102_001_03_109847.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;某电子公司员工周三，江苏省淮安市，双十一购物节前夕，一家商业公司正在对包裹进行分类。请参阅第 13 页的故事&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - PROJECT WEANS VILLAGERS OFF ILLEGAL DRUG TRADE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_001_6542bc7ded50d203d2ca1b94.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/001/20231102_002_03_78872.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;左：一名犯人泰国清莱的 Doi Hang 惩教所学习和农业旅游中心为游客提供传统泰式按摩。中：中心的学员展示有机土壤。右：中心的犯人正在采集天然橡胶。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/001/20231102_002_03_44872.png&quot; />; &lt;p>;来自Huay San的Kanya Laomi因贩毒而入狱，目前从事Roi Jai Rak项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile /2023-11-02/001/20231102_002_03_61872.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一名囚犯在清莱 Doi Hang 中心学习园艺技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 泰国北部的 Huay San 小村庄曾经是外人禁区，政府官员和商人很少到访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于臭名昭著的金三角毒品产区（由泰国、老挝和缅甸部分地区组成）旁边，该村是非法毒品的重要储存和集散中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于清迈省的Huay San几乎家家户户都参与毒品交易，并拥有自己的贩毒网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 但今天的情况不同了，因为该村庄现已成为泰国禁毒运动的典范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这一重大转变归功于 Mae Fah 发起的一个项目Luang 基金会是一家私人非营利组织，成立的目的是改善贫困人口和被剥夺机会的人们的生活质量。该基金会管理着泰国和其他亚洲国家的众多项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Roi Jai Rak 项目由 Bajrakitiyabha Narendiradebyavati 公主于 2017 年发起，旨在通过创造一系列就业机会、减少家庭开支来保护当地社区免受毒品滥用，并采取可持续收入的长期战略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huay San 村民 Kanya Laomi 曾参与毒品交易，并在检查此类货物时染上毒瘾，他说：“几乎所有人在我的村庄，过去靠种植罂粟或贩卖毒品为生。这种生活方式让他们赚钱很快，但也有生命危险。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多年前，Kanya 出狱后加入了 Roi Jai Rak 项目，现在受雇为一名环卫工人。她有两个孩子，但从来没有告诉过他们她以前是如何谋生的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我记得当时每次看到警察我都会感到害怕。现在，我觉得我过着体面的生活。我可以告诉我的孩子我的工作，而且我不再害怕警察。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目的特点是有一个系统的计划，并通过多种方式来实施。充足的水资源、优质的土壤和森林，保证了当地人民的粮食供应和基础设施的发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;学习中心&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为该社区的主要职业，农业专家被邀请研究在项目区建立综合农业系统的可能性。示范区占地12公顷，作为社区成员的学习中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;示范区分为不同主题的区域，包括果树、农业自给自足、灌溉技术、甚至还有树苗苗圃。为农民组织考察旅行，激发他们的学习热情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 非法毒品问题对全球安全与稳定构成严重威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2008年至2017年，全球缉获安非他明联合国毒品和犯罪问题办公室的数据显示，冰毒从 8 吨增加到 70 吨。该办公室预测，到 2027 年，这一数字将增至 132 吨，在 20 年内增长了 16 倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 东南亚非法药物市场的年价值估计为 4,950 亿泰铢（1,365 万美元） ）。由于泰国占这一总数的 25% 以上，政府已拨款大量资金来打击非法毒品问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mae Fah Luang 基金会运营发展总裁 Narong Apichai 表示，除了犯罪和暴力，非法毒品问题被归咎于贫困，这就是为什么许多人参与此类活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “Roi Jai Rak 的字面意思是“携手并进，共同维护和保护” #39;.解决非法药物问题的有效方法是解决根本原因，即贫困和缺乏机会，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目已惠及近5000名居民，占地5939公顷，涉及泰北四个主要村庄——Huay San、North Meung Ngam、South Meung Ngam和Suk Reutai &amp;mdash ;和 20 个较小的村庄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “它提供了一个结构良好的发展模式，学习中心的人员帮助村民自助。有了这些可持续的措施，社区就不再需要依赖非法药物或其他非法活动。” Narong说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目还充当了当地农民与CP Starlanes Co购买水果的沟通桥梁。该公司通过提供设施来支持农民，并教授他们质量控制方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一位不愿透露姓名的 Somboon 村民曾参与贩毒，但现在拥有一个芒果园。 。 “过去，每个种植水果的家庭都与中间商打交道，很容易受到价格波动的影响，”他说。他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 通过该项目，Somboon 学会了种植优质水果用于出口，这增加了村民的收入。收入。而且，在大公司的支持下大规模种植水果，意味着村民不太可能再靠毒品谋生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们种植的芒果主要出口到日本和韩国。韩国对农药残留有非常严格的标准。由于我们收到了专业指导，我们的芒果价格预计将从每公斤 20 泰铢上涨到 60 泰铢，这非常令人鼓舞。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Roi Jai Rak项目的成功也引起了地理上靠近泰国的国家的关注。例如，今年4月，中国西南部的云南警察学院20余人组成的代表团前往泰国考察该项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国与缅甸、老挝接壤的几个城镇仅距金三角100公里，自20世纪90年代以来一直是中国毒品主要来源地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 近年来，中国与澜沧江-湄公河流域国家组织联合禁毒行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中、泰、缅、老等国还开展了替代种植方法、禁毒教育等广泛议题的交流研究，推动打击毒品交易区域合作.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 考察期间，中国代表团成员对项目区村庄发生的深远变化印象深刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;不同的选择&lt;/b>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 很难相信短短几年内就实现了如此深远的转变，当地人现在有如此多的选择来谋求可持续的生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国代表团成员表示，这不是一次性投资，而是教人们通过自己的努力去生活的过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 皇太后基金会的Narong，说该项目还有助于提高教育质量和保护环境。 “这些措施降低了社区重新从事非法毒品活动的风险，”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，该项目还通过向妇女群体传授使用缝纫机等额外技能来支持当地人的手工业。建立了社区市场以促进旅游业。游客可以在市场上购买农产品、传统服装和历史悠久的编织产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这个项目旨在让每个人共同努力，确保社区的和平、稳定和可持续发展。这些努力的目的是确保社区成员自豪和有尊严地守法生活。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;yangwanli@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Flying Tigers return to Chongqing, Guilin to rekindle friendship]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_001_6542bc80ed50d203d2ca1b95.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 周三，罗宾·奥尔尼 (Robin Olney) 在重庆史迪威博物馆墙上的飞虎队大合影中看到了她的父亲理查德 (Richard)，她非常激动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是我永远不会忘记的时刻。 （在重庆看到父亲的照片）心里暖暖的，难以言表。” 70多岁的老太太在父亲的照片前对媒体说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她没想到会在重庆看到父亲的照片。 “千里迢迢来到这里见到我的父亲，真是太特别了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她正在随一个主要由飞虎队退伍军人及其家人组成的代表团访问中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 1941年，一群美国志愿飞行员，后来被称为飞虎队，来到中国，与中国人民并肩作战，抗击入侵的日本军队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 36-前往重庆的代表团成员包括周一在北京迎来 103 岁生日的飞虎队老将哈里·莫耶 (Harry Moyer)、飞虎队老将梅尔·麦克穆伦 (Mel McMullen) 和中美航空遗产基金会主席杰弗里·格林 (Jeffrey Greene)。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 1942 年，飞虎队的# 39；总部从云南省昆明迁至重庆，以保卫遭受日军猛烈轰炸的中国战时首都的领空和安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在重庆史迪威博物馆，为纪念已故美国陆军将军约瑟夫·史迪威，这位在抗日战争后期（1931-45年）也与中国人民并肩作战的英雄，退伍军人为将军送上了鲜花。周一访问北京后，美国代表团参观了将军的雕像，参观了将军故居，并参观了二战期间美国对华空中支援图片展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;旋风般的中国之旅包括周二前往广西壮族自治区桂林，周四他们将前往昆明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 美国飞虎队司令克莱尔·李·陈纳德将军的历史文物，周二，向桂林羊塘机场的飞虎队遗址公园捐赠了这些遗产公园，这里曾经是飞虎队的指挥所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们必须牢记过去，迈向更美好的未来， ”飞虎队历史组织主席拉里·乔布 (Larry Jobe) 表示，他希望保留该志愿者团体的遗产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该组织捐赠了 80 件与飞虎队相关的物品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2015年，桂林市政府修建了该公园，以纪念该遗址的历史并促进中美友谊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “收集这一时期的文物是随着退伍军人的去世，日子一天比一天艰难。他们的纪念品和宝藏常常被年轻一代所忽视。像桂林公园这样的博物馆可以帮助保存这些记忆。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈纳德将军的女儿辛西娅·路易斯·陈纳德带来了她父亲在桂林使用过的望远镜，以及空军部队专用的绣旗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span >;联系作者：tanyingzi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - Inmates given welcome opportunities to prepare for life after their release]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_002_6542bc82ed50d203d2ca1b96.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 泰国北部惩教中心主任表示，泰国北部约 70% 的男性囚犯因毒品相关非法活动而入狱，而女性囚犯中这一比例更高.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “认识到女性囚犯的需求与男性囚犯不同，是促进女性在监禁期间的健康和生活质量的关键因素，”清迈女子惩教所所长 Acharee Srisunakrua 说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们希望当局对女性囚犯更加关注性别问题” ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2006 年，在 Bajrakitiyabha Narendiradebyavati 公主的支持下，泰国启动了一个项目，为该国的女囚犯提供道义支持、基本医疗保健和其他机会。&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>; 被称为 Kamlangjai，翻译为“启发”在泰语中，该项目旨在帮助泰国社会需要机会的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Acharee 表示，泰国各地的许多女子惩教机构已经启动了多项计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 清迈女子惩教所推出了许多成功的项目。其中包括一个改变生活的图书馆，有助于增强囚犯的生活质量。自我发展和快乐中心，提高囚犯的能力通过社会工作者或心理学家组织的团体活动和活动来促进心理健康。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “由于心理发展被认为是康复和重新融入社会的另一项重要功能，因此我们在机构内开展冥想练习等活动，” Acharee说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该机构还提供多种职业的职业培训，包括美发、传统泰式按摩、泰丝编织、手工艺和餐饮服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于泰国的职业培训中心清迈女子惩教所的成立是为了让囚犯有机会在狱中实习并学习语言技能，以在出狱前增强她们的信心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Acharee 表示，所有这些努力都显着减少了囚犯的工作量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在清莱中央监狱监管下的泰国北部 Doi Hang 惩教所，男性囚犯也为回到外面的世界生活做好准备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 该机构的学习和农业旅游中心为囚犯提供他们所需的当地技能，特别是有机农业、健康、手工艺和酒店业方面的技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pairat Khaminthakool，指挥官清莱中央监狱表示，“有时，被拘留者和缓刑犯等群体没有足够的机会重新融入主流社会，因此该中心成为帮助他们的平台。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心向公众开放，由 Doi Hang 惩教所的警官和表现良好的刑期即将结束的囚犯管理。它允许在押人员通过工作赚钱，为刑满释放后的资金存钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2012 年，我们设立了一个基金，为刑满释放人员提供资金，帮助他们重新回归社会，并为他们提供帮助。为希望进入职业机构或大学的前囚犯提供机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - Fact box]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_002_6542bc85ed50d203d2ca1b97.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中国是对毒品犯罪处罚最严厉的国家之一，对毒品非法行为采取零容忍态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与柬埔寨、老挝一起，缅甸、泰国、越南和联合国毒品和犯罪问题办公室、中国共同建立和完善了大湄公河次区域禁毒谅解备忘录机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 30年来，这一程序已成为本地区最重要的多边禁毒合作机制。过去五年，该地区超过20万公顷的土地种植了新作物，包括甘蔗、玉米、茶叶和热带水果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 约200家中国公司正在努力为农民提供金三角种植罂粟的替代品。这些企业已经做出了数百次这样的努力，主要在老挝和缅甸北部地区开展工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来源：中国外交部&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - PROJECT WEANS VILLAGERS OFF ILLEGAL DRUG TRADE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_002_6542bc88ed50d203d2ca1b98.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/002/20231102_002_03_78872.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;左：一名犯人泰国清莱的 Doi Hang 惩教所学习和农业旅游中心为游客提供传统泰式按摩。中：中心的学员展示有机土壤。右：中心的犯人正在采集天然橡胶。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/002/20231102_002_03_44872.png&quot; />; &lt;p>;来自Huay San的Kanya Laomi因贩毒而入狱，目前从事Roi Jai Rak项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile /2023-11-02/002/20231102_002_03_61872.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一名囚犯在清莱 Doi Hang 中心学习园艺技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 泰国北部的 Huay San 小村庄曾经是外人禁区，政府官员和商人很少到访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于臭名昭著的金三角毒品产区（由泰国、老挝和缅甸部分地区组成）旁边，该村是非法毒品的重要储存和集散中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于清迈省的Huay San几乎家家户户都参与毒品交易，并拥有自己的贩毒网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 但今天的情况不同了，因为该村庄现已成为泰国禁毒运动的典范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这一重大转变归功于 Mae Fah 发起的一个项目Luang 基金会是一家私人非营利组织，成立的目的是改善贫困人口和被剥夺机会的人们的生活质量。该基金会管理着泰国和其他亚洲国家的众多项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Roi Jai Rak 项目由 Bajrakitiyabha Narendiradebyavati 公主于 2017 年发起，旨在通过创造一系列就业机会、减少家庭开支来保护当地社区免受毒品滥用，并采取可持续收入的长期战略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huay San 村民 Kanya Laomi 曾参与毒品交易，并在检查此类货物时染上毒瘾，他说：“几乎所有人在我的村庄，过去靠种植罂粟或贩卖毒品为生。这种生活方式让他们赚钱很快，但也有生命危险。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多年前，Kanya 出狱后加入了 Roi Jai Rak 项目，现在受雇为一名环卫工人。她有两个孩子，但从来没有告诉过他们她以前是如何谋生的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我记得当时每次看到警察我都会感到害怕。现在，我觉得我过着体面的生活。我可以告诉我的孩子我的工作，而且我不再害怕警察。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目的特点是有一个系统的计划，并通过多种方式来实施。充足的水资源、优质的土壤和森林，保证了当地人民的粮食供应和基础设施的发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;学习中心&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为该社区的主要职业，农业专家被邀请研究在项目区建立综合农业系统的可能性。示范区占地12公顷，作为社区成员的学习中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;示范区分为不同主题的区域，包括果树、农业自给自足、灌溉技术、甚至还有树苗苗圃。为农民组织考察旅行，激发他们的学习热情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 非法毒品问题对全球安全与稳定构成严重威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2008年至2017年，全球缉获安非他明联合国毒品和犯罪问题办公室的数据显示，冰毒从 8 吨增加到 70 吨。该办公室预测，到 2027 年，这一数字将增至 132 吨，在 20 年内增长了 16 倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 东南亚非法药物市场的年价值估计为 4,950 亿泰铢（1,365 万美元） ）。由于泰国占这一总数的 25% 以上，政府已拨款大量资金来打击非法毒品问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mae Fah Luang 基金会运营发展总裁 Narong Apichai 表示，除了犯罪和暴力，非法毒品问题被归咎于贫困，这就是为什么许多人参与此类活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “Roi Jai Rak 的字面意思是“携手并进，共同维护和保护” #39；。解决非法药物问题的有效方法是解决根源问题，即贫困和缺乏机会。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目已惠及近5000名居民，占地5939公顷，涉及泰北四个主要村庄——Huay San、North Meung Ngam、South Meung Ngam和Suk Reutai &amp;mdash ;和 20 个较小的村庄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “它提供了一个结构良好的发展模式，学习中心的人员帮助村民自助。有了这些可持续的措施，社区就不再需要依赖非法药物或其他非法活动。” Narong said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The project also acts as a communications bridge between local farmers and CP Starlanes Co on the purchase of fruit. The company supports farmers by providing facilities and also teaches them quality control methods.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A Huay San villager, who wished to be identified only as Somboon, used to be involved with drug trafficking, but now owns a mango orchard. &amp;quot;In the past, each family that grew fruit dealt with middlemen, and were vulnerable to price fluctuations,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to the project, Somboon learned to grow high-quality fruit for export, which increased villagers&amp;#39; incomes. Moreover, planting fruit on a large scale with the support of a big company meant the villagers were less likely to return to drugs to earn a living.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The mangoes we grow are mainly exported to Japan and South Korea, which have very strict standards for pesticide residue. As a result of the professional guidance we receive, our mango prices are tipped to rise from 20 baht to 60 baht per kilogram, which is very encouraging,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Roi Jai Rak Project&amp;#39;s success has also attracted attention from countries close to Thailand geographically. For example, in April, a delegation of more than 20 members from Yunnan Police College in Southwest China traveled to Thailand to study the project.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Several towns and cities in China, which borders Myanmar and Laos, are only 100 kilometers from the Golden Triangle, which has been a major source of drugs in China since the 1990s.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In recent years, China has organized joint anti-drug operations with countries in the Lancang-Mekong River Basin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Exchanges and studies covering a wide range of topics, such as alternate planting methods and anti-drug education, have also been conducted between China, Thailand, Myanmar and Laos to improve regional cooperation in the fight against drug dealing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the study tour, members of the Chinese delegation were impressed by the far-reaching changes made to villages in the project area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Different options&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is hard to believe that such a far-reaching transformation has been achieved in just a few years, and that local people now have so many options to earn a sustainable living.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A member of the Chinese delegation said this is not a one-time investment, but a process of teaching people to live their lives as a result of their own efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Narong, from the Mae Fah Luang Foundation, said the project also helps develop educational quality and sustain the environment. &amp;quot;These measures reduce the risk of the community returning to illicit drug operations,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Moreover, the project supports the handicraft businesses of locals by teaching groups of women additional skills such as using sewing machines. A community market has been set up to promote tourism. Travelers can buy agricultural produce, traditional clothing and time-honored weaving products at the market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This project is designed for everyone to work together to ensure peace, stability and sustainability of the community. The aim of these efforts is to ensure that members of the community live law-abiding lives with pride and dignity,&amp;quot; Narong said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;yangwanli@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Researchers help UN map blackouts in Gaza]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_003_6542bc8bed50d203d2ca1b99.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/003/20231102_003_01_44495.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;High-resolution nighttime light images show the worsening power supply situation in the Gaza Strip on Oct 11(center) and Oct 12 (right), compared with Sept 14(left).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A team of Chinese researchers from Hubei province has helped the United Nations map the scale of power blackouts in the besieged Gaza Strip, using nighttime remote sensing technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The discoveries can be used to fine-tune global relief efforts aimed at easing a rapidly worsening humanitarian crisis in the coastal enclave, said Li Xi, the project&amp;#39;s lead scientist.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li, a professor at Wuhan University&amp;#39;s School of Remote Sensing and Information Engineering, now heads the State Key Laboratory of Information Engineering in Surveying, Mapping and Remote Sensing on campus.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Oct 8, a day after the conflict broke out between Palestine and Israel, Li reached out to Origin Space, a technology startup in Nanjing, Jiangsu province, for fresh satellite images of Gaza.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the early hours on Oct 11, a commercial satellite owned by the company captured a high-resolution nighttime light image of Gaza, the first of many to follow. Analyses of the images led to a grim conclusion: The power supply in Gaza had dwindled after Oct 7.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The changes in nighttime lights can reflect fluctuations in electricity supply, and they can be used to assess the impact of a range of disasters and conflicts,&amp;quot; Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the analysis, as of mid-October, vast swaths of Gaza were facing massive power outages. The power supply had declined by more than 90 percent in most areas compared with pre-conflict levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By Oct 21, more than 80 percent of buildings in Gaza had no power supply. Only hospitals and other healthcare facilities had access to electricity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the five governorates in the Gaza Strip &amp;mdash; North Gaza, Gaza City, Deir Al Balah, Khan Younis and Rafah, the southernmost Rafah region faced the least disruptions in power supply, the study said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The power supply had not been restored even in late October, it said. The findings were outlined in three reports drafted since early October by Li and two of his students, Cao Hanrui and Jia Minghui, in partnership with the United Nations Satellite Center, known as UNOSAT. First produced for the UN&amp;#39;s internal discussions, the reports were made public starting in mid-October.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li said his connections with UNOSAT go back a decade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2013, Li reached out to the organization through LinkedIn. The professor had advertised his latest research on the application of nighttime remote sensing technology in evaluating damage inflicted by disasters. A month later, he received a message from Lars Bromley, a chief analyst at UNOSAT, seeking cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As part of the long-running partnership, analyses of satellite images by Li and his colleagues have been used to plan a range of relief efforts, including in Iraq in 2018, in quake-ravaged Turkiye in February, and in Sudan in the aftermath of an armed conflict that broke out in April.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The places in the world that need help often happen to be the areas where nighttime remote sensing technology can be most useful,&amp;quot; Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at lilei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Filmmakers share insights into industry&#39;s development at festival]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_003_6542bc8eed50d203d2ca1b9a.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/003/20231102_003_02_119495.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; The 2023 China Golden Rooster and Hundred Flowers Film Festival, one of the country&amp;#39;s most prestigious movie industry events, kicked off on Wednesday in the coastal city of Xiamen, Fujian province, gathering many insiders and celebrities to discuss the prospects of the domestic film industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the aim of boosting the Chinese film industry, the festival is hosting a movie market section for the first time. A total of 126 film and television project agreements were signed on the first day, valued at a staggering 28.05 billion yuan ($3.83 billion).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A series of events were lined up on Wednesday, including a forum themed on exploring sustainable ways of industry development and the opening ceremony of an exhibition of new domestic releases.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The top attraction of the festival, the 36th China Golden Rooster Awards &amp;mdash; one of the country&amp;#39;s highest film honors &amp;mdash; will see a total of 20 awards, including those for best picture, best actor and best actress being presented on Saturday night.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wednesday&amp;#39;s forum witnessed heated discussions on how to better convey Chinese stories and enhance the influence of Chinese cinema overseas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Director Wuershan, an ethnic Mongolian whose film Creation of the Gods I: Kingdom of Storms has been nominated in nine categories for this year&amp;#39;s awards, said that China&amp;#39;s long history provides the perfect cultural soil for cinematic creation. Creation of the Gods I: Kingdom of Storms is the first installment of a planned trilogy adapted from a Ming Dynasty (1368-1644) novel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wuershan said there are many classic works in the country that have prevailed over centuries and still resonate emotionally with people, making them treasures to seek inspiration from.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guan Hu, director of the war epic The Eight Hundred, suggested that Chinese creators should not only focus on grand-scale narratives, but also pay attention to the ups and downs, and twists and turns, of ordinary individuals&amp;#39; fates in different eras that secure their respective chapters in Chinese history.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While discussing how Chinese filmmakers can learn from peers in top markets like Hollywood, Liu Xiaoshi, famed for directing the Chinese test pilot-themed blockbuster Born to Fly, said local talent should study their systematic and efficient procedures of filmmaking but should also persist with China&amp;#39;s own aesthetics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A-list actor Wu Jing, known for China&amp;#39;s two highest-grossing films &amp;mdash; The Battle at Lake Changjin and Wolf Warriors II &amp;mdash; said that he believes Chinese filmmakers still have a lot of work to do while endeavoring to cooperate with the world&amp;#39;s top filmmakers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu also recalled that he once had difficulties in line translation due to cultural differences when shooting the sci-fi blockbuster Meg 2: The Trench, jointly produced by China and the United States, further fueling his yearning to promote Chinese culture overseas and let more foreign audiences know about modern China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Xuejian, an award-winning actor known for the sci-fi epic The Wandering Earth II, said that he hopes Chinese filmmakers will take more inspiration from the country&amp;#39;s remarkable advances in science and technology, including space exploration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yin Hong, deputy chairman of the China Film Association, said that the domestic movie market has witnessed a rise in the diversity of genres this year, exemplified by the soaring popularity of various types of blockbusters during the Spring Festival holiday, the summer holiday and the National Day vacation, all lucrative box office seasons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking about a healthy box office collection of more than 49 billion yuan so far this year, Yin said the Chinese film industry has experienced a robust recovery, making it one of the fastest-recovering film markets in the world after the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yin added that he hopes that in the future, the export of Chinese films can be more specifically segmented, as Chinese traditional culture probably sells well in North America and Europe, while Africa may be more interested in stories set in modern China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xufan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Nanjing Massacre remembered]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/02/content_003_6542bc91ed50d203d2ca1b9b.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-02/003/20231102_003_03_62495.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A visitor attends an exhibition displaying historical records on the Nanjing Massacre in Budapest, Hungary, on Monday. The exhibition was organized by the Memorial Hall of the Victims in the Nanjing Massacre by Japanese Invaders. Approximately 300,000 Chinese civilians and unarmed soldiers were killed in a span of six weeks after Japanese troops captured the city of Nanjing in East China&amp;#39;s Jiangsu province on Dec 13, 1937.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:21:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>