<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Cyberspace pledges set to narrow divide]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_001_654d421eed50d203d2ca248b.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中国再次致力于推动构建网络空间命运共同体，将推动全球互联网领域更广泛的合作与交流，有利于缩小全球数字鸿沟，分析人士和业内人士表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席在2023年乌镇世界互联网大会开幕式视频致辞中强调，要继续推动构建网络空间命运共同体&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他呼吁国际社会深化数字领域国际交流与合作，扩大信息技术服务可及性，缩小数字鸿沟，更好保障民生&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平的讲话是在2015年乌镇会议上发表具有里程碑意义的讲话、提出北京的重大原则和主张的八年后发表的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中央财经大学中国互联网经济研究院数字经济学教授欧阳日辉表示，习近平的最新讲话展现了强烈的责任感&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，缩小数字鸿沟就是缩小国家、地区、行业、人群之间的差距。 “这还涉及缩小数字技术的获取、使用和知识方面的鸿沟。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;弥合数字鸿沟需要政府和平台公司更加积极主动的努力，以及不同领域的共同努力。他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据中国网络空间研究院发布的一份报告，中国一直积极参与建设全球互联网基础设施，以扩大互联网的覆盖范围，包括帮助各国建设光纤和网络。基站网络和改善全球数字连接网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，中国企业帮助南非开发了非洲第一个5G网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总部位于北京的智库中国与全球化中心表示，中国对网络空间共同未来的承诺符合相互尊重和主权的原则，“体现了完整性，因为它表现出了其所宣称的线上意图和线下地缘政治行为”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，中国在网络空间打造合作未来的承诺“具有重要意义，因为该国作为大国的双重角色”。人工智能的市场参与者和人工智能技术的领先创新者”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “其市场规模确保其人工智能使用引领趋势，而其在人工智能开发方面的快速进步使其成为关键架构师制定全球人工智能实施标准，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京上个月提出全球人工智能治理倡议，呼吁各国加强人工智能治理的信息交流和技术合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强发展中国家在全球人工智能治理中的代表性和发言权，确保各国在人工智能发展和治理中权利平等、机会平等、规则平等。一份官方文件解释了这一举措。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 意大利比萨圣安娜高等研究学院机器人学教授、下一代机器人公司副首席执行官安东尼奥·弗里索利 (Antonio Frisoli) 表示，他发现习近平的讲话“非常鼓舞人心”，因为它提出了促进网络空间和平发展的全球愿景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，习近平的愿景不是聚焦一国发展，而是聚焦国际共同发展。 “我从他的讲话中了解到，现阶段达成共同愿景的重要性显而易见。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习主席周三还呼吁各国尊重各自选择的发展道路和治理模式欧阳教授表示，中国的全球网络空间愿景与中国的全球网络空间愿景形成鲜明对比。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “随着数字技术重塑全球秩序，中国明确表示将寻求更多对话和交流，求同存异，构建共赢网络空间。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Fans at National Zoo in US bid farewell to three pandas]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_001_654d4221ed50d203d2ca248c.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_001_02_151.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;小七姬&lt;/ p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_001_02_198.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;天天&lt;/p>; &lt;img src= &quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_001_02_215.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;梅香&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家动物园的三只大熊猫在华盛顿特区——一对23年前来到美国的夫妇和他们3岁的儿子——周三前往中国，对于数以百万计的粉丝来说，这是一个激动人心的时刻，他们通常将熊作为参观动物园的原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周三中午，随着装有小七姬（“小小鸡”）的箱子在华盛顿杜勒斯国际机场即将被装上联邦快递的飞机时，小熊猫似乎正在向窗户挥舞着爪子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 三名动物园工作人员，包括大熊猫助理馆长劳里·汤普森（Laurie Thompson）和一名兽医主管官员与这三人一起旅行，并带来了大熊猫的丰富礼物。最喜欢的食物，包括：约 220 磅竹子、八磅食叶饼干、六磅苹果和一磅煮熟的南瓜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 经过 21 小时的“大熊猫快车”旅程后包括在阿拉斯加短暂加油，小齐吉和他的父母、25岁的梅香和26岁的甜甜已经抵达成都，受到中国保护研究中心饲养员的迎接大熊猫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 它们将被送往中国西南部四川省卧龙国家级自然保护区神树坪基地，在那里它们将被隔离约30天。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 对于来自美国首都及其他地区的动物园游客来说，告别熊猫并不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一位被称为 DC 熊猫女孩的动物园游客写道：“亲爱的美香、甜甜和肖齐霁——我已经害怕这篇文章有一段时间了，生活在否认之中，希望这一天永远不会到来。因为告别你是我做过的最艰难的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “你可能永远不知道，但这些年来你给了我这么多。即使在我最黑暗的时刻，你也给了我微笑、大笑和寻找快乐的理由。你以人类根本无法做到的方式提供了安慰和支持，”她的信还在继续。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 史密森尼国家动物园和保护生物学研究所所长布兰迪·史密斯 (Brandie Smith) 表示，当一家三口启程前往中国的新家时，他们留下了“巨大的” ”华盛顿的遗产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“世界各地的人们都追随这些大熊猫，分享我们的喜悦，并为我们的成功奠定基础，这令人兴奋又令人谦卑。”史密斯说。 “随着我们大熊猫计划的这一章的结束，我们仍然致力于保护这个物种，并期待与我们的中国同事继续合作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当被问及她将如何应对空荡荡的生活时，在动物园的大熊猫栖息地，史密斯说她会立即考虑未来，与同事一起把大熊猫带回来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于那些想知道何时会迎来新熊猫的游客，她会告诉他们什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她会告诉游客什么？ >; &lt;p>; “我会说他们必须像我一样等待，直到我们确切地知道该信息，”史密斯告诉《中国日报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们与中国的同事有着良好的关系，我们期待着共同努力将他们带回来，”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 每年有超过 200 万游客到动物园参观，大熊猫是他们的首选。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在 8 月份接受《中国日报》采访时，史密斯说，熊的消失可能意味着其他动物将得到“一点额外的”保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2000年，中美两国签署《大熊猫合作研究繁育协议》，第二对大熊猫“美香”和“甜甜”在动物园停留十年，从当年 12 月 6 日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 贷款协议续签两次，每次延长五年，直至 2020 年 12 月 7 日。然后又延长三年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 自2000年中国与史密森国家动物园开始合作以来，双方合作“密切而富有成效”中国驻美国大使馆公使徐学源表示，“我们这么多人一大早就聚集在这里，就是为了说告别大熊猫回归中国，不言而喻这些可爱动物的独特魅力。”徐在动物园的送行仪式上说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大熊猫属于中国。大熊猫也属于世界。中国将继续与包括美国在内的合作伙伴在濒危物种保护和研究以及生物多样性保护方面密切合作。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 动物园表示：“从出生、迈出第一步，到咀嚼竹子、在雪地里玩耍……大熊猫摄像机将世界各地的熊猫粉丝带入了美香、田的精彩时刻。”田和他们的幼崽，”动物园称，自推出以来，大熊猫摄像机的页面浏览量已超过 1 亿次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;huanxinzhao@chinadailyusa.com&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi greets Cambodia on 70th anniversary of independence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_001_654d4223ed50d203d2ca248d.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席周四向柬埔寨国王西哈莫尼致贺电，祝贺柬埔寨独立70周年，表示中方将一如既往坚定支持东南亚国家发展习近平表示，柬埔寨人民坚定不移走符合本国国情的发展道路，国家发展不断取得新成就.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年是中柬建交65周年和中柬友好年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平回顾今年我同西哈莫尼国王的会见习近平在北京、浙江杭州等地，擘画构建中柬命运共同体蓝图。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在贺电中表示，高度重视发展中柬关系&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 表示愿同西哈莫尼国王一道，加强两国关系战略引领，共同建设高质量、高水平、高标准的中柬共同体。新时代，命运共同体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天，中共中央总书记、国家主席习近平向柬埔寨人民主席洪森致贺电。 #39;s派对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mojingxi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Music for healing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_001_654d4226ed50d203d2ca248e.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_001_04_181.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;费城交响乐团成员周四，北京协和医院为患者和工作人员表演。这是乐团第13次访华，将在北京、上海、天津、苏州等城市演出。参见故事，第 3 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Scientists finds clues to crack mystery of long COVID]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_001_654d4229ed50d203d2ca248f.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 经过两年多对康复的 COVID-19 患者的跟踪，一组中国科学家发现了可以解释长期 COVID-19 机制的线索。他们发现了关键的生物标志物，可以帮助识别高危人群并开发治疗方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Long COVID-19 –其特征是，即使在初次感染三个月后，仍会出现挥之不去的症状，如疲劳、呼吸困难或认知功能障碍——世界卫生组织表示，估计约有 10% 至 20% 的感染者受到影响。这种疾病背后的生物学原理仍然是个谜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 对于《柳叶刀》旗下在线期刊 EBioMedicine 上周发表的研究，一组中国研究人员研究了 181 名从医院出院的 COVID-19 患者。 2020年1月至2020年5月期间，研究人员对181名年龄和性别相匹配的健康个体进行了调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 研究人员在接下来的两年内进行了3次随访，从案例研究中收集了血浆样本并进行了分析血液蛋白的结构和功能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们确定了感染后两年内 COVID-19 幸存者不同生物过程的四种恢复模式，从而收集了对长期 COVID 潜在机制的分子见解，”该研究由中日友好医院副院长、著名呼吸与危重症专家曹斌领衔的研究团队发布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 其他作者包括来自北京协和医院和北京协和医院的研究人员。湖北省武汉市的武汉金银潭医院登记了第一例国内病例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 分析结果进一步使研究人员发现了 23 个似乎与挥之不去的 COVID-19 症状有关的生物标志物。识别生物标志物对于识别感染该病的高风险人群以及评估实验性治疗的结果至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在长期新冠肺炎的诊断和治疗都具有挑战性的背景下，研究结果提出生物标志物可以进行更精确的干预，以减轻长期新冠病毒的负担。”该研究称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 5 月初，世界卫生组织宣布，尽管世界各地的科学家正在努力了解与挥之不去的症状相关的生物因素，但 COVID-19 大流行不再构成全球卫生紧急事件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国疾病预防控制中心原主任高福在 9 月份发表的一篇论文中表示，长期的 COVID-19 症状很常见，而且大部分患者大约需要一到两个月才能完全康复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京大学第一医院感染性疾病科主任王贵强在5月接受采访时表示，新冠病毒感染后症状持续存在，对于大多数人来说，19 感染通常会在一年内消散，无需对病情感到紧张。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在上一波疫情期间，我们没有看到大量长期感染 COVID-19 的患者。暴发。但对于重症高危老年人、患有严重慢性病或免疫功能低下的人群，应给予特别关注和照顾。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangxiaoyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - ANCIENT HERITAGE HIGHLIGHTS XINJIANG&#39;S KEY NATIONAL UNITY ROLE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_001_654d422ced50d203d2ca2490.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_002_01_41.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;汉代锦缎是陈列于新疆维吾尔自治区首府乌鲁木齐的新疆博物馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_002_01_24。 png&quot; />;&lt;p>;博物馆展示了该地区最新的考古发现。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/ 20231110_002_01_58.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;新疆文物考古研究所文物保护员在整理出土陶器。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/ resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_002_01_75.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;新疆奇台县唐朝墩遗址罗马浴场鸟瞰图。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_002_01_92.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;新疆轮台县佐尔库特遗址为汉代遗址提供了线索。&lt;/ p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/001/20231110_002_01_109.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;北亭遗址的大量发现新疆吉木萨尔县证明了它在古代丝绸之路上的重要地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在风沙和冰雪之下，在岁月的侵蚀下，涌现出无数的文物，诉说着一段绚丽多彩的往昔故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，新疆维吾尔自治区的考古发现，有助于揭示该地区文明的起源及其在形成统一国家中的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 这些发现范围广泛，从反映丝绸之路辉煌的纪念性城市到从天山到帕米尔高原的各个遗址。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 感谢国家考古研究院制作的新疆考古蓝图根据自治区文物局2018年发布的文件，五年来相关工作进展迅速，取得了重要突破。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新疆文物考古研究所副所长党志浩表示据了解，2018年以来，在国内九所院校的支持下，新疆各地已启动91个考古发掘项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些项目涉及从旧石器时代到清代的20多个遗址（ 1644-1911），近五年来，新疆有4处遗址入选中国年度十大考古新发现排行榜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们收获很多”来自对城市遗址、坟墓、信标、寺庙、洞穴、古代矿区和其他遗址的研究。这份珍贵的遗产让我们更加清晰地了解新疆的社会发展。”党说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些发现为遥远的过去生命提供了重要线索。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，阿勒泰地区吉木乃县的通天洞遗址，距今已有45000年的历史。 ，产生了新疆已知最早的人类聚居地。该遗址出土的石器也为石器时代和铁器时代与人类跨越欧亚草原的迁徙提供了重要证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在帕米尔高原边缘的喀什地区塔什库尔干塔吉克自治县，考古学家们发现了一个有8000年历史的生产石器的工厂——是当时中国最大的煤矿之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，伊犁哈萨克自治州尼勒克县的吉仁台沟口遗址提供了世界上最早使用煤炭的证据，距今约 3,000 至 3,600 年遗址中发现的建筑遗址和陶器揭示了该地区所谓的游牧经济是如何形成的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这些发现极大地加深了我们对新疆史前时代的了解，”党说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;统一性与多样性&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考古学还为中国古代中央王朝如何统治新疆地区、巩固民族团结、党补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在昌吉回族自治州吉木萨尔县，对唐代（618-907）北庭遗址的发掘继续为人们对这个贸易中心提供了新的认识。该遗址过去也被称为贝什八里，于 2014 年作为丝绸之路：长安天山走廊路线网的一部分被列入世界遗产名录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 郭武，中国社会科学院研究员主持发掘工作的考古研究所介绍说：“这是公元7世纪至14世纪天山北坡最大的古城。通过对城门、佛寺、街道、水道的发掘，我们逐步拼凑出北庭的布局，了解北庭在北疆非凡的政治地位。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐代时以这座城市为中心，有效治理北天山，确保丝绸之路的稳定和繁荣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们的新发现表明，中央王朝的治理体系被介绍到这座城市，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，2021年在北庭遗址核心区出土的陶片残片上有“北天寺”字样。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 研究结果表明，即使是北庭这样的边疆地区，在国家治理体系的延伸中也没有被忽视。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 从寺庙遗址来看，其建造方法和设计与中国的寺庙非常相似。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “出土遗址的宏伟壮观也符合历史事实，即唐朝统治者花费了大量的财富和精力来保卫这个通向中原的门户。”西，”郭说。 “该遗址还启发我们了解现代背景下中国共享社区的重要性。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在巴音郭楞蒙古自治州尉犁县的基亚克库都克烽火台遗址—— 2021年中国十大考古新发现之一——一组边境哨所产生了数百份文件和信件，涉及政治、军事、经济、文化、宗教和许多其他主题。这些发现进一步反映了唐朝对该地区的统治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 遗址中发现的唐朝士兵的手写笔记也记录了他们的个人生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新疆研究院首席考古学家胡兴军现场考古工作人员表示：“这些发现为我们了解唐朝如何管理边疆，以及当时中央政府如何保障丝绸之路沿线的交通提供了重要参考。由此填补了历史文献中的许多空白。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中央王朝对新疆的统治可以追溯到唐代之前，汉代（公元前 206 年至公元 24 年）设立西域都护府。 ）。然而，保护地的具体位置，学者们仍有待确定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管如此，近五年来，在巴音郭楞轮台县佐尔库特遗址，出土了宏伟的建筑遗址、高台、三座古建筑遗址。层层城基显示了汉代的核心地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新疆自古以来就被认为是多宗教并存的地方，考古学家也发现了更多的证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在奇台县发现的唐朝墩遗址和吐鲁番的西庞遗址都可以追溯到唐代至元代（1271-1368），可以说是这种文化交流的最好证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 景教两处遗址均出土了教堂遗址，以及丝绸之路沿线各种语言书写的手稿，包括中文、古维吾尔文和叙利亚文。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 景教在中国古代文献中被称为“景教”，是它的一个分支。基督教起源于今天的叙利亚，曾在中国流行。唐朝墩遗址还发现了佛寺遗址，甚至还发现了罗马式浴场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;全球关注&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新疆考古调查早在20世纪，无数海外探险家抵达该地区。这些出国考察引发了巨大争议，许多珍贵文物、文献和壁画随后流向海外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “然而，新疆古代文明研究却成为世界学术界的热门话题，”党说。 “时至今日，海外学者仍然渴望熟悉我们近年来发现的新材料，通过交流，考古学家可以孕育更多的想法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 20世纪90年代，海外考古学家，特别是来自日本的专家参加了新疆的重点联合发掘工作。和田地区民丰县尼雅遗址出土了一件著名的汉代锦缎，上面绣有“五星出现东天，造福中原”的字样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也引发了日本民众对丝绸之路的热捧。正在东京富士美术馆举办的“丝绸之路世界遗产展”展出了从27家中国机构借来的237件珍贵文物。新疆出土文物是十年来在海外举办的中国规模最大的丝绸之路主题展览的主要亮点之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 党说，尽管之前有过发现，但对新疆考古学家来说至关重要的是详细探索中国以外的更多遗址，从实物证据中更全面地了解文化传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周日，党和他在新疆文物考古研究所的同事们开始了对中国的首次正式访问哈萨克斯坦和乌兹别克斯坦在两国寻找共同发掘和研究的地点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “通过参与海外项目、获取第一手资料，我们可以更好地了解自己的研究，让更多人听到我们的声音遍及全球，”党说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;对公众的启示&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考古发现不仅启发学者解决学术难题，也帮助公众更好地了解自己的家园。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 由于新疆气候干燥，该地区出土的文物尽管年代久远，但在发现时通常状况良好。印有“东方天空出现五颗行星……”字样的锦缎、数千年历史的纺织品和木乃伊是新疆博物馆吸引游客的主要景点。此外，近年来的新发现也引起了新的兴趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 修缮一新的新疆博物馆于去年五月向游客开放，展示了该地区的许多新发现，包括来自吉仁泰的煤炭沟口遗址和唐代边塞出土文献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 博物馆馆长、考古学家于志勇表示：“展品生动、深入地向公众展示了历史。&lt;/p>; &lt;它们表明，各民族文化是中华文明不可分割的一部分，新疆历来是多民族杂居、不同宗教长期共存、多种文化交融的地方。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于新的考古展览，该博物馆自去年重新开放以来已接待了超过 170 万人次参观。在繁忙时期，它每天接待超过15,000人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在发掘过程中，我们经常会发现许多相同类型和设计的文物，例如陶器，”党说。 “这些文物除了为我们在研究所继续研究提供样本外，还可以为该地区越来越多的新建博物馆提供丰富的藏品。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 阿勒泰地区副研究员卓娅·巴吉特 (Zoya Baqit)参与通天洞遗址发掘工作的北疆博物馆表示：“我简直不敢相信我能为这样一个里程碑式的发现做出贡献。这让我为我的家乡感到自豪。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈萨克族卓亚从新疆大学历史系毕业，他认为考古学可以帮助当地人更好地了解他们的过去，并提供一个大局观。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，在通天洞遗址，考古学家发现了具有 5000 年历史的碳化小米和小麦谷物。小米被认为起源于中国北方——大约一万年前，在北京发现了世界上已知最古老的人类栽培的小米—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在阿勒泰地区发现小米和小麦，体现了我们的家乡在连接不同地区方面所发挥的关键作用。”卓娅说道。考古证据表明，新疆与中原平原在历史上有着密切的联系。我想在日常工作中向年轻游客解释这个有趣的故事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 考古还可以丰富公众的参观体验，北亭遗址是新疆第一座考古遗址。国家级考古遗址公园。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年公园共接待游客9万余人次。数字化和虚拟现实技术为他们提供了遗址及其建筑的全景，以及出土壁画和雕像的特写镜头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Saydin Abudula，吉姆萨尔博物馆副馆长，负责该遗址的保护者说，近年来的发掘帮助人们了解了这座城市的原始景观与今天干旱的沙漠景观不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是一个拥有网络的地方。水路。这些发掘不仅为我们保护土遗址提供了参考，也启发我们开发更多相关的主题参观项目。” ”赛丁说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐代鼎盛时期，北庭人口达4万多人，可见当时是一座大城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通过充分说明发掘出来的遗址，我们可以给游客讲述一个精彩的故事。对该遗址的更好认可将进一步促进当地文化产业和经济。” Saydin补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkaihao@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - ANCIENT HERITAGE HIGHLIGHTS XINJIANG&#39;S KEY NATIONAL UNITY ROLE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_002_654d422ced50d203d2ca2491.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/002/20231110_002_01_41.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;汉代锦缎是陈列于新疆维吾尔自治区首府乌鲁木齐的新疆博物馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/002/20231110_002_01_24。 png&quot; />;&lt;p>;The museum showcases recent archaeological findings in the region.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/002/ 20231110_002_01_58.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A cultural relics conservator at the Xinjiang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archaeology works on excavated pottery.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/ resfile/2023-11-10/002/20231110_002_01_75.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;An aerial view of a Roman-style bath at the Tangchaodun site in Qitai county, Xinjiang.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/002/20231110_002_01_92.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;The Zorkut site in Luntai county, Xinjiang, offers clues to ruins from the Han Dynasty.&lt;/ p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/002/20231110_002_01_109.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A wealth of discoveries made at the Beiting site in Jimsar county, Xinjiang, have provided evidence of its key status on the ancient Silk Road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Beneath sands and snow, and eroded by time, myriad cultural relics have emerged to tell a colorful story of the past in a vast area of northwestern China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Archaeological findings in the Xinjiang Uygur autonomous region in recent years have helped in the discovery of the origins of civilization in the area and the role played in forming a united nation.&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; The discoveries range from monumental cities that reflect the glory of the Silk Road to various sites scattered from the Tianshan Mountains to the Pamir Plateau.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to a blueprint on archaeology in Xinjiang produced by the National Cultural Heritage Administration and released by the regional government in 2018, related work has proceeded swiftly in the past five years, yielding key breakthroughs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dang Zhihao, deputy director of the Xinjiang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archaeology, said that with the support of nine institutes and universities elsewhere in China, 91 archaeological excavation programs have been launched throughout Xinjiang since 2018.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The programs involve more than 20 sites, ranging from the Paleolithic period to the Qing Dynasty ( 1644-1911), and in the past five years, four sites in Xinjiang have been included in China&amp;#39;s annual top 10 lists of new archaeological findings.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve gained much from the studies of city ruins, graves, beacons, temples, caves, ancient mining areas and other sites. This precious heritage gives us a clearer picture of Xinjiang&amp;#39;s social development,&amp;quot; Dang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some findings have produced vital clues to life in the distant past.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, the Tongtiandong cave site in Jeminay county, Altay prefecture, which is some 45,000 years old, yielded the earliest-known human settlement in Xinjiang. Stone tools excavated at the site also provided crucial evidence linking the Stone Age and Iron Age with human migration across the Eurasian grasslands.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Tashikurgan Tajik autonomous county, Kashgar prefecture, on the edge of the Pamir Plateau, archaeologists found an 8,000-year-old plant that produced stone tools &amp;mdash; one of the largest at that time in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meanwhile, the Jirentai Goukou site in Nilka county, Ili Kazak autonomous prefecture, offered proof of the world&amp;#39;s earliest use of coal some 3,000 to 3,600 years ago, while architectural ruins and pottery found at the site shed light on how a so-called nomad economy formed in the region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;These discoveries have significantly deepened our understanding of Xinjiang&amp;#39;s prehistoric era,&amp;quot; Dang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Unity and diversity&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Archaeology has also provided vital evidence of how central dynasties in ancient China governed the Xinjiang area, thus consolidating national unity, Dang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Jimsar county, Changji Hui autonomous prefecture, excavations at the Tang Dynasty (618-907) Beiting ruins continue to provide a new understanding of this trade hub. The ruins, also known in the past as Beshbaliq, were inscribed on the World Heritage List in 2014 as part of Silk Roads: the Routes Network of Chang&amp;#39;an-Tianshan Corridor.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guo Wu, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences&amp;#39; Institute of Archaeology, who led the excavations, said: &amp;quot;This was the largest ancient city on the northern slopes of the Tianshan Mountains from the 7th to 14th centuries. From excavations of the city gates, Buddhist temples, streets and waterways, we have gradually pieced together its layout to gain an understanding of Beiting&amp;#39;s extraordinary political status in northern Xinjiang.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Beiting Protectorate was established in the city during the Tang Dynasty as a center to effectively govern northern Tianshan to ensure stability and prosperity of the Silk Road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Our new findings show that the central dynasty&amp;#39;s governance system was introduced to the city,&amp;quot; Guo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, broken pieces of pottery bearing the characters bei tian si, which translates as &amp;quot;a temple to show mercy&amp;quot;, were unearthed in a core area of the Beiting ruins in 2021.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The findings show that even frontier areas such as Beiting were not neglected in extending the national system of governance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ruins of temples show that their construction methods and designs bear a close resemblance to those used for their counterparts on the plains of central China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The grandeur of the unearthed ruins also matches historical findings that Tang rulers spent a huge amount of their wealth and energy to safeguard this gateway leading to the west,&amp;quot; Guo said. &amp;quot;The site also inspires us to understand the importance of a shared community in China in a modern context.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the Kiyak Kuduk beacon towers site in Yuli county, Bayingol Mongolian autonomous prefecture &amp;mdash; one of China&amp;#39;s top 10 new archaeological findings in 2021 &amp;mdash; a group of frontier posts yielded hundreds of documents and letters on subjects ranging from politics, the military, and the economy, to culture, religion and many other themes. These findings further reflect the Tang rule in the region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Handwritten notes from Tang soldiers found at the site also document their personal lives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hu Xingjun, the leading archaeologist from the Xinjiang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archaeology working at the site, said: &amp;quot;The findings provide crucial references for us to discover how the Tang Dynasty managed its borderlands and how transportation along the Silk Road was ensured by the central government at the time. Many gaps in historical documents are thus filled.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Rule of Xinjiang by central dynasties dates back way beyond the Tang Dynasty, with the Protectorate of the Western Regions established during the Han Dynasty (206 BC to AD 24). However, scholars have still to locate the exact location of the protectorate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nonetheless, in the past five years, at the Zorkut site in Luntai county, Bayingol, unearthed ruins of grand architecture, high terraces, and three layers of city foundations indicate its core status during the Han Dynasty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xinjiang was long known as a place where different religions coexisted, and archaeologists have uncovered more evidence of this.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The newly discovered Tangchaodun site in Qitai county, and the Xipang site in Turpan, both of which date from the Tang Dynasty to the Yuan Dynasty (1271-1368), are arguably the best evidence of such cultural exchanges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nestorian Church ruins were excavated at both sites, along with manuscripts written in various languages along the Silk Road, including Chinese, ancient Uygur script and Syriac.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Known as jingjiao in ancient Chinese documents, the Nestorian Church, a branch of Christianity that originated in present-day Syria, was once popular in China. Ruins of a Buddhist temple and even a Roman-style bath were also found at the Tangchaodun site.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Global attention&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Archaeological investigations began in Xinjiang early in the 20th century, when numerous overseas explorers arrived in the region. These foreign expeditions triggered huge controversy, as many precious artifacts, documents and murals subsequently ended up overseas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;However, studies of ancient civilizations in Xinjiang became a popular topic in academia worldwide,&amp;quot; Dang said. &amp;quot;Today, overseas scholars are still eager to familiarize themselves with the new material we have discovered in recent years, and through exchanges, archaeologists can nurture more ideas.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the 1990s, overseas archaeologists, especially those from Japan, took part in key joint excavations in Xinjiang. A renowned Han Dynasty brocade embroidered with words that translate as &amp;quot;the five planets appeared in the eastern sky, benefiting the central plains&amp;quot;, was found at the Niya site in Minfeng county, Hotan prefecture.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These excavations also triggered a fad for the Silk Road among the Japanese public. The Great Silk Road World Heritage Exhibition, which is ongoing at Tokyo Fuji Art Museum, features 237 precious artifacts on loan from 27 Chinese institutions. Relics unearthed in Xinjiang are one of the main highlights of this biggest Chinese exhibition themed on the Silk Road to be staged overseas for a decade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dang said that despite previous discoveries, it is crucial for archaeologists from Xinjiang to explore more sites outside China in detail to gain a bigger picture of cultural communications from physical evidence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Sunday, Dang and his colleagues at the Xinjiang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archaeology set off on their first official visits to Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan to look for sites for joint excavations and studies in the two countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;By joining overseas projects and obtaining materials firsthand, we can better understand our own studies and enable our voices to be heard more widely around the globe,&amp;quot; Dang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Inspiration for public&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Archaeological discoveries not only inspire scholars to solve academic puzzles, but they also help the public better know their homeland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to Xinjiang&amp;#39;s dry climate, relics unearthed in the region are usually in good condition when found, despite their age. The brocade bearing the words &amp;quot;five planets appeared in the eastern sky &amp;hellip;&amp;quot;, textiles and mummies thousands of years old are key attractions for visitors to the Xinjiang Museum in Urumqi, capital of the autonomous region. In addition, new findings in recent years have created fresh interest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The renovated Xinjiang Museum, which opened to visitors in May last year, has played host to many new findings in the region, including coal from the Jirentai Goukou site and documents unearthed from Tang Dynasty frontier posts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Zhiyong, director of the museum and also an archaeologist, said, &amp;quot;The exhibits vividly and comprehensibly illustrate history to the public.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;They show that the cultures of all ethnic groups are an inseparable part of Chinese civilization and that Xinjiang has always been a place where many ethnic groups live in a shared community, different religions have long coexisted, and various cultures join together.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to new archaeological exhibitions, the museum has received more than 1.7 million visits since its re-opening last year. In busy periods, it welcomes more than 15,000 people a day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;During an excavation, we often find many relics of the same type and design, such as pottery,&amp;quot; Dang said. &amp;quot;Apart from providing us with samples to continuously study at the institute, these relics can provide rich collections for the growing number of new museums across the region.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zoya Baqit, an associate research fellow at Altay Museum in northern Xinjiang, who joined the excavation at the Tongtiandong site, said: &amp;quot;I simply cannot believe that I can make a contribution to such a milestone discovery. It makes me feel proud of my hometown.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Graduating from Xinjiang University after studying history, Zoya, a member of the Kazakh ethnic group, feels that archaeology helps locals better understand their past and provides a big picture of how different cultures met with each other.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, at the Tongtiandong cave site, archaeologists found 5,000-year-old carbonized grains of millet and wheat. Millet was thought to originate from North China &amp;mdash; the world&amp;#39;s oldest-known human-cultivated millet grains were found in Beijing about 10,000 years ago &amp;mdash; while wheat was widely considered to be first grown in the Mesopotamia region in West Asia.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The discovery of millet and wheat in Altay reflects the pivotal role our hometown played in linking different regions,&amp;quot; Zoya said. &amp;quot;Archaeological evidence shows the close connections between Xinjiang and the plains of central China throughout history. I want to explain this interesting story to younger visitors in my daily work.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Archaeology can also enrich the public&amp;#39;s visiting experiences, with the Beiting site being home to Xinjiang&amp;#39;s first national-level archaeological ruins park.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The park has welcomed more than 90,000 visitors this year. Digitization and virtual reality technology provide them with a panoramic view of the site and its buildings, and close-ups of excavated murals and statues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Saydin Abudula, deputy director of the Jimsar Museum, who is in charge of conservation at the site, said excavations in recent years have helped people understand that the city&amp;#39;s original landscape was different from the arid desert scene of today.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This was a place with a network of waterways. The excavations not only provide reference points for us to preserve earthen ruins, they also inspire us to develop more related thematic visiting programs,&amp;quot; Saydin said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At its peak during the Tang Dynasty, Beiting was home to more than 40,000 residents, indicating that it was a big city at that time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;By fully explaining the excavated ruins, we can tell a splendid story to tourists. Better recognition of the site will further bolster the local cultural industry and economy,&amp;quot; Saydin added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkaihao@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - CPI dips in Oct amid ample food supply]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_003_654d422fed50d203d2ca2492.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s consumer prices registered negative growth for the second time this year in October, indicating that the recovery in demand is not yet solid and more macroeconomic policy support is likely, experts said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The country&amp;#39;s inflation may remain low before recovering in early 2024, creating favorable conditions for expanding next year&amp;#39;s fiscal deficit and launching more monetary accommodative measures such as cutting the reserve requirement ratio &amp;mdash; the proportion of money that lenders must keep as reserves &amp;mdash; and interest rates, they said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The consumer price index, a main gauge of inflation, dipped 0.2 percent year-on-year in October, the National Bureau of Statistics said on Thursday, versus a flat reading in September and marking the second such decline so far this year following a 0.3 percent drop in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dong Lijuan, an NBS statistician, attributed the decline to ample food supply thanks to good weather and falling consumer demand after the combined Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Food prices decreased 4 percent year-on-year in October as the slump in pork prices widened from 22 percent in September to 30.1 percent, which dragged the CPI down by 0.55 percentage points. The price growth in the services sector, including travel and airlines, decelerated to 1.1 percent from 1.2 percent a month earlier, the NBS said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Qing, chief macroeconomic analyst at Golden Credit Rating International, said the direct reason for the CPI growth turning negative again is falling food prices.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;However, the continued sluggish prices of various goods and services other than food are the fundamental reason for the recent low price level. Behind this is the fact that consumer demand remains relatively weak, and the foundation for economic recovery needs to be further strengthened,&amp;quot; Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The growth in core CPI &amp;mdash; which excludes volatile food and energy prices and is deemed a better gauge of the supply-demand relationship in the economy &amp;mdash; came in at 0.6 percent year-on-year in October, down from 0.8 percent a month earlier, the NBS said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s producer price index, which gauges factory gate prices, dropped by 2.6 percent in October from a year ago, versus a 2.5 percent decrease in September and staying negative for the 13th consecutive month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wen Bin, chief economist at China Minsheng Bank, said that China&amp;#39;s inflation may remain subdued for a quarter before moderately recovering early next year, given that domestic demand improves slower than supply while external demand may remain sluggish.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pork prices continued to soften amid weaker-than-usual demand and abundant supply so far this month, indicating that November&amp;#39;s CPI may continue to register a low reading, Nomura analysts said in a research note.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Maohua, an analyst at China Everbright Bank, said a low price level is conducive to stabilizing the low-income population&amp;#39;s purchasing power but would dampen businesses&amp;#39; investment willingness if it lasts long.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China should and is likely to leverage the low inflation environment and provide continuous macroeconomic policy support, to facilitate the recovery in demand and thus economic growth, Zhou said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Specifically, analysts at United States investment manager Vanguard expect that the People&amp;#39;s Bank of China, the country&amp;#39;s central bank, may implement an RRR cut and slightly reduce interest rates in the coming quarters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan Gongsheng, governor of the PBOC, said on Wednesday that the central bank is set to further reduce financing costs and maintain ample liquidity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Yongding, a former member of the Monetary Policy Committee of the PBOC and an academic member of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said it would be sensible to set next year&amp;#39;s deficit-to-GDP ratio above 3 percent if necessary, adding that an expansionary fiscal policy is crucial to stabilize growth at a level in line with China&amp;#39;s potential growth rate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhoulanxv@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Travel products in spotlight]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_003_654d4232ed50d203d2ca2493.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/003/20231110_003_02_64.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A visitor examines exhibits at the China pavilion of the World Travel Market London in Britain on Monday. Themed &amp;quot;Nihao China&amp;quot;, the pavilion offered a rich variety of tourism resources and services, drawing worldwide travel service providers and travelers who are eager to visit, or revisit, China. The three-day event ended on Wednesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Quake relief]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_003_654d4234ed50d203d2ca2494.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-10/003/20231110_003_03_47.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Nepal&amp;#39;s Deputy Prime Minister and Home Minister Narayan Kaji Shrestha (third from left) and Chinese Ambassador to Nepal Chen Song (second from right) attend a ceremony marking the handover of Chinese emergency relief material in Pokhara, Nepal, on Wednesday. The aid for earthquake-hit areas in western Nepal include 600 cotton tents and 4,600 blankets worth 5 million yuan ($686,300).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China, Russia vow to deepen pragmatic military cooperation, safeguard stability]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/10/content_003_654d4237ed50d203d2ca2495.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China is willing to work with Russia to further deepen pragmatic cooperation between the two militaries and safeguard global and regional prosperity and stability, said General Zhang Youxia, vice-chairman of the Central Military Commission, while meeting on Wednesday in Moscow with Russian President Vladimir Putin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang said the friendship between China and Russia has developed continuously and strengthened with time. He added that this year, the two countries&amp;#39; heads of state had two successful meetings and reached a series of important consensuses, charting a new blueprint for China-Russia relations, according to the Ministry of National Defense.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The sound relationship between the two militaries serves as an important symbol of the high level and particularity of China-Russia relations, Zhang said, noting that in recent years, the development of China-Russia military ties has maintained strong momentum, with diversified highlights of cooperation in various fields.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang said that China is willing to work together with Russia to implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, further deepen pragmatic military cooperation, and jointly safeguard the interests of both countries as well as global and regional prosperity and stability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Putin said that the friendly relations between Russia and China are conducive to maintaining global and regional peace and stability. He emphasized that the relations are completely different from the kinds of alliance seen during the Cold War.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Russian president said that in recent years, the economic and trade relationship between the two countries has developed rapidly, and the two countries have maintained close coordination on international multilateral platforms such as the United Nations, the Shanghai Cooperation Organization and BRICS.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that cooperation between the two militaries in various fields has developed with a sound momentum and achieved fruitful results, playing an important role in safeguarding the strategic security of the two countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Putin emphasized that Russia is willing to strengthen strategic communication with China, upgrade the level of practical cooperation and continuously push forward the in-depth development of bilateral relations between the two countries and two militaries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Wednesday morning, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu held a welcoming ceremony for Zhang and had official talks with him.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This year, President Xi Jinping has had two meetings with President Putin &amp;mdash; one during Xi&amp;#39;s state visit to Moscow in March, and the other in Beijing in October, when Putin was attending the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During his three-day state visit to Russia, Xi said that consolidating and developing long-term good-neighborly and friendly relations with Russia is China&amp;#39;s strategic choice and conforms to the prevailing trend of the times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding military cooperation, China and Russia plan to regularly organize joint maritime and air patrols, exercises and training, strengthen exchanges and cooperation between the two militaries, including those under existing bilateral mechanisms, and further deepen military mutual trust, according to the joint statement signed by the two presidents during Xi&amp;#39;s state visit in March.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang and Shoigu have met with each other twice this year, with their first meeting taking place in late October, when the Russian defense minister was attending the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum, a global security conference.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, Zhang told Shoigu that China is willing to work with Russia to handle various kinds of security threats and challenges, and safeguard the world&amp;#39;s strategic balance and stability, according to China&amp;#39;s Defense Ministry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jiangchenglong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>