<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi highlights advancement in education]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_001_65075d39ed50d203d2c9c758.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 随着尖端技术和人才的国际竞争日益加剧，特别是在一些国家/地区之间，竞争日益激烈。近年来，尽管中国领导人试图压制中国的发展，但中国领导层强调把国家建设成为教育强国，这反过来又有助于强国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席，习近平总书记高度重视国家教育、科学技术、人才队伍建设，指出教育强国是建设社会主义现代化强国的战略先导。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “建设教育强国，是实现科技自力更生、科技强国的重要支撑，是促进全体人民共同富裕的有效途径，是实现人类命运共同体的根本工程。”走中国现代化道路，全面推进中华民族伟大复兴” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 5月29日，中共中央总书记习近平在中共中央政治局集体学习会上发表重要讲话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 习近平在集体学习中的讲话发表在中共中央旗舰刊物《求是报》第十八期上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平关于教育的讲话当前，世界正在经历新一轮科技演进和产业变革。在此背景下，中国面临越来越多的地缘政治竞争挑战，以及以美国为首的西方国家打压、封锁中国经济技术进步的挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在全国巡视等多个场合，习近平在周五给东北大学师生的回信中强调，要坚持科技自立、科技自强，全面推进国家现代化建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周六，在辽宁省沉阳市庆祝建校100周年之际，习近平表示，希望学校立足国家战略需要，培养更多高层次人才，扩大优势学科领先优势，不断产出一流学科成果。高水平的科研成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在《求是》杂志周六发表的讲话中，习近平阐述了中国将如何成为教育领军者。 “只有基础教育健康发展，才能稳步推进教育强国、持续发展”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，高等教育是我国成为教育强国的关键。 “要优先建设世界一流大学和优势学科，加强基础学科、新兴学科、交叉学科发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “科技与工程教育应进一步推进。要加大自主培养我国拔尖创新人才的力度，为关键领域核心技术突破提供支撑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2012年党的十八大以来，党中央高度重视教育事业，事关国家前途、党的未来。中共中央、国务院印发《关于加快推进教育现代化、建设国家教育现代化的重要决策》。 2019年2月，教育部印发《规划纲要》，规划了到2035年基本实现社会主义现代化、教育强国的教育现代化发展蓝图。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 于永跃，武汉大学马克思主义学院教授表示，加快发展教育强国，必须着眼于国家现代化建设进程。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;“我们要统筹考虑世界大发展、大转型、大调整给国家教育现代化带来的挑战和机遇，对接国家科技强国战略培养新时代高素质劳动力，推动乡村振兴” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国已建成世界上最大规模的教育体系，教育现代化总体水平进入中等偏上水平国家行列。中国在全球教育指数中排名第23位，较2012年上升26位，进步最快。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Beijing, Washington hold talks to stabilize relations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_001_65075d3bed50d203d2c9c759.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 在周末中美多轮高层会谈中，北京要求华盛顿切实履行不支持“台独”的承诺。正确认识中国发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央政治局委员、中央外事工作委员会办公室主任王毅周六、周日在马耳他与美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文举行多轮会晤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 双方围绕稳定和改善中美关系进行了坦诚、实质性和建设性的战略沟通， ”外交部周日在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 声明称，王强调，台湾问题是“中美关系中最不可侵犯的红线”。他呼吁美方恪守中美三个具有里程碑意义的联合公报，履行不支持“台独”的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，这是符合历史逻辑的，“无法避免”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 会谈期间，双方同意就亚太、海洋事务和外交政策举行中美磋商，据外交部声明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 双方同意继续落实去年两国元首在印尼巴厘岛会晤时达成的重要共识，保持高层交往。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Old tea forests in Pu&#39;er win World Heritage Site title]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_001_65075d3eed50d203d2c9c75a.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_001_03_67296.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;景迈山上的一个村庄这张照片拍摄于8月3日，位于云南省普洱市。该地区以其古老的茶树和较早利用茶资源而闻名。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_001_03_84296.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;3月25日，春茶采收伊始，农民在景麦山采摘茶叶。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 周日，在沙特阿拉伯利雅得举行的联合国教科文组织世界遗产委员会第45届会议上，普洱景迈山老茶林文化景观被列入世界遗产名录。成为中国第57个列入世界遗产名录的世界遗产，也是第一个与茶有关的世界遗产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新命名的遗产地位于云南省普洱市澜沧拉祜族自治县，由五片规模较大、保存完好的老茶林组成，海拔1250米至1500米；三座防护屏障林；以及老茶林中的九个古村落，主要居住着布朗族、傣族。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 人文景观是布朗族先民共同创造的——公元10世纪移居景迈山，后来发现并驯化了野生茶树—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当地人民在长期实践的基础上，发展出了林下种植技术，即让小型且耐荫的灌木或乔木在傣族树冠下茁壮成长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当地人为茶树生长创造了理想的光照条件，同时通过保存完好的森林生态系统防止虫害，从而生产出优质的有机茶叶，不使用农药和化肥。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 在第 45 届会议上，联合国教科文组织世界遗产委员会指出，该地区“是林下茶叶种植传统的特殊见证”，这使得“不同土地利用的互补空间分布得以发展” ，提供生态系统和小气候，支持老茶林的种植和居住在这个有机进化的文化景观中的社区的福祉”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 委员会表示，文化景观是可持续发展的杰出范例。基于水平和垂直土地利用模式相结合的土地利用系统。 “这种土地利用系统允许在景迈山的山区环境中互补利用自然资源，是布朗族和傣族人民与充满挑战的环境中人类互动的一个特殊例子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li国家文物局局长群在利雅得承诺，中国将加大力度，更好地监管遗产地，应对气候变化挑战，引导当地社区参与保护项目，规范旅游业，确保持久、突出和普世价值&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们还将推动国际交流与合作，在世界遗产保护和管理方面承担更多责任。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京大学世界遗产研究中心主任陈耀华表示，在大规模梯田茶园发挥作用的背景下，景迈山的茶叶种植技术非常独特。过去12年来一直领导该遗址研究的陈说，它代表了能够激发当今世界可持续发展的生态伦理和智慧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据他的研究，山上约 10% 的茶树树龄至少有 100 年，最古老的茶树已有 300 多年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 90% 以上的茶树都来自种植茶叶。土著社区的收入，他们维持着古老的治理体系来保护该遗址。该制度包括与祖先信仰有关的传统节日和仪式，即神灵居住在茶林以及当地的动植物群中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，普洱当地政府和云南省有关部门针对景迈山文化景观保护出台了三项法律、七项规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 景迈山世界遗产核心区面积约72平方公里。缓冲区面积约120平方公里。 2012年，老茶林文化景观被列入中国申报世界遗产预备名单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkaihao@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China, ASEAN eye closer ties as expo, summit start]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_001_65075d41ed50d203d2c9c75b.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_001_04_111296.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;游客购买榴莲周六，马来西亚出席在广西壮族自治区南宁市举行的第二十届中国-东盟博览会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周日，李强总理重申北京致力于睦邻友好、真诚互利、睦邻友好的周边政策。中方愿以包容性的态度加强与东南亚国家联盟的关系，呼吁进一步密切中国与东盟十国的利益纽带。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国愿扩大进口独特、高品质产品李克强在第20届中国—东盟博览会和中国—东盟商务与投资峰会开幕式上致辞时表示，将积极推介东盟成员国优质产品，扩大中间品贸易规模。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周日至周二在广西壮族自治区南宁举办，来自40多个国家的近2000家企业齐聚一堂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “双方要实现更大发展，中国和东盟必须共同参与双方要本着互利互惠的原则开展合作，构建更加紧密的利益共享网络，将我们的合作提升到更高的水平。”李克强向东盟领导人和工商界代表表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2022年，中国与东盟贸易额达9753亿美元，同比增长11.2%，双方互利共赢。 2020年以来连续三年第一大贸易伙伴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李克强强调，要挖掘国际陆海贸易新通道潜力，不断增强区域互联互通，建设各类合作示范区，探索合作&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京将坚定不移支持以东盟为核心的区域合作框架，推动“一带一路”和“一带一路”建设更好对接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 目前，中国-东盟自贸区3.0版谈判进展顺利，中方愿加快谈判进程。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 李克强强调，2024年中国—东盟人文交流年是扩大文化、旅游、青年等领域合作、增进相互了解的重要契机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;柬埔寨首相洪马内在博览会开幕式上致辞时表示，北京将进一步推进制度性开放，在知识产权保护和促进公平竞争方面取得更大进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洪马内表示，东盟和中国可以“向世界展示加强多边合作的实实在在的好处，而不倾向于保护主义、单边主义或经济民族主义”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 洪马内表示，东盟和中国需要加强合作和相互依存” “通过进一步开放市场，提高互联互通、供应链弹性、供应链产能和贸易便利化”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这位上个月上任后首次访华的柬埔寨领导人表示： “我们需要共同努力，促进双向投资。另外，我们应该加强技术支持，特别是在符合市场要求和需求方面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 马来西亚总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣表示，马来西亚采用了西方和中国的技术，特别是华为的技术， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说马来西亚“没有受到威胁或压力，因为我们的工作是建立在数百年关系的信任和信心的基础上”做出的决定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 安瓦尔呼吁东盟和中国共同努力，关注地区和平与繁荣，促进双边和多边贸易关系。 “我乐观地认为，进博会将继续成为我们企业的催化剂，促进合作，拉动经济复苏。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国与东盟合作的强劲势头也提振了信心&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国通用技术（集团）控股有限公司总经理陆益民表示，李克强周日的讲话为中国与东盟“坚持”指明了方向“坚持开放包容，构建友好可持续伙伴关系，互利共赢”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陆总表示，公司将继续深化与东盟各国在绿色低碳发展方面的合作，循环经济、健康医疗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广西柳工机械国际业务中心高级总监李东春表示，进博会和峰会为公司提供了良好的国际交流和客户拓展平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; “过去二十年，我们在东盟10个成员国发展了当地合作伙伴。我们在东盟市场的表现越来越好。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - DALIAN OPENS ITS DOORS WIDER TO BUSKERS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_001_65075d43ed50d203d2c9c75c.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_002_01_25614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;乐队在室外表演辽宁省大连市的购物中心。今年夏天，市政府鼓励街头艺人为当地居民和游客提供优质的街头表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/ 001/20230918_002_01_42614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;大连广场民乐表演吸引大批观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_002_01_61614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;人体彩绘艺术家充当大连街头的小提琴手。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_002_01_59614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A今年夏天，街头艺人在大连拉二胡。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/001/20230918_002_01_62614 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;大连街头艺人演奏古琴。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09- 18/001/20230918_002_01_60614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;蒋欣睿在大连海滩表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上个月一个凉爽的夏日夜晚，街头艺人蒋欣睿在最受欢迎的歌曲之一中用吉他低声吟唱。辽宁省大连市的海滩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 路人被她的歌声吸引驻足观看，并随着音乐挥舞着手机上的手电筒。江演奏时，夕阳西下，微风吹过，海浪轻轻拍打着海岸线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这位 25 岁的女孩说，她并不是海滩上唯一的街头表演者，海滩上通常有几位这样的艺术家。每天都可以看到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年夏天，大连当局鼓励像姜这样的街头艺人为当地居民和游览这座中国最热闹的城市之一的游客提供高质量的街头表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月初，市文化和旅游局启动了一项项目，号召街头艺人到公共广场、海滩、公园、购物中心进行表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该局艺术处处长张宝勤表示，虽然我市街头艺人数量众多，但当局启动这样的项目，允许他们在特定地点表演，这还是第一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们希望通过邀请街头艺人的加入来丰富我们城市的文化活动，希望他们能为大连带来生机和活力。”张说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 要获得官方许可，街头艺人必须提交工作录像并参加才艺测试。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说测试很简单。旨在评估街头艺人的健康状况以及表演质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “至少一小时的街头艺人需要体力。我们也希望他们的表演足够好，能够吸引观众。”张补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目很快得到了大连街头艺人的热烈响应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 每周在街头街头表演两次的江先生申请了许可证，很快就获得了批准。 7月和上个月，她每个周末都会在指定地点唱歌、弹吉他，包括繁忙的购物中心外、大量游客经常光顾的海滩、以及遍布城市的广场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她她在高中时开始街头表演，从街头乐队的表演中汲取灵感。江说，第一次街头表演时，她浑身发抖，因为太紧张了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 现在，她是一名经验丰富的街头艺人，当她在街头唱歌时，她会在面前放置两个条形码，供观众扫描。一个是捐款，另一个是让人们可以在直播中观看她的表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;在线观众&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每次江泽民在公共场所街头表演时，她直播自己的表演，通常会吸引数百名观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除了每周两次户外演唱外，她几乎每天都在网上表演。蒋说，她喜欢街头表演，因为她觉得这就像在一场小型音乐会上表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们喜欢在完成工作后停下来看我表演。这些对我来说都是美好的时刻。有时，他们会拿着手电筒挥舞手机，跟我一起哼哼。我仔细观察他们，看看他们对我的音乐有何反应。这些甜蜜的时刻鼓励我继续街头表演。”江说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她在网上拥有大约 70,000 名粉丝，每月收入从 30,000 元到 80,000 元（（4,113 美元到 10,976 美元）不等，大部分来自在线捐款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 江写下了她的许多内容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她为在夏天去世的爷爷写了一首脍炙人口的歌曲《大连的夏天》，歌曲中包含了她生活的这座城市的很多特色。和他住在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在我唱这首歌之前，我向那些在网上观看我的人以及来这座城市的游客介绍这座城市，”江说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大连因其海滩和宜人的气候而成为热门旅游目的地。市文化和旅游局发布的数据显示，今年夏天五一假期，超过370万人次涌入这座城市，而暑期期间，超过370万人次涌入这座城市。 ，它接待了数千万游客。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于当局对街头艺人的支持以及这座城市对游客的强烈吸引力，越来越多的音乐家和艺术家在街头表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 姜女士说，她的一个朋友是一位小提琴老师，今年夏天，她每天晚上在该市最繁忙的广场上卖艺一小时，工作一天后，收入约为1000元。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 街头涂鸦项目的组织者之一李晓旭表示，街头涂鸦、人体彩绘、穿着汉服演奏中国传统乐器的民间乐队等艺术形式， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她说，大连有很多街头艺人，其中一些是今年夏天向公众介绍的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李认为大连街头艺人的一部分将街头文化传播到城市的 100 多个广场，街头艺人经常选择在那里表演。这些广场很多都靠近大海或面向海滩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;放松的机会&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;盘石，当地的一支摇滚乐队，其七名成员都是兼职音乐家&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 组合歌手王贤瑞在一家模具厂技术部工作。乐队的另外两名成员也是工厂工人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “音乐为我们提供了摆脱日常工作的机会。我们喜欢玩它，尤其是当我们在街上街头表演时，” 41岁的王先生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 乐队成员晚上下班后都会练习。去年，当王先生看到街头艺人表演时，他觉得盘石也应该到街头表演。这个想法得到了乐队成员的热烈支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在广场表演与在现场演出或音乐节表演有很大不同。路人可能是第一次见到我们。在街上吸引他们并赢得他们的掌声更具挑战性。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 乐队的街头表演曲目旨在让人们在一天的工作后得到放松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王说，当他看到这些时，他感到很高兴陌生人——大多数是不熟悉摇滚乐的父母或祖父母——带着孩子或孙子在大连的广场散步时，欣赏乐队的音乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说，广场上卖渔具的小贩等了一个小时才看到一个晚上乐队表演。摊主第一次见到盘石，他一直坚持到演出结束，非常享受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王说：“城市里的生活压力很大。我们的街头表演让人们停下来休息一下。虽然演出很费时间和精力，但我们很享受。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于大连有很多公共广场，王补充道，乐队未来几年的目标是在所有广场上演出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 距离盘石表演的广场几公里远，金钟南与多元宇宙三重奏组一起演奏打击乐，吸引了一大群以年轻游客为主的观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多元宇宙有一个很大的金说，这些支持者中有很多人飞到大连观看乐队的街头表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管乐队成员收到了无数商业演出的邀请，但他们自2014年以来，街头表演一直持续至今。这些表演大多在夏季上演，此时大连迎来大量游客。乐队每周演出三场，每场演出持续一小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 金说，大连的街头艺人已经建立了在线聊天群，互相推荐演出地点。这些地点大多位于吸引大量游客的地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这座城市对街头艺人非常友好。只要我们不妨碍他人、不造成滋扰、不在小区里玩耍，就没有人要求我们离开。”金说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除了户外表演外，市政府还邀请街头艺人到室内表演，特别是在博物馆的公共区域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年夏天，一个由学生和老师组成的小型管弦乐队大连艺术学院街头艺人与弦乐四重奏在大连博物馆演奏室内乐。即使是上个月的一个下雨的下午，街头艺人也吸引了观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大连艺术学院校长助理李军表示，多年来，这座城市一直在培养市民的艺术素养。对各种音乐的欣赏。它努力“拉近距离” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “除了吸引当地人，大连还试图吸引年轻人的注意力，这就是该市推出街头表演项目的原因，”李军表示，东北城市都面临着年轻人南迁的问题，大连也不例外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “街头艺术、街头表演是吸引年轻人的好方法。”吸引年轻人来到这座城市，让他们热爱大连，并说服他们留下来。”李军说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大连并不是中国唯一推广街头艺术或鼓励街头艺人在地方当局指定区域表演的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海、首都杭州等城市浙江省政府已向街头艺人颁发许可证，在某些地点为观众提供高质量的表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 项目组织者李晓旭表示，她已经走访过中国许多有街头文化的城市。如何保证街头艺人有序表演、在哪里表演等问题，这些城市都还没有答案，但在大连，当局已经在这方面迈出了第一步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “我们组织者和表演者对大连街头文化的未来充满信心，”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：dengzhangyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - DALIAN OPENS ITS DOORS WIDER TO BUSKERS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_002_65075d43ed50d203d2c9c75d.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/002/20230918_002_01_25614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;乐队在室外表演辽宁省大连市的购物中心。今年夏天，市政府鼓励街头艺人为当地居民和游客提供优质的街头表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/ 002/20230918_002_01_42614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;大连广场民乐表演吸引大批观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/002/20230918_002_01_61614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;人体彩绘艺术家充当大连街头的小提琴手。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/002/20230918_002_01_59614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A今年夏天，街头艺人在大连拉二胡。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/002/20230918_002_01_62614 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;大连街头艺人演奏古琴。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09- 18/002/20230918_002_01_60614.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;蒋欣睿在大连海滩表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上个月一个凉爽的夏日夜晚，街头艺人蒋欣睿在最受欢迎的歌曲之一中用吉他低声吟唱。辽宁省大连市的海滩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 路人被她的歌声吸引驻足观看，并随着音乐挥舞着手机上的手电筒。江演奏时，夕阳西下，微风吹过，海浪轻轻拍打着海岸线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这位 25 岁的女孩说，她并不是海滩上唯一的街头表演者，海滩上通常有几位这样的艺术家。每天都可以看到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年夏天，大连当局鼓励像姜这样的街头艺人为当地居民和游览这座中国最热闹的城市之一的游客提供高质量的街头表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月初，市文化和旅游局启动了一项项目，号召街头艺人到公共广场、海滩、公园、购物中心进行表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该局艺术处处长张宝勤表示，虽然我市街头艺人数量众多，但当局启动这样的项目，允许他们在特定地点表演，这还是第一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们希望通过邀请街头艺人的加入来丰富我们城市的文化活动，希望他们能为大连带来生机和活力。”张说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 要获得官方许可，街头艺人必须提交工作录像并参加才艺测试。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说测试很简单。旨在评估街头艺人的健康状况以及表演质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “至少一小时的街头艺人需要体力。我们也希望他们的表演足够好，能够吸引观众。” Zhang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The project quickly received a warm response from buskers in Dalian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang, who busks on the streets twice a week, applied for a permit, which was quickly approved. In July and last month, she sang and played her guitar at designated locations every weekend, including outside a busy shopping center, on beaches frequented by large numbers of tourists, and in squares that dot the city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She started busking when she was in high school, drawing inspiration from a band performing on a street. Jiang said she trembled when she gave her first street performance, as she was so nervous.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Now an experienced busker, she places two barcodes in front of her for audiences to scan when she sings on streets. One is for donations, while the other enables people to watch her perform during a livestreaming session.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Online audiences&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Every time Jiang busks in public places, she livestreams her performances, which usually attract audiences of several hundred.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to singing outdoors twice a week, she performs online almost every day. Jiang said she enjoys busking, as she feels it is like performing in a small concert.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;People like to stop and watch me perform after they finish work. These are wonderful moments for me. Sometimes, they wave their phones with the torchlights on and hum along with me. I watch them closely to see how they react to my music. These sweet moments encourage me to continue busking,&amp;quot; Jiang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She has about 70,000 fans online and earns from 30,000 yuan to 80,000 yuan (($4,113 to $10,976) every month, mostly from online donations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang writes many of her songs, which convey her experiences and feelings.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She wrote the popular number Dalian&amp;#39;s Summer for her grandfather, who died in summertime. In the song, she includes many features of the city, where she lived with him.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Before I sing this song, I introduce the city to those watching me online, as well as tourists visiting the city,&amp;quot; Jiang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dalian is a popular destination for its beaches and pleasant weather. Data issued by the city&amp;#39;s culture and tourism bureau show that more than 3.7 million visitors flocked to the city during the five-day May Day holiday this summer, while during the summer, it accommodated tens of millions of tourists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to the authorities&amp;#39; support for buskers and the city&amp;#39;s strong appeal to tourists, musicians and artists are performing on its streets in increasing numbers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang said one of her friends, a violin teacher, busked for one hour every evening in the city&amp;#39;s busiest square this summer after a day&amp;#39;s work, earning about 1,000 yuan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Xiaoxu, one of the busking project&amp;#39;s organizers, said art forms such as street graffiti, body painting, folk bands playing traditional Chinese instruments while wearing hanfu (Chinese-style costumes in ancient times), and rock bands will feature on the streets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said Dalian has many buskers, some of whom were introduced to the public this summer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li attributes part of Dalian&amp;#39;s busking culture to the city&amp;#39;s 100-plus squares, where buskers often choose to perform. Many of these squares are near the sea or face beaches.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Chance to relax&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Panshi, a local rock band whose seven members are part-time musicians, has busked in Dalian&amp;#39;s squares since last year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Xianrui, the group&amp;#39;s singer, works in the technology department at a molding factory. Two of the band&amp;#39;s other members are also factory workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Music offers us a chance to get away from our daily work. We enjoy playing it, especially when we busk on the streets,&amp;quot; Wang, 41, said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The band members practice in the evenings after work. Last year, when Wang saw a busker perform, he thought that Panshi should also play on the streets. The idea received warm support from his band mates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Performing in squares is very different from playing at live house venues or music festivals. It may be the first time that passersby have seen us. Attracting them and winning their applause is much more challenging on the street,&amp;quot; Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The band&amp;#39;s street performance repertoire is aimed at getting people to relax after a day&amp;#39;s work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said he feels happy when he sees strangers &amp;mdash; mostly parents or grandparents who are unfamiliar with rock and roll &amp;mdash; enjoying the band&amp;#39;s music when they take a walk with their children or grandchildren in Dalian&amp;#39;s squares.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said a vendor selling fishing gear in a square waited for an hour to see the band perform one evening. It was the first time the vendor had seen Panshi, and he stayed to the end of the performance, which he thoroughly enjoyed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said: &amp;quot;Life in cities is stressful. Our busking allows people to stop and take a break. Although performing takes time and energy, we really enjoy it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As Dalian has many public squares, Wang added that the band&amp;#39;s goal in the next few years is to perform in all of them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Several kilometers away from the square where Panshi performed, Jin Zhongnan played percussion music with the trio Multiverse, watched by a large crowd that mainly comprised young tourists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Multiverse has a large number of fans in cities across China, and Jin said many of these supporters fly to Dalian to watch the band&amp;#39;s street performances.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the band members have received numerous invitations to perform commercially, they have continued to busk since 2014. Most of these performances are staged in summer, when Dalian welcomes large numbers of tourists. The band plays three times a week, with each performance lasting an hour.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin said buskers in Dalian have set up online chat groups to recommend performance sites for one another. Most of these sites are in areas that attract crowds of tourists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The city is really friendly to buskers. As long as we&amp;#39;re not obstructing people, not creating a nuisance, or playing in a residential community, no one asks us to leave,&amp;quot; Jin said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to outdoor performances, the city authorities have invited buskers to perform indoors, especially in public areas at museums.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This summer, a small orchestra comprising student and teacher buskers from Dalian Art College played chamber music with a string quartet at Dalian Museum. Even on a rainy afternoon last month, the buskers attracted an audience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jun, assistant to the Dalian Art College president, said that for years the city has cultivated citizens&amp;#39; appreciation for all kinds of music. It strives to &amp;quot;close the distance&amp;quot; with residents through culture, especially music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Apart from attracting locals, Dalian tries to draw young people&amp;#39;s attention, and that&amp;#39;s why the city launched the busking project,&amp;quot; Li Jun said, adding that cities in northeastern China face the problem of young people moving to those in the south of the country, and Dalian is no exception.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Street art and busking are good ways of attracting young people to the city, getting them to love Dalian, and persuading them to stay,&amp;quot; Li Jun said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dalian is not the only place in China to promote street art or encourage buskers to perform in areas designated by local authorities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cities such as Shanghai and Hangzhou, capital of Zhejiang province, have granted permits to buskers offering quality performances for audiences at certain locations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Xiaoxu, the project organizer, said she has visited many cities in China that have a busking culture. Questions such as how to ensure the buskers perform in an orderly manner, and where they should perform, have yet to be answered in these cities, but in Dalian, the authorities have taken the first step in this regard.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We organizers and the performers are confident about the future of Dalian&amp;#39;s busking culture,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at dengzhangyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China ready to bolster Belt and Road cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_003_65075d46ed50d203d2c9c75e.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/003/20230918_003_01_44263.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Premier Li Qiang addresses the opening ceremony of the 20th China-ASEAN Expo and the China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit on Sunday in Nanning, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Premier Li Qiang stressed China&amp;#39;s readiness to bolster Belt and Road cooperation and uphold the centrality of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations in regional affairs during separate meetings with leaders of Laos, Vietnam, Indonesia and Malaysia over the weekend.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li was in Nanning, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, to attend and address the opening ceremony of the 20th China-ASEAN Expo and the China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Nanning, he met with Lao Prime Minister Sonexay Siphandone, Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh and Indonesian Vice-President Ma&amp;#39;ruf Amin on Saturday. He met with Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the meeting with Sonexay, Li said that China is willing to continue with the high-quality construction of the Belt and Road with Laos and promote the continuous improvement of bilateral cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Both sides should further unleash the potential of the China-Laos Railway in spurring the development of both countries, Li said, adding that China supports Laos in enhancing its domestic development capabilities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The premier expressed China&amp;#39;s willingness to import more high-quality Lao products and strengthen people-to-people exchanges to promote mutual understanding and friendship between the two peoples.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He pledged support to Laos as the rotating chair of ASEAN next year, saying that Beijing stands ready to work with Laos to push forward with the building of a community with a shared future between China and ASEAN.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sonexay expressed appreciation for China&amp;#39;s support for the socioeconomic growth of Laos, saying that his country firmly adheres to the one-China principle and supports Beijing in safeguarding its core interests.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During talks with the Vietnamese prime minister, Li said that China stands ready to import more high-quality Vietnamese products that are suitable for the Chinese market, explore the upgrading of border ports and accelerate the construction of smart ports to facilitate trade between the two countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li called upon both sides to strengthen cooperation over rail connectivity and key minerals and jointly forge a system of mutually beneficial, stable and unimpeded industrial and supply chains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Both sides should adhere to dialogue and consultation to manage differences and work together firmly to uphold fairness and justice, Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pham Minh Chinh said that Vietnam and China are comrades and brothers, and the comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership between Hanoi and Beijing is Vietnam&amp;#39;s oldest, highest-level and most prioritized foreign relationship.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vietnam&amp;#39;s development of foreign relations will not harm the interests of third parties, and his country adheres to the one-China principle and supports China&amp;#39;s development, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While meeting with Indonesian Vice-President Ma&amp;#39;ruf Amin, Li said that Beijing and Jakarta must prioritize cooperation over initiatives including Regional Comprehensive Economic Corridor and the &amp;quot;Two Countries, Twin Parks&amp;quot;, and seek closer exchanges, and cooperation in education, culture, tourism, youth and sports.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is also willing to strengthen multilateral cooperation with Indonesia, jointly uphold the unity and centrality of ASEAN, and maintain the correct direction of East Asian cooperation, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Indonesian leader expressed readiness to deepen bilateral cooperation in economy, trade and people-to-people exchanges and enhance coordination and mutual support in regional and multilateral affairs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the talks with Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim on Sunday, Li highlighted China&amp;#39;s readiness to better align development strategies, continue with the high-quality building of Belt and Road and ensure the sound implementation of landmark cooperation projects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Games Village opens doors to first group of athletes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_003_65075d49ed50d203d2c9c75f.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/003/20230918_003_02_61263.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Indian athletes arrive at the Asian Games Village, which officially opened on Saturday morning in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 19th Asian Games Village officially opened on Saturday morning, welcoming the first batch of Chinese delegates to Hangzhou, the capital of East China&amp;#39;s Zhejiang province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking before the opening ceremony, Ng Ser Miang, vice-president of the International Olympic Committee, said the slogan of the Hangzhou Games, &amp;quot;Heart to Heart, @Future&amp;quot;, is a very appropriate one. He added that this is the place where at least 12,000 athletes from all over Asia will compete very seriously and keenly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to him, the upcoming Hangzhou Asian Games will further enhance global collaboration and cooperation. &amp;quot;This Games will provide a great opportunity, in this beautiful city of Hangzhou, for these athletes to share experiences, their culture and diversity, heart to heart and under the same roof,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We are standing here together in a truly magnificent Asian Games Village,&amp;quot; said Vinod Kumar Tiwari, acting director general of the Olympic Council of Asia, at the opening ceremony. &amp;quot;I regard this Asian Games Village as Olympic-standard and even more so,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tiwari said he has been visiting Hangzhou for the past eight years, and has been impressed by the plans and preparations made for the 19th Asian Games, especially the Games Village.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Made up of the Athletes&amp;#39; Village, the Technical Officials&amp;#39; Village and the Media Village, the Asian Games Village will welcome and play host to more than 20,000 people, providing accommodation, catering, transportation, cultural, technological, medical and commercial services, among others, for them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Such innovative concepts and arrangements have never before been seen in the history of the Asian Games or even the Olympic Games, Tiwari said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It highlights the unity and solidarity of the Olympic movement in Asia,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is sending 886 athletes to the Asian Games, which opens on Saturday. During the Games, the Chinese athletes, 437 women and 449 men, will compete in 407 events in 38 sports.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Yufei, Olympic badminton champion, said she is looking forward to her stay in the Asian Games Village.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Competing on home turf will be very exciting for me,&amp;quot; said Chen, who is a Hangzhou native. &amp;quot;It will mean pressure, but it will also serve as motivation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;My goal is to see the national flag raised and the national anthem played on the athletics field,&amp;quot; said Zhu Yaming, men&amp;#39;s Olympic triple jump medalist, who is aiming for a gold in the upcoming competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Apart from the Asian Games Village in Hangzhou, five sub-villages in the cities of Ningbo, Wenzhou, Jinhua, Tonglu county and Chun&amp;#39;an county also opened on the same day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Over 12,000 athletes from 45 Asian countries and regions will participate in the 19th Asian Games, the largest ever in the event&amp;#39;s history, in terms of the number of participants.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mazhenhuan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Forum strengthens ties amid global challenges]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_003_65075d4bed50d203d2c9c760.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; All countries should work to strengthen cooperation and multilateralism in order to jointly tackle global challenges including climate change and economic resilience, according to politicians and leading scholars participating in the Beijing Humboldt Forum 2023.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They highlighted the importance of fostering green, low-carbon and sustainable development, saying that will offer increasing opportunities and create new growth drivers for global development in the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wolfgang Schussel, former chancellor of Austria, commented that as an advocate of an open economy and multilateralism, China boasts great growth potential, especially in its domestic market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;There&amp;#39;s also enormous potential in new innovations, new ideas, new patents&amp;hellip; I&amp;#39;m absolutely looking forward to seeing China play an important role,&amp;quot; he told China Daily on the sidelines of the forum on Saturday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meanwhile, he noted that some politicians are looking to protect their own trade market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the forum, he said global trade has proved resilient in the face of multiple shocks amid rising protectionism and trade tensions, and the positive trend for international trade will continue in the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Citing a report by the International Monetary Fund, he said decoupling would be a terrible disaster and mistake, which would mean huge losses for the global economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the IMF report, titled &amp;quot;Confronting fragmentation where it matters most: Trade, debt, and climate action&amp;quot;, estimates of the longer-term cost of trade fragmentation varies from 0.2 percent of global output to almost 7 percent, which is roughly the combined annual output of Germany and Japan. If technological decoupling is added to the mix, some countries could see losses of up to 12 percent of GDP, the report said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking ahead, Schussel said countries need to work together and deepen cooperation in a wide range of fields including trade and green development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Zhongxiu, president of the University of International Business and Economics in Beijing, said China has been actively deepening its high-level opening-up while boosting self-reliance in some key fields.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said the push for decoupling and breaking chains violates economic laws and is an unsustainable choice, adding that China needs to continuously strengthen the resilience of the industrial and supply chains as well as seek &amp;quot;dual circulation&amp;quot; development to attract global suppliers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Against the background of major global challenges that threaten the world and humanity, Andreas Riecken, Austrian ambassador to China, said that it is no longer enough to just exchange strategies on green, low-carbon and sustainable development for the world&amp;#39;s economy. &amp;quot;Rather, we must act, cooperate multilaterally and across borders in a politically responsible manner.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Riecken, China and Austria are driving forces with regard to green technologies, paving the way for a cleaner and more eco-friendly future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is taking concrete steps to foster green and high-quality development as it embarks on a path to carbon peak and neutrality. The country has set an ambitious goal of peaking carbon dioxide emissions before 2030 and reaching carbon neutrality before 2060.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;ouyangshijia@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China, ASEAN eye closer ties as expo, summit start]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_003_65075d4bed50d203d2c9c761.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-18/003/20230918_001_04_111296.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Visitors shop for durians from Malaysia at the 20th China-ASEAN Expo in Nanning, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, on Saturday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Premier Li Qiang reaffirmed on Sunday Beijing&amp;#39;s commitment to a neighborhood policy of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness in bolstering ties with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, calling for a closer bond of interests between China and the 10-nation regional group.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The country stands ready to scale up the imports of unique and high-quality products from ASEAN member states and to expand the trading scale of intermediate goods, Li said while addressing the opening of the 20th China-ASEAN Expo and the China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The expo, which is being held in Nanning, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, from Sunday through Tuesday, has brought together nearly 2,000 businesses from over 40 countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For both sides to attain greater development, China and ASEAN must engage in cooperation based on the principles of mutual benefit and reciprocity, forge a tighter network of shared interests and elevate our cooperation to a higher level,&amp;quot; Li told ASEAN leaders and representatives from the business community.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Trade between China and ASEAN grew by 11.2 percent year-on-year to $975.3 billion in 2022, and the two sides have been each other&amp;#39;s largest trading partner for three consecutive years since 2020.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The premier highlighted the need to tap into the potential of new international land and sea trade routes, continuously enhance regional connectivity, establish various cooperation demonstration zones, and explore cooperation in emerging areas such as green and low-carbon initiatives as well as the digital economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Beijing will remain unwavering in its support for an ASEAN-centered regional cooperation framework and will enable a better alignment between the Belt and Road Initiative and the development strategies of ASEAN countries, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Negotiations on version 3.0 of the China-ASEAN Free Trade Area are now progressing smoothly, and China stands ready to expedite the talks, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li highlighted the China-ASEAN Year of People-to-People Exchanges in 2024 as a key opportunity to expand cooperation over culture, tourism and youth, and to enhance mutual understanding.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The premier also assured the business leaders that Beijing will forge ahead with institutional opening-up, make greater strides in intellectual rights protection and promote fair competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Addressing the opening ceremony of the expo, Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Manet said that ASEAN and China can &amp;quot;show the world examples of tangible benefits of strengthening multilateral cooperation without leaning toward protectionism, unilateralism or economic nationalism&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hun Manet said that ASEAN and China need to reinforce cooperation and interdependence &amp;quot;by further opening markets and improving connectivity, supply chain resilience, supply-link production capacity and trade facilitation&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Cambodian leader, who is making his first visit to China after taking office last month, said: &amp;quot;We need to work together to promote two-way investment. In addition, we should strengthen technical support, especially in complying with market requirements and demands.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said his country has adopted technologies from both the West and China, and Huawei in particular, in the deployment of 5G.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said Malaysia made the decisions &amp;quot;without being threatened or pressured because we work based on trust and confidence of centuries of relationships&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Anwar appealed for collective efforts of ASEAN and China to focus on regional peace and prosperity, and foster bilateral and multilateral trade relations. &amp;quot;I am optimistic that the expo will continue to serve as a catalyst for our businesses, fostering great collaboration and stimulating economic recovery.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The robust momentum of cooperation between China and ASEAN has also buoyed the confidence of business leaders at the Nanning expo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lu Yimin, general manager of China General Technology (Group) Holding, said that Li&amp;#39;s speech on Sunday showed the way for China and ASEAN &amp;quot;to adhere to openness and inclusiveness to build a friendly and sustainable partnership and uphold mutual benefit and win-win outcomes&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lu said his company will continue to deepen cooperation with ASEAN member states in green and low-carbon development, circular economy and healthcare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Dongchun, senior director of the international business center at Guangxi Liugong Machinery, said the expo and the summit have offered the company a good platform for international communication and client exploration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Over the past two decades, we have developed local partners across the 10 ASEAN member states. Our performance in the ASEAN markets is getting better and better,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Xi highlights advancement in education]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/18/content_003_65075d4bed50d203d2c9c762.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; As international competition increases for cutting-edge technologies and talented people, and particularly amid some countries&amp;#39; attempts in recent years to suppress China&amp;#39;s development, the Chinese leadership has emphasized building the country into a leader in education, which in turn will contribute to a stronger nation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping, who attaches great importance to the country&amp;#39;s progress in the sectors of education, science and technology, and human resources development, has pointed out that making the nation a leader in education will serve as a strategic precursor to building a great modern socialist country in all respects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Building a leading country in education is an important support for achieving greater self-reliance and strength in science and technology, an effective approach to promoting common prosperity for all, and a fundamental project to advance the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation on all fronts through a Chinese path to modernization,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi, who is also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, made the remarks at a group study session of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee on May 29.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The speech that Xi gave at the group study session was published on Saturday in the 18th issue of Qiushi Journal, the flagship magazine of the CPC Central Committee.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi&amp;#39;s remarks on education came as the world is undergoing a new round of technological evolution and industrial transformation. Against such a backdrop, China is facing increasing challenges arising from geopolitical competition and attempts by United States-led Western countries to suppress and blockade its economic and technological progress.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On many occasions, including his inspection tours nationwide, Xi has highlighted the importance of seeking scientific and technological independence and strength in advancing the nation&amp;#39;s modernization drive in all respects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a reply letter sent on Friday to the faculty and students at Northeastern University in Shenyang, Liaoning province, which celebrated its 100th anniversary on Saturday, Xi expressed the hope that the university could cultivate more high-caliber talent based on the country&amp;#39;s strategic needs, expand its leading edge in strong disciplines, and continue to produce high-level scientific research results.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the speech published on Saturday by Qiushi Journal, Xi explained how China will make itself a leader in education. &amp;quot;Only when basic education enjoys sound development, can we make steady progress in building up our country&amp;#39;s strength in education and sustaining its momentum,&amp;quot; Xi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized that higher education is the key to China&amp;#39;s becoming a leading nation in the field of education. &amp;quot;Priority must be given to the building of world-class universities and superior disciplines, and the development of basic, emerging and interdisciplinary subjects must be strengthened.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Education in science and technology and engineering should be furthered. Greater efforts should be made to nurture China&amp;#39;s top-notch and innovative talent on our own to provide support for achieving breakthroughs in core technologies in key fields,&amp;quot; Xi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the 18th CPC National Congress in 2012, the CPC Central Committee has considered education to be of great significance to the future of the country and the Party. It also has made important decisions to accelerate the modernization of education and develop the country as a leader in this regard.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The CPC Central Committee and the State Council, China&amp;#39;s Cabinet, released an education modernization plan in February 2019, outlining blueprints for the sector&amp;#39;s modernization and development by 2035, the year by which the country is determined to basically achieve socialist modernization and become an education powerhouse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Yongyue, a professor at Wuhan University&amp;#39;s School of Marxism, said that to accelerate the development of China as a leading country in education, the focus should be fixed on the process of the nation&amp;#39;s modernization drive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We need to comprehensively consider the challenges and opportunities brought by the world&amp;#39;s major development, transformation and adjustment to the nation&amp;#39;s modernization in the education sector, while aligning with national strategies of building a technology powerhouse, developing a quality workforce in the new era and promoting rural vitalization,&amp;quot; Yu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China has established the largest education system in the world and joined the ranks of upper- to middle-level countries in terms of the overall level of modernization in education. China ranks 23rd in a global education index, up 26 spots from 2012, with the fastest progress in the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 04:21:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>