<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[015Q&amp;A WITH CEO - China vital engine for global economic growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_015_65441618ed50d203d2ca1ebb.htm#015Q&amp;A WITH CEO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/015/20231103_015_01_32784.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;裴宏临时总裁安斯泰来大中华区&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/015/20231103_015_01_31784.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Nancy Wang 国家经理LinkedIn 中国&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/015/20231103_015_01_34784.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Hannah Ha Mayer 亚洲区主席Brown&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/015/20231103_015_01_35784.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Aldous Wong 亚洲区主席兼总裁——豪迈集团太平洋业务及全球执行董事会顾问&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 编者按：凭借强有力的政策支持、坚持不懈的技术创新和产业升级，中国经济复苏势头持续增强三季度国内生产总值同比增长4.9%，前9个月同比增长5.2%。 《中国日报》与跨国公司高管进行了一系列问答，讨论他们对中国经济的看法以及他们将如何定位未来在中国的业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Q1 鉴于当前复杂的全球经济和地缘政治形势，您如何在整体全球业务雷达中定位中国市场？您对今明两年中国经济和贵公司在华经营有何展望？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; PEI：虽然全球形势复杂，存在一些不确定因素，我们对中国的信心没有改变。作为1994年进入中国的全球制药公司，安斯泰来是中国市场重大变化和机遇的见证者和受益者。在制药行业，中国的扩张速度非常快，这主要是由于其庞大的人口和医疗保健支出以及公众健康意识的提高。中国一直是安斯泰来的重要市场。全球增长，凭借其强劲的业绩和战略意义，现已成为我们的全球战略市场之一。中国为我们提供了市场潜力，也为我们提供了利用全球专业知识推动和加速创新的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王：过去几年，LinkedIn 的 B2B 业务在中国取得了相当大的成功。我们的人才解决方案业务在过去八年里增长了五倍，而 LinkedIn 营销解决方案的规模也扩大了一倍。在全球经济持续放缓的背景下，我们高兴地看到中国外贸继续展现竞争优势。出口成为拉动经济增长的重要引擎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在全球营商环境的不确定性下，寻求全球化发展的中国企业也面临着不断变化的挑战，这对企业的各方面能力和竞争优势提出了新的要求。 ，从全球战略制定到本地组织和人才团队建设，从品牌营销到运营合规。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们将继续立足中国，继续致力于帮助中国企业实现国际化业务目标，通过我们的人才、营销和学习解决方案，利用 LinkedIn 在全球拥有超过 10 亿会员的全球专业网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; HA：中国仍然是一个战略市场，不仅对我们而言公司和我们的客户，也为世界。中国企业不断适应变化，我们见证了他们在海外投资、开拓新市场的努力。孖士打继续为寻求扩大全球影响力的公司提供服务，在他们在不熟悉的司法管辖区规划投资活动时就法律复杂性和机遇提供咨询。我们相信，市场对像我们这样的法律技能的需求仍然强劲，我们在跨境交易方面的经验，加上对中国文化的深刻理解，使我们能够成为客户规避风险的桥梁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 黄：鉴于全球20%的人口在中国，如果我们要实现建设更安全、更清洁、更健康的目标，那么在中国和更广泛的亚太地区的增长和投资至关重要每个人、每一天的未来。我们的战略是“在中国成长，加速亚太”，以中国为核心，加速我们的有机和无机增长。豪迈亚太区综合生产研发中心于今年九月开业，有力地证明了我们的战略和长期承诺。它将成为我们加速创新、协作、伙伴关系和本地化增长推动力的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Q2 从长远来看，您对中国经济有信心吗？您对中国经济的信心如何？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; PEI：我们对中国经济充满信心。随着新冠肺炎（COVID-19）后对经济的持续努力和高质量发展的持续政策，我们相信未来中国的经济将更具活力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在安斯泰来，我们致力于将创新科学转化为患者的价值。这些地区对高价值、以患者为中心的医疗保健解决方案的需求正在上升，主要是由于大量的人口和医疗保健支出以及公众健康意识的提高。此外，我们看到中国对创新的坚定承诺，全社会的创新创造潜力应该得到最大程度的释放。创新是制药业务的支柱。安斯泰来作为全球创新者在中国进一步加速以患者为中心的创新是非常令人鼓舞的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王：在全球经济加速重启的今天，我们很高兴看到中国保持了其领先地位。国家统计局最新数据显示，今年上半年，我国国内生产总值同比增长5.5%。进入下半年，包括联合国、世界银行、国际货币基金组织在内的众多国际组织和机构纷纷上调对2023年中国经济总体增长预期，中国继续成为重要增长点世界经济的引擎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我们对中国经济的长期增长充满信心。我们认为，中国的开放举措、不断优化的营商环境、科技创新、本土企业全球化以及政府的其他努力有助于其经济增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; HA：中国已经过去十年经历了指数级增长，现在是经济从制造业转型为更成熟和可持续模式的时候了。鉴于强有力的支持性国内政策以及人民的创业精神和动力，我们对中国的长期增长充满信心。所有这些因素将继续推动经济发展，帮助中国应对任何短期挑战。可持续发展是积极变革的一个例子，我们看到了中国转型计划的雄心勃勃的目标，以及发展电动汽车、绿色金融、可再生能源等相关产业的努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄：在豪迈，我们用几十年而不是几天的时间来制定我们的战略。亚太地区，尤其是中国，是豪迈未来十年及更长时间内的战略市场和增长引擎。我们认为中国市场潜力巨大、机遇巨大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《健康中国2030》提出规划提出了中国雄心勃勃的长期承诺，致力于解决工业化、城市化、人口老龄化和慢性生活方式疾病日益流行带来的挑战。我们在健康评估、治疗解决方案和生命科学领域提供领先的技术和数字解决方案。他们可以帮助我们在中国的客户满足不断增长的医疗保健需求，解决可预防的疾病，并为改善患者的治疗效果做出贡献。通过这种方式，我们将实现我们的目标，为中国每个人建设更健康的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 第三季度中国经济决策者承诺加大吸引外资的力度，放宽市场准入，确保国内外企业公平竞争。在此背景下，您预计中国当局近期会有哪些新的政策举措？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; PEI：我们赞赏中国营商环境的持续进步。对于一家跨国公司来说，更加市场化、规则化、国际化的营商环境，不仅可以增强业务运营的连续性，也可以为医药市场注入动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为最重要的新兴制药市场之一，中国正在积极转型，以增强其创新医疗保健系统，超越其市场增长规模。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在我看来，既定的创新奖励制度将推动高推动产业高质量发展，推动产业升级，最终提高中国人民的健康水平。我们期待更多的努力扩大患者对创新药物的可及性，以及持续改善的营商环境，这将使我们更有信心更快地将创新科学转化为中国患者的价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王：中国&amp; #39;对高标准开放和改善外商投资营商环境的承诺提振了包括LinkedIn在内的跨国公司的信心。我们相信中国经济的潜力、韧性和长期可持续性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我们很高兴看到中国政府官员为加强全球合作、支持中国企业走出去所做的努力。我们期待看到更多进一步促进中国对外开放、加强国际合作的政策和举措。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我们将利用这些举措带来的商机，继续为中国企业提供支持在全球市场上占据重要地位，为中国的高质量发展做出贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; HA：继续拥有能够帮助中国发展的法律架构至关重要促进境内外投资，营造创新环境。我们已经看到此类框架的一些令人鼓舞的迹象，并期待更多的出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，随着粤港澳大湾区内部合作的不断加强，已经提出了推动数字经济和发展的机制。促进数据传输以降低企业的合规成本。这对在中国内地设有业务的香港公司尤其有帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，我们还看到知识产权保护总体有所增加，在专利申请方面，外国公司创新专利的注册和知识产权使用费贸易的增加。在这些领域建立信任将鼓励更多企业将技术知识带到中国，积极推动创新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 黄：作为世界第二大经济体，中国展现了强大的韧性，尽管充满挑战的政治和商业环境。中方重申坚持高水平开放，强调要加大吸引和利用外资力度，放宽市场准入，推动现代服务业开放，给予外资企业国民待遇。 2022 年 12 月召开的年度中央经济工作会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 如今，中国是世界上可再生能源最大的投资者之一。从“天蓝水清”到“绿色发展”，“绿色发展”已成为中国的重要战略方针。通过提供监测和保护稀缺自然资源的技术，我们帮助客户创造更加可持续的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Q4 随着中国继续走自主发展之路，追求高质量发展，现代化，从长远来看，贵公司在该国的业务愿景是什么？您认为中国现代化进程中会出现哪些商机？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; PEI：中国医药市场实现高质量发展，从仿制药为主向仿制药为主转变。创新驱动，中国政府强有力的有利政策正在改变整个行业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 安斯泰来将战略重点放在肿瘤学、创新药物和疗法的突破上。我们一直在加快创新药物的引进，提高可及性，造福中国患者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我们将继续聚焦市场开拓、产业升级、创新创造、质量效益提升等。我们也将继续与政府和地方合作伙伴一道，引领中国医疗健康产业的创新和服务升级，共同实现“健康中国2030”的目标。支持中国经济高质量发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王：在中国进一步实现现代化的背景下，我们认为全球化已经成为越来越多国家日益重要的战略方向。中国公司，释放Linked-In中国的商业潜力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2023年，我们将本地业务重点转向协助在中国运营的公司寻找熟练的国际人才并将其产品和服务营销到海外.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我们的业务主要集中在三个领域：LinkedIn Talent Solutions帮助中国企业制定有竞争力的国际化人才战略，实现更高效的人才招聘； LinkedIn营销解决方案支持中国企业精准触达海外市场目标受众，打造有凝聚力的品牌和营销效果； LinkedIn学习解决方案帮助中国企业及时识别并赋予员工基本技能，快速响应市场变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据第三方研究机构数据，未来将有约5.9万家中国出口企业设立分支机构到2024年，海外市场的办事处将拥有450万名员工。这些公司是我们的目标客户。因此，我们对中国业务未来的发展充满信心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; HA：从机遇来看，我们看到很多主权财富基金设立了专门的基金来投资中国大陆。 ，我们还听说中东基金有兴趣投资高科技和可再生能源行业。凭借我们在中东的网络和联系，以及我们为中东客户在中国及其他地区的合法存在提供建议的工作，我们预计这方面的资金将进一步流入。在大湾区，由于人口众多且渗透率较低，我们预计保险业将进一步增长。孖士打与全球近 400 家保险公司和保险相关实体合作，我们预计该行业的服务、合同以及并购活动未来将会增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 黄：我们看到许多新的趋势和有趣的机会豪迈公司可以在其中发挥重要作用，包括推动清洁能源转型的安全技术、眼部护理、智能废水技术和数字健康。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些新趋势是我们所热衷的进军全球和中国，因为它们与我们为每个人每天创造更安全、更清洁、更健康的未来的目标高度一致。我相信，在中国市场不断追求高质量发展的同时，我们会看到更多这样的机会，这也解释了我们在这里的策略——投资中国，赋能亚太增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Q5 您能否与我们分享一两个您与中国共同成长过程中成功的商业或个人故事？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; PEI：未来三到五年，我们将继续利用中国的利好政策，与政府和所有合作伙伴一起，以更快的速度加速我们改变生活的创新。这将使我们能够解决中国高度未满足的医疗需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王：LinkedIn 最近的数据显示，自 2015 年以来，工作技能组合已经发生了约 25% 的变化，预计这一数字至少将达到由于人工智能等新技术的快速发展，到 2030 年这一数字将达到 65%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们相信人工智能将加速劳动力学习并提高技能的重要性。根据 LinkedIn Data Insight 的数据，支持提升技能并采用人工智能的公司将在吸引和留住顶尖人才方面取得最大成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 采用技能优先的人才管理方法是扩大人才库的最佳方式，提高现有员工的技能，并增强员工的敏捷性。为了支持这一做法，我们于今年7月将LinkedIn学习解决方案引入中国市场，帮助中国企业的员工全面提高需求技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 帮助中国企业促进人工智能的学习和发展技能方面，LinkedIn将在2023年12月15日前向中国企业用户免费开放全球企业中最受欢迎的10大人工智能相关课程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; HA：我在90年代初开始担任见习律师当人们对中国的入境投资越来越感兴趣时。我协助客户在各个行业领域组建了众多合作合资企业和合资企业。我们是香港与内地同事合作的先驱之一。自那时以来，我们一直在继续这一旅程——从并购到帮助客户应对监管环境。令人惊奇的是，中国法律和监管体系的成长和发展如何帮助我打造职业生涯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我也很高兴来到香港，这里是一个内地门户，与大湾区紧密相连。我有幸见证了所有新的发展，并成为第一个在当地帮助客户抓住入境和出境机会的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 黄：改革开放以来，中国经历了世界历史上规模最大、速度最快的城市化进程。安全是“十四五”规划（2021-25）和2035年长期目标的首要任务之一。我们的安全部门带来了先进的安全技术，包括火灾探测和灭火、人流和车流监控、工业门禁控制等。我们在中国城市的一系列关键工业和物流运营中利用全球技术，提高城市治理能力，并保护工作中的人员和资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Remains of Li Keqiang cremated]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_001_6543fb35ed50d203d2ca1cbf.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_001_01_74.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;国旗飘扬周四，北京天安门广场下半旗。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_001_01_57 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;周四，习近平在北京八宝山革命公墓与李克强的妻子程虹握手表示哀悼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李克强同志的遗体，中共十七届、十八届、十九届中央政治局常委、原国务院总理李克强于周四在北京八宝山革命公墓火化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 李先生被赞誉为优秀共产党员、久经考验的忠诚共产主义战士、杰出的无产阶级革命家、政治家、党和国家的领导人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李先生于00岁时因心脏病突发去世： 10月27日，上海，10月10日，全力救援未果。 68岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平、李强、赵乐际、王沪宁、蔡奇、丁薛祥、李希、韩正、胡锦涛等都曾在李克强任职期间看望过他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周四上午，公墓礼堂内一片肃穆，背景音乐响起悲痛的挽歌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大厅里挂着黑底白字横幅，上面写着“深切哀悼李克强同志”。横幅下是他的肖像。上午9时许，习近平和夫人彭丽媛、李强、赵乐际、王沪宁、蔡奇、丁薛祥、李希、韩正等人缓缓走到李克强遗体前，肃立默哀，三鞠躬。他们与李某的家属一一握手，表示哀悼。胡锦涛向李克强逝世致送花圈表示哀悼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 其他党和国家领导人或到公墓瞻仰，或通过各种方式表达哀悼。中央有关部门领导、李克强的亲友和家乡代表也到公墓悼念他的逝世。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Regional growth points to nation&#39;s firm economic recovery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_001_6543fb38ed50d203d2ca1cc0.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 前三季度全国31个省级地区中超半数GDP同比增速好于全国平均水平，表明我国经济正在复苏&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 考虑到经济持续复苏态势以及支持性政策措施逐步落地，分析人士认为四季度GDP和全年GDP增​​速将有望超过5%，增速将进一步回升。超过2023年5%左右的全年增长目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们预计短期内会有更多政策宽松，以扩大有效需求，提振市场预期。他们表示，可能采取的举措包括进一步放宽购房限制、进一步下调关键政策利率以及再次降低存款准备金率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 截至周四，31 个省级地区已发布经济增长数据前九个月。前三季度，有17个地区同比增速5.2%跑赢全国，其中西藏自治区、海南省、内蒙古自治区分别增长9.8%、9.5%和7.2%。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 1-9月，川鄂、重庆等11个地区GDP增速高于上半年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 共有13个省区前九个月GDP超过3万亿元人民币（4110亿美元），其中广东和江苏前三季度GDP超过9万亿元人民币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “多个省级政府已宣布激励措施以鼓励本季度的增长并实现年度增长目标，”北京福斯特经济咨询有限公司首席经济学家冯建林表示。经济结构转型升级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，相信未来几个月各地区将重点关注释放消费潜力、扩大有效投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们预计中国经济第四季度增长5.1%至5.4%，预计2023年全年增长率在5.2%左右。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “要实现全年增长目标，四季度增长要在4.4%以上。”康卡特数据技术（杭州）有限公司首席经济学家杨景浩表示，“因此，我对今年中国经济增长持乐观态度。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杨景浩补充说，六省区占中国经济的近一半——广东、江苏、山东、浙江、河南、四川——力争实现今年经济发展目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 增速未能高于全国平均水平的地区要着力夯实经济复苏基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; “多个地区披露了发行专项再融资债券的计划，这将有助于缓解地方政府财政压力，化解地方政府债务风险，”杨说。 “这些新举措加上第四季度有利的基数效应，意味着中国第四季度的经济业绩可能会更好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鉴于一系列政策措施的逐步生效以及政策制定者的预期举措为进一步提振经济，中国银行研究院研究员叶银丹表示，预计四季度中国GDP增长5.7%左右，预计全年GDP增​​长5.3%左右&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，北京福斯特经济咨询公司的冯先生警告称，需求依然疲弱和房地产行业的压力将带来压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;ouyangshijia@chinadaily.com。 cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Help for injured]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_001_6543fb3bed50d203d2ca1cc1.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_001_03_105.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;医务人员携带周三，拉法过境点加沙一侧受伤的女孩。埃及安全部门消息人士周三称，​​当天有多名来自加沙地带的伤者通过拉法过境点进入埃及。查看更多信息，第 11 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - LIFE LOOKS UP FOR VILLAGERS IN XINJIANG]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_001_6543fb43ed50d203d2ca1cc5.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_002_02_79.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;新疆维吾尔自治区海域自治区为人类、动物和其他形式的野生动物共存提供了栖息地。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/ 20231103_002_02_45.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;新疆博斯腾湖是中国最大的内陆淡水湖之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023 -11-03/001/20231103_002_02_28.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;游客在新疆哈密巴里坤哈萨克自治县高家湖湿地风景区合影。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily .com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_002_02_70.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;游客在新疆哈密巴里坤哈萨克自治县湿地里游览。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https ://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_002_02_88.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;哈密河国家湿地公园里的白鹭休息。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot; https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/001/20231103_002_02_11.png&quot; />; &lt;p>;20世纪80年代末，我国东部主要水道哈密河新疆维吾尔自治区，几近干涸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，近年来，在被誉为“母亲河”的哈密河沿岸，时常看到白鹭等野生鸟类在觅食和休息。哈密​​地区。这些鸟已成为该地区的风景名胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 自1998年以来，该县当局向河流供水以改善环境。 2019年，当局启动了哈密河生态修复工程，并建立了哈密河国家湿地公园。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 湿地公园管理办公室主任宋占石表示，通过修复更多沿河改造1万多户棚户区，保留原有水系并增设植物，沿河绿化率从18%上升到78%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 公园南北绵延约42公里，宽约400米。河边亭台楼阁，流水潺潺，花草古树为背景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 家住哈密益州区的84岁的阿卜杜·卡德尔说：“这里很美。”这里很美，每天在这里散步都感觉很开心。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 哈密河国家湿地公园吸引了广大游客休闲、娱乐、健身、单纯赏景的游客.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 哈密降雨量少，70%以上的土地是沙漠和山地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 哈密地区是新疆最缺水的地区之一，哈密地区河流是天山南麓的重要生命线。这条河的水源主要来自山上的积雪融水，保护水源、提高用水效率对于哈密的社会经济发展和人民生计至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;水、哈密拥有丰富的风能、太阳能资源。已成为以风电基地、光伏基地为主的国家综合能源枢纽。该地区规划建设新能源基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，风电、光伏发电的间歇性、波动性特点给电网安全稳定运行带来挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 徐国网新源新疆哈密抽水蓄能有限公司总经理、党委副书记红卫表示，正是由于这些因素，哈密抽水蓄能电站项目已经启动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “为了电网，抽水蓄能电站充当“超级电力银行”。当电网面临高需求时，电站会从水库放水发电，保证稳定供应。” ”徐说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在需求低迷时期，电站利用非高峰电力来抽水和储存能量。这一独特优势促进了新能源消纳，有效缓解新能源发电波动，减少风电、太阳能发电停电，提高新能源发电效率，维护电网稳定运行。”&lt;/p>; &lt;该电站位于哈密市伊州区天山乡三道沟河畔，正在建设中。由于水将被引入下游的石城子水库，这对水资源保护和维持高环境标准提出了挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “由于该电站的水源是哈密的主要生产和生活用水water source, the construction process involves disposing of industrial and domestic wastewater to the highest standards, with additional investment exceeding 100 million yuan ($13.6 million),&amp;quot; Xu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yan Kai, deputy director of the Hami Development and Reform Commission, said, &amp;quot;We are also employing local villagers and herdsmen, promoting grassland restoration, and striving to achieve the green construction goal of protecting source water quality for the extremely arid Hami region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Since the project was implemented, vegetation near the power station has increased and improved significantly, and the groundwater level has also risen to some extent.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The power station, which is scheduled to be fully operational in 2028, has a designed annual generation capacity of nearly 1.37 billion kilowatt-hours. This capacity can reduce coal consumption by about 239,000 metric tons and carbon dioxide emissions by 596,000 tons annually, contributing to carbon peak and carbon neutrality goals being achieved.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Costs reduced&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Located 160 km north of the East Tianshan Mountains, Naomao Lake town in Yiwu county, Xinjiang, nestles deep in the vast Gobi Desert, sharing borders with Mongolia to the north and east.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The area has abundant sunlight, a dry climate, and a vast difference between daytime and nighttime temperatures. It is known for a forest that covers some 31,333 hectares and for the production of high-quality Hami melons, which are recognized domestically and internationally.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The late-maturing Hami melon cultivation area covers about 2,667 hectares, yielding fruit of exceptional shape, color, texture and high commercial value.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wei Bin, 34, a villager with nearly 20 hectares of melon fields, said: &amp;quot;We use sheep manure as organic fertilizer in our fields, and the soil&amp;#39;s high nutrition levels result in exceptional Hami melons. We earn an average income of about 4,000 yuan from every 0.066 of a hectare, and this year&amp;#39;s crop of melons has already been ordered by merchants from various areas.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By promoting the use of membrane drip irrigation systems and using irrigation methods controlled by a smartphone app, overall water costs have been reduced by 30 percent. In addition, increasing the frequency of irrigation while reducing the amount of water used for this purpose has improved the crispness and color of the melons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Mingsheng, a member of the Naomao Lake Town Party Committee, said, &amp;quot;Naomao Lake-branded Hami melons are exported to countries such as Vietnam through e-commerce channels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The melon industry in Hami will develop melon wine and freeze-dried products, improve the industry&amp;#39;s market-oriented management, stabilize prices, and increase melon farmers&amp;#39; incomes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hami melon cultivation base, which completed the transition to membrane drip irrigation in 2001, has saved 175 million cubic meters of water over 22 years, equivalent to the total water volume of Tianchi in the Tianshan Mountains. This initiative not only ensures the groundwater level remains stable, but also provides vital support for development of the coal and chemical industries in Yiwu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the first half of this year, Yiwu county&amp;#39;s GDP reached 11.52 billion yuan, a year-on-year rise of 31 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Mountain divide&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hami is divided into northern and southern areas by the Tianshan Mountains. In the southern area, fertile land and the Gobi Desert converge, while the northern area features forests, grasslands, snowcapped mountains and glaciers. As a result, Hami is a microcosm of Xinjiang, as it can experience four seasons in a single day and different weather conditions within a 16-kilometer radius.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Barkol Kazakh autonomous county in the north, located next to Yiwu, is home to a landscape rich in snow-capped mountains, forests, grasslands and lakes. Viewed from the Gaojiahu Wetland Scenic Area, the distant Tianshan Mountains are covered with snow and ice, while rivers and lakes dot the grassland. This ecosystem not only serves as a habitat for birds such as gray geese and ruddy shelducks, but also attracts tourists from across China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The scenic area, which is located in the northern part of Shirenzi township, Barkol county, and covers 59,400 hectares, is one of the country&amp;#39;s most important wetlands.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Poverty that existed in the area more than a decade ago, when there was dust on sunny days and deep mud when it rained, has long disappeared.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Bumpy and muddy roads have been transformed into smooth belts of asphalt, and low-rise, dilapidated adobe houses replaced by comfortable, well-equipped rural-style homes. Villagers not only enjoy a pleasant environment, but also increased employment opportunities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 2021, with an investment of 31 million yuan from Henan province as part of its assistance to Xinjiang, construction projects such as sightseeing corridors, wooden walkways, and water recreational facilities have been implemented in the Gaojiahu Wetland Scenic Area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These projects have comprehensively expanded and improved infrastructure in the area, significantly enhanced living conditions for farmers and herdsmen, and improved the quality of tourist services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, more than 300 local jobs have been created, and employment indirectly generated for over 1,200 people &amp;mdash; consolidating the achievements made in poverty alleviation, and serving as an ideal example of rural revitalization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang Xiaoliang, secretary of the Party Group and deputy director of the Cultural, Sports, Broadcasting, Television and Tourism Bureau in Barkol, said, &amp;quot;The assistance received from Henan has greatly broadened our construction ideas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Fish ponds in this area used to be surrounded by saline-alkaline soil, but now we have built accommodations from which to view the stars at night, with the first floor used for lodging and the second floor for barbecues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;French windows offer views of the beautiful lake, which are very popular among tourists. Last year, the scenic area received nearly 700,000 visitors, each spending an average of 268 yuan. Tourism income exceeded 200 million yuan, and locals are now earning more.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ma Xianghui, deputy secretary of Barkol County CPC Committee and commander of Henan Assistance to Xinjiang Command in Barkol County, said, &amp;quot;For the next step, we will better implement the concept of &amp;#39;green mountains and clear waters are as valuable as mountains of gold and silver&amp;#39;, protect the environment of Gaojia Lake, improve the level of tourist services, attract more visitors, and help villagers sustainably increase their income.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wuyanbo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Renewal of Sino-US sci-tech agreement urged]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_001_6543fb4fed50d203d2ca1cca.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Experts from China and the United States have warned that scientific communities in both nations and around the world would face significant uncertainty if the China-US Science and Technology Agreement fails to survive the current difficulties in bilateral relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They are calling for scientists from the two countries to push for the renewal of the agreement for the benefit of all humanity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In late August, just before the renewal deadline, Washington made a last-minute decision to temporarily extend the agreement by six months.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This short-term, six-month extension will keep the agreement in force while we seek authority to undertake negotiations to amend and strengthen the terms of the STA,&amp;quot; a US State Department official told Reuters at the time. &amp;quot;It does not commit the US to a longer-term extension.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xue Lan, a professor and dean of Schwarzman College at Tsinghua University, said the long-term continuation of the agreement is of great importance, because without such a framework, &amp;quot;all bilateral scientific and technological cooperation would be put in a very difficult position&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Without the agreement, there would definitely not be a basis for cooperation between the two sides,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The landmark agreement, signed in 1979 by then Chinese leader Deng Xiaoping and then US president Jimmy Carter, was one of the first shoots of cooperation after the countries normalized diplomatic relations that year. It has generally been renewed about every five years since, with the most recent renewal being in 2018.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a summary of bilateral science and technology exchanges, the Chinese embassy in the US said the agreement has provided a legal framework for governmental cooperation and an effective platform for civilian cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The agreement&amp;#39;s original text, released by the Foreign Ministry, set out the basic principles for science and technology cooperation and exchanges between the two governments. It also encouraged governments, universities and research institutions of the two countries to cooperate in areas including agriculture, energy, health, the environment, education and academic exchanges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cooperation under the agreement has included exchanging scientific information, sending scholars and students to each other&amp;#39;s country, conducting joint research experiments, and collaborating on project planning and research outcome exchanges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xue said the scientific communities in China and the US had initiated a series of exchange visits in the 1970s, before the agreement was signed, that laid the foundation for cooperation in science and technology when they established diplomatic relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than four decades later, the agreement is facing unprecedented political challenges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In late June, a letter from 10 Republican lawmakers urged US Secretary of State Antony Blinken not to renew the agreement, arguing that Beijing would seek to use it to strengthen its military and undermine US sovereignty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yuan Zheng, deputy director of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences&amp;#39; Institute of American Studies, said that argument was &amp;quot;groundless&amp;quot;, because the US had been wary of China from the very beginning and no cooperation with China under the agreement had ever involved the US&amp;#39; most advanced technologies, including ones with military applications.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that bilateral cooperation on science and technology had always been two-way, voluntary and based on the premise of mutual benefit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scientific relations between the US and China have worsened since 2018, when the administration of then US president Donald Trump launched the &amp;quot;China Initiative&amp;quot; to target researchers with Chinese ties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The now-defunct program, which resulted in some high-profile false arrests and prosecutions, cast a shadow over scientific collaborations and prompted many scientists of Chinese origin to leave the US for other countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In an article published in Foreign Affairs magazine in mid-September, former Massachusetts Institute of Technology president L. Rafael Reif cited a recent survey of Chinese American university scientists sponsored by the Asian American Scholar Forum. The survey found that 65 percent of respondents were worried about collaboration with China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The number of research papers co-authored by US and Chinese scientists fell in 2021 for the first time in three decades, according to statistics released by Japan&amp;#39;s Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yuan said that was an indication of the chilling effect caused by the China Initiative and neo-McCarthyism in the US, which made many US scientists, especially Chinese American scientists, afraid to cooperate with Chinese colleagues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The US also introduced a series of sanctions or legislative bills targeting Chinese scientific institutions or technology enterprises in recent years, further chilling Sino-US scientific and technological cooperation, Yuan said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; An international cooperation officer at the Chinese Academy of Sciences, who requested anonymity, said a decoupling of science and technology would do serious harm to scientists and science itself.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Most scientific research can&amp;#39;t be done behind closed doors, and no country is able to stay ahead (in any one field) forever,&amp;quot; the officer said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Alan Jeffrey Giacomin, editor-in-chief of the scientific journal Physics of Fluids, said that international collaboration could produce unique results.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said the journal was an example of the fruit of cooperation, with its 15-person editing team including two associate editors from Beijing &amp;mdash; Professor Xu Chunxiao from Tsinghua University and Professor Yao Zhaohui from the University of Chinese Academy of Sciences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I chose these two associate editors because they&amp;#39;re the best choices for Physics of Fluids and they have played a crucial role,&amp;quot; Giacomin said. &amp;quot;They edit papers not regionally, not just from China, but from all over the world. Their reputations are worldwide.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Reif, the former MIT president, said that allowing international talent, including Chinese students, to study in the US was &amp;quot;overwhelmingly beneficial&amp;quot; to the country, with 90 percent of science, technology, engineering and mathematics students from China who had earned doctoral degrees in the US between 2000 and 2015 still in the US in 2017, &amp;quot;helping the country advance&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China has been the largest source country of international students in the US since 2008, with about 290,000 students studying in the country in the 2021-22 academic year, according to a white paper released by the Beijing-based Center for China and Globalization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; John Holdren, who was a science adviser to former US president Barack Obama and is currently a professor at the Harvard Kennedy School, told Foreign Policy that &amp;quot;without the implicit permission that the existence of this overarching framework provides, there will be many institutions, many individuals, who would simply not engage with their Chinese counterparts&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;A lot of the interactions wouldn&amp;#39;t happen,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xue, the Tsinghua University professor, urged the scientific communities of both countries to work together to minimize the impact of geopolitics on science and technology cooperation and promote the renewal of the agreement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This is the common aspiration and also the shared responsibility of the scientific communities in China and the US,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jiangchenglong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - Rivers and mountains home to stories of a rich past]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_002_6543fb43ed50d203d2ca1cc4.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Xinjiang Uygur autonomous region boasts a large number of lakes, rivers and other bodies of water.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The impressive Altay, Tianshan and Kunlun Mountains &amp;mdash; three colossal ranges that showcase the region&amp;#39;s unique geographical features &amp;mdash; stretch across Xinjiang.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The natural treasures to be seen within this vast expanse of terrain include glaciers covering an area of 26,000 square kilometers, and comprising 42 percent of China&amp;#39;s glacial area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Glistening in the sunlight, these glaciers gradually melt and merge, forming a network of rivers that crisscross the land, nurturing the soil.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Amid this breathtaking natural panorama lies the Tarim River, the longest inland river in China, which weaves its way through the heart of Xinjiang. Its basin is home to green oases in an otherwise arid landscape. These oases are not merely geographical features; they are cradles of life, supporting agriculture, wildlife and, most important, nearly half of Xinjiang&amp;#39;s population.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meanwhile, the Ili River, with its abundant annual runoff, transforms the region into a tapestry of vibrant colors, thanks to the humid climate it sustains. This lush environment stands as one of China&amp;#39;s vital biodiversity conservation areas, sheltering a rich variety of flora and fauna.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These ancient rivers, formed over millennia, tell stories of civilizations long past, their courses interwoven with intricate patterns of the land.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As people journey through Xinjiang&amp;#39;s diverse landscape &amp;mdash; from the rugged terrain sculpted by the Tianshan Mountains to the gentle curves of riverbanks &amp;mdash; they discover the region&amp;#39;s best-kept secrets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Over time, human habitation has left an indelible mark, shaping not only the land but also the culture and traditions of those who call Xinjiang home.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In every whisper of the wind and ripple of the rivers, there are stories waiting to be heard &amp;mdash; stories of resilience, adaptation and coexistence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;weiwangyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - LIFE LOOKS UP FOR VILLAGERS IN XINJIANG]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_002_6543fb43ed50d203d2ca1cc5.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/002/20231103_002_02_79.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;The waters in Xinjiang Uygur autonomous region provide habitats for the coexistence of humans, animals and other forms of wildlife.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/002/20231103_002_02_45.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Bosten Lake in Xinjiang is one of the largest inland freshwater lakes in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/002/20231103_002_02_28.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Visitors pose at the Gaojiahu Wetland Scenic Area in Barkol Kazakh autonomous county, Hami, Xinjiang.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/002/20231103_002_02_70.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Visitors enjoy the wetland in Barkol Kazakh autonomous county, Hami, Xinjiang.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/002/20231103_002_02_88.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Egrets rest in Hami River National Wetland Park.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/002/20231103_002_02_11.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; During the late 1980s, the Hami River, the main waterway in the east of the Xinjiang Uygur autonomous region, nearly dried up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in recent years, wild birds such as egrets have been seen feeding and resting along the Hami, which is known as the &amp;quot;Mother River&amp;quot; of Hami prefecture. The birds have become a scenic attraction in the area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 1998, the authorities in the prefecture have supplied water to the river to improve the environment. In 2019, the Hami River Ecological Restoration Project was launched by the authorities, who also established the Hami River National Wetland Park.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Song Zhanshi, director of the management office at the wetland park, said that by renovating more than 10,000 shantytowns near the river, preserving the original water system and adding plants, the greening rate along the waterway has risen from 18 percent to 78 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The park, which stretches for about 42 kilometers north to south, is some 400 meters wide. It features pavilions by the riverside against a backdrop of gently flowing water, flowers, grass and old trees.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Abdu Kader, 84, who lives in Hami&amp;#39;s Yizhou district, said, &amp;quot;It is beautiful here, and I feel very happy walking in the area every day.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hami River National Wetland Park attracts a wide range of visitors for leisure, entertainment, fitness activities, and simply to enjoy the scenery.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hami has scant rainfall, and more than 70 percent of its land is desert and mountains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The prefecture is one of the most water-deficient areas of Xinjiang, with the Hami River acting as a vital lifeline at the southern foot of the Tianshan Mountains. The river is sourced mainly by melting snow on the mountains, and protecting water sources and using water more efficiently are crucial for Hami&amp;#39;s socioeconomic development and people&amp;#39;s livelihoods.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Despite its lack of water, Hami boasts abundant wind and solar resources. It has become a national comprehensive energy hub, mainly consisting of wind power bases and photovoltaic bases. New energy bases are planned for the area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, the intermittent nature and volatile characteristics of wind power and photovoltaic power pose challenges to the safe and stable operation of the grid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xu Hongwei, general manager and deputy Party secretary of State Grid Xinyuan Xinjiang Hami Pumped Storage Co, said that as a result of these factors, work has started on the Hami Pumped Storage Power Station.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For the grid, a pumped storage power station acts as a &amp;#39;superpower bank&amp;#39;. When the grid faces high demand, the power station releases water from the reservoir to generate electricity and ensure a stable supply,&amp;quot; Xu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;During periods of low demand, the power station uses off-peak electricity to pump and store energy. This unique advantage promotes the consumption of new energy, effectively mitigates fluctuations in generating this energy, reduces wind and solar power stoppages, improves the efficiency of generating new energy, and maintains the stable operation of the power grid.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The power station is being built alongside the Sandaogou River in Tianshan township, Yizhou district, Hami. As water will be introduced downstream into the Shichengzi Reservoir, this poses challenges for water protection and maintaining high environmental standards.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Since the water source for the power station is Hami&amp;#39;s primary production and domestic water source, the construction process involves disposing of industrial and domestic wastewater to the highest standards, with additional investment exceeding 100 million yuan ($13.6 million),&amp;quot; Xu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yan Kai, deputy director of the Hami Development and Reform Commission, said, &amp;quot;We are also employing local villagers and herdsmen, promoting grassland restoration, and striving to achieve the green construction goal of protecting source water quality for the extremely arid Hami region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Since the project was implemented, vegetation near the power station has increased and improved significantly, and the groundwater level has also risen to some extent.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The power station, which is scheduled to be fully operational in 2028, has a designed annual generation capacity of nearly 1.37 billion kilowatt-hours. This capacity can reduce coal consumption by about 239,000 metric tons and carbon dioxide emissions by 596,000 tons annually, contributing to carbon peak and carbon neutrality goals being achieved.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Costs reduced&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Located 160 km north of the East Tianshan Mountains, Naomao Lake town in Yiwu county, Xinjiang, nestles deep in the vast Gobi Desert, sharing borders with Mongolia to the north and east.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The area has abundant sunlight, a dry climate, and a vast difference between daytime and nighttime temperatures. It is known for a forest that covers some 31,333 hectares and for the production of high-quality Hami melons, which are recognized domestically and internationally.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The late-maturing Hami melon cultivation area covers about 2,667 hectares, yielding fruit of exceptional shape, color, texture and high commercial value.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wei Bin, 34, a villager with nearly 20 hectares of melon fields, said: &amp;quot;We use sheep manure as organic fertilizer in our fields, and the soil&amp;#39;s high nutrition levels result in exceptional Hami melons. We earn an average income of about 4,000 yuan from every 0.066 of a hectare, and this year&amp;#39;s crop of melons has already been ordered by merchants from various areas.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By promoting the use of membrane drip irrigation systems and using irrigation methods controlled by a smartphone app, overall water costs have been reduced by 30 percent. In addition, increasing the frequency of irrigation while reducing the amount of water used for this purpose has improved the crispness and color of the melons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Mingsheng, a member of the Naomao Lake Town Party Committee, said, &amp;quot;Naomao Lake-branded Hami melons are exported to countries such as Vietnam through e-commerce channels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The melon industry in Hami will develop melon wine and freeze-dried products, improve the industry&amp;#39;s market-oriented management, stabilize prices, and increase melon farmers&amp;#39; incomes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hami melon cultivation base, which completed the transition to membrane drip irrigation in 2001, has saved 175 million cubic meters of water over 22 years, equivalent to the total water volume of Tianchi in the Tianshan Mountains. This initiative not only ensures the groundwater level remains stable, but also provides vital support for development of the coal and chemical industries in Yiwu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the first half of this year, Yiwu county&amp;#39;s GDP reached 11.52 billion yuan, a year-on-year rise of 31 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Mountain divide&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hami is divided into northern and southern areas by the Tianshan Mountains. In the southern area, fertile land and the Gobi Desert converge, while the northern area features forests, grasslands, snowcapped mountains and glaciers. As a result, Hami is a microcosm of Xinjiang, as it can experience four seasons in a single day and different weather conditions within a 16-kilometer radius.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Barkol Kazakh autonomous county in the north, located next to Yiwu, is home to a landscape rich in snow-capped mountains, forests, grasslands and lakes. Viewed from the Gaojiahu Wetland Scenic Area, the distant Tianshan Mountains are covered with snow and ice, while rivers and lakes dot the grassland. This ecosystem not only serves as a habitat for birds such as gray geese and ruddy shelducks, but also attracts tourists from across China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The scenic area, which is located in the northern part of Shirenzi township, Barkol county, and covers 59,400 hectares, is one of the country&amp;#39;s most important wetlands.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Poverty that existed in the area more than a decade ago, when there was dust on sunny days and deep mud when it rained, has long disappeared.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Bumpy and muddy roads have been transformed into smooth belts of asphalt, and low-rise, dilapidated adobe houses replaced by comfortable, well-equipped rural-style homes. Villagers not only enjoy a pleasant environment, but also increased employment opportunities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 2021, with an investment of 31 million yuan from Henan province as part of its assistance to Xinjiang, construction projects such as sightseeing corridors, wooden walkways, and water recreational facilities have been implemented in the Gaojiahu Wetland Scenic Area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These projects have comprehensively expanded and improved infrastructure in the area, significantly enhanced living conditions for farmers and herdsmen, and improved the quality of tourist services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, more than 300 local jobs have been created, and employment indirectly generated for over 1,200 people &amp;mdash; consolidating the achievements made in poverty alleviation, and serving as an ideal example of rural revitalization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang Xiaoliang, secretary of the Party Group and deputy director of the Cultural, Sports, Broadcasting, Television and Tourism Bureau in Barkol, said, &amp;quot;The assistance received from Henan has greatly broadened our construction ideas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Fish ponds in this area used to be surrounded by saline-alkaline soil, but now we have built accommodations from which to view the stars at night, with the first floor used for lodging and the second floor for barbecues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;French windows offer views of the beautiful lake, which are very popular among tourists. Last year, the scenic area received nearly 700,000 visitors, each spending an average of 268 yuan. Tourism income exceeded 200 million yuan, and locals are now earning more.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ma Xianghui, deputy secretary of Barkol County CPC Committee and commander of Henan Assistance to Xinjiang Command in Barkol County, said, &amp;quot;For the next step, we will better implement the concept of &amp;#39;green mountains and clear waters are as valuable as mountains of gold and silver&amp;#39;, protect the environment of Gaojia Lake, improve the level of tourist services, attract more visitors, and help villagers sustainably increase their income.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wuyanbo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Experts welcome nation&#39;s financial-opening pledge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_003_6543fb46ed50d203d2ca1cc6.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China will remain committed to opening its financial industry and market despite a more turbulent global financial landscape, a point that was reiterated at a recent high-profile meeting, experts said on Thursday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the key focuses of the country&amp;#39;s financial opening-up in the coming years would be further aligning domestic regulations and standards with global standards, better managing risks related to cross-border capital flows and steadily advancing renminbi internationalization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They said that such efforts will reinforce a win-win scenario whereby global financial institutions capitalize on China&amp;#39;s vast growth opportunities, while the country&amp;#39;s financial sector can achieve high-quality development to better support its modernization endeavors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Their comments came after the central financial work conference that concluded on Tuesday. The meeting highlighted the importance of promoting high-standard financial opening-up while ensuring national financial and economic security.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was decided at the conference that China should steadily expand institutional opening-up in the financial sector, facilitate cross-border investment and financing and attract more foreign financial institutions and long-term capital to invest and operate in the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The People&amp;#39;s Bank of China, the nation&amp;#39;s central bank, stressed at a meeting on Thursday the need to steadily advance financial market institutional opening-up, vowing to deepen reform and opening-up of the foreign exchange market and expand financial market connectivity between the Chinese mainland and Hong Kong.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;All of this signals that the momentum of accelerated financial opening-up in recent years will continue,&amp;quot; said Wang Qing, chief macroeconomic analyst at Golden Credit Rating International.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said he expects efforts to focus on advancing institutional opening-up, which means that rules, regulations, management and standards in financial industries and markets would become more in line with global norms and encourage more foreign financial institutions to expand business in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recognizing that China has already taken essential steps to open up its financial industries, Achim Kassow, a member of the board of management at Munich Re, a German reinsurer, said further improved clarity on regulations and acceptance of global business models would provide a more predictable business environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China has rolled out a series of financial opening-up measures since 2018, including removing ownership caps in the fund management and securities industries. According to the China Securities Regulatory Commission, nine securities companies with foreign majority stakes and nine wholly foreign-owned fund management companies have been approved to operate in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan Yuanyuan, an associate researcher at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences&amp;#39; Institute of World Economics and Politics, said that while deepening institutional financial opening-up would help China attract more long-term capital, the associated risks regarding cross-border capital flows should be well addressed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It is crucial to guard against the negative impact of short-term speculative money, which can flow in and out quickly and in large amounts, reducing its shock to the economy and financial markets,&amp;quot; Pan said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Global financial market volatility has intensified amid major central banks&amp;#39; sharp monetary tightening to curb inflation and a rise in geopolitical tensions, with the onshore renminbi weakening by 5.27 percent against the US dollar so far this year to 7.3179 as of Thursday evening.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was stressed at the central financial work conference that the management of foreign exchange markets should be strengthened so that the renminbi exchange rate can remain generally stable at a reasonable and balanced level. The meeting also called for efforts to push forward renminbi internationalization in a cautious and steady manner.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The overall direction of continuing to internationalize the renminbi remains unchanged,&amp;quot; said Lou Feipeng, a researcher at Postal Savings Bank of China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The focus going forward should be on facilitating trade and investment, supporting the healthy development of the offshore renminbi markets and enhancing the ability to manage risks under open conditions.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhoulanxv@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Preparations underway]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_003_6543fb49ed50d203d2ca1cc7.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/003/20231103_003_02_59.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Workers make arrangements on Wednesday for the sixth China International Import Expo in Shanghai. The event will be held at the National Exhibition and Convention Center (Shanghai) from Sunday through Friday. More than 3,400 exhibitors from around the world will take part in the expo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China to push for Gaza cease-fire as UN Security Council rotating president]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/03/content_003_6543fb4ced50d203d2ca1cc8.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/003/20231103_003_03_108.png&quot; />; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-03/003/20231103_003_03_42.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Zhang Jun, China&amp;#39;s permanent representative to the United Nations, introduces the work priorities of the country&amp;#39;s rotating presidency of the UN Security Council for November at a news conference at the UN headquarters in New York on Wednesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China assumed on Wednesday the rotating presidency of the United Nations Security Council for November with a focus on the Palestine-Israel conflict.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Palestine-Israel situation tops the Security Council&amp;#39;s agenda this month, said Zhang Jun, China&amp;#39;s permanent representative to the UN.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It is imperative to push for a cease-fire and halt the fighting, prevent further civilian casualties, prevent a larger-scale humanitarian disaster and prevent the conflict from spilling over,&amp;quot; he told reporters at a news briefing on the work of China&amp;#39;s presidency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The presidency of the Security Council rotates among its 15 members monthly. China last held the rotating presidency in August 2022.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The presidency for November comes amid the criticism the Security Council is facing for its perceived slow response to the ongoing Palestine-Israel conflict.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As of Thursday, the number of Palestinian casualties in the Gaza Strip had passed 9,000, according to the Hamas-run Health Ministry in Gaza. More than 1,400 people in Israel have lost their lives so far, most of them killed in the Oct 7 Hamas attack, Israeli authorities said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;As the rotating president of the Security Council, China will respond to the calls of the international community and work with all parties concerned to promote responsible and meaningful collective action by the council in a timely manner,&amp;quot; Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized that based on the current situation and tasks facing the Security Council and the expectations of all parties, China will &amp;quot;push the Security Council to take action, fulfill its responsibilities under the UN Charter, demonstrate its commitment, promote the easing of tensions and support diplomatic efforts&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We will urge the Security Council to focus on the root causes, look at the complex problem of the intertwining of the development deficit and the security deficit, and explore ways to solve it from a broader perspective,&amp;quot; Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We will also push the Security Council to improve its working methods, strengthen unity and cooperation, enhance its authority and efficiency, and respond more effectively to the current complex situation,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Security Council will also consider issues related to Syria, Yemen and Bosnia-Herzegovina this month, according to Zhang. It will take action on the UN assistance mission in Sudan, the UN mission in the Central African Republic and the extension of the authorization of sanctions on Somalia, as well as hold its annual regular dialogue with the commissioner of UN peacekeeping police, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Foreign Ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said on Thursday that China has always been a builder of world peace, a contributor to global development and a defender of the international order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China will firmly uphold the international system with the UN at its core, the international order underpinned by international law, and the basic norms governing international relations based on the purposes and the principles of the UN Charter,&amp;quot; he said at a regular news conference.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;minluzhang@chinadailyusa.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>