<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/<item><title><![CDATA[018TURKIYE SPECIAL - So much to gain from close ties, say experts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_018_652d995ded50d203d2ca0a93.htm#018TURKIYE SPECIAL]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/018/20231017_018_01_28.png&quot; />; &lt;p>;作为新兴市场代表市场观察人士和工商界领袖表示，中土两国加强贸易投资联系、扩大共同利益至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中土两国经济、文化等领域具有很强的互补性。中国社科院研究员任琳表示，两国在投资和服务贸易方面的依存度仍然较高。位于北京的国家全球战略研究院。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与货物贸易不同，服务贸易是指无形服务的销售和提供，例如交通、金融、旅游、电信、建筑、广告、计算机等&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《中国的“30-60”》碳目标、技术创新、产业转型和新数字经济的持续努力将为土耳其的增长提供动力。”任正非表示，两国应努力加强合作和多边主义，共同应对气候变化、经济韧性等全球性挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为实现高质量增长，中国采取了切实举措，推动绿色发展和绿色发展。高质量发展，走碳中和之路。国家提出了2030年二氧化碳排放达到峰值、2060年实现碳中和的宏伟目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国务院发展研究中心市场经济研究所研究员任兴洲便利的地理位置、快速的工业化发展速度、熟练的劳动力以及与全球企业的多元化商业联系将推动土耳其成为未来几年“一带一路”倡议快速发展的门户和贸易枢纽。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她表示，这一趋势将由中国和土耳其企业充分发挥产能和技术合作优势，挖掘服务业和新能源产业的商业潜力来推动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 江西江西省南昌市电动汽车生产商江铃集团电动汽车于9月中旬宣布，将于10月向土耳其交付300辆新能源汽车。中国汽车制造商的“逸”据该公司工程研究院副院长聂小勇介绍，出口土耳其的这款车型采用双电机，综合输出功率170千瓦，0-100公里/小时加速时间为5.8秒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据该公司与土耳其客户签署的合作协议，2024年至2026年间，土耳其合作伙伴将在土耳其设立专业销售团队和展示店，建设35个销售网络土耳其愿与中方一道，充分发挥两国政府间合作委员会作用，共建“一带一路”，加强经贸、科技等领域合作。土耳其外交部7月发布的信息显示，两国在能源、航空和旅游等领域合作，应对全球挑战，推动建立多极世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 渴望加强两国的商业联系，首届土中商务会议于 7 月中旬在伊斯坦布尔举行，100 多名土耳其和中国工商界人士参加了会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 土耳其工商协会董事会成员卡加泰·奥兹多格鲁 (Cagatay Ozdogru) ” 表示，在政治和经济不确定时期，先进技术从根本上改变了全球竞争规则，并补充说，土耳其年轻而充满活力的人口为中国提供了充足的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张先生则表示中国贸促会副会长少刚表示，人工智能、智慧城市、绿色科技、数字技术是中土两国应加强合作的潜在领域，并强调中方愿与土耳其加强合作。推动两国关系在互利共赢基础上迈向更高水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二届土中商务会议将于2024年在华举办，推动两国合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;” ；中国拥有发达、令人羡慕的基础设施。土耳其企业可以在人工智能、大数据、5G和高铁等领域开展合作，并与中国合作伙伴建立物理连接。”北京中国科学技术发展研究院副院长孙福全说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[018TURKIYE SPECIAL - Turkish Airlines leads the pack by investing in service and technology]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_018_652d995fed50d203d2ca0a94.htm#018TURKIYE SPECIAL]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/018/20231017_018_02_15.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;土耳其航空飞往目的地数量众多。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/018/20231017_018_02_19.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;该航空公司还船上提供优质厨师服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/018/20231017_018_02_18.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;招待发自内心的服务可以确保客人有宾至如归的感觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 土耳其航空成立于 1933 年，拥有五架飞机，现已发展成为全球领先的航空公司，拥有 419 架飞机（客运和货运），飞往全球 344 个目的地。凭借其广泛的网络以及连接两大洲的伊斯坦布尔枢纽的中心、战略和独特地位，土耳其航空飞往的目的地比世界上任何其他航空公司都多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为广受青睐的全球航空公司作为星空联盟成员，土耳其航空为经济舱和商务舱的乘客提供令人愉悦的不同旅行体验，并以其卓越的产品和服务而获得国际认可。为了保持竞争力并成为全球最受欢迎的航空公司，土耳其国家航空公司在服务质量、机上娱乐系统、舒适的座椅、美食、专属休息室及其员工方面进行了投资。作为欧洲先锋航空公司，土耳其航空始终走在航空业最新技术进步和创新的前沿，并拥有最年轻的机队之一。其总部伊斯坦布尔机场已准备好提供充分的条件来实现该航空公司的目标。凭借其无与伦比的服务、卓越的质量和可靠性，土耳其航空决心在竞争中保持领先地位，保持航空业的全球领先地位，同时继续致力于提供凭借其独特的功能和服务，为乘客提供最尊贵的旅行体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 土耳其航空&amp;#39;目前网络如下： 欧洲：43个国家122个目的地；中东：13个国家37个目的地；远东：22个国家47个目的地；北美和南美：9个国家23个目的地；非洲：41个国家62个目的地；国内：土耳其境内 53 个目的地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[019BUSINESS - Shanghai eyes glory in gene therapy biz]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_019_652d9962ed50d203d2ca0a95.htm#019BUSINESS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/019/20231017_019_01_15.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;展出的医疗机器人&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海市政府周一表示，其目标是大力推广基因治疗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该市将建设五个临床医学研究中心到2025年，建成20个基因治疗创新基地和平台，建成15个基因治疗骨干企业。技术创新与产业发展（2023-25）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是周一开幕的为期五天的2023上海国际生物医药产业周开幕式上公布的四项行动计划之一。&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>; 所有这些新政策都是为了加快上海建设具有国际影响力的生物医药创新中心。更大的目标是打造世界一流的生物医药产业集群。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “基础研究、关键核心技术、关键装备材料将成为上海生物医药创新的重点方向” ，”上海市政府副秘书长庄木弟在发布行动计划时表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “浦东新区张江细胞与基因产业园和闵行区浦江基因未来谷将成为实现目标的主要动力，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海市经济和信息化委员会的数据显示，近年来，该市在生物医药创新特别是基因治疗方面继续保持良好态势。 1月至8月，上海研发的首创创新药临床试验133项获得国家药监局批准。其中20个涉及细胞和基因治疗领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周一公布的另外三个行动计划涉及合成生物学创新、医疗机器人和生物医学智能制造领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 在医疗机器人领域，上海力争到2025年建成张江和大零湾两个产业集聚区，一个以设计研发为主，另一个以前沿创新和临床试验为主。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们的目标是打造10款创新型、世界一流的医疗机器人，打造手术、康复、辅助服务等10个可推广、可复制的应用示范场景。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “2019年以来，全国本土获批企业或实验室的首创创新药四分之一来自上海，本地创新医疗器械六分之一来自上海。”在国内注册的均来自上海。这座城市已经从创造和模仿的中心发展成为创新的领导者。一批新药、我国首个细胞治疗新药和世界一流医疗器械快速涌现。”上海市副市长陈杰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海生物医药领域的外资和本土民营经济都在增长。官方数据显示，今年1月至8月，该市共有23个生物医药领域新重大项目启动，总投资达55.8亿元人民币（7.63亿美元）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhouwenting@ chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[019BUSINESS - Briefly]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_019_652d9965ed50d203d2ca0a96.htm#019BUSINESS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; &lt;b>;9月份全社会用电量增长9.9%&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为经济活动重要晴雨表的中国用电量继续稳定增长周一官方数据显示，9月份。国家能源局表示，上月全社会用电量7811亿千瓦时，同比增长9.9%。第一产业用电量增长8.6%，第二、三产业用电量分别增长8.7%和16.9%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;网购指数呈上升趋势&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;中国物流与采购联合会表示，9月份电子商务物流运行指数为112.3点，环比上升1.2点。上月业务总量分类指数为123.9点，比8月份上升2.5点。 9月份满意度分类指数为101.5点，比8月份上升0.2点，连续第四个月呈上升趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[019BUSINESS - Chinese e-commerce, logistics powerhouses upping their game across Europe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_019_652d9968ed50d203d2ca0a97.htm#019BUSINESS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中国电商物流企业正加大在欧洲拓展配送网络、建设物流基础设施的力度，全面提升配送效率，维护产业链供应链稳定。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 中国电子商务巨头京东在欧洲的全渠道零售品牌 Ochama 最近宣布将其送货上门服务扩展到另外 19 个国家，该公司旨在扩大其在欧洲大陆的业务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ochama 于 2022 年 1 月首次在荷兰推出，提供融合线上和线下购物体验的零售模式。购物者可以通过Ochama的应用程序享受在线订购商品的便利，该应用程序提供食品、消费电子、美容、母婴产品等广泛的商品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 它提供两种选择上门服务和送货上门。此次扩张使 Ochama 的送货上门服务覆盖了 24 个国家/地区的网络，并与荷兰、卢森堡、比利时、法国和德国的现有服务进行了整合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 目前，Ochama 已建立了 500 多个提货点在欧洲设有 20,000 平方米的仓库，并在荷兰运营着一个 20,000 平方米的仓库，由 AGV（自动导引车）机器人提供动力，可显着提高分拣效率。所有订单都将在荷兰 Ochama 的自动化仓库进行包装，然后运送到最终目的地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “海外仓和快递网络是推动中国发展的重要基础设施” 39;跨境电商板块”国内咨询公司互联网经济研究院企业对企业和跨境活动高级分析师张周平表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 菜鸟网络是中国科技巨头阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司的物流部门，该公司还在加快建设物流网络并提升其在欧洲的服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该公司已扩大其在西班牙的最后一英里配送网络，在马德里和巴塞罗那等九个主要城市以及两个城市提供次日达服务。西班牙其他 20 多个城市提供当日送达服务。该配送网络得益于菜鸟对自动分拣中心和包裹储物柜等智能物流基础设施的投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该公司在马德里和巴塞罗那开发了一个由约 500 个包裹储物柜组成的网络，以提供更快、更快捷的服务。更高效、减少碳足迹的体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 顺丰航空是物流巨头顺丰速运的航空分公司，在提供航空货运服务和扩大其在欧洲的货机机队方面投入巨资。 7月，该公司开通了一条连接湖北省鄂州至德国法兰克福的新航空货运航线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海万庆咨询有限公司首席执行官陆振旺表示，公司正在努力投资海外仓和供应链&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，发展国际航空货运业务，有利于企业提升长途货运能力，进一步提高跨境货运能力。中国物流与采购联合会研究部副主任杨大庆表示，边境配送效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;fanfeifei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[019BUSINESS - Cooperative projects lead way for China and Turkiye to thrive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_019_652d996bed50d203d2ca0a98.htm#019BUSINESS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/019/20231017_019_04_20.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;土耳其参展商展位4月15日广交会。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/019/20231017_019_04_23.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一台起重机将一个集装箱释放到一列货运列车上，该列车将从天津开往土耳其。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着中国和土耳其进入绿色和创新引领增长的新时代，这一转型将为他们提供运力分析人士和商界领袖表示，“一带一路”倡议和土耳其的发展正在创造许多机遇。 39；中间走廊倡议。他们深化和多元化了双边商业合作和贸易渠道，为他们增强增长实力提供了自然选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中间走廊是一项旨在将土耳其通过格鲁吉亚、阿塞拜疆、土耳其与中国连接起来的倡议。里海，然后是哈萨克斯坦或土库曼斯坦、乌兹别克斯坦和吉尔吉斯斯坦。土耳其外交部公布的信息显示，它设想复兴古代丝绸之路，并与“一带一路”倡议形成天然的协同效应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 土耳其在丝绸之路经济带中的战略地位北京中国国际经济交流中心副首席经济学家张永军表示，作为欧洲、亚洲和中东的交汇点，将为其作为近年来发展势头强劲的区域交通枢纽的作用铺平道路。&lt;他表示，尽管近年来中国和土耳其经济受到全球商品需求疲软和地缘经济碎片化的影响，但两国在双边贸易中的相互依存程度仍然稳定。&lt;/p>;中国海关总署数据显示，受益于中土货物贸易结构互补和区域互联互通大项目，2022年中土贸易额同比增长12.8%，达到385.5亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据政府数据，2023年前8个月双边贸易持续增长势头，两国贸易额同比飙升14%，达到298.9亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 中国向土耳其出口的产品主要有光伏产品、智能手机、工程机械、制造设备、钢铁、电子和家用电器。海关数据显示，除矿产、贵金属、贱金属、化工产品和农产品外，土耳其向中国出口的产品还包括塑料、橡胶、家具、玩具、运输设备以及纺织服装产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;国家发改委综合交通研究所研究员冯浩表示，三年来，中欧班列显得更加重要。由于COVID-19停运期间空运和海运选择有限，货运列车在稳定全球供应链和产业链方面发挥了至关重要的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中欧班列也受益于土耳其&amp;#39他说，土耳其正在建设和完善铁路、基础设施和服务业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2020年土耳其和中国之间开通直达列车服务就是这种发展的一个例子。列车沿跨里海东西中部走廊经巴库-第比利斯-卡尔斯铁路。航线全长近8700公里，途经两大洲、两海、五个国家，从伊斯坦布尔到陕西西安，用时不到两周。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国中车&amp;#按销售收入计算，排名第 39 的最大轨道交通设备制造商，6 月开始在土耳其安卡拉生产无人驾驶高速地铁列车。该项目是中国在海外建设的首个时速120公里无人驾驶地铁项目，也是土耳其首个无人驾驶地铁项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 无人驾驶高速地铁列车由中国中车湖南省子公司中车株洲机车公司制造。中车株机公司副总经理廖洪涛介绍，这些列车最多可容纳1100名乘客。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 列车配备了符合国际最高标准的全自动操作系统。该系统消除了驾驶室，使列车能够执行启动、停止、乘客装载和维修操作等无人功能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，这些列车采用了全自动列车重连技术他说，提高编组过程的灵活性，满足乘客在一天中不同时间的不同需求。廖补充说​​，新开发的齿条控制牵引系统可以适应大坡道，使列车在运行时保持稳定的性能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 伊斯坦布尔机场地铁线是连接机场与机场的重要交通枢纽。市中心，是土耳其第一条高速地铁线。线路全长约34公里，日运量可达80万人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 廖表示，中国列车制造商注重与当地企业在各个阶段的合作和双赢伙伴关系，例如采购、制造、运营、维护等环节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “该列车制造项目本地化率达到60%。该项目除了创造约200个就业岗位外，还将直接拉动当地轨道交通产业的发展。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年6月，共有13家当地企业与中车株洲机车公司在土耳其签署了本地化采购协议。自2009年以来，该公司与地方政府、企业和社区合作，为伊斯坦布尔、安卡拉、伊兹密尔等城市提供了400多辆高端城轨车辆和服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 同样在6月，国家电力公司总部位于北京的国有企业投资公司宣布，装机容量为21兆瓦的土耳其胡努特鲁电厂光伏发电项目已于5月下旬并网发电。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 该项目运营方国家电投表示，该太阳能发电项目每年可提供约3339万千瓦时的清洁电力，相当于为6677户家庭供电。还将节省标准煤约10,179吨，减少污染物排放约27,789吨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 光伏发电项目将提升该地区的经济竞争力，同时降低站务用电率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国资委发布的信息显示，在全球绿色能源转型的大背景下，公司不断布局胡努特鲁电厂附属可再生能源发电产能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国家电投目前正在进行光伏项目二期、三期建设，旨在增加可再生能源装机容量，让电站更加绿色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[020WORLD - Access sought for aid to Gaza]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_020_652d996eed50d203d2ca0a99.htm#020WORLD]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/020/20231017_020_01_12.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦人搜寻被困幸存者周一，加沙地带汗尤尼斯一栋建筑在以色列空袭中被毁，废墟下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国际和人道主义组织恳求“立即无条件准入”。为加沙提供关键援助，以阻止危机迅速升级，目前流离失所者人数估计已突破 100 万——巴以暴力冲突已经过去 10 天了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据报道，清洁水、食物和其他重要物资即将耗尽，联合国发出呼吁，联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯表示不应将这些物资据美联社报道，世界卫生组织表示，包括为 30 万名患者提供服务的医疗用品在内的救生援助正在等待通过拉法过境点进入加沙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; 古特雷斯还敦促巴勒斯坦伊斯兰抵抗运动（哈马斯）释放其俘虏，以应对以色列迫在眉睫的地面入侵，以消灭该激进组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此举还迫使加沙 230 万人口中的一半被迫撤离。民众撤离家园。这个数字似乎正在上升——美联社报道称，以色列军方周一下令居住在黎巴嫩边境附近 28 个社区的居民撤离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 关于开放埃及与加沙地带的拉法边境的讨论在西部和中部地区盛行。东方传媒界。周一，半岛电视台报道称，在埃及安全部门消息人士称协议即将达成后，以色列和哈马斯均否认在加沙南部达成任何停火协议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 埃及国家信息服务处，该国的“国家信息服务中心”主要信息、意识和公共关系机构”周日发表文章称，拉法过境点是开放的，“但在以色列轰炸后无法使用”，并援引该机构外交部长 Sameh Shoukry 接受 CNN 的采访。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; 此外，埃及官员援引官员的话称，拉法过境点只能用于向巴勒斯坦人运送人道主义援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 双方死亡人数已突破 4,000 人，其中 14,000 多人受伤，1,000 多人受伤。失踪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;呼吁降级&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在加沙临时通知进行大规模疏散的情况下，要求降级局势的呼吁不断增加.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 联合国近东巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处总专员菲利普·拉扎里尼 (Philippe Lazzarini) 表示，他的机构“处于崩溃的边缘”。并不再能够提供人道主义援助。该机构正在寻求1.04亿美元的资金，用于向加沙提供救生援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国中央电视台周一称，中国正在向近东救济工程处和巴勒斯坦权力机构提供紧急人道主义援助。中央电视台援引中国国际发展合作署的话说，这些援助是为了缓解加沙的人道主义局势，解决食品和医疗等紧迫需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周日，阿联酋宣布向近东救济工程处在加沙地带的人道主义应对行动提供新捐款 2000 万美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 以色列计划在加沙开展地面行动，在边境部署大量部队和坦克，以“消灭哈马斯”引起了国际社会的质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据《阿拉伯新闻》和多家媒体报道，阿拉伯联盟和非洲联盟周日在一份联合声明中表示，这可能“导致前所未有的种族灭绝” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据半岛电视台报道，伊朗警告以色列，如果以色列军队进入加沙进行地面行动，与哈马斯的战争仍在继续，地区局势将升级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 美国总统乔·拜登，在哈马斯发动袭击后，他很快公开宣布支持以色列。 10 月 7 日发生的袭击事件，周日在接受哥伦比亚广播公司新闻采访时警告说，以色列再次占领加沙地带的任何举动“都将是一个大错误”，但他补充说，介入以消灭哈马斯武装分子是“必要的要求” ;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 路透社对此报道做出了贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jan@chinadailyapac.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[020WORLD - Briefly]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_020_652d9971ed50d203d2ca0a9a.htm#020WORLD]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; &lt;b>;阿富汗&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;中国捐赠抗震救灾物资抵达&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首批援助物资抵达阿富汗&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;中国政府捐赠的抗震救灾物资周日上午运抵阿富汗赫拉特国际机场，并移交阿方。包括帐篷和折叠床在内的救援物资已从机场的两架中国货机上卸下。本月早些时候，阿富汗西部发生了两次致命地震，每次震级为 6.3 级，随后又发生了几次余震，震中位于赫拉特省 Zanda Jan 地区，造成至少 1,000 人死亡，数千人受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;b>;美国&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;众议院准备在混乱的议长竞选中投票&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国众议院，过去两年陷入瘫痪周日，成员们被告知，共和党人之间的领导权斗争持续了数周，该委员会将于周二进行投票，这是选举议长的最新尝试。众议员吉姆·乔丹周五赢得了共和党提名，领导众议院，但这位强硬保守派似乎远远没有获得他夺取议长木槌所需的支持。由于发言人的缺席，导致商会无法就关键支出措施采取行动，也无法对国内和国际危机做出反应，会员们变得越来越沮丧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;厄瓜多尔&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &lt;b>;诺博亚赢得总统职位，承诺重建国家&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;厄瓜多尔总统候选人丹尼尔·诺博亚巩固了当选总统的地位，全国选举委员会（CNE）表示援引周日举行的总统决选的初步结果。随着90.78%的选票清点完毕，CNE宣布诺博亚赢得厄瓜多尔总统选举。 CNE 主席戴安娜·阿塔曼特 (Diana Atamaint) 确认选举结果“不可逆转”，并宣布诺博亚成为南美国家当选总统。周日，诺博亚告诉他西南部家乡奥隆的支持者，他的目标是“恢复和平……为年轻人带回教育”。并创造就业机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;希腊&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;移民船在岛上沉没后造成3人死亡&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两名男子希腊海岸警卫队称，一艘移民小艇周一在希腊东部岛屿海岸沉没，据报道失踪的人被发现还活着，使幸存者总数达到 10 人。已找到一名妇女和两名男子的尸体这艘小艇在土耳其附近的锡米小岛海岸过夜沉没后，早些时候从海上沉没。幸存者告诉当局，这艘船总共载有 13 人。尽管据报道没有更多人失踪，但海岸警卫队表示，作为预防措施，他们将继续在该地区进行几个小时的搜救行动，直到所有幸存者完成证词。船上人员的国籍目前尚不清楚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;波兰&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;反对派似乎将推翻执政的民族主义者&lt;/b>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; Poland&amp;#39;s ruling nationalists appeared on Monday to have lost their parliamentary majority in the nation&amp;#39;s most pivotal election in decades, potentially opening the way for opposition parties to seize power in what would be a huge political shift. An Ipsos exit poll published early on Monday gave the Law and Justice party 36.6 percent of the vote, which would translate into 198 lawmakers in the 460-seat lower house of parliament. Opposition parties, led by former European Council president Donald Tusk&amp;#39;s liberal grouping Civic Coalition, were projected to win a combined 248 seats, with Civic Coalition seen winning 31.0 percent of ballots cast.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[020WORLD - Closer ties between China and Thailand fuel development]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_020_652d9974ed50d203d2ca0a9b.htm#020WORLD]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/020/20231017_020_03_32.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; Fueled by complementary trade, joint interests and vast cooperation potential, closer economic and trade ties between China and Thailand will benefit the two countries in the long run, said analysts and business leaders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the two sides making notable progress in big-ticket projects &amp;mdash; including the China-Thailand Railway and a number of manufacturing and energy programs &amp;mdash; they said that enhanced business relations will create vitality and stability to ensure supply chains across the Asia-Pacific region and the world in years ahead.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to the tangible growth of the Belt and Road Initiative and the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership, as well as their complementary goods trade, China-Thailand trade grew by 3 percent year-on-year to $134.99 billion in 2022, data from China&amp;#39;s General Administration of Customs showed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The RCEP, the world&amp;#39;s largest free trade deal, covers 10 member states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations and its five free-trade agreement partners: China, Japan, South Korea, Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The implementation of this agreement will not only bring tariff cuts to Thai exporters, but encourage Chinese manufacturers to ship more goods to Thailand, said Hong Junjie, vice-president of the University of International Business and Economics in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to agricultural products, Thailand&amp;#39;s exports to China include rubber, chemicals, raw materials for plastic goods, data storage devices, automotive parts, integrated circuits and refined oil, according to customs statistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China ships mainly computers, telecommunication equipment, trains, diesel oil, steel, lighting products, medical equipment, textiles and household appliances to Thailand. Its passenger vehicles and trucks have also become popular in the Southeast Asian country in recent years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;With both countries pursuing green, high-quality and innovation-led growth, the two-way investment cooperation has expanded from sectors such as agriculture, energy, finance, infrastructure and manufacturing to other fast-growing areas,&amp;quot; said Bai Ming, deputy director of international market research at the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said these areas include trade in services, the production of electric vehicles, 5G, big data and cloud computing, with scientific and technological innovation acting as a driving force.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For instance, Chinese carmaker BYD is building a plant in Thailand. After its completion in 2024, vehicles manufactured from this factory will be sold nationally and exported to other Southeast Asian economies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Thailand has a solid base in the automotive industry with mature manufacturing capabilities, so we chose to build a factory here after careful deliberation,&amp;quot; said Liu Xueliang, general manager of BYD Asia-Pacific Auto Sales Division.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As China has created more favorable conditions for global companies to grow in its vast market, Thailand&amp;#39;s beverage company TCP Group announced in July that it added investment to its new production base in Nanning, the capital of South China&amp;#39;s Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region. The company is betting on the Chinese market for greater growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The move marked the Thai company&amp;#39;s expansion into the country and moved its total investment in the Chinese market to 3.3 billion yuan ($451 million) over the past two years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The new production base covers an area of about 90,000 square meters and is estimated to become one of the most important producers of TCP&amp;#39;s Red Bull energy drinks. Notably, it is equipped with four fully automatic production lines.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Saravoot Yoovidhya, CEO of TCP Group, said that the Chinese government has created a market-oriented and world-class business environment governed by a sound legal framework. Such efforts undoubtedly injected stronger impetus to the development of TCP Group and other multinational corporations in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China and Thailand are also deepening cooperation in the digital economy. For instance, their businesses are working together to develop digital projects such as &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; transportation, tourism and healthcare in Thailand. Meanwhile, cross-border e-commerce platforms have been introduced in the Southeast Asian nation so farmers can use them to sell their produce and increase their incomes, according to information released by the Beijing-headquartered China Council for the Promotion of International Trade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[020WORLD - Mistine embraces opportunities in Chinese market under BRI]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_020_652d9976ed50d203d2ca0a9c.htm#020WORLD]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/020/20231017_020_04_22.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Mistine offers a wide range of sun protection products in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following 35 years of success in Thailand, Mistine, a renowned cosmetic brand, has seized the opportunities presented by the Belt and Road Initiative to enhance trade relations between China and the countries and regions involved in it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mistine was founded in Thailand by Better Way (Thailand) Co in 1988. Better Way (Shenzhen) Cosmetics, a Chinese-Thailand joint venture, was established in 2016 to bring Mistine to Chinese consumers and contribute to the BRI.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Mistine, the brand initially launched in China on online platforms in 2016 and quickly expanded to offline channels, acquiring a significant market share.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Currently, Mistine products are distributed in more than 30,000 offline stores including Watsons, Sanfu, KKV and Colorist in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Over the past seven years, Mistine has garnered widespread acclaim from Chinese consumers. It has held the top position in terms of sales volume in the category of sunscreen for three consecutive years starting from 2021. This year, the brand announced that both its sales revenue and volume topped all other sunscreen products available in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Since entering the Chinese market, Mistine has been exploring brand development models suitable for the Chinese market. We have strengthened its brand strength through various means such as brand image change, core product launches, innovation and omnichannel expansion,&amp;quot; said Danai Derojanawong, president of Mistine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;At present, Mistine has become a cosmetics enterprise integrating sunscreen, skin care, cosmetics, perfume and aromatherapy in China,&amp;quot; said Derojanawong.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company said various factors have contributed to its development in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 1988, the brand has been focusing on research and development as it requires a lot of time and experience. That is why it has established a professional R&amp;amp;D team, supported by experts from all over the world recently. Mistine&amp;#39;s global R&amp;amp;D team is composed of five major scientific researchers who come from China, Thailand and Germany. Together, they push Mistine&amp;#39;s R&amp;amp;D system toward world-class scientific research and are committed to provide their consumers with higher-quality products.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Backed by a skilled R&amp;amp;D team, Mistine has achieved significant advancements in the study of sun protection and introduced the innovative technologies known as Solarcut, Smart Activation, Ultra-whitening and Bio-Genesis. Mistine said these cutting-edge technologies will not only repair sunburned skin but provide powerful anti-oxidation properties against light aging.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2023, the brand launched the upgraded version of its Aqua Base Ultra Protection Matte &amp;amp; Light Facial Sunscreen Pro in China, representing a significant breakthrough. The upgraded version incorporates Photobiology technology, developed by Arieh Washel, one of top scientists in the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Apart from evolving its offerings in China, the brand has made significant efforts to the establishment and enhancement of industry standards in the sunscreen sector. Collaborating with renowned testing and certification service provider SGS, Mistine has established a state-of-the-art lab dedicated to ensuring the quality of its sunscreen products. At the same time, Mistine launched the Sunscreen Cosmetics Industry Standardized Development Initiative with the Shanghai Pharmaceutical Industry Association&amp;#39;s Cosmetics Specialized Committee to promote the establishment of industry norms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The brand also demonstrates its expertise and compassion through various corporate social responsibility programs. In August, Tori Zhang, R&amp;amp;D director of Mistine China, and a team of experts from universities participated in a CSR program aimed at raising awareness about the importance of sun protection among children in the Tibet autonomous region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As Mistine looks to the future, it remains dedicated to strengthening its presence and commitment in China. This commitment includes continuous launch of new and high-quality products, driving innovation in the market and engaging in corporate social responsibility initiatives. Through these endeavors, Mistine is poised to create a brighter and more promising future for its customers and the communities it serves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[021CULTURE - An emotional journey]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/17/content_021_652d9979ed50d203d2ca0a9d.htm#021CULTURE]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/021/20231017_021_01_17.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Singer Gong Linna (third from the left) and her musician friends premiered her new album at the Temple of Heaven in Beijing on Oct 4.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-17/021/20231017_021_01_18.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Gong Linna&amp;#39;s new album features the story of a legendary ancient woman.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gong Linna started singing at the age of 5 in her hometown, Guiyang, Guizhou province in Southwest China. The musically versatile youngster enrolled to study folk music at the Chinese Conservatory of Music in Beijing at 16. She held her first solo concert in 1999. In 2000, she won the Chinese National Singing Competition as the best female singer and became a popular figure at various galas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Throughout her early career, the singer performed many Chinese folk songs, which are mostly high-pitched with cheerful style.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was not until after she graduated, and met music scholars in Amsterdam, that she learned about qinge, and became interested in the art form, which is a combination of Chinese guqin and vocal music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I met Frank Kouwenhoven and Antoinet Schimmelpenninck, who were studying Chinese music, in Amsterdam. They asked me why I didn&amp;#39;t sing qinge songs, and I realized that I had never really learned about the genre, though I had studied Chinese music for years,&amp;quot; recalls Gong. &amp;quot;Later I found out that qinge requires singers to match the playing of the guqin, which is quiet, ethereal and distant, totally different from the way I sing Chinese folk songs. I was intrigued.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With a history of more than 3,000 years, guqin, a plucked seven-stringed instrument, represents China&amp;#39;s foremost solo musical instrument tradition, and was added to the Representative List of the Intangible Cultural Heritage of Humanity by UNESCO in 2008.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Closely associated with guqin, qinge &amp;mdash; with qin referring to guqin and ge meaning song &amp;mdash; is an essential element of literati music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After working with guqin player Lin Chen, and Wang Hua, a bamboo flute and xiao player, on her first qinge album, Xian&amp;#39;ge Qingyun (Classical Qin Songs), in 2009, Gong recently released her second qinge album, by NCPA Classical Music Channel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Oct 4, Gong, and her musician friends, gave a concert, premiering the new album at the Divine Music Administration, which was first built in 1420, and is one of the five major structures at the Temple of Heaven, an imperial sacrificial altar. It was the highest ritual music academy for training and practicing imperial sacrificial music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Unlike her first qinge album, which featured classic songs played on the guqin, such as Yuge Diao (Fisherman Words), Yangguan Sandie (Parting for Yangguan) and Qiufeng Ci (Autumn Breezes), this new album, Song of the Barbarian Reed-Whistle in Eighteen Stanzas, presents a guqin piece written by Cai Wenji, a female poet and composer from the Han Dynasty (206 BC-AD 220).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Divided into 18 parts, the guqin piece expresses the composer&amp;#39;s emotion on her way back home 12 years after she was taken prisoner by the Xiongnu nomads, becoming a chieftain&amp;#39;s wife and bearing two children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the album, which was recorded in Beijing in February, Gong worked with Lin and Wang again. She also invited more friends, sheng player Nie Yunlei and percussionist Li Shang, to play with her.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Lin, the new album is quite different from Gong&amp;#39;s first qinge album, which sounded diverse and displayed the singer&amp;#39;s ability to master different music styles. This recording is of an independent work of great length, consisting of 18 parts and which takes around 40 minutes to perform in its entirety.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Song of the Barbarian Reed-Whistle in Eighteen Stanzas is rich in musical styles, incorporating elements of chanting and storytelling, making it highly dramatic,&amp;quot; says Lin. &amp;quot;Throughout the entire piece, the singer shifts between the third-person perspective to narrate the miserable living conditions during wartime, and a first-person perspective to express the emotions of Cai Wenji herself, such as the suffering of being exiled far from her homeland, the excitement of returning home and the inner struggle and dilemma of parting with her beloved children.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gong recalls that, when they recorded the first qinge album, the team spent a long time in Germany, where Gong lived with her husband, composer Robert Zollitsch. When they prepared for the new album, Gong invited Lin to live with her in the mountainous area of Yunnan province, where the musicians worked together on arranging the 18 parts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Without a conductor, we just improvised and figured out each part. For example, we used percussion to depict the scenes of war, and we used sheng to express power. Xiao and bamboo flute were used to create the feeling of ancient China,&amp;quot; says Gong. &amp;quot;Song of the Barbarian Reed-Whistle in Eighteen Stanzas has been in my heart for years. During the pandemic, my family and I were separated for a long time, and it was during that time that I felt a deep connection with Cai Wenji, her sorrow over life&amp;#39;s ups and downs and her love for her homeland.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The recording is yet another valuable exploration in the culture of ancient Chinese melodies,&amp;quot; says 78-year-old guqin master Wu Wenguang, a representative inheritor of the instrument and a senior professor at the China Conservatory of Music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Though Gong was trained to perform Chinese folk songs, the singer never stops pushing boundaries. In 2009, when she released a lyricless song Tante, or Perturbed in English, composed by her German husband, she soon became an internet sensation. With her powerful voice, wide vocal range and dramatic facial expressions, the song drew rave reviews.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Along with her husband, Gong has long been exploring the realm of &amp;quot;new Chinese art music&amp;quot;, which aims to preserve the essence of traditional Chinese folk music in new forms. The couple has adapted traditional Chinese poems into songs as well as making songs about the 24 Solar Terms, a traditional Chinese calendar that summarizes different seasonal phenomena.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This summer, Gong showcased her versatility as a veteran vocalist, seamlessly moving between pop and folk vocal techniques with her performance in Riding the Wind 2023, the fourth season of a reality show by Mango TV that aims to showcase women aged in their 30s to 50s.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writer at chennan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:52:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>