<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Ties elevated to all-weather partnership]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_001_650214e3ed50d203d2c9c3cb.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/001/20230914_001_01_162429.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平主席向委内瑞拉致意周三，正在北京进行国事访问的总统尼古拉斯·马杜罗·莫罗斯在人民大会堂举行会谈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国和委内瑞拉将两国关系提升为全天候战略伙伴关系。周三，各国同意推进共建“一带一路”，在经贸、教育、旅游、科技、卫生、航天、民航等领域合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席与委内瑞拉总统总统尼古拉斯·马杜罗·莫罗斯联合宣布提升两国的主权级别。双方在北京人民大会堂举行会谈后共同见证了协议的签署。两国发表关于建立全天候战略伙伴关系的联合声明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 马杜罗应习近平主席邀请对中国进行为期一周的国事访问。这次访问将持续到周四，这是他作为委内瑞拉总统第五次访华。习近平还访问了广东省深圳市、上海市、山东省。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 会谈中，习近平高度评价中委关系近年来的发展，表示两国关系正处在一个新的发展阶段。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他向马杜罗表示，中方始终从战略高度和长远角度看待中委关系，坚定支持委内瑞拉的努力维护国家主权、尊严和社会稳定，反对外部干涉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 双方要推动中委战略合作取得更多丰硕成果，为两国人民带来更多福祉为世界和平与发展注入更多正能量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平向马杜罗介绍了中国改革开放特别是经济特区建设情况。他表示，改革开放是中国大踏步赶上时代的重要抓手，是中国走向今天的关键举措。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国珍惜取得的宝贵经验”在此过程中，我们将继续推进改革开放。没有任何力量能够阻挡中国的进步和发展。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中方支持委内瑞拉建设经济特区，愿分享相关经验，助力委内瑞拉发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明年是两国建交50周年。习近平表示，中委建交期间，双方要加强人文交流，推进各领域务实合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中方愿进口更多优质、有特色的委内瑞拉产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 祝贺委内瑞拉成为拉美地区第一个加入中国发起的国际月球研究站项目的国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国要在月球等多边机制中密切合作。习近平指出，加强同联合国、77国集团加中国的团结合作，维护《联合国宪章》宗旨和原则，维护发展中国家共同利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中方高度重视中拉关系发展，愿与委内瑞拉等拉美国家一道，推动中国同地区整体合作，共同打造命运共同体。马杜罗表示，中国已成为致力于和平、发展和全人类福祉的伟大国家，成为推动新多极世界的重要引擎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，我对中国进行国事访问，将委中关系提升为全天候战略伙伴关系具有历史意义，将开启两国关系新时代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 委内瑞拉积极支持中国马杜罗表示，提出“一带一路”倡议、全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，愿同中方在联合国、联合国等多边框架内密切沟通与合作。委内瑞拉在联合声明中重申加入金砖国家的兴趣，中方欢迎委内瑞拉的积极意愿并支持其努力&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - 10 paintings from Africa on display at Tiangong]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_001_650214e6ed50d203d2c9c3cc.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/001/20230914_001_02_57429.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;中国航天员景海鹏 (周三，朱阳柱（右）和桂海潮在天宫空间站通过视频连线向北京观众介绍非洲青年创作的十幅获奖画作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;非洲青年正在展示从宇宙前所未有的角落可以实现什么远大的梦想——天宫空间站。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些作品是通过以“我的梦想”为主题的竞赛评选出来的，该竞赛收到了来自42个非洲国家的2000多件参赛作品。它们现正在中国空间站首届国际艺术展上展出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周三在北京举行的颁奖仪式上，正在天宫执行任务的三名宇航员向空间站介绍了这10幅画作。观众，包括获奖者和参与者，通过空间站录制的视频通话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 宇航员朱扬柱展示了其中两幅画作——第一个来自尼日利亚，题为“共同的愿望”；另一个来自埃及，题为“中国是非洲实现太空梦想的希望”。后者中，一名非洲宇航员在另一个星球上与一名中国宇航员握手，背景是地球，可以清楚地看到中国和非洲大陆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “你的画展示了非洲青年对载人航天事业的热情，让我对未来中非航天合作充满信心。”朱说。 “探索未知宇宙、发展太空技术是人类的共同事业，离不开包括非洲在内的世界各国的合作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 另一幅名为“L”的画作;统一，来自马里，展示了彩色布片被缝在一起，象征着和平与团结。朱镕基说，这一理念是“消除分歧和裂痕，共同建设和平、美丽的世界”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 本次比赛由论坛中方后续行动委员会秘书处联合主办。中非合作与中国载人航天工程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 颁奖仪式上，肯尼亚内罗毕大学孔子学院四年级学生凯伦·切贝特 (Caren Chebet) 与来自九个非洲国家的青年一起参加了颁奖仪式。 ”飞入太空。她表示，通过学习和合作中国的太空探索技术，非洲人很快将在太空中看到的不仅仅是他们的画作，还有他们自己。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;切贝特对中国给年轻人带来希望表示衷心感谢非洲人，包括像她这样的女孩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jianchanglong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - PROVINCE SETS ITS SIGHTS FIRMLY ON THE FUTURE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_001_650214e9ed50d203d2c9c3cd.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/001/20230914_002_01_78246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;船舶通过船闸四月的三峡大坝。过去五年，大坝年货运量突破亿吨。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09- 14/001/20230914_002_01_27246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;湖北省省会武汉市一家智能工厂的生产线上，工人们正在操作机器。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com .cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/001/20230914_002_01_61246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;湖北荆州码头的货船上正在卸煤。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https ://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/001/20230914_002_01_44246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一列高速列车穿过荆州一座新的钢梁桥。 11月完成大梁安装。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/001/20230914_002_01_101246.png&quot; />; &lt;p >; 背景中矗立着一排建筑物，阳光照耀在整洁的道路上，旁边是郁郁葱葱的草坪和新种植的树苗，这些树苗通过木支架固定在地面上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 乍一看，这似乎只是另一个典型的例子在中国很多地区都可以看到新建的办公大楼。但穿着安全背心和头盔的工作人员、冒着白烟的烟囱和高高耸入空中的管道，提醒游客进入了一家化工厂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于枝江姚家港化工园区，该工厂位于湖北省宜昌市，是当地企业湖北三宁化工有限公司的生产基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该基地年产60万吨乙二醇，采用智能技术支持，包括5G。乙二醇用作防冻剂​​，用于制造聚酯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 负责搭建该智能系统的该公司员工杨文华表示，借助这些技术，工厂显着提高了生产的安全性和效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 智能系统还有助于减少有害副产品的形成量——杨说，这使得整个制造过程更加环保。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该公司是该工业园区内 108 家运营企业之一，该园区成立于 2008 年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;负责监管该园区的枝江高新区管委会表示，园区内大多数企业过去主要专注于生产化肥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 夏说，现在，它们已扩展到新材料和生物医药等领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 园区拥有完善的供应链，一些企业生产的产品甚至副产品可以成为其他企业的原材料。夏说，这反过来又降低了物流和处理成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 园区计划吸引更多优质、有竞争力的企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们对想要入驻园区的企业，要从五个方面进行评估——他们的安全、环境友好、能源消耗、利润和投资，”夏说，园区已经拒绝了很多不合格的候选人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 园区的发展是宜昌这个曾经严重依赖化工产业的长江城市如何实现转型的生动例子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席在不同场合强调保护长江的重要性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2016年在重庆召开的加强长江流域治理座谈会上在长江经济带发展中，习近平强调，恢复长江生态环境是压倒性的重要任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两年后，2018年在湖北考察时，习近平在宜昌讲话时指出，经济带建设要科学有序，发展不能破坏环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;改善长江环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 长江周边1公里范围内130多家化工企业已被关闭或搬迁，同时采取严格措施确保废水得到妥善处理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当地化工企业兴发集团总经理助理陈晓庆表示，该工厂已关闭排入长江的废水排放口。这些废水现在被送往政府建造的污水处理厂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在被污水处理厂接收之前，废水必须按照政府的要求进行处理，陈说，政府的要求“非常高”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 陈先生表示，为了满足这些要求，公司花费了大量资金对设备进行升级改造。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是一个“相当痛苦”的过程。最初是流程，现在是公司“最大的核心能力”陈补充道，“关键是减少环境影响的能力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于湖北西部的宜昌的故事说明了当局为改善该省的增长方式和追求高增长所做的努力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 湖北日报报道，今年初，湖北省印发《关于进一步推进化工产业发展的指导意见》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 省政府在《指导意见》中表示，全省化工企业要生产优质原材料，攻克技术难题，提供高端和紧缺产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 严禁在自然保护区等地方设立化工园区。政府表示，全省化工园区安全生产三年行动计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;经济驱动力&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除了努力提高化工行业的绩效外，湖北当局还努力发展其他传统产业，例如汽车湖北是重要的汽车制造基地。 2021年，湖北省汽车产量约210万辆，占全国汽车产量的8%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着新能源汽车在中国的发展，湖北省的发展势头越来越强劲。新能源汽车和智能汽车是该省重点发展的五个新兴产业之一，旨在将其打造成创新中心和制造基地，以进一步提升竞争力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多家新能源汽车企业和电池制造商该省的目标是到明年将新能源汽车产业的产值提高到 3000 亿元人民币（410 亿美元）以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些公司包括襄阳腾龙汽车有限公司、该公司于2017年在湖北北部的襄阳市开始运营，生产新能源客车和多用途汽车。公司总部位于江苏省。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 腾龙股份副总经理周生明表示，公司选择襄阳是因为这座城市良好的营商环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当地他说，政府非常支持，公司享受税收和土地使用方面的优惠政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这座城市还为汽车企业提供了稳定的供应链。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 汽车已经在中国制造襄阳四十年，汇聚了数百家汽车生产企业和汽车零部件工厂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 10年来，襄阳始终与新能源汽车产业同步发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; 2013年，中央公布了包括襄阳在内的28个城市和地区支持推广新能源汽车的名单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021年，襄阳制定了汽车产业转型行动计划，并决定设立推广新能源汽车专项资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周先生说，他的公司用于制造车辆的所有汽车零部件中，60％至70％是由襄阳或湖北其他地区的公司提供的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; “你可以在这里购买你想要的所有汽车零部件，”他补充说，他的公司现在每年生产和销售 4,000 至 5,000 辆汽车。其中约15%出口到印度尼西亚、马来西亚和埃及等国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 襄阳决心发展新能源汽车产业的另一个例子是新能源汽车制造商开设电池工厂比亚迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年1月，市政府与比亚迪签署协议，并采取一系列措施，为工厂早日开业铺平道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 建设工厂工厂于去年4月开工，12月第一条生产线投产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比亚迪电池子公司张达达表示，如此快的节奏体现了高水平。襄阳市政府对新能源汽车产业高度重视。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除襄阳外，湖北省其他几个城市也被纳入该省进一步壮大汽车产业的战略。&lt;/p>; &lt;正在着力打造贯穿东南西北、覆盖武汉、孝感、随州、襄阳、十堰等城市的“汽车产业走廊”。目标是使这些城市成为全国的汽车生产基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 湖北还计划通过引入人工智能、大数据等新兴技术来增强汽车产业。湖北省拥有便捷的交通运输传统优势，在发展汽车等各产业方面具有竞争优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 湖北航空、铁路、公路、水运网络交织，使湖北省&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说，比亚迪在襄阳设立电池工厂的一个重要原因是，该市的地理位置可以方便地到达大多数其他省份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为抓住更多发展机遇，湖北正致力于成为国际交通枢纽。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年7月，湖北鄂州市花湖机场开业。主要起降货运航班，省政府希望将机场打造成内陆自由贸易港。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一年来，机场已开通飞往比利时列日等8个海外目的地的货运航班；印度金奈；德国法兰克福；截至7月中旬，省政府与顺丰速运共建的机场已累计起降国际航班203架次，运送旅客8700余人次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鄂州市常务副市长于克表示，作为提高机场竞争力的措施的一部分，该市正在邀请主要货运航空公司、国际物流公司和货运公司&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 余在4月份的新闻发布会上表示，当地政府还鼓励以花湖机场为基地的航空公司在海外建立货运基地，加强与主要国际航空货运枢纽的合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们希望通过这种方式打造一条高效的新空中丝绸之路，扩大世界贸易”。于说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者wangqingyun@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China&#39;s drive to modernize boosts global supply chains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_001_650214eced50d203d2c9c3ce.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中国建设现代产业体系将帮助世界更好应对未来供应链可能出现的干扰，保障世界经济在挑战和不确定性中平稳运行经济学家和企业高管表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们指出，产业脱钩给全球经济复苏带来巨大风险，他们表示，中国对跨国公司具有巨大吸引力，因为中国拥有完整的供应链支撑体系、强大的物流体系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “现代产业体系”是指现代产业体系。 “一带一路”已成为中国的一个关键词，最高领导层强调，这是国家经济发展的优先任务、支撑现代化建设的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席强调，现代产业体系是现代国家的物质技术基础。他还指出，经济发展的重点要放在实体经济上，为实现第二个一百年奋斗目标，把我国建设成为富强民主文明的社会主义现代化国家提供坚实的物质支撑。到2049年，中华人民共和国将迎来百年华诞，和谐美好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主任&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央政治局在7月下旬的一次会议上也表示：当务之急是进一步推进产业体系现代化，培育壮大战略性新兴产业，发展更多支柱产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 波士顿咨询集团全球名誉主席汉斯-保罗·伯克纳表示推进工业现代化的努力将有助于中国向价值链高端迈进，使经济呈现“创新型、人才密集型、消费驱动型、绿色型”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这样的转型将有助于中国保持领先地位。伯克纳表示，在地缘政治紧张局势以及将生产迁回发达国家等不利因素的背景下，中国在全球供应链中占据重要地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 美中贸易全国委员会主席克雷格·艾伦表示，中国“是一个”，因为该国的规模激励了美国公司，而且其生态系统通过基础设施和人才投资得到了极大加强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Isabel Ge Mahe，副总裁苹果大中华区董事总经理兼苹果公司大中华区董事总经理表示，“过去30年，中国供应商成长得非常快，成为我们供应链中不可或缺的、特别重要的一部分。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 苹果很高兴她表示，尽管有外媒报道称该公司正在考虑将部分 iPhone 生产转移到印度，但愿意推动中国向智能制造转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年，苹果推出了 50 美元的 iPhone百万供应商员工发展基金，为供应商员工提供自动化和先进制造技术培训，包括编程和机器人技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在美国政府极力推动脱钩的半导体行业，美国芯片公司英特尔公司首席执行官帕特里克·基辛格(Patrick Gelsinger)今年迄今已三次访问中国，他表示：“中国在英特尔业务中发挥着极其重要的作用。”战略。公司与中国合作伙伴和客户建立了长达近40年的长期合作关系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月下旬，英特尔与广东省深圳市南山区政府启动了英特尔大计划湾区创新中心，专注人工智能、芯片应用等技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 外资企业背后热情在于中国拥有世界上最齐全的工业体系。据工信部统计，2022年，中国连续13年成为全球第一制造大国，制造业产值占全球近30%。&lt;/工信部表示，已有570多家中国工业企业进入全球研发投入250​​0强，支撑供应链能力不断增强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，银行和金融服务集团发布的一份报告显示，中国向价值链上游迈进，中国正在成为其他地方制造商使用的中间产品的出口国，而不是进口国，这有助于加强互联互通，从而提高全球供应链的竞争力汇丰银行今年早些时候的数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 报告称，在亚洲，来自中国大陆的中间产品进口目前平均占所有零部件进口的近 20%。此外，东南亚国家联盟的出口商越来越依赖中国大陆的零部件，而不是其他来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，中国在半导体等关键技术方面仍面临瓶颈，需要付出更多努力来推动专家表示，要迈向更绿色、更智能、更高端的制造业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 著名经济学家、哥伦比亚大学可持续发展中心主任杰弗里·萨克斯表示：“中国现在的实力的一点是，它处于未来许多最重要技术创新的最前沿，这对未来中国的制造业非常有利。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 证据已经存在清除。中国在全球灯塔网络名单中占据主导地位，该项目由世界经济论坛与麦肯锡咨询公司于 2018 年合作推出。 Co 追踪应用最先进数字技术的先进制造工厂，即灯塔工厂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 迄今为止，中国拥有 50 家此类灯塔工厂，是数量最多的国家，占占全球三分之一以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国社会科学院院长黄群辉经济研究所表示，制造业是创新活动最多的领域，中国在基础材料、制造工艺、软件等领域的工业实力还需要付出更多努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Denis Depoux咨询公司罗兰贝格全球董事总经理表示：“中国产业集群的质量和深度、灵活性以及快速让大量人员投入工作并推出消费电子新产品的能力，瑞士工业公司 Georg Fischer 首席执行官安德烈亚斯·穆勒 (Andreas Mueller) 表示，尽管许多人在“谈话”中讨论供应链多元化，但它们都令人印象深刻，无法轻易替代。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在水平上，需要看看在“行走”过程中发生了什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 4月下旬，GF在江苏扬州和辽宁沉阳的两家工厂举行了开业仪式。此举体现了格芯对中国的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们在中国感到宾至如归”，”穆勒说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;masi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - PROVINCE SETS ITS SIGHTS FIRMLY ON THE FUTURE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_002_650214eced50d203d2c9c3cf.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/002/20230914_002_01_78246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;船舶通过船闸四月的三峡大坝。过去五年，大坝年货运量突破亿吨。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09- 14/002/20230914_002_01_27246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;湖北省省会武汉市一家智能工厂的生产线上，工人们正在操作机器。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com .cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/002/20230914_002_01_61246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;湖北荆州码头的货船上正在卸煤。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https ://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/002/20230914_002_01_44246.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一列高速列车穿过荆州一座新的钢梁桥。 11月完成大梁安装。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/002/20230914_002_01_101246.png&quot; />; &lt;p >; 背景中矗立着一排建筑物，阳光照耀在整洁的道路上，旁边是郁郁葱葱的草坪和新种植的树苗，这些树苗通过木支架固定在地面上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 乍一看，这似乎只是另一个典型的例子在中国很多地区都可以看到新建的办公大楼。但穿着安全背心和头盔的工作人员、冒着白烟的烟囱和高高耸入空中的管道，提醒游客进入了一家化工厂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于枝江姚家港化工园区，该工厂位于湖北省宜昌市，是当地企业湖北三宁化工有限公司的生产基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该基地年产60万吨乙二醇，采用智能技术支持，包括5G。乙二醇用作防冻剂​​，用于制造聚酯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 负责搭建该智能系统的该公司员工杨文华表示，借助这些技术，工厂显着提高了生产的安全性和效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 智能系统还有助于减少有害副产品的形成量——杨说，这使得整个制造过程更加环保。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该公司是该工业园区内 108 家运营企业之一，该园区成立于 2008 年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;负责监管该园区的枝江高新区管委会表示，园区内大多数企业过去主要专注于生产化肥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 夏说，现在，它们已扩展到新材料和生物医药等领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 园区拥有完善的供应链，一些企业生产的产品甚至副产品可以成为其他企业的原材料。夏说，这反过来又降低了物流和处理成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 园区计划吸引更多优质、有竞争力的企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们对想要入驻园区的企业，要从五个方面进行评估——他们的安全、环境友好、能源消耗、利润和投资，”夏说，园区已经拒绝了很多不合格的候选人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 园区的发展是宜昌这个曾经严重依赖化工产业的长江城市如何实现转型的生动例子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席在不同场合强调保护长江的重要性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2016年在重庆召开的加强长江流域治理座谈会上development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt, Xi stressed that this is an overwhelmingly important task to restore the river&amp;#39;s ecology and the environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two years later, during an inspection visit to Hubei in 2018, Xi said in Yichang that the economic belt should be developed in a scientific and orderly manner, and this development must not undermine the environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Inspired by Xi&amp;#39;s words, the authorities in Yichang launched strenuous efforts to improve the environment of the Yangtze.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than 130 chemical companies located within 1 kilometer of the river have been closed or relocated, while stringent measures have been taken to ensure wastewater is properly treated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Xiaoqing, assistant general manager of Xingfa Group, a local chemical company, said the factory has closed its wastewater outlets into the Yangtze. The wastewater is now sent to a government-built sewage treatment plant.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before being accepted by the plant, the wastewater must be treated according to government requirements, which Chen said are &amp;quot;very high&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said that to meet these requirements, the company spent a large amount on upgrading its equipment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This was a &amp;quot;rather painful&amp;quot; process at first, but now the company&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;greatest core competency&amp;quot; is the ability to reduce its environmental impact, Chen added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The story of Yichang, located in western Hubei, illustrates the efforts made by the authorities to improve the province&amp;#39;s growth pattern and pursue high-quality development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hubei Daily reported that earlier this year, Hubei issued a guideline to further advance its chemical industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The provincial government said in the guideline that chemical companies in the province should manufacture high-quality raw materials, and work to overcome technical challenges to provide high-end products and those that are in short supply.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is strictly forbidden to set up chemical industrial parks in places such as nature reserves, source water conservation areas, and areas within 1 km of the Yangtze River, the government said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The government also issued a three-year action plan to improve safety at chemical industrial parks in the province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Economic drivers&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to working to improve the performance of the chemical industry, the authorities in Hubei are striving to advance other traditional industries, such as the automobile sector, to achieve better growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hubei is a major automobile manufacturing base. In 2021, about 2.1 million vehicles were produced in the province, accounting for 8 percent of China&amp;#39;s total.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As the new energy vehicle, or NEV, industry gains ever stronger momentum in China, Hubei is looking to turn itself into an innovation hub and manufacturing base for new energy and smart vehicles, one of five emerging industries the province aims to promote to further hone its competitiveness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A number of NEV companies and battery makers are operating in the province, which has set a goal of raising the value of its new energy vehicle industry to more than 300 billion yuan ($41 billion) by next year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These companies include Xiangyang Tenglong Automobile Co, which began operating in Xiangyang city in northern Hubei in 2017 to produce new energy buses and multipurpose vehicles. The company is headquartered in Jiangsu province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Shengming, deputy general manager of Tenglong, said the company chose Xiangyang because of the city&amp;#39;s welcoming business environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The local government is very supportive, and the company enjoys preferential tax and land use policies, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The city also provides a steady supply chain for car companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Automobiles have been made in Xiangyang for four decades, and the city is home to several hundred car manufacturers and auto parts factories.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Over the past 10 years, Xiangyang has kept pace with growth of the NEV industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2013, the central government released a list of 28 cities and regions, including Xiangyang, to support in promoting the use of NEVs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2021, Xiangyang drew up an action plan to transform its automobile industry, and decided to establish a special fund for promoting NEVs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou said of all the auto parts his company uses to make vehicles, 60 to 70 percent are provided by companies in Xiangyang or other areas of Hubei.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;You can buy all the auto parts you want here,&amp;quot; he said, adding that his company now produces and sells 4,000 to 5,000 vehicles a year. Some 15 percent of them are exported to countries such as Indonesia, Malaysia and Egypt.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another example of Xiangyang&amp;#39;s determination to boost its NEV industry is the launch of a battery factory by new energy vehicle manufacturer BYD.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The city government signed an agreement with BYD in January last year, and adopted a series of measures to pave the way for the early opening of the factory.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Construction of the plant started in April last year, and its first production line went into operation in December.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Dada, an employee at BYD&amp;#39;s battery-making subsidiary, said such a fast pace demonstrates the high level of importance the Xiangyang government places on the NEV industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to Xiangyang, several other cities in Hubei are included in the province&amp;#39;s strategy to further reinforce its automobile industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is working on establishing an &amp;quot;automobile industry corridor &amp;quot;running southeast to northwest and covering the cities of Wuhan, Xiaogan, Suizhou, Xiangyang and Shiyan. The aim is to make these cities an automobile production base for the whole country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hubei also plans to strengthen the automobile industry by introducing emerging technologies, including artificial intelligence and big data. The province has a traditional advantage in convenient transportation links, giving it a competitive edge in developing various industries, including the automobile sector.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The interwoven network of air routes, railways, highways and waterways in Hubei make the province a transportation hub connecting east and west, and north and south.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang said an important reason for BYD opening its battery factory in Xiangyang is that the city&amp;#39;s location makes it easy to reach most other provinces in the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To seize more opportunities for growth, Hubei is aiming to become an international transportation hub.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In July last year, Huahu Airport opened in Ezhou city, Hubei. It mainly handles cargo flights, and the provincial authorities hope to make the airport an inland free-trade port.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One year on, the airport has launched cargo flights to eight overseas destinations, including Liege, Belgium; Chennai, India; Frankfurt, Germany; and Los Angeles and New York in the United States.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As of mid-July, the airport, jointly constructed by the provincial government and delivery and logistics company SF Express, had handled 203 international flights carrying more than 8,700 tons of cargo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Ke, executive vice-mayor of Ezhou, said that as part of measures to increase the airport&amp;#39;s competitiveness, the city is inviting major cargo airlines, international logistics companies and freight forwarders to base themselves at the facility.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu said at a news conference in April that the local government also encourages airlines based at Huahu Airport to establish cargo bases overseas and strengthen their cooperation with major international air cargo hubs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In this way, we hope to create a highly efficient new Silk Road in the air to expand world trade,&amp;quot; Yu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at wangqingyun@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Beijing plays constructive role for better global governance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_003_650214efed50d203d2c9c3d0.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Beijing has said a document just released by the country&amp;#39;s Foreign Ministry focuses on key areas of global governance reform and testifies to China&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;constructive role in international affairs&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Foreign Ministry issued on Wednesday a comprehensive document titled &amp;quot;The Proposal of the People&amp;#39;s Republic of China on the Reform and Development of Global Governance&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Observers noted that the document was released amid the ongoing 78th session of the United Nations General Assembly, which opened on Sept 5. The general debate of the UN General Assembly will take place from Sept 19 to 26.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The document elaborated on China&amp;#39;s positions and detailed propositions in key areas of global governance such as peace and security, development, human rights and society.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It also addressed some new frontiers in global governance as well the reform of multilateral institutions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On specific hot spot issues, the document said that Beijing &amp;quot;firmly supports a political settlement of the Ukraine crisis&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;all efforts conducive to a peaceful settlement of the crisis should be supported&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China welcomes the New Agenda for Peace presented by UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, and &amp;quot;is ready to have further discussions and build consensus with all parties&amp;quot;, the document said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Commenting on Beijing&amp;#39;s solutions for global issues, the document called on the international community to jointly implement the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative and the Global Civilization Initiative &amp;mdash; three major visions put forward by President Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It also asked countries to &amp;quot;jointly build a community with a shared future for mankind&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning said the document &amp;quot;demonstrates China&amp;#39;s sense of responsibility as a major country and its constructive role in international affairs&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By releasing the document as the 78th UN General Assembly session gets underway, China is contributing its ideas to global governance reform, Mao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Experts said that China&amp;#39;s active role in improving global governance does not eye narrow-minded geopolitical competition but the common good of the whole of mankind.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;What Beijing looks to is better governance in various countries, better livelihood of the peoples, greater impetus for the economic recovery in the post-pandemic era,&amp;quot; said Su Xiaohui, deputy director of the Department of American Studies at the China Institute of International Studies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Also, China is working hard on expanding the lineup of international public goods for tackling global issues such as climate change, as well as for providing more and better solutions for hot spot security issues, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mao, the spokeswoman, pointed out that the current international situation is chaotic, and various global challenges are emerging one after another.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The international community is looking to the UN to play an active role in international affairs and make new progress in reforming and improving the global governance system,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ongoing session of the UN General Assembly presents an important opportunity for the international community to build on political consensus, enhance solidarity and cooperation and work together to meet challenges, the spokeswoman said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Poetry as art]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_003_650214f2ed50d203d2c9c3d1.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/003/20230914_003_02_50463.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Visitors to the Zhejiang Museum of Art admire famous poet Su Shi&amp;#39;s work, Record on the Pavilion of the Old Drunkard, depicted through rubbings, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province, on Wednesday. Su Shi was a poet, calligrapher, essayist, gastronomer, pharmacologist, politician and travel writer who lived during the Song Dynasty (960-1279).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Spokesman: Military collusion worsens situation for Taiwan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_003_650214f5ed50d203d2c9c3d2.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; A Chinese mainland spokesman voiced strong opposition on Wednesday to recent frequent military collusion between the United States and Taiwan to strengthen the island&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;defense &amp;quot;capabilities, saying that such moves only serve to increase the dangers faced by the island.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Binhua, spokesman for the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council, said at a news conference in Beijing that since Taiwan&amp;#39;s Democratic Progressive Party came to office in 2016, the island&amp;#39;s arms purchases from the US and its defense budget have risen year by year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Taiwan&amp;#39;s defense budget for 2024 has touched a record high of NT$606.8 billion ($18.98 billion), almost doubling over the past eight years. Taiwan was also the largest buyer of US weapons from 2020 to 2022, according to the spokesman.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last month, the US approved the potential sale to Taiwan of arms at an estimated cost of $500 million, as well as new military aid for the island worth up to $80 million.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said that the DPP&amp;#39;s insistence on pushing for &amp;quot;Taiwan independence&amp;quot; by relying on the US has jeopardized the interests of the Taiwan people and also undermined peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The mounting debt caused by the increasing arms purchases only serves to make the people of Taiwan more anxious,&amp;quot; he said, adding that the DPP could never alter the mainland&amp;#39;s firm will to achieve the complete reunification of the motherland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The spokesman also condemned the DPP authorities for putting forward the so-called &amp;quot;four requests on Taiwan&amp;#39;s participation in the United Nations&amp;quot; as the 78th session of the UN General Assembly began last week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The DPP authorities also claimed that they would invite &amp;quot;diplomatic allies&amp;quot; to submit a joint letter to the UN secretary-general, urging him to rectify the UN&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;misinterpretation&amp;quot; of the UN General Assembly Resolution 2758.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said the 26th session of the UN General Assembly adopted Resolution 2758 with an overwhelming majority in 1971 which made it clear that there can only be one seat representing China at the UN, and no issues exist about the so-called &amp;quot;two Chinas&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;one China, one Taiwan&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Taiwan has no right to join the UN,&amp;quot; he said, adding that by challenging the basic principles of international relations and the consensus of the international community year after year, the DPP only makes it clearer to the world that Taiwan is an integral part of China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyi1@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Chen has lengthy experience working in Taiwan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_003_650214f8ed50d203d2c9c3d3.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Chen Binhua, a former reporter with lengthy experience working in Taiwan, made his debut on Wednesday as a spokesman for the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At a news conference in Beijing, Chen, who became the deputy director of the information bureau of the Taiwan Affairs Office earlier this year, greeted reporters from both sides of the Strait in Mandarin and Hokkien, a dialect which is spoken in Fujian province and Taiwan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen, 51, is from Zhao&amp;#39;an, a county in Zhangzhou in southern Fujian. After graduating from the department of Chinese language and literature at Xiamen University, he joined Xinhua News Agency in 1993.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2001, as part of the first group of journalists from the mainland, he went to Taiwan on a one-month reporting trip. On arriving at the airport in Taiwan, Chen greeted the crowd in fluent Hokkien, making a deep impression on the local media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During his stay in Taiwan, Chen was famous for engaging in a heated debate with the then-deputy director of Taiwan&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;mainland affairs council &amp;quot;during a news conference in September 2001. He questioned the accuracy of the spokesman&amp;#39;s hostile speech about the mainland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In later years, he traveled around the island and wrote several books, including Enjoy Taiwan, sharing his experiences on the island.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Through exchanges with people from various sectors and places in Taiwan, I have gained a comprehensive understanding of their work, daily lives and thoughts. This has provided me with deeper insights into the Taiwan question,&amp;quot; Chen said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It will be helpful for me in my role as the spokesman to effectively introduce the mainland&amp;#39;s policies to Taiwan, using expressions that our compatriots, especially those in Taiwan, are willing to listen to and can understand.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Commenting on the recent deterioration in the cross-Strait relations, Chen said he believes that as long as the people on both sides work together, the &amp;quot;spring&amp;quot; of extensive exchanges and development across the Strait will arrive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After joining the Taiwan Affairs Office, Chen served as deputy director of the research bureau, and later moved to the position of deputy director of the economic bureau.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Taiwan Affairs Office has had eight spokespersons, including the current spokespersons Zhu Fenglian and Chen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - FM: No policy issued to ban purchase, use of iPhones]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_003_650214faed50d203d2c9c3d4.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; The Foreign Ministry said on Wednesday that China has not issued any law, regulation or policy document to ban the purchase and use of cellphones of Apple or other foreign brands, but noted that media reports have exposed security incidents involving iPhones.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mao Ning, spokeswoman for the ministry, made the remarks at a regular news conference in response to reports that China has asked officials at some government agencies not to use iPhones for work or bring them into office.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Chinese government attaches great importance to cybersecurity and information security, and treats domestic and foreign companies as equals, she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mao said she hopes that all cellphone companies operating in China will strictly abide by the country&amp;#39;s laws and regulations, such as the Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We hope they will enhance information security management, protect consumers&amp;#39; data stored in the cellphones against theft by any individual or organization, and ensure information security,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mao reiterated that China is committed to advancing high-level opening-up, protecting the rights and interests of foreign companies in accordance with the law, and fostering a world-class business environment that is market-oriented, law-based and internationalized. &amp;quot;We always have an open attitude toward foreign-funded enterprises,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China welcomes foreign enterprises to seize the opportunities presented by the country&amp;#39;s development and share in the outcomes of its economic growth, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is Apple&amp;#39;s third-largest market and accounted for 19 percent of the company&amp;#39;s $394 billion revenue last year, Bloomberg reported.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Apple unveiled its iPhone 15 series and other new products on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhoujin@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Golden harvest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/14/content_003_650214fded50d203d2c9c3d5.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-14/003/20230914_003_06_67463.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Workers dry and process bamboo products at Jiangxi Runye Bamboo Products Co at Tanfang Industrial Park in Fuzhou, Jiangxi province, on Wednesday. The bamboo industry is helping the city bolster green growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>