<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Boost Yangtze economic belt&#39;s role]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_001_65285064ed50d203d2ca06cb.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_001_01_40.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平总书记周三，中共中央总书记、国家主席习近平在江西景德镇历史文化街区考察，了解陶瓷文化保护传承情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展，在突破核心技术、维护国家粮食、能源、产业链供应链安全方面发挥更大作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平周四在江西南昌主持召开推进经济带发展座谈会时作出上述表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，要坚持绿色发展，通过科技创新统筹生态文明建设和经济社会发展，让长江经济带国家战略更好支撑和服务国家现代化建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 江西是长江经济带的一部分，该经济带由11个省级地区组成，从长江上游的内陆四川省一直延伸到沿海的上海。官方数据显示，该地区覆盖了全国40%的人口，占全国国内生产总值的40%以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 自国家将长江经济带发展纳入国家战略以来，七年前，习近平已主持召开四次专题座谈会。前三届分别于2016年1月在重庆、2018年4月在湖北省武汉市、2020年11月在江苏省南京市举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在周四的研讨会上，高级官员也出席了会议习近平对中央和有关省市实施经济带发展战略取得的重大成就表示肯定，强调在环境保护和创新驱动发展方面作出的努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必须看到，经济带生态文明建设和高质量发展正处于关键转折点，还存在不少困难和问题需要解决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，经济带事关国家发展全局，国家战略相关地区要统筹发展与安全，在维护国家安全等方面发挥更大作用。粮食、能源、产业链和供应链、水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 加大力度保护我国最长河流长江流域的环境，避免过度开发，习近平说。他强调，要通过产业转型减少碳排放和污染，促进绿色发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在创新驱动发展方面，习近平要求把经济带的科技研发和人才优势转化为经济带的优势。发展新动能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 重点领域核心技术突破，推动产业链供应链现代化，提升制造业竞争力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 要发展战略性新兴产业，推动数字经济与实体经济融合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平还强调，要发挥经济带的区位优势，更好地推动数字经济与实体经济融合发展。连接国内国际两个市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 加大力度扩大国际经济合作，更好发挥长江自由贸易试验区作用，发挥制度创新先行者作用，探索新路径&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，要加强区域协调一体化，重点加强省际合作、生态治理、共同发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强区域交通互联互通，确保经济带各地区政策一致、规则统一、行动协调。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，各级各类企业要切实担负起推动经济带发展的责任，引导各类企业和社会组织积极参与经济带发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他补充说，要投入人力、物力和资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Double joy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_001_65285067ed50d203d2ca06cc.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_001_02_14.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;看护人员抱着大熊猫幼崽周四，瑞宝（左）和惠宝在韩国龙仁市爱宝乐园游乐园举行的揭名仪式上。这对双胞胎出生97天了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - PETS TAKE TO THE ROADS AND AIR WITH THEIR OWNERS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_001_65285069ed50d203d2ca06cd.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_002_01_30.png&quot; />; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_002_01_39.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一只柴犬在怀来永定河上游嬉戏河北省。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_002_01_11.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;宠物主人及其宠物狗狗们在乐宠乐行组织的旅行中玩得很开心。总部位于北京的旅游平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_002_01_8.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;宠物主人和他们的动物们在狗狗乐宠乐行组织的旅行中玩得很开心。总部位于北京的出行平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_002_01_7.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;骑行者一只柴犬在北京郊区旅行。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/001/20231013_002_01_12.png&quot; />;&lt;p >; 西伯利亚哈士奇犬 Winky 和 ​​14 岁边境牧羊犬 Yumi 正在探索四川省野勒湖畔的草原。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 越来越多的宠物主人带宠物去旅行，相关服务包括专业旅游、住宿、医疗等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 主人表示，让宠物多看看有好处。例如，主人可以陪伴他们的动物乘坐摩天轮、缆车、皮划艇和桨板。他们还带它们去看海、露营、游览草原。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 通过沉浸在野外，与大多数时间生活在城市生活的其他动物、宠物互动，获得近距离接触大自然。一些业主表示，带宠物去旅行可以避免外出旅行时不得不把它们留在家里的负罪感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 宠物友好酒店、包机和跟团旅游是目前提供的众多个性化服务之一&amp;mdash;证明需求强劲并且这个利基业务领域有很大的潜力。中国社会在对待动物方面似乎也变得更加包容和宽容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年 5 月，来自广东省深圳市的 28 岁的 Bonnie Yao 带着她的边境牧羊犬“念念”穿越中国西部，历时 50 天。下岗后想花时间探索荒野。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我认为带宠物去旅行是个好主意，因为它们属于大自然。尤其是长期生活在城市的狗狗，可能会因为工作能力和技能没有得到充分发挥而感到压力或抑郁。经常带他们出去玩可以给他们一个表达自己的机会。”姚说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她补充说，念念“羊群”四川省甘孜藏族自治州草原上的几只小羊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “念念对这些小羊很好奇。在确保他不会伤害他们之后，我让他和他们玩了一会。他跑来跑去，时刻注视着他们，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 姚女士补充说，在这次旅行中，她进一步领略了大自然的美丽。 “我们在雪山之巅看到了最美的日落。那一刻，我感觉自己仿佛来到了世界的尽头。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 24岁的蔡怡是江苏省南京市的一名活动策划人，自从2021年拥有她的小猎犬“普普”以来，她每次旅行都会带着它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “ ；一开始我以为她很听话，但后来我发现她太疯狂了。如果她不耗尽她所有的力量，她就会毁掉我的家。所以，为了防止我外出时家里变得乱七八糟，我带她去旅行，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她补充说，在南京寄养宠物的费用太高，每天大约50-80元（6.80-10.90美元），节假日每天大约100元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 蔡带着普普去了浙江省安吉市、杭州市、山东省沿海城市青岛和上海。由于她不会开车，所以主要使用叫车服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她说，一些喜欢狗的司机允许普普离开她的宠物笼。 “他们还问我是否想停下来，让狗回应大自然的召唤，呼吸新鲜空气。他们对狗非常友好，”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 普普一般都能很好地适应新环境，蔡说，因为比格犬相对无所畏惧，对大多数事物都充满好奇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我的狗第一次去新环境时海滩上，她很怕海浪，对着大海狂吠，但几道海浪拍打过来后，她就没事了。后来，她甚至想跑进海浪里。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们去青岛的时候，我把普普打扮得漂漂亮亮的，很多游客都过来和她合影。这些都是美好的回忆。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 蔡说，普普平时表现很好，就是比较随机应变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们去亚洲宠物展的时候在上海，她在安检口拉屎，令人尴尬。我无论走到哪里都必须随身携带纸张，以免给别人带来麻烦。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 蔡补充说，除了宠物笼外，她没有给普普准备什么。狗狗饿了，蔡就去酒店给她找点水煮肉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;好伙伴&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 孟周，24岁，宠物饲养员。广东佛山的电商工作人员说，她的金毛毛毛让旅行变得更加有趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “毛毛在车里掉毛，但当我们听音乐时，他听的是我们说话。高速公路上的生活有时是缓慢而放松的。我们租了一辆电动滑板车，让他坐在前面。当我们在红绿灯处停下来时，他喜欢舔我们旁边等车的人。它非常可爱，”周说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她和丈夫有一次把狗留在家里一天左右。每当他们通过监控摄像头查看毛毛的情况时，毛毛都显得精神不振，吃饭睡觉都没有兴趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他只是等我们回来，这让我们为他感到难过，所以我们决定每当我们外出时，就开始带他一起去，”周说，并补充说，他们带着狗总共行驶了5000公里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 夫妻俩购买了益生菌和止血粉，以防止毛毛因环境原因出现胃部不适、食欲不振等症状。变化，或因道路颠簸而受伤。他们还在车上装了狗粮、零食、玩具、折叠碗、水碗、毛巾、沐浴露等生活必需品。当然，还有便便袋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周说，他们避开了旅游高峰期和热门旅游景点，而是选择了空旷的地方。在预订酒店时，他们会仔细选择那些明确允许携带宠物的酒店。他们还提前打电话，因为有些酒店可能会额外收取宠物清洁费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “酷热的天气或者下雨天对狗狗来说不太好，毛毛也不行。” ;不喜欢穿防雨夹克。但尽管有这些不便，我知道他喜欢旅行，”周补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tracy Bai，29 岁，在四川省成都市从事游戏行业，拥有一只 14 岁的边境牧羊犬 Yumi、一只西伯利亚哈士奇 Winky、一只雪鞋猫 Kuang Kuang 和一只一只 1 岁的布偶猫。她想带着她的宠物去每一个她去过的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 白和她的丈夫每次去旅游都会带着两只狗，但只带猫去人烟稀少、安静的地方，因为猫对它们的敏感度特别敏感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这对夫妇有许多温馨的回忆——比如陪由美看烟花，看猫狗在雨中玩耍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “除了食物、其他用品和玩具外，我们会根据旅行的需要携带特定物品，比如玩水的救生衣，雪地的护目镜和雪地靴。我还会带驱虫剂、梳子和离子水来梳洗。此外，我还为猫带来了猫砂盆、笼子和床。难怪大家都说带猫去旅行比较麻烦。”白说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “带宠物旅行需要做好充分的准备，比如制定行程、收拾好应急物资以应对突发情况。在访问期间采取负责任的行为也很重要，以鼓励宠物友好型住宿的发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;旅行团&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于对携带宠物乘坐公共汽车、地铁、火车和飞机的旅行有限制，因此大多数主人会开车带着宠物出行。不过，也有一些人选择专门的跟团游。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张少鹏，乐宠乐行创始人，一家狗狗公司。 2018年成立的北京旅游平台表示，该公司的行程包括游览草原、海滩、山脉、湿地和湖泊。还可以为狗狗私人预订参观水族馆和游乐园。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 行程范围从游览附近景点的一两天到游览甘肃省甘南藏族自治州等目的地的三天或更长时间、内蒙古呼伦贝尔、海南三亚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于距离北京较近的目的地，该公司会安排巴士，50座车通常只载15名左右的乘客，为狗狗提供更多空间锻炼身体并避免空气质量不佳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 对于偏远目的地，我们提供宠物包机服务，将狗与主人一起放在机舱内的宠物笼中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在旅行之前，公司询问狗的情况性格和健康状况。例如，发情的狗和有攻击性的狗不准外出旅游，以确保其他狗的安全，心脏病有问题的狗不准前往高海拔地区。医生会全程陪伴狗狗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该公司通常会预订一整层的房间，以避免狗狗受伤。吠叫打扰了客人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我曾经住在一家宾馆，接待员为狗准备了欢迎礼物，其中包括玩具和发光项圈，以减少动物在晚上迷路的机会，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 入住时，酒店为主人分配的楼层和房间类型是根据狗的大小而定的，大型动物被安置在较大的房间和较低的楼层。张补充说，房间里放置了专门为动物准备的狗碗、垫子、毛巾和消毒喷雾剂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该公司每月组织约 15 次旅行，而 2018 年只有两到三次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我看到宠物旅行逐渐被社会所接受。 2015年，当我进入这个行业时，宠物旅行还是一片空白，很少有酒店愿意容纳动物。”张说，并补充说，现在也有更可靠的宠物旅游组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 35岁的Queenie Fu，北京的一名餐饮经理，和她的柯基犬可乐和七喜参加了该公司的一次旅行团，游览了内蒙古的草原，还短暂游览了北京郊区的密云水库。她说，这些狗与其他狗成了朋友，宠物主人也喜欢社交活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 傅最难忘的时刻包括和狗们在桨板上玩耍，以及七夕翘起舌头、抽动双腿的时刻。假装爬完山累坏了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;新服务&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着生活水平的提高，越来越多的家庭开始饲养宠物，目前宠物数量已超过1亿只在中国。随着人们对动物的热爱不断加深，越来越多的主人希望带着它们去旅行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京第二外国语学院旅游科学学院副教授王金伟表示，现在越来越多的中国人将宠物视为家庭的一员，带它们去旅行是理所当然的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着越来越多的企业意识到这个市场的商机，相关的旅游产品和服务也迅速涌现，王补充道，比如宠物友好型酒店和风景名胜区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “宠物也给人类带来快乐和舒适，而旅行则可以缓解人们的工作压力。”两者的结合，满足了人们悠闲生活的心理需求。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，专门为宠物提供的设施仍然有限，例如小木屋、座椅和酒店。关于宠物的相关法律法规也缺乏。王补充道，“健康、卫生、意外事故以及可能的传染病”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鉴于此，未来预计会有更多针对宠物的创新产品，如专用床、旅行保险和医疗护理，以确保宠物的安全。他说，主人和他们的动物在旅行期间得到适当的照顾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 罗兰贝格咨询公司负责人 Kathy Jiang 表示，大多数携带宠物旅行的人都来自中高端收入群体，他们&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她建议酒店、景点逐步增加服务，比如为宠物提供房间、提供专用餐具等。蒋说，还应该加强宣传，提高公众对此类服务的认识，并加大对宠物旅游公司的投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “宠物旅游正在发展成为一个潜力巨大的新市场。它还推动了宠物酒店和旅游服务提供商等新兴行业的发展。”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;chenmeiling@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Nation&#39;s pollution fight increasing longevity, says study]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_001_6528506ced50d203d2ca06ce.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 十年前的北京，空气净化器卖得很热，人们呆在室内，试图躲避外面的浓重雾霾。呼吸被污染的空气对健康造成严重危害。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 如今，同样的空气净化器却积满了灰尘，北京居民享受户外活动而不必担心生病，新鲜空气不再是一种奢侈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 过去十年的逆转是惊人的。中国当局经常通过指出大气中空气污染物浓度的下降和每年空气质量较好的天数稳步增加来证明空气质量从那时到现在的巨大差异。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 10年来，北京空气重污染天数比例下降近95%，从2013年的58天下降到2022年的仅3天。2013年，首都PM2.5年均浓度为每立方米 89.5 微克。去年，密度下降至每立方米30微克。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，美国一家机构最近的一项研究，以更直接的方式强调了空气质量改善的效果——这意味着中国人的寿命有望延长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021年中国空气污染水平比2013年下降了42.3%，2013年是国家发动“攻坚战”的一年。芝加哥大学能源政策研究所八月下旬编制的年度空气质量生活指数报告显示，“污染”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “由于这些改善，中国普通公民的预期生活质量如果持续减少，则可以延长 2.2 年。”它说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 世界只经历了“小幅衰退”。 2013 年至 2021 年间，空气污染水平有所下降。报告称，这种下降“完全归功于中国的进步”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 报告称，“如果没有中国空气污染水平的急剧下降，污染，2013年至2021年间全球平均污染将略有增加。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国在治理方面取得了“惊人的成功”报告称，2013年秋季，国家制定了《国家空气质量行动计划》，治理空气污染发生了。该文件制定了到 2017 年底改善空气质量的具体目标，其中包括斥资 2700 亿美元减少人口稠密地区污染的计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为了实现这些目标，中国政府限制了汽车数量在大城市的道路上，削减烟囱工业的产能，禁止在重点地区新建燃煤电厂，并从煤炭转向天然气和电力作为燃料，为农村家庭提供温暖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些行动的基础是共同的要素：政治意愿和人力和财力资源，相互促进。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当公众和政策制定者拥有这些工具时，采取行动的可能性就会大得多。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 赵亮于 2014 年发起了一个名为 Airman 的草根非政府组织，专注于对抗空气污染，他敏锐地意识到政治意愿在推动国家空气质量改善中所发挥的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 赵亮敏锐地意识到政治意愿在推动国家空气质量改善方面所发挥的作用。 p>; &lt;p>; 在该非政府组织成立之初，赵想要接触空气污染者或政府官员并不容易。但他发现政府“越来越开放”。赵指出，在中国政府的顶层设计中，引入了一系列机制来迫使基层官员更加努力地工作。以2016年高调启动的中央环保督察为例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;督察组由部长级官员带队，向国务院副总理领导的中央领导小组汇报。 39;内阁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “与基层官员沟通时，他们不再说不重要。”这是一个很大的变化，”赵说。 “他们愿意与我们沟通。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，报告警告说，中国的污染水平仍然没有达到世界卫生组织建议的指导方针，并且仍然对该国的预期寿命构成威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; “如果中国能够将污染水平从 2021 年的水平减少到达到世界卫生组织的指导方针，并且这种减少能够永久持续下去，那么中国人的平均预期寿命将增加 2.5 年，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;houliqiang@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China, North Macedonia vow to carry ties forward]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_001_6528506fed50d203d2ca06cf.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国家主席习近平周四同北马其顿总统彭达罗夫斯基互致贺电，庆祝两国建交30周年，并表示将推动两国关系发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在致彭达罗夫斯基的贺电中表示，30年来，中北马其顿互信不断加深，传统友谊历久弥新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国在人文领域合作积累了宝贵经验。习近平表示，中方在基础设施建设、文明互鉴、卫生健康等领域合作取得了丰硕成果，对此表示高度赞赏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中方高度重视习近平表示，我愿同彭达罗夫斯基一道，不断加强政治引领，深化互信、友谊、合作。以建交30周年为新起点，推动中北马其顿关系发展。共同开创中北马其顿关系美好未来，为两国人民带来更多福祉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彭达罗夫斯基表示，30年来，两国尊重彼此战略选择北马其顿愿同中方加强合作，促进共同发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两国拥有共同利益，合作潜力巨大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - State fund&#39;s move buoys investors&#39; confidence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_001_65285072ed50d203d2ca06d0.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 随着经济复苏迹象增强，中国主权财富基金旗下中央汇金投资增持了中国四大商业银行的股份，分析师称表示将有助于进一步提振投资者的信心&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中央汇金增持“四大”各0.01个百分点贷款人——中国银行、中国农业银行、中国建设银行和中国工商银行——根据银行的报告，并计划在未来六个月内进一步增持银行的股份。周三晚间发布公告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 向主要银行注资之际，中国定于下周发布第三季度 GDP 数据，专家们对此表示乐观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; GROW Investment Group首席经济学家洪浩在一份研究报告中表示，中央汇金公司购买了总计约4.77亿元人民币（6600万美元）的股份，发出了积极信号，将增强投资者情绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周四A股市场反应积极。上证综指上涨 0.94%，深成指收涨 0.83%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在中国银行股价飙升的带动下，周四 A 股银行股上涨 1.38%。北向资本上涨3.18%，建设银行上涨2.68%。境外投资者买入A股市场的金额——资本净流入近70亿元，结束9月下旬以来的流出趋势。方正证券首席策略师曹六龙表示，中央汇金出手后，A股市场通常会在平均一个月内出现反弹。 A股上市银行、美容服务提供商和通讯公司普遍在主权财富基金公告发布后的5至30天内出现最大涨幅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 分析师表示，中国正处于经济复苏的关键时刻，进一步加强股市与实体经济的联系具有重要意义。他们补充说，中央汇金公司的注资对于提振市场信心、更好地服务经济增长能够起到非常有效的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 东吴证券分析师在周四的研究报告中解释说，中央汇金公司的注资可以起到非常有效的作用。汇金公司类似于日本、美国等发达经济体的市场平准基金。无国界医生组织的成立是为了通过购买交易所交易基金或个股来缓解市场波动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京大学新结构经济学研究院院长林毅夫预计，中国将实现 GDP 增长今年增长 5.5% 至 6%，仍然是“增长最快”的国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他建议，为了更好地实现这一目标，政府应采取一定的反周期措施，例如更加积极的财政刺激和扩张性货币政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 摩根大通中国区首席代表经济学家朱海滨预计，今年中国经济增速可能达到5%，高于此前预测的4.8%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “8月中旬以来宣布的增量政策宽松行动的影响，包括住房市场的需求方宽松措施以及降息和降准的措施尚未完全反映在8月份的数据中，这可能会在未来几个月影响实体经济。对此，我们上调了第三季度、第四季度和全年的增长预测。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国国际金融公司分析师林英奇表示，过去几个月，中国主要经济指标，包括采购经理人指数、工业企业盈利能力和通胀等， ，都显示出国家内生增长动力小幅复苏的迹象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 结合中央汇金的最新举措，市场信心将得到提振，资金流向有望进一步增强。林说，此举进一步增强了A股市场的韧性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;shijing@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - PETS TAKE TO THE ROADS AND AIR WITH THEIR OWNERS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_002_65285072ed50d203d2ca06d1.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/002/20231013_002_01_30.png&quot; />; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/002/20231013_002_01_39.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一只柴犬在怀来永定河上游嬉戏河北省。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/002/20231013_002_01_11.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;宠物主人及其宠物狗狗们在乐宠乐行组织的旅行中玩得很开心。总部位于北京的旅游平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/002/20231013_002_01_8.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;宠物主人和他们的动物们在狗狗乐宠乐行组织的旅行中玩得很开心。 travel platform based in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/002/20231013_002_01_7.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Cyclists take a shiba on a trip in suburban Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/002/20231013_002_01_12.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Winky, a Siberian husky, and Yumi, a 14-year-old border collie, explore grassland beside Yele Lake in Sichuan province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More pet owners are taking their animals on travels, with related services such as specialized tours, accommodations and medical care now available.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Owners said it is good for the pets to see more of the outside world, as this broadens their experience of life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, owners are accompanying their animals on Ferris wheels, cable cars, in kayaks and on paddle boards. They also take them to view the sea, on camping trips, and to visit grassland areas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By immersing themselves in the wild and interacting with other animals, pets, who live urban lives most of the time, get up close with nature. Some owners said that taking their pets on trips helps avoid the guilt of having to leave them at home when they go traveling.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pet-friendly hotels, charter flights and package tours are among the many personalized services now available &amp;mdash; proof that demand is strong and there is plenty of potential in this niche business sector. Chinese society also appears to have become more inclusive and tolerant in dealing with animals.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In May, Bonnie Yao, 28, from Shenzhen, Guangdong province, traveled across western China for 50 days with her border collie Nian Nian after being laid off and wanting to spend time exploring wilderness areas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I think taking pets on trips is a good idea, because they belong to nature. In particular, dogs that live in cities for a long time may experience stress or depression because their working abilities and skills are not fully used. Taking them out to play frequently can give them an opportunity to express themselves,&amp;quot; Yao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She added that Nian Nian &amp;quot;herded&amp;quot; several lambs on grassland in Ganzi Tibetan autonomous prefecture, Sichuan province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Nian Nian was very curious about the lambs. After ensuring that he wouldn&amp;#39;t harm them, I let him play with them for a while. He ran around, constantly keeping an eye on them,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yao added that during the trip, she further appreciated the beauty of nature. &amp;quot;We saw the most beautiful sunset at the summit of a snow mountain. At that moment, I felt as though I had arrived at the end of the world,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cai Yi, 24, an event planner in Nanjing, Jiangsu province, has taken her beagle Pu Pu on every trip she has made since owning her in 2021.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;At first, I thought she was obedient, but I subsequently found that she is too crazy. If she does not use up all her energy, she will destroy my home. So, to prevent the house becoming a mess when I&amp;#39;m out, I&amp;#39;ve taken her on trips,&amp;quot; Cai said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She added that the cost of boarding a pet in Nanjing is too high, at about 50-80 yuan ($6.80-$10.90) per day, and about 100 yuan a day during holidays.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cai has taken Pu Pu to Anji and Hangzhou in Zhejiang province, the coastal city of Qingdao, Shandong province, and to Shanghai. She mainly uses ride-hailing services, as she cannot drive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said some drivers who like dogs allow Pu Pu out of her pet carrier. &amp;quot;They also ask if I want to stop and let the dog answer a call of nature and get some fresh air. They are very friendly to dogs,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pu Pu generally adapts well to new environments, because beagles are relatively fearless and curious about most things, Cai said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The first time my dog went to the beach, she was scared of the waves and barked at the sea, but after a few waves crashed against her, she was fine. Later, she even wanted to run into the waves,&amp;quot; Cai said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;When we went to Qingdao, I dressed Pu Pu up nicely, and many tourists came over and took photos with her. These are beautiful memories.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cai said Pu Pu usually behaves well, apart from a tendency to randomly answer the call of nature.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;When we went to Pet Fair Asia in Shanghai, she pooped at the security checkpoint, which was embarrassing. I have to take paper with me everywhere we go to avoid causing trouble for others,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cai added that apart from a pet carrier, she prepares little for Pu Pu. If the dog is hungry, Cai finds some boiled pork for her at a hotel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Good companions&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Men Zhou, 24, a pets&amp;#39; e-commerce worker in Foshan, Guangdong province, said her golden retriever Mao Mao has made traveling much more fun.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Mao Mao sheds hair in the car, but while we listen to music, he listens to us talking. Life on the highway can be slow and relaxing at times. We rented an electric scooter, sitting him up front. When we stopped at traffic lights, he liked to lick the people waiting at them alongside us. It was quite adorable,&amp;quot; Zhou said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She and her husband once left the dog at home for a day or so. Whenever they checked on him through a surveillance camera, Mao Mao seemed lethargic and uninterested in eating or sleeping.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;He just waited for us to come back, which made us feel sorry for him, so we decided to start taking him with us whenever we went out,&amp;quot; Zhou said, adding that they have traveled for a total distance of 5,000 kilometers with the dog in the car.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The couple bought probiotics and hemostatic powder to prevent Mao Mao experiencing stomach discomfort, loss of appetite due to environmental changes, or injuries from bumps in the road. They also packed essential daily items such as dog food, snacks, toys, collapsible bowls, water bowls, towels and shower gel in the car. And, of course, poop bags.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou said they avoided peak travel periods and popular tourist attractions, opting instead for open areas. When booking hotels, they carefully chose those that explicitly allow pets. They also called in advance, as some hotels may charge additional cleaning fees for pets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s not good for dogs to travel in extremely hot weather or rain, and Mao Mao doesn&amp;#39;t like wearing a rainproof jacket. But despite these inconveniences, I know he enjoys traveling,&amp;quot; Zhou added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tracy Bai, 29, who works in the games industry in Chengdu, Sichuan province, owns a 14-year-old border collie Yumi, a Siberian husky Winky, a snowshoe cat Kuang Kuang, and a 1-year-old Ragdoll cat. She wants to take her pets to every place she visits.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Bai and her husband take the two dogs whenever they toured, but only take the cats to less populated and quiet places, as cats are particularly sensitive to their environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The couple have many heartwarming memories &amp;mdash; for example, accompanying Yumi to watch fireworks, and seeing the cats and dogs playing together in the rain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Besides food, other supplies and toys, we take specific items depending on the requirements for the trip, such as life jackets for playing in the water, and goggles and snow boots for the snow. I also take insect repellent, combs and ionized water for grooming. In addition, for the cats, I bring litter boxes, carriers and beds. It&amp;#39;s no surprise that everyone says it&amp;#39;s more troublesome to take a cat on a trip,&amp;quot; Bai said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Taking pets traveling requires thorough preparation, such as making an itinerary and packing emergency supplies for unexpected situations. It&amp;#39;s also important to behave responsibly during a visit to encourage the growth of pet-friendly accommodations.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Package tours&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As there are restrictions on traveling with pets on buses, subways, trains and airplanes, most owners travel with their animals by car. However, some choose specialized package tours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Shaopeng, founder of Lechonglexing, a dogs&amp;#39; travel platform based in Beijing that was established in 2018, said the company&amp;#39;s trips include visits to grasslands, beaches, mountains, wetlands and lakes. Private bookings are also available for dogs to visit aquariums and amusement parks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Trips range from one or two days for nearby attractions, to three days or more for visits to destinations such as Gannan Tibetan autonomous prefecture, Gansu province, Hulunbuir, Inner Mongolia autonomous region, and Sanya, Hainan province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For destinations relatively close to Beijing, the company arranges buses, with a 50-seater vehicle usually only carrying about 15 passengers to give dogs more room for exercise and avoid poor air quality.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For remote destinations, chartered flights for pets are available, with dogs placed in pet carriers inside the aircraft cabin with their owners.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before they travel, the company inquires about the dogs&amp;#39; personalities and health status. For example, dogs in heat and those that are aggressive are not allowed to go on a tour, to ensure the safety of other dogs, and those with heart problems are not allowed to go to high-altitude areas. A doctor accompanies the dogs throughout a trip.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company usually books an entire floor of rooms to avoid the dogs&amp;#39; barking disturbing guests.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I once stayed in a guesthouse where the receptionist prepared welcoming gifts for dogs, which included toys and glow collars to reduce the chance of an animal getting lost at night,&amp;quot; Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During check-in, the hotel floor and type of room assigned to an owner is based on a dog&amp;#39;s size, with large animals housed in bigger rooms and on lower floors. Dog bowls, mats, towels specifically for the animals, and disinfectant sprays are placed in the rooms, Zhang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company organizes about 15 trips a month, compared with only two or three in 2018. Customers using its services are generally those born between 1985 and 1995.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I have seen pet travel gradually being accepted by society. In 2015, when I entered the industry, pet travel was a complete blank, with few hotels willing to accommodate animals,&amp;quot; Zhang said, adding that there are now also more reliable pet travel organizations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Queenie Fu, 35, a catering manager in Beijing, and her corgis Kele and Qixi joined one of the company&amp;#39;s tours to a grassland area in Inner Mongolia and also took a short trip to the Miyun Reservoir in suburban Beijing. She said the dogs made friends with other dogs, and pet owners also enjoyed social activities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The most memorable moments for Fu included playing with the dogs on paddle boards and when Qixi tilted her tongue and twitched her legs to pretend she was exhausted after climbing a mountain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;New services&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With improved living standards, more families are raising pets, who now number more than 100 million in China. As love for their animals deepens, a rising number of owners are looking to travel with them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Jinwei, an associate professor at Beijing International Studies University&amp;#39;s School of Tourism Sciences, said more Chinese now regard pets as part of the family, so it&amp;#39;s only natural to take them on travels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As more companies sense the business opportunities in this market, related tourism products and services are fast becoming available, such as pet-friendly hotels and scenic spots, Wang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Pets also bring happiness and comfort to humans, while travel relieves people from work stress. Combining the two meets people&amp;#39;s psychological demands for a leisurely life,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, there are still only a limited number of facilities especially for pets, such as cabins, seats and hotels. There is also a lack of related laws and regulations about pets&amp;#39; health, sanitation, accidents and possible infectious diseases, Wang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In view of this, more innovative products for pets, such as special beds, travel insurance and medical care can be expected in the future to ensure that owners and their animals are properly cared for during trips, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kathy Jiang, principal at consultancy Roland Berger, said most people traveling with pets are from the medium- and high-end income groups, who have greater demands for their travel experience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She suggested that hotels and attractions gradually increase their services, such as providing rooms for pets and making special tableware available. There should also be improved promotion to raise public awareness of such services, and increased investment in pet travel companies, Jiang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Pet travel is developing into a new market with great potential. It is also driving development of emerging sectors such as pet hotels and tourism service providers,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;chenmeiling@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Increase seen in births of second, third children]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_003_65285075ed50d203d2ca06d2.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Babies born as the second or third child in a family accounted for about 54 percent of new births in China last year, the National Health Commission said on Thursday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Statistics showed that babies born as the second child accounted for about 39 percent of new births last year, compared with 41.1 percent in 2021. The percentage of babies born as the third child rose slightly by 0.5 percentage points year-on-year to 15 percent last year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2013, families were allowed to have two children if either of the parents was an only child, and in 2015 all couples were allowed to have two children. In May 2021, all families were allowed to have up to three children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The policy adjustment has seen the ratio of children born as the second or third child rising gradually, from around 30 percent in 2013 to around 50 percent in recent years, according to the commission.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, the total number of new births has kept falling in the country at the same time. Last year, there were 9.56 million newborns nationwide, down from 10.62 million in 2021. This is the first time the number has dipped below 10 million since the late 1940s.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The continuously falling number of newborns over the years is seen as a major driver behind the historic fall in the country&amp;#39;s total population recorded last year. China&amp;#39;s total population dropped by 850,000 in 2022.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The statistics showed that the gender ratio at birth last year was 111.1 boys for every 100 girls, compared with 118 in 2013.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As part of the efforts to boost births, the number of nursery care facilities increased to nearly 76,000 last year, with 2.57 nursery care slots per 1,000 people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The statistics also showed that China&amp;#39;s healthcare capacity has been improving in recent years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By the end of last year, the total number of hospital beds stood at 9.75 million, a year-on-year increase of 300,000. The number of hospital beds per 1,000 people also rose to 6.92 last year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The number of physicians per 1,000 people and that of nurses also increased slightly compared with the previous year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Notably, healthcare infrastructure also expanded, with a total of 36,448 community health service centers and stations established throughout the nation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangxiaoyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Taiwan compatriots urged to promote cross-Strait ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_003_65285078ed50d203d2ca06d3.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Top political adviser Wang Huning called on Taiwan compatriots on Thursday to devote themselves to promoting the peaceful development of cross-Strait relations and striving for the future of national reunification and rejuvenation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang, a member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&amp;#39;s Political Consultative Conference, made the remarks at the sixth forum of social groups of Taiwan compatriots held in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About 300 Taiwan compatriots from home and abroad attended the event organized by the All-China Federation of Taiwan Compatriots. The federation was established in 1981 and comprises Taiwan compatriots residing on the Chinese mainland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said the forum will promote a deeper level of spiritual connection between compatriots on both sides of the Strait and promote deeper exchanges and cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Achieving the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation requires joint efforts from both sides and the complete reunification of the motherland relies on the collaboration of compatriots, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More Taiwan compatriots will share the vast opportunities and achievements of the mainland&amp;#39;s modernization, and they will deepen their identification with the motherland, as well as with Chinese culture and history, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang urged resolute opposition to &amp;quot;Taiwan independence&amp;quot; separatist activities and external interference, and called for safeguarding peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ji Bin, vice-chairman of the All-China Federation of Taiwan Compatriots, said the organization will unite more Taiwan compatriots to promote cross-Strait exchanges and national reunification.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng-hung, director of the Association of Taiwan Enterprises on the mainland, said that Taiwan businesspeople on the mainland can feel the tangible benefits brought about by the peaceful development of cross-Strait relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Any turmoil, tension or conflict across the Taiwan Strait will only harm and potentially bring disaster to the people,&amp;quot; Li said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huang Wenhan, a Taiwan compatriot who works in Australia, said the younger generation in Taiwan should explore the mainland and learn about the real motherland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;They can learn more about the motherland&amp;#39;s history and culture while deepening cross-Strait ties through colorful activities involving education, cultural exchanges and fellowships,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyi1@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Lighting the torch]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_003_6528507bed50d203d2ca06d4.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/003/20231013_003_03_15.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Torchbearers in Guangzhou, Guangdong province, light a torch from a flame holder on Thursday in the run-up to the 4th Asian Para Games. The torch relay for the Games will commence on Oct 19, and the main cauldron will be ignited at the opening ceremony on Oct 22.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Journalists called on to be good narrators of BRI-related stories]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/13/content_003_6528507eed50d203d2ca06d5.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-13/003/20231013_003_04_42.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; Journalists should strive to be bridges between civilizations to promote peace and development and be good narrators of stories related to the Belt and Road Initiative, officials and representatives of global media agencies said at a forum on Thursday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun Yeli, deputy head of the Publicity Department of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and director of the State Council Information Office, called on journalists to tell better stories about the BRI, and to promote mutual learning among civilizations and help maintain peace, promote development and advance common prosperity through their reporting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He made the remarks at the 2023 Belt and Road Journalists Forum hosted by the All-China Journalists Association in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The forum, themed &amp;quot;Building a Beautiful Silk Road, Jointly Promoting Prosperity and Development&amp;quot;, invited nearly 100 heads of journalists&amp;#39; organizations and media representatives from more than 40 countries and regions involved in the BRI.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Journalists have the responsibility to use their pens, cameras and microphones to report on the intersection of national interests, telling stories of shared opportunities created by the BRI, said He Ping, president of the All-China Journalists Association.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A declaration was also read out at the forum by Christopher Isiguzo, chairman-in-office of the Belt and Road Journalists Network and national president of the Nigeria Union of Journalists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the declaration, parties involved expressed their commitment to enhancing political mutual trust, economic and trade exchanges, cultural exchanges and media cooperation among nations, and enhancing people&amp;#39;s willingness to understand and trust each other.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Isiguzo said that journalists do not just witness history. They could shape it, and they can create a world where the exchange of ideas and cooperation brings prosperity for all.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Atal Sembiring Depari, chairman of the Confederation of ASEAN Journalists and the Indonesian Journalists Association, said the role journalists play in shaping public perceptions and understanding of this valuable endeavor is very important, adding that they have a responsibility to report on the initiative accurately, impartially and comprehensively, highlighting the opportunities brought by it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guy Mettan, founder of the Geneva Press Club in Switzerland, praised the achievements of the BRI, saying that in the past 10 years, it has been changing the economy of the Eurasian continent, reshaping global economic and trade routes and helping to create a more equitable and multipolar world order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Georgina Kekea, president of the Media Association of Solomon Islands, said she hopes to gain a deeper understanding of the BRI at the forum, so that she can accurately report on the initiative and its potential impact on the Solomon Islands.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In the spirit of unity and cooperation, we can go toward a future of shared prosperity and development for all our nations,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;yangran1@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>