<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi stresses WTO reform, opening-up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_001_65149888ed50d203d2c9fbe1.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中共中央总书记习近平周三强调，北京致力于积极全面参与世界贸易组织改革和调整习近平在中共中央政治局集体学习时表示，中国将以更高水平的开放推动深化改革、谋求高质量发展党的核心领导层中央。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 会议在讨论WTO之前，听取了中国国际贸易经济合作研究院院长顾学明的讲座&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，中国要以申请加入《跨太平洋伙伴关系全面进步协定》和《数字经济伙伴协定》为契机，挖掘更大进口潜力，扩大进口潜力。市场准入，提高对外国投资的吸引力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他重申国家致力于营造符合市场原则、法治和国际标准的营商环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，2001年中国加入世贸组织，是中国对外开放的里程碑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据海关总署统计，中国已成为世界第一大开放国家。截至2022年，中国连续六年成为最大的货物贸易国，2022年其货物进出口总额同比飙升7.7%，达到创纪录的42.07万亿元人民币（5.76万亿美元）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平在会议上表示，中国从全球经济贸易规则的被动接受者和主动适应者转变为重要参与者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，加入世贸组织的决定已经得到充分证明，因为入世不仅加快了中国发展，也造福了世界经济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，参与世贸组织改革，要坚定维护以世贸组织为核心的多边机制的权威性和有效性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国家必须始终站在历史正确的一边，顺应经济全球化的大方向，倡导自由贸易和真正的贸易自由化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他重申，中国反对单边主义、保护主义，反对将经贸问题政治化、武器化，反对在这些问题上超越国家安全理念的行为。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 中国将本着构建人类命运共同体的理念，细化和充实自己参与世贸组织改革的方案，坚决维护发展中国家的合法权益习近平指出，今年是中国改革开放45周年，习近平指出，要坚持不懈推进国家自身改革，同步推进中国改革开放45周年。积极主动对接高标准国际经贸规则，稳步扩大规则等领域制度化开放习近平提出建设贸易强国的目标，包括推动贸易升级&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，要把保障国家经济安全放在首位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;span>;xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Disciplinary inspections key for Party governance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_001_6514988bed50d203d2c9fbe2.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 中共中央政治局周三召开会议，审议中共二十届中央委员会3月底启动的第一轮纪律检查报告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中共中央总书记习近平主持会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与会人员指出首轮纪律检查推进政治监督以“具体、有针对性、经常性”的方式，发出明确信号：坚持从严治党和党的自身改革是一个持续的过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 实践证明纪律检查是发现问题、解决问题的有效手段，要继续努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此次纪律检查涉及30家中央企业党组织、5家中央企业党组织。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 9月20日至22日，中央巡视组共15个督察组反馈情况，明确了被巡视单位存在的问题。会议指出，在统筹发展与安全、全面从严治党、党风廉政建设等方面存在短板。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导干部要压实责任，采取严格、具体措施，对问题进行整改。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 督促检查党组织加强党的全面领导，不断增强党的核心功能和竞争力巩固中国特色社会主义物质政治基础，增强金融企业实力支持实体经济和国家战略，推动高质量发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 要统筹发展与安全，着眼底线，采取有效措施，防范和解决重大问题。会议代表表示，纪律检查是中国共产党反腐败斗争、对党内权力运行和党员干部行使权力进行检查和监督的重要手段。 39； &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Driving growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_001_6514988ded50d203d2c9fbe3.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/001/20230928_001_03_168199.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;员工组装汽车9月21日，山东省青岛市即墨区一家工厂内。即墨拥有400多家整车厂和汽车零部件生产企业，近期订单不断增加。国家统计局周三公布的数据显示，8月份中国主要工业企业利润强劲反弹，同比增长17.2%。参见故事，第 3 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Former Irish PM calls protectionism a mistake]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_001_65149890ed50d203d2c9fbe4.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/001/20230928_003_05_42923.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;伯蒂·埃亨&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 爱尔兰前总理伯蒂·埃亨表示，爱尔兰花了几十年时间才认识到保护主义是一个根本性错误，今天的国家不应该重蹈覆辙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 曾任总理的埃亨1997年至2008年担任爱尔兰总理的他最近在接受《中国日报》采访时发表上述言论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他指出，欧盟与中国之间稳定健康的关系符合各方利益，他警告说，这一想法通过施加贸易限制来背离多边主义的做法是错误的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “早在 20 世纪 30 年代和 1940 年代，爱尔兰领导人就曾经认为，通过关税保护产品对人民有利。只有当我们取消关税和限制并开放贸易时，我们才会发展得更多。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 现在爱尔兰已成为世界上最有利于商业发展的地区之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 爱尔兰被一些人称为欧洲硅谷，是许多全球企业的总部所在地。近年来，中爱两国双向贸易持续增长，去年双边贸易额达238亿美元，同比增长3.8% &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 埃亨表示，这些成果不是通过保护主义和限制取得的，而是通过允许贸易和保护知识产权取得的。他指出，当贸易数字增长时，这对企业来说是双赢的局面、消费者和投资者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这对世界有好处。但当政治因素阻碍时，事情就会变慢。”他说，并补充说，一些国家总能找到这样或那样的理由来反对不加限制的贸易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在最新的案例中，尽管中国和欧洲在过去二十年中建立了牢固的经济相互依存关系，但欧盟委员会最近宣布对中国电动汽车制造商进行反补贴调查，中国认为此举源于保护主义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一旦调查启动，欧盟所在地布鲁塞尔将不得不做出决定是否在九个月内征收临时关税。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在我看来，所有这些都会适得其反。”它不起作用，因为所有这些事情都以正常方式对业务不利。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他还表示，这对爱尔兰等欧洲小国来说尤其不利，因为它们无法像法国或德国等大国那样通过补贴抵消产品关税。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 但埃亨表示，他相信中国政府和欧盟在承认分歧的同时，正在努力取得进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周一，国务院副总理何立峰共同主持了第十届中国-欧盟峰会。欧盟与欧盟委员会执行副主席瓦尔迪斯·东布罗夫斯基斯在北京举行高层经贸对话。这是自COVID-19爆发以来首次举行对话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据对话后的新闻稿，双方经过坦诚务实的会谈，达成了一系列双赢的成果议题包括宏观经济、贸易投资、产业供应链、金融合作等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我认为解决问题的最好办法是坐下来，探讨这些问题，讨论它们，看看能得到什么结果。”妥协和不同之处，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，1998年，他作为第一位访问中国的爱尔兰总理来华时注意到，当时来华的欧洲政要并不多。 “现在来的总理和高级官员越来越多，”他说，这有助于他们熟悉中国的运作方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为中国的常客，埃亨表示，过去十年来，他亲眼目睹了全球化和多边主义在中国的进步。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “欧盟和中国必须在气候变化、生物多样性、健康问题、债务减免、人道主义援助以及许多其他全球问题上共同努力，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 埃亨还表示，对中欧关系的未来持乐观态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 统计数据显示，中国和欧盟互为第二大贸易国2022年，尽管全球经济复苏缓慢，双边贸易额仍创历史新高8473亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mojingxi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - 13-year-old girl is China&#39;s youngest Asiad champ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_001_65149893ed50d203d2c9fbe5.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/001/20230928_001_05_98199.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;崔晨曦参加周三，浙江省杭州市亚运会女子街头滑板比赛决赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周三，崔晨曦凭借勇敢的表现成为中国亚运会历史上最年轻的金牌得主。 13岁滑板运动员在浙江省杭州市钱塘轮滑运动中心举行的女子街头比赛中获胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 街头比赛中，滑冰者们在崎岖的赛道上表演大胆的技巧，赛道上有铁轨和滑道。差距。来自中国东部山东省济南市的崔在以困难着称的高铁上取得了令人印象深刻的着陆——这是她的许多竞争对手都避免的举动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这位少女是中国国家队最年轻的运动员，以 242.62 分夺得金牌。 18岁的同胞曾文辉以236.61分获得银牌，16岁的日本滑板运动员伊藤美佑以221.59分获得铜牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 直到周三，中国最年轻的亚运金牌的称号奖牌获得者是 15 岁的滑板运动员陈野，他在周一的男子公园比赛中获胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 本届奥运会最年轻的参赛者是 9 岁的菲律宾人 Mazel Paris Alegado。周一在女子公园决赛中排名第九的滑板运动员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 崔说这次胜利对她来说意义重大。 “我一直想赢得金牌。这次比赛和其他比赛不一样，所以特别想赢这个。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被问赛前是否紧张，她摇头说：“我爸让我留下来放松，享受比赛并展示我的技能。只要我全力以赴，我就无怨无悔。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;滑板运动植根于街头文化，与年轻人的生活方式和态度息息相关，是一项强调自由和个人的运动&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 崔在 2020 年才开始玩滑板，当时她 3 岁时就开始练习滑旱冰，当时 COVID-19 大流行不允许她练习滑旱冰。她的父亲是一位滑板爱好者，建议她在家尝试滑板。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我记得我第一次踏上滑板的那一天。感觉非常顺畅。这是一见钟情，”崔说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一年之内，她就登上了专业级别赛事的领奖台。 2022年，她在山东省运动会女子街头项目中获得第三名。很快，她就加入了省滑板队，接受了更全面、更有条理的训练计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年早些时候，崔在2017年举行的世界街头滑板锦标赛上获得了女子街头项目的第30名。阿拉伯联合酋长国沙迦，以及 2023 Street Pro Tour 意大利罗马站第 17 名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在滑板运动中，受伤是不可避免的，但在讨论痛苦和挫折时，崔表示——发挥出了超出她年龄的韧性。 “当我开始玩滑板时，我觉得这很有趣。后来我意识到人们在玩滑板时会受到很多伤害。但这就是滑板运动的精神所在。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大多数时候，受伤只是这个过程的一部分，她补充道，她只是坚持下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除了日常训练之外，崔的生活也围绕着滑板。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 谈到自己的爱好，她提到了手指滑板，即用手指操纵微型滑板。她喜欢在这些旨在模仿真实滑板动作的小型滑板上表演技巧和动作。 “有时，我什至会在手机上玩滑板相关的游戏，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为中国代表团中最年轻的成员，崔女士受到了运动员们的喜爱，并收到了很多徽章作为礼物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是值得的。提到其中一项运动会名称中的“陈”字机器人吉祥物“辰辰”和她的名字一样。这就是为什么她喜欢这个吉祥物，并收集了许多带有他的徽章。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 崔女士与曾代表中国参加2021年东京奥运会的银牌得主曾建立了密切的联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 曾表示，崔是“中国队的未来”。 &amp;ldquo;我觉得她很优秀。未来我们将并肩前行。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xingwen@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - ESPORTS MARKS MILESTONE AT ASIAN GAMES IN HANGZHOU]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_001_65149896ed50d203d2c9fbe6.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/001/20230928_002_01_34117.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/001/20230928_002_01_41117.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 将电子竞技列为官方正式项目，这是一个里程碑亚运会奖牌颁奖典礼目前正在浙江省省会杭州举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 亚洲各地运动员的目光都集中在亚运会上，其中许多人将亚运会的加入视为最新的推动力&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月，亚洲电子竞技联合会主席霍启刚在广东深圳举行的2023年全球电子竞技峰会上发表讲话时表示：“亚洲电子竞技产业正在蓬勃发展，并已经释放出其巨大的潜力。它具有将不同背景、文化、国家和地区的人们联系在一起的力量。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2018年首都雅加达亚运会，电子竞技首次作为表演项目被列入亚运会印度尼西亚队夺得两金一银。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为今年杭州的正式奖牌运动，电子竞技共有七项比赛：王者荣耀亚运版、Dota 2、梦幻三国2、 《英雄联盟》、《绝地求生》手游亚运版、《街头霸王V》、《EA SPORTS》 FIFA品牌的足球比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国队参加了七项赛事中的六项，除了《街头霸王V》。中国队的31名球员是从125名候选人中选拔出来的，而国家队的五名球员六支队伍的教练是从27名参赛者中选出的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国英雄联盟队伍主教练朱凯表示：“从2012年开始，我在英雄联盟工作了11年，我执教过许多职业俱乐部并赢得过比赛。不过，执教英雄联盟国家队参加亚运会，对我来说是一种特殊的荣誉和责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我要做的就是确保我们的队员有最好的状态参加亚运会” 。我们根据2018年雅加达亚运会和职业联赛的经验，在项目开始前就做了周密的计划。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 朱说，他的球员平均每天训练10个小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在我们的集训期间，我们为队员们做了很多准备工作，包括心理疏导、重大体育赛事的训练、甚至性格测试，”朱补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这样的经历对于年轻选手来说是新鲜的，他们中的大多数都是第一次加入国家队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这一代选手经历了电子竞技的急剧发展。在过去的十年里。成熟的职业联赛体系、国家队的热烈支持、快速发展的产业，这些对于很多刚接触电子竞技的玩家来说是难以想象的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 吉星，中国职业联赛主教练2018年亚运会金牌得主传奇队告诉新华社：“十年前，当我加入第一个电子竞技俱乐部时，我感觉自己仿佛走进了一家隐藏在老街区的网吧。 。但看看我们现在拥有的。这个行业发展如此之快，有些俱乐部甚至拥有了自己的大楼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 自2012年加入该行业以来，吉曾担任过许多职务，包括战术分析师、教练、领队和俱乐部经理。他迄今为止最难忘的职业记忆是2018年亚运会，当时他带领中国队在表演项目上夺得金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我看到体育冠军为我们的国家赢得了荣誉，但没想到有一天我也会做同样的事情。能够为这个行业做出贡献，我感到非常荣幸。”季说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 电竞火爆的一个重要原因是游戏产业的快速发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月2023全球电竞峰会暨腾讯电竞年会发布发展报告预计到今年年底，全球电子竞技观众将达到 5.74 亿，而到 2025 年，这一数字可能将增长至 6.41 亿。报告称，到今年年底，全球电子竞技收入预计将达到18亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2月份，中国音像和数字出版协会电子竞技发布的报告委员会称，去年中国电子竞技观众和玩家总数达到4.88亿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 腾讯游戏副总裁、腾讯电竞总经理侯火星表示，“电子竞技是数字时代蓬勃发展的新兴产业” ，我们拥有数以百万计的电竞选手和观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们期待与更多合作伙伴在国际交流、人才选拔培养、数字体育研究、行业标准化等方面进行进一步的交流与合作”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;梦想成真&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将电子竞技纳入重大赛事对于许多在该行业工作的人来说是梦想成真，包括中国英雄联盟队前主教练吉认为，这将进一步推动该行业的全球增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “电子竞技纳入亚运会将使更多人参与其中亚洲乃至全世界都在熟悉电子竞技，更多的人可能会决定加入这个大家庭。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除了亚运会，电子竞技在其他地方也受到关注。例如，3月份举办的奥林匹克电子竞技系列赛，是国际奥委会（IOC）与国际单项体育联合会和游戏发行商合作打造的全球虚拟模拟体育赛事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首届奥林匹克电子竞技周在新加坡举行。为期四天的盛典展示了多项优质虚拟体育赛事以及最新的模拟体育技术和创新成果。本次活动旨在支持奥林匹克运动中电子竞技的发展，并与竞技游戏界进行互动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与亚运会的电子竞技比赛项目不同，奥林匹克电子竞技周选择了10场比赛国际奥委会主席托马斯·巴赫 (Thomas Bach) 在 5 月份表示，“我们对电子竞技的态度是优先考虑虚拟体育项目” ;意思是现实体育——有体育活动的地方，例如骑自行车和划船。与此同时，甚至还有电子形式的跆拳道以及其他一些运动项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些运动员的身体活动与从事传统运动的运动员处于同一水平。无论您是在家骑自行车参加环法自行车赛的一段赛程，还是进行真正的比赛，身体活动和挑战都是一样的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2021 年，国际奥委会一致通过了《奥林匹克议程2020+5》，其中包括鼓励虚拟体育的发展以及进一步与视频游戏社区互动。但也有一些“红线”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 巴赫表示，“对于电子游戏来说，有一条非常清晰的红线。与奥林匹克价值观相矛盾的游戏，例如杀手游戏或歧视性游戏，是奥林匹克运动绝对的禁忌。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;不仅仅是运动员&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 虽然很多年轻的电竞爱好者只能梦想成为顶尖选手，但这个行业并不只是舞台上的耀眼人物，它还包含了各种各样的人才，包括游戏设计师、战队经理和主播。&lt;/p>; &lt;季说：“电子竞技是一个可以与很多其他领域合作的产业。未来会和更多的行业对接，会创造更多的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “比如教练员的转型需要专家。”战术和决策转化为数据和可视化信息，以便我们更好地分析我们的战术。我们需要更多的人才。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ji补充道，职业选手的标准非常高，但并不是所有热爱电竞的人都能成为顶尖选手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “确实有才华的职业选手不会沉迷于游戏。他们必须高效并快速完成任务。此外，成为一名成功的职业选手需要的不仅仅是拥有良好的技能。球员需要有坚强的心态，懂得与球队很好的配合。”季补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 解说员管泽元就是这样的一个例子，他在电子竞技方面表现出色，但作为一名选手却表现不佳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我想成为一名职业选手，但很明显我的天赋不够，”关说，他充满激情的评论风格在社交媒体上吸引了超过 750 万粉丝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我想继续参与电子竞技。记得2017年我第一次去巴西担任解说员时，观众的热情给我留下了深刻的印象。这是我第一次感觉到对电子竞技的热情可以像足球比赛一样高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “电子竞技教会了我很多东西，包括需要坚持，这是成功的关键。在这个行业里，我遇到了很多优秀的人，他们教会了我很多东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;shifutian@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - ESPORTS MARKS MILESTONE AT ASIAN GAMES IN HANGZHOU]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_002_65149896ed50d203d2c9fbe7.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/002/20230928_002_01_34117.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/002/20230928_002_01_41117.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 将电子竞技列为官方正式项目，这是一个里程碑亚运会奖牌颁奖典礼目前正在浙江省省会杭州举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 亚洲各地运动员的目光都集中在亚运会上，其中许多人将亚运会的加入视为最新的推动力&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月，亚洲电子竞技联合会主席霍启刚在广东深圳举行的2023年全球电子竞技峰会上发表讲话时表示：“亚洲电子竞技产业正在蓬勃发展，并已经释放出其巨大的潜力。它具有将不同背景、文化、国家和地区的人们联系在一起的力量。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2018年首都雅加达亚运会，电子竞技首次作为表演项目被列入亚运会印度尼西亚队夺得两金一银。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为今年杭州的正式奖牌运动，电子竞技共有七项比赛：王者荣耀亚运版、Dota 2、梦幻三国2、 《英雄联盟》、《绝地求生》手游亚运版、《街头霸王V》、《EA SPORTS》 FIFA品牌的足球比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国队参加了七项赛事中的六项，除了《街头霸王V》。中国队的31名球员是从125名候选人中选拔出来的，而国家队的五名球员六支队伍的教练是从27名参赛者中选出的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国英雄联盟队伍主教练朱凯表示：“从2012年开始，我在英雄联盟工作了11年，我执教过许多职业俱乐部并赢得过比赛。不过，执教英雄联盟国家队参加亚运会，对我来说是一种特殊的荣誉和责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我要做的就是确保我们的队员有最好的状态参加亚运会” 。我们根据2018年雅加达亚运会和职业联赛的经验，在项目开始前就做了周密的计划。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 朱说，他的球员平均每天训练10个小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在我们的集训期间，我们为队员们做了很多准备工作，包括心理疏导、重大体育赛事的训练、甚至性格测试，”朱补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这样的经历对于年轻选手来说是新鲜的，他们中的大多数都是第一次加入国家队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这一代选手经历了电子竞技的急剧发展。在过去的十年里。成熟的职业联赛体系、国家队的热烈支持、快速发展的产业，这些对于很多刚接触电子竞技的玩家来说是难以想象的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 吉星，中国职业联赛主教练2018年亚运会金牌得主传奇队告诉新华社：“十年前，当我加入第一个电子竞技俱乐部时，我感觉自己仿佛走进了一家隐藏在老街区的网吧。 。但看看我们现在拥有的。这个行业发展如此之快，有些俱乐部甚至拥有了自己的大楼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 自2012年加入该行业以来，吉曾担任过许多职务，包括战术分析师、教练、领队和俱乐部经理。他迄今为止最难忘的职业记忆是2018年亚运会，当时他带领中国队在表演项目上夺得金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我看到体育冠军为我们的国家赢得了荣誉，但没想到有一天我也会做同样的事情。能够为这个行业做出贡献，我感到非常荣幸。”季说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 电竞火爆的一个重要原因是游戏产业的快速发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月2023全球电竞峰会暨腾讯电竞年会发布发展报告预计到今年年底，全球电子竞技观众将达到 5.74 亿，而到 2025 年，这一数字可能将增长至 6.41 亿。报告称，到今年年底，全球电子竞技收入预计将达到18亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2月份，中国音像和数字出版协会电子竞技发布的报告委员会称，去年中国电子竞技观众和玩家总数达到4.88亿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 腾讯游戏副总裁、腾讯电竞总经理侯火星表示，“电子竞技是数字时代蓬勃发展的新兴产业” ，我们拥有数以百万计的电竞选手和观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们期待与更多合作伙伴在国际交流、人才选拔培养、数字体育研究、行业标准化等方面进行进一步的交流与合作.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Dream come true&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The inclusion of esports at a major event is a dream come true for many people who work in the sector, including Ji, former head coach of the Chinese League of Legends squad, who believes it will further boost the industry&amp;#39;s global growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The inclusion of esports at the Asian Games will allow more people in Asia and the world to familiarize themselves with esports, and more of them will probably decide to join this big family,&amp;quot; Ji said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the Asian Games, esports has attracted attention elsewhere. For example, the Olympic Esports Series, which was staged in March, is a global virtual and simulated sports competition created by the International Olympic Committee, or IOC, in collaboration with international federations and games publishers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In June, the first-ever Olympic Esports Week was staged in Singapore. The four-day festival showcased a number of quality virtual sports and the latest simulated sports technologies and innovations. This event is designed to support the development of esports within the Olympic Movement and to engage with the competitive games community.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Different from the esports events at the Asian Games, the 10 games at the Olympic Esports Week were chosen by international federations to represent their sports, which are mostly simulations of traditional sports such as baseball, cycling and tennis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; IOC President Thomas Bach said in May, &amp;quot;Our approach to esports is to prioritize virtual sports &amp;mdash; meaning reality sports &amp;mdash; where there is physical activity, such as cycling and rowing. In the meantime, there is even an electronic form of taekwondo, along with a number of other sports.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The physical activity of these athletes is on the same level as those engaged in traditional sports. Whether you&amp;#39;re doing a leg of the Tour de France on your cycle at home, or doing the real leg, the physical activity and the challenges are the same.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2021, the IOC unanimously approved the Olympic Agenda 2020+5, which includes encouraging the development of virtual sports and engaging further with video games communities. But there are some &amp;quot;red lines&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Bach said, &amp;quot;When it comes to e-games, there is a very clear red line. Games that are contradictory to Olympic values, such as killer games or those that are discriminatory, are absolutely taboo to the Olympic Movement.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;More than players&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While many young esports enthusiasts can only dream of becoming top players, the industry is not solely about those who shine on the stage, as it comprises a variety of talent, including games designers, team managers and broadcasters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ji said: &amp;quot;Esports is an industry that can cooperate with many other sectors. In the future, it will be connected to more industries, which will create increased opportunities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For example, there is a need for experts to transform coaches&amp;#39; tactics and decisions into data and visual information so that we can better analyze our tactics. We need more talent.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ji added that there are extremely high standards for professional players, but not all those who love esports will make it to the top.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Truly talented professional players are not addicted to games. They have to be highly efficient and complete their tasks quickly. Moreover, becoming a successful professional player requires a lot more than merely having good skills. A player needs to have a strong mentality and know how to cooperate well with the team,&amp;quot; Ji added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One such example is commentator Guan Zeyuan, who has done well in esports, but not as a player.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I wanted to become a professional player, but it was obvious that I&amp;#39;m not talented enough,&amp;quot; said Guan, whose passionate style of commentary has attracted more than 7.5 million followers on social media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I want to continue being involved with esports. I remember the first time that I went to Brazil to work as a commentator in 2017. I was deeply impressed by the passion of the spectators. It was the first time I felt that the level of passion for esports could be as high as that for a soccer match.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Esports has taught me a lot, including the need to be persistent, which is key to being successful. In this industry, I have met many great people, who have taught me a lot.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;shifutian@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Industrial profits rebound to buoy economic recovery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_003_65149899ed50d203d2c9fbe8.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s economic recovery is likely to accelerate over the rest of the year after industrial profits rebounded strongly in August, signaling that the growth of the world&amp;#39;s second-largest economy is back on a firmer footing and the supportive government policies have begun to take effect, economists said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While the green shoots of recovery have strengthened their confidence that China is on track to achieve its annual growth target of around 5 percent in 2023, economists said the country still needs to grapple with stress in the property market as well as the still-weak demand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking to the rest of the year, they expect to see more property easing policies, forceful fiscal measures and a third round of cuts across key policy rates, to support the growth of the Chinese economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data from the National Bureau of Statistics showed on Wednesday that China&amp;#39;s industrial profits rebounded in August for the first time in more than a year, adding to signs that the economy had bottomed out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Industrial enterprises with annual revenue of at least 20 million yuan ($2.7 million) each saw their total profits jump 17.2 percent year-on-year in August after a 6.7 percent decline in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Weining, a statistician at the NBS, attributed the improvement in industrial profits to the steady rebound in industrial production and improved corporate profitability with a series of stimulus measures gradually taking effect.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the January-August period, industrial firms&amp;#39; profits fell 11.7 percent year-on-year to 4.66 trillion yuan, narrowing from the 15.5 percent drop in the first seven months, the bureau said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Looking ahead, the decline in industrial profits will continue to narrow in the first nine months given the improvement in producer prices and the base effect,&amp;quot; said Zheng Houcheng, chief macro economist at Yingda Securities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;While industrial companies still face pressures amid lackluster demand, a series of recently released supportive measures, such as tax and fee reductions and boosting technological innovation, will significantly strengthen the market confidence and benefit companies&amp;#39; future development,&amp;quot; said Ding Yue, deputy general manager at Zolix, a Beijing-based supplier of optical instruments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that as the producer price index is poised to rebound from the bottom gradually, declines in industrial profits will further narrow in the near future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; NBS data showed China&amp;#39;s industrial output jumped 4.5 percent in August, up from a 3.7 percent increase in July. And China&amp;#39;s August producer price index, which gauges factory-gate prices, was down 3 percent from a year earlier after the 4.4 percent annual contraction seen in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Recent data suggests that the economy likely bottomed out in July, and that activity is indeed now moving in the right direction,&amp;quot; said Louise Loo, lead economist at British think tank Oxford Economics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She added that her team, therefore, maintained its China growth forecast for 2023 at 5.1 percent, expecting GDP growth to pick up pace in the third and fourth quarters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While most hard macro data is now on a firmer footing than in July, Loo said there remain two lingering areas of weakness &amp;mdash; property and sentiment. &amp;quot;Data on sentiment remains subdued, reflecting the extent of the confidence crisis among homebuyers, consumers, and investors, notwithstanding the cyclical support to activity from stimulus.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking forward, she said her team assumes local governments will be tasked to step up their infrastructure on-balance sheet spending, a more prudent policy response compared to past easing cycles. On the monetary policy front, she expects a third round of cuts of 10 basis points across key policy rates this year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The People&amp;#39;s Bank of China, the country&amp;#39;s central bank, has vowed to continuously support the real economy and strengthen policy adjustments as the country&amp;#39;s economic recovery is picking up pace, despite still facing a harsh external environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The PBOC said in a statement on Wednesday that it will intensify the implementation of the monetary policy tools that have been introduced to ensure a reasonably ample level of liquidity while encouraging a rebound in price levels to maintain them within a reasonable range.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Maohua, an analyst at China Everbright Bank, said the country will likely step up the use of structural monetary tools to support the weak links in the real economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at ouyangshijia@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China&#39;s first suspended monorail line launched]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_003_6514989ced50d203d2c9fbe9.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/003/20230928_003_02_113923.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A suspended monorail train undergoes a test run in May in Wuhan, Hubei province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s first commercial suspended monorail line opened to the public on Tuesday in Wuhan, the capital of Hubei province, offering commuters a surreal experience like riding a futuristic vehicle in a sci-fi movie.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Zhengying, a local resident who took the train on Wednesday, called her journey &amp;quot;extremely cool &amp;quot;and said she would bring her family for a ride the next time. &amp;quot;The view from the railcar was splendid. It was a fun ride,&amp;quot; Li added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The operational first phase of the project covers a total distance of 10.5 kilometers and has six stations in the Optics Valley of China, a national innovation demonstration zone in Wuhan, according to Optics Valley Traffic Company, the operator of the line. The maximum operating speed of the monorail train is 60 km per hour and the two cars have a joint passenger capacity of 220. The transparent glass floor offers commuters an aerial view of the city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The line operates for 12 hours each day, between 8 am and 8 pm, with a train departing every 10 minutes. The entire operation process is fully automated and requires no human intervention, unless there is an emergency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Anjun, head of the equipment system division of the monorail, said the number of passengers on the first two days exceeded their expectations. The railway operator had to bring down the train departure interval to eight minutes to clear the rush. The interval will be further shortened to cope with the sea of tourists during the National Day holiday, Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Commuters can buy a monthly ticket with an unlimited number of rides for 120 yuan ($16). Onetime and one-day tickets cost 30 yuan each till Oct 6, the end of the National Day holiday period. The one-day and one-time ticket fares after the holiday are yet to be announced.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Honggang, chief designer of China Railway Fourth Survey and Design Institute Group, one of the construction companies involved in the project, said the monorail route is very scenic as it links parks, lakes and hills in the Optics Valley.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Kecheng, senior designer at CRRC Qingdao Sifang, another company involved in the project, said the monorail uses multiple shock absorbers to increase the stability of the railcars and offer passengers a smoother ride.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The railcars are made of light aluminum alloy to reduce weight, and boasts flywheel energy storage system, which converts electrical energy into kinetic energy for reuse during braking, the senior designer said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huang Yingru said she brought her son from Shenzhen, Guangdong province, to Wuhan for a monorail ride during the trial runs in summer. &amp;quot;My son had seen videos of the suspended train online and wanted to take a ride. He was so excited and happy during the whole journey, especially because he could see the city through the glass floor. It was an amazing experience for both of us,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at zoushuo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Travel rush]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_003_6514989eed50d203d2c9fbea.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/003/20230928_003_03_59923.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Passengers throng the Lianyungang Railway Station in Jiangsu province on Wednesday, the first day of the National Day holiday travel period, which will continue till Oct 8.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Chinese tech firm count at Asiad mirrors progress]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/28/content_003_651498a1ed50d203d2c9fbeb.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-28/003/20230928_003_04_76923.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A robot delivers newspapers on Tuesday at the Main Media Center for the Asian Games in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The strong presence of Chinese internet and technology companies as sponsors of the 19th Asian Games has grabbed the attention of viewers around the world. This demonstrates China&amp;#39;s great achievements in the digital sector and its strengths in technological innovation, experts said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The event, which is ongoing in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province, has attracted a record 176 sponsors. Among the 11 official prestige partners, five are Chinese internet and technology companies, according to the organizing committee of the Games.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These five enterprises are tech heavyweight Alibaba Group Holding Ltd, telecom operators China Mobile and China Telecom, Alibaba Group&amp;#39;s mobile payment platform Alipay and cybersecurity company DAS-Security.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Moreover, Chinese artificial intelligence company SenseTime and short-video app Kuaishou are among the 16 official exclusive suppliers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By comparison, there were only 52 sponsors for the 16th Asian Games held in 2010 in Guangzhou, Guangdong province, with only three companies from the internet and tech sector &amp;mdash; China Mobile, online gaming company NetEase Inc and consumer electronics maker TCL Technology Group Corp.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing unit of Alibaba Group, said it is providing fundamental technological support for event management and results distribution, as well as making live cloud broadcasting signals available for the 19th Asian Games.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company is also helping build a digital platform to achieve efficient and intelligent scheduling of personnel, vehicles and services in the Asian Games Village.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We believe that technological innovation plays a significant role in driving digital transformation for sports events,&amp;quot; said Selina Yuan, president of international business at Alibaba Cloud Intelligence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Migu, the digital content unit of China Mobile, is offering live-streaming services for the Hangzhou Games by leveraging its advantages in fields such as 5G and 4K ultra high-definition resolution.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan Helin, co-director of the Digital Economy and Financial Innovation Research Center at Zhejiang University&amp;#39;s International Business School, said, &amp;quot;By sponsoring the Asian Games, Chinese technology companies can boost their brand awareness and influence among overseas consumers, and showcase their technological prowess and innovation capabilities.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The strong presence of Chinese internet and technology companies in a top-notch international event reflects the country&amp;#39;s rapid progress in cutting-edge technologies, such as 5G, cloud computing and AI, as well as its growing competitiveness in science and technology on the global stage, Pan added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s strength in sci-tech innovations has taken a qualitative leap in recent years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the 2022 Global Innovation Index released by the World Intellectual Property Organization, the country has jumped to the 11th spot and remains the only middle-income economy among the top 30.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;fanfeifei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>