<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - More signals of stabilizing ties urged]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_001_6551422bed50d203d2ca26a7.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_001_01_137863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;舞龙舞狮舞蹈表演将于周六晚上在旧金山唐人街上演，这是该市吸引游客和与会者参加即将举行的亚太经济合作组织会议的努力的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src= &quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_001_01_154863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;周六在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织会议海报，美国加利福尼亚州。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在不稳定因素日益加剧和经济不稳定的情况下，稳定中美商业关系并防止经济“脱钩”的努力将有利于两国企业和消费者。专家和商界领袖周日表示，全球经济存在不确定性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们还表示，随着备受期待的两国领导人会晤临近，需要发出更多积极信号，因为这些信号不仅有助于增强两国的信心，而且有助于增强两国人民的信心。中国国际经济交流中心首席研究员张燕生表示，“美国国内存在一些极端分子，追求‘经济脱钩’” #39；两国依靠稳定、高层的沟通对话机制，讨论共同关心的问题，改善双边经济关系至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 39、中美两国最大的经济体，经济关系的改善将为世界经济注入更大的正能量，特别是在美国通胀持续存在、全球投资和贸易大幅放缓的情况下。张说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，中美经济关系的不确定性对其他严重依赖全球贸易的国家的发展产生了负面影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京外交学院国际关系学院表示，美国对中国的限制性措施，特别是在先进技术领域，最终将适得其反。李说，这将对美国企业的利益造成很大损害，美国企业不能放弃中国巨大的市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说，美国增加了如此多的产品，这是不公平的。将中国企业列入出口黑名单“实体清单”，中方通过对话表达对此类问题的关切具有重要意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “对两国人民负责”两国和世界其他国家必须达成共识，保持良好的经济关系，共同维护世界发展。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “美方应采取实际行动推动双边经济关系发展，中方也应继续致力于进一步深化改革、扩大开放，加强与美国的经贸关系。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 美国水务技术提供商赛莱默公司中国及亚洲区总裁吕书平强调，和谐的中美商业关系有助于在华美国企业的发展。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 尽管外部存在不确定性，中国仍成为该公司第二大单一市场——仅落后于美国市场——吕说，“通过销售收入，以及具有长期战略意义的市场。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 赛莱默不仅扩大了在中国市场的影响力，还将其在中国制造的产品大量出口到中国。吕补充说，“一带一路”沿线国家和区域全面经济伙伴关系协定几乎所有签署国均已参加。多轮“坦诚、务实、深入、建设性”对话在旧金山举行会谈。预计此次会谈将有助于推动习近平主席与美国总统拜登举行富有成果的会晤。专家表示，去年11月两国元首在印度尼西亚巴厘岛会晤达成重要共识后，此次会晤备受期待。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 代表中国处理经济问题的何副总理据财政部称，应耶伦邀请于周三至周日访问美国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 财政部副部长廖敏在旧金山举行的新闻发布会上表示&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 廖表示，双方同意加强沟通，寻求共识，管控分歧，避免因误会而导致摩擦意外升级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方还强调，中美不谋求经济“脱钩”，一致同意两国将携手应对共同挑战，在气候变化、低收入和低收入国家债务等问题上开展合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，中国对美国的做法表达了担忧。限制双向投资、制裁中国企业、出口管制和额外关税。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 耶伦在周五的新闻发布会上表示，美中关系是“最重要的关系之一” ”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “它所走的道路将为我们两国和世界各地的人们带来机遇和挑战，”耶伦说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “过去两天在旧金山举行的会议又向前迈出了一步，”耶伦说道。她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：zhongnan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Humanitarian crisis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_001_6551422ded50d203d2ca26a8.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_001_02_115863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦人抵达汗尤尼斯逃离加沙北部的家园后，周六在加沙地带南部。巴以冲突不断升级，引发严重人道主义危机。查看更多内容，第 8、11 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Top food policy expert hails nation&#39;s efforts to bolster its grain resilience]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_001_65514230ed50d203d2ca26a9.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_001_03_171863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;布拉姆·戈瓦茨&lt;/p >; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_001_03_136863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;在线扫码查看更多。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 中国最近努力遏制对粮食进口的依赖并增加农业研究经费，帮助世界领先的粮食进口国增强应对全球粮食价格上涨和供应链困境的能力，国际粮食政策专家表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国为发展粮食生产做出了巨大努力，”总部位于墨西哥巴坦的国际玉米和小麦改良中心总干事布拉姆·戈瓦茨说。 “中国在粮食安全方面投入了大量资金。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 戈瓦茨在本月初对北京进行为期一周的访问期间发表了上述言论，他在北京寻求在中断后与中国研究人员恢复合作关系&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts 表示，中国最近在增加农作物产量和对技术驱动的育种技​​术（包括基因编辑）的投资方面所做的努力提高了产量，并使该国&amp;#34; #39;食品供应更具弹性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “多元化供应链的发展帮助中国快速应对”， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 10月下旬，农业农村部表示，今年全国粮食产量预计连续第九年超过6.5亿吨，创历史新高。尽管一些农田在夏季遭受热浪和暴雨袭击，但产量仍创下历史新高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 官员们在一次会议上表示，产量增加的部分原因是种植面积扩大和高产作物品种的采用。商务部市场与信息司司长刘汉表示，一系列因素导致全球大米价格创15年新高，其中包括更多极端天气事件。刘说，保护主义抬头​​、地区冲突以及印度因干旱引发的出口禁令。相比之下，9月份中国国内大米采购价格仅比1月份上涨0.7%。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 戈瓦尔茨表示，中国稳定的粮食供应是世界的福音。 “如果中国缺乏粮食安全，就会给供应链带来压力，因为这是一个人口众多的大国，”他说。他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他将全球粮食安全的现状描述为“可怕”，并表示“一场冲突就可能破坏全球小麦供应的稳定，并且由于我们在一个地方发生的冲突，全世界”。”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts 表示，当前的粮食供应系统很脆弱。 “我们需要韧性，因为如果今天发生地区冲突，明天就会出现疾病，”他说。他说。 “如果我们不加以阻止，气候变化可能会毁掉整个粮食领域。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些挑战意味着世界需要改造其粮食供应系统，因为各国生产的粮食占其粮食总量的比例更大。他说，当地的食物组合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 政府还需要增加小农的收入。他补充道，获得创新技术、更好的种子和信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts 表示，最近中国推动本土转基因玉米和大豆品种商业化的成果非常令人鼓舞，将有助于减少农药的使用，并补充道，转基因生物“需要成为您工具箱中可用的技术”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，中国在 20 世纪 60 年代曾为养活自己的人口而努力奋斗，但现在已经转型为农业强国，这要归功于数十年的农业投资。如今，中国拥有高素质的科学家、强大的数据处理能力、分子育种技术和制种能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 戈瓦茨表示，中国是全球种质资源共享的旗手——对于开发更高产、更有营养的作物或动物品种至关重要的遗传资源。他赞扬中国向非洲派遣农业技术人员的努力，作为更广泛的“一带一路”倡议的一部分，以帮助促进饥饿地区的粮食生产，从而有利于全球粮食安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国真正将所有国际演员聚集在一起，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;lilei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Singles Day shopping gala drives recovery of consumption]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_001_65514233ed50d203d2ca26aa.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 今年“双11”购物盛宴，中国消费者涌入电商平台，抢购价值千亿元的折扣商品，推高了国产品牌和高端产品的销量&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 专家表示，这体现了中国消费市场的巨大活力和韧性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为中国年度最大的购物盛会，双十一他们补充说，“11”或“11-11”促销晚会从10月下旬开始，到周六达到顶峰，对刺激人们的购买欲望、促进消费复苏和经济增长发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 过去的双11节日的特点是通过折扣带动销售，创造了创纪录的商品交易额（GMV）。然而，行业观察人士表示，追逐高 GMV 已不再是焦点，他们指出，中国购物者正变得更加理性，仔细审视自己的需求，注重质量和价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 天猫、中国科技重量级阿里巴巴该集团的企业对客户平台表示，从 10 月 31 日晚上 8 点到周六午夜，402 个品牌（包括 243 个国内品牌）的销售额超过 1 亿元人民币（1,370 万美元）。在此期间，38,000个品牌的成交额同比激增超过100%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 阿里巴巴和另一家知名电商平台京东均未透露今年购物的具体GMV数据。狂欢。阿里巴巴仅表示，用户和商户规模出现“显着”增长，带动了订单量和 GMV 的整体增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 京东表示，其交易量、订单量和用户参与度“达到了创历史新高”。为期数周的促销盛会，超过60个品牌销售额突破10亿元，近2万个品牌成交额同比增长三倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国年轻消费者越来越多地选择优质本土品牌，其中，90后、2000后的消费额占国产品牌总销售额的62%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，高端电子设备在京东的成交额激增。线上市场，可折叠智能手机上涨300%，数码相机上涨100%，游戏笔记本电脑上涨50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “消费已成为提振中国的主要动力”随着经济的增长，双十一购物节对于释放消费者的热情至关重要。购买潜力和促进经济复苏，”国家发改委宏观经济研究院研究员王云表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王云表示，国产品牌，特别是融入中国传统元素的创意设计，在中国和海外市场越来越受欢迎。 #39;的年轻一代，他们的民族自豪感和对中华文化的信心日益增强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;更有意义&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年的王说，双11促销活动具有更重要的意义，因为这是中国优化COVID-19应对措施以来的第一次，并补充说，中国的消费市场已获得增长动力，总体增长率预计将达到7%左右今年双十一期间，各大电商强调低价，促销手段更加简单，直接降价是首选策略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Britton Russell 是全球咨询公司 Alix-Partners 的消费者和零售业务负责人。中国区表示，2023年是疫情后第一个光棍节，消费回归正常水平。我们看到情绪和支出更加强劲，与 2022 年相比，总支出增长了 18%”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 虽然基于价值的购物并不是什么新鲜事，但消费者对潜在购买比以往任何时候都更加谨慎和了解他说，因为他们追求每次购买的最大价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Russell 还强调，“理性消费推动的是对品质的追求，而不是浮华的促销”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jason Yu，将军市场研究机构凯度消费者指数中国区经理表示，中国消费者在今年的购物狂潮中更加注重价值。 “他们希望购买性价比高的商品，而不是仅仅以牺牲质量为代价获得低价商品。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年前三季度中国消费市场回暖。据国家统计局数据，作为消费强度重要指标的零售额，1-9月同比增长6.8%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国消费者也愿意关注贝恩咨询公司的一份报告称，更多新颖的平台模糊了娱乐和零售之间的界限，特别是在抖音和快手等短视频平台提供的直播电子商务领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;fanfeifei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - CHINA VISIT UNDERSCORES FLYING TIGERS&#39; LEGACY]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_001_65514236ed50d203d2ca26ab.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_002_01_28911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;飞虎队队员10 月 29 日，在北京八达岭长城与飞虎队第一代、第二代和第三代传人合影。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile /2023-11-13/001/20231113_002_01_98911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;飞虎队老队员哈利·莫耶（中排左）与代表团其他成员在云南昆明观看演出。&lt;/ p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_002_01_64911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;代表们在北京向抗战英雄致敬。&lt; /p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_002_01_81911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;莫耶会见已故女儿辛西娅·陈纳德美国将军克莱尔·李·陈纳德，飞虎队队长。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/20231113_002_01_45911.png &quot; />;&lt;p>;莫耶与北京的一名小学生击掌。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/001/ 20231113_002_01_122911.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 最后幸存的飞虎队——帮助中国人民抗击日本侵略的美国二战空军老兵——刚刚获得了一次难得的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们与第一代、第二代甚至第三代飞虎队的队员们重聚并前往中国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为期10天的访问于本月初结束，代表团一行30余人参观了北京、重庆、云南省省会昆明等地的名胜古迹和旅游景点。他们还参加了友谊活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 四代人的代表都向《中国日报》讲述了他们为什么以及如何支持中美两国人民增进友谊、解决彼此之间缺乏了解的问题。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 飞虎队老兵哈利·莫耶 (Harry Moyer) 在访问中国期间迎来 103 岁生日。在完成战争期间的空军任务后，他仅在1995年访问过该国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 10月30日，莫耶在美国驻华大使馆在北京举办的活动中收到了两个大生日蛋糕&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当被问及自己的生日愿望时，莫耶说：“给大家讲笑话，把快乐、祝福与和平传播到全世界，让与所有人的伟大友谊。这就是我们必须拥有的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说世界上的人们“必须团结起来”，并补充说，“因为逆境而做到这一点是一件很难的事情” ，但是如果人们努力的话，这是一件很容易做到的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 飞虎队的该任务始于 1941 年，由美国第一志愿兵团承担，该团于 1942 年 7 月解散。美国第 14 空军于次年继续执行该任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 莫耶 (Moyer) 1941年被派往意大利执行战斗任务的他说：“当日本人进入上海和南京时，全世界的报纸、福克斯新闻片和《生活》杂志都进行了报道。”遭受日本占领的严酷考验……我只是觉得我想为此做点什么。因此，当我需要做出决定时，我就这么做了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 莫耶于 1944 年 1 月抵达中国，当时他和他的团队被调往驻华美国第 14 空军。在克莱尔·陈纳德将军的指挥下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我本可以回家——”我已经完成了足够回家的任务，但我选择和我的团队一起去中国。我一直待到 1944 年 9 月才回家。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当被问及与战时经历相比，他最近访问中国所看到的发展和变化时，莫耶说：“这太神奇了。”即使在 1995 年，这也是令人惊叹的——你在这里看到的进步，所有的建设和人民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国人民历来是勤劳的民族，这一点今天是有目共睹的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习主席习近平9月回信给莫耶、飞虎队老将梅尔·麦克马伦和中美航空遗产基金会主席杰弗里·格林，表示希望将飞虎队精神传承给下一代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 莫耶的孙子们在最近的这次旅行中与他同行，他说：“他们将获得大量有关中国及其文化的信息和历史。这是一件大事，因为中国的文化如此多元、如此古老。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;危险航班&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; David Goodrich 是他的儿子飞虎队飞行员杰克·古德里奇（Jack Goodrich）是仅存的少数“驼峰飞行员”之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这些飞行员​​从缅甸（现在的缅甸）飞越喜马拉雅山飞往昆明，运送燃料、弹药和其他补给品，中国人民需要抵抗日本人”。大卫·古德里奇说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当他还是个孩子的时候，他的父亲给他讲了有趣的儿童睡前故事，但直到他长大了很多，他才听到了更相关的故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古德里奇说，当他父亲的飞机满载物资时，在极端天气条件下飞越山峰有时会很困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;” ;他谈到了可怕的雷暴，而在那些日子里，他们没有雷达或 GPS 等技术。他们依靠仪器飞行，但由于闪电会影响仪器，所以他们必须依靠视觉飞行。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我父亲经常告诉我，中美两国在战斗中结下的友谊是最牢固的友谊，他为这些友谊至今仍然存在而感到自豪。”&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>; 他的父亲告诉他，中国人民是多么友好、热情，这个国家是多么美丽。 “这就是为什么我一直梦想着能回到祖国看看中国人民，”他说。古德里奇说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我（对中国）的印象可能主要是从电视或电影中获得的，所以亲眼目睹这个国家是压倒性的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 讨论如何更好地改进他说：“现在的学校与我上学时不同，因为你可以在网上做很多事情，但我仍然认为没有什么比来到中国和人民见面更好的了。” /p>; &lt;p>; “我们需要面对面，讲述我们的故事，分享我们共同的目标，我也相信我们都希望生活在一个和平的世界，需要让彼此知道这是最重要的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;共同点&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月30日，杨万明在北京出席美国代表团纪念活动时中国人民对外友好协会会长陈纳德在致辞时引用飞虎队创始人陈纳德回忆录《战士之路》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是我最喜欢的”希望飞虎队的标志只要有需要就一直高高挂在空中，并希望它永远被太平洋两岸铭记，作为两个伟大人民在战争与和平中为共同目标而努力的象征。”杨引述了回忆录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈纳德的孙女内尔·陈纳德·卡洛韦 (Nell Chennault Calloway) 表示，她祖父的故事以及与中国的联系始于 1937 年，当时他于 6 月 6 日抵达中国距离 7 月 7 日北京卢沟桥事件还有几周的时间 –日本全面侵华战争的开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “他亲眼所见，亲耳所闻，中国人民正在遭受酷刑，日本人也在对他做事。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “他没有关注他们的政治，他没有关注他们的意识形态，但他看到（事实）有人需要他并且1937年，陈纳德对中国军队进行了一项调查，发现中国军队有500架飞机，“但能飞的只有91架”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 四年后，他回到中国，招募了一批年轻人，组建了美国第一志愿志愿队，也就是后来的飞虎队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 队员超过2000人。飞虎队在帮助中国的过程中做出了最终的牺牲，而数千名中国人在营救遇险美国飞行员时丧生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈纳德航空军事博物馆首席执行官卡洛韦表示，她听过很多美国飞行员的故事飞机被击落后被中国人救起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这可能不是一件容易的事情，但那些中国人冒着生命危险，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 卡洛韦补充说，她的博物馆的创始人之一是一架轰炸机上的领航员，他的飞机被击落后被中国人救起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “虽然中国人正在把他送回他的人民所在的地方，他们经过了许多村庄……他们经过的每个村庄的酋长都在横幅上签下了对美国航海家的良好祝愿，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “当他回来时，情报人员说，‘你知道吗，如果日本人能够掌握那个东西，村长们就会冒着生命危险。他们签署的横幅？日本人会回去并消灭这些村庄。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 卡洛韦补充道：“这些中国人希望这名士兵一切顺利，尽管这意味着他们可能会因此而被消灭。”对我来说，这意义重大。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;青少年参与&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jackson Long，飞虎队 Clifford Long 的 15 岁曾孙先生是一代人，希望将友谊传承下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他是中国饺子的粉丝，也是高中高尔夫球队的狂热成员，给他留下最深刻印象的是曾祖父的战时故事是他在两次飞机失事中幸存下来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说中国与他从美国媒体和媒体获得的对中国的印象“有很大不同” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “仅仅通过社交媒体你无法真正了解中国的一切......你必须在这里体验中国所提供的所有令人惊叹的不同文化，” ;他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这位十年级学生强调了更好地吸引年轻人传承飞虎队精神的重要性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “如果我们只是让一群 50 多岁的人在一个房间里，了解所有这些信息，并且只留在那个群体中，那么它就不会真正被传承下去。”下一代，” ”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他补充说，当他回到美国学校时，他一定会告诉他的同学下次和他一起去中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们参观了长城，很酷。当我向他们展示我在墙上的照片时，我会告诉他们原因。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - CHINA VISIT UNDERSCORES FLYING TIGERS&#39; LEGACY]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_002_65514236ed50d203d2ca26ac.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/002/20231113_002_01_28911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;飞虎队队员10 月 29 日，在北京八达岭长城与飞虎队第一代、第二代和第三代传人合影。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile /2023-11-13/002/20231113_002_01_98911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;飞虎队老队员哈利·莫耶（中排左）与代表团其他成员在云南昆明观看演出。&lt;/ p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/002/20231113_002_01_64911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;代表们在北京向抗战英雄致敬。&lt; /p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/002/20231113_002_01_81911.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;莫耶会见陈纳德之女陈纳德美国将军克莱尔·李·陈纳德，飞虎队领导人。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/002/20231113_002_01_45911.png &quot; />;&lt;p>;莫耶在北京与一名小学生击掌。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/002/ 20231113_002_01_122911.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 最后幸存的飞虎队——帮助中国人民抗击日本侵略的美国二战空军老兵——刚刚获得了一次难得的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们与第一代、第二代甚至第三代飞虎队的队员们重聚并前往中国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为期10天的访问于本月初结束，代表团一行30余人参观了北京、重庆、云南省省会昆明等地的名胜古迹和旅游景点。他们还参加了友谊活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 四代人的代表都向《中国日报》讲述了他们为什么以及如何支持中美两国人民增进友谊、解决彼此之间缺乏了解的问题。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 飞虎队老兵哈利·莫耶 (Harry Moyer) 在访问中国期间迎来 103 岁生日。在完成战争期间的空军任务后，他仅在1995年访问过该国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 10月30日，莫耶在美国驻华大使馆在北京举办的活动中收到了两个大生日蛋糕&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当被问及自己的生日愿望时，莫耶说：“给大家讲笑话，把快乐、祝福与和平传播到全世界，让与所有人的伟大友谊。这就是我们必须拥有的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说世界上的人们“必须团结起来”，并补充说，“因为逆境而做到这一点是一件很难的事情” ，但是如果人们努力的话，这是一件很容易做到的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 飞虎队的该任务始于 1941 年，由美国第一志愿兵团承担，该团于 1942 年 7 月解散。美国第 14 空军于次年继续执行该任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 莫耶 (Moyer) 1941年被派往意大利执行战斗任务的他说：“当日本人进入上海和南京时，全世界的报纸、福克斯新闻片和《生活》杂志都进行了报道。” exposed to the harshness of the Japanese occupation &amp;hellip; and I just felt I wanted to do something about it. So when the time came for me to make a decision to do this, I did.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Moyer arrived in China in January 1944, when he and his group were transferred to the US 14th Air Force in China under the command of General Claire Chennault.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I could have gone home &amp;mdash; I had completed enough missions to go home, but I chose to go to China with my group. I stayed until September 1944, when I came home,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Asked about the developments and changes he has seen on recent visits to China compared to his wartime experiences, Moyer said: &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s amazing. Even in 1995, it was just amazing &amp;mdash; the progress that you see here, all the construction and the people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The Chinese have always been an industrious people, and this is well recognized today.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping wrote a reply letter in September to Moyer, fellow Flying Tigers veteran Mel McMullen and Sino-American Aviation Heritage Foundation Chairman Jeffrey Greene, stating that he hoped the spirit of the Flying Tigers would be passed down to the next generation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Moyer, whose grandchildren traveled with him on the recent trip, said: &amp;quot;They&amp;#39;re going to gain a lot of information and a lot of history about China and its culture. That&amp;#39;sa big thing, because the culture of China is so diverse and so ancient.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Risky flights&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; David Goodrich is the son of Flying Tigers pilot Jack Goodrich, one of the few remaining &amp;quot;Hump Pilots&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;These pilots flew from Burma (now Myanmar) into Kunming over the Himalayas to deliver fuel, ammunition and other supplies that the Chinese people needed to resist the Japanese,&amp;quot; David Goodrich said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When he was a boy, his father told him funny children&amp;#39;s bedtime stories, but it wasn&amp;#39;t until he was much older that he heard stories that were more related to the war.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Goodrich said that when his father&amp;#39;s plane was heavily loaded with supplies, it was sometimes challenging to fly over mountain peaks in extreme weather conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;He talked about horrible electrical storms, and in those days, they didn&amp;#39;t have radar or technology such as GPS. They flew by instruments, but as lightning would affect the instruments, they had to fly by sight,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;My father often told me that the friendships forged between the Chinese and Americans during battle were the strongest friendships, and that he is proud that those friendships still exist today.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His father told him how friendly and warm the Chinese people are and how beautiful the country is. &amp;quot;That&amp;#39;s why it&amp;#39;s long been a dream for me to come and see the Chinese people in their homeland,&amp;quot; Goodrich said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;My impression (of China) was maybe gained mostly from television or movies, so to see the country for myself was overwhelming.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Discussing ways to better engage the younger generation from both nations, he said, &amp;quot;Schools now are different to when I was a schoolboy, because you can do so many things online, but I still think that nothing actually beats coming to China and meeting the people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We need to see each other face to face, tell our stories and share our common goals, and I also believe that we all want to live in a world of peace and need to let each other know that this is what is the most important.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Common grounds&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At a commemorative event attended by the US delegation in Beijing on Oct 30, Yang Wanming, president of the Chinese People&amp;#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries, quoted from Way of a Fighter, a memoir of Flying Tigers founder Chennault, when delivering a speech.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It is my fondest hope that the sign of the Flying Tigers remains aloft just as long as it is needed, and that it will always be remembered on both shores of the Pacific as the symbol of two great peoples working toward a common goal in war and peace,&amp;quot; Yang quoted from the memoir.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nell Chennault Calloway, Chennault&amp;#39;s granddaughter, said her grandfather&amp;#39;s story and bonds with China began in 1937, when he arrived in the country in June, six weeks ahead of the Lugou Bridge Incident in Beijing on July 7 &amp;mdash; the start of Japan&amp;#39;s full-scale invasion of China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;He saw and heard that Chinese people were being tortured, and the Japanese were also doing things to him,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;He didn&amp;#39;t look at their politics, he didn&amp;#39;t look at their ideologies, but he looked at (the fact) that there were people who needed him and the skills he had been working on for 20 years.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1937, Chennault carried out a survey of the Chinese military, finding that it had 500 airplanes, &amp;quot;but only 91 that could fly&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Four years later, he returned to China and recruited a group of young men, forming the First American Volunteer Group, later known as the Flying Tigers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than 2,000 members of the Flying Tigers made the ultimate sacrifice while helping China, while thousands of Chinese lost their lives rescuing US pilots in distress.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Calloway, also CEO of Chennault Aviation and Military Museum, said she has heard many accounts of US pilots being saved by Chinese after their planes were shot down.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;That may not be an easy thing to do, but those Chinese risked their lives,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Calloway added that one of the founders of her museum was a navigator on a bomber, who was rescued by Chinese after his plane was shot down.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;While the Chinese were getting him back to where his people were, they went through many villages &amp;hellip;The chiefs of every village they passed through signed a banner of good wishes to the US navigator,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;When he got back, the intelligence people said, &amp;#39;Do you realize the village chiefs were putting their own lives at risk if the Japanese had been able to get hold of that banner they signed? The Japanese would have gone back and wiped out the villages&amp;#39;.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Calloway added: &amp;quot;These Chinese wished this soldier well, even though it meant they could be destroyed for doing so. To me, that means so much.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Youth engagement&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jackson Long, the 15-year-old great-grandson of Flying Tiger Clifford Long Sr, is a member of the generation that is expected to carry forward the legacy of friendship.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A fan of Chinese dumplings, and an avid member of his high school golf team, what impresses him most of all his great-grandfather&amp;#39;s wartime stories is that he managed to survive two plane crashes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said China is &amp;quot;a lot different &amp;quot;from the impression he gained of the country from the US media and politicians.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;You can&amp;#39;t really grasp everything about China just by looking at social media ... you have to be here to experience all the amazing different cultures that China has to offer,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 10th-grade student underlined the importance of better engaging young people to pass on the Flying Tigers&amp;#39; legacy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;If we just got a bunch of people in their 50s in a room, learned all this information, and it just stayed with that group, it wouldn&amp;#39;t really get carried on to the next generation,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that when he returned to his school in the US, he would definitely tell his fellow students to visit China with him the next time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We visited the Great Wall, which is pretty cool. I&amp;#39;ll tell them why, when I show them pictures of myself on the Wall,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - APEC forum seeks to hear diverse voices]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_003_65514238ed50d203d2ca26ad.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Vulnerable communities around the world often suffer the first and worst blow of industrial pollution and climate change, and thus need better representation in climate policy discussions and decision-making processes, experts and officials said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They made the remarks at an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum on Friday, which kicked off the 2023 APEC Economic Leaders&amp;#39; Week in San Francisco in the United States.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The APEC Multistakeholder Forum marks the first time a diverse, multistakeholder dialogue is being organized during the APEC week. As a groundbreaking initiative, the forum addresses the local impacts of climate change and just transition on the region&amp;#39;s diverse communities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The forum has brought together more than 150 representatives of sustainable businesses, private organizations including charities and indigenous groups, and young peoples&amp;#39; and women&amp;#39;s groups from APEC economies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Key topics being discussed at the forum, which runs in San Francisco through Monday, include community-level actions, transition experiences of indigenous people, voices of youth, public-private partnerships and innovative low-carbon solutions that are inclusive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Organized with the support of the US Department of State and the APEC Secretariat, the multistakeholder forum has an agenda that aims to highlight community-level interventions that take into account the needs of vulnerable communities during the global shift toward net-zero economies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Enabling a transition to low-carbon economies throughout the region, which grapples with the aforementioned issues, is a key US APEC priority, according to the organizers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Rebecca Sta Maria, executive director of the APEC Secretariat, said, &amp;quot;Having dialogues like this provides a platform for stakeholders to discuss inclusion, specifically for the underrepresented groups or groups made vulnerable by the energy crisis and technological and climate change readiness.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The APEC has some policy options &amp;mdash; spanning from support for access to decent work to comprehensive structural reforms &amp;mdash; to ensure that &amp;quot;we have policies that promote sustainable practices and social safety nets&amp;quot;, Maria said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the speakers at the forum, the APEC economies are wrestling with the broad and complex structural reform challenge of decarbonizing the world&amp;#39;s supply chains, energy supplies and transportation systems.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; So it is imperative to address the local impact of this transition on the region&amp;#39;s diverse communities from a grassroots perspective, they emphasized.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; California Attorney General Rob Bonta said there are vulnerable communities around the world that are overburdened, do not have enough resources and are hurt first and worst. &amp;quot;They live at the intersection of poverty and pollution, and are deserving of commitments and investments, support, and us seeing and valuing those communities,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;What we truly need if we want to be successful is to ensure our transition toward a greener future is the topic of our conversation &amp;mdash; a just one, a just transition and an equitable transition that includes all communities and includes our workers,&amp;quot; Bonta said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Fighting against climate change requires a strong commitment to addressing the inequities that have caused vulnerable communities to be hurt first and worst by its impacts,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ambassador Matt Murray, US&amp;#39; senior official for APEC, said, &amp;quot;Although the impact of climate change affects everyone, it does not affect all communities equally.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some in the APEC region &amp;mdash; often those who have not historically had the opportunities to participate in making decisions to address the climate crisis &amp;mdash; experience greater suffering, Murray said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We have a responsibility to actively engage with diverse voices and perspectives in climate discussions.... By bringing all groups&amp;#39; unique experiences and knowledge to the table, we can find the most effective solutions for climate adaptation and mitigation for all,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gloria Duffy, co-president and CEO of the Commonwealth Club of California, said the Pacific basin is &amp;quot;our common home&amp;quot;, which &amp;quot;ties us together through trade, identity, the movement of people, our security, our common environment&amp;quot;, and especially the way the challenges of climate change are met. &amp;quot;It necessitates that we work together throughout this region for a zero-carbon future,&amp;quot; she underscored.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;vivienxu@chinadailyapac.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Development on right track]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_003_6551423bed50d203d2ca26ae.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/003/20231113_003_02_42656.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina rides a train on Saturday to inaugurate the Dohazari-Cox&amp;#39;s Bazar Railway, constructed under the Belt and Road Initiative to bolster connectivity and transportation infrastructure in the South Asian country. The 103.5-kilometer railway was partially built by China Civil Engineering Construction Corp and China Railway Group.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Taiwan official calls for more exchanges]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_003_6551423eed50d203d2ca26af.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Keelung Mayor Hsieh Kuo-liang voiced his opposition to &amp;quot;Taiwan independence&amp;quot; and advocated mutual understanding, peaceful development and a common vision for people from both sides of the Taiwan Strait during the weekend in Shenzhen, Guangdong province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hsieh, who is on the Chinese mainland to participate in the &amp;quot;cross-Strait integration month&amp;quot;, a series of events for people from both sides to strengthen family ties and promote exchanges and cooperation, made the remarks on several occasions during his visit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Opposing &amp;#39;Taiwan independence&amp;#39;, enhancing exchanges in various fields across the Taiwan Strait and promoting goodwill between the two sides will undoubtedly lead to an improvement in cross-Strait relations,&amp;quot; Hsieh said on Sunday during a group interview with China Daily and other media organizations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that he hopes the two sides can work together to expand participation, deepen exchanges between cities and bring benefits to compatriots on both sides of the Strait.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In his speech at the Straits Port City Forum on Saturday, Hsieh reiterated his commitment to opposing &amp;quot;Taiwan independence &amp;quot;and promoting peaceful development, and outlined areas of cooperation for port cities on both sides of the Strait.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized that the purpose of these exchanges is &amp;quot;mutual understanding, fostering friendship, working together and promoting peaceful development&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hsieh&amp;#39;s clear stance on opposing &amp;quot;Taiwan independence&amp;quot; and his commitment to enhancing exchanges between both sides earned him praise and support from those who share his vision for a peaceful and cooperative future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan Xianzhang, deputy head of the State Council Taiwan Affairs Office, said, &amp;quot;The enthusiastic participation of thousands of Taiwan compatriots in the events of the integration month once again demonstrates their collective desire for peace, development, exchange and cooperation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; All the events aim to show respect and care for Taiwan compatriots, Pan said, adding that the mainland continues to create better conditions and more opportunities for Taiwan&amp;#39;s youth to come to the mainland for exchanges, studies, employment and entrepreneurship.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qin Weizhong, mayor of Shenzhen, said that peaceful development and cooperation are the common aspirations of people on both sides of the Strait, and Shenzhen will work for the benefit of and to promote happiness among Taiwan compatriots working and living in the city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The integration month runs from late October through late November, and features over 30 series of exchange activities encompassing various sectors such as the economy, culture, sports, youth and media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Its overarching objective is to forge a new era&amp;#39;s bond between the two sides of the Taiwan Strait, intensify interactions, particularly among the younger generation, and collaboratively advance cross-Strait integration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangxu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Double 11 festival record set with 639 million parcels handled in a day]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_003_65514240ed50d203d2ca26b0.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/003/20231113_003_04_59656.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Employees sort parcels at a China Post workshop in Yongzhou, Hunan province, on Sunday. Logistics companies have taken several measures this year to ensure timely package delivery during the Double 11 online shopping festival.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China set a record by handling 639 million parcels on Saturday, demonstrating the resilience and vitality of China&amp;#39;s economic development, the State Post Bureau of China said on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The volume was 1.87 times that of regular days, with a year-on-year increase of 15.76 percent, the bureau said. Nov 11, also known as Double 11, is one of China&amp;#39;s most important online shopping festivals.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than 5.26 billion parcels were handled between Nov 1 and Saturday, an increase of 23.22 percent compared with the same period of last year. During this time, the average daily volume was 1.4 times that of off-peak days, according to the bureau.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The express delivery volume during the Double 11 festival period once again set a new record, indicating the recovery of the consumer market and demonstrating the resilience and vitality of China&amp;#39;s economic development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This year, most online stores offered big sales on two days &amp;mdash; Nov 1 and Saturday, with discounts and coupons on offer on the days in between.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the bureau, the parcel delivery sector has integrated with the e-commerce and manufacturing sectors, creating a record high in the volume of parcels handled on Nov 11.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past, customers frequently complained about parcels being delivered late, well after Double 11, with a large number of packages overcrowding distribution centers. Following the integration of the parcel delivery industry with the e-commerce industry chain, a large number of preordered goods are now kept ready at the warehouses of parcel delivery firms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; SF Express is one such major parcel delivery company in China that stores preordered products in its warehouses to make the delivery process fast during Double 11.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before Double 11, SF Express expanded its fast delivery service to more than 200 cities in China. The company cooperated with e-commerce stores and brands to allocate popular and preordered products in advance and stored them in SF&amp;#39;s warehouses across the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the company, more than 230 million parcels were allocated to 11 warehouses nationwide. When the presale began, the parcels could be delivered to customers within half a day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liang Yinghua, head of YTO Express in Dongxing, a county-level border city in South China&amp;#39;s Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, said the increase in volume of parcels during the Double 11 this year was about 20 percent more compared with off-peak days.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to setting up of more warehouses and extending the time for the shopping spree, the increase in volume was gradual and orderly, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Now, it is rare to see parcels overcrowding distribution centers,&amp;quot; he said, adding that the preparation for the Double 11 festival included inspection of vehicles and equipment and adding more staff to the front line.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The peak season for China&amp;#39;s parcel delivery sector began on Nov 1 this year and will last for 102 days, according to the bureau.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s parcel delivery sector has boomed over the past decade. As of October, China handled more than 100 billion parcels this year. In 2013, the annual figure was less than 9.2 billion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The sector&amp;#39;s vitality has demonstrated that China&amp;#39;s economy has continued to improve, the bureau said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;luowangshu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Top food policy expert hails nation&#39;s efforts to bolster its grain resilience]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/13/content_003_65514240ed50d203d2ca26b1.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/003/20231113_001_03_171863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Bram Govaerts&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-13/003/20231113_001_03_136863.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Online See more by scanning the code.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s recent efforts to curb its reliance on food imports and step up agricultural research funding have helped the world&amp;#39;s leading food importer become more resilient to global grain price hikes and supply chain woes, a top international food policy expert said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China has made a tremendous effort to evolve its food production,&amp;quot; said Bram Govaerts, director-general of the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center, which is headquartered in El Batan, Mexico. &amp;quot;China has invested a lot in science and technology for food security.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts made the remarks early this month during a weeklong visit to Beijing, where he sought to renew partnerships with Chinese researchers following the disruptions caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts said that China&amp;#39;s recent endeavors to increase crop production and investment in technology-driven breeding techniques, including gene-editing, had bolstered yields and made the country&amp;#39;s food supply more resilient.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The development of diversified supply chains has helped China to respond rapidly,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In late October, the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs said that this year, the country&amp;#39;s grain output is expected to exceed 650 million metric tons for the ninth consecutive year and hit a historical high despite some farmland being hit by heat waves and torrential rain over the summer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The increased yield would be due in part to larger growing areas and the adoption of high-yield crop varieties, officials said at a news conference in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Han, who oversees the ministry&amp;#39;s market and information division, said a range of factors had sent global rice prices to a 15-year high, including more extreme weather events, increasing protectionism, regional conflicts and a drought-induced export ban by India.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In comparison, China&amp;#39;s domestic rice procurement price in September was just 0.7 percent higher than in January, Liu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts said that stable food supply in China is a boon for the world. &amp;quot;If there&amp;#39;sa lack of food security in China, it will put pressure on the supply chains because this is a big country with a lot of people,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He described the current state of global food security as &amp;quot;scary&amp;quot;, saying that &amp;quot;one conflict can destabilize global wheat availability, and because of the conflict we had in one place, the world was suffering from increased wheat prices&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts said the current food supply system is fragile. &amp;quot;We need resilience because if today there was a regional conflict, tomorrow there would be a disease,&amp;quot;他说。 &amp;quot;And climate change could take out whole areas of food if we do not prevent it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The challenges meant that the world needs to revamp its food supply system, with countries producing a larger percentage of their food mix locally, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Governments also need to increase small farmers&amp;#39; access to innovative technology, better seeds and information, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts said the outcome of a recent drive to commercialize homegrown, genetically modified maize and soybean varieties in China had been very encouraging and would help reduce pesticide use, adding that GMO &amp;quot;needs to be a technology available in your toolkit&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that China, which used to scramble to feed its own population in the 1960s, had transitioned into an agricultural powerhouse thanks to decades of investment in agriculture. It now boasts highly educated scientists, strong data processing capabilities, molecular breeding know-how and seed production prowess.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Govaerts said that China was a flag-bearer in the global sharing of germ plasm resources &amp;mdash; genetic resources that are critical to developing higher-yielding and more nutritious crop or animal varieties. He praised China&amp;#39;s efforts to send agrotechnicians to Africa as part of the broader Belt and Road Initiative to help bolster food production in hunger-prone regions as a boon to global food security.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China is really getting together all the international actors,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;lilei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>