<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi stresses mutual understanding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_001_6549564ced50d203d2ca20e7.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_001_01_180078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平主席与澳大利亚周一，安东尼·艾博内塞总理在北京人民大会堂握手。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001 /20231107_001_01_163078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;国家主席习近平周一在北京人民大会堂会见古巴总理马雷罗·克鲁兹。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com .cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_001_01_197078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;国家主席习近平周一会见塞尔维亚总理布尔纳比奇。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_001_01_214078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;国家主席习近平周一会见南非副总统马沙蒂莱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平主席周一在北京会见澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞时强调，中澳两国要通过和平共处增进相互理解和信任，通过合作共赢实现共同发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 习近平对即将迎来2016年以来澳大利亚总理首次访华的阿尔巴内斯表示，两国要充分挖掘中澳自贸协定潜力，拓展在气候变化、能源和环境等领域合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 总统表示，阿尔巴内塞此访是双方以往交往的延续和新的开始，今年是双方交往的一个新起点。高夫·惠特拉姆访华50周年——习近平指出，这是澳大利亚总理首次访华。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国已恢复各领域交往，走出了改善和发展关系的正确道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，由于贸易问题和其他挑战，中澳关系陷入困境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年，尽管中国仍是澳大利亚的主要贸易伙伴，两国之间的贸易额仍同比下降 3.9%，至 2,209 亿美元。习近平表示，中澳同为亚太国家和二十国集团成员，没有历史恩怨和根本利害冲突，双方可以成为相互信任、相互促进发展的伙伴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在世界形势深刻变化中把握中澳关系正确方向也很重要习近平对客人说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国国家主席指出，如果一个国家只把自己的国家利益放在第一位，那么世界就显得狭小而拥挤，充满了风险和竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但从命运共同体的角度看，世界广阔、丰富，充满机遇、充满合作。他补充说，在全球危机的汹涌浪潮中，世界各国不是各自乘坐190多艘小船，而是同乘一艘大船。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平呼吁两国顺应潮流&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 面对复杂的外部环境，中国经济他说，中国的发展仍然是建立在坚实的基础和许多有利条件之上的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国的稳定发展带来了世界经济急需的确定性。中国的发展离不开世界，世界的发展也需要中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，筑起“小院高墙”行动;，脱钩、去风险本质上都是违背市场规律、违背技术发展、违背人类社会发展潮流的各种形式的保护主义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为两国企业投资经营提供良好营商环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国政府应支持立法机构、政党、智库、青年等交流，地方层面便利人员往来习近平指出，中方在亚太地区不搞排他性小圈子，不搞集团政治，不搞集团对抗。小圈子解决不了世界面临的重大挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国应对任何破坏亚太地区的图谋保持警惕和反对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他还表示愿同澳大利亚开展更多三边、多边合作，支持南太国家增强发展韧性、应对气候变化等挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 阿尔巴内塞是第七次访华，也是他首次访华。总理表示，双方应相互尊重、互利共赢，保持沟通与交流，增进了解与合作，实现互利共赢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中方允许存在分歧，但双方不应让分歧决定两国关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国拥有广泛共同利益，对话与合作应该是正确选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;堪培拉愿积极推动同北京双边关系稳定发展，加强经贸往来，加强清洁能源、气候变化等领域合作，为两国人民带来更多福祉，他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周一，总统还在人民大会堂分别与古巴、塞尔维亚和南非领导人举行了会晤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;古巴&lt;/b >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在会见古巴总理马雷罗·克鲁斯时，习近平表示，中方欢迎古方高质量参与“一带一路”合作，挖掘农业、旅游、医疗卫生、科技等领域潜力，为推动“一带一路”建设注入新动力。推动两国合作走实走实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平赞扬两国在老一辈领导人的引领下结下的牢不可破的纽带。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 指出中方观点和看法习近平表示，从战略高度和全局高度发展两国及两国执政党的特殊友好关系，中方愿同古方深化政治互信和战略协作，交流治国理政经验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;继续坚定支持古巴人民反对外部干涉和封锁、捍卫国家主权和民族尊严的努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平还表示，希望古巴利用好这一机会&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周日在上海出席第六届进博会开幕式的马雷罗表示，通过此次中国之行，古巴将同中方深化务实合作，保持密切配合在国际和地区事务中，反对霸权主义和霸凌行径，维护国际公平正义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;塞尔维亚&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在会见塞尔维亚总理时习近平指出，中塞是休戚与共的铁杆朋友。新形势下，中方愿同塞方共同努力，推动两国关系高质量发展，更好造福两国人民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，需要两国共同努力。建设运营重大合作项目，推动中塞自贸协定早日生效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中方支持塞尔维亚走自主发展道路，愿加强多边协调与合作布尔纳比奇赞赏中塞关系发展，表示中国已成为塞尔维亚最大投资伙伴，斯梅代雷沃钢铁等合作项目植物改变了塞尔维亚的国家发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国在六个月内达成的自由贸易协定充分表明了双方进一步深化两国关系的坚定决心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;布尔纳比奇表示，中方一贯支持塞尔维亚维护国家主权和尊严，表示塞尔维亚坚定奉行一个中国政策，愿与中方共同推动共建“一带一路”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;南非&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在会见南非副总统马沙蒂莱时，习近平表示，中方愿同非洲国家推动一批高标准、以民为本、可持续的项目，包括南非在内，构建高水平的中非命运共同体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平还重申中国致力于落实支持非洲工业化和农业现代化倡议推动中非人才发展合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中非应继续在金砖国家合作机制内密切合作，加强发展中国家团结合作，推动全球治理体系更好惠及发展中国家谈到中南关系进入“黄金时代”，习近平表示，中方愿同南方共同努力，充实中南全面战略伙伴关系内涵，推动两国关系迈上新台阶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，中方支持南非探索适合本国国情的现代化道路，将进一步夯实中南政治互信的坚实基础。马沙提莱表示，习近平主席8月对南非的访问进一步巩固了两国关系。南非将更好地将自身发展战略同“一带一路”倡议对接，深化同中方各领域务实合作，不断加强协作他补充说，在多边框架内与中国合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - President calls for stronger innovation partnerships]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_001_6549564fed50d203d2ca20e8.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国家主席习近平周一呼吁构建更加紧密的科技创新伙伴关系，为“一带一路”高质量发展作出贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平向首届“一带一路”科技交流大会周一在重庆开幕表示祝贺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在信中表示，第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛成功举办推动“一带一路”进入高质量发展新阶段，科技合作是重要组成部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国将弘扬和平合作、开放合作的丝路精神包容互鉴、互利共赢，全面落实“一带一路”科技创新合作行动计划，推进国际科技创新交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中方愿与各方共同努力与各国一道挖掘创新发展潜力，释放创新合作潜力，加强创新伙伴关系，推动创新成果惠及各国人民，为推动“一带一路”高质量发展和建设贡献力量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 以“共同创新、共同发展”为主题，构建人类命运共同体。本次会议由科技部、中国科学院、中国工程院、中国科学技术协会、重庆市人民政府、四川省人民政府共同主办政府。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Vision China highlights crucial role of science and technology]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_001_65495652ed50d203d2ca20e9.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_001_03_141078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;演讲嘉宾与每位嘉宾互动周一在湖北省武汉市举行的“视觉中国”活动期间，还有其他活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周一的“视觉中国”活动凸显了中国和世界范围内广泛的科技交流与合作。 -中国中部湖北省武汉市的科技重地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 视觉中国以“科技创新引领未来”为主题，力求凸显科技在贡献力量中的关键作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在中国日报社和武汉市人民政府联合主办的活动中，来自各界的发言者概述了各领域的主要趋势和作用&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国日报副总编辑刘伟岭表示，我国科技取得重大突破，成为创新型国家。党的十八大以来，实施创新驱动发展战略，深化科技体系建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 武汉凭借丰富的科技优势，在光电等领域也取得了显着进步。科技和教育资源丰富，包括92所高等院校和101个研究机构，她补充说，这座城市的成就体现了中国作为科技创新者的显着进步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国的科技成就不仅是全球合作的成果，也为国际社会做出了宝贵贡献。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们致力于分享中国科技互利合作故事，营造开放、公平、公正、非歧视的科技发展环境，推动全球合作在创新方面，”刘补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 武汉市副市长王元成表示，武汉是具有全国影响力的科创中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 武汉在科技创新方面取得了多项突破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “当前，武汉正处于关键阶段。”提升发展阶段、转变增长动力”王先生还对国内外科技、经济、学术和商业领袖为城市发展提出的建议表示感谢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 数字化转型合伙人、领军人物朱大卫罗兰贝格中国服务部副总裁，分享了他对下一代制造业的见解以及提升制造业竞争力的六大趋势，例如安全短供应链、可持续发展和透明度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，制造业竞争力现在已不再是问题。 ”分享了他的家族六代人与中国的渊源以及他在武汉投资生物技术和医药研发，促进中外科学文化交流的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;认识到粮食对不断增长的世界人口日益重要，他表示自己的工作重点已转向农业技术创新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 霍沃斯表示，中国在世界科技格局中占有重要地位&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 华为技术有限公司副总裁兼知识产权负责人范志勇表示，技术创新日益全球化，并以华为与华为联合开发的人工智能视频服务为例。 39;的全球合作伙伴并被广泛应用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，要进一步全球化创新，需要更多的人才和健全的知识产权保护体系，这也需要全球共同努力培育。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 武汉长江光纤光缆公司高级副总裁Jan Bongaerts回顾了该公司过去几十年来为该市数字化转型做出的贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 他表示，正利用国家政策向海外输出创新成果，不断缩小全球数字鸿沟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 公司将努力成为光电子信息领域的领跑者他补充说，通过致力于创新和中国光谷（武汉高科技开发区）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 澳大利亚科学院院士、澳大利亚科学院名誉院长查尔斯·麦凯 (Charles Mackay)山东齐鲁工业大学药学院分析了饮食、肠道菌群与免疫反应之间的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创新和科学发现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jianchanglong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - FARMERS SEEK SOLUTIONS AMID CLIMATE CHANGE CRISIS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_001_65495655ed50d203d2ca20ea.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_001_04_136078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;在线扫码查看更多代码。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_002_01_63818.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;左：Richard Ngunga (右）站在肯尼亚马金杜的农田上，他在那里打了一个井来灌溉农作物。中：9 月份，Makongeni 村的农民正在接受挖 Zai 坑的培训。右：卡西尼村农民展示9月份收获的抗旱粮食。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_002_01_114818 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;九月，马金杜卡西尼村，牛正在拉车运水。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile /2023-11-07/001/20231107_002_01_46818.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Kasioni 村的居民在自家农场前合影。周五该地区开始下雨。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/001/20231107_002_01_29818.png&quot; />;&lt;p >;卡西尼雨季到来之前的 9 月，裂隙线等待播种。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/ 001/20231107_002_01_139818.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; Richard Ngunga 是一位在肯尼亚村庄出生和长大的退休教师，他对童年有着美好的回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他回忆起该地区高大的常青树，大树健康的牲畜群、附近的马金杜河、旱季灌溉土地的农民以及充足的粮食供应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “当我在马库埃尼县马孔盖尼长大时，这里人烟稀少。村，” 62 岁的恩贡加 (Ngunga) 站在他的农场里说道，当时一列火车从沿海城市蒙巴萨开往肯尼亚首都内罗毕，距离只有几百米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大约 30 年前，肯尼亚降雨量充沛。面积和丰收已是常态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 如今，气候变化的破坏性影响显而易见。马金杜河完全干涸，土地尘土飞扬，水资源匮乏，几乎没有高大的树木生长，几乎看不到成群的牲畜。村民们的内心充满了挫败感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，由于不可预测的雨季和日益严重的干旱，农业不再是可靠的收入来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ngunga希望当地人停止砍伐树木烧炭，转而种植更多树木并投资于替代燃料来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 世界气象组织 9 月发布的《2022 年非洲气候状况》报告称，虽然非洲大陆只占全球温室气体排放量的一小部分，但它却受到气候变化的严重影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年，超过 1.1 亿非洲人直接受到气象、气候和水的影响报告称，造成超过 85 亿美元的经济损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据报道，约 5,000 人死亡，其中 48% 因干旱，43% 因洪水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 自2020年以来，肯尼亚、埃塞俄比亚和索马里在连续五个雨季歉收后，经历了40年来最严重的干旱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 干旱导致生活在干旱和半干旱县的350万肯尼亚人面临严重粮食短缺联合国人道主义事务协调厅表示，这是因为不安全。干旱还导致农村地区 260 万头牲畜死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 距 Makongeni 约 10 分钟车程的 Kasioni 村的 Raphael Munyao 与 Ngunga 分享了类似的观察结果。 Munyao将该地区的情况归因于森林砍伐、人口增长、温室气体排放和高温。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “与几年前不同，当时我们收获了足够的农作物供消费，然后出售剩余的，现在我们必须购买我们的食物，其中大部分是进口的，而且非常昂贵，” Munyao 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，由于水位下降，泉水的自来水供应受到严格限制，村民现在步行约 5 公里才能到达钻孔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Munyao说许多家庭由于缺乏经济能力而无法让孩子读完高中，其中许多人依靠农业为生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ngunga 是社区中少数幸运者之一，正如他所管理的那样去年打了一个井，以缓解气候变化带来的挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他的绿色大院看起来与邻居的大院完全不同——这清楚地证明了可靠的供水带来的变革性好处。恩贡加种植了各种蔬菜，并在马金杜的市场上出售，他还种植了香蕉、玉米、木瓜和豆类，并养鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;需求量大&lt;/b>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ngunga 希望他所在村庄的年轻人考虑通过下沉钻孔投资灌溉农业，其中大多数人已经搬到了大城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “土壤肥沃，需求旺盛。”因为食物总是很高，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 那些无力投资该地区钻孔的人正在转向气候智能型农业来提高产量，这要感谢菲比·姆万甘吉 (Phoebe Mwangangi) 为农民提供的这项技术培训。&lt;/p>; &lt; Mwangangi 是该地区的一名小农，他创立了社区组织扶贫资源中心。她接受了国际半干旱热带作物研究所的培训，该研究所是一个为农村发展进行农业研究的国际组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她还指导农民采取缓解气候变化的措施，帮助他们在气候变化时收获农作物。降雨量极少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mwangangi 目前正在与六组农民一起工作，他说：“农民们参观我们的示范农场，学习如何整地、如何种植农作物以及农作物的类型种植农作物。然后，我们鼓励他们在自己的农场实践在中心学到的知识。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她补充说，气候智能型农业实践和创新方法旨在保护水和土壤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些方法包括形成裂口线——一种低技术含量的雨水收集系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 拖拉机挖出 30 厘米深的裂隙线，以松动土壤。然后，农民在裂口处施肥，然后在其中种植农作物。土壤中的粪便可以保留水分，这样农作物在没有下雨的情况下可以存活长达三周。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mwangangi 说：“我们对土壤的干扰降到最低。当撕裂线形成时，两条线之间会留下一个区域，我们在其中进行浅层除草。我们不会挖得很深，因此土壤基本上保持完好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 农民还挖坑来种植种子。坑的面积为 60 平方厘米或 90 平方厘米，深 30 厘米，间距 60 厘米至 90 厘米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 60 平方厘米的扎坑可容纳 5 粒玉米种子，而 90 平方厘米的扎坑可容纳 5 颗玉米种子。一粒含有九粒种子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 坑中的表土与有机肥混合，用于填充坑以增加土壤肥力和土壤保水能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结果，这些坑解决了土壤贫瘠、土地退化和保湿等问题，使干旱和半干旱土地的生产力更高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在 Makongeni 村，当 Mwangangi 向农民们指示时，他们很难掩饰自己的兴奋之情。挖哉坑。这些农民是 Aimi me Bidii 自助小组的成员，他们承诺在即将到来的雨季之前准备至少 20 个坑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该小组由 Richard Ngunga 的妻子 Petronilla Ngunga 领导，有75名成员，希望将人数增加到100人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们的目标是确保村里每个家庭都能自力更生，收获足够的粮食供消费。我们位于一个城镇内，由于我们的农场很小，我们希望最大限度地提高产量，”去年以教师身份退休的佩特罗尼拉·恩贡加 (Petronilla Ngunga) 说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管拥有土地上有钻孔的优势，并从事灌溉农业，但她仍致力于鼓励邻居耕种——甚至给他们空间在她的土地上种植。 “我喜欢帮助人们，并希望看到他们改善生活，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在参加了挖掘 Zai 坑的培训课程后，来自 Manyani 村的小农、九个孩子的母亲 Kambua Andrew 对这个想法感到非常兴奋。她付给一位邻居相当于 13.47 美元的钱，让他帮忙在她的一小块土地上挖坑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我希望通过使用这种创新的耕作方法，我能够收获足够的食物照顾我的家人度过即将到来的雨季，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上个季节，她的小农场只收获了 20 公斤豇豆，而玉米和豆类作物则因降雨不足而干涸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 农民们也面临着困难。鼓励通过投资农场池塘和水库来收集地表径流，以在旱季给牲畜浇水和种植蔬菜。地表径流是土壤饱和时发生的水流，雨水、融水或其他来源的多余水流过土地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 缓解气候变化的另一种方法是种植各种抗旱植物。绿豆（一种豆类）、高粱、豇豆和珍珠粟等作物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Phoebe Mwangangi 表示，由于采用了气候智能型农业系统，产量有所增加。&lt;/p>; &lt; Uithi Museo 自助小组是气候智能型农业培训的受益者之一。该组织有 50 名成员，并拥有一块土地作为示范农场。在自己的农场里，每个成员都执行他们收到的指示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们练习挖掘 15-30 厘米深度的裂线，并种植各种抗旱作物，如豇豆、高粱、珍珠粟、木豆和青豆，以分散气候变化风险。小组成员还接受了如何烹饪这些农作物以获取营养的指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;培训受到赞扬&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 参观小组的《中国日报》记者得到了准备好的食物该组织的主席 Agnes Nzomo 表示：“我们很高兴通过培训学会了减缓气候变化和消除贫困，并增加了通过学习不同的准备方法来了解农作物的价值。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她说，正在计划种植 Melia volkensii &amp;mdash;落叶耐旱树木，可生产抗白蚁的优质木材。这些树木和草将被种植在农场用于商业目的。回报将用于改善小组或用于其他项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Makindu 的农民表示，他们希望 10 月至 12 月的雨季能够取得成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 肯尼亚气象部门表示其季节性预测显示，全国降雨量可能会增加，东部地区在此期间降雨的可能性更大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 降雨量增加将是由于该地区海面温度高于平均水平所致。该部门表示，赤道中东部太平洋，表明存在厄尔尼诺现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 四个星期后的10月23日，当《中国日报》访问马金杜时，该地区尚未出现任何降雨，尽管降雨量为该国大部分地区，包括邻近马金杜的一些地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周五终于开始下雨。 “虽然有所推迟，但我们对这个赛季将会取得成功持乐观态度，” Phoebe Mwangangi 在周六的电话中说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她和其他几位农民已经在他们的农场挖了 Zai 坑和撕裂线，现在正在播种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系方式作者：edithmutethya@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - FARMERS SEEK SOLUTIONS AMID CLIMATE CHANGE CRISIS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_002_65495655ed50d203d2ca20eb.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/002/20231107_001_04_136078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;在线扫码查看更多代码。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/002/20231107_002_01_63818.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;左：Richard Ngunga (右）站在肯尼亚马金杜的农田上，他在那里打了一个井来灌溉农作物。中：9 月份，Makongeni 村的农民正在接受挖 Zai 坑的培训。 Right: Farmers show drought-resistant grain they harvested at Kasioni village in September.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/002/20231107_002_01_114818.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Cattle are used to pull a cart carrying water at Kasioni village, Makindu, in September.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/002/20231107_002_01_46818.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Residents of Kasioni village pose in front of their farm. Rain started falling in the area on Friday.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/002/20231107_002_01_29818.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Rip lines wait to be sown in September before the arrival of the rainy season at Kasioni.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/002/20231107_002_01_139818.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; Richard Ngunga, a retired teacher born and raised in a Kenyan village, has fond memories of his childhood.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He recalls the tall evergreen trees in the area, large herds of healthy livestock, the nearby Makindu River, farmers irrigating their land during the dry season and abundant food supplies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;When I was growing up in Makongeni, Makueni county, there were very few people in the village,&amp;quot; said Ngunga, 62, standing on his farm as a train traveled just a few hundred meters away toward Nairobi, the Kenyan capital, from the coastal city of Mombasa.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About 30 years ago, there was abundant rainfall in the area and bumper harvests were the norm.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Today, the devastating impact of climate change is all too apparent. The Makindu River is completely dry, the land is dusty, water is scarce, few tall trees grow and hardly any herds of livestock can be seen. Frustration is etched on the villagers&amp;#39; faces as most of them struggle to put food on the table.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, farming is no longer a reliable source of income due to unpredictable rainy seasons and increasingly severe droughts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ngunga wants locals to stop felling trees to burn charcoal, and instead plant more trees and invest in alternative sources of fuel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The State of the Climate in Africa 2022 report published in September by the World Meteorological Organization said that while the continent is responsible for only a fraction of global greenhouse gas emissions, it is suffering disproportionately from climate change.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last year, more than 110 million people in Africa were directly affected by meteorological-, climate- and water-related hazards, resulting in economic losses of more than $8.5 billion, the report said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some 5,000 fatalities were also reported, with 48 percent of them due to drought and 43 percent related to flooding.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 2020, Kenya, Ethiopia and Somalia have experienced the worst drought in 40 years, following five consecutive failed rainy seasons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The drought left 3.5 million Kenyans living in arid and semiarid counties facing acute food insecurity, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs said. The drought also killed 2.6 million livestock in rural areas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About a 10-minute drive from Makongeni, Raphael Munyao shared similar observations with Ngunga at Kasioni village. Munyao attributes the situation in the area to deforestation, a rising population, greenhouse gas emissions and high temperatures.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Unlike several years ago, when we harvested sufficient crops for consumption, and sold the surplus, we now have to buy our food, most of which is imported and very expensive,&amp;quot; Munyao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that villagers now walk about 5 kilometers to access a borehole, because the supply of tap water from a spring is strictly rationed due to falling water levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Munyao said many families are unable to educate their children past high school due to a lack of finances, with many of them depending on agriculture for a living.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ngunga is among the lucky few in the community, as he managed to sink a borehole last year to mitigate the challenges posed by climate change.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His green compound looks totally different to those of his neighbors&amp;#39;-clear evidence of the transformational benefits of a reliable water supply. Ngunga has grown a variety of vegetables, which he sells at the market in Makindu, and he has also planted bananas, maize, pawpaws and legumes, and farms fish.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;High demand&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ngunga wants young people from his village, most of whom have relocated to major cities, to consider investing in irrigated agriculture by sinking boreholes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The soil is fertile and the demand for food is always high,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Those unable to afford to invest in boreholes in the area are turning to climate-smart agriculture to improve their yields, thanks to Phoebe Mwangangi, who trains farmers in this technique.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A smallholder farmer in the area, Mwangangi founded the Poverty Alleviation Resource Center, a community-based organization. She was trained by the International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics, an international organization that conducts agricultural research for rural development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She also instructs farmers on climate change mitigation measures to help them harvest their crops when there is minimal rainfall.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mwangangi, who is currently working with six groups of farmers, said, &amp;quot;Farmers visit our demonstration farms to learn how to prepare the land, how to plant crops, and the type of crops to plant. We then encourage them to practice what they have learned at the center on their own farms.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She added that climate-smart agricultural practices and innovative methods are aimed at conserving water and soil.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These methods include forming rip lines &amp;mdash; a low-tech system of harvesting rainwater.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A tractor digs rip lines 30 centimeters deep to loosen the soil. Farmers then apply manure to the rip lines before planting crops in them. The manure in the soil retains water so that crops can survive for up to three weeks in the absence of rain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mwangangi said: &amp;quot;We cause minimum disturbance to the soil. When rip lines are formed, an area is left between the two lines, in which we perform shallow weeding. We don&amp;#39;t dig very deep so that the soil remains largely intact.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Farmers also dig Zai pits to plant seeds. The pits are either 60 square centimeters or 90 sq cm, 30 cm deep and 60 cm to 90 cm apart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A 60-sq-cm Zai pit holds five maize seeds, while a 90-sq-cm one holds nine seeds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Topsoil from a pit is mixed with organic manure, which is used to fill the pit to increase soil fertility and the capacity of the soil to retain water.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a result, the pits address the issues of infertile soil, land degradation, and moisture retention, making arid and semiarid land more productive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At Makongeni village, farmers struggled to hide their excitement as Mwangangi instructed them on digging Zai pits. The farmers, who are members of the Aimi me Bidii Self Help Group, promised to prepare at least 20 pits before the upcoming rainy season.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The group, which is headed by Petronilla Ngunga, wife of Richard Ngunga, has 75 members and wants to raise the number to 100.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We aim to ensure that every family in the village is self-reliant in terms of harvesting enough food for consumption. We are located within a town, and as our farms are small, we want to maximize yields,&amp;quot; said Petronilla Ngunga, who retired last year as a teacher.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Despite having the advantage of a borehole on her land, and engaging in irrigated agriculture, she is committed to encouraging her neighbors to farm &amp;mdash; even giving them space to plant on her land. &amp;quot;I like to help people, and want to see them improve their livelihoods,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After attending a training session on digging Zai pits, Kambua Andrew, a smallholder farmer from Manyani village, and mother of nine, was enthused by the idea. She paid one of her neighbors the equivalent of $13.47 to help dig the pits on her small piece of land.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I hope that by using this innovative farming method, I will be able to harvest enough food to see my family through the forthcoming rainy season,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last season, she only managed to harvest 20 kilograms of cowpeas on her small farm, while maize and bean crops dried up due to inadequate rainfall.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Farmers are also being encouraged to harvest surface runoff by investing in farm ponds and reservoirs to water their livestock and grow vegetables during the dry season. Surface runoff is the water flow that occurs when soil is saturated, and excess water from rain, meltwater or other sources flows over the land.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another way of mitigating climate change is to plant a variety of drought-resistant crops such as green grams (a species of legumes), sorghum, cowpeas and pearl millet.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Phoebe Mwangangi said yields have increased as a result of adopting the climate-smart system of farming.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Uithi Museo Self Help Group is one of the beneficiaries of climate-smart agricultural training. The group has 50 members and a piece of land that acts as a demonstration farm. On his or her own farm, each member carries out the instruction they receive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They practice digging rip lines to a depth of 15-30 cm, and grow a variety of drought-resistant crops such as cowpeas, sorghum, pearl millet, pigeon peas and green grams to spread climate change risks. Members of the group have also been instructed on cooking these crops for nutritional purposes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Training praised&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China Daily reporters who visited the group were served food prepared from pearl millet and sorghum.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Agnes Nzomo, the group&amp;#39;s chairwoman, said, &amp;quot;We are grateful that through our training we have learned to mitigate climate change and eradicate poverty, as well as add value to crops by learning different ways to prepare them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said plans are underway to plant Melia volkensii &amp;mdash; deciduous drought-tolerant trees that produce high-quality timber resistant to termites. These trees, as well as grass, will be planted on farms for commercial purposes. Returns will be used to improve the group or for use in other projects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Farmers in Makindu said they hoped the October-December rainy season would be successful.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Kenya Meteorological Department said in its seasonal forecast that the entire country is likely to experience increased rainfall, with a higher chance of rain in eastern areas during this period.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The increased rainfall will be driven by warmer than average sea surface temperatures over the central and eastern equatorial Pacific Ocean, indicating the presence of El Nino conditions, the department said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When China Daily visited Makindu four weeks later on Oct 23, the area had not received any rainfall, despite rain falling in most parts of the country, including some areas neighboring Makindu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Rain finally started falling on Friday. &amp;quot;Though it was delayed, we are optimistic that the season will be successful,&amp;quot; Phoebe Mwangangi said in a phone call on Saturday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She and several other farmers have already dug Zai pits and rip lines on their farms and are now planting seeds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at edithmutethya@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - US firms voice confidence in China at CIIE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_003_65495658ed50d203d2ca20ec.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; United States-based companies are attending the sixth China International Import Expo, showcasing their eagerness to deepen cooperation with China amid gradually stabilizing bilateral relations, according to corporate executives and experts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With closer ties most widely expected in healthcare, agriculture and technology, the executives said China&amp;#39;s increasing appeal for US companies will continue due to its robust domestic market and unwavering dedication to opening up its economy, despite globally subdued investment sentiment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The scale of this year&amp;#39;s expo, which runs through Friday in Shanghai, is the largest in the CIIE&amp;#39;s history.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The strong presence of US businesses at the expo came after high-level exchanges between China and the US, and more efforts are likely to be made to promote interaction and cooperation between the world&amp;#39;s two largest economies, experts added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Stephane Bancel, CEO of the mRNA vaccine developer Moderna, said it was a &amp;quot;very important and historic day&amp;quot; for the US company, after Moderna announced that its research and production headquarters project broke ground in Shanghai&amp;#39;s Minhang district on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 3.6 billion yuan ($495 million) project, the first investment of the company on the Chinese mainland, is the largest foreign-invested biomedical project in China to date.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Bancel, the company is set to tap into the Chinese market by offering every patient personalized medicine, and it will conduct further clinical trials of its new medicines in the country. It took only a couple of months to materialize the strategic cooperation contract that Moderna signed with Shanghai authorities in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The US Department of Agriculture is also leading a delegation of 17 exhibitors at the CIIE.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Chang, vice-president of Cargill Investments (China), the Chinese branch of the US agriculture and food company Cargill, said that &amp;quot;nearly one-fifth of Cargill&amp;#39;s consumers are in China, and the country is an extremely important market for us&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Whether it is raw materials or processed goods, China&amp;#39;s vast consumer base provides a huge market for agricultural products, giving China a core position in the global agricultural supply chain,&amp;quot; Liu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the unveiling ceremony for a US agricultural product pavilion at the CIIE on Monday, US Ambassador to China Nicholas Burns said that economic and trade cooperation between China and the US is very important, and Washington does not seek to decouple from Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Bai Ming, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation, said US companies&amp;#39; enthusiasm for the CIIE has demonstrated that there is more room for bilateral economic cooperation between the two countries, and further efforts can be undertaken to boost such cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mutual respect and win-win cooperation are what companies from both sides want, Bai said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Frank Meng, chairman of Qualcomm China, which is participating in the CIIE for the sixth year, said the US chip heavyweight sees huge opportunities in partnering with Chinese companies in 5G, artificial intelligence, internet of things and intelligent connected vehicles, as the company highlights its commitment to China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Qualcomm has consistently considered China as a pivotal business partner and valued customer, viewing it as more than just a market or a link in the supply chain,&amp;quot; Meng said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that in past years, smartphones that use Qualcomm&amp;#39;s flagship mobile chips and were launched by Chinese companies accounted for nearly half of the initial launches worldwide. &amp;quot;This underscores the significance of the Chinese market and our partnership with Chinese companies,&amp;quot; Meng said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Puay Koon Chia, Asia-Pacific president of the US-based global materials science company Dow, said that the CIIE &amp;quot;is an important platform for us to showcase our latest innovative technologies for China and the region&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;it highlights the valuable partnerships we have in China&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company signed a $300 million memorandum of understanding with ZKH Group, a Chinese industrial digital service company, at the CIIE on Sunday. Under the cooperation, the two will tap into burgeoning silicone markets downstream, such as electrification, transportation, packaging and construction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at masi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Xi calls for greater efforts to build a peaceful nation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_003_6549565bed50d203d2ca20ed.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; President Xi Jinping called on Monday for efforts to make greater contributions to advancing the Peaceful China Initiative to a higher level.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi, who is also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remark in Beijing when he met with representatives of model units that apply the &amp;quot;Fengqiao model&amp;quot; for promoting community-level governance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi encouraged them to carry on their work and further develop the &amp;quot;Fengqiao model&amp;quot; for promoting community-level governance in the new era.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Created by people in Fengqiao township of Zhuji, Zhejiang province, some 60 years ago, the &amp;quot;Fengqiao model&amp;quot; has been known for relying on the people to resolve disputes at the community level, and has since been promoted across the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the 18th CPC National Congress in 2012, Xi has made a series of important instructions on applying and further developing the &amp;quot;Fengqiao model&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Localities have earnestly implemented Xi&amp;#39;s instructions and closely relied on the people to explore new methods of community-level governance to create a safe and stable social environment for advancing Chinese modernization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cai Qi and Li Xi, both members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee, were present at the meeting. Cai is also director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, and Li is also secretary of the CPC Central Commission for Discipline Inspection.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Cold spell prompts emergency response in some regions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_003_6549565eed50d203d2ca20ee.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_003_03_44419.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Tourists brave heavy snowfall to visit the Shenyang Palace Museum in Shenyang, capital of Liaoning province, on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A cold front triggered strong winds and heavy snowfall in northern and northeastern China over the weekend, heralding an early winter this year, meteorologists said on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They called for contingency plans across a wide range of sectors &amp;mdash; from food production to power supply and road safety &amp;mdash; to cope with the harsh weather.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In response, local authorities implemented emergency measures, including the temporary suspension of classes and business operations in some parts of the country and an early activation of heating systems.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fang Chong, chief forecaster at the National Meteorological Center, said that snowfall in northeastern China has started earlier than usual. &amp;quot;The first snow in the region is often seen in late November or early December,&amp;quot; he said at a news conference in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fang described the snowfall in the northeastern region as &amp;quot;rather intense&amp;quot;, and said it has the potential of reaching a record high in parts of Heilongjiang, the northernmost province and a major food production area. He added that efforts were needed to save crops and protect farm animals in such weather.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The National Meteorological Center said on Sunday that a cold wave had pushed the mercury down in the Xinjiang Uygur and Inner Mongolia autonomous regions and Gansu province. The cold spell is forecast to continue until midweek, bringing a mix of blizzards, sleet and gale-force winds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Late on Saturday, the center activated its second-lowest level of emergency response for cold waves and blizzards, after issuing a lowest level of emergency response a day earlier.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It issued an orange alert for snowstorms and activated a blue alert for gales. China has a four-tier warning system for severe weather, with red being the most serious, followed by orange, yellow and blue.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The center renewed all three alerts on Monday. It forecast that heavy snowfall and blizzards will hit parts of Inner Mongolia and Heilongjiang, Jilin and Liaoning provinces until early Tuesday. Snowfall could reach 35 millimeters in some of the affected areas, and temperatures could plunge by 10 C to 14 C in parts of Inner Mongolia and northeastern China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To alleviate the impact of the cold spell, transportation authorities in Inner Mongolia said on Sunday that personnel, equipment and materials are on standby to tackle disruption caused by heavy snowfall. The frequency of road inspections has also been increased to quickly spot damage and avoid traffic disruption.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yuan Bin, a forecaster at the National Meteorological Center&amp;#39;s public meteorological service center, said that snowfall could lead to icy roads and poor visibility, causing traffic disruption.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Up to 20-millimeter-thick layers of ice have been spotted covering some power lines in Jilin and Liaoning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This could damage power equipment and disrupt supply at a time of increasing electricity consumption due to heating needs, and authorities need to step up energy storage and make emergency plans,&amp;quot; Yuan said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;lilei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Dunhuang cultural show]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_003_65495661ed50d203d2ca20ef.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_003_04_61419.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Dancers dressed as &amp;quot;flying apsaras&amp;quot;, the angel-like beings known as feitian in Chinese, perform on Sunday during the opening ceremony of an exhibition on artworks featuring elements of Dunhuang culture at Roy Thomson Hall in Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Vision China highlights crucial role of science and technology]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_003_65495661ed50d203d2ca20f0.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_001_03_141078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Guest speakers interact with each other during the Vision China event on Monday in Wuhan, Hubei province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A wide range of scientific and technological exchanges and cooperation both in China and across the world were highlighted at the Vision China event on Monday in the sci-tech powerhouse of Wuhan in Central China&amp;#39;s Hubei province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under the theme &amp;quot;Leading to the Future with Technological Innovation&amp;quot;, Vision China sought to highlight the crucial role of science and technology in contributing to the country&amp;#39;s next stage of development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the event, hosted jointly by China Daily and Wuhan Municipal People&amp;#39;s Government, speakers from various sectors outlined the key trends and functions of fields including manufacturing, artificial intelligence and agricultural technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Weiling, deputy editor-in-chief of China Daily, said that China has achieved critical sci-tech breakthroughs and become an innovation-oriented country as the nation has implemented an innovation-driven development strategy and deepened its sci-tech system since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wuhan has also made remarkable progress in areas such as optoelectronics by leveraging its abundant sci-tech and educational resources, including 92 colleges and universities and 101 research institutes, she said, adding that the city&amp;#39;s accomplishments have exemplified China&amp;#39;s notable strides as a sci-tech innovator.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China&amp;#39;s achievements in science and technology have not only been a result of global cooperation, but have also made valuable contributions to the international community,&amp;quot; Liu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We are committed to sharing stories of how China fosters mutually beneficial sci-tech cooperation and to creating an open, fair, just and nondiscriminatory environment for sci-tech development, while promoting global cooperation in innovation,&amp;quot; Liu added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Yuancheng, vice-mayor of Wuhan, said that the city is a science and innovation hub with national influence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The city has witnessed a number of breakthroughs in the field of science and technology, including China&amp;#39;s first practical optical fiber, the first photoelectric transmission system, and the first international standard for optical communication.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;At present, Wuhan is at a critical stage of upgrading its development stage and transforming its growth momentum,&amp;quot; said Wang, who also expressed thanks to sci-tech, economic, academic and business leaders at home and abroad for their suggestions on the city&amp;#39;s development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; David Zhu, partner and leader of digital transformation service of Roland Berger China, shared his insights about next-generation manufacturing and six key trends to boost manufacturing competitiveness, such as safe and short supply chains, sustainability and transparency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said manufacturing competitiveness is now no longer only determined by product and price, adding that winning markets with manufacturing differentiation should be the final target.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Simon Haworth, a renowned British entrepreneur and investor involved in the biotechnology and agritech markets, and founder of Tramlines Fund, shared the story of the six generations of his family&amp;#39;s connection with China and his investment in biotechnology and pharmaceutical research and development in Wuhan, which has promoted scientific and cultural exchanges between China and foreign countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recognizing the growing importance of food for a growing world population, he said that his focus has shifted to agricultural technology innovation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Haworth said that China has an important position in the world&amp;#39;s scientific and technological landscape.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fan Zhiyong, vice-president and head of intellectual property at Huawei Technologies, said that technological innovation has become increasingly global, citing Huawei&amp;#39;s artificial intelligence video services which were developed jointly with the firm&amp;#39;s global partners and are widely used.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that in order to further globalize innovation, there should be more talents and a robust intellectual property protection system, which also needs global efforts to cultivate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jan Bongaerts, senior vice-president of Wuhan-based Yangtze Optical Fibre and Cable, recalled his company&amp;#39;s contribution to the city&amp;#39;s digital transformation in the past several decades.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said it is taking advantage of China&amp;#39;s policy to export innovative achievements overseas, and is constantly narrowing global digital gap.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company will strive to be the leader in the optical electronic information sector by being committed to innovation and the Optical Valley of China, a high-tech development zone in Wuhan, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Charles Mackay, a fellow of the Australian Academy of Science, and honorary president of the School of Pharmaceutical Sciences of Qilu University of Technology in Shandong province, analyzed the relationship between diet, gut microbiota and immune response.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He called for more efforts to develop new medicines to help prevent and treat human diseases, based on technological innovation and scientific findings.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;jiangchenglong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Xi stresses mutual understanding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/07/content_003_65495661ed50d203d2ca20f1.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_001_01_180078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping and Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese shake hands on Monday at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_001_01_163078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping greets Cuban Prime Minister Manuel Marrero Cruz on Monday at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_001_01_197078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping meets with Serbian Prime Minister Ana Brnabic on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-07/003/20231107_001_01_214078.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping meets with South African Deputy President Paul Mashatile on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping stressed on Monday the need for China and Australia to build up mutual understanding and trust through peaceful coexistence and achieve common development through win-win cooperation, during a meeting in Beijing with Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi told Albanese, who is marking the first visit to China by an Australian prime minister since 2016, that the two nations should fully tap into the potential of the China-Australia Free Trade Agreement, expand cooperation in areas such as climate change and the green economy, and uphold the global and regional free trade system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The president noted that the visit by Albanese can be seen as a continuation of past interactions between both sides and a new beginning, as this year marks the 50th anniversary of Gough Whitlam&amp;#39;s visit to China &amp;mdash; the first visit to China by an Australian prime minister.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two nations have resumed exchanges in various sectors and embarked on the correct path of improving and developing their relationship, Xi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Relations between China and Australia had stumbled in recent years amid trade issues and other challenges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Trade between the two nations dropped 3.9 percent year-on-year to $220.9 billion last year, even though China remained Australia&amp;#39;s largest trading partner and the biggest market for Australian exports.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi said that China and Australia, both countries in the Asia-Pacific and members of the G20, share no historical grievances or fundamental conflicts of interest, adding that the two sides can become partners who trust each other and facilitate each other&amp;#39;s development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is also important to grasp the right direction of China-Australia relations amid the profound changes in the global situation, Xi told his guest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Chinese president pointed out that if a nation only prioritizes its national interests, the world seems small and crowded, and full of risks and competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, if viewed from the perspective of a shared future, the world is vast and abundant, and full of opportunities and cooperation. In the tumultuous waves of global crises, the countries in the world are not each riding in more than 190 small boats but on a shared big vessel, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi called on the two nations to follow the trends of the times, building a relationship based on equality, seeking common ground while reserving differences, pursuing mutual benefit, and continuing to advance the bilateral comprehensive strategic partnership.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Faced with a complex external environment, the Chinese economy has withstood the pressure, stabilized its scale and improved its quality, he said, adding that China&amp;#39;s development is still built on a solid foundation and many favorable conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s stable development brings much-needed certainty to the world economy. China&amp;#39;s development cannot be separated from the world, and the world&amp;#39;s development also needs China, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi pointed out that actions seeking to build &amp;quot;small yards and high fences&amp;quot;, decoupling or de-risking are in essence all forms of protectionism that go against the laws of the market, technological development and the trends of development in human society.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He made an appeal for both nations to provide a favorable business environment for the investment and operation of enterprises in both countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two governments should support exchanges between legislative bodies, political parties, think tanks and youth, and at subnational levels, facilitate easier exchanges of personnel, and enhance mutual understanding and friendship between the two peoples, Xi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China does not form exclusive small circles, or engage in group politics or bloc confrontation in the Asia-Pacific region, the president said, adding that small circles cannot solve the major challenges facing the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Both nations should be vigilant against and oppose any attempts to disrupt the Asia-Pacific region, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also expressed readiness to carry out more trilateral and multilateral cooperation with Australia and support South Pacific countries in enhancing their development resilience and addressing challenges such as climate change.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Albanese, who is making his seventh visit to China and his first as prime minister, said both sides should respect each other, seek mutual benefit, maintain communication and exchanges, enhance understanding and cooperation, and achieve mutual benefit and win-win results.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said it is natural for Australia and China to have differences, but the two sides should not let the differences define their relationship.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two nations, with their broad shared interests, should see dialogue and cooperation as their right choices, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Canberra is willing to actively promote the stable development of bilateral relations with Beijing, enhance economic and trade exchanges, and strengthen cooperation in areas such as clean energy and climate change, to bring more benefits to the peoples of both countries, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Monday, the president also held separate meetings with leaders from Cuba, Serbia and South Africa at the Great Hall of the People.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Cuba&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When meeting with Cuban Prime Minister Manuel Marrero Cruz, Xi said China welcomes Cuba to participate in high-quality Belt and Road cooperation by tapping potential in fields such as agriculture, tourism, healthcare and science and technology for the pursuit of concrete and solid progress in bilateral cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi hailed the unbreakable bonds fostered between the two countries under the guidance of the older generations of leaders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that China views and develops the special friendly ties between the two countries and their ruling parties from a strategic and holistic perspective, Xi said China is willing to deepen political mutual trust and strategic collaboration with Cuba and exchange experience on governance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will continue to firmly support the Cuban people&amp;#39;s efforts to oppose external interference and the blockade and defend its sovereignty and national dignity, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi also expressed the hope that Cuba will make good use of the ongoing China International Import Expo and promote the entry of more of its specialty products to the Chinese market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Marrero, who attended the opening ceremony of the sixth CIIE in Shanghai on Sunday, said that, through his trip to China, he has gained a better understanding of the country&amp;#39;s remarkable achievements and the core leading role played by the Communist Party of China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cuba will work with China to deepen practical cooperation, maintain close collaboration in global and regional affairs, oppose hegemony and bullying, and safeguard international fairness and justice, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Serbia&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During his meeting with Serbian Prime Minister Ana Brnabic, Xi pointed out that China and Serbia are ironclad friends who have stood together through thick and thin. Under the new circumstances, China is willing to work with Serbia to promote the high-quality development of bilateral ties and better benefit the two peoples, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi emphasized the need for both countries to make concerted efforts to build and operate major cooperation projects, and promote the early entry into force of the China-Serbia Free Trade Agreement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China supports Serbia in pursuing an independent development path, and is willing to enhance multilateral coordination and cooperation with Serbia to jointly uphold international fairness and justice, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Brnabic hailed the development of bilateral ties, saying that China has become Serbia&amp;#39;s largest investment partner, and cooperation projects such as the Smederevo Steel Plant have transformed Serbia&amp;#39;s national development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The free trade agreement reached between the two countries within six months fully demonstrates their firm determination to further deepen their relationship, she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that China has always supported Serbia in safeguarding national sovereignty and dignity, Brnabic said Serbia firmly adheres to the one-China policy and wants to work with China to promote the joint construction of the Belt and Road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;South Africa&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When meeting with South African Deputy President Paul Mashatile, Xi said China is willing to promote a number of high-standard, people-centered and sustainable projects with African countries, including South Africa, to build a high-level China-Africa community with a shared future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi also reiterated China&amp;#39;s commitment to implementing the initiatives on supporting Africa&amp;#39;s industrialization and agricultural modernization, and promoting China-Africa cooperation on talent development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China and Africa should continue to closely cooperate within the BRICS cooperation mechanism, strengthen solidarity and cooperation among developing countries and promote the global governance system to better benefit those countries, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking of the China-South Africa relationship, which has entered &amp;quot;a golden age&amp;quot;, Xi said China is willing to work with South Africa to enrich their comprehensive strategic partnership and bring bilateral ties to new levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He stressed that China supports South Africa&amp;#39;s efforts in exploring a path to modernization that is suited to its own conditions and will further reinforce the solid foundation of political mutual trust with the nation and intensify mutually beneficial cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mashatile said that Xi&amp;#39;s visit to South Africa in August further consolidated the two countries&amp;#39; traditional friendship and also gave strong momentum to the future development of bilateral ties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; South Africa will better align its own development strategies with the Belt and Road Initiative, deepen practical cooperation with China in various areas and continue enhancing collaboration with China within multilateral frameworks, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>