<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Joint building of Belt and Road full of vitality]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_001_652ef5f4ed50d203d2ca0b9d.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/001/20231018_001_01_45.png&quot; />; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/001/20231018_001_01_36.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平和夫人彭丽媛（中）与外国领导人合影周二，他们及其配偶出席在北京人民大会堂举行的第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。习近平为外宾举行欢迎宴会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席周二强调，要秉持合作初心、不忘发展使命，推动“一带一路”高质量合作习近平在为出席第三届“一带一路”建设的国家元首、政府首脑和国际组织负责人等国际政要举行的欢迎宴会上发表讲话时表示： “一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛在北京举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “‘一带一路’合作十年来蓬勃发展、硕果累累，如今又充满生机和活力。”他说。 “我们要以干劲和干劲，踏上迈向下一个黄金十年的新征程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在会上表示，“让我们借此机会，向所有参与并做出贡献的人们致以敬意！” “一带一路合作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还表示：“当今世界很不安宁。世界经济下行压力加大。全球发展面临多重挑战。尽管如此，我们依然坚信，和平、发展、合作、共赢的历史潮流不可阻挡，人民对美好生活的向往一如既往，各国实现共同发展的愿望依然强烈。发展繁荣势不可挡。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周二晚，习近平和夫人彭丽媛在人民大会堂迎接领导人夫妇，并合影留念。宴会在雄伟建筑的金色大厅举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 总统在讲话开始时说：“春天是开花的季节，秋天是收获的季节。” “一带一路”倡议提出10年来，中国与“一带一路”沿线国家携手努力，践行了和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; “我们共同为全球互联互通做出了贡献，为国际经济合作打造了平台。我们共同成为全球增长的驱动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们共同实施了数千个合作项目，取得了扎实的成果。我们共同谱写了推动互联世界、为所有人实现个人和集体繁荣之路的宏伟篇章。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些成就都不是自然而然落在我们手中的，也不是任何人授予的。这些都是“一带一路”沿线国家政府、企业和人民用勤劳、智慧和勇气实现的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”追求发展、促进共赢、点燃希望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人类历史证明，没有合作就没有丰收”。坚持不懈的精神和不懈的努力，也同样能够取得可持续的成果，造福子孙后代。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是我们这一代政治领导人对当代和子孙后代必须履行的责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xuwei@中国日报网&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - BRI to bear more fruit globally, say executives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_001_652ef5f7ed50d203d2ca0b9e.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/001/20231018_001_02_7.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;企业高管互动第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛“一带一路”企业家大会周二在北京国家会议中心举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”倡议不断推进，将不断产生实质性合作、投资和成果政府高级官员和企业高管周二表示，全球范围内的企业增长机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在北京举行的第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛“一带一路”企业家大会上发言时，他们表示：通过这种合作，中外企业可以增强研究能力，拥抱尖端技术，完善应用专业知识。这些活动有可能重塑其增长轨迹，并在促进经济可持续发展方面发挥关键作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国务院副总理何立峰在会上表示，中国愿意扩大与“一带一路”沿线国家的相互市场准入打造更多贸易合作平台，构建多元化融资体系，深化产能合作，扩大双向投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 副总理强调，中方鼓励与会各国企业积极推动经贸合作。大数据、人工智能、新能源等领域。中共中央政治局委员、中共中央政治局委员何贺表示，这将推动“一带一路”建设朝着更加绿色、健康、智慧的方向发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国国际贸易促进委员会称，来自中外企业的300名代表签署了合作协议，项目涵盖基础设施、清洁能源、人工智能、金融服务、现代农业和轨道交通等多个领域。会议主办方介绍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 理事会表示，项目数量、涉及国家和地区、交易金额均明显超过上届2019年在北京举行的CEO会议&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据国务院新闻办公室最近发布的白皮书，2013年至2022年，中国与“一带一路”沿线其他经济体双向投资总额超过3800亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;p>; Harilela酒店集团主席兼首席执行官、香港总商会前主席Aron Harilela表示，在保护主义可能撕裂世界的时刻，“一带一路”倡议诉说着共同未来的愿景——在这一愿景中，各国和企业可以共同努力，不仅使人们的生活更美好，而且可以用来应对世界面临的经济、社会和环境挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”倡议是中国人民大学重阳金融研究院执行院长王文表示，“一带一路”倡议不仅凝聚了各方力量，还构建了共同发展的增长理念、合作平台和市场网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ” .com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Kenyan president hails mutually beneficial ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_001_652ef5faed50d203d2ca0b9f.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/001/20231018_001_03_37.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;在线&amp;lt ;/b>;扫码查看更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/001/20231018_001_03_33.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;William鲁托&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 肯尼亚总统威廉·鲁托表示，肯尼亚与中国的关系是互利共赢、合作共赢的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鲁托周五在接受采访时发表上述言论在前往北京出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛之前，他们在肯尼亚首都内罗毕接受了媒体采访。他于周日抵达北京，开始作为肯尼亚总统首次访华。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对中国对非援助是“债务陷阱”的言论，鲁托表示，非洲国家他们能够为自己谈判出他们认为对非洲人民和作为合作伙伴的中国平衡和公平的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “有神话，有谣言，有看法。现实是，我们最大的债务不是欠中国的。我们对世界银行、国际货币基金组织、欧盟、美国和许多其他组织负有巨大的义务。”肯尼亚总统说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，非洲作为一个大陆，重新设计与世界其他地区的关系非常重要。非洲国家元首已决定，无论何时非洲与其他伙伴接触，他们都将确保这一进程是结构化的、尊重的和互利的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鲁托提到肯尼亚和中国之间深厚的历史联系，由各国栽培的过去 60 年来两国领导人和人民的共同努力，证明了两国保持着牢固的双边关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们有着超越普通政府结构的友谊纽带，”他说，并补充说，这种关系在商业和文化等许多领域的民间交流中根深蒂固。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚刚结束任期第一年的鲁托表示，肯尼亚与肯尼亚的关系中国正在从一个以贸易和贷款为基础的国家发展为一个以投资为基础的国家。他表示，肯尼亚很高兴中国不把自己认为正确的事情强加于人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 肯尼亚是成功实施总统提出的“一带一路”倡议的非洲国家的典范。鲁托表示，习近平10年前的讲话与肯尼亚2030年愿景一致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在“一带一路”框架内，肯尼亚建设了标准轨距铁路和2000多公里的道路基础设施，并他说，欢迎更多的中国企业，这些企业现在已成为该国家喻户晓的企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国贸易质量和数量的提高也得到了肯尼亚总统的赞扬，他说，肯尼亚现在可以向中国出口牛油果等农产品，并正在寻求扩大其产品组合以包括更多产品和服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ruto 表示，“一带一路”倡议对全球发展发挥了重要作用，因为它涉及 150 多个国家和近乎世界人口的70%。他表示，他期待与中国和其他全球领导人分享“一带一路”经验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “例如，在肯尼亚，我们在“一带一路”倡议下建设了标轨铁路和其他基础设施。”我们愿意与其他成员分享这些项目如何提振我们的经济、连接我们的村庄、改善老百姓的生活、促进商业发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”论坛将成为一个平台鲁托表示，要利用已经取得的成就，建设更美好的明天，不让任何人落后，并补充说，非洲将考虑农业和商业数字化等新的、现代的合作领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ；我期待与热衷于肯尼亚机遇的中国投资者会面。我们有多达 13 项投资倡议和协议，这些将在我访问期间达成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该论坛是在下个月在阿拉伯联合酋长国举行的 COP28 气候峰会之前举行的鲁托表示，肯尼亚和中国在倡导气候行动方面具有互补关系。这是因为中国在可再生能源领域的技术进步方面处于全球领先地位，而肯尼亚拥有太阳能、风能和地热能等资源，可以利用这些技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说，肯尼亚正处于可再生能源领域的领先地位。联合国环境规划署在国家和全球范围内倡导气候行动的前沿，位于该国的联合国环境规划署总部是唯一位于南半球的联合国总部。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 联合国人居署项目也设在肯尼亚，肯尼亚是最早禁止使用塑料袋的国家之一，并很荣幸能够主办最近在内罗毕举行的首届非洲气候峰会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鲁托表示，肯尼亚赞赏中国的支持众所周知，该领域的大部分基础设施，例如太阳能发电站，都在中国积极发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “因此，中国正在协助可再生能源领域的发展。”世界各国提出干预措施、技术、设备和基础设施来促进气候行动并提供解决方案，我们准备作为其合作伙伴实施这些技术。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：otiato@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - BRI unleashes opportunities, say executives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_002_652ef5fded50d203d2ca0ba0.htm#002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 企业高管和行业专家周二表示，“一带一路”倡议为全球企业带来了巨大机遇，为跨国公司创造了充满希望的环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;渣打集团董事长何塞·维纳尔斯周二在北京举行的“一带一路”首席执行官会议上表示，通过参与国政府之间的强有力合作以及与私营部门和国际金融机构的接触，在支持跨境发展方面取得了有意义的进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 维纳尔斯表示，随着“一带一路”进入新的十年，这为更多“一带一路”合作伙伴提供了机遇，支持可持续发展、数字创新、包容性、韧性和互联互通等重要领域进一步高质量发展和增长.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路是我行的战略重点。我们的存在以及我们的“一带一路”活动和合作伙伴关系，使我们能够在过去五年中支持近 650 个“一带一路”相关项目，总价值超过 1110 亿美元。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 经过多年的发展，“一带一路”已成为许多跨国公司全球布局的关键因素之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ACWA Power董事长Mohammad A. Abunayyan表示，中沙在“一带一路”框架下的合作为清洁能源项目取得重大进展铺平了道路，沙特将继续重申对中国和中国合作伙伴的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ACWA Power 看到了在“一带一路”倡议下进一步合作的巨大潜力，这为该公司提供了加强互联互通、促进经济增长和创造长期繁荣的独特机会。”他在“一带一路”工商领导人大会上表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “‘一带一路’强调高质量合作，与我们共同发展繁荣的共同愿景完美契合。” “一带一路”为我们发挥优势、分享专业知识、促进创新以实现这些目标提供了理想的平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “沙特和中国已经为可再生能源领域的合作奠定了坚实的基础。 ，我们必须以此为契机，进一步优化“一带一路”的潜力。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为一家全球物流公司，联邦快递表示，它拥抱“一带一路”增强的互联互通和降低的运输成本，以扩大其在参与国家和地区的业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 联邦快递美国联邦快递高级副总裁、联邦快递中国区总裁陈嘉伟表示，多年来，联邦快递深入参与“一带一路”项目，为全球产业链供应链稳定做出了贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;“联邦快递将发挥我们在国际物流领域的优势和专业知识，拓展在中国和“一带一路”沿线国家的网络，优化我们的跨境运输服务组合，加强中国与其他“一带一路”沿线国家和地区的联系， ” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国人民大学教授徐勤华表示，过去几年，“一带一路”给世界带来了重大发展机遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一带一路”为世界带来了巨大的发展机遇。徐说，过去几年基础设施建设项目，带动了参与国家和地区取得了重大进展，特别是在铁路、能源基础设施发展等领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”给世界带来了新的见解。她补充道，国际合作、绿色创新和可持续发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：zhengxin@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - Reporters upbeat about forum&#39;s role in communication]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_002_652ef600ed50d203d2ca0ba1.htm#002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/002/20231018_002_02_26.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;记者了解中国景泰蓝周一，在北京举行的第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛媒体中心，一种通过焊接金属条并填充珐琅膏来装饰金属器皿的技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 外国记者报道第三届“一带一路” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我最感兴趣的是主题涉及绿色能源、绿色发展以及为确保我们拥有可转让给真正需要清洁技术以促进发展的国家而付出的一切努力。”津巴布韦最大报纸《先驱报》记者 Walter Nyamukondiwa 表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nyamukondiwa 表示，气候变化已成为发展的重大挑战，国家、企业和组织必须为此付出代价。在追求和维持发展的同时特别关注环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他补充说，津巴布韦交通和基础设施发展部长菲利克斯·莫纳 (Felix Mhona) 将出席在北京举行的活动。尼亚穆孔迪瓦表示，他期待向莫纳了解本国已经在筹建的“一带一路”框架下的项目以及未来的合作前景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周二和周三举行的峰会将包括三场关于互联互通、绿色发展和数字经济的高层会议。还将举办六场主题分论坛，涵盖海上合作、民心相通、贸易畅通等主题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 智利媒体《公民报》记者玛丽亚·桑胡埃萨表示，世界面临的最重要、最紧迫的任务是加快向绿色经济转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们知道，我们正处于非常危险的境地，气候变暖的风险与日俱增。”所以这是论坛期间我最感兴趣的维度之一，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 智利总统加布里埃尔·博里奇在北京出席此次活动时，桑胡埃萨表示，她计划报告智利将在可再生技术合作方面达成的共识，作为“一带一路”的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 桑胡埃萨补充说，这次论坛也是在世界其他地区因冲突引发的对抗加剧之际召开的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，“我们有这个倡议，实际上正在实施”她说：“合作的方向，让各国坐在一起讨论共同的挑战和共同的目标”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 巴基斯坦《观察家外交家》杂志主编 Saud Faisal Malik 表示他将重点关注该倡议的未来协议，特别是商业领域可能达成的新谅解备忘录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 马利克表示，位于国家会议中心的媒体中心的各种设施给他留下了深刻的印象。 ”媒体中心设施齐全，为媒体朋友提供了一切便利。它有不同的中国活动，如传统医学和木块技术，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据活动主办方介绍，已有近4000名中外记者报名报道本次活动，其中海外记者超过1200名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 坦桑尼亚记者Kwizela Basebya ” 说：“我在论坛媒体中心看到的最重要的事情之一就是技术。我看到很多大规模的新技术涌现，比如人工智能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “媒体中心的环境和设置很漂亮，很棒，很现代。”我认为这是记者工作和报道论坛的好地方，”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangxiaoyu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - Great Wall walk]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_002_652ef603ed50d203d2ca0ba2.htm#002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/002/20231018_002_03_34.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;参加第十六届的选手周二，“汉语桥”世界中学生中文比赛在北京长城巡演。比赛以“汉语飞翔”为主题，于10月16日至31日在北京和云南举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS： &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - Belt and Road nations increase patents]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_002_652ef606ed50d203d2ca0ba3.htm#002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 最近的一份报告称，过去十年，随着中国更多专利申请的动力增强，越来越多的创新者参与“一带一路”倡议的技术交流与合作。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 据中国中央领导层发布的报告显示，去年，共有3,982个“一带一路”沿线国家的创新实体在中国申请了专利，比2013年中国提出“一带一路”倡议时增加了654个。报告称，这一增幅意味着“随着‘一带一路’倡议的深入，‘一带一路’沿线国家对中国知识产权保护环境的看法更加积极”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 报告显示，过去10年，共有115个“一带一路”国家向中国提交了专利申请。大部分来自韩国，其次是意大利、新加坡、奥地利和卢森堡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 截至目前，“一带一路”国家在华累计申请量达25.3万件，其中不少为发明和外观设计专利涵盖半导体、计算机技术、数字通信等技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着中国来自“一带一路”沿线国家的专利申请增多，市场主体也走出去拓展业务，加强知识产权合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 报告显示，中国企业在“一带一路”沿线国家申请和公开的专利数量从2013年的2,000件增加到去年的15,000件，年增长率达25.8%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报告补充称，中国申请人中，大部分来自广东省，其次是长三角地区和京津冀地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着中国已成为全球绿色低碳创新的重要贡献者， -碳技术近年来在“一带一路”沿线国家的相关专利申请也呈上升趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2013年至去年，涉及低碳技术的发明专利申请超过3500件。报告称，中国企业在“一带一路”沿线国家应用碳技术，年均增长16.7%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 作为全球最大的清洁能源市场和装备制造商，中国积极发挥自身优势环保技术创新优势，为推动绿色发展提供有力支撑。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据中国国务院新闻办公室去年发布的《一带一路：构建人类命运共同体的重要支柱》白皮书。一周以来，中国已与50多个伙伴国家和国际组织建立了知识产权合作关系，其目标是营造知识价值得到应有尊重的创新和商业环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caoyin@中国日报网&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - Kenyan president hails mutually beneficial ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_002_652ef608ed50d203d2ca0ba4.htm#002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/002/20231018_001_03_37.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;在线&amp;lt ;/b>;扫码查看更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/002/20231018_001_03_33.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;William鲁托&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 肯尼亚总统威廉·鲁托表示，肯尼亚与中国的关系是互利共赢、合作共赢的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鲁托周五在接受采访时发表上述言论在前往北京出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛之前，他们在肯尼亚首都内罗毕接受了媒体采访。他于周日抵达北京，开始作为肯尼亚总统首次访华。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对中国对非援助是“债务陷阱”的言论，鲁托表示，非洲国家他们能够为自己谈判出他们认为对非洲人民和作为合作伙伴的中国平衡和公平的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “有神话，有谣言，有看法。现实是，我们最大的债务不是欠中国的。我们对世界银行、国际货币基金组织、欧盟、美国和许多其他组织负有巨大的义务。”肯尼亚总统说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，非洲作为一个大陆，重新设计与世界其他地区的关系非常重要。非洲国家元首已决定，无论何时非洲与其他伙伴接触，他们都将确保这一进程是结构化的、尊重的和互利的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鲁托提到肯尼亚和中国之间深厚的历史联系，由各国栽培的过去 60 年来两国领导人和人民的共同努力，证明了两国保持着牢固的双边关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们有着超越普通政府结构的友谊纽带，”他说，并补充说，这种关系在商业和文化等许多领域的民间交流中根深蒂固。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚刚结束任期第一年的鲁托表示，肯尼亚与肯尼亚的关系中国正在从一个以贸易和贷款为基础的国家发展为一个以投资为基础的国家。他表示，肯尼亚很高兴中国不把自己认为正确的事情强加于人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 肯尼亚是成功实施总统提出的“一带一路”倡议的非洲国家的典范。鲁托表示，习近平10年前的讲话与肯尼亚2030年愿景一致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在“一带一路”框架内，肯尼亚建设了标准轨距铁路和2000多公里的道路基础设施，并他说，欢迎更多的中国企业，这些企业现在已成为该国家喻户晓的企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两国贸易质量和数量的提高也得到了肯尼亚总统的赞扬，他说，肯尼亚现在可以向中国出口牛油果等农产品，并正在寻求扩大其产品组合以包括更多产品和服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ruto 表示，“一带一路”倡议对全球发展发挥了重要作用，因为它涉及 150 多个国家和近乎世界人口的70%。他表示，他期待与中国和其他全球领导人分享“一带一路”经验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “例如，在肯尼亚，我们在“一带一路”倡议下建设了标轨铁路和其他基础设施。”我们愿意与其他成员分享这些项目如何提振我们的经济、连接我们的村庄、改善老百姓的生活、促进商业发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”论坛将成为一个平台鲁托表示，要利用已经取得的成就，建设更美好的明天，不让任何人落后，并补充说，非洲将考虑农业和商业数字化等新的、现代的合作领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ；我期待与热衷于肯尼亚机遇的中国投资者会面。我们有多达 13 项投资倡议和协议，这些将在我访问期间达成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该论坛是在下个月在阿拉伯联合酋长国举行的 COP28 气候峰会之前举行的鲁托表示，肯尼亚和中国在倡导气候行动方面具有互补关系。这是因为中国在可再生能源领域的技术进步方面处于全球领先地位，而肯尼亚拥有太阳能、风能和地热能等资源，可以利用这些技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他说，肯尼亚正处于可再生能源领域的领先地位。联合国环境规划署在国家和全球范围内倡导气候行动的前沿，位于该国的联合国环境规划署总部是唯一位于南半球的联合国总部。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 联合国人居署项目也设在肯尼亚，肯尼亚是最早禁止使用塑料袋的国家之一，并很荣幸能够主办最近在内罗毕举行的首届非洲气候峰会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鲁托表示，肯尼亚赞赏中国的支持众所周知，该领域的大部分基础设施，例如太阳能发电站，都在中国积极发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “因此，中国正在协助可再生能源领域的发展。”世界各国提出干预措施、技术、设备和基础设施来促进气候行动并提供解决方案，我们准备作为其合作伙伴实施这些技术。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：otiato@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - BRI to bear more fruit globally, say executives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_002_652ef608ed50d203d2ca0ba5.htm#002BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/002/20231018_001_02_7.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;企业高管互动第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛“一带一路”企业家大会周二在北京国家会议中心举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”倡议不断推进，将不断产生实质性合作、投资和成果政府高级官员和企业高管周二表示，全球范围内的企业增长机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在北京举行的第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛“一带一路”企业家大会上发言时，他们表示：通过这种合作，中外企业可以增强研究能力，拥抱尖端技术，完善应用专业知识。 These activities can potentially reshape their growth trajectory and play a pivotal role in fostering sustainable economic development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vice-Premier He Lifeng said at the conference that China is willing to expand mutual market access with countries involved in the BRI, create more trade cooperation platforms, build up a diversified financing system, deepen production capacity cooperation and expand two-way investment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The vice-premier stressed that China encourages businesses from all participating countries to actively promote cooperation in areas such as big data, artificial intelligence and new energy. This will drive the development of BRI toward a greener, healthier and more intelligent direction, said He, who is also a member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the conference, nearly 300 delegates from Chinese and foreign companies signed cooperation agreements, which encompass projects in various fields, including infrastructure, clean energy, artificial intelligence, financial services, modern agriculture and rail transportation, according to the China Council for the Promotion of International Trade, one of the event&amp;#39;s organizers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The number of projects, countries and regions involved, and the value of deals have notably surpassed those of the previous CEO conference, which was held in Beijing in 2019, the council said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two-way investment between China and other economies involved in the BRI totaled more than $380 billion between 2013 and 2022, according to a white paper recently released by the State Council Information Office.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Aron Harilela, chairman and CEO of Harilela Hotels Group and former chairman of the Hong Kong General Chamber of Commerce, said that at a time when protectionism could tear the world apart, the BRI speaks to a vision of a shared future &amp;mdash; a vision where countries and businesses can work together not just to make people&amp;#39;s lives better, but a framework they can use to tackle the economic, social and environmental challenges the world faces.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The BRI is a growth concept, a cooperative platform and a market network built for the common development, said Wang Wen, executive dean of Renmin University of China&amp;#39;s Chongyang Institute for Financial Studies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The initiative not only unites the strengths of emerging economies, but also promotes dialogue and exchange between developed and developing countries, consolidating and balancing the old and new forces of global development, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at zhongnan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - Mutual benefits in spotlight in Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_003_652ef60bed50d203d2ca0ba6.htm#003BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_18.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Gabriel Boric&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_22.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Joko Widodo&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_25.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Kassym-Jomart Tokayev&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_29.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Aleksandar Vucic&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_34.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Shavkat Mirziyoyev&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_38.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Abiy Ahmed&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_41.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Viktor Orban&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/003/20231018_003_01_45.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;James Marape&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;CHILE&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping stressed on Tuesday the need for China and Chile to better align their development strategies, promote high-quality building of the Belt and Road, and foster new growth engines for bilateral cooperation in clean energy, the digital economy and sci-tech innovation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In talks with Chilean President Gabriel Boric, Xi called for both sides to firmly support each other in pursuing development paths that suit their national conditions and safeguard each other&amp;#39;s core interests and major concerns.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Beijing stands ready to enhance exchanges with Santiago in national governance experience and share its successful practices in poverty alleviation, green transitioning and environmental protection, Xi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China welcomes more high-quality agricultural produce and specialty products from Chile into the Chinese market, he said, adding that the nation will encourage more companies to take part in the construction of major projects in Chile.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also expressed readiness to promote Chinese language teaching and learning, bolster bilateral cooperation at the local level, facilitate people-to-people exchanges, strengthen public support for bilateral ties and promote mutual learning between civilizations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi underscored China&amp;#39;s strong emphasis regarding its ties with Latin America, saying that Beijing appreciates Santiago&amp;#39;s positive contributions to the development of China-Latin America relations and the construction of the China-CELAC (Community of Latin American and Caribbean States) Forum.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Boric said he hopes his visit will be an opportunity to strengthen bilateral cooperation in areas such as environmental protection, poverty reduction, energy, technology and mining.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chile supports China&amp;#39;s accession to the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement, he said, adding that his country hopes to become a hub for China&amp;#39;s cooperation with Latin American countries and play an active role in promoting China-Latin America relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the talks, the two leaders witnessed the signing of multiple bilateral cooperation agreements covering the Belt and Road Initiative, development cooperation, industrial investment, the digital economy, technological innovation, customs inspection and quarantine, agriculture, the Antarctic, and cooperation with small and medium-sized enterprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; XU WEI&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;INDONESIA&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping hailed on Tuesday the tremendous benefits that cooperation between China and Indonesia has brought to the peoples of the two countries, saying that Beijing and Jakarta have set a good example for international cooperation under the Belt and Road Initiative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi made the remarks when meeting in Beijing with Indonesian President Joko Widodo. Xi first proposed jointly building the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road in Indonesia in 2013.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized that China, together with Indonesia, will continue to view and develop bilateral relations from a strategic and long-term perspective, deepen all-around strategic cooperation and boost support for each other on issues of core interest and major concern, thus pursuing modernization paths suited to their respective national conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that the Jakarta-Bandung High-Speed Railway is a flagship project of China-Indonesia cooperation under the BRI, Xi called on the two sides to summarize their successful experiences, ensure the railway&amp;#39;s high-quality operation and develop an economic corridor centered around it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China supports the participation of its government bodies and enterprises in the construction of major projects such as Indonesia&amp;#39;s building of a new capital, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi expressed China&amp;#39;s willingness to increase imports of high-quality agricultural and fishery products from Indonesia, strengthen cooperation in emerging industries such as the digital economy and photovoltaics, and proactively engage in exchanges and cooperation in areas such as food and agricultural technologies, poverty alleviation, healthcare and education.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China and Indonesia should closely coordinate to maintain the central position of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, promote open regionalism and fulfill the responsibility of major developing countries, in order to jointly promote reform of the global governance system and uphold international fairness and justice, Xi added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Widodo, who is also paying a state visit to China, said his country regards China as a significant strategic partner and expects to further strengthen cooperation and mutual trust with China to develop a closer partnership.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two heads of state jointly inaugurated the operation of the Jakarta-Bandung High-Speed Railway after their talks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; MO JINGXI&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;KAZAKHSTAN&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping called on China and Kazakhstan to strengthen cooperation and achieve more results in jointly building the Belt and Road in order to better benefit their peoples, while meeting with Kazakh President Kassym-Jomart Tokayev in Beijing on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi said that a healthy, stable and dynamic China-Kazakhstan relationship is conducive to the development and revitalization of the two countries, as well as to regional peace and stability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regardless of changes in the international situation, China and Kazakhstan should look out for and support each other, pass on the concept of good-neighborliness and friendship from generation to generation, and promote further development of the China-Kazakhstan permanent comprehensive strategic partnership, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi said China is willing to continuously facilitate trade and investment with Kazakhstan, increase imports of high-quality and green agricultural products from Kazakhstan, expand green energy cooperation and strengthen connectivity with efforts such as enhancing the capacity, scale and efficiency of China-Europe freight trains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He encouraged the two sides to strengthen cooperation, enhance strategic synergy between the Digital Silk Road and Digital Kazakhstan, and boost exchanges in digital technologies such as cross-border e-commerce and big data.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi also called for stronger people-to-people and cultural exchanges and closer cooperation at the local level, noting that a mutual visa exemption agreement between the two countries will take effect and that the Kazakhstan tourism year in China will be launched next year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tokayev said that his country has been firmly supporting and proactively participating in the Belt and Road Initiative since the day Xi first proposed the joint building of the Silk Road Economic Belt 10 years ago in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said Kazakhstan will deepen practical cooperation and strengthen people-to-people exchanges with China to jointly build the next golden three decades of China-Kazakhstan relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tokayev spoke highly of China&amp;#39;s impartial stance and active role in international affairs, including its efforts to promote the settlement of the Ukraine crisis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; MO JINGXI&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;SERBIA&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping and visiting Serbian President Aleksandar Vucic pledged on Tuesday to boost pragmatic cooperation between China and Serbia in various fields, especially in joint construction of the Belt and Road, to translate the countries&amp;#39; traditional friendship into concrete cooperation results.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They witnessed the signing of bilateral cooperation documents, including the midterm action plan for Belt and Road cooperation, a memorandum of understanding on industrial and investment cooperation and a free-trade agreement, after their meeting in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the meeting, Xi hailed the ironclad friendship between the two countries, saying that China-Serbia ties have withstood changes in the international situation, setting an example for friendly relations between China and European countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi emphasized that in the face of profound changes in the international landscape unseen in a century, both sides should view their relations from a strategic standpoint and long-term perspective, firmly support each other on their core interests and major concerns, and support each other in choosing their own development path.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China firmly supports Serbia in safeguarding its national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and is willing to continue to strengthen alignment with Serbia on development strategies, transforming the traditional friendship between them into more practical cooperation results, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi underlined the need for both sides to work together to build and operate the Hungary-Serbia railway project well, give full play to the economic and social benefits of projects such as the Chinese-invested Smederevo steel mill, and solidly promote cooperation in key areas such as infrastructure construction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Both countries should actively explore new growth drivers for cooperation and comprehensively strengthen cooperation to renew their ironclad friendship in the new era, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vucic said he led a large delegation of the Serbian government to attend the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, demonstrating Serbia&amp;#39;s respect for, friendship with and the importance it attaches to China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China has always respected and treated Serbia as a partner on an equal footing, and provided valuable support to Serbia when it was in times of difficulty, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; CAO DESHENG&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;UZBEKISTAN&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping said on Tuesday that China is willing to take the 10th anniversary of the Belt and Road Initiative as an opportunity for China and Uzbekistan to learn from and support each other&amp;#39;s national modernization drive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi made the remark when meeting with Uzbek President Shavkat Mirziyoyev.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that China and Uzbekistan share similar goals and ideas for development, Xi said the two countries will inject more certainty and positive energy into regional peace and prosperity by jointly building a China-Uzbekistan community with a shared future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China supports Uzbekistan in maintaining sovereignty, independence and territorial integrity, and firmly opposes any force&amp;#39;s interference in Uzbekistan&amp;#39;s internal affairs under any pretext, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi called on the two sides to put into place their medium-to-long-term cooperation plans in the economic, trade, and investment fields, promote cooperation in key areas, and create conditions for the early construction of the China-Kyrgyzstan-Uzbekistan railway project.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to expand its imports of high-quality products from Uzbekistan and welcomes more young people from Uzbekistan to study in China, he said, adding that China is ready to provide more scholarships to the Uzbek side.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi also urged the two sides to set up cultural centers in each other&amp;#39;s country at an early date, speed up the Luban Workshop project and promote experience exchanges and cooperation in poverty reduction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to work with Uzbekistan to earnestly implement the outcomes of the China-Central Asia Summit in Xi&amp;#39;an in order to contribute to the development and revitalization of the six countries, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mirziyoyev said his country regards China as a reliable partner and the Uzbekistan-China relationship has served as a model of good-neighborliness and mutual benefit for neighboring countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Uzbekistan hopes to learn from China&amp;#39;s poverty reduction experience and deepen exchanges and cooperation in various fields such as trade and investment, connectivity, renewable energy, agriculture and people-to-people exchanges within the framework of the Belt and Road Initiative, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; MO JINGXI&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;ETHIOPIA&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping called on Tuesday for China and Ethiopia to be friends who jointly promote common development and win-win cooperation as well as partners in enhancing South-South unity and cooperation and upholding international fairness and justice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi made the remarks during a meeting with Ethiopian Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed. He congratulated Ethiopia on joining the BRICS cooperation mechanism, saying that the East African country is an important participant in joint building of the Belt and Road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi underlined the need for both countries to constantly consolidate their traditional friendship and mutual trust, and deepen pragmatic cooperation to achieve more fruitful results in promoting bilateral ties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized that China supports Ethiopia in safeguarding its sovereignty, security and development interests, and the two countries should continue to strengthen unity and cooperation and should firmly support each other on issues concerning their core interests and major concerns.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to strengthen practical cooperation with Ethiopia in various fields within the framework of the Belt and Road Initiative and the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation, support Ethiopia&amp;#39;s postwar reconstruction and economic revitalization and enhance partnership in green development, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ahmed said that China is an important partner, and Chinese investment and other bilateral cooperation projects, especially those under the BRI, have effectively promoted Ethiopia&amp;#39;s economic and social development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ethiopia&amp;#39;s relationship with China is on the right path, and further strengthening bilateral relations is not only crucial for Ethiopia but also of great significance for South-South unity, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ahmed said that Ethiopia hopes to learn from China&amp;#39;s experience in Party and State governance, and looks forward to further promoting the joint construction of the Belt and Road with China. Ethiopia welcomes more Chinese investment, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative and the Global Civilization Initiative, all proposed by Xi, embody equality, openness and mutual respect, and they are conducive to promoting common development, said Ahmed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two countries issued a joint statement on the establishment of an all-weather strategic partnership.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; CAO DESHENG&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;HUNGARY&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China and Hungary should make joint efforts to ensure the on-time completion and operation of the Hungary-Serbia railway project, build up the scale of cross-border e-commerce and expand cooperation in the information technology and new-energy sectors, President Xi Jinping said on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking during a meeting with Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban in Beijing, Xi stressed China&amp;#39;s commitment to promoting a deep synergy of the Belt and Road Initiative with Hungary&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Opening to the East&amp;quot; policy, and sharing development opportunities and achievements.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China stands ready to scale up imports of high-quality agricultural products from Hungary, and the two sides should make good use of cultural centers established in each other&amp;#39;s countries, encourage language teaching and learning, and pass down the tradition of China-Hungary friendship to future generations, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He commended Hungary for pursuing a friendly policy toward China and actively supporting the BRI.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to continue being a trustworthy friend and partner of Hungary, and take the China-Hungary comprehensive strategic partnership to new levels as next year marks the 75th anniversary of bilateral diplomatic relations, said the president.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While noting that cooperation between China and Central and Eastern European countries serves the common interests of both sides, Xi said that China is willing to work with Hungary to continue guiding this cooperation in the right direction, enriching its content and enabling the stable and long-term development of China-Europe relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Orban, who also took part in the previous two editions of the Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, underlined the contribution of Chinese companies, including the construction of the Hungary-Serbia railway project in spurring Hungary&amp;#39;s socioeconomic growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He expressed steadfast support for the BRI and pledged continuous participation in the initiative, which he said has led to significant positive changes in the world and promotes global economic growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hungary will continue to be a trustworthy friend and partner of China within the European Union, he said, adding that his country opposes any &amp;quot;decoupling&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;de-risking&amp;quot; practices and is willing to strengthen economic, trade, investment and connectivity cooperation with China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; XU WEI&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;PAPUA NEW GUINEA&lt;/B>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s assistance to Pacific island countries is part of South-South cooperation, and is characterized by sincerity and selflessness, President Xi Jinping said on Tuesday during a meeting in Beijing with Papua New Guinean Prime Minister James Marape.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xi said that in conducting such assistance, China does not attach political conditions or seek exclusive rights, nor does it impose its will on others or make empty promises.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The nation fully respects the will and actual needs of Pacific island countries, and will continue to deepen cooperation with them and help them pursue long-term economic and social development, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China appreciates Papua New Guinea&amp;#39;s adherence to the one-China principle and its firm support for China on issues concerning its core interests and major concerns, he said, adding that China firmly supports Papua New Guinea in safeguarding its national sovereignty, security and development interests.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that Papua New Guinea was the first Pacific island country to sign a memorandum of understanding and a cooperation plan for jointly building the Belt and Road with China, Xi said that construction of projects such as the Independence Boulevard in Port Moresby and the Butuka Academy have made positive progress, playing a leading and exemplary role in promoting cooperation between China and Pacific island countries in joint construction of the Belt and Road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to continue to develop high-quality cooperation with Papua New Guinea on the BRI, share the development opportunities brought by Chinese-style modernization, align the development strategies of the two countries, strengthen cooperation in infrastructure, agriculture, forestry, fisheries, clean energy, climate change and other fields, and help Papua New Guinea achieve industrialization and modernization, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Marape said that Papua New Guinea firmly adheres to the one-China principle, and China&amp;#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity must be respected.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that strengthening cooperation with China is not only significant for Papua New Guinea but also for the world, he said the nation will continue to work with China to deepen their comprehensive strategic partnership, and promote mutually beneficial cooperation between South Pacific island countries and China for a better future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; CAO DESHENG&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[004BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION - BRI points Saudi Arabia&#39;s rail network in the right direction]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/18/content_004_652ef60eed50d203d2ca0ba7.htm#004BELT AND ROAD FORUM FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/004/20231018_004_01_11.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Passengers wait to board a metro train to take part in the Hajj in Mecca, Saudi Arabia, in June.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-18/004/20231018_004_01_14.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Employees of China Railway Construction Corp assist passengers at one of the stations on the Mecca Metro Line.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the launch of the Belt and Road Initiative in 2013, China has been collaborating with participating countries on a number of infrastructure construction projects that have benefited local residents.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Over the years, Chinese businesses have played an increasingly active role in projects under the BRI framework, and their depth and breadth of involvement continue to expand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; July 1 saw the end of this year&amp;#39;s Hajj, the annual pilgrimage for Muslims to Mecca, Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Mecca Metro, the first light railway constructed and operated by China Railway Construction Corp, a State-owned enterprise, in the Middle East, carried more than 2.15 million pilgrims during the weeklong annual event.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During this year&amp;#39;s Hajj, the Mecca Metro service &amp;mdash; which started related operations at 4 am local time on June 25 and concluded at 6 pm local time on July 1 &amp;mdash; provided 2,208 trips, surpassing the planned target by 131.2 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The entire operation was carried out seamlessly, thereby ensuring the safety, stability and orderliness of the transportation service.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the pilgrimage, Saleh bin Nasser Al-Jasser, Saudi Arabia&amp;#39;s minister of transport, expressed his appreciation of the CRCC operations team for its professionalism and the close cooperation of all parties involved in the service.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I would like to express my heartfelt thanks to you for your outstanding efforts in transporting passengers on schedule,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With a total length of 18.25 kilometers, and with nine stations connecting three holy sites, the railway played a crucial role in transporting pilgrims to and from the sites.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Part of the light rail was constructed by the China Railway 16 Bureau Group, a CRCC subsidiary.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Sept 11, China Construction News reported that CR16, a pioneering force in contributions to the BRI, not only operates the largest high-end equipment production base in northern China under the CRCC, but has also built an integrated trade network that connects many countries and regions worldwide.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The newspaper added that the company will continue to actively contribute to the BRI as it strives to promote exchanges, cooperation and mutual development between China and participating countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Challenges overcome&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the Mecca Metro, another railway construction project in Saudi Arabia has been completed by CCRC, despite the challenges of building a high-speed railway in desert conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With a total length of 450 km and a top speed of 360 km per hour, the Haramain High Speed Railway, aka the Mecca-Medina railway, runs through four cities &amp;mdash; Mecca, Rabigh, Jeddah and Medina &amp;mdash; providing services for more than 15 million passengers annually, according to statistics from the Hainan University Belt and Road Research Institute.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As the world&amp;#39;s first high-speed railway to cross a desert, the facility was completed after numerous challenges were overcome, including laying solid foundations in a desert region, harsh weather &amp;mdash; such as frequent sandstorms and extreme temperatures &amp;mdash; and a shortage of skilled workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This is the third rail project we have built in Saudi Arabia. Previously, we built the Saudi Arabia North-South Railway and the Mecca Light Rail. During seven years of construction of the Mecca-Medina high-speed railway, we have trained more than 400 local technical workers, hired over 1,000 local workers and created more than 1,500 job opportunities,&amp;quot; said Chen Debin, a project manager with the China Railway 18th Bureau Group in the Mecca-Medina project.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We have not only exchanged engineering and technical expertise, but we have also established many deep friendships with the local people.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;quanzhanfu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>