<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Nation called on to firm up confidence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_001_6515cafced50d203d2c9fcec.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_001_01_133654.png&quot; />; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_001_01_111654.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;国家主席习近平，中共中央总书记、国家主席周四，中央军委在北京人民大会堂举行隆重庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年招待会并讲话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席致电周四全国上下坚定信心、团结奋进，为建设强大的中国、实现民族复兴而不懈奋斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们的力量源于团结，信心比金子更宝贵。” ;中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在北京人民大会堂举行的庆祝中华民国成立74周年盛大招待会上说： 39岁的中华民国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，国家的前途是光明的，但“我们脚下的路并不总是平坦的”。他号召全国人民继续克服困难、砥砺前行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新中国成立74年来，国家从一贫如洗到全面建成小康社会。他说，全面建成小康社会，开启了建设强国、实现民族复兴的新征程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是中国共产党领导人民取得的伟大成就。”全国各族人民经过艰苦奋斗，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在肯定今年中国经济社会发展取得的成就的同时，也指出，当前国际形势发生深刻变化，中国前进道路上仍面临不少风险挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;p>; “我们要以推动高质量发展为中心，全面、认真、全面贯彻落实新发展理念，加快构建新发展格局。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，要加强宏观调控，扩大有效内需，激发企业主体活力，持续推动经济持续复苏，不断改善社会预期。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 有效防范化解重大风险，努力实现今年经济社会发展目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 推动高水平开放，继续深化改革习近平指出，稳步扩大规则、法规、标准等制度性开放，推动“一带一路”合作高质量发展，增强经济韧性和活力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平在讲话中强调，要继续坚持香港、澳门特别行政区“一国两制”原则，确保香港、澳门长期繁荣稳定。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 他重申中方致力于推动两岸关系和平发展以及解决台湾问题的决心。他表示，实现祖国完全统一是人民心声、时代潮流、历史进程的必然，任何力量都阻挡不了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平还强调，中国将坚持和平发展坚定奉行互利共赢的开放战略，维护国际公平正义，践行真正的多边主义，与各国人民一道应对各种全球性挑战，创造人类更加美好的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;国务院总理李强主持招待会。中共中央政治局常委其他同志出席活动——赵乐际、王沪宁、蔡奇、丁薛祥、李曦——以及国家副主席韩正和约800名中外与会者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周六，习近平和其他领导人将与各界代表一起在天安门广场敬献花篮。向逝去的民族英雄致敬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - President urges greater efforts to protect women, children&#39;s rights, interests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_001_6515caffed50d203d2c9fced.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;习近平主席提出，加大力度保护妇女儿童合法权益，让尊重妇女、关爱儿童成为全社会的普遍共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平日前对全国妇女儿童工作作出指示时强调，妇女是一支重要力量。妇女和儿童是全面建成社会主义现代化强国、推动中华民族伟大复兴的未来先锋队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 各级党委和政府必须更加深刻认识妇女工作的重要意义&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，要坚持男女平等基本国策和儿童发展优先原则，妇女儿童事业要坚定不移。发展必须全面落到实处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平还要求，积极为妇女参与国家经济社会发展创造条件、搭建平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 总理李强周四在北京召开的妇女儿童工作电视电话会议上作出重要指示。妇女儿童的利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: China to work more closely with UNESCO]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_001_6515cb02ed50d203d2c9fcee.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席周四表示，中国愿同联合国教育、科学及文化组织更加密切合作，加强遗产保护，促进文化交流，为全球共同发展作出贡献。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在北京会见联合国教科文组织总干事阿祖莱时表示，多年来，中国一贯支持联合国教科文组织工作，积极开展联合国教科文组织各项倡议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 习近平表示，中国与教科文组织的合作意义重大，有助于促进世界和平与发展，有必要把这种宝贵的合作继续下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 世界是多元文明组成的，中国是世界上文明最多的国家之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平强调，中国有14亿多人口，其巨大发展本身就是对人类文明进步的重要贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 我国正在全面建设社会主义现代化强国，实施科教兴国战略，致力于扩大教育、科技、文化事业发展， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中方高度重视同包括教科文组织在内的各方国际交流与合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿祖莱表示，中国政府一贯支持教科文组织工作。联合国教科文组织女童奖她表示，中国资助的妇女教育为促进全球妇女和女童教育发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 联合国教科文组织对与中国在各领域的广泛共识和良好合作感到满意阿祖莱表示，希望进一步加强与中方在文化遗产保护以及科学文化技术等领域的交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mojingxi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - BRI-themed archaeology outcomes on display]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_001_6515cb05ed50d203d2c9fcef.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_001_04_40654.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;访客浏览展板周四在北京故宫博物院举办的展览中，人们看到了石质葬床。这些展示粟特人民艺术风格的展板已于5月从美国运回，粟特人民在古代丝绸之路的文化交流中发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 双方合作取得了丰硕成果。由于“一带一路”倡议，过去十年涉及中国的考古项目，其中的亮点将在北京的一个大型展览中展出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在协作世界中蓬勃发展：“一带一路” “文化遗产考古合作”周四在北京故宫博物院神武门画廊开幕，展出来自国内外17家机构的84件文物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据胡和平介绍，文化和旅游部部长表示，过去十年，中国与24个国家开展了44个合作考古项目。中国还参与了6个国家的11个国际历史遗迹保护项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国和世界各地的文化遗产保护者携手守护人类共同的财富”，胡锦涛在展览开幕式上说。 “他们谱写了民心相通的迷人篇章。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;”展品还凸显了包容互鉴、合作共赢的丝绸之路精神， ”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此次展览将持续一月，许多文物都是近年来中外联合考古项目中沿着陆上和海上丝绸之路发掘的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自中国、哈萨克斯坦、乌兹别克斯坦、阿联酋等国的文化遗产研究机构也展示了反映古代商路文明交流的重要藏品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，展品包括一幅拓片。中国和沙特考古学家在麦加附近的塞里安港口遗址发现了石碑，中阿联合考察团在阿联酋朱尔法遗址出土了中国瓷器碎片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据故宫博物院研究员、展览策展人王光耀介绍，在阿联酋发现的明初（1368-1644）青花宫廷瓷器可能来自其中一个国家。伟大的中国航海家郑和的船队横渡印度洋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陕西省咸阳出土的唐代（618-907）骆驼陶像可能会提醒您丝绸之路沿线繁忙商队的人们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 其他文物，例如来自新疆维吾尔自治区一座 9 至 13 世纪景教（叙利亚基督教的一个分支）寺庙遗址的壁画，以及带翅膀的狮身人面像吊坠，从公元前二世纪到公元前一世纪，在乌兹别克斯坦出土，进一步表明了整个历史上该贸易网络的包容性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两块精美的中国石质葬床面板，据信是在公元 4 世纪之间和7世纪，也首次公开展出。曾在海外失踪，5月从美国被遣返回国，体现了中美两国在打击文物犯罪方面的密切合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 乌兹别克斯坦总统助理赛伊达·米尔济约耶娃在展览开幕式上致辞，回忆了唐朝时期中国高僧玄奘西行，连接中国和中亚的故事。她表示，玄奘时代的展品将激发现代更多的经济和文化合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 哈萨克斯坦驻华大使馆公使衔参赞努尔兰·阿科什卡罗夫表示：丝绸之路不仅是为了货物的流通，更是为了知识和思想的交流、文化的相互丰富。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkaihao@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - ANCIENT POEMS CAPTURE THE SOUL OF MID-AUTUMN FESTIVAL]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_001_6515cb08ed50d203d2c9fcf0.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_003_01_59528.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;此作品于19日-世纪画家费一庚和张雄描绘了嫦娥在沐浴着月光的梅花枝间拥抱玉兔。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/ resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_003_01_40528.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;姚远的一幅 18 世纪绘画描绘了中秋之夜的赏月。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_003_01_58528.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;金耳环上有玉兔和杵臼。该耳环属于明朝孝靖皇后（1368-1644）。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_003_01_57528 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;北宋徽宗（960-1127 年）的书法作品，其中有赵大成抄写的一首诗。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com .cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_003_01_60528.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;张一男，中国国家图书馆中国古代文献研究员。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https: //mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/001/20230929_003_01_81528.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 1076年，中国诗人、散文家苏轼发现自己陷入了数百公里的自我流放之中在与当权者发生分歧后，他从北宋（960-1127）的首都离开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当时 39 岁的苏写下以下几行：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 生平悲喜离合&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;月亮有盈有亏，月相变化无穷&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人类以来就是这样&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;愿我们在她的恩典下长寿&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论距离有多远，分享它的光芒&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他新获得的自由允许苏（1037-1101）去打猎——他也通过文字捕捉到了这种经历—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 苏在这个特殊的日子里做了每个中国人都应该做的事情。晚上&amp;mdash;望月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;思念弟弟，他的诗句与登月的想象天衣无缝地融合在一起：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我愿乘风上天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 唯恐玉堂清冷&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他描绘月色的空灵，“穿过朱阁，透过花格窗， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 苏从此开始深入思考万物的轮回，它不仅决定了月相，也让每一次的相遇都成为一次缘分的开始。再见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 苏的作品优美而令人沉思，在下一个千年里由于特殊的原因而在中国人中产生了共鸣。中秋节期间的月亮被认为是最圆、最亮的，它代表了人们一直渴望但又难以实现的东西：圆满。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一个拥抱这一点的人转瞬即逝的圆满是宋代诗人赵大成。他写下了这些诗句，以此向月亮致敬：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 所有明亮的事物都被月亮的光辉淹没&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 所有黑暗的海洋都被她的光辉照亮&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>; 如果不是北宋第八位皇帝徽宗（1082-1​​135 年）于 1110 年将其抄写成书法杰作，这部作品就不会如此出名。北京故宫博物院藏品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这并不是唯一一次中秋节与中国皇帝密切相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据传说，那些起来反抗的人以明朝（1368-1644）未来开国皇帝朱元璋为首的元朝（1271-1368）统治者将计划在节日之夜进行叛乱的信息隐藏在月饼中，并分发给民众那些参加叛乱的人。这个传说的真实性永远无法得到证实，它增添了围绕节日及其最著名食物的寓言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 故事的中心人物是传奇弓箭手侯的妻子嫦娥。易先生击落了天上十个太阳中的九个，从而拯救了地球免遭酷热。嫦娥偷偷服用了自己和丈夫的大剂量长生不老药后，飘到了天空，她别无选择，只能忍受孤独。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐代诗人李商隐（813-858）就这位名义上供奉月饼的女子的命运写下了这样的诗句：“嫦娥一定是悔恨不已，在浩瀚的夜空里养育着一颗破碎的心。” ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 食品历史学家认为，唐朝（618-907）以其开放性和与中国以外地区的频繁交流而闻名，一定对这个国家的烹饪传统产生了影响。月饼的馅料从莲蓉到咸鸭蛋黄，形似满月，可能曾经被称为“胡饼”，或者来自异国的蛋糕（到帝国的西部，粟特商人通过丝绸之路到达的地方）路）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这一说法的真实性仍存在很大争议，但有一件事是确定的——在那段时间，中秋节也被称为月亮节，在流行文化中根深蒂固。文人墨客的关注只是时间问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;怀旧之情&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张一男，国家图书馆中国古代文献研究员”中国的中秋诗虽然很多都是欢乐的，但那些充满怀旧和失落感的诗始终牵动着心弦。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这或多或少是不可避免的，因为文学与人们对话的方式。探索复杂而深刻的情感，如爱、失落、悲伤和人类苦难，让人们——作者和读者一样——面对并处理自己的经历，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在这方面，唐代为诗人提供了大量的机会，其中李白（701-762）和杜甫（712-770）是他们时代的杰出人物。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 李白在秋夜写下这样的诗句：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一抹月色笼罩长安城&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万户传来单调的敲打声&lt;/p​​>; &lt;p>;边疆什么时候才能和平&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我的良人远征归来？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;敲击声是由女人们发出的，她们经过一整天的工作，沐浴在月光下，用木棍敲打刚织好的布，使其变得更柔软，准备缝成即将到来的冬天的衣服。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 许多出生在李白之前或之后的人都将月亮与战争以及女人和她的士兵丈夫的分离联系在一起——由于唐朝统治者保卫边疆的努力而成为一个流行的主题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 虽然李白的词句可以在任何秋夜写成，但此后这部作品被视为这是中秋节的标志性作品，以及诗人的许多其他与月亮有关的作品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杜，2020 年 BBC 纪录片《杜甫，中国》的主题。唐代最伟大的诗人，成长于盛唐时期的书香世家，培养了他的才华，并把他培养成一个重视家庭、热衷于侍奉朝廷的儒家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说：“ ”这些经历都没有让他做好准备，应对 755 年爆发的两位当地军阀领导的叛乱对曾经强大的唐朝造成的动乱和破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这或多或少是正确的。杜氏这一代诗人，用情感的原始性和艺术深度的作品来回应他们的痛苦和悲伤。这样，他们共同开创了中国诗歌的黄金时期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平定叛乱四年后的767年中秋之夜，杜诗作了两首诗，其中一首&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一轮明月高挂如明镜&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 思乡之情折铁刀&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 漂流如浮芦不间断&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 距离遥远，任何到达（月球上）桂花树的努力都是徒劳&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这不是杜第一次写下思念他的家人，包括他的兄弟、妻子和孩子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 阅读这部作品字里行间的人都熟悉吴刚这个传奇人物，他是一个被流放到月球的樵夫，在那里他被赋予了用铁刀砍伐的任务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “桂花”与“地位高”同音，传统上被认为是吉祥的，特别是对于那些希望通过功名获得名誉的年轻人来说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杜甫年轻时曾写道，他想“辅佐我主，直到他的名声胜过古代圣王”。当这部作品在杜去世前三年出现时，诗人感到疲倦、幻灭，甚至怨恨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他写的同一首诗的最后一句中：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我凝视着玉兔&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 几乎能数清自己的新毛&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 嫦娥的唯一陪伴，玉兔总是拿着杵臼出现，永远捣着丹药长生不老，讽刺的是，这直接造成了窈窕淑女的悲剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 而吴刚和玉兔却被判苦役——尽管它把两人都变成了仙人——杜甫一生都在期盼，这使得他的作品具有永恒的辛酸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;后起之秀&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 苏轼，诗人、散文家，同时也是一位文学家。多才多艺的书法家和公职人员，成年后有一个良好的开端，在事情开始出错之前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 20 岁时，他参加了朝廷考试，以其言语的力量震惊了考官。 24岁的他已经是一颗冉冉升起的新星，看起来前途一片光明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，1071年，事情开始朝着不同的方向发展，当时34岁的苏公开批评一位著名部长的改革措施。苏先生后来在远离京城的自我流放中度过了一段时光，期间他写下了本文开头提到的那首诗，诗中他想知道为什么离开家乡的时候月亮总是更圆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说：“苏氏当然有他的抱怨，但与四年后（1080年）他在另一首中秋诗中表达的悲惨失望感相比，这些都算不了什么。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去年，苏因撰写被视为诽谤法庭的文章而被判入狱103天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “人生中我们经历过多少次秋天的寒冷？”诗人问道，他接着感叹“月亮的光芒常常被云遮住了”。苏氏“举杯悲叹北望”，所指无疑是指的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在他流放于现在的黄冈市期间，湖北省的苏先生发明了一道以自己名字命名的猪肉菜肴，至今仍广受欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这个自由奔放的人从不让命运打败他。两年后，也就是徽宗诞生的公元1082年中秋日，苏“登高远望，天上流云无痕”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当晚”，他再次“举杯”，并非哀叹自己受的虐待，而是“举杯邀月，与我和我的影子共舞”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 苏在悼念李白他的个人悲喜诗同样充满了源自想象和个人主义的崇高感。李白曾经写过关于在月亮上寻找陪伴和月影的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 同样是在1082年，苏与朋友们开始了一次夜间冒险。登上悬崖顶发出“原始的尖叫”，他后来在他的文学巨著《赤壁二赋》中记录了这一情景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 张说：“此时，苏已是穿过隐喻的旋转门并乘坐情感的钟摆。但他并没有变得愤世嫉俗和怨恨，而是镇定自若。因此，他此后的写作常常充满一种强大的平静，这反映了他内心的力量和平静。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在接下来的二十年里，苏被召回宫廷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1101年，64岁的苏被再次召回，于公元7月28日北上途中去世。农历，距离中秋节还有两周。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏在《1082首诗》中写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今夜不知是何夜&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 却愿乘风去月&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在那水晶宫&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 笛声一响，感动万千心&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 那人曾一度怀疑自己能否忍受月寒的他，终于踏上了嫦娥奔月的旅程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhaoxu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Nation to advance opening-up, Li says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_002_6515cb0bed50d203d2c9fcf1.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;李强总理周四重申，中国将继续向世界开放，致力于合作共赢，强调需要促进相互理解、和平与友谊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李克强是在北京会见外国使节和专家时作出上述表示的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在会见52个国家和国际组织新任驻华使节和代表时，李克强表达了中方的立场。高度重视发展同各国和国际机构的友好合作关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，中国政府将为使节代表履职提供支持和便利，希望他们发挥桥梁和纽带作用增进中国同国际社会的相互了解、信任与合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国始终是世界和平的维护者、促进共同发展的国家，致力于构建人类命运共同体。中方愿与各方共同努力，为世界和平与发展注入更多确定性、稳定性和正能量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 注意到中国正在通过高质量发展全面推进中国现代化，李克强表示，当前，我国经济总体形势正在恢复向好，前景广阔。中国将为世界经济复苏和可持续发展提供更多动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国将坚持对外开放的基本国策，奉行互利共赢的开放战略&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国将与各方一道，践行真正的多边主义，通过合作实现共同增长，更好造福世界人民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外国专家代表荣获中国政府友谊奖，总理对专家们为中国科技发展、人才培养和现代化进程作出的贡献表示赞赏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专家们李克强表示，在这个需要友谊、合作、和平、发展的世界，贡献尤为可贵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 专家们远道而来，促进了交流，加强了合作，用行动传播友谊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国欢迎世界各国人才，希望外国专家继续深入参与国家发展。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &lt;span>;wangqingyun@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Joint support for female education]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_002_6515cb0eed50d203d2c9fcf2.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/002/20230929_002_02_84647.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;彭丽媛（第二位）习近平主席夫人（右）和联合国教科文组织总干事奥黛丽·阿祖莱（左二）在2023年联合国教科文组织女童奖颁奖典礼上与获奖者合影周四在北京举行的妇女教育会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Country&#39;s first cross-sea high-speed railway opens]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_002_6515cb11ed50d203d2c9fcf3.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/002/20230929_002_03_38647.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;旅客登上福州客机-周四的厦门高铁列车，头戴花卉头饰参加非物质文化遗产宣传活动。戴花头是福建省泉州浔埔渔村妇女的习俗。周四是高铁开通运营的第一天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周四，中国第一条跨海高铁在福建省开通运营，标志着中国高铁的又一里程碑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上午9时15分，543名旅客在省会福州福州南站搭乘复兴号动车组G9801次，抵达厦门北站上午 10:16。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陈贤军支付了 126 元（17.2 美元）的火车二等座座位，他说他很高兴成为第一批乘坐高速列车的乘客之一多年来一直关注其发展更新。 “从福州到厦门，出行将非常方便。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该列车设计最高时速350公里，停靠福建5个城市，途经山脉、海湾、跨海大桥，全长277.4公里。专家表示，该项目被认为是海上轨道交通的重大突破，将促进旅游业、区域经济和中国交通运输业的高质量发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; initial stages of the railway&amp;#39;s operations, there will be 16 train trips a day. This will increase to 124 a day in the fourth quarter of the year, said Yang Bin, deputy director of the passenger transport department of China Railway Nanchang Group.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The railway can link Fuzhou and Xiamen in just 55 minutes at the fastest speed, to include residents in both cities in a &amp;#39;one-hour living circle&amp;#39;,&amp;quot;他说。 The previous fastest train took 1 hour and 20 minutes to make the journey.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fuzhou and the economically dynamic and popular tourist destination of Xiamen play important roles in the socioeconomic development of Fujian. The railway is expected to benefit 30 million people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liang Po-hsiang, a passenger from Taiwan, said the service is faster than other bullet trains and pays great attention to details. Each seat has a USB interface to charge a phone, which is &amp;quot;quite convenient&amp;quot;, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liang runs a new media business in Fuzhou and is involved in activities related to cross-Strait exchanges. &amp;quot;Many netizens hope that we can take high-speed trains to Taiwan by 2035. I wish it could become true,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier this month, Fujian was designated a demonstration zone for cross-Strait integrated development by the central government to promote exchanges with Taiwan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fastest cross-sea railway along the west coast of the Taiwan Strait, it has a sea view along 19.9 km of its tracks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Che Yanxue, a conductor, said the train uses advanced technology to reduce noise and shaking, so passengers feel more comfortable.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The first-class seats can be adjusted automatically. The business seats offer wireless charging devices and intelligent touch-screen terminals for entertainment. The No 4 carriage has Braille for passengers in need,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at chenmeiling@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - &#39;Love Beijing&#39; short-video contest launched, praised]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_002_6515cb14ed50d203d2c9fcf4.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-29/002/20230929_002_04_83647.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Online See video by scanning the code.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fourth edition of the highly anticipated &amp;quot;100 Reasons to Love Beijing&amp;quot; short-video contest was launched on Wednesday, with creative talents from around the world expected to share their perspectives and stories about the vibrant capital.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The launch ceremony was held in the Summer Palace on Wednesday evening with bright moonlight bathing the event, which was held two days before this year&amp;#39;s Mid-Autumn Festival.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Foreign experts, students and Chinese guests attended the launch ceremony, sharing their experiences of and attachment to the modern city and its long history.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xu Hejian, director of the Beijing Municipal Information Office, said in just three years the competition had become a remarkable success, with a staggering number of participants. The contest has garnered nearly 6,000 short-video submissions, and inspired the creative minds of more than 3,000 international contestants, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Weiling, deputy editor-in-chief of China Daily, emphasized the power of the short videos and illustrations in showcasing Beijing&amp;#39;s special allure.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Through the collection of these media formats, we hope to provide more foreign friends with an opportunity to personally experience the splendor of Beijing, while also sharing its unique charm with an even broader audience both domestically and internationally,&amp;quot; Liu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China Daily featured its well-known video show Potside Chats at the launch, with three foreign hosts sharing their experiences and views of Beijing while tasting traditional Chinese food including roast duck, sugarcoated haws and noodles with soybean paste.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Stephanie Stone, Erik Nilsson and Jennifer Holstein named key words to express their feelings about Beijing, such as &amp;quot;convenience&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;safety&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;community&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;choices&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Community has been, by far, the most gratifying thing about living in Beijing,&amp;quot; said Stone. &amp;quot;There are good people everywhere and creative people everywhere. All these amazing creatives from around the world have somehow found their way to Beijing and connected.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nilsson said he loved raising his children in Beijing, while Holstein expressed how great it was to be able to return home at midnight without worrying about her own safety.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The theme of this year&amp;#39;s contest is &amp;quot;In Beijing&amp;quot;, allowing contestants to delve into the multifaceted essence of the city and depict their personal encounters and discoveries. To participate, individuals can submit their video entries at the web address, http://bj100.spotlightbeijing.com, as well as via China Daily&amp;#39;s new media platform.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;dujuan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Shanghai unveils handbook for expats]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_002_6515cb17ed50d203d2c9fcf5.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; To attract more expats to Shanghai and help them better integrate into the city, municipal authorities on Thursday released a handbook, which explains local policies and provides service information for expatriates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The handbook was compiled by the Foreign Affairs Office of the Shanghai municipal government in collaboration with the Shanghai People&amp;#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries. It provides comprehensive information for both new arrivals and longtime expat residents on various aspects of everyday life in Shanghai.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The handbook has four sections &amp;mdash; Shanghai essentials, living in Shanghai, exploring Shanghai, and a service directory.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &amp;quot;living in Shanghai&amp;quot; section includes practical information such as administrative procedures on arrival, useful mobile phone apps, as well as details on public transportation, housing, education, healthcare, emergency hotlines and public holidays.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &amp;quot;exploring Shanghai&amp;quot; section provides information on cultural venues, international exhibitions and events, shopping, landmarks and local specialties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The handbook, which took into account the views and suggestions of many expat residents, has around 40 illustrations and 36 QR codes, which can connect users to service information and instructions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kong Fu&amp;#39;an, director of the municipal foreign affairs office and executive vice-president of the association for friendship, said expats are valued members of the community who make significant contributions to the city&amp;#39;s development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Together, we aim to build Shanghai into a global hub of talent where people from every corner of the globe can converge and thrive. We&amp;#39;ll continue to introduce services and measures to provide thoughtful services so that expats can enjoy a pleasant stay and successful career here,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Natacha Tarascon from France, who has lived in Shanghai for a decade, said that life as an expat in the city is easy and safe. High-quality education and medical care are also reasons that the mother of three chooses to stay in Shanghai.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;My kids, who were all born and raised in Shanghai, have been learning Chinese, French and English since they were born. Diverse learning and mixing cultures will surely open their minds,&amp;quot; said Tarascon, who founded a children&amp;#39;s skin care brand in Shanghai in 2019.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said she started her business in Shanghai because the city has always been open to new brands and the municipal government is very supportive of startups. &amp;quot;Also, we can easily collaborate with high-end suppliers and innovative factories here,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhouwenting@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Measures to solidify growth in foreign trade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/29/content_002_6515cb1aed50d203d2c9fcf6.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China will implement a series of policy measures, including advancing trade cooperation in the new energy vehicle sector and upgrading the development of processing trade, to solidify its foreign trade growth this year, government officials said on Thursday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking at a news conference on the 134th China Import and Export Fair, or Canton Fair, Guo Tingting, vice-minister of commerce, said that in response to the challenges posed by the global economic recovery slowdown and weakening demand for goods, the government will roll out new measures to facilitate the export of used cars and support domestic companies in establishing warehouses in overseas markets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fair, with a total exhibition area of 1.55 million square meters, will be held in Guangzhou, Guangdong province, from Oct 15 to Nov 4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Highlighting the significant role of promoting trade liberalization and facilitation, Guo reaffirmed China&amp;#39;s commitment to firmly upholding the multilateral trading system, with the World Trade Organization as its core.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China remains dedicated to maintaining a high level of openness to the global market and aims to expedite the development of a high-standard network of free trade zones,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping, who is also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, has stressed efforts to actively participate in the reform of the WTO and improve the ability to handle high-level opening-up. He made the remarks while presiding over a group study session of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee on Wednesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is in the midst of a green transformation, as traditional export sectors like clothing, household appliances and furniture make room for a fresh wave of technologically advanced and eco-friendly products, said Sun Xiao, secretary-general of the Beijing-based China Chamber of International Commerce.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chu Shijia, director of the Guangzhou-based China Foreign Trade Center, one of the Canton Fair organizers, said, &amp;quot;This shift reflects the country&amp;#39;s transition toward a new era of growth driven by innovation and sustainability.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China saw steady export growth of mechanical and electrical products, such as data processing devices, cellphones and automobiles between January and August, which rose 3.6 percent year-on-year to 8.97 trillion yuan ($1.23 trillion). This accounted for 58 percent of the country&amp;#39;s total exports. In particular, exports of automobiles totaled 442.7 billion yuan, up 104.4 percent year-on-year, data from the General Administration of Customs showed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After participating in various trade shows to gain more orders, Jiangsu General Science Technology Co, a tire manufacturer based in Wuxi, Jiangsu province, exported $164,700 worth of tires to Malaysia, Thailand and Pakistan last week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to the multiple free trade agreements between China and many countries involved in the Belt and Road Initiative, tire exports enjoy favorable tariff preferences in those importing countries, said Zhang Gaorong, the company&amp;#39;s executive vice-president.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Moreover, the rubber imported from these signatory countries for tire manufacturing in China can also leverage these tariff preferences, further bolstering our competitive edge in the global market,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhongnan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 04:21:19 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>