<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Take cyberspace to new level]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_001_654bfba5ed50d203d2ca232b.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/001/20231109_001_01_83242.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平主席在周二，2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会以视频方式开幕。为期三天的峰会汇聚了来自全球科技企业和中国领先互联网企业的高管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平主席周三呼吁共同推动构建网络空间命运共同体让互联网更好造福各国人民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他在2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会视频开幕式上致辞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;连续第十年在浙江水乡古镇乌镇举办，来自全球科技企业和中国领先互联网企业的高管齐聚一堂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在讲话中提到这是他在2015年的会议上提出的倡议，当时他呼吁构建网络空间命运共同体。他的建议得到了国际社会的广泛认可和积极响应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在当今世界大变局和大混乱交织的背景下，解决发展赤字、解决安全挑战、加强人文交流是我们时代面临的共同挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，互联网日益成为发展新动力、安全保障新领域、文化交流新平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方深化交流务实合作，共同推动构建网络空间命运共同体迈上新台阶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们主张坚持发展优先，建设更加包容繁荣的网络空间， ” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平指出，这涉及深化数字领域国际交流合作，加快科技成果商业化应用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，要扩大可及性推动信息技术服务业发展，缩小数字鸿沟，通过互联网发展更好保障民生，让更多国家和人民分享互联网发展成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们倡导共享安全与和平，构建更加和平安全的网络空间” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尊重网络主权以及各国自主选择的发展道路和治理模式，遵守网络空间国际规则，反对网络霸权，反对网络对抗和军备竞赛习主席呼吁各方深化网络安全务实合作，有效打击网络犯罪，加强数据安全和个人信息保护，妥善处理规则冲突、社会风险和伦理挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中方愿与各方一道，落实全球人工智能治理倡议，推动人工智能安全发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们倡导文化交流互鉴，构建更加平等包容的网络空间。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 加强网上沟通对话，帮助各国人民相互了解，促进不同文明包容共存，更好弘扬人类共同价值观。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 中国国家主席的讲话激励了与会的商界领袖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 促进欧洲与中国之间数字和高科技合作的协会 ChinaEU 主席 Luigi Gambardella，习近平的讲话重申了北京引领发展包容安全互联网、让更多国家和人民共享互联网经济成果的决心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;呼吁优先发展并确保更加包容和繁荣的网络空间符合欧洲团结和机会平等的价值观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 互联网巨头腾讯控股高级副总裁郭凯天表示，该公司受到“ “在推动经济发展、维护网络安全、促进文化发展方面承担更多责任”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;知识共享平台知乎创始人兼首席执行官周原表示，公司受到了高层领导的号召激励构建网络空间命运共同体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “也激励我们以科技创新驱动未来互联网发展，让科技创新成为促进社会包容、普惠普惠的力量。”和工业弹性，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - HK, MACAO ADD THRUST TO NATION&#39;S SPACE EXPLORATION]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_001_654bfba8ed50d203d2ca232c.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/001/20231109_002_01_73535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;月球土壤样本采集嫦娥五号探测器在香港大学展出。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/001/ 20231109_002_01_76535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;参观者在湖北省武汉市的航天展览会上观看中国火箭的复制品。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/ 2023-11-09/001/20231109_002_01_27535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;地球科学家钱玉琪检查地球模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/ resfile/2023-11-09/001/20231109_002_01_44535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;钱和地球科学家同事 Joseph Michalski 检查月球土壤图像。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily. com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/001/20231109_002_01_26535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;参观者在安徽省合肥市的一个展览中拍摄从长征二号E火箭回收的发动机的照片。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; 许多人看着夜空中明亮的月亮，想知道地球的卫星到底隐藏着什么秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，很少有人有机会接触月球土壤并进行研究与钱宇奇不同，它是为了解开这些谜团。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年年初，香港大学地球科学系博士后钱宇奇申请进入月球土壤样本来自中国国家航天局。钱先生的申请于6月获得批准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是香港首次获取月球土壤样本进行研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 虽然年仅28岁，但钱先生是一位戴着墨镜的地质学家。留着平头，研究月球近十年了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他对月球上的一切事物充满热情。他的电脑桌面上有一个显示月亮的屏幕保护程序。他背着一个背包，背包上写着“探月”两个字，办公桌上还放着一个月球模型。钱先生还反复强调他的月球研究是多么有趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱先生对太空的兴趣可以追溯到他的童年。当他沉浸在科幻电影和小说中时，他发现这些故事总是以太空为背景，而地质学家扮演着重要的角色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2013年通过高考后，钱学森攻读了地质学学位。中国地质大学（武汉），位于湖北省。他说，他只能选择以地球地质为主的专业，因为当时大陆没有专门针对行星科学或深空探索的本科专业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱先生很努力，因为他知道研究地球地质可以为探索其他行星奠定坚实的基础。他的机会很快就来了，中国的探月工程势头强劲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2004年，中国正式启动嫦娥工程，分三个阶段探测月球，以实现三个目标：无人探月、载人登月、建立月球基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 无人探月，即中国探月工程，也分为绕月、着陆、返回三个阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 绕月阶段从 2004 年开始，包括 2007 年的嫦娥一号和 2010 年的嫦娥二号，从轨道上探索月球表面。着陆阶段包括2013年嫦娥三号和2018年嫦娥四号登陆月球表面进行详细探测。返回阶段包括2020年嫦娥五号任务，收集月球样本返回地球。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 嫦娥工程启动后，许多大陆大学研究人员改变了研究重点登月并参与这些任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;研究角色&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年5月，钱所在的大学成立了行星科学研究所，其目标是引领月球和行星科学研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该研究所在大学组织了一场讲座，展示其研究成果。钱先生听了讲座，觉得很有趣。当晚，他给该所的一位资深教授写了一封信，表示自己想为中国的航天事业做出贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱学森的能力和热情给他留下了深刻的印象，教授收他为研究生——为钱学森提供了参与国家月球研究的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在导师的指导下，钱学森根据嫦娥三号和嫦娥四号收集的数据进行了大量研究。还支持嫦娥五号发射前研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;嫦娥五号任务团队旨在从5万平方公​​里的预选区域中选择最佳着陆地点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱学森在实验室里呆了很多天，广泛审查了卫星捕获的月球表面遥感档案。他发现预选区的东部地区可能含有大约20亿年历史的玄武岩——可能会使后续的土壤收集比美国和前苏联等其他国家先前获得的任何样本都要年轻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些样本可以提供对月球形成历史的深入了解。鉴于早期月球和地球环境的相似性，这也可以帮助科学家解开地球早期历史的秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱学森发表了一篇论文，提出了嫦娥五号的着陆地点，引发了科学家和任务团队的广泛讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 嫦娥五号原定于 2017 年发射。然而，当年 7 月，当长征五号大型火箭发射时，该项目遭遇了重大挫折。嫦娥五号主助推器运载火箭未能升空。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 工程师们迅速对失败原因展开紧急调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是对于钱来说，这也是一段痛苦的时光。 “长征五号是一项关键工程，必须尽快解决这个问题。然而，时间表并不确定，我对此深感担忧。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在密切关注有关长征五号和嫦娥五号的新闻报道的同时，钱学森继续在大学攻读博士学位，同时继续专注于月球研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 长征五号终于在2020年11月发射，搭载嫦娥五号升空。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 探测器准确落在钱学森建议的位置，采集了1731克样品。此外，对土壤的分析证实了钱的研究。该土壤比之前返回地球的任何月球火山沉积物都要年轻近10亿年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;租赁机会&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2021年7月以来，中国国家航天局国家航天局探月与航天工程中心已向符合条件的组织提供了租用月球研究样本进行相关研究的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱学森受导师要求研究一些土壤样本，很快就写了几篇相关论文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 12月，钱学森以优异的成绩完成博士学位。为了表彰他的模范工作，他于今年年初获得了李四光优秀博士生奖，这是中国地学学生的最高奖项之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱接下来决定通过以下方式进一步推进他的月球研究：香港大学地球科学系的博士后职位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 探月等深空任务需要大量的财务和技术能力——通常是中国、美国以及欧洲航天局等国家的保留地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “在香港进行研究使我有机会继续参与国家项目，进一步为国家做出贡献，”钱说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在香港进行月球地质研究还可以带动当地相关产业的发展，激励香港年轻人参与这一领域，加强香港与内地在深空领域的合作钱说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 香港学者研究月球地理大多依靠遥感数据，而不是直接分析月球土壤。 “我可以用我的能力来填补这方面的空白，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 3月份加入港大后——成为该机构第一个从事月球研究的机构——钱先生很快就开始申请月球土壤用于他的工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年年初，国家航天局再次开始接受月球样品申请，钱先生花了一个月的时间准备一份提案，并在截止日期前提交。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 几周后，国家安全局打电话给他，说他的提案已通过初审，现在需要进行口头答辩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 5月底，钱在北京为他的提案进行了答辩。 ，向评委介绍了自己的研究思路、团队成员、实验设备以及所在大学的样品储存条件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在申请过程中，钱先生发现国内的月球科学进展很快。许多顶尖大学现在都提供本科课程来培养深空和行星领域的专业知识。他们的教职员工和学生以及来自主要机构的研究人员正在申请研究月球土壤，其目的超出了钱的火山学研究范围。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;名单已批准&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt; 6月，国家航天局发布了最终批准借用月球研究样本的名单。来自 16 个研究机构的 23 名个人的总共 60 份申请获得批准。总共分发了超过 12,328 毫克的样品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱是成功的申请者之一——获得四个月球样品，总重量为822.6毫克。可以借用一年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 7月底，钱先生前往北京采集样本，但他此行恰逢台风“多克苏里”到来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;台风造成降雨，国家航天局按时为学者准备样品——以免耽误全国各地前来收集的人的研究工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当钱坐在回香港的火车上时，大雨无情地倾盆而下，遮住了窗外的景色。继续赶路的时候，他在手机上看到暴雨造成的伤亡不断扩大的新闻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 不过，他无暇担心自己的安全，注意力全都集中在月球上。样品。他小心翼翼地用减震泡沫将容器固定在背包内。他紧紧握住背包，尽量保护样本免受火车的每一次震动和晃动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11个小时的旅程结束，安全回到香港后，他才终于放松下来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; “保护这些样本对我们自己和香港空间科学界来说都是梦想成真，”钱其琛补充说，此次收购也体现了中央政府对香港支持的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中央批准他的请求，也表明了希望看到香港在该领域发展能力的愿望钱补充道，未来一年，他将利用月球样本解开月球火山历史之谜，尝试提供对其地质历史及其与太阳系行星体形成和演化的联系的见解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，他希望他的应用程序将有助于在香港大学建立一个全面的机制，用于储存月球样本并进行研究&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;第一个里程碑&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱说，月球是人类探索宇宙之旅的第一个里程碑，并补充说中国在不久的将来有许多探月计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 嫦娥六号定于明年某个时候发射。成为第一个从月球暗面获取样本的探测器。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2026年，中国计划发射嫦娥七号，对月球南极水资源进行调查。此后，该国计划在月球上建立小型基地。此外，中国的目标是在2030年之前实现载人登月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 正在研究嫦娥六号着陆地点的钱学森计划继续获取探测器带回的土壤样本。他表示，自己也将尽力参与未来的国家航天事业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱学森等许多港澳人士正在积极为国家的航天事业做出贡献。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，澳门科技大学自2005年起就开始参与嫦娥工程的数据分析和科学研究，是粤港澳第一所大学港澳大湾区参与国家探月工程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2019年底，国家航天局宣布在港澳大湾区设立太空探索与科学中心澳门大学利用澳门优势，提升大湾区与国际科研机构的深层次合作。此外，内地与澳门联合研制的首颗空间科学卫星“澳门科学一号”已于今年发射升空。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 同时，香港理工大学在硬件研发方面也做出了可圈可点的贡献。支持国家太空探索工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2013年，理大与中国空间技术研究院的专家合作开发相机指向系统。尽管在充满挑战的条件下运行，这款导航相机还是由嫦娥三号降落在月球上，捕捉月球景观的图像。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该相机后来进行了更新，并在嫦娥三号期间再次使用。 2018年嫦娥四号任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，理大团队还负责开发用于对嫦娥五号探测器在2020年收集的月球土壤进行采样的装置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同年，理大进一步成功研发及制造火星登陆监控摄像头，这是参与天问一号任务的飞船上的关键仪器之一——理大还对嫦娥三号和嫦娥四号任务着陆区的地质和地形进行了详细分析，支持两个探测器找到合适的着陆点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 香港至少有三所大学提供本科和硕士学位课程，用于培养航空航天人才，每年有100名毕业生专门研究航空航天技术。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2020年，国家第四批航天员选拔启动，首次向港澳地区开放。本月，该过程进入了最后阶段，包括来自两座城市的几名候选人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 钱说：“虽然公众的注意力往往集中在眼前的问题上，但科学家们却着眼于更长远的未来。战争、流行病、气候危机或超级病毒爆发等事件可能有一天使地球变得不适宜生命生存，而今天的科学努力将有助于确保人类未来的家园。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;oasishu@chinadailyhk.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Forest guardians &#39;migrate&#39; with the birds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_001_654bfbabed50d203d2ca232d.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/001/20231109_001_03_102242.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;森林警察队员巡逻2月9日，云南哀牢山。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着鸟儿飞过云南哀牢山，一支森林警察队伍也同样在“迁徙”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 南华县红土坡森林派出所的7名民警，绰号“迁徙派出所”，自9月起将在山上待到3月，以防止偷猎和其他野生动物犯罪。楚雄彝族自治州，“迁徙”时多带衣物被子和生活用品”沿途有430种候鸟的重要迁徙路线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 车站建于1984年，位于山脚下，最初没有自来水，也没有电话服务，后来演变成一间小公寓。 2010年，他说。 “我们现在住的是双层床，不再住帐篷了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据张介绍，当地一些曾经生活极度贫困的村民以捕鸟为食或作为收入来源，这导致了一座“寂静的山”检查通常在夜间进行，“我们冒着黑暗和崎岖的山路，没有手电筒来抓捕偷猎者”，没有鸟儿在叽叽喳喳地叫。据杨正强警官介绍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时，民警要出远门时，会携带帐篷，以防不能及时返回公寓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 民警曾经在车站工作过的刘艳说，冬天是最难熬的时候，因为山里湿度大，她的被子永远干不干。 “一旦脱离了同伴，我就无法形容那种孤独的感觉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管辛苦，但官员们表示，他们的工作是值得的，鸟儿的数量也很多&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为配合这一工作，当地公安局与哀牢山国家级自然保护区合作，设立了鸟类和植物监测站。还使用了红外监控装置来帮助防止偷猎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于警员与技术的结合，各种动植物已返回保护区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;派出所已官员们说，逐渐成为野生动物的中转站。每年，他们都会释放 1,000 多只经过康复的鸟类和其他动物，如黑长臂猿、熊和蟒蛇—— &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据派出所所长张介绍，2019年，山地保护区非法盗猎举报为零。他补充说，随着鸟类的回归，改造也带动了当地群众的收入增加，因为很多村民都开设了民宿，接待每年来山上观鸟的游客。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;“环境逐年改善，人们的生活越来越好，保护意识也越来越强，我们的工作很有成就感。”张说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：zoushuo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Former Iraqi president calls for peace and stability]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_001_654bfbaeed50d203d2ca232e.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/001/20231109_001_04_66242.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;巴勒姆·萨利赫&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; 在目睹了伊拉克多年的战争、内乱和恐怖主义之后，伊拉克前总统巴勒姆·萨利赫如今渴望整个中东的和平与稳定。他呼吁结束当前的巴以冲突，并赞扬中国在巴勒斯坦局势上的立场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2018 年 10 月至 2022 年 10 月担任伊拉克总统的萨利赫在接受中国日报专访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在谈到当前巴勒斯坦局势时，这位前总统表示，盲目的暴力和残酷的冲突必须停止。他说，以平民和基础设施为目标是不可接受的，这严重违反了国际人道主义法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们对中国主张结束这场战争的立场感到鼓舞，也对中国的立场感到鼓舞。”他在联合国安理会的立场值得赞扬。”萨利赫表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调了中国与阿拉伯世界和国际社会伙伴进行磋商的重要性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 表示局势极其危险，并可能进一步升级萨利赫呼吁国际社会共同努力制止冲突，防止冲突进一步升级，因为这可能对整个中东和更广泛的全球安全造成毁灭性打击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 萨利赫对伊中关系的发展表示赞赏近年来，两国合作达到前所未有的水平，去年双边贸易额达530亿美元。他说，中国已成为伊拉克的主要贸易伙伴，伊拉克是中国的第三大原油供应国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 萨利赫曾在伊拉克政府担任过多个高级职务，包括副总理经济事务部长、计划部长和经济委员会主席知道改善经济状况对伊拉克人民有多么重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “现在我们正在优先考虑经济重建和复兴，改革我们的经济以结构性方式，以便我们能够应对我们面临的许多挑战，包括减轻贫困、为年轻人提供服务和就业机会，以及应对我国所面临的环境挑战。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “伊拉克需要基础设施。中国是合作伙伴，我们期待在这个问题上共同努力。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2015年，中伊签署共建“一带一路”合作文件。萨利赫表示，中国提出的“一带一路”倡议意义重大，中国企业已经开始参与伊拉克经济重建，经营油田、建设学校。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他高度评价全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议和全球文明倡议均由习近平主席提出，并表示“这些倡议所蕴含的价值观对世界上所有人都很重要，产生重大影响”。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; “伊拉克和阿拉伯世界以及整个中东地区都非常积极地参与这些举措，”他说。 “当可持续发展和一体化经济建立在包容、平衡和为世界不同地区创造机会的基础上时，可持续发展和一体化经济至关重要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，尽管世界各地存在许多冲突，但所有人类社会都希望同样的事情——安全、和平、人权、就业和可持续发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这不能基于零和游戏来实现。”这必须是双赢的局面。意识形态不能在这个问题上分裂我们。你的繁荣和我的繁荣是相辅相成的。你无法想象一个繁荣、安全的世界，其中一个地区表现良好，而其他地区则表现不佳。”萨利赫表示，中国与世界交往的特点是尊重文化和历史的多样性、耐心和务实。中阿务实合作不断深化，前景广阔。作为发展中国家，中阿应共同承担重要责任，共同推动落实首届中阿领导人会晤《利雅得宣言》，对于探索符合双方国家优先目标的现代化道路、坚持多边主义、反对意识形态对抗具有重要意义萨利赫在接受采访时对中国追求民族复兴的现代化建设表示赞赏，说中国的现代化确实重要、鼓舞人心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些年来我一直密切关注中国发生的事情。中国正在成为地区乃至世界的主要经济强国。对于包括伊拉克在内的许多发展中国家来说，这确实非常鼓舞人心。我们可以做到这一点。我们可以从你的经历中学到很多东西，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - HK, MACAO ADD THRUST TO NATION&#39;S SPACE EXPLORATION]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_002_654bfbaeed50d203d2ca232f.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/002/20231109_002_01_73535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;月球土壤样本采集嫦娥五号探测器在香港大学展出。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/002/ 20231109_002_01_76535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;参观者在湖北省武汉市的航天展览会上观看中国火箭的复制品。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/ 2023-11-09/002/20231109_002_01_27535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;地球科学家钱宇奇检查地球模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/ resfile/2023-11-09/002/20231109_002_01_44535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;钱和地球科学家同事 Joseph Michalski 检查月球土壤图像。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily. com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/002/20231109_002_01_26535.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;参观者在安徽省合肥市的一个展览中拍摄从长征二号E火箭回收的发动机的照片。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; 许多人看着夜空中明亮的月亮，想知道地球的卫星到底隐藏着什么秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，很少有人有机会接触月球土壤并进行研究it to unlock such mysteries, unlike Qian Yuqi.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the start of this year, Qian, a postdoctoral fellow from the Department of Earth Sciences at the University of Hong Kong, or HKU, applied to access lunar soil samples from the China National Space Administration. His application was approved in June.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was the first time Hong Kong had secured lunar soil samples for study.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although he is only 28, Qian, a geologist who wears dark glasses and sports a flat haircut, has been studying the moon for nearly a decade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His enthusiasm for all things lunar runs deep. His computer desktop boasts a screen saver showing the moon. He carries a backpack displaying the Chinese characters for &amp;quot;moon exploration&amp;quot;, and a model of the moon sits on his office desk. Qian also repeatedly emphasizes just how interesting his lunar studies are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian&amp;#39;s interest in space dates to his childhood. While immersing himself in science fiction films and novels, he noticed that these stories were always set in space, with geologists playing significant roles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After passing the college entrance examination in 2013, Qian pursued a degree in geology at China University of Geosciences (Wuhan) in Hubei province. He could only choose a major centered on the Earth&amp;#39;s geology, as no undergraduate programs on the mainland at that time were specifically focused on planetary science or deep space exploration, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian worked hard, as he knew that studying the Earth&amp;#39;s geology could lay a solid foundation for exploring other planets. His opportunity soon arrived, with China&amp;#39;s lunar exploration program gaining significant momentum.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2004, China officially launched the Chang&amp;#39;e project to explore the moon in three phases to fulfill three aims: unmanned lunar exploration, a manned lunar landing, and establishing a lunar base.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The unmanned lunar exploration, or the Chinese Lunar Exploration Program, also consists of three phases: orbiting, landing and returning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The orbiting phase, which began in 2004, involved Chang&amp;#39;e 1 in 2007 and Chang&amp;#39;e 2 in 2010 exploring the lunar surface from orbit. The landing phase involved Chang&amp;#39;e 3 in 2013 and Chang&amp;#39;e 4 in 2018 landing on the moon&amp;#39;s surface for detailed exploration. The returning phase included the Chang&amp;#39;e 5 mission in 2020, which collected lunar samples for a return to Earth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the Chang&amp;#39;e project started, many mainland university researchers switched their research focus to the moon and became involved in these missions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Research role&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In May 2011, Qian&amp;#39;s university established the Planetary Science Institute, with the aim of spearheading research in lunar and planetary science.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The institute organized a lecture at the university to present its research findings. Qian attended the lecture, finding it deeply interesting. That night, he wrote a letter to a senior professor at the institute, stating that he wanted to contribute to furthering China&amp;#39;s space endeavors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Impressed by Qian&amp;#39;s ability and enthusiasm, the professor accepted him as his research student &amp;mdash; giving Qian access to national lunar research.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under his mentor&amp;#39;s guidance, Qian conducted a lot of research based on data collected by Chang&amp;#39;e 3 and Chang&amp;#39;e 4. He also supported a prelaunch study for Chang&amp;#39;e 5.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Chang&amp;#39;e 5 mission team aimed to select the best landing site from a 50,000-square-kilometer preselected zone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian remained in his laboratory for many days, extensively reviewing remote sensing archives of the moon&amp;#39;s surface captured by satellites. He discovered the eastern region of the preselected zone may contain basalts that are about 2 billion years old &amp;mdash; potentially making subsequent soil collections younger than any previous samples secured by other nations, such as the United States and the former Soviet Union.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Such samples could provide insights into the moon&amp;#39;s formative history. Given the similarities between early lunar and Earth environments, this could also help scientists unravel the secrets of the Earth&amp;#39;s early history.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian released a paper suggesting the landing site for Chang&amp;#39;e 5, stimulating extensive discussion among scientists and the mission team.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chang&amp;#39;e 5 was due to launch in 2017. However, in July that year, the project experienced a significant setback when the Long March 5 large carrier rocket, which is the main booster of Chang&amp;#39;e 5, failed to lift off.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Engineers swiftly launched an emergency investigation into the cause of the failure.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This was also a distressing time for Qian. &amp;quot;As the Long March 5 was a critical project, the problem had to be tackled quickly. However, the timeline was uncertain, and I found this deeply worrying,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While closely following news reports about the Long March 5 and Chang&amp;#39;e 5, Qian continued his doctorate research at his university, while remaining focused on lunar studies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Long March 5 was finally launched in November 2020, taking Chang&amp;#39;e 5 skyward.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The probe landed precisely where Qian recommended, collecting 1,731 grams of samples. In addition, analysis of the soil confirmed Qian&amp;#39;s research. The soil is nearly 1 billion years younger than any previous lunar volcanic deposits returned to Earth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Rental opportunities&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since July 2021, the China National Space Administration, or CNSA, Lunar Exploration and Space Engineering Center has granted eligible organizations the opportunity to rent lunar research samples for related research.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Asked by his mentor to research some soil samples, Qian quickly wrote several papers about them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In December, Qian completed his doctorate with flying colors. In recognition of his exemplary work, he received the Li Siguang Outstanding Ph. D. Student Award early this year, one of the highest awards for geoscience students in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian next decided to further his lunar research through a postdoctoral position in HKU&amp;#39;s Department of Earth Sciences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Deep space missions such as lunar exploration demand significant financial and technological capabilities &amp;mdash; typically the preserve of nations such as China and the United States, and the European Space Agency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Doing research in Hong Kong offers me the opportunity to remain engaged in a national project, further contributing to the country,&amp;quot; Qian said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Researching lunar geology in Hong Kong can also stimulate development of related local industries, inspire young people in the city to take part in this field, and enhance cooperation between Hong Kong and the mainland on deep space exploration, Qian said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scholars in Hong Kong studying the moon&amp;#39;s geography mostly rely on remote sensing data, rather than direct analysis of lunar soil. &amp;quot;I can use my abilities to fill a gap in this respect,&amp;quot; Qian said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After joining HKU in March &amp;mdash; becoming the first at the institution to engage in lunar research &amp;mdash; Qian soon started to apply for lunar soil for his work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Early this year, the CNSA again began accepting applications for lunar samples, and Qian spent a month preparing a proposal, submitting it before the deadline.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A few weeks later, the CNSA phoned him to say his proposal had passed the initial review and would now require an oral defense.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of May, Qian defended his proposal in Beijing, introducing his research ideas, team members, equipment for experiments, and sample storage conditions at his university to the panel of judges.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the application process, Qian found that lunar science in the country is progressing swiftly. Many top universities now offer undergraduate programs to cultivate expertise in deep space and planetary domains. Their faculty and students, along with researchers from key institutions, are applying to study lunar soil for purposes beyond Qian&amp;#39;s volcanology research.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;List approved&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In June, the CNSA issued the final approved list for borrowing lunar research samples. A total of 60 applications from 23 individuals at 16 research institutions were endorsed. In all, just over 12,328 milligrams of samples have been distributed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian was among the successful applicants &amp;mdash; obtaining four lunar samples with a total weight of 822.6 mg. He can borrow them for one year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of July, Qian traveled to Beijing to collect the samples, but his trip coincided with the arrival of Typhoon Doksuri.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Despite heavy rain caused by the typhoon, the CNSA prepared the samples on time for scholars &amp;mdash; preventing any delays in research for those throughout the country who traveled to collect them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As Qian sat on the train heading back to Hong Kong, rain poured relentlessly, obscuring the view beyond his window. As he continued his journey, he read news on his phone of the escalating casualties caused by the severe downpours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, he had no time to worry about his safety, as his attention was firmly focused on the lunar samples. He carefully secured the container inside his backpack in shock-absorbing foam. He held the backpack tightly to try to protect the samples from every vibration and sway of the train.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He finally relaxed only after his 11-hour journey ended and he was back in Hong Kong safely.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Securing these samples is a dream come true for ourselves and Hong Kong&amp;#39;s space science community,&amp;quot; Qian said, adding that such acquisition also reflects the central government&amp;#39;s commitment to supporting the city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By granting his request, the central authorities also demonstrated their desire to see Hong Kong develop capabilities in the field of space and keep pace with advances made on the mainland, Qian added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the coming year, Qian said he will use the lunar samples to unlock mysteries of the moon&amp;#39;s volcanic history, try to provide insights into its geological past, and its connection to the formation and evolution of planetary bodies in the solar system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Furthermore, he hopes his application will help establish a comprehensive mechanism at HKU for storing lunar samples and conducting research, thus enhancing the city&amp;#39;s capacity to take part in future national lunar exploration missions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;First milestone&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian said the moon is the first milestone on humankind&amp;#39;s journey to exploring the cosmos, adding that China has many lunar exploration plans for the immediate future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chang&amp;#39;e 6, scheduled for launch sometime next year, is set to become the first probe to retrieve samples from the dark side of the moon.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2026, China plans to launch Chang&amp;#39;e 7 to investigate water resources at the moon&amp;#39;s south pole. After this, the nation envisions establishing small bases on the moon. Furthermore, China is aiming for a manned landing on the moon before 2030.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian, who is researching the landing site for Chang&amp;#39;e 6, plans to continue obtaining soil samples brought back by the probe. He said he will also try his best to become involved in future national space missions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many people in Hong Kong and Macao, such as Qian, are actively contributing to the nation&amp;#39;s space exploration efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, Macau University of Science and Technology, or MUST, has been involved in data analysis and scientific research for the Chang&amp;#39;e project since 2005.It is the first university in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, or GBA, to be involved in the nation&amp;#39;s lunar project.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of 2019, the CNSA announced the establishment of a space exploration and science center at the Macao university to improve the deep level of cooperation between the GBA and international research institutes by using Macao&amp;#39;s advantages. In addition, Macao Science 1, the first space science satellite jointly developed by the mainland and Macao, was launched this year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meanwhile, Hong Kong Polytechnic University, or PolyU, has made noteworthy contributions to developing hardware to support national space exploration efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2013, PolyU collaborated with experts from the China Academy of Space Technology to develop the Camera Pointing System. Despite operating in challenging conditions, this navigation camera was landed on the moon by Chang&amp;#39;e 3 to capture images of the lunar landscape.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The camera was later updated and used again during the Chang&amp;#39;e 4 mission in 2018.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Furthermore, the PolyU team was responsible for developing the device used to sample lunar soil collected by the Chang&amp;#39;e 5 probe in 2020.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That year, PolyU further successfully developed and manufactured the Mars Landing Surveillance Camera, one of the key instruments aboard the spacecraft taking part in the Tianwen 1 mission &amp;mdash; the nation&amp;#39;s first to the Red Planet.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; PolyU also conducted a detailed analysis of the geology and topography of the landing zones for the Chang&amp;#39;e 3 and Chang&amp;#39;e 4 missions, supporting the two probes to find suitable landing sites.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At least three universities in Hong Kong offer undergraduate and master&amp;#39;s degree programs for training aerospace personnel, with 100 graduates specializing in aerospace technology each year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2020, selection of the nation&amp;#39;s fourth batch of astronauts started, with the process open to applicants from Hong Kong and Macao for the first time. This month, the process reached the final stage, and included several candidates from both cities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian said: &amp;quot;While public attention often focuses on immediate concerns, scientists look farther into the future. Events such as wars, pandemics, climate crises, or outbreaks of superviruses could render Earth inhospitable to life someday, and today&amp;#39;s scientific endeavors will contribute to securing humanity&amp;#39;s home in the future.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;oasishu@chinadailyhk.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Central bank to take steps to bolster economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_003_654bfbb1ed50d203d2ca2330.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s monetary policymakers are set to further reduce financing costs and maintain ample liquidity, in support of the country&amp;#39;s economic recovery that has gathered steam, said Pan Gongsheng, governor of the People&amp;#39;s Bank of China, the nation&amp;#39;s central bank.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dedicated to safeguarding financial stability, the central bank will also provide liquidity support for some indebted local governments when necessary and prevent risks in the property market from spreading to other sectors, Pan said on Wednesday while addressing the Annual Conference of Financial Street Forum 2023 in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Experts said that Pan&amp;#39;s remarks underlined the central bank&amp;#39;s intention to reinforce the improving recovery momentum. The PBOC may implement a cut in the reserve requirement ratio &amp;mdash; the proportion of money that banks must keep as reserves &amp;mdash; this month at the earliest, and another interest rate cut cannot be ruled out in the remainder of the year, they added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s economic momentum has strengthened recently with rallying production and consumption as well as an improving employment and inflation situation, Pan said, adding that the country is well on track to accomplish this year&amp;#39;s GDP growth target of around 5 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The central bank will keep interest rates at a level that can facilitate the economy achieving its potential growth rate as part of its countercyclical adjustments, Pan said. &amp;quot;Financing costs of the real economy will be lowered while maintaining an overall stable level.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The potential growth rate is the highest possible rate at which an economy can grow without triggering inflation, while operating at full employment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Efforts will also be made to ensure a reasonably ample liquidity level, enhance the efficiency of existing loans and guard against overshooting risks of the yuan exchange rate, Pan said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lou Feipeng, a researcher at Postal Savings Bank of China, said that to ensure an ample liquidity level, an RRR cut is likely this month to meet the rising liquidity demand due to the issuance of a large amount of government bonds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the pressure imposed by a strong US dollar on the renminbi easing, an interest rate cut is also possible in the fourth quarter, said Charlie Zheng, chief economist at Samoyed Cloud Technology Group Holdings.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s current economic growth is probably below its potential rate, meaning that there may be room for the central bank to reduce interest rates to boost growth, Zheng said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But experts said any bold interest rate cut is unlikely as commercial banks are under pressure from falling interest revenues while the central bank is expected to avoid any excessive stimulus that could worsen long-term economic prospects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China&amp;#39;s economy needs a reasonable growth rate, but achieving high-quality, sustainable development is even more important,&amp;quot; Pan said, adding that the PBOC will amplify support for areas in line with major strategies and weak links in the economy, including technological innovation and small, private enterprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan&amp;#39;s remarks echoed the central financial work conference last week, which called for creating an enabling monetary and financial environment and providing more high-quality financial services to major strategies, key areas and weak links, while stressing the need to forestall and defuse financial risks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s size of government debt is on the lower-middle end globally, Pan said, adding that the country has taken steps to promote the transition of local government financing vehicles into financially independent, sustainable enterprises that do not rely on government credit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The central bank will provide regions facing relatively heavy debt burdens with emergency liquidity support when necessary, Pan said, which experts said will likely be launched in the form of a special purpose vehicle, a monetary policy tool.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan added that the country&amp;#39;s property market correction has had a manageable impact on the financial system as real estate-related loans account for only 23 percent of the outstanding value of bank loans while property market transactions have improved since August.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The PBOC will work to prevent risks of the property market from rippling through other sectors, equally meet reasonable financing needs of real estate enterprises of different types of ownership and keep their key financial channels such as loans and bonds stable, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhoulanxv@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Bracing for winter]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_003_654bfbb4ed50d203d2ca2331.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/003/20231109_003_02_62107.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A veterinarian examines a giraffe at the Nantong Forest Safari Park in Nantong, Jiangsu province, on Wednesday, the first day of Start of Winter. Known as Lidong in Chinese, Start of Winter is the 19th of the 24 solar terms in the traditional Chinese solar calendar and ends on Nov 21 this year. The park launched physical checkups for its nearly 20,000 animals in order to ensure their good health as the temperatures drop.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Foreign minister pledges to upgrade maritime connectivity with all parties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_003_654bfbb7ed50d203d2ca2332.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/003/20231109_003_03_104107.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; China underlined on Wednesday the need to resolutely resist bloc-based confrontation and zero-sum games in the world&amp;#39;s oceans and resolve disputes through dialogue, and it vowed to upgrade maritime connectivity with all parties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These pledges were made by Foreign Minister Wang Yi in his address to the opening of the fourth Symposium on Global Maritime Cooperation and Ocean Governance in Sanya, Hainan province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a prerecorded video speech, Wang said that disputes over maritime territories, rights and interests left over by history &amp;quot;should be resolved through friendly consultation between parties directly concerned&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Analysts said Wang&amp;#39;s remarks serve as an unequivocal reminder of China&amp;#39;s strong sense of responsibility as a major country, sending a signal about the consistency of Beijing&amp;#39;s maritime policy on the South China Sea to its neighbors in the region, as well as some Western countries, which have stirred up tension in the sea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that &amp;quot;peace and tranquillity at sea bears on all countries&amp;#39; security and interests&amp;quot;, Wang said &amp;quot;it is important to take the legitimate concerns of all countries seriously &amp;quot;and continuously improve emergency communication mechanisms to build solidly grounded and truly lasting maritime security.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is willing to work with all the 10 members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations to reach an early conclusion of negotiations over the expected Code of Conduct in the South China Sea to build &amp;quot;a peaceful and secure order in the South China Sea&amp;quot;, Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a proof of the latest progress between China and ASEAN countries over the South China Sea issue, their senior officials convened on Oct 26 in Beijing, where all parties announced the official launch of the third reading of the code&amp;#39;s draft text.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vice-Foreign Minister Sun Weidong said on Tuesday at a seminar in Shanghai that the code &amp;quot;will provide solid rule-based guarantees for greater effects in managing and controlling differences over the South China Sea&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Experts at Wednesday&amp;#39;s forum said that Washington is the largest destabilizing factor behind recent ups and downs in the South China Sea, and it should stop undermining the joint efforts by ASEAN countries and China in managing differences over maritime issues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Da Wei, a professor and director of Tsinghua University&amp;#39;s Center for International Security and Strategy, said that the United States has been seeking to install what it claims as &amp;quot;guardrails&amp;quot; for its ties with China, but it has at the same time been sending military aircraft on so-called &amp;quot;freedom of navigation &amp;quot;operations and close-in reconnaissance at China&amp;#39;s doorstep in the sea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Putting aside the friction in the sea, the two sides could work together more on global maritime governance and cooperation, and make it another highlight such as that on climate change, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Sheng, president of the National Institute for South China Sea Studies, noted that this year marks the 10th anniversary of China&amp;#39;s proposal to jointly build the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road, and countries &amp;quot;need to move faster &amp;quot;in its building in order to advance maritime connectivity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since it was put forward, &amp;quot;its maritime routes have reached 117 ports in 43 countries around the world. A number of projects have been implemented, such as the Colombo Port in Sri Lanka&amp;quot;, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Also, we need to build a globally oriented blue partnership and enhance coordination and assistance among countries and regions in maritime affairs,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In his speech, Foreign Minister Wang Yi also said, &amp;quot;The oceans should become a bond that facilitates exchanges and cooperation among countries, not a block that decouples, disrupts supply chains or isolates one from another&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; All parties should &amp;quot;share development opportunities and achievements&amp;quot;, he said, adding that China will &amp;quot;continue to step up infrastructure cooperation with other countries on such fields as ports and submarine fiber optic cables, safeguard the safety of sea routes, and steadily enhance maritime connectivity&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Heilongjiang launches safety inspections after deadly gymnasium roof collapse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_003_654bfbb9ed50d203d2ca2333.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/003/20231109_003_04_45107.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A resident clears snow beside his vehicle in Jiamusi, Heilongjiang province, on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Authorities in Heilongjiang province have launched an extensive inspection drive to detect and eliminate major safety hazards after a gymnasium roof collapsed on Monday evening in Huanan county of Jiamusi, leaving three dead and two others injured.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The campaign focuses on gymnasiums, sports and fitness venues, theaters and museums as the northeast province experiences severe weather and more blizzards are expected, according to the provincial housing and urban-rural development department and emergency management department.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Professionals, including architects, structural experts and safety testing personnel across the province have been asked to put forward suggestions to help eliminate potential risks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A resident surnamed Liu in Huanan said, &amp;quot;All local fitness centers are closed and the snow has prompted suspension of classes in primary schools, middle schools and kindergartens, as well as off-campus educational institutions from Monday to Wednesday.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Authorities carried out inspections in major markets, targeting safety hazards and providing guidance on snow removal to property owners.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Similar inspections were carried out across the province to ensure public safety. On Tuesday evening, a roof collapse was also reported at a funeral home in Qitaihe, an eastern city in the province, though there were no injuries, according to a statement released by the city&amp;#39;s civil affairs bureau.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jinlin district of Yichun, another city in Heilongjiang, has sent 26 teams comprising 107 members to inspect possible safety issues in local sports stadiums, educational institutions, agricultural greenhouses, buildings housing livestocks on farms, offices, dilapidated homes, and welfare institutions such as nursing homes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The inspection covered 276 locations in the district, and 29 problems were identified and rectified, according to local authorities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The province issued a red alert on Sunday for blizzards, the most severe warning in China&amp;#39;s four-tier color-coded weather alert system, according to the local meteorological service. Multiple cities in the province experienced heavy snowfall and the cold wave will continue in Northeast China over the next two days, bringing gales and snowfall in Heilongjiang.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Weather authorities in both Huanan county and Jiamusi city issued red alerts for blizzards on Sunday. It snowed in Huanan from midnight of Monday to 8 am on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In this round of cold wave, Northeast China received wet snow, which is much heavier than dry snow,&amp;quot; Wu Rui, chief forecaster at the Shanghai Meteorological Service, told ThePaper, a Shanghai-based media outlet. &amp;quot;The weight of 50 centimeters of wet snow in an area of 100 square meters can reach 4 metric tons.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;However, whether the factor directly caused the collapse in Huanan still needs to be investigated,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Jiming, a construction engineer at Beijing Institute of Architectural Design, told Beijing News that &amp;quot;because of the uneven accumulation of ice on the building, the pressure at individual points would have been very severe&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He added that in extreme meteorological conditions, inspection and maintenance should be more comprehensive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As of Wednesday, official investigation into the gym roof collapse in Huanan was still underway.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at zhouhuiying@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Former Iraqi president calls for peace and stability]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_003_654bfbb9ed50d203d2ca2334.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/003/20231109_001_04_66242.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Barham Salih&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After witnessing years of war, internal strife and terrorism in Iraq, Barham Salih, the former Iraqi president, today aspires for peace and stability in the whole of the Middle East. He called for an end to the ongoing Palestine-Israel conflict and praised China&amp;#39;s stance on the Palestinian situation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Salih, who was president of Iraq from October 2018 to October 2022, made the remarks in an exclusive interview with China Daily.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking about the current situation in Palestine, the former president said the mindless violence and brutal conflict must stop. Targeting civilians and infrastructure was unacceptable, constituting a gross violation of international humanitarian laws, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We are heartened by China&amp;#39;s position advocating the end of this war, and China&amp;#39;s stance at the United Nations Security Council is commendable,&amp;quot; Salih said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He stressed the importance of China&amp;#39;s consultations with the Arab world and partners in the international community.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Stating that the situation is extremely dangerous and could escalate further, Salih called on the international community to work together to stop the conflict and prevent further escalation, as that could be devastating for the entire Middle East and wider global security.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Salih hailed the development of Iraq-China ties in recent years, saying that cooperation between the two countries reached an unprecedented level last year, with bilateral trade amounting to $53 billion. China has become a major trading partner for Iraq, and Iraq is the third-largest supplier of crude oil to China, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Salih, who has held several senior positions in the Iraqi government, including deputy prime minister for economic affairs, minister of planning and head of the economic committee, knows how important it is for the Iraqi people to improve economic conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Now we are prioritizing economic reconstruction and regeneration, reforming our economy in a structural way so that we can deal with the many challenges that we have, including alleviating poverty, providing services and jobs for our young people, and also dealing with the environmental challenges that our country is afflicted with,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Iraq needs infrastructure. China is a partner, and we look forward to working together on this matter,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2015, China and Iraq signed a cooperation document on joint construction of the Belt and Road. Noting that the China-proposed Belt and Road Initiative is very significant, Salih said that Chinese companies have already begun participating in Iraq&amp;#39;s economic reconstruction by operating oilfields and building schools.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He spoke highly of the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative and the Global Civilization Initiative, all proposed by President Xi Jinping, and said that &amp;quot;the values inherent in these initiatives are important and consequential to all of us in the world&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Both Iraq and the Arab world, the Middle East in general, are very much engaged with these initiatives,&amp;quot;他说。 &amp;quot;Sustainable development and integrated economies are crucial when based on inclusiveness, balance and creating opportunities for different parts of the world.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He emphasized that despite the many conflicts around the world, all human societies want the same thing &amp;mdash; security, peace, human rights, jobs and sustainable development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;This cannot be done based on a zero-sum game. It has to be a win-win situation. Ideologies cannot divide us on this matter. Your prosperity and mine are interlinked. You cannot imagine a prosperous, secure world where one region is doing well and others are not.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Salih said that Chinese engagement with the world is characterized by respecting diversity of cultures and history, patience and pragmatism in seeking practical solutions to problems.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Practical cooperation between China and Arab countries has been deepening steadily with promising prospects, he said, adding that as members of developing countries, they should shoulder the important responsibility of working together to promote world peace and development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The implementation of the Riyadh Declaration of the first China-Arab States Summit is important to explore modernization paths that are in line with the national priorities of both sides, uphold multilateralism, oppose ideological confrontation, break away from the old path of geopolitical conflicts, and advocate harmonious coexistence and commitment to common security, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the interview, Salih expressed his appreciation for the modernization drive China is pursuing for national rejuvenation, saying that modernization in China is truly important and inspiring.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I have been watching closely what is happening in China over the years. China is emerging as a major economic powerhouse in the region, and in the world as a whole. And for many countries in the developing world, including Iraq, this is truly, truly inspiring. We can do it. And we can learn a lot from that experience that you have had,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Forest guardians &#39;migrate&#39; with the birds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-11/09/content_003_654bfbb9ed50d203d2ca2335.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-11-09/003/20231109_001_03_102242.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Forest police team members patrol in the Ailao Mountains in Yunnan province on Feb 9.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Along with the birds flying over the Ailao Mountains in Yunnan province, a forest police team has likewise been &amp;quot;migrating&amp;quot; since September and will stay in the mountains until March to prevent poaching and other wildlife crimes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nicknamed the &amp;quot;migratory police station&amp;quot;, the seven officers with the forest police station of Hongtupo, Nanhua county, in the Chuxiong Yi autonomous prefecture, carry extra clothing, quilts and daily necessities while &amp;quot;migrating&amp;quot; in the forests on an annual mission to safeguard the avian travelers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Yueping, who has worked at the station for 17 years and now heads it, said the Ailao Mountains, which are rich in biodiversity, are located along an important route for 430 kinds of migratory birds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Established in 1984, the station, which is at the foot of a mountain, initially had neither running water nor phone service, but it evolved into a small apartment in 2010, he said. &amp;quot;We now have bunk beds instead of living in tents.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Zhang, some local villagers who used to live in extreme poverty hunted birds for food or as a source of income, which resulted in a &amp;quot;silent mountain&amp;quot; where no birds were twittering.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Inspections usually occur at night, when &amp;quot;we brave the darkness and bumpy mountain road with no torchlight to catch poachers,&amp;quot; according to Officer Yang Zhengqiang.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sometimes, when the officers have to go far, they carry a tent in case they can&amp;#39;t return to the apartment in time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Officer Liu Yan, who once worked at the station, said winter was the toughest time, because her quilt was never dry due to the high humidity in the mountains. &amp;quot;Once I strayed away from my companions, and I can&amp;#39;t describe the feeling of loneliness.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Despite the hardships, officers said their work is worthwhile, with the number of birds as well as the number of species in the forests increasing over the years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To facilitate the effort, the local public security bureau has worked with the Ailao Mountains National Nature Reserve to set up bird and plant monitoring stations. Infrared monitoring devices are also used to help prevent poaching.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Due to the combination of officers and technology, all kinds of animals and plants have returned to the reserve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The police station has gradually become a stopover for wild animals, officers said. Each year, they release more than 1,000 rehabilitated birds and other animals, such as black gibbons, bears and pythons &amp;mdash; enough to open a minizoo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2019, the mountain reserve had zero report of illegal poaching, according to Zhang, the head of the police station. With birds returning, the transformation has also led to an increase in local people&amp;#39;s income, because many villagers have opened homestays to host visitors who come to the mountains to watch the birds each year, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The environment is improving year by year, and people&amp;#39;s lives get better and they have stronger awareness of protection, making our jobs very fulfilling,&amp;quot; Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at zoushuo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>