<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Tourists boost consumption numbers in holiday season]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_001_651f0a7ced50d203d2c9ffe9.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/001/20231006_001_01_69452.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;参观者欣赏兵马俑周三，在陕西省西安市秦始皇帝陵博物院展出。节日期间，博物馆日均接待游客6万人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 旅游活动激增，带动了消费相关行业，“八一”期间全国出游人数和消费收入大幅增长。中秋节和国庆节假期相结合，显示出世界第二大经济体强劲的韧性和复苏势头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 长假过去一年，已有 1.14 亿人次乘火车出行7天。去年国庆7天长假期间，仅有7216万人次乘坐火车。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着出行人数的不断增加，多个地区都发布了长假消费数据，同比创出新高。节日消费同比回升，进而带动内需回升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 文化和旅游部表示，长假前三天，累计国内旅游人次3.95亿人次同比增长75.8%。国内旅游收入达3422.4亿元人民币（468.7亿美元），同比增长125.3%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 凯度消费者指数中国区总经理Jason Yu表示：“八天的长假今年是中国消费者一年中最长的假期，旅游和各渠道消费的激增预示着消费需求的回升令人欣慰。他补充说，假期期间的体验式消费也展现了中国消费力的强大韧性和活力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京体育休闲体育与旅游学院副院长蒋依依大学表示，今年的假期是疫情后首次持续八天，为中长途旅行提供了充足的时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 主要旅游目的地从假期中受益匪浅。据新华社报道，海南省海口市海关在假期前六天共实现免税销售额10.1亿元。 13万名免税购物者主要为入境国内游客。销售额和购物人数较去年同期分别增长94.2%和120%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据贵州日报报道，贵州省商务厅表示，前两天“双节”期间，全省消费总额101.1亿元，同比增长40.46%，消费者人数1420万人，同比增长37.39%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京市文化和旅游局透露，假期前三天，北京重点旅游景区共接待游客682.5万人次，增长60.6%与2019年相比，同比增长31.8%；累计实现营业总收入41876万元，同比增长25.2%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangzhuoqiong@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Japan starts second round of toxic water discharge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_001_651f0a7fed50d203d2c9ffea.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/001/20231006_001_02_86452.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;公民团体成员上台周四，在韩国首尔日本大使馆大楼前举行集会，要求日本停止将受损的福岛第一核电站的核污染水排放到海洋中。&lt;/p >; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/001/20231006_002_06_103484.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; 日本开始释放受损福岛核污染水周四，在第二轮演习中，第一核电站落入太平洋，引发了广泛的抗议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管日本和其他国家民众的担忧和反对越来越多，但排放还是在上午 10 点左右开始：据该工厂运营商东京电力公司称，当地时间上午 30 点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 东京电力表示，计划在未来 17 天内排放 7,800 吨所谓的处理水。 9月11日结束的第一轮核污染排放过程中，排放了大致相同数量的核污染水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海洋排放遭到了国内外的强烈反对。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; “日本政府和东京电力公司应立即停止这种向海洋排放的行为，并认真考虑替代方案。砂浆凝固等替代方案确实是可行的，”龙谷大学政策科学教授兼公民协会主席 Kenichi Oshima 表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周三，数十名日本民众在东京电力总部前举行集会，敦促该公司停止排放有毒水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; “处理与熔化燃料接触的水是从未预料到的，这违背了各种方法，而且没有办法证明其安全性，”非政府组织东京无核广场的董事会成员山崎久隆说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 东京无核广场的另一位成员富冢元雄表示：“福岛核辐射造成了各种健康问题，并且受影响的人数正在增加。日本政府正在做一件可怕的事情。太令人愤慨了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上个月，包括福岛渔业工人在内的日本151人团体对日本政府和东电提起诉讼，要求停止海洋捕捞&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 原告声称，海洋排放侵犯了他们的捕鱼权，并威胁到消费者的和平生活权利。他们还寻求废除核监管机构的制裁。批准安装排水设施并禁止排放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在首尔，一群韩国活动人士周四在日本大使馆附近举行新闻发布会，谴责倾倒行为并敦促日本政府立即制止“反人类核恐怖主义罪行”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们在一份声明中表示，日本政府不值得信任，第一轮核泄漏已经在海洋中造成了麻烦，并指出，计划持续30多年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周三，俄罗斯外交部发言人玛丽亚·扎哈罗娃批评日本缺乏透明度，且未能提供有关放水的全面信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;在9月下旬举行的国际原子能机构大会上，中国国家原子能机构副主任刘京表示，福岛核泄漏是一个重大核安全问题，因为这是一次前所未有的人工排放污水中国核官员表示，大量放射性核素入海的累积效应存在很大的不确定性，并指出日本未能给出对国际社会的强烈抗议作出可信和科学的回应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 日本环境省上个月报告称，受损发电厂附近拆除工地的潜在放射性铁屑被盗，并进一步加剧了疑虑和担忧。建筑工人非法出售。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，在马来西亚，环保人士和商业团体反对日本最新的倾销行为，警告称此举将长期损害海洋环境和人类健康。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 8月24日有毒水泄漏后，马来西亚宣布将严密检查所有来自日本的高风险食品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该国多个城市举行了抗议活动。抗议者 David Kong Hon Kong 在接受马来西亚日报《星报》采访时表示：“每个人都应该明确抗议向海洋排放受核污染的水，以保护世界免受另一场危机的影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sophine Tann马来西亚自然遗产保护协会副主席表示，随着时间的推移，世界各地的海洋都将受到影响，因为洋流会传播水中的污染物和毒素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我反对（倾销），除非日本政府和当局能够给我们比他们所提供的更具体的答案。例如，让日本人使用并饮用经过处理的水一年，然后看看会产生什么影响，”谭恩说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新华社对这篇报道做出了贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：jianxueqing@chinadaily.com.cn。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - FENTANYL CRISIS CASTS LONG SHADOW OVER THE US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_001_651f0a81ed50d203d2c9ffeb.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/001/20231006_003_01_31228.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;加州总检察长罗布Bonta 去年 10 月在洛杉矶举行的新闻发布会上就加州司法部采取的芬太尼执法行动发表讲话。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/ 2023-10-06/001/20231006_003_01_65228.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;2021 年 7 月，吸毒者躺在宾夕法尼亚州费城肯辛顿社区的街道上。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile .chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/001/20231006_003_01_48228.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;纽约布鲁克林非营利组织推出的自动售货机，分发芬太尼试纸、纳洛酮和卫生用品6 月 5 日发布套件。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/001/20231006_003_01_82228.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;缉毒行动2021 年 11 月，政府官员站在佛罗里达州劳德代尔堡埃弗格莱兹港查获的大麻和可卡因包裹旁边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 29 岁的克里斯托弗·卡尔维德 (Christopher Calvird)，他一直想成为一名基督教牧师并创办自己的教堂过去五年里，他一直在旧金山街头为人们服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 但在他 29 岁生日三周后，留着棕色短发、微笑时脸上有酒窝的卡尔维德被发现死亡。独自一人在城市公园。当他意识到死亡临近时，他跪倒在地，以祈祷的姿势死去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尸检显示他死于芬太尼中毒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芬太尼的药力强50倍比海洛因强，是一种强效合成阿片类药物，类似于吗啡，但强度强 50 至 300 倍。即使是最小的剂量也可能导致死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据显示，去年有近 110,000 名美国公民死于药物过量和药物中毒。每天约有 300 人，是五年前的两倍多。超过一半的药物过量死亡病例中都发现了芬太尼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 旧金山卫生官员表示，该市今年因芬太尼药物过量导致的死亡人数可能会创下纪录。官员们称，仅 7 月份就有 71 人死于吸毒过量，而今年吸毒过量死亡的 80% 是由芬太尼造成的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年迄今为止，已有 473 人死于吸毒过量。旧金山，芬太尼导致了其中 385 人死亡。如果这个速度继续下去，该市的死亡总数将超过去年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上个月，加州一条高速公路旁竖起了一块印有卡尔维德照片的广告牌。在他温暖的微笑旁边，用大字写着“芬太尼杀人”。该广告牌是由他伤心欲绝的母亲詹妮弗·布尔鲁尔 (Jennifer Burruel) 竖起的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她告诉当地电视台 KCRA，“下次有人嘲笑昏迷不醒或在街上的人时，他们就记住，有一位母亲晚上哭着入睡，因为那是他们的孩子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在美国，与芬太尼过量相关的死亡人数正在飙升。 CDC 表示，2021 年，仅合成阿片类药物就有 70,000 多人过量死亡，这一数字超过了越南、伊拉克和阿富汗战争期间美国军事人员损失的总和。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 20世纪60年代，芬太尼被疼痛专家描述为“神奇药物”。它可以有效缓解手术后的极度疼痛。药物芬太尼于 1998 年被美国食品和药物管理局批准作为止痛药，通常用于治疗严重或慢性疼痛的患者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，它也可能是致命的。仅 2 毫克的芬太尼就是致死剂量，小至 0.25 毫克的剂量就会使使用者面临很高的风险。相比之下，海洛因的致死剂量为 100 毫克，而可卡因的致死剂量为 250 毫克。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;主要来源&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 美国缉毒局美国缉毒局 (DEA) 表示，墨西哥的卡特尔和其他犯罪集团已成为美国芬太尼的主要来源。一些共和党议员将不断增长的芬太尼贸易与非法移民联系起来，声称乔·拜登总统的政府已经失去了与墨西哥的边境控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这是你的错，”田纳西州众议员安迪·奥格尔斯 (Andy Ogles) 在总统 2 月份的国情咨文演讲中呼吁结束美国的芬太尼危机时，向拜登大喊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “让他站在那里”板着脸告诉我们他有办法，大笔一挥就可以关闭边境……这冒犯了我，”奥格尔斯说，他将吸毒过量死亡与美国与墨西哥边境的贩毒联系起来。 “他对此什么也没做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，墨西哥总统安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔 (Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador) 在三月份斥责了美国政客。他说芬太尼不是墨西哥的问题，而是美国的问题，并补充说美国应该利用家庭价值观来对抗毒瘾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么他们不（美国）美国）解决他们的社会衰退问题吗？洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔说道。他发表这一声明之际，一些共和党人提议利用美国军队攻击墨西哥的毒品实验室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《华盛顿邮报》的一篇报道称，芬太尼也藏在通过官方入境口岸的客车和卡车中加利福尼亚州和亚利桑那州。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 官员称，超过 90% 的芬太尼是通过官方过境点、海关和边境巡逻队 (CBP) 进口的。但参议院 2020 年发布的港口安全报告数据显示，CBP 仅扫描了约 15% 的商业货物和 1% 的车辆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 芬太尼在贩毒集团中很受欢迎，因为它比其他药物威力更强。麻醉品，其数量比海洛因或可卡因更容易走私。芬太尼与其他药物混合，使它们的药效更强、更有价值，但它的致命性非常高，一个人携带的数量足以杀死整个城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 去年，DEA 查获了超过 5000 万支芬太尼。 -掺有药丸和超过 4,535 公斤芬太尼粉末 -足以杀死每一个美国公民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;长期升级&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几十年来，美国政府致力于解决毒品过量问题，但也犯了很多错误美国第一波阿片类药物过量浪潮源于 20 世纪 90 年代羟考酮和其他处方阿片类药物处方的增加。过量死亡涉及此类阿片类药物，美国药品制造商、分销商和连锁药店赚取了数十亿美元的利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 患者隐私法和美国各州之间缺乏协调，导致个人可以收集大量阿片类药物处方。然后他们出售多余的药片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 第二波浪潮始于 2010 年，因过量服用海洛因而死亡的人数迅速上升。随着政府打击处方阿片类药物，一些阿片类药物使用者转而使用海洛因，因为它更容易获得。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大约在 2013 年，第三波浪潮开始，海洛因经销商希望通过将其产品与海洛因混合来增加利润。芬太尼。当时，联邦当局仍然在更大的阿片类药物危机背景下考虑芬太尼，而不是承认它是一种需要采取有针对性的方法的单独威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《华盛顿邮报》去年的一份报告揭示了之前的额外监督美国政府。例如，由于预算限制，收集新罪犯尿样的被捕者药物滥用监测计划于 2013 年停止。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 同样，药物滥用警告网络收集了来自医疗机构的药物使用和用药过量信息。和紧急响应人员的计划于 2011 年终止。尽管该计划的一个版本在 2018 年重新推出，但那时芬太尼危机已经出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 曾担任乔治·W·布什政府毒品政策顾问的基思·汉弗莱斯 (Keith Humphreys)。布什和巴拉克·奥巴马政府对《华盛顿邮报》表示：“这些计划尽管不完美，但至少给了我们一些东西。他们被取消了资助。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Elissa Tierney 领导了“不再有一个”运动的拉票工作，该运动联合了草根力量，为毒品危机采取行动和提供支持，她说：“反毒品战争一直在进行。已经持续了 50 年，药物过量危机却没有好转；情况越来越糟。我认为这是因为政客和当权者没有倾听他们的康复社区的意见。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前总统唐纳德·特朗普在即将到来的芬太尼危机的风口浪尖上就任。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 虽然特朗普承诺沿美墨边境修建隔离墙以阻止毒品贩运，但芬太尼主要通过入境口岸进入美国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《纽约时报》报道说，政府正在考虑可能取消整个白宫国家药物管制政策办公室。该办公室由“缉毒沙皇”领导，曾被用来领导禁毒战争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2017 年 5 月，特朗普政府考虑削减缉毒沙皇办公室 96% 的资金预算。此外，特朗普直到就任总统九个月后才提名办公室主任汤姆·马里诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《华盛顿邮报》报道后，马里诺的提名迅速被撤回，该报道透露：他支持一项法案，该法案加大了缉毒局执行联邦法律的难度，打击被发现违规的药品制造商、分销商和药房。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒂尔尼说：“十年又十年，我们看到了同样的事情发生。他们严厉打击一种毒品，紧接着又出现了一种更致命的毒品。事情是从海洛因开始的。他们开始将海洛因定为犯罪。芬太尼出现了，他们开始将芬太尼定为犯罪。 ……每次他们打击一种毒品时，一种更致命的毒品就会出现。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 雪莉·沃克·霍布森 (Sherri Walker Hobson)，前联邦检察官，曾任加利福尼亚州圣地亚哥的美国助理检察官，目前领导芬太尼类药物工作组自 2017 年以来一直在追踪圣地亚哥港口附近缉获的毒品数量的增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 霍布森去年告诉《华盛顿邮报》：“他们说他们发现致命的芬太尼剂量来自墨西哥贩毒集团，不是中国。人们过于关注中国，却没有关注球在哪里。他们并没有认真对待卡特尔。一切都与中国、中国、中国有关。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 到目前为止，美国尚未将芬太尼相关物质正式列为一类。芬太尼类似物在美国暂时受到管制，分类将于明年12月到期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，中国外交部发言人毛宁表示，中国对芬太尼类物质进行分类管制，管制品种远超美国。我国常驻联合国代表团9月18日表示，中方反对任何形式的毒品合法化。毒品和毒品问题的政治化。 “迄今为止，中国是第一个也是唯一一个将芬太尼类物质正式列为一类的国家，”代表团表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;不确定的影响&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五月，拜登政府公开支持立法，通过引入新的强制性最低刑期来扩大对药物使用的刑事定罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 《纽约时报》援引全国州立法机关会议的话说，仅在2023年的立法会议上，至少有46个州就提出了数百项芬太尼犯罪法案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 弗吉尼亚州立法者将芬太尼列为“恐怖主义武器” &amp;mdash;增加毒贩刑期的举措。爱荷华州的一项法律对销售芬太尼判处最高 50 年的刑期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 阿肯色州和德克萨斯州已加入宾夕法尼亚州、科罗拉多州和怀俄明州等约 30 个州的行列，实施与毒品相关的杀人法规。法律允许对谋杀罪提出指控，即使是那些在社交场合分享含有致命芬太尼剂量的毒品的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 但批评者表示，毒品政策应优先考虑防止致命的过量用药，而不是对陷入困境的人进行刑事定罪和惩罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 蒂尔尼说：“目前毒品政策的重点应该是尽可能防止致命的药物过量。但相反，美国再次陷入了一场灾难性的毒品战争，这场战争的重点是惩罚而不是拯救生命的目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“国会议员和包括新泽西州在内的数十个州正在着手颁布尽管数十年的证据表明严厉的惩罚对于阻止吸毒或毒品交易几乎没有作用，但仍采取更严厉的毒品处罚。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在新泽西州，立法者正在降低二级犯罪的芬太尼门槛，推动一项法案蒂尔尼表示，因持有芬太尼并意图分发芬太尼而入狱会毁掉那些想要康复的人的生活。 “当人们出狱后，他们的犯罪记录会伴随他们一生，这使得他们更难找到稳定的住房和工作，”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “惩罚患有药物滥用障碍的人，而不是专注于真正的解决方案，只会让我们陷入痛苦和孤立的循环中。我们现在没有将其视为公共卫生危机。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新华社对此报道有贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;minluzhang@chinadailyusa.com&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China seeks unity with Himalayan neighbors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_001_651f0a84ed50d203d2c9ffec.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 北京呼吁跨喜马拉雅地区的邻国加强团结，在互联互通、绿色经济和生态保护方面实现共同进步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些国家地理位置优越中国高级外交官王毅表示，两国在生态保护方面有着高度相似的观点和文化联系，是“携手实现现代化进程的伙伴”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王毅，中共中央政治局委员中共中央政治局委员、中央外事工作委员会办公室主任在第三届中国西藏跨喜马拉雅国际合作论坛在西藏林芝开幕式上发表讲话星期四。来自40多个国家和国际组织的代表参加了为期三天的论坛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 跨喜马拉雅地区是世界上海拔最高的地区。论坛成立于2018年，旨在促进地区与各国互联互通、共同发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王在致辞中指出，论坛发起以来，中方开展了广泛、深入的合作。 ——与跨喜马拉雅地区国家深入合作，“为促进该地区经济社会发展、完善生态环境治理发挥重要作用”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国签署环境协议与印度、巴基斯坦、尼泊尔、斯里兰卡签署合作协议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与各国在清洁能源、水利、污水处理、森林保护、应对气候变化等领域开展一批合作项目&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王毅在讲话中强调，“亚洲的世纪已经到来”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王毅呼吁地区国家“坚持相互尊重和共同发展”。各国应“相互尊重主权和领土完整，互不干涉内政”。谈及加强地区互联互通时，王毅表示，“我们要尊重彼此的内政，在涉及彼此核心利益的问题上相互支持，坚持通过对话协商解决分歧”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在谈到加强地区互联互通时，王毅强调，要推动区域一体化，聚焦高质量共建“一带一路”，“继续推进铁路、公路、航空、电力等双多边优先领域（合作）和重点项目” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为提升地区国家生态环境保护能力，王建议各国在应对气候变化、生物多样性保护、环境污染防治等领域深化双边和多边合作&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国愿继续与地区国家分享历史性发展机遇”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Plan gives steel industry hope of brighter days ahead]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_001_651f0a87ed50d203d2c9ffed.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 尽管中国钢铁行业面临下行压力，但乐观情绪仍在增强，专家预测，得益于国家稳增长的努力、新的钢铁政策，供需平衡将有所改善。中国冶金工业规划研究院院长范铁军表示，一些钢材的需求不断增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “例如，在造船领域，从石油动力船舶向天然气动力船舶的转变以及液化天然气运输船的日益使用，需要能够承受低温和高温的高韧性钢材。深冷环境，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “此外，汽车出口的激增也带动了汽车运输船用钢材的新订单，导致对薄规格造船板等产品的需求不断增加。”&lt;/p>; &lt;上半年，受房地产市场持续低迷影响，需求低迷，钢铁行业产能过剩。为此，工信部会同六部委于8月下旬发布《关于通过推动技术创新、扩大高新技术应用等措施稳定钢铁工业增长的方案》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 专家表示，此类政策的实施、房地产市场的激励措施以及传统的9-10月销售旺季将有助于拉动需求，特别是在特钢行业，进一步稳定价格，为行业可持续发展做出贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 特殊钢是指具有比普通钢更高的强度和韧性的物理和化学性能，以及服务于特殊钢的钢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据大宗商品价格追踪机构Mysteel统计，上半年，36家A股上市钢铁企业中有23家实现盈利，其中7家实现盈利。同比增长。这七家企业中有五家是特钢制造商。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在深圳上市的江苏常宝钢管有限公司，一家生产用于石油勘探和新能源汽车的高科技嵌入式钢管的制造商，以利润增长榜名列前茅。增长150.6%，达到4.5亿元人民币（6235万美元）。该公司在半年财务报告中表示，增长的主要原因是新能源汽车等新兴领域新钢铁产品的开发。&lt;/p>; &lt;专家表示，我国高端装备制造、汽车、绿色能源、航空航天等新兴产业的发展将持续拉动特钢需求，行业在优化提升方面仍有较大空间产品结构和市场应用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 传统钢铁企业也加大力度，通过为新兴行业提供钢材来寻求增长机会。以鞍钢为例，其二氧化碳运输船用690兆帕低温钢等关键技术和产品取得了突破。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “近年来，鞍钢不断增强技术创新能力并增加研发投入，使其高于行业平均水平。”鞍钢技术开发部总经理刘凤强表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据中国钢铁工业协会介绍，随着促进基础设施建设、消费、房地产等政策激励措施落地见效，钢铁市场前景将向好，整体钢铁需求将在经历一段减产期后找到新的平衡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 范还呼吁进一步努力制定钢铁行业标准，他表示是推动行业高质量发展的重要抓手，也是我国从钢铁生产大国向钢铁强国迈进的重要一步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;liuyukun@chinadaily.com .cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Fujian plays key BRI role in sea trade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_002_651f0a89ed50d203d2c9ffee.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Fujian province has used its unique strengths to advance the implementation of the Belt and Road Initiative and has achieved fruitful results in building the core region of the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road, its vice-governor, Guo Ningning, said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A four-pronged corridor consisting of sea, land, air and cyberspace connectivity had taken shape in the eastern Chinese province, Guo told Xinhua News Agency in an interview.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said 317 enterprises and institutions had joined in a sea transportation network linking 131 ports in 43 countries and regions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The province had also expanded the capacities of the China-Europe freight train service and adopted multimodal transport, including sea-rail transport, to link the East and West, Guo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In terms of air transport connectivity, 85 international flight routes to major cities across the globe had been opened in Fujian, she said, adding that the province had also launched remote sensing satellites and helped build a satellite data service center, providing maritime surveying and mapping services for countries and regions involved in the initiative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Given the advantages of its location on China&amp;#39;s southeast coast, Fujian has been considered a vital link and corridor in BRI cooperation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guo emphasized the continuous expansion of Fujian&amp;#39;s economic and trade cooperation with countries and regions taking part in the BRI, saying that the province had invested in nearly 1,400 projects in 95 such countries and regions in the past decade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The volume of trade between Fujian and countries and regions involved in the initiative over the past decade totaled 4.4 trillion yuan ($608.4 billion), with last year&amp;#39;s figure of 735.1 billion yuan up 142 percent from that in 2012.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Given that 80 percent of the 16 million overseas Chinese with ancestral homes in Fujian now lived in Southeast Asia, the province considered the region key to its endeavors to build the core region of the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road, Guo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Association of Southeast Asian Nations had become the province&amp;#39;s largest trade partner, she said, as well as its second-largest investment destination and one of its major sources of foreign investment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Chinese end of an industrial parks project between China and Indonesia had become home to 620 trade enterprises, Guo said, adding that enterprises based in Fujian had launched 36 industrial projects in the Indonesian end of the project.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guo also mentioned the province&amp;#39;s efforts in establishing closer people-to-people ties, saying that Juncao, a technology developed in Fujian that uses grass to grow mushrooms, had spread across the globe and helped people in developing countries shake off poverty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cities in Fujian have sister-city relationships with 124 cities across the globe, she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The province now planned to improve its integrated multidimensional transportation networks, speed up the construction of new types of infrastructure, and aggregate more resources and production factors from home and abroad, Guo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fujian would continue to leverage its demonstration role as the core zone of the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road, push forward with high-level opening up, and contribute more to BRI cooperation and Chinese modernization, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Golden harvest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_002_651f0a8ced50d203d2c9ffef.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/002/20231006_002_02_59484.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Farmers set peeled corn cobs out to dry in the sun on Wednesday at an agricultural cooperative in Luancheng district, Shijiazhuang, Hebei province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Thefts tarnish outdoor music festival]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_002_651f0a8fed50d203d2c9fff0.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; When Cui Jian, one of China&amp;#39;s best-known rock stars, performed on the main stage at the Central China Midi Festival 2023 on Sept 30, it was an exciting moment for music lovers who had traveled from across the country to join the four-day outdoor music festival in Nanyang, Henan province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was the first time the ancient city in Central China had hosted an outdoor Midi Festival &amp;mdash; one of the most popular and oldest outdoor music festivals in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From Sept 29 to Oct 2, during the eight-day Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, the festival showcased over 80 rock music acts from home and abroad, with about 150,000 fans attending.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But after it ended, many people, including those who had stayed in its camping zone, reported that personal property such as computers, phones, clothes and camping equipment had been stolen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A statement released by the festival&amp;#39;s organizer on Oct 5 said the Nanyang city police department had received 73 reports of thefts and 65 cases had been documented.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The police department arrested some people for taking personal property from music festival attendees and was able to return the property to its proper owners,&amp;quot; the organizer said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It also said an internet user who had posted untrue information on a social media platform had been arrested for misleading people to believe that equipment left in the camping zone was no longer wanted by its owners.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The statement also criticized negative and misleading comments about Nanyang that were posted on social media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;There were many comments exhibiting regional prejudice, which are wrong and have a negative impact on Nanyang,&amp;quot; it said. &amp;quot;We will see you here in Nanyang next year.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One fan, Yan Bin, said people had a great time at the festival.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The organizer told attendees about the possibility of rain days before the event started,&amp;quot; Yan said. &amp;quot;Though the ground was muddy, people had lots of fun there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It was definitely annoying when the stealing cases were reported. But the reaction of the local police department was fast. It&amp;#39;sa warning for organizers of outdoor music festivals, who should be prepared to make the events safer.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Central China Midi Festival 2023 was one of a number of Midi Festival events celebrating the 30th anniversary of the Midi School, China&amp;#39;s first school of contemporary music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2000, the first Midi Festival was held at the school in northern Beijing&amp;#39;s Haidian district.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nearly all China&amp;#39;s top rock stars have performed at the festivals, now held across the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Music critic Guo Zhikai, who has organized other outdoor music festivals, said the local government had put a great deal of effort into making the festival happen, and it had been a good opportunity for the city to attract tourists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For the event organizer, it&amp;#39;s also a great idea to bring those top rock musicians to Nanyang, expanding the fan base and attracting young people during the national holiday,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;However, it&amp;#39;s sad to have thefts bring shame to the music festival.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For outdoor music festival organizers, safety is a priority. Besides the security members who failed to carry out their duties, those who gave out rumors and wrong information are responsible for causing the chaos.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;chennan@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Villagers see dreams take flight at airport]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_002_651f0a91ed50d203d2c9fff1.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/002/20231006_002_04_42484.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A local woman presents an embroidered ribbon to a child at Xiangxi Biancheng Airport in Xiangxi Tujia and Miao autonomous prefecture in Hunan province on Aug 18.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the first flight from a new airport in Hunan province&amp;#39;s Xiangxi Tujia and Miao autonomous prefecture took off for Beijing on Aug 18, it was a big day for 48-year-old Yang Chaowen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang, from the prefecture&amp;#39;s Shibadong village, had never flown before and it was also his first trip to the capital.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang, who traveled with his wife, said that thanks to the opening of Xiangxi Biancheng Airport, just 15 km from Shibadong, they could take the flight &amp;quot;right from their home&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We were extremely excited to be able to take the first airplane from Xiangxi, and we feel proud and happy,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Having an airport near home used to be unimaginable for the villagers, as the village was still mired in extreme poverty just a decade ago.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nestled among the mountains of the prefecture, the airport is shaped like a phoenix spreading its wings. It covers 235 hectares and was built with a total investment of nearly 2.9 billion yuan ($401.8 million).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The terminal building covers 11,000 square meters, and the runway is 2,600 meters long, with five aircraft stands. The airport can handle aircraft such as Boeing 738s and Airbus A321s and was designed to handle 300,000 passengers a year, traveling on 3,571 departing and arriving aircraft.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang used to sell fruit and vegetables, but as the local infrastructure was very poor, a single trip to the township took more than two hours. Later, he went to the provinces of Guangdong and Zhejiang to find work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After President Xi Jinping visited Shibadong in 2013 and put forward the concept of targeted poverty alleviation, Yang decided to return home.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He later opened a restaurant to cash in the tourism boom in the village, and said that thanks to the construction of infrastructure including parks, roads and parking lots and the renovation of buildings, local people could now find work near home.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Xin, the head of the airport&amp;#39;s ground service, said the people of the prefecture were very enthusiastic about the airport, which has regular round-trip flights to just two cities &amp;mdash; four a week to Beijing and three a week to Guangzhou in Guangdong.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Every day, there are people from different places in Xiangxi coming to the airport to see flights, and if there are no flights during the time of their visits, they come to see the airport,&amp;quot; Zhao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most passengers coming to the airport were villagers taking airplanes for the first time as the airport was still not widely known to tourists from outside the prefecture, Zhao said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We plan to add two passenger flights by the end of this year, and also open freight flights in the future,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;Xiangxi boosts many famous scenic spots and the number of flights at the airport will increase considerably as more people learn about it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi Qunfang, a 30-year-old villager, was another passenger flying for the first time on the Aug 18 flight to Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Words could not describe how excited I was to take a flight to Beijing,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi, who works as a tour guide in Shibadong, said she could make a living in her hometown while also taking care of her son and parents.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In the past, we often said that we wanted to leave the mountains and see the bigger world, and now we can fly to see the world,&amp;quot;她说。 &amp;quot;We can even go to Beijing and return home on the same day. It is unimaginable.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zoushuo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Plan gives steel industry hope of brighter days ahead]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_002_651f0a91ed50d203d2c9fff2.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Optimism is growing despite downward pressure on China&amp;#39;s steel industry, with experts predicting a better supply-demand balance thanks to the country&amp;#39;s efforts to stabilize growth, new policies for managing crude steel production, and increasing demand from emerging sectors like new energy vehicles and solar power.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fan Tiejun, the head of the China Metallurgical Industry Planning and Research Institute, said there was an increasing need for some steel products.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For example, in shipbuilding, the transition from oil-powered to gas-powered ships and the increasing use of liquefied natural gas transport vessels demands high-resilience steel that can withstand low-temperature and deep-cold environments,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In addition, surging vehicle exports are boosting new orders for steel used in car transport ships, leading to increasing demand for products like thin-spec shipbuilding plates.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the first half of the year, the steel industry saw surplus production amid sluggish demand, particularly due to the prolonged downturn in the real estate market. As a result, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, together with six other ministry-level authorities, released a plan in late August to stabilize the growth of the steel industry through measures such as promoting technological innovation to expand the use of high-tech steel products in emerging sectors to boost demand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Experts said the implementation of such policies, incentives for the real estate market, and the traditional September-October peak season for sales would help drive up demand, especially in the special steel sector, and further stabilize prices, contributing to the industry&amp;#39;s sustainable development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Special steels are those with physical and chemical properties that provide higher strength and toughness than ordinary steels, and those that serve specific purposes in areas such as aerospace engineering and shipbuilding.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to commodity price tracker Mysteel, in the first half of the year, 23 of the 36 A-share-listed steel companies recorded profits, with seven seeing year-on-year growth. Five of those seven were special steel manufacturers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shenzhen-listed Jiangsu Changbao Steel Tube, a manufacturer of high-tech-embedded steel tubes used for oil exploration and new energy vehicles, topped the profit-growth list with a 150.6 percent surge to 450 million yuan ($62.35 million).The company said in its half-year financial report that a primary reason behind the growth was the development of new steel products in emerging sectors like new energy vehicles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Experts said the development of high-end equipment manufacturing, automotive, green energy, aerospace, and other emerging industries in China would continue to drive up demand for special steels, and the sector still had ample room for optimization and improvement in terms of product structure and market applications.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Traditional steel companies have also stepped up efforts to seek growth opportunities by providing steel products for emerging sectors. Angang Steel, for example, has made breakthroughs in key technologies and products, including its 690 megapascal low-temperature steel for carbon dioxide transport ships.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In recent years, Angang has continuously enhanced its technological innovation capabilities and increased investment in research and development to stand above the industry average,&amp;quot; said Liu Fengqiang, general manager of Angang&amp;#39;s technology development department.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the China Iron and Steel Association, as policy incentives to boost infrastructure construction, consumption and the real estate sector take effect, the steel market&amp;#39;s prospects will improve, and overall steel demand will find a new balance after a period of output reduction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fan also called for further efforts to set standards in the steel sector, which he said was a crucial lever for promoting the sector&amp;#39;s high-quality development and a vital step for China to evolve from a big steel producer to a competitive steel powerhouse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;liuyukun@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002HOLIDAY NATION - Japan starts second round of toxic water discharge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/06/content_002_651f0a91ed50d203d2c9fff3.htm#002HOLIDAY NATION]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/002/20231006_001_02_86452.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Members of civic groups stage a rally on Thursday in front of a building that houses the Japanese embassy in Seoul, South Korea, to demand a stop to Japan&amp;#39;s release of nuclear contaminated water from the damaged Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant into the ocean.&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-06/002/20231006_002_06_103484.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; Japan started releasing nuclear-contaminated water from the crippled Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant into the Pacific Ocean on Thursday, in the second round of the exercise, amid widespread protests.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Despite mounting concerns and opposition among people in Japan and other countries, the discharge commenced at around 10:30 am local time, according to the Tokyo Electric Power Company, the plant&amp;#39;s operator.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; TEPCO said it plans to discharge 7,800 metric tons of so-called treated water over the next 17 days. Roughly the same amount of nuclear-contaminated water was discharged during the first round of the process that ended on Sept 11.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ocean discharges have faced a severe backlash both at home and abroad.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The Japanese government and TEPCO should immediately cease this ocean discharge and seriously consider alternative options. Alternatives such as mortar solidification are indeed viable,&amp;quot; said Kenichi Oshima, a policy science professor at Ryukoku University and chairman of the Citizens&amp;#39; Commission on Nuclear Energy, in a written interview with China Daily.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dozens of Japanese people held a rally in front of the TEPCO headquarters in Tokyo on Wednesday, urging the company to stop releasing the toxic water.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Disposing of water that has come into contact with melted fuel, which was never anticipated, goes against various methods and there is no way to prove its safety,&amp;quot; said Hisataka Yamasaki, a board member of the nongovernmental organization No Nukes Plaza Tokyo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Motoo Tomizuka, another member of No Nukes Plaza Tokyo, said: &amp;quot;Various health problems have occurred due to the radiation from Fukushima, and the number of affected people is increasing. The Japanese government is doing something terrible. It&amp;#39;s outrageous.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last month, a group of 151 people in Japan, including fishery workers in Fukushima, filed a lawsuit against the Japanese government and TEPCO to call for a halt to the ocean discharge.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The plaintiffs claimed that the ocean discharge violates their fishing rights and threatens the rights of consumers to live peacefully. They are also seeking nullification of the nuclear regulators&amp;#39; approval of facilities installed for the water discharge and a ban on the release.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Seoul, a group of South Korean activists held a news conference on Thursday near the Japanese embassy, condemning the dumping and urging the Japanese government to immediately stop the &amp;quot;nuclear terrorism crimes against humanity&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They said in a statement that the Japanese government is untrustworthy as the first round of the release has already caused trouble in the ocean, noting that the discharge is planned to continue for over 30 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Wednesday, Russian Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova criticized Japan over its lack of transparency and failure to provide full access to information regarding the water release.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the General Conference of the International Atomic Energy Agency held in late September, Vice-Chairman of the China Atomic Energy Authority Liu Jing said the discharge from Fukushima is a major nuclear safety issue, as it is an unprecedented artificial release of contaminated water from nuclear accidents into the sea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is a lot of uncertainty about the cumulative effect of the release of large quantities of radionuclides into the sea, said the Chinese nuclear official, noting that Japan has failed to give a credible and scientific response to the international outcry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Doubts and concerns were further fueled after Japan&amp;#39;s environment ministry reported last month that potentially radioactive iron scraps from a demolition site near the crippled power plant were stolen and illegally sold by construction workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meanwhile in Malaysia, environmentalist and business groups have opposed Japan&amp;#39;s latest dumping, warning that such a move will harm the marine environment and human health over the long term.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following the release of the toxic water on Aug 24, Malaysia announced that it would closely inspect all high-risk food products from Japan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Protests were held in many cities of the country. Speaking to the Malaysian daily The Star, protester David Kong Hon Kong said: &amp;quot;Everyone should unequivocally protest the release of nuclear-contaminated water into the ocean to protect the world from another crisis.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sophine Tann, vice-president of the Association for the Protection of Natural Heritage of Malaysia, said that over time, entire oceans and seas of the world would be affected as ocean currents can spread the water&amp;#39;s contaminants and toxins.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I am against (the dumping) unless the Japanese government and authorities can give us a more concrete answer than what they have provided. For example, let the Japanese people use and drink the treated water for a year and then see what the effects could be,&amp;quot; Tann said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xinhua contributed to this story.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at jiangxueqing@chinadaily.com.cn.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>