<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Spirit of Flying Tigers should live on]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_001_650a07e7ed50d203d2c9c9c6.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席表示，中美作为大国，未来将对世界和平、稳定、发展承担更多责任，两国共同努力至关重要实现相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 总统在回信中美航空遗产基金会主席杰弗里·格林和飞虎队老战士哈里·莫耶的来信中作了上述表示。和梅尔·麦克马伦。这份日期为 9 月 12 日的回信于周二发布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是习近平在一个月内向友好的美国公民做出的第三次回信，也是他努力促进和建立两国持久关系的一部分&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在回信中表示，回顾过去，中美两国人民共同抗击日本法西斯，经受了血与火的考验，结下了深厚友谊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他指的是中国空军美国志愿军，该部队于1941年由美国将军克莱尔·李·陈纳德组建，俗称“飞虎队”。根据该计划，一批美国志愿飞行员前往中国，在二战期间与中国人民并肩作战，抗击入侵的日本军队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平还在信中重申，发展中美关系中美关系的希望在人民、基础在人文、未来在青年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，中美关系健康稳定发展新时代的奋斗需要“新一代飞虎队”的参与和支持，他表示希望飞虎队精神能够在两国人民之间代代相传。&lt;/p>; &lt;中美航空遗产基金会成立于1998年，是美国的一个民间组织，旨在重燃两国人民的合作精神，增进两国人民的友谊和理解。通过教育年轻人了解他们祖先的成就，该基金会力求提供灵感，激发航空领域更大的成就和合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 最近，将于 2020 年迎来 100 岁生日的 Greene、Moyer 和90多岁的麦克马伦联名致信习近平，介绍了基金会和飞虎队老战士对促进中美友好交往的支持。他们还表示愿意继承和发扬中美合作精神。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平从他们那里了解到，越来越多的美国青少年正在参加飞虎队友谊学校和青年领袖项目。近500名飞虎队老战士和数百名家属曾访问过中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在此回信之前，习近平还回信了美中青少年学生交流协会和各界朋友的来信习近平在回信中表示，希望两国人民加强沟通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些互动是在今年以来中美高层密集会晤之际进行的。最近一次会议是中共中央政治局委员、中央外事工作委员会办公室主任王毅周末在马耳他与美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文举行的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 专家表示，人文交流对于稳定和发展中美关系发挥着重要作用。习主席致力于通过个人交往增进两国人民友谊和了解，为克服政治障碍、加强人文交流指明了方向、提供了途径、提振了信心。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; 样式=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - CITY POWERS AHEAD WITH GREEN TRANSFORMATION]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_001_650a07eaed50d203d2c9c9c7.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/001/20230920_002_01_46140.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;黄海湿地江苏盐城，依鸟而居。每年从东亚到澳大利亚的秋季迁徙路线。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/001/20230920_002_01_28140.png&quot; />;&lt; p>;东方鹳在喂雏鸟。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/001/20230920_002_01_51140.png&quot; />;&lt;p >;一只芦苇鹦鹉在湿地里休息。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/001/20230920_002_01_45140.png&quot; />;&lt;p >;世界上近一半的勺嘴鹬在盐城湿地度过两到三个月的时间，吃掉足够的食物并储存足够的能量飞到冬季栖息地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 每年八月，都会有奇观预示着候鸟的开始一年一度的秋季迁徙在江苏省盐城迷人的黄海湿地展开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些鸟类在从东亚飞往澳大利亚的途中，会在这个天然避风港停留。每年，数以百万计的人像发条一样涌向盐城的沼泽湿地，从该地区其他地区的寒冷冬季中寻求慰藉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这片湿地占地 188,643 公顷，被列为国家重点保护的湿地。 2019 年被联合国教科文组织列为世界遗产，为国际自然保护联盟濒危物种红色名录上的 17 种候鸟提供了优质栖息地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 从周一开始，为期三天的 2023 年世界候鸟大会沿海生态保护与可持续发展国际平台沿海论坛将在盐城举办。来自国内外政府、联合国机构、国际组织和学术机构的约400名代表将出席论坛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;条子泥湿地属于黄海湿地，每年迎来20万至30万只候鸟.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 世界上近一半的勺嘴鹬在湿地度过两到三个月的时间，吃掉足够的食物并储存足够的能量飞到冬季栖息地。这些鸟的体长只有14到16厘米，大约有人类拳头那么大。它们黑色的嘴巴，形状像小饭勺，被许多观鸟者认为很可爱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多年来在盐城拍摄鸟类照片的摄影师李东明说：“这些可爱的生物拥有高标准的生活环境。近年来，随着鱼虾贝类的丰富和环境的改善，我们摄影师能够拍摄到更多这些生物的照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “自从盐城申请世界海洋公园以来，我们摄影师能够拍摄到更多这些生物的照片。”遗产名录获得批准后，地方和国家政府加大了对该地区的保护力度。例如，近年来，我们看到诺德曼青脚鹬的数量稳步上升。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鸟儿降落在风景如画的湿地，见证了盐城的生态保护工作。这片湿地不仅是鸟类的栖息地，也是对绿色低碳未来坚定不移的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城东台市副市长王卫国沿海经济区管理委员会表示，诺德曼青脚鹬数量的不断增加给他留下了深刻的印象，诺德曼青脚鹬是一种以湿地为家的濒临灭绝的物种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “国际研究人员估计，其中只有 600 只。 2012 年，濒临灭绝的鸟类仍然存在。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “不过，我们发现的数量超出了预期，今年在湿地观测到的鸟类有1560只。”这些数字每年都达到新的高度——这是湿地环境繁荣的最好证明。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城当局的说法是：环保工作取得的显著成效和绿色低碳转型，对鸟类物种的复兴起到了关键作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城是中国唯一拥有两个国家级湿地自然保护区的地级市盐城拥有两个国家湿地公园——两个国家级湿地公园和一个世界自然遗产。九龙口和大纵湖——并划拨湿地保护面积41.6万公顷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;坚定承诺&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;盐城绿色港将在湿地保护中发挥关键作用减少碳排放，中国海洋石油总公司江苏滨海液化天然气项目一期于本月开始运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 按年处理600万吨液化天然气的能力计算盐城绿色能源港党委副书记徐斌表示，绿色港每年将采用环保解决方案，为江苏居民提供28个月的用气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预计每年可减少二氧化碳排放3764万吨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这一减排量相当于种植8000万棵树对环境的积极影响。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城致力于建设新能源产业，重点做大做强风电、光伏产业。一个引人注目的项目是位于该市大丰区的一个海上风电场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 风力涡轮机叶片产生的电力先转化为电力，然后通过水下电缆传输到升压站，该升压站连接到&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城市委书记周斌今年初表示，该市新能源装机装机容量已突破 1300 万千瓦，正在加速达到 2000 万千瓦，产业规模达 2000 亿元人民币（275 亿美元）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “作为长三角地区第一座城市新能源发电量千万千瓦，盐城海上风电发电量占全省近半壁江山、全国20%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “盐城拥有长三角地区最大的绿化面积，空气质量持续保持江苏最好，在全国城市中名列前茅。”在盐城，我们的每一次呼吸都是清肺，每一步都是轻松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “盐城拥有全国最长的海岸线、最大的滨海滩涂面积、最广阔的海域、最美丽的海岸线。”江苏广阔的发展腹地。我们致力于更高水平的对外开放，努力建设生态绿色宜居城市。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 近年来，努力恢复退化干旱地区条子泥湿地滨海湿地。生态修复工作已开展27.6公里，恢复湿地面积4000多公顷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王副主任说：“我们的目标是提高质量、稳定湿地。”沿海生态系统的功能和服务功能。我们的目标是恢复珍稀濒危候鸟栖息地，增强物种多样性，将东台滨海地区打造成全球公认的滨海湿地保护典范。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 加强公众参与为保护湿地和世界遗产，盐城当局将旧火车站改造成黄海​​湿地博物馆，为游客提供身临其境的体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 湿地系列教材还引入中小学生，进一步培养年轻一代的环保意识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;微生物研究&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 微生物学家Irina Druzhinina伦敦邱园皇家植物园的科学家一直在研究湿地的微生物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微生物可以分解聚己内酯，这是一种广泛用于医药、包装和 3D 打印的聚合物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在南京农业大学就读四年期间，参与了黄海沿岸附近的这个项目。 7 月，Druzhinina 和她的研究同事在《危险材料杂志》上发表了一篇论文，详细介绍了国际团队在湿地盐沼生态系统中取得的大量发现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “来自从微生物学的角度来看，这是一个有趣的地方，它是海洋和陆地栖息地之间的边界。它具有有用的海洋特有因素，例如盐度，而且还具有丰富的碳供应，因此湿地中的微生物高度多样化，” Druzhinina 说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “没有任何一个发现的时刻。由于这些条件，我们已经知道该地区具有巨大的潜力……但发现 184 种真菌和 55 种能够分解聚己内酯的细菌菌株是相当令人惊讶的。”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 这些塑料降解微生物于 2021 年 5 月在大丰进行了采样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管塑料具有许多优点，但塑料污染已成为迫切需要解决的重大国际问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 科学家人们很早就意识到，在某些真菌和细菌中发现的酶有可能促进塑料降解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Druzhinina 说：“发现能够降解聚己内酯的细菌和真菌并不完全出乎意料，但我们在这项研究中发现的微生物超出了最初的预期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她补充说，对这些潜在应用的研究和理解“才刚刚开始……但我可以看到，还有相当多的研究”。光明未来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者cangwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Relics in spotlight]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_001_650a07eded50d203d2c9c9c8.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/001/20230920_001_03_55401.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;工作人员安排文化活动周一，香港故宫博物院即将举行的《凝视三星堆：四川考古新发现》展览的遗物。此次展览将于9月27日开始，一直持续到1月8日，共展出120件由青铜、玉器、黄金和陶瓷制成的文物，其历史可追溯至约2,600至4,500年前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Economic growth target within reach, say intl experts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_001_650a07f0ed50d203d2c9c9c9.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 8月份经济回暖的苗头增强了国际金融机构的信心，他们认为中国有望实现5%左右的年增长目标，负增长在需求复苏的情况下，消费者通胀不太可能再次出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然而，房地产市场回升的初步迹象能否持续仍存在不确定性，短期内可能会进一步放松住房政策，以确保强劲复苏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 摩根大通首席中国经济学家朱海滨表示，鉴于8月经济形势好转，他上调了对中国下半年经济增长的预测。超预期的经济数据和逐步传导的政策支持，包括最近加速发行特别地方政府债券，这可能会促进基础设施活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 朱表示，他预计中国全年经济增长周五公布的 8 月份零售额和工业产出增长数据分别超出市场预期，同比增长 4.6% 和 4.5%，将增长触及 5%，高于之前预测的 4.8%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们认为政府将能够实现（大约）5% 的增长目标，”德意志银行首席中国经济学家熊毅表示。 “近期贸易和物价高频数据显示出企稳迹象，而8月份信贷（扩张）加速也令人鼓舞。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 房地产领域的政策调整可能会影响房地产行业的发展。熊表示，通过刺激新移民和其他潜在买家的住房需求，对一二线城市的房地产销售产生积极影响，并补充说中国经济增长预计将达到4.6%第三季度同比增长 5%，第四季度提高至 5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此番言论是在中国人民银行与外国金融机构会面后发表的。周一，作为中国吸引外资和扩大金融开放努力的一部分，机构和企业纷纷出席。摩根大通、汇丰银行、德意志银行和特斯拉的代表均出席了会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 由于中国经济可能已经触底，专家表示，有迹象表明，中国的通胀也将出现复苏。需求增加，继 7 月份消费者价格指数同比下降 0.3% 之后，8 月份同比正增长 0.1%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国的通胀确实非常低......但是，将中国描述为陷入通缩螺旋是错误的。”汇丰银行首席亚洲经济学家兼全球研究亚洲联席主管 Frederic Neumann 表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “潜在需求仍在增长，我们还没有看到生产者和消费者出现通货紧缩心态” ，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管如此，专家警告说，中国经济仍在等待房地产市场的好转以实现全面复苏。 “不过，这些政策措施是否足以带动房地产市场持续复苏，还有待观察。”德意志银行熊先生表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 经济合作与发展组织在最新的经济展望中表示，中国经济今年预计将增长5.1%，以房地产市场的结构性压力为由比6月份的预测低0.3个百分点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 摩根大通的朱表示，短期内可能会出现更多需求侧宽松的住房政策。一线、二线城市限购、限购、限价可能会有所放松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：zhoulanxv@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Mainland sees sharp rise in cross-Strait marriages]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_001_650a07f2ed50d203d2c9c9ca.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/001/20230920_001_05_163401.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;双方情侣8 月 22 日，台湾海峡两岸在福建省厦门市举行集体婚礼，庆祝七夕节或中国情人节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 两岸婚姻正在经历一场重大盛事。分析人士称，由于更好的就业和经济前景，新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 大流行后，越来越多的夫妇在中国大陆定居，从而出现反弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据台湾“大陆事务”最近的一份报告截至6月，两岸结婚总数突破35万对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上半年，两岸结婚3532对，同比增长185%，报道称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 福建省家居服务业协会两岸婚姻委员会主任冯发鹏表示，台湾民进党当局以COVID-19为借口封锁&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2008年至2015年国民党执政期间，两岸交往密切，每年有数报告称，两岸结婚人数在1万对以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2016年民进党上台后，这一数字逐渐下降。受影响，2020年和2021年每年下降到2000多对。数据显示，疫情的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冯说，近年来，随着台湾经济衰退，许多年轻人来到大陆求学、就业、创业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;“随着基层交流逐渐恢复，更多的年轻人来到内地，很多人已经定居下来，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 台湾海峡两岸婚姻家庭服务联盟理事长施雪燕表示，近年来，越来越多的两岸夫妇，特别是新婚夫妇选择在大陆定居。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 石来自河北省张家口，24年前与一名台湾男子结婚后移居台湾。她说，很多像她这样的女性正在考虑搬回大陆，这表明两岸关系正在经历20世纪70年代以来未曾有过的变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“台湾的发展已经陷入停滞” ，而且许多年轻人的工资很低。相比之下，快速发展的大陆已成为对他们有吸引力的地方。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 大陆持续推出利好政策，为台湾同胞安居乐业提供便利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 台湾工程师卢英智，福建工业大学副教授。 2011年，他搬到福建省省会福州，在福州大学交通学院工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 卢说，随着福建出台惠台政策，生活变得更加便利。与当地人待遇相同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他于2014年认识了在物流行业工作的妻子。两人于2019年结婚，并于次年生下一名男婴。由于工作和家庭的原因，卢决定在大陆定居。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “两岸婚姻弥足珍贵，值得珍惜。”遗憾的是，有些情侣因为性格不同而分手。”他说。 “对于来自不同背景的伴侣来说，相互理解、包容是很重要的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 卢说，他的儿子与家庭双方都很融洽，甚至还捡到了一份礼物。去台湾探亲后会说一点当地方言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 家政服务协会冯先生表示，两岸婚姻不仅能增进相互了解和文化交流，更是“两岸同胞的纽带”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 福建是距离台湾最近的大陆省份，约占大陆两岸婚姻的三分之一。冯说，随着福建省吸引更多台湾人，这种婚姻预计会增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上周，大陆发布通知，将福建打造为海峡两岸一体化发展示范区，并推出更多措施”帮助他们就业、融入生活方式，为融合发展贡献力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 8月，福建省家居服务业协会成立海峡两岸婚姻家庭专门委员会。该委员会由婚姻顾问和婚礼策划师组成，提供婚介和感情咨询等专业服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 它还组织两岸婚姻家庭联谊活动，并进行调查以评估他们在服务方面面临的困难，包括住房和儿童教育。冯说，这些调查有助于为政府部门提供参考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 委员会计划建立一个利用大数据服务婚介的在线平台，并鼓励更多台湾婚庆行业人士参与他说，在大陆工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者zhangyi1@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - CITY POWERS AHEAD WITH GREEN TRANSFORMATION]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_002_650a07f2ed50d203d2c9c9cb.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/002/20230920_002_01_46140.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;黄海湿地江苏盐城，依鸟而居。每年从东亚到澳大利亚的秋季迁徙路线。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/002/20230920_002_01_28140.png&quot; />;&lt; p>;东方鹳在喂雏鸟。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/002/20230920_002_01_51140.png&quot; />;&lt;p >;一只芦苇鹦鹉在湿地里休息。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/002/20230920_002_01_45140.png&quot; />;&lt;p >;世界上近一半的勺嘴鹬在盐城湿地度过两到三个月的时间，吃掉足够的食物并储存足够的能量飞到冬季栖息地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 每年八月，都会有奇观预示着候鸟的开始一年一度的秋季迁徙在江苏省盐城迷人的黄海湿地展开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这些鸟类在从东亚飞往澳大利亚的途中，会在这个天然避风港停留。每年，数以百万计的人像发条一样涌向盐城的沼泽湿地，从该地区其他地区的寒冷冬季中寻求慰藉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这片湿地占地 188,643 公顷，被列为国家重点保护的湿地。 2019 年被联合国教科文组织列为世界遗产，为国际自然保护联盟濒危物种红色名录上的 17 种候鸟提供了优质栖息地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 从周一开始，为期三天的 2023 年世界候鸟大会沿海生态保护与可持续发展国际平台沿海论坛将在盐城举办。来自国内外政府、联合国机构、国际组织和学术机构的约400名代表将出席论坛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;条子泥湿地属于黄海湿地，每年迎来20万至30万只候鸟.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 世界上近一半的勺嘴鹬在湿地度过两到三个月的时间，吃掉足够的食物并储存足够的能量飞到冬季栖息地。这些鸟的体长只有14到16厘米，大约有人类拳头那么大。它们黑色的嘴巴，形状像小饭勺，被许多观鸟者认为很可爱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多年来在盐城拍摄鸟类照片的摄影师李东明说：“这些可爱的生物拥有高标准的生活环境。近年来，随着鱼虾贝类的丰富和环境的改善，我们摄影师能够拍摄到更多这些生物的照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “自从盐城申请世界海洋公园以来，我们摄影师能够拍摄到更多这些生物的照片。”遗产名录获得批准后，地方和国家政府加大了对该地区的保护力度。例如，近年来，我们看到诺德曼青脚鹬的数量稳步上升。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 鸟儿降落在风景如画的湿地，见证了盐城的生态保护工作。这片湿地不仅是鸟类的栖息地，也是对绿色低碳未来坚定不移的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城东台市副市长王卫国沿海经济区管理委员会表示，诺德曼青脚鹬数量的不断增加给他留下了深刻的印象，诺德曼青脚鹬是一种以湿地为家的濒临灭绝的物种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “国际研究人员估计，其中只有 600 只。 2012 年，濒临灭绝的鸟类仍然存在。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “不过，我们发现的数量超出了预期，今年在湿地观测到的鸟类有1560只。”这些数字每年都达到新的高度——这是湿地环境繁荣的最好证明。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城当局的说法是：环保工作取得的显著成效和绿色低碳转型，对鸟类物种的复兴起到了关键作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城是中国唯一拥有两个国家级湿地自然保护区的地级市盐城拥有两个国家湿地公园——两个国家级湿地公园和一个世界自然遗产。九龙口和大纵湖——并划拨湿地保护面积41.6万公顷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;坚定承诺&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;盐城绿色港将在湿地保护中发挥关键作用减少碳排放，中国海洋石油总公司江苏滨海液化天然气项目一期于本月开始运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 按年处理600万吨液化天然气的能力计算盐城绿色能源港党委副书记徐斌表示，绿色港每年将采用环保解决方案，为江苏居民提供28个月的用气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预计每年可减少二氧化碳排放3764万吨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这一减排量相当于种植8000万棵树对环境的积极影响。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城致力于建设新能源产业，重点做大做强风电、光伏产业。一个引人注目的项目是位于该市大丰区的一个海上风电场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 风力涡轮机叶片产生的电力先转化为电力，然后通过水下电缆传输到升压站，该升压站连接到&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 盐城市委书记周斌今年初表示，该市新能源装机装机容量已突破 1300 万千瓦，正在加速达到 2000 万千瓦，产业规模达 2000 亿元人民币（275 亿美元）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “作为长三角地区第一座城市to generate tens of millions of kilowatts of new energy power, Yancheng&amp;#39;s offshore wind power generation accounts for nearly half the province&amp;#39;s total and 20 percent of the national total,&amp;quot; Zhou said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Renowned for having the largest green area in the Delta region, Yancheng consistently achieves the best air quality in Jiangsu, ranking among the top cities nationwide in this respect. Every breath we take in Yancheng refreshes our lungs, and every step we make brings us a sense of relaxation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Yancheng boasts the longest coastline, largest coastal mud flats area, broadest sea area, and the most extensive development hinterland in Jiangsu. We are committed to embracing a higher level of openness to the outside world, with the aim of building a city that is ecologically green and livable.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Efforts have been made in recent years to restore degraded and arid coastal wetlands in the Tiaozini Wetland. Ecological restoration work has been carried out along a 27.6 km stretch of land, with more than 4,000 hectares of wetlands restored.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang, the deputy director, said: &amp;quot;Our goal is to enhance the quality, stability and service functions of coastal ecosystems. We aim to restore habitats for rare and endangered migratory birds, enhance the diversity of species, and establish the Dongtai coastal area as a globally recognized model for the protection of coastal wetlands.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To enhance public engagement with wetlands and world heritage sites, the authorities in Yancheng have repurposed the city&amp;#39;s old railway station as the Yellow Sea Wetland Museum to provide an immersive experience for visitors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A series of textbooks on wetlands aimed at primary and middle school students has also been introduced to further nurture a sense of environmental protection among the younger generation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Microbe research&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Irina Druzhinina, a microbiologist at the Royal Botanic Gardens in Kew, London, has been researching microbes at the wetland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Microbes can break down polycaprolactone, a polymer widely used in medicine, packaging and 3D printing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She worked on this project near the Yellow Sea coast during a four-year stint at Nanjing Agricultural University. In July, a paper published by Druzhinina and her fellow researchers in the Journal of Hazardous Materials detailed the high number of discoveries made by the international team working in the salt marsh ecosystem at the wetland.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;From a microbiological point of view, it&amp;#39;s an interesting place, which acts as a borderline between marine and terrestrial habitats. It has helpful marine-specific factors such as salinity, but also a rich carbon supply, so the microbes in the wetland are highly diverse,&amp;quot; Druzhinina said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;There was no single moment of discovery. Because of the conditions, we already knew that the area had great potential in terms of what we might find there... but to discover 184 fungal and 55 bacterial strains capable of breaking down polycaprolactone was quite astonishing.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These plastic-degrading microorganisms were sampled in May 2021 in Dafeng.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Despite the many advantages plastics offer, plastic pollution has become a major international problem that desperately needs solutions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scientists have long been aware that enzymes found in some fungi and bacteria have the potential to contribute to plastic degradation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Druzhinina said, &amp;quot;Discovering bacteria and fungi capable of degrading polycaprolactone was not entirely unexpected, but the number of microorganisms we uncovered in this study surpassed initial expectations.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She added that the research and understanding of these potential applications is &amp;quot;just at a starting point ... but I can see that there is quite a bright future.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at cangwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - China urges US to put ties back on track]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_003_650a07f5ed50d203d2c9c9cc.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/003/20230920_003_01_48544.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Vice-President Han Zheng shakes hands on Monday with United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on the sidelines of the 78th session of the UN General Assembly in New York.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vice-President Han Zheng told US Secretary of State Antony Blinken in New York on Monday that China hopes the United States will meet it halfway to bring their relations back on the right track.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a meeting held on the sidelines of the ongoing 78th session of the United Nations General Assembly, Han said a sound and stable China-US relationship will benefit both countries and the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Describing China&amp;#39;s development as an opportunity rather than a challenge, and a gain rather than a risk to the US, Han said the two sides can contribute to each other&amp;#39;s progress and achieve common prosperity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that China has maintained consistency and stability in its policy toward the US, and has always viewed and handled bilateral relations based on the principles of mutual respect, peaceful coexistence and win-win cooperation as put forward by President Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Han expressed the hope that the US will work with China to follow through on the important consensuses reached between President Xi and US President Joe Biden during their meeting in Bali, Indonesia, on Nov 14.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also said that China hopes the US will take concrete actions, create favorable conditions and do more to enhance understanding, mutual trust and mutually beneficial cooperation, in order to put China-US relations back on a healthy and stable track and deliver benefits to both countries and the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Blinken, who visited Beijing three months ago, said the US hopes that China will continue to achieve success and promote world economic growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The US looks forward to strengthening its communications with China, managing their differences and advancing cooperation, the top US diplomat said, according to a readout from the Chinese side.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; US State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said that Blinken and Han had &amp;quot;candid and constructive&amp;quot; discussions, building on recent high-level engagements between the two countries to maintain open lines of communication and responsibly manage the US-China relationship.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Blinken emphasized that the US will continue to use diplomacy to advance its interests and values and to discuss areas of difference, according to the spokesperson.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Blinken also explored potential areas of cooperation and advocated for progress on shared transnational challenges. &amp;quot;Both sides reiterated their commitment to maintaining open lines of communication, including follow-on senior engagements in the coming weeks,&amp;quot; the spokesperson said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In his meeting with UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, Han said the world today is confronted with accelerated changes unseen in a century, with various unstable and uncertain factors intertwined, making it more necessary to uphold true multilateralism and requiring a stronger United Nations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The vision of building a community with a shared future for humanity, the Belt and Road Initiative, the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative and the Global Civilization Initiative &amp;mdash; all proposed by President Xi &amp;mdash; are highly aligned with the ideals and goals of the UN, and have been widely recognized and actively supported by the international community, Han said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will, as always, be a builder of world peace, a contributor to global development and a defender of the international order, and it will support the UN in playing a central role in international affairs, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guterres thanked Han for China&amp;#39;s contribution to the UN and its activities, and the two discussed the need to accelerate climate action as well as the implementation of the Sustainable Development Goals, according to a statement issued by the office of the UN spokesperson.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A readout from the Chinese side said that Guterres also highly appreciated the important initiatives proposed by President Xi, and said he looked forward to China playing a more leading role in global development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;huanxinzhao@chinadailyusa.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Book on Xi&#39;s ideas on human rights published in 6 languages]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_003_650a07f8ed50d203d2c9c9cd.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Foreign readers can now read editions of a book featuring President Xi Jinping&amp;#39;s discourses on human rights in Arabic, Portuguese, German, Swahili, Urdu and Vietnamese.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The six editions of the book were published recently by the Foreign Languages Press.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The book provides an encompassing selection of Xi&amp;#39;s remarks, writings and comments regarding respecting and securing human rights.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It aims to help overseas readers understand Xi&amp;#39;s profound thoughts on human rights and take stock of China&amp;#39;s significant practices in respecting and protecting human rights.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through the book, readers can also access Beijing&amp;#39;s proposed solutions for advancing global human rights governance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Last year, the Central Compilation and Translation Press published the book&amp;#39;s Chinese-English, Chinese-French, Chinese-Russian, Chinese-Spanish and Chinese-Japanese editions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Observers said the book will help ensure that China&amp;#39;s outlook on human rights is better understood by the rest of the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While continuously advancing its own human rights cause, China has &amp;quot;taken tangible actions to promote global human rights governance towards being more fair, just, reasonable and inclusive&amp;quot;, said a report released on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The report was co-released by the China Society for Human Rights Studies and Xinhua News Agency&amp;#39;s think tank New China Research.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The report stressed that China has consistently participated in United Nations&amp;#39; human rights affairs in a responsible manner and actively participated in global human rights governance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On global governance, the country is a deeply involved participant in international mechanisms, a co-builder of rules, an active advocate for exchanges and cooperation, and an important promoter of reform, the report said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Healthy lesson]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_003_650a07fbed50d203d2c9c9ce.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/003/20230920_003_03_65544.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Children in Huzhou, Zhejiang province, learn about oral hygiene on Tuesday, ahead of the 35th Chinese Teeth Care Day on Wednesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - FM: Relations don&#39;t target third party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_003_650a07fded50d203d2c9c9cf.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Foreign Minister Wang Yi has stressed that China-Russia cooperation &amp;quot;does not target any third party, is not subject to disruption by any third party, and is not swayed by any third party&amp;quot;, as he called on the two countries to adhere to true multilateralism.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang made the remarks on Monday in Moscow when meeting with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As major countries in the world and permanent members of the UN Security Council, Wang said that China and Russia bear important responsibilities for maintaining global strategic stability and promoting world development and progress.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Chinese foreign minister said the two countries should further strengthen strategic cooperation, uphold genuine multilateralism, promote a multipolar world and advance global governance toward greater equity and fairness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Noting that bilateral ties have maintained a sound and stable momentum of development, Wang said that this will continue to contribute to the development and revitalization of the two countries and bring important benefits to their people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lavrov said President Xi Jinping&amp;#39;s successful visit to Russia and his meeting with President Vladimir Putin in March have set a clear direction for the future of Russia-China relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Russia is ready to prepare for the next high-level exchanges between the two countries, strengthen the synergy of the two nations&amp;#39; development plans, and deepen cooperation in various fields, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking on the Ukraine situation, Wang said China has consistently adhered to the right direction of seeking peace talks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China &amp;quot;will play a constructive role in the political settlement of the crisis in its own way&amp;quot;, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lavrov shared his views on the Ukraine crisis, saying that the Russian side will continue to be open to negotiations and dialogue.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Beijing issued its official position paper about the Ukraine conflict in February &amp;mdash; China&amp;#39;s Position on the Political Settlement of the Ukraine Crisis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lavrov hailed the document, saying that the Chinese position paper &amp;quot;takes into account the security concerns of all sides and is conducive to eliminating the root causes of the conflict&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the talks on Monday, Beijing and Moscow spoke highly of the historic expansion of the membership of BRICS.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the 15th BRICS Summit in Johannesburg, South Africa, last month, six countries &amp;mdash; Argentina, Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates &amp;mdash; were invited to become new BRICS members.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Both sides &amp;quot;expressed willingness to work with all BRICS member states to build a greater BRICS platform of solidarity, cooperation and common development&amp;quot;, the Chinese Foreign Ministry said in a release.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lavrov said Russia will play its role as the rotating chair of BRICS and work with China to promote greater development of the BRICS cooperation mechanism.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Tuesday, Wang co-chaired the 18th round of China-Russia strategic security consultation in Moscow with Nikolai Patrushev, secretary of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. The two sides exchanged ideas on stepping up strategic coordination and reinforced their mutual trust.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Wide range of themes in play at first Golden Panda Awards]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-09/20/content_003_650a0800ed50d203d2c9c9d0.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-09-20/003/20230920_003_05_110544.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; Golden pandas are everywhere in Chengdu, Sichuan province, these days. As the city hosts the first-ever Golden Panda Awards on Tuesday and Wednesday, the mascot of the event is making its presence felt in public places such as subway stations and airports and on the streets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The city is home to the famed Chengdu Research Base of Giant Panda Breeding.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Golden Panda Awards, jointly hosted by the China Federation of Literary and Art Circles and the Sichuan provincial government, is an international event to promote humanistic exchanges and the building of a global community with a shared future through film and television productions, in which the giant panda serves as a symbol of cultural significance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To be held in Sichuan once every two years, the event will select outstanding film and television productions from around the world that promote the common values of all mankind and meet the common aesthetic pursuit of mankind. The jury members will be professionals of global eminence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chinese director Zhang Yimou, who has won the Berlin Golden Bear prize and the Venice Golden Lion prize, is the president of the jury for this year&amp;#39;s Golden Panda Awards. The chairman of the documentary category is two-time Oscar winning director, writer and producer Malcolm Clarke.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The theme of this year&amp;#39;s Golden Panda Awards is &amp;quot;Brilliant Civilization, Resplendent Vision&amp;quot;. A total of 25 awards will be presented in four categories: film, TV drama, documentary and animation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Tuesday, jurors started the final selection process from 90 nominated works that have cleared the preliminary screening, and the final awards will be announced on Wednesday evening.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of the 90 nominations, 29 are films, 26 are TV dramas, 20 are documentaries and 15 are animations, organizers said. A total of 7,024 works from 104 countries and regions were submitted, with 70 percent being works from outside China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Ren Zhonglun, a jury member and vice-chairman of the China Film Association, the works shortlisted for final evaluation are of excellent quality from major countries around the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The works deal with themes such as traditional culture, nature, geography, ecological and environmental protection, family ethics, suspense, science fiction and fantasy. All the submissions are intended to promote truth, goodness and beauty, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the running for the Best Film prize are Jojo Rabbit, which has anti-fascism as the background of the story; Persian Lessons, submitted by Information China Media, which deals with human beauty; The Last Film Show, submitted by Orange Studio in India, which has strong national characteristics; and The Wandering Earth II, submitted by China Film Co, which conveys the concept of a community with a shared future for mankind, Ren said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 05:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>