<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi to address forum on BRI cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_001_65270cf4ed50d203d2ca047d.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席将出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式，这是一次全球盛会，有助于勾画未来发展的里程碑式愿景，打造外交部发言人华春莹周三宣布，习近平将在10月17日至18日在北京举行的论坛开幕式上发表主旨演讲。总统还将为出席论坛的嘉宾举行欢迎宴会和双边活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 论坛主题为“高质量一带一路合作：共同发展繁荣”值此“一带一路”倡议提出10周年之际，来自130多个国家和30多个国际组织的代表齐聚一堂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 曲波，外交学院国际关系研究所所长表示，下周的聚会是中国今年举办的最大规模的外交活动，具有里程碑意义，因为它将为未来十年“一带一路”高质量发展勾勒出新的路线图。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; #39;开幕式上的讲话预计将成为具有重大全球意义的施政报告，国际社会正在寻找线索，了解北京如何将“一带一路”倡议与习近平提出的其他重大倡议（例如全球发展战略）结合起来“一带一路”倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这么多国家和国际组织的代表出席论坛，充分说明了全球对‘一带一路’倡议的支持程度， ” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “更重要的是，这表明有如此多的国家从这一倡议中受益。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 根据周二发布的白皮书，截至6月，北京已与150多个国家和30多个国际组织签署了“一带一路”合作文件。 2013年至2022年，中国与“一带一路”沿线国家进出口贸易额累计达到19.1万亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 除了开幕式和双边会议外，论坛还将举办丰富多彩的边会活动，包括首席执行官会议。举办互联互通、绿色发展、数字经济三场高层论坛。还将举办贸易畅通、民心相通、智库交流、廉洁丝绸之路、地方合作、海洋合作等六场专题论坛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周泰东，中心副主任国际发展知识杂志表示，论坛议程体现了“一带一路”合作的原则，为“一带一路”未来发展提供了线索。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路”始终坚持开放、绿色、廉洁合作迈向包容性和可持续发展，”他说。 “未来，‘一带一路’将继续以互联互通和数字经济发展为重点，进一步推进绿色发展，保障产业链供应链稳定畅通。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span >;xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Quake aid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_001_65270cf7ed50d203d2ca047e.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/001/20231012_001_02_74.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;人们携带捐赠的帐篷周二，中国在阿富汗赫拉特地震灾区进行了救援。周六阿富汗发生一系列强烈地震后，中国红十字会向阿富汗红新月会提供了20万美元现金作为紧急人道援助。周三，另一场 6.3 级地震袭击了该国西部地区。查看更多信息，第 10 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Fact-finding trip]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_001_65270cfaed50d203d2ca047f.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/001/20231012_001_03_57.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;习近平总书记周二，中共中央政治局常委视察江西省九江市长江国家文化公园园区。他了解了当地公园建设和长江沿岸生态修复等情况。习近平还考察了九江石化，了解九江石化向绿色发展转型的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - China&#39;s lead role in green transition praised]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_001_65270cfded50d203d2ca0480.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/001/20231012_001_04_130.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;苏丹艾哈迈德·贾比尔&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 即将召开的联合国COP28气候大会候任主席苏丹·艾哈迈德·贾比尔称赞中国在促进世界绿色转型和推广可再生能源方面发挥的领导作用，并表示他已获得“ “压倒性的支持”他上周在北京接受《中国日报》独家采访时表示，这种支持对于使这次峰会成为历史性的一次、取得前所未有的成果至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “中国一直是COP进程的积极参与者，也是阿联酋的战略伙伴，”来自阿拉伯联合酋长国的阿尔·贾比尔 (Al Jaber) 说道。气候变化特使兼工业和先进技术部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他是在对北京进行为期两天的访问时发表上述言论的，这是他在第二十八届联合国气候变化大会之前第二次访问中国。联合国气候变化框架公约缔约方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 全球气候峰会俗称 COP28，将于 11 月 30 日至 12 月 12 日在阿联酋的迪拜酋长国举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Al Jaber 表示，尽管有人呼吁停止使用化石燃料，但仍将继续利用化石燃料来确保全球能源安全。然而，国家——富有还是贫穷——必须快速有序地从石油和天然气转向更清洁的能源，从太阳能、风能到氢能，以避免气候灾难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “世界无法在此之前脱离当前的能源系统我们建设新能源体系。相反，我们希望继续使石油和天然气行业脱碳。”他指出，即使在最先进的减少世界碳足迹的计划中，也无法消除化石燃料。 “将继续需要石油和天然气来满足全球能源需求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Al Jaber 引用了阿联酋针对传统能源部门的脱碳行动——现在是碳强度最低的产油国——举例说明更“务实”的做法和“结果驱动” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在过去的二十年里，阿联酋实现了可再生能源的商业化，并通过电气化运营和采用碳等方法，使其石油工业变得更加气候友好。捕获和存储技术，他说。​​&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我想要解决方案。我不想要危言耸听的做法。我想在激情和现实之间取得平衡，”阿尔贾比尔表示，并补充说，世界需要将可再生能源供应量增加两倍，并提高传统能源部门的效率，以实现“公平、公正、公平和负责任”的世界。向气候友好型能源转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 为了使这一转型可行，Al Jaber 表示必须改革气候融资体系，以便南半球能够实现其减排目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 他表示，他还指望发达国家履行 2009 年做出的承诺，每年向发展中国家提供 1000 亿美元，帮助其实现绿色转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提供、可获得或负担得起的资源已经推迟了进展……这就是《巴黎协定》尚未实施的原因”他说的是认真的，指的是2015年世界领导人达成的协议，将全球气温升幅与工业化前水平相比控制在1.5摄氏度以内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 本月早些时候，联合国气候变化框架公约秘书处发布了一份关于全球首个全球气温升高的报告。盘点，衡量实现《巴黎协定》目标的进展情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 报告称，履行现有承诺并将升温限制在比工业化前水平高 1.5 摄氏度的范围内的窗口正在迅速缩小，国际公共财政必须从战略角度进行调整Al Jaber 表示，不幸的是，这方面并没有取得太大进展。 “我们已经偏离了正轨。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示希望在 COP28 上恢复信心，并利用这次活动将言辞转化为行动和可行的时间表，希望成功减少 22 亿吨到 2030 年，温室气体排放量将减少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是他的“北极星”目标。阿尔贾比尔说，以及保持变暖目标可实现的基线要求。 “我们不应该再对任何认为自己是问题所在的人指手画脚。我们的敌人是排放，”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;lilei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Nation to advance building of high-quality overseas projects]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_001_65270d00ed50d203d2ca0481.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;中国将进一步推进海外优质项目建设，拓展自贸区网络，努力扩大与各国经济合作规模和质量一位高级官员周三表示，中国与“一带一路”国家的经贸务实合作不断发展，秉持共商共建共享的理念。商务部副部长郭婷婷表示，十年来，中国的合作在范围和质量上不断提升，实现了共赢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国超大市场为参与国提供了重要发展机遇” “‘一带一路’倡议，原产于这些国家的商品目前占中国进口总额的近一半，”郭在接受新华社采访时强调，110多个“一带一路”国家视中国为重要贸易伙伴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 海关总署数据显示，中国进口和出口与“一带一路”沿线国家的出口额从2013年的6.46万亿元人民币（8850亿美元）增加到去年的13.76万亿元人民币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与此同时，中国与“一带一路”沿线国家之间的双向投资总额超过380美元据国务院新闻办公室周二发布的白皮书显示，2013年至2022年，中国对外直接投资超过2400亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 郭表示，中国对外直接投资超过2400亿美元。与“一带一路”沿线国家的贸易投资合作，有利于资源高效配置，加快产业链供应链融合发展，为构建开放型世界经济注入更多活力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界银行报告显示，“一带一路”带动参与方贸易增长4.1%，吸引外资增长5%。到2030年，“一带一路”每年将为全球带来1.6万亿美元收入，占全球GDP的1.3%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 未来，中国将更好地同沿线国家政策、规划、产业对接商务部副部长表示，为进一步加强基础设施互联互通，基础设施建设是“一带一路”的重要领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 过去10年，中国与东盟签署了价值2万亿美元的合同郭说，“一带一路”沿线国家已完成项目总价值1.3万亿美元，涉及交通、电力、石化、通讯、水利、污水处理等多个领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “一带一路国家受益匪浅”这些合作项目在完善基础设施建设、促进互联互通、增进人民福祉、增强发展能力等方面取得了积极成果。今年前8个月，中国企业在“一带一路”沿线国家新签节能环保项目，合同额160亿美元，同比增长郭说，增长22.2%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国将继续拓展新的合作领域，引导企业加强绿色等基础设施项目建设，帮助“一带一路”沿线国家实现绿色发展。她说，数字化发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 郭重申中国决心进一步扩大高标准自由贸易区网络，表示中国将推动加入《全面且进步的跨太平洋伙伴关系协定》 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “实践证明，自由贸易协定能够有效稳定和深化参与方经贸合作，促进企业发展，增强民心。” ”的福祉，“ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 郭说，中国将落实好区域全面经济伙伴关系协定，该伙伴关系已于6月在所有15个成员经济体中生效，并补充说，中国将推进与其他国家的自贸协定谈判或升级进程。东南亚国家联盟、海湾合作委员会以及塞尔维亚、洪都拉斯、新西兰、秘鲁等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 截至目前，中国已与28个国家和地区签署自贸协定，其中20个国家和地区是东南亚国家联盟、海湾合作委员会以及塞尔维亚、洪都拉斯、新西兰、秘鲁等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkeju@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - HONG KONG VOLUNTEERS RISE TO OCCASION AT ASIAN GAMES]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_001_65270d03ed50d203d2ca0482.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/001/20231012_002_01_26455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;篮球运动员王新宇问候浙江省杭州亚运会比赛中的志愿者。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/001/20231012_002_01_43455.png &quot; />;&lt;p>;奥运会期间，志愿者在媒体中心工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/001/20231012_002_01_60455 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;志愿者与奥运会吉祥物之一合影。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/ 001/20231012_002_01_78455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;志愿者为奥运会活动设置障碍。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023- 10-12/001/20231012_002_01_95455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;比赛前志愿者清理壁球场。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023 -10-12/001/20231012_002_01_77455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;来自香港的志愿者何佩佩被选为奥运会火炬手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何佩佩毫不犹豫地制作了专程从香港飞往浙江省省会杭州，为周日结束的第十九届亚运会担任志愿者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “对于这样一项具有国际地位和意义的盛事，问题不应该是我为什么要参加，而是为什么不参加，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 出生于1985年的何女士曾在银行工作，但厌倦了这份工作后，转而加入香港警队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马尾辫、快步走、语速快的她，诠释了香港影视剧中常见的香港女警形象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年三月，听说港岛女警领先的慈善组织39;s协会正在推荐当地居民担任亚运志愿者，何先生第一个站出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何先生说：“通常会有几个人的差距。”亚运会规模的赛事之间间隔了数年。人生苦短，我年纪也不小了，不能错过这个机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从三月份开始，何女士就用所有的业余时间为当志愿者做准备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 她先通过协会的面试，然后到香港赛马会管理的屯门公众骑术学校接受训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 训练期间，何女士让她第一次进入马厩，近距离接触马匹，让她亲身了解了马厩的运营、马匹的营养和马术训练等知识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 按照亚组委的要求，她完成了网上课程经过几个月的准备工作，学习了相关材料，通过了考试，最终被选为志愿者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上个月，在同事的支持下，何女士利用自己积累的假期，腾出时间在&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她于9月19日抵达杭州，入住距离主办亚运会马术比赛的桐庐马术中心约50分钟车程的酒店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 每天，何女士凌晨 4 点起床，确保早上 6 点左右到达比赛场地，两小时后开始工作。她经常忙到深夜，有时忙到晚上 11 点或午夜，常常只能抽出大约 5 个小时的时间。每天睡觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何负责提供英语翻译服务。她帮助来自不同国家和地区的运动员、技术人员和工作人员相互交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;明显的相似之处&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说自己花了很多时间&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 第一次参观马厩时，何女士有一种熟悉的感觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “桐庐的马厩和北京的马厩有很多相似之处。”屯门的设施及基建方面，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 得知香港赛马会为桐庐马术中心的发展提供技术支持后，何女士表示对香港与内地的合作有了更深入的了解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她的主要职责是帮助两名来自英国的马蹄铁匠与内地工作人员沟通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何说识别不同的修蹄工具很困难，因为它们看起来很相似并有复杂的英文名称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 马蹄铁匠们花了很多时间在白板上写下这些工具的名称，并将它们与其他物体进行比较，以教何识别它们。 “我花了一天时间才熟悉这些术语，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何说这两个英国人很有幽默感。为了营造快乐的工作氛围，他们让她写下名言和笑话，并在白板上画画和涂鸦，每天更换。作为她在马术中心第一天的座右铭，她写道：“生活不一定要完美才能精彩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在马术活动的最初几天，天气炎热，一些人中暑了。何女士被叫去医疗室帮忙，当贵宾室迎宾的志愿者生病时，她也介入提供帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，她还被要求与一位外籍客人进行沟通关于奖牌颁奖仪式的排练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我的职责是随叫随到，随时准备前往任何需要我的地方。我绕着中心跑步，每天通常走 10,000 步，”何女士说，她最珍惜和志愿者们建立的友谊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在中心，27名来自香港的志愿者在抵达杭州之前彼此不认识。每个人都分配了不同的任务。何女士努力将他们团结在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她从香港带来了徽章，与内地志愿者分享。由于电视剧中的香港警察形象，他们对香港警察特别感兴趣，她耐心地回答了他们关于工作的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在杭州的头几天，何女士很难适应气候，睡眠不好，在吵杂的环境下总是需要大声喊叫才能让自己听到。结果，她的声音变得沙哑，有一天，她说话都困难了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 朋友们很快就把所有的药都给了她，有的还给何叫了外卖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国庆节下午，没有安排比赛，组委会为志愿者们安排了一场庆功晚会，并邀请志愿者们上台表演。有的跳舞，有的唱歌，还有的朗诵诗歌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 香港摇滚乐队Beyond是何的歌曲的灵感来源，她的独唱很快得到了朋友们的加入。他们一起随着音乐合拍地挥手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我感觉我们当时就是一个大家庭”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;很难离开&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着志愿服务即将结束，何说她无法​​想象必须离开杭州。&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>; “我以为我会有复杂的情绪，”她说，并补充说，这次志愿者经历将在她心中占有特殊的位置，成为她一生中最美好的回忆之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杭州亚组委主任王杰志愿者部门表示，整个运动会，港澳台志愿者表现出了非凡的无私和奉献精神。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 筹备期间的志愿者招募反应热烈，招募了约31.7万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 总共有37,600名志愿者从这个库中被选出来，承担各种任务，包括整个奥运会的语言服务、接待工作、技术支持和场馆维护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 志愿者被称为“小绿莲花”这个术语的灵感来自于他们制服的颜色。这个昵称象征着他们作为“充满活力的力量”的角色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王说，60朵“小绿莲”来自香港，4朵来自澳门，8朵来自台湾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;p>; 来自香港的60人中，有29人是由香港大学和香港科技大学推荐的。他们在杭州奥体中心网球中心工作。此外，还有27名志愿者被两个社会组织推荐——香港青年协会及港岛妇女会。他们在桐庐马术中心提供服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 来自澳门和台湾的志愿者大部分是在大陆读书的大学生，他们是通过公开招募的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 来自香港的志愿者语言能力较好的澳门和台湾地区经常担任接待员或翻译。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王先生表示，志愿者们的服务让他很感动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，在香港唯一的铁路运营商港铁公司工作的林浩峰此前曾 18 次志愿参加国际活动，包括 2008 年北京奥运会奥运会和2010年亚运会在广东省省会广州举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 得知第十九届亚运会将在杭州举行后，林郑月娥从香港来到杭州，理所当然地成为了杭州亚运会的志愿者。第19次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王先生表示，在与港澳台志愿者的互动中，感受到他们强烈的国家认同感，为能够为正在举办的大型活动做出贡献而感到自豪&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，这些志愿者在与他人互动时表现出了积极主动、开放的态度。他说，他们中的许多有体育爱好的人对国际赛事有了更专业的了解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王补充道，其中一些志愿者在抵达杭州之前接受了培训，凸显了他们对亚运会的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 王说，香港、澳门和台湾居民在开展志愿工作时面临着额外的挑战，包括协调时间、管理工作和学习以及处理出行问题。他对这些志愿者克服困难、全心全意为亚运做出贡献表示深深的感谢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，除了亚运之外，杭州还举办了G20峰会等各种大型活动。以及中国国际动漫节。下个月还将举办全球数字贸易博览会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王表示，希望亚运会成为促进杭州与香港、澳门、台湾之间更多沟通和交流的催化剂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; “今后我们将欢迎港澳台居民更多地来杭州旅游。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;oasishu@chinadailyhk.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - HONG KONG VOLUNTEERS RISE TO OCCASION AT ASIAN GAMES]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_002_65270d03ed50d203d2ca0483.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/002/20231012_002_01_26455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;篮球运动员王新宇问候浙江省杭州亚运会比赛中的志愿者。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/002/20231012_002_01_43455.png &quot; />;&lt;p>;奥运会期间，志愿者在媒体中心工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/002/20231012_002_01_60455 .png&quot; />;&lt;p>;志愿者与奥运会吉祥物之一合影。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/ 002/20231012_002_01_78455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;志愿者为奥运会活动设置障碍。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023- 10-12/002/20231012_002_01_95455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;比赛前志愿者清理壁球场。&lt;/p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023 -10-12/002/20231012_002_01_77455.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;来自香港的志愿者何佩佩被选为奥运会火炬手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何佩佩毫不犹豫地制作了专程从香港飞往浙江省省会杭州，为周日结束的第十九届亚运会担任志愿者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “对于这样一项具有国际地位和意义的盛事，问题不应该是我为什么要参加，而是为什么不参加，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 出生于1985年的何女士曾在银行工作，但厌倦了这份工作后，转而加入香港警队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马尾辫、快步走、语速快的她，诠释了香港影视剧中常见的香港女警形象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年三月，听说港岛女警领先的慈善组织39;s协会正在推荐当地居民担任亚运志愿者，何先生第一个站出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何先生说：“通常会有几个人的差距。”亚运会规模的赛事之间间隔了数年。人生苦短，我年纪也不小了，不能错过这个机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从三月份开始，何女士就用所有的业余时间为当志愿者做准备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 她先通过协会的面试，然后到香港赛马会管理的屯门公众骑术学校接受训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 训练期间，何女士让她第一次进入马厩，近距离接触马匹，让她亲身了解了马厩的运营、马匹的营养和马术训练等知识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 按照亚组委的要求，她完成了网上课程经过几个月的准备工作，学习了相关材料，通过了考试，最终被选为志愿者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上个月，在同事的支持下，何女士利用自己积累的假期，腾出时间在&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她于9月19日抵达杭州，入住距离主办亚运会马术比赛的桐庐马术中心约50分钟车程的酒店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 每天，何女士凌晨 4 点起床，确保早上 6 点左右到达比赛场地，两小时后开始工作。她经常忙到深夜，有时忙到晚上 11 点或午夜，常常只能抽出大约 5 个小时的时间。每天睡觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何负责提供英语翻译服务。她帮助来自不同国家和地区的运动员、技术人员和工作人员相互交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;明显的相似之处&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说自己花了很多时间&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 第一次参观马厩时，何女士有一种熟悉的感觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “桐庐的马厩和北京的马厩有很多相似之处。”屯门的设施及基建方面，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 得知香港赛马会为桐庐马术中心的发展提供技术支持后，何女士表示对香港与内地的合作有了更深入的了解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她的主要职责是帮助两名来自英国的马蹄铁匠与内地工作人员沟通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何说识别不同的修蹄工具很困难，因为它们看起来很相似并有复杂的英文名称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 马蹄铁匠们花了很多时间在白板上写下这些工具的名称，并将它们与其他物体进行比较，以教何识别它们。 “我花了一天时间才熟悉这些术语，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 何说这两个英国人很有幽默感。为了营造快乐的工作氛围，他们让她写下名言和笑话，并在白板上画画和涂鸦，每天更换。作为她在马术中心第一天的座右铭，她写道：“生活不必完美才精彩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在马术活动的最初几天，天气炎热，一些人中暑了。何女士被叫到医疗室帮忙，当贵宾室迎宾的志愿者生病时，她也介入提供帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 此外，她还被要求与一位外籍客人进行沟通关于奖牌颁奖仪式的排练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我的职责是随叫随到，随时准备前往任何需要我的地方。我绕着中心跑步，每天通常走 10,000 步，” Ho said, adding that she cherished the most the friendships she formed with her fellow volunteers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the center, 27 volunteers from Hong Kong, who didn&amp;#39;t know one another before arriving in Hangzhou, were each assigned different tasks. Ho made efforts to unite them together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She brought badges from Hong Kong to share with the mainland volunteers. As they were particularly interested in the Hong Kong police due to the force&amp;#39;s portrayal in TV dramas, she patiently answered their questions about her work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In her first few days in Hangzhou, Ho struggled to adapt to the climate, slept badly, and always needed to shout to make herself heard in noisy conditions. As a result, her voice became hoarse, and one day she had difficulty speaking.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Her friends were quick to offer her all the medicine they had, and some even ordered takeout food for Ho.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the afternoon on National Day, when no competitions were scheduled, the organizing committee arranged a celebratory party for the volunteers, during which they were invited to perform on stage. Some danced, some sang, and others recited poetry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hong Kong rock band Beyond was the inspiration for Ho&amp;#39;s songs, and her solo act was quickly joined by her friends. Together, they waved their hands in time to the music.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I felt that we were a big family at that time,&amp;quot; Ho said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Hard to leave&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As the end of her voluntary service approached, Ho said she could not imagine having to leave Hangzhou.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I thought I would have mixed emotions,&amp;quot; she said, adding that her volunteer experience would hold a special place in her heart and be one of the most beautiful memories of her life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Jie, director of the Hangzhou Asian Games Organizing Committee&amp;#39;s volunteer department, said that throughout the Games, the volunteers from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan demonstrated exceptional selflessness and dedication.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There was an overwhelming response to the volunteer recruitment process during the preparatory period, with about 317,000 people applying.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A total of 37,600 volunteers were chosen from this pool for various tasks, including language services, reception work, technical support and venue maintenance throughout the Games.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Volunteers were known as &amp;quot;little green lotuses,&amp;quot; a term inspired by the color of their uniforms. The nickname symbolized their role as the &amp;quot;vibrant power&amp;quot; behind the scenes and also reflected the deep affection people held for them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said 60 &amp;quot;little green lotuses &amp;quot;were from Hong Kong, four came from Macao, and eight from Taiwan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the 60 from Hong Kong, 29 were recommended by the University of Hong Kong and Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. They worked at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Centre Tennis Centre. In addition, 27 volunteers were recommended by two social organizations &amp;mdash; the Hong Kong Federation of Youth Groups and the Hong Kong Island Women&amp;#39;s Association. They provided services at the Tonglu Equestrian Centre.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most of the volunteers from Macao and Taiwan were university students studying on the mainland, who were recruited through open enrollment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Volunteers from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan with relatively good language skills often worked as receptionists or translators.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said he was touched by the volunteers&amp;#39; personal stories and their willingness to serve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For example, Lam Ho-fung, who works for the MTR Corp, the sole rail operator in Hong Kong, previously volunteered for international events 18 times, including the 2008 Beijing Olympic Games and the 2010 Asian Games in Guangzhou, capital of Guangdong province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After learning that the 19th Asian Games would be held in Hangzhou, Lam traveled to the city from Hong Kong, aptly becoming a volunteer for the 19th time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said that after interacting with the volunteers from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan, he felt their strong sense of national identity, adding that they were proud to contribute to a large-scale event being staged by China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said these volunteers exhibited a proactive and open attitude when interacting with others. Many of them who have sports hobbies had a more professional understanding of international events, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some of these volunteers underwent training before arriving in Hangzhou, highlighting their commitment to Asian Games, Wang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Residents of Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan face additional challenges in performing voluntary work, including coordinating their time, managing their work and studies, and dealing with travel problems, Wang said. He expressed deep gratitude to these volunteers for overcoming such obstacles and wholeheartedly contributing to the Asian Games.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said that in addition to the Asian Games, Hangzhou has hosted various large-scale events, such as the G20 Summit and the China International Cartoon Animation Festival. It will also stage the Global Digital Trade Expo next month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang said he hoped the Asian Games would serve as a catalyst to foster more communication and exchanges between Hangzhou, Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We would welcome residents from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan visiting Hangzhou more often in the future,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;oasishu@chinadailyhk.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - IMF &#39;welcomes&#39; steps in property market]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_003_65270d06ed50d203d2ca0484.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/003/20231012_003_01_17.png&quot; />; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s near-zero inflation means it has space to ease monetary policy, and it has taken &amp;quot;welcome&amp;quot; measures to address property market difficulties that were a factor in the International Monetary Fund cutting the country&amp;#39;s GDP growth forecast to 5 percent for 2023, IMF chief economist Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looming large over China&amp;#39;s growth prospects is the challenging real estate situation, in which a number of pre-sold units have not been completed and developers face financial difficulties, resulting in downward pressure on and a lack of confidence in the real estate market, Gourinchas said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Clearly, what this calls for is forceful action by the authorities to help &amp;mdash; for instance ... restructure struggling property developers &amp;mdash; to make sure that there isn&amp;#39;t any increase in financial instability,&amp;quot; Gourinchas said on Tuesday during the annual meetings of the IMF and World Bank in Marrakech, Morocco.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve seen some measures that have been taken in recent months, in recent weeks,&amp;quot;他说。 &amp;quot;These measures are welcome, but they need to be at scale.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a statement issued on Sept 26 at the conclusion of its discussion of the World Economic Outlook report, the IMF Executive Board said, &amp;quot;Most directors noted the risk of a further deterioration in China&amp;#39;s property sector and, in this regard, welcomed the recent policy actions taken by the authorities.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The property sector has been a pillar of China&amp;#39;s economy, but it has been a drag on the nation&amp;#39;s economic recovery.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping, who is also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, has underscored the significant impact of the real estate sector on other facets of the country&amp;#39;s economic and social development. In an article published in February in the journal Qiushi, the flagship magazine of the CPC Central Committee, he called for efforts to effectively forestall and defuse systemic risks arising in the property sector.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following a key meeting of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee in late July that decided property policies should be adjusted and optimized in a timely manner, authorities issued a series of measures on Aug 31, including adjustments to ease restrictions on the classification of first-home buyers, lower existing first-home loan rates and extend tax incentives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mortgage interest rate for first-time homebuyers should be no less than the level of 20 basis points below the loan prime rate, according to a statement issued by the People&amp;#39;s Bank of China, the country&amp;#39;s central bank, and the National Administration of Financial Regulation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a result, trading in the real estate market has become brisker. In September, the total sales of the country&amp;#39;s top 100 real estate developers surged 24.8 percent month-on-month, Xinhua News Agency reported last week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the IMF news conference, Gourinchas also said that China&amp;#39;s monetary policy can &amp;quot;certainly&amp;quot; help its economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;There is a sense in which monetary policy can be eased. China is in a very different place than the rest of the world, in terms of the inflation pressures. If anything, their inflation numbers are below target, so they have room to ease monetary policy,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Worldwide, even as central banks have taken decisive action, inflation remains above target in almost all economies with an inflation target, the IMF said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It noted that among major central banks with inflation above target, the Bank of Canada, the Bank of England, the European Central Bank and the United States Federal Reserve all raised rates in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The largest exception to this pattern is China, where headline inflation is subdued and below the authorities&amp;#39; target, and the PBOC reduced interest rates in June and August,&amp;quot; it added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The central bank cut the one-year loan prime rate in June and August by 25 basis points in total. The one-year LPR was 3.45 percent last month, while the five-year LPR, on which lenders base their mortgage rates, was unchanged at 4.2 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Global core inflation, excluding food and energy prices, was down from a peak of 8.5 percent in the first quarter of 2022, at a quarterly annualized rate, to 4.9 percent in the second quarter of 2023, nearly two-thirds of the way back to the pre-pandemic annual average of 2.8 percent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&amp;#39;s core inflation in the second quarter of 2023 was 0.3 percent, compared with 4.6 percent in the eurozone and 4.7 percent in the US, according to the latest IMF statistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That means China will have room to support the household sector on the fiscal side, by redeploying some of the fiscal measures and helping households and consumers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;So these are sort of the measures we would encourage the authorities to undertake. And I think they are moving in that direction, and this is to be welcomed,&amp;quot; Gourinchas said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also said that &amp;quot;typically, if there is one percentage point lower growth in China, this translates into something like 0.3 percentage point lower growth in the rest of the world&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To avert the likelihood of China&amp;#39;s economy further slowing down, a downside risk to global growth, the IMF said there should be effective policy response in preserving financial stability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That could be achieved by expediting the restructuring of struggling property developers, facilitating the completion of housing projects, and addressing the growing strain in local government finances, all of which would help restore business and consumer confidence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Policy space has shrunk but is not fully exhausted. Given the lack of inflationary pressure, the People&amp;#39;s Bank of China has some room to ease,&amp;quot; the IMF said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Stronger policy support in China than currently envisioned &amp;mdash; through means-tested transfers to households in particular &amp;mdash; could bolster the recovery and generate positive global spillovers, it said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Globally, growth is projected to fall from 3.5 percent in 2022 to 3 percent in 2023 and 2.9 percent in 2024. The figure for next year is 0.1 percentage point lower than the IMF&amp;#39;s July projection.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The weaker growth prospects also reflect the rising incidence of climate risks, with increased frequency of large natural disasters and rising geo-economic fragmentation&amp;quot; such as US-China trade tensions, Gourinchas said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;While some countries may benefit in the short term, in the medium term, all lose,&amp;quot; he said, adding that &amp;quot;multilateral cooperation can help reverse some of these headwinds for the world economy&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;huanxinzhao@chinadailyusa.com&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Time to feast]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_003_65270d09ed50d203d2ca0485.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-12/003/20231012_003_02_39.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Tourists take part in a &amp;quot;hundred-family banquet&amp;quot; on Tuesday in Longsheng, a county in Guilin, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region. Apart from the banquet, local residents belonging to the Zhuang ethnic group celebrated the harvest by demonstrating primitive fishing skills, releasing thousands of fry, fishing in muddied waters and competing in the art of filleting fish.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Borrell to attend high-level Sino-EU talks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_003_65270d0ced50d203d2ca0486.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Foreign Ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin announced on Wednesday that European Union foreign policy chief Josep Borrell will visit China and attend the 12th round of the China-EU High-Level Strategic Dialogue from Thursday to Saturday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China welcomes Borrell and believes his trip will help promote the healthy and stable development of China-EU relations and lay the groundwork for future high-level exchanges,&amp;quot; Wang said at a regular news briefing in Beijing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Borrell&amp;#39;s visit, which was twice rescheduled since it was announced in April, will also provide new impetus for China and the EU to jointly address global challenges and safeguard world peace and stability, Wang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Observers noted that the visit will provide an opportunity for China and the EU to facilitate mutual understanding through discussions on a variety of issues such as practical cooperation, hot spot regional issues and global affairs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Haidong, a professor at the Institute of International Relations at China Foreign Affairs University, said that economic and trade issues will be among the focal points of discussion during Borrell&amp;#39;s visit, particularly after the European Commission officially launched an anti-subsidy investigation into the import of electric cars from China on Oct 4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li said whether the two sides can handle the issue properly matters to the stability and development of China-EU ties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;There is no doubt that the practice of imposing restrictions on Chinese products while seeking to profit from the huge Chinese market will not be accepted by the Chinese side,&amp;quot; Li said, adding that cooperation will be a natural result when the two sides build up mutual trust through communication.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang, the spokesman, said that China and the EU share extensive common interests as two major forces for world peace, two major markets for common development and two major civilizations for humanity&amp;#39;s progress.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This year marks the 20th anniversary of the establishment of the comprehensive strategic partnership between China and the EU.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the beginning of this year, the two sides have had frequent high-level interactions and carried out dialogue and cooperation at all levels in different areas, showing a positive momentum in China-EU relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a phone call with Foreign Minister Wang Yi in August, Borrell said he looks forward to visiting China as soon as possible to jointly prepare for this year&amp;#39;s EU-China leaders&amp;#39; meeting and to promote the further development of EU-China relations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;mojingxi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Nation to advance building of high-quality overseas projects]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/12/content_003_65270d0ced50d203d2ca0487.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; China will further advance the construction of high-quality overseas projects and expand the network of free trade zones, as part of its efforts to increase the scale and enhance the quality of economic cooperation with countries involved in the Belt and Road Initiative, a senior official said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following the approach of consultation and collaboration for shared benefits, China&amp;#39;s practical cooperation in economy and trade with Belt and Road countries has grown in scope and quality over the past decade and achieved win-win results, said Guo Tingting, vice-minister of commerce.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China&amp;#39;s supersized market has provided important development opportunities for countries involved in the BRI, and goods originating in these countries now account for nearly half of China&amp;#39;s total imports,&amp;quot; Guo said in an interview with Xinhua News Agency, emphasizing that more than 110 Belt and Road countries count China as an important trade partner.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data from the General Administration of Customs showed that China&amp;#39;s imports and exports with Belt and Road countries increased from 6.46 trillion yuan ($885 billion) in 2013 to 13.76 trillion yuan last year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meanwhile, two-way investment between China and other countries involved in the BRI totaled more than $380 billion between 2013 and 2022, of which China&amp;#39;s outward direct investment exceeded $240 billion, according to a white paper released by the State Council Information Office on Tuesday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guo said that China&amp;#39;s trade and investment cooperation with Belt and Road countries has aided in the efficient allocation of resources, accelerated the integrated development of the industrial and supply chains, and injected more vitality into the creation of an open global economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to a World Bank report, the BRI increased the trade of participating parties by 4.1 percent and attracted 5 percent more foreign investment. By 2030, the BRI will generate $1.6 trillion in global revenue each year, accounting for 1.3 percent of global GDP.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Going forward, China will better align with the policies, planning and industries of countries participating in the BRI, in order to further enhance infrastructure connectivity, the vice-minister of commerce said, underlining that infrastructure construction is an important area of the initiative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past 10 years, China has signed contracts worth $2 trillion with Belt and Road countries and completed projects worth $1.3 trillion, covering a wide range of sectors including transportation, electricity, petrochemical, communication, water conservancy and wastewater treatment, Guo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Belt and Road countries have benefited from these cooperation projects in terms of improving infrastructure development, promoting connectivity, enhancing people&amp;#39;s well-being and strengthening their ability to develop,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the first eight months of this year, Chinese businesses inked new energy-saving and environmental protection projects in Belt and Road countries, with a contract value of $16 billion, a year-on-year increase of 22.2 percent, Guo said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will continue to expand its new areas of cooperation and guide enterprises to strengthen construction of green and other infrastructure projects, in a bid to help Belt and Road countries realize green and digital development, she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Reiterating China&amp;#39;s resolve to further expand the network of high-standard free trade zones, Guo said the country will promote accession to the Comprehensive and Progressive Trans-Pacific Partnership Agreement and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement in a proactive manner.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Free trade agreements, as demonstrated by past practices, can effectively stabilize and deepen economic and trade cooperation among participants, promote enterprise development and enhance people&amp;#39;s well-being,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China will well implement the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership, which came into force for all 15 member economies in June, Guo said, adding that the country will advance the process of negotiating or upgrading FTAs with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, the Gulf Cooperation Council and Serbia, Honduras, New Zealand and Peru, among others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To date, China has signed FTAs with 28 countries and regions, 20 of which are those involved in the initiative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangkeju@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:21:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>