<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Blueprint set for Yangtze economic belt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_001_652c59fced50d203d2ca0947.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;习近平主席提出的长江经济带高质量发展最新愿景，为长江经济带继续走在全国前列奠定了基础。分析人士表示，现代化、绿色发展和核心技术的突破。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 身为中共中央总书记的习近平提出了他的愿景，即该地区更好地服务和支持中国现代化建设，周四在江西省南昌市与官员举行会议。这是习近平自2016年以来主持的第四次此类会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 专门研究长江经济带的武汉大学经济学教授吴传清表示，习近平提出了一系列新政策， “将构成该地区成为国家现代化建设支柱的路线图”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“毫无疑问，长江经济带已经名列前茅。” - 在经济增长或环境保护方面表现出色的地区。唯一的问题是这个表现最好的地区如何才能表现得更好。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 经济带包括长江沿岸11个省级地区——亚洲最长的河流——从中国西部的四川、云南省一直延伸到中国东部的经济重镇，包括江浙省和上海。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该地区面积超过 200 万平方公里，占全国面积的五分之一，占占中国总人口的40%以上。截至 2022 年，其 GDP 达到 55.98 万亿元人民币（7.67 万亿美元），约占全国GDP 的 46.2%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平周四重申了统筹推进环境保护、避免过度开发的原则。吴说，该地区已实施长江禁渔十年以及其他一系列生态修复措施，最有可能体现习近平所倡导的“绿水青山就是金山银山”的理念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 农业部和农业部下属机构周四发布的一份报告农村和其他三个部门发现，自2021年1月起实施的为期10年的禁渔令已经使长江水生物种明显恢复。 2020年以来，本土物种数量增加25类，濒危长江江豚数量比2017年增加23.4%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平在江西考察时告诉随行官员，保护长江江豚种群生态环境建设是一项长期事业，不能自满。 “现在的长江只能用‘大病初愈’来形容”， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 江西省社会科学院院长李志猛说：发展战略研究院表示，事实证明，统筹协调的保护措施非但没有抑制经济增长，反而推动经济带走上了高质量发展之路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李说习近平的最新讲话将为该地区经济绿色化、产业链供应链现代化、重点突破核心技术、发展先进制造业和新兴产业铺平道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;经济带面临的一个紧迫问题是解决不同地区特别是腹地上游地区和东部较发达地区发展不平衡问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平在会上强调，要鼓励资本、技术、劳动密集型产业从东部地区向中西部地区、城市向腹地地区流动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东南大学教授岳书晶39岁经济管理学院表示，长江经济带制造业蓬勃发展，国际贸易蓬勃发展，已成为中国对外开放的重要门户和“一带一路”的重要支柱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 岳说，创新将是推动该地区未来增长和开放的关键因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “创新已经重塑了这一角色推动地区在国际市场的发展，将继续帮助优化外贸投资结构，提高在全球价值链中的地位。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Glimpse into history]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_001_652c59ffed50d203d2ca0948.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/001/20231016_001_02_145.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;媒体代表参观壁画周五，新疆维吾尔自治区吐鲁番葡萄沟风景区的展览馆。来自香港、澳门特别行政区、台湾、东南亚等地的20余家华文媒体代表参加吐鲁番“一带一路”实地考察，更多地了解了古代丝绸之路的遗产。此次巡演自10月9日开始，还前往喀什、乌鲁木齐等新疆其他地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Central bank vows more solid support for real economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_001_652c5a01ed50d203d2ca0949.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 近期经济指标好转，央行行长表示将加大对实体经济的支持力度，专家预计这将进一步坚定对国家的信心。#中国人民银行行长、央行行长潘功胜认为，我国经济运行积极因素增多，社会预期不断增强。国家外汇管理局表示，人民银行将持续支持和用好经济动能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 总量性、结构性货币工具有望更好发挥作用，为扩大内需、提振预期提供更多实质性保障潘基文在参加周六在摩洛哥马拉喀什结束的为期两天的国际货币和金融委员会会议时表示，要支持实体经济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他发表这番言论之际，中国经济复苏的迹象越来越多。 39; 的经济活动，官方采购经理的; 9月份制造业指数从8月份的49.7升至50.2，六个月来首次回到扩张区间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着社会融资总量的增量，9月份融资活动也有所回升;实体经济融资总额——中国人民银行周五的数据显示，2019 年房地产投资总额为 4.12 万亿元人民币（5639.3 亿美元），同比增加 5638 亿元人民币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着专家表示，潘的最新政策包括根据首次购房者的财产所有权状况而不是抵押贷款历史向他们提供优惠的抵押贷款条件，以及降低现有首次购房者的抵押贷款利率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此番言论凸显了央行在近期经济活动回升的情况下继续加大对经济复苏支持力度而不是放松刺激措施的政策立场，有利于夯实国家经济复苏的基础。&lt;/国际货币基金组织(IMF)驻华高级代表史蒂文·巴内特(Steven Barnett)表示，尽管存在房地产逆风，但考虑到当前的经济形势，中国仍有空间通过将财政刺激转向消费者支出和实施进一步的货币宽松政策来提振经济。景顺固定收益亚太区主管 Freddy Wong 表示，央行可能会进一步降低利率政策基准，以促进经济复苏，并补充说，他认为目前的通胀不会引发系统性风险。中国部分房地产开发商流动性紧张。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 官方数据显示，中国金融风险总体可控，占金融体系资产90%以上的银行业总体稳健特别是大型银行保持较高信用评级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 潘补充说，央行实施稳健的货币政策有针对性、有力，加大逆周期调节力度，有效应对国内外风险挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 潘表示，中国将更加注重经济增长与可持续发展的平衡，在保持合理增速的同时，积极推动高质量可持续发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 专家表示，潘基文的言论预示着央行在运用结构性工具支持普惠金融后，未来可能会加大对促进消费、创新和绿色增长以及相关新基建的重视、科技创新、绿色发展、民营企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhoulanxv@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div >;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Beijing bolsters mediation efforts, seeks lasting peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_001_652c5a04ed50d203d2ca094a.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/001/20231016_001_04_162.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;一名警察携带周六，受伤儿童被送往医院，在加沙地带被以色列袭击摧毁或损坏的建筑物周围的搜救行动仍在继续。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在过去的一周里，北京一直致力于对巴以问题进行深入调解与包括美国和沙特阿拉伯在内的主要相关方发生冲突，寻求早日停火并避免重大人道主义灾难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 北京特使准备前往中东进行调解观察人士表示，东方即将到来，中国正在以守信、务实的方式忠实履行负责任大国的建设性作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国政府中东问题特使翟隽表示，周日表示，本周他将“访问中东一些有关国家，进一步加强各方协调”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们工作的方向是寻求停火” ，保护平民，缓和局势并促进和平谈判，”他说，并警告说，冲突“正在加速扩大”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 当被问及冲突中中国公民的安全时，翟证实，四名中国公民已被杀，两人仍被杀害。失踪者和六人受伤正在当地医院接受治疗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 巴以冲突成为外交部长王毅周六与美国国务卿通电话的首要话题安东尼·布林肯与沙特外交大臣费萨尔·本·法尔汉亲王。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王毅在与布林肯通电话时强调，“大国应保持客观、公正、冷静，保持克制，带头遵守国际法” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 巴勒斯坦问题的根本解决取决于落实两国方案，建立独立的巴勒斯坦国，实现巴勒斯坦之间和平共处中共中央政治局委员王说，布林肯表示，美国支持“两国方案”。愿同中方加强沟通协调。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王毅在与费萨尔亲王通电话时表示，各方应避免局势升级，尽快回到谈判桌前。中国“正在与各方密切沟通，寻求停火”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，当务之急是“尽一切努力确保平民安全，尽快建立人道主义通道”。外交部周日发表的一份声明称，“尽可能并确保加沙人民的基本需求”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 沙特外长表示，中国“在促进世界发展方面发挥着重要和基础性的作用”。 “和平与稳定”，利雅得愿与北京共同努力，确保各方遵守国际人道主义法，履行联合国安理会关于巴勒斯坦问题的相关决议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周日，王还表示与伊朗外长阿卜杜拉希安通电话，表示伊斯兰国家应在巴勒斯坦问题上加强团结，同心协力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在会见欧盟外交与安全政策高级代表何塞普时王毅周五在北京与巴西总统首席顾问塞尔索·路易斯·努内斯·阿莫林通电话，敦促国际社会在“两国方案”基础上形成共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 分析人士指出，北京的斡旋努力体现了中国对“两国解决方案”的尊重，这一点得到了国际社会的认可，也得到了国际社会的认可。联合国安理会决议及其维和理念旨在平衡、务实地照顾各方利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个问题，北京相信，只要朝着合理的目标不断努力，一定会取得一些进展和成果。”中国国际问题研究所副研究员苏晓晖表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她在审视今年早些时候阿拉伯世界蓬勃发展的和解进程时，不应忽视北京在调解方面的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国推动伊朗和沙特阿拉伯之间的和解就是一个很好的证据，证明如果有关各方能够朝着同一目标迈进并建立一个解决方案，那么这个棘手的问题就可以最终得到解决。”尽管矛盾极其复杂，但气氛仍然温和、冷静。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 中国现代国际关系研究院院长牛新春说。中东研究所警告说，随着冲突扩大，有可能蔓延到加沙地区以外的地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “如果冲突扩大到黎巴嫩或叙利亚，局势的波动可能会加剧。”中东局势将急剧恶化，给中东和平带来新的困境。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - DANCE DRAMA SETS STAGE FOR INTERNATIONAL CULTURAL EXCHANGES]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_001_652c5a07ed50d203d2ca094b.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/001/20231016_002_01_27.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/001/20231016_002_01_26.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 舞剧咏春拳，由深圳歌剧院制作上月底，广东省舞蹈剧场在充满活力的新加坡迎来了万众瞩目的海外首演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 演出从9月28日开始连续上演三晚，集中体现了联合舞蹈团的深刻观察。国家理论家肯·威尔伯：“当不同的文化交汇时，就会产生独特而精彩的创作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该剧是今年最成功、最畅销的中国舞蹈之一戏剧，在新加坡滨海艺术中心上演 –海湾剧场，其中一场演出七次加演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在抵达新加坡之前，该剧自去年在深圳首演以来，已在中国巡演，在30多个城市上演了90多场演出。它广受好评，尤其受到年轻观众的欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新加坡，当观众聚集在剧院外观看演出的最后一晚时，有一种兴奋的感觉。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 53 岁的唐·洛 (Don Low) 是一名大学美术讲师，他从朋友那里听说了这部作品，当时他和家人在一起，其中包括正在庆祝 83 岁生日的母亲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我的”妈妈练功夫已经有30年了，所以我想她会喜欢这个表演的。我们也借此机会赶上文化表演，因为我们已经有一段时间没有参加文化表演了。” ”Low 说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 29 岁的中国公民 Janna Pan 说，当她听说演出要在新加坡举行时，她立即购买了门票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这非常难”买票，因为这个剧团很有名。我非常高兴有机会亲自观看演出，”在建筑行业工作的潘说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该剧以 20 世纪 90 年代的电影为背景，讲述了中国功夫大师叶问的故事。该剧采用戏中戏的形式，围绕顶尖功夫大师之间的惊心动魄的对决展开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 它以五种中国武术为特色——咏春拳、太极拳、八卦掌、八极拳、螳螂拳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 剧中的打斗场面充满了情感，而咏春拳的情节和人物则以讲述普通人的故事和英雄们在追求正义和平等的过程中互相支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;欣快的反应&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新加坡的最后谢幕期间，人们的情绪是欣喜的，因为观众们欢呼雀跃，热烈鼓掌，并向演员们起立鼓掌。来自深圳歌剧院的年轻演员们舞蹈剧场同样热情，在演出结束后的签售会上向排起长队的观众致意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 演出导演表示，将咏春拳带到新加坡是一次难忘的经历。该剧由中国舞蹈艺术新星韩震、周莉亚执导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 韩震表示：“新加坡华人很多，所以我们感觉很亲近。新加坡观众对我们的欢迎方式也让我们深受感动。通过这部舞剧，我们希望人们能够更深入地了解中国伟大的传统文化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是韩周首次合作制作以功夫为主的作品&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们多次前往广东，参观纪念馆、参观功夫大师的作品，了解更多武术知识。故居。他们还与多位教练交谈，了解功夫的历史、传统和变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周说，表演者在学习咏春拳的舞蹈动作之前都接受了严格的武术训练。考虑到制作的物理要求，这是一项具有挑战性的工作。选手们需要动作优雅、速度快、力量大，并以深厚的情感刻画人物角色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国古典舞的很多动作都来自于中国的武术和戏曲。所以古典舞的发力方式和武术非常相似。我们还将现代舞和传统武术的动作融合在一起，为这个节目创造了独特的特色。”周说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 制作团队成员表示，他们希望明年能够进行世界巡演，其中包括访问欧洲。一月份，他们计划在香港上演咏春拳，并对为新加坡观众带来更多表演的前景感到兴奋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 功夫作为中国传统文化的内在象征，吸引了强烈的关注。受到世界各地追随者的追捧，他们被其不同的战斗风格、策略、哲学、道德和智慧所吸引。这些因素强调身心的平衡以及内心的平静。功夫的经久不衰也得益于李小龙、成龙和李连杰主演的电影。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新加坡许多武术学校和培训机构提供多种课程和风格，吸引了众多学员。此外，定期举办武术表演和比赛，为练习者提供比武、展示技艺的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 前往新加坡观看表演的咏春爱好者 Nigel Lan 表示很有趣观看武术在融合现代舞蹈的新环境中表演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这位 38 岁的律师表示，年轻人现在比以前更能接触文化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; “当我在 20 世纪 80 年代长大时，中国还没有完全开放。但如今，年轻人正在积极寻找与自己的根源重新建立联系的方法，无论是通过汉服文化（穿着中国传统服装和配饰）还是诸如此类的表演。对我来说，练习咏春拳让我有机会深深地感受到我与中国根源的联系。”兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;关键角色&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;像咏春拳这样的节目对于帮助将武术传播给更广泛的受众（包括年轻一代）至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;关键角色&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>; 9月30日，新中商会文化教育委员会主席林登丽带着15岁的孙子到新加坡看咏春拳。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 这是她第二次观看演出，第一晚是应中国大使馆的邀请观看的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 林女士是三十多年来孜孜不倦的文化艺术捍卫者，帮助促进了新加坡和中国之间的许多文化交流和项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我还想再看一遍演出，以加深我的知识和理解，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在林的旁边，她的孙子 Jaden Chng 说道：“我喜欢看叶问电影，也听说过很多关于咏春拳的好消息。观看演出是一次非常意外但有趣的经历。”香港武侠电影《叶问》系列取材于同名咏春拳大师的一生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 关系源远流长的新加坡和深圳推出双边措施&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观众池淑娜表示，咏春拳等作品促进了国际文化交流，将中华文化推向国际舞台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 她补充说，应加大力度组织新中之间的文化活动，例如举办工作坊、研讨会和讲座，以促进观众参与和加深了解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 社交媒体和其他数字渠道也可以池说，这有助于吸引观众并提高此类节目的知名度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她建议两国演员、导演、制作团队和其他艺术家之间加强交流，促进艺术创新。学校还可以举办更多此类作品，让新加坡和中国的学生了解彼此的文化和历史。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “观看这场美妙的视听盛宴，给大家带来了感动、美好的享受。”确实，艺术无国界。”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 位于广东省省会广州市的中山大学新闻与传播学院助理教授林家琳表示，咏春拳在新加坡获得的七首返场标志着咏春拳的制作和制作。 #39；非常受欢迎。林补充说，深圳在促进文化交流方面所做的努力也是值得赞扬的，这也是该节目成功的背后。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “深圳的文化多样性、创意产业、文化机构和国际交流使这座城市成为文化表达、创新和跨文化对话的充满活力的平台。咏春拳的成功在于创意文化表达，它植根于深圳的创意产业，包括设计、时尚、艺术和科技。”林说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这座城市蓬勃发展的创意产业促进了创新和艺术表达，不仅为弘扬和保存中华文化做出了贡献，而且还展示了表演者的才华。”作品和艺术家的和创作者的与公众互动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;联系作者：wangxu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - DANCE DRAMA SETS STAGE FOR INTERNATIONAL CULTURAL EXCHANGES]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_002_652c5a07ed50d203d2ca094c.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/002/20231016_002_01_27.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/002/20231016_002_01_26.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 舞剧《咏春拳》，由深圳歌剧院制作上月底，广东省舞蹈剧场在充满活力的新加坡迎来了万众瞩目的海外首演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 演出从9月28日开始连续上演三晚，集中体现了联合舞蹈团的深刻观察。国家理论家肯·威尔伯：“当不同的文化交汇时，就会产生独特而精彩的创作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该剧是今年最成功、最畅销的中国舞蹈之一戏剧，在新加坡滨海艺术中心上演 –海湾剧场，其中一场演出七次加演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在抵达新加坡之前，该剧自去年在深圳首演以来，已在中国巡演，在30多个城市上演了90多场演出。它广受好评，尤其受到年轻观众的欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新加坡，当观众聚集在剧院外观看演出的最后一晚时，有一种兴奋的感觉。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; 53 岁的唐·洛 (Don Low) 是一名大学美术讲师，他从朋友那里听说了这部作品，当时他和家人在一起，其中包括正在庆祝 83 岁生日的母亲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我的”妈妈练功夫已经有30年了，所以我想她会喜欢这个表演的。我们也借此机会赶上文化表演，因为我们已经有一段时间没有参加文化表演了。” ”Low 说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 29 岁的中国公民 Janna Pan 说，当她听说演出要在新加坡举行时，她立即购买了门票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这非常难”买票，因为这个剧团很有名。我非常高兴有机会亲自观看演出，”在建筑行业工作的潘说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该剧以 20 世纪 90 年代的电影为背景，讲述了中国功夫大师叶问的故事。该剧采用戏中戏的形式，围绕顶尖功夫大师之间的惊心动魄的对决展开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 它以五种中国武术为特色——咏春拳、太极拳、八卦掌、八极拳、螳螂拳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 剧中的打斗场面充满了情感，而咏春拳的情节和人物则以讲述普通人的故事和英雄们在追求正义和平等的过程中互相支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;欣快的反应&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新加坡的最后谢幕期间，人们的情绪是欣喜的，因为观众们欢呼雀跃，热烈鼓掌，并向演员们起立鼓掌。来自深圳歌剧院的年轻演员们舞蹈剧场同样热情，在演出结束后的签售会上向排起长队的观众致意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 演出导演表示，将咏春拳带到新加坡是一次难忘的经历。该剧由中国舞蹈艺术新星韩震、周莉亚执导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 韩震表示：“新加坡华人很多，所以我们感觉很亲近。新加坡观众对我们的欢迎方式也让我们深受感动。通过这部舞剧，我们希望人们能够更深入地了解中国伟大的传统文化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这是韩周首次合作制作以功夫为主的作品&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他们多次前往广东，参观纪念馆、参观功夫大师的作品，了解更多武术知识。故居。他们还与多位教练交谈，了解功夫的历史、传统和变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 周说，表演者在学习咏春拳的舞蹈动作之前都接受了严格的武术训练。考虑到制作的物理要求，这是一项具有挑战性的工作。选手们需要动作优雅、速度快、力量大，并以深厚的情感刻画人物角色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “中国古典舞的很多动作都来源于中国武术和戏曲。所以古典舞的发力方式和武术非常相似。我们还将现代舞和传统武术的动作融合在一起，为这个节目创造了独特的特色。”周说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 制作团队成员表示，他们希望明年能够进行世界巡演，其中包括访问欧洲。一月份，他们计划在香港上演咏春拳，并对为新加坡观众带来更多表演的前景感到兴奋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 功夫作为中国传统文化的内在象征，吸引了强烈的关注。受到世界各地追随者的追捧，他们被其不同的战斗风格、策略、哲学、道德和智慧所吸引。这些因素强调身心的平衡以及内心的平静。 The enduring popularity of kung fu can also be credited to movies starring Bruce Lee, Jackie Chan and Jet Li.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many martial arts schools and training institutions in Singapore offer a variety of courses and styles, attracting numerous students. In addition, martial arts performances and competitions are held regularly to provide opportunities for practitioners to compete and show their skills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nigel Lan, a wing chun enthusiast who went to see the show in Singapore, said it was interesting to see martial arts performed in a new context in which fusion was blended with contemporary dance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 38-year-old lawyer said young people are now more connected to culture than before.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;When I was growing up in the 1980s, China had still to fully open up. But today, young people are actively looking for ways to reconnect with their roots, be it through hanfu culture (wearing traditional Chinese clothing and accessories) or shows such as this. For me, practicing wing chun offers the chance to feel deeply connected to my Chinese roots,&amp;quot; Lan said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;Pivotal roles&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shows such as Wing Chun are pivotal in helping spread martial arts to a wider audience, including the younger generation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lin Deng Li, chairman of the Singapore-China Business Association&amp;#39;s culture and education committee, went to see Wing Chun in Singapore on Sept 30 with her 15-year-old grandson.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was the second time she had seen the show, having watched it on the first night at the invitation of the Chinese embassy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lin, a tireless champion of arts and culture for more than 30 years, has helped promote many cultural exchanges and programs between Singapore and China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I still want to watch the show again to deepen my knowledge and understanding,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Alongside Lin, her grandson Jaden Chng said: &amp;quot;I love watching the Ip Man films, and had heard many good things about Wing Chun. It was a very unexpected but interesting experience to see the show.&amp;quot; The Ip Man series of Hong Kong martial arts films are based on the life of a wing chun master of the same name.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Singapore and Shenzhen, who have a long-standing and close relationship, have launched bilateral measures such as the Singapore-China (Shenzhen) Smart City Initiative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Audience member Chi Shu Na said productions such as Wing Chun promote international cultural exchanges and bring Chinese culture to the international stage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She added that greater efforts, such as staging workshops, symposiums and lectures, should be made to organize cultural activities between Singapore and China to promote audience participation and deepen understanding.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Social media and other digital channels can also help attract audiences and raise the profile of such shows, Chi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She suggested that more exchanges take place between actors, directors, production teams and other artists from both countries to promote artistic innovation. Schools could also stage more such productions to enable students from Singapore and China to learn about each other&amp;#39;s culture and history,&amp;quot; Chi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Watching this beautiful audio and visual feast gave everyone a touching and beautiful sense of enjoyment. Truly, art has no borders,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lin Jialin, an assistant professor at Sun Yat-sen University&amp;#39;s School of Journalism and Communication in Guangzhou, capital of Guangdong, said the seven encores Wing Chun received in Singapore signifies the production&amp;#39;s immense popularity. Shenzhen&amp;#39;s efforts to promote cultural exchanges, which lie behind the show&amp;#39;s success, should also be credited, Lin added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Shenzhen&amp;#39;s cultural diversity, creative industries, cultural institutions and international exchanges have made the city a dynamic platform for cultural expression, innovation and cross-cultural dialogue. The success of Wing Chun lies in creative cultural expression, which is rooted in Shenzhen&amp;#39;s creative industries, including design, fashion, art and technology,&amp;quot; Lin said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The city&amp;#39;s thriving creative sector fosters innovation and artistic expression, contributing not only to the promotion and preservation of Chinese culture, but also to showcasing performers&amp;#39; work and artists&amp;#39; and creators&amp;#39; engagement with the public.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at wangxu@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Foreign firms set to invest more]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_003_652c5a0aed50d203d2ca094d.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/003/20231016_003_01_67.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;The 134th session of the China Import and Export Fair, or Canton Fair, opens in Guangzhou, Guangdong province, on Sunday. The autumn edition of the biannual event will be held in three phases in Guangzhou and will run through Nov 4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Heads of several multinational companies have said that they will continue to invest in China due to the country&amp;#39;s strategic importance in their global operations as Vice-Minister of Commerce Wang Shouwen reiterated that the Chinese government accords high attention to foreign-invested enterprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking at a seminar on foreign trade in Guangzhou, Guangdong province, Wang said on Sunday that the position of the Chinese government on expanding opening-up and attracting foreign investment remains unchanged, with the commitment to further increasing market access, protecting the property rights of foreign-invested enterprises and creating a sound business environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The seminar coincided with the 134th session of the China Import and Export Fair, or Canton Fair, which opened in Guangzhou on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Foreign-invested enterprises play an important role in the development of China&amp;#39;s foreign trade. The country will provide them with more opportunities in their effort to explore the Chinese market and expand foreign trade, with multiple comprehensive advantages including the vast market, well-established supply chain and clustered talent and technology, Wang added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking on the sidelines of the fair, Zhao Bingdi, president of Panasonic Corp China, said that Panasonic is committed to its development in China and has made new investments in 14 bases since 2020.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nearly 30 percent of Panasonic&amp;#39;s business in China is export-oriented, Zhao said, adding that China has a comprehensive industrial chain and that its advantage in R&amp;amp;D and innovation has become increasingly prominent in recent years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Panasonic hopes to further strengthen its R&amp;amp;D in China and anticipates greater development in the country, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao&amp;#39;s views were echoed by delegates attending the 35th International Business Leaders&amp;#39; Advisory Council for the Mayor of Shanghai on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Stefan Paul, CEO of global logistics giant Kuehne+Nagel International AG, said the company&amp;#39;s commitment to China remains &amp;quot;resolute&amp;quot;, which is evident in its most recent investments in two facilities that became operational in Chengdu, Sichuan province, in May.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The facilities, built for animal healthcare firm Elanco, comprise a 3,000-square-meter manufacturing warehouse and a 12,000-square-meter distribution center for finished products.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China has evolved into a leader in several transformative industries, including new mobility and renewable energy, presenting compelling opportunities for us to collaborate with industry leaders and export their technology and products worldwide. To facilitate this, we will continue investing in our people, technology and expertise within China, focusing on Shanghai,&amp;quot; said Paul, who is attending the event in Shanghai in person for the first time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Apart from its regional headquarters and three trading companies in Shanghai, United States agriculture and food company Cargill has built an innovation center, a shared service center, an oil seed crushing plant, three feed mills and a food technology company in the Yangtze River Delta region. According to Cargill&amp;#39;s executive chair of the board David MacLennan, each of these investments required confidence in the region&amp;#39;s industrial ecosystem and continued access to regional and global supply chains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China occupies a prominent position in Cargill&amp;#39;s global strategy. Cargill needs Shanghai to function as a highly efficient and rule-based hub connecting China to the world,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On top of that, multinational corporations in China depend on efficient industrial capabilities and reliable infrastructure, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Miguel Angel Lopez Borrego, CEO of German industrial giant Thyssenkrupp AG, said that China&amp;#39;s huge market and strong global impact inevitably influence multinational companies&amp;#39; decisions on industrial chain layout.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China has comprehensive upstream and downstream resources, a substantial pool of technological talent, an extremely powerful industrial chain and a resilient and flexible supply chain,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Shanghai municipal government, 940 multinational companies had set up their regional headquarters in the city as of the end of the third quarter, of which 49 were ventures launched this year. The number of foreign-funded regional R&amp;amp;D centers stands at 551.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Contact the writers at shijing@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Cultural bonds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_003_652c5a0ded50d203d2ca094e.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/003/20231016_003_02_50.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Foreign students learn to make jianbing, a type of Chinese crepe, on Saturday during their visit to a village in Linyi, Shandong province. More than 20 students from eight countries embarked on an enlightening journey to the village where they experienced traditional handicrafts and intangible cultural heritage projects, including movable-type printing and sachet-making.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - New survey ship to help enhance maritime safety]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_003_652c5a10ed50d203d2ca094f.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/003/20231016_003_03_104.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;Haixun 08, China&amp;#39;s most advanced vessel for ocean surveys, is commissioned on Sept 21 in Shanghai.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The deployment of Haixun 08, the largest and most advanced surveying ship in China&amp;#39;s maritime safety system, will extensively improve the country&amp;#39;s oceanographic research and its support capability for maritime industries, according to the ship&amp;#39;s chief designer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ye Hao from the Marine Design and Research Institute of China in Shanghai, a subsidiary of China State Shipbuilding Corp, said that Haixun 08 is mainly tasked with surveying underwater conditions and hydrological information along sea lanes. It is also capable of conducting scientific operations, emergency search and rescue missions as well as wreck location.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;If we wish to guarantee the smooth and safe operation of ships, we&amp;#39;d better know clearly about the natural conditions of sea lanes such as the depth of water, the ocean currents and the geological structures of the seabed,&amp;quot; Ye said on the sidelines of the four-day China Marine Equipment Expo 2023, which concluded on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The expo is one of the largest events of the nation&amp;#39;s marine and shipbuilding sectors. A total of 715 enterprises and research bodies took part in the expo, displaying more than 6,500 products and technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Until now, some small vessels were used for surveying sea lanes, but these are only able to operate in coastal waters, and many of them have become old, Ye said. &amp;quot;Considering the fact that our shipping companies operate worldwide, it was necessary to build a new, advanced vessel for survey work in distant oceans.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Haixun 08 is equipped with state-of-the-art measurement and positioning apparatus. It also features a strong data-processing capacity, which will allow researchers to analyze and use related information onboard the vessel rather than having to transmit data back to ground-based processing facilities like earlier, the chief engineer said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Marine Design and Research Institute of China, the ship is 123.6 meters long, 21.2 meters wide and has a displacement of more than 8,200 metric tons. Its maximum speed is 16 knots (30 kilometers per hour). It can operate in all oceans, except in the polar regions, and is capable of sailing more than 33,000 kilometers in a single voyage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Haixun 08 can accommodate up to 100 sailors and researchers and can independently work as long as 60 days, without needing to be refueled and resupplied.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Construction of the vessel started in December 2019 at Jiangnan Shipyard in Shanghai. The vessel&amp;#39;s main frame was completed in July 2022, and then it continued to be mounted with equipment and carried out several trial operations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ship was formally commissioned to the Shanghai-based Eastern Navigation Service Center of the Maritime Safety Administration on Sept 21.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhaolei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Education plays key role in trend of delaying marriage, childbirth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_003_652c5a12ed50d203d2ca0950.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; The age at which Chinese people get married or have children has increased steadily in the past 30 years, according to a new study.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Titled &amp;quot;Postponement of Marriage and Childbearing in China during 1990-2020: Trends and Characteristics&amp;quot;, the study analyzes the national census and sampling survey data to explain the trends of delayed marriage and childbirth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The study found that the nationwide average age for first marriage increased from 22.87 in 1990 to 28.67 in 2020. Although there were small dips along the way, there was a clear upward trend in both urban and rural areas to delay marriage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The rate of unmarried people also increased significantly in the past 30 years, the study found. In 1990, only 4.82 percent of Chinese people were unmarried at age 30. The rate increased to 21.75 percent in 2020.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The study, published in academic journal Population Research, was penned by Zhang Xianling, an associate professor at the School of Sociology and Psychology at Central University of Finance and Economics, and Sheng Yinan, a professor at the School of Labor and Economics at Capital University of Economics and Business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Education has been an important factor for young people delaying their marriage, according to the study. The more educated one is, the more likely one will delay getting married, it found.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As more women in rural areas received higher education, their prospect of marrying undereducated men became bleak, and it was more likely for them to stay unmarried for their whole life, the study showed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Almost 20 percent of men with only primary school education were unmarried at age 40 in 2020, up by 8 percent since 1990, Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With more rural women going to cities to receive education and find work, it is easier for them to find men with more financial means, she said, adding that this is a key reason for many undereducated men in rural areas not finding a suitable partner.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In many places, the practice of a man offering betrothal money to his prospective bride continues, so it is difficult for a man with low financial means to find a suitable wife, Zhang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;With urbanization continuing and more women receiving better education, we predict the trend will continue, and it will be even harder for a man with low education and inadequate financial means to find a wife,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is important for men to receive more education, work harder and improve their financial status, while the social practice of betrothal gifts should also stop, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the study, women in China prefer having children after getting married, which is by default increasing the age at which they have children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The average childbearing age of women increased to 29 in 2020 from 26 in 1990. The trend was more common among urban women, whose average childbearing age in 2020 was 30.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Tingting, 31, from Changsha in Hunan province, got married two years ago. She said that she and her husband have decided to improve their own lives further before having a child.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Having a baby now will be a tough challenge for us. We both have very busy professional lives and will hardly have time to look after the baby. Besides, the cost of raising a child is high,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Ministry of Civil Affairs, around 6.83 million couples had registered for marriage last year, which was a new low in nine years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A survey conducted by Zhenai.com, a popular matchmaking website, found that more than 60 percent of the surveyed women in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, support getting married and having children late, and they consider 31 to be the ideal age for marriage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than 60 percent of the women were also single, and they said they had not been in a relationship for almost two years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang, the associate professor, said that many young people consider both marriage and having children optional. The rising cost of living and the prospect of having to raise children amid increasing economic pressures act as major deterrents, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zoushuo@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Beijing bolsters mediation efforts, seeks lasting peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/16/content_003_652c5a12ed50d203d2ca0951.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-16/003/20231016_001_04_162.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;A police officer carries an injured child to a hospital on Saturday as search and rescue operations continued around buildings that were destroyed or damaged by Israeli attacks in Gaza.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Throughout the past week, Beijing has been working on intensive mediation of the Palestine-Israel conflict with major relevant players, including the United States and Saudi Arabia, to seek an early cease-fire and avert a major humanitarian disaster.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With an envoy from Beijing poised to embark on a mediation trip to the Middle East soon, China is faithfully fulfilling its constructive role as a responsible major country in a trustworthy and pragmatic way, observers said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhai Jun, the Chinese government&amp;#39;s special envoy on the Middle East issue, said on Sunday that this week he will &amp;quot;visit some of the countries concerned in the Middle East to further strengthen coordination among various parties&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The direction of our work is to seek a cease-fire, protect civilians, de-escalate the situation and promote peace talks,&amp;quot; he said, warning that the conflict &amp;quot;is now expanding at an accelerated pace&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When asked about the safety of Chinese citizens amid the conflict, Zhai confirmed that four Chinese citizens had been killed, two were still missing and six others who were injured were being treated at local hospitals.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Palestine-Israel conflict stood out as a primary topic of Foreign Minister Wang Yi&amp;#39;s phone conversations on Saturday with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the phone conversation with Blinken, Wang emphasized that &amp;quot;major countries should remain objective, fair and calm, exercise restraint, and take the lead in abiding by international law&amp;quot; when dealing with international or regional hot spot issues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fundamental solution to the Palestinian question relies on the implementation of the two-state solution, the establishment of an independent Palestinian state and the realization of peaceful coexistence between Palestine and Israel, said Wang, who is also a member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Blinken said the US supports the &amp;quot;two-state solution&amp;quot; and is willing to strengthen communication and coordination with China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In phone talks with Prince Faisal bin Farhan, Wang said all parties should refrain from escalating the situation and should return to the negotiation table as soon as possible, and China &amp;quot;is communicating intensively with various parties to seek a cease-fire&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said it is imperative to &amp;quot;make every effort to ensure the safety of the civilians, to establish humanitarian access as soon as possible and to secure the basic needs of the people in Gaza&amp;quot;, according to a statement on Sunday by the Foreign Ministry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Saudi foreign minister said that China &amp;quot;plays an important and fundamental role in promoting world peace and stability&amp;quot;, and Riyadh is ready to work with Beijing to make sure that various parties comply with international humanitarian law and fulfill the relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions on the Palestinian question.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On Sunday, Wang also spoke by phone with Iranian Foreign Minister Hossein Amir-Abdollahian, saying that Islamic countries should boost unity over the Palestinian question and speak with one voice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While meeting with European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Josep Borrell on Friday in Beijing and talking by phone with Chief Advisor of the Presidency of Brazil Celso Luiz Nunes Amorim on Thursday, Wang urged the global community to formulate a consensus based on the &amp;quot;two-state solution&amp;quot; at an early date.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Analysts noted that Beijing&amp;#39;s mediation efforts illustrate the nation&amp;#39;s respect for the &amp;quot;two-state solution&amp;quot;, which has been recognized by the global community and in UN Security Council resolutions, and its peacemaking philosophy aims to take care of the interests of various parties in a balanced and pragmatic way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;While some parties or countries in the world are more focused on the complexity of the whole issue, what Beijing believes is that some progress and outcomes surely will be made with consistent efforts for advancing toward a reasonable goal,&amp;quot; said Su Xiaohui, an associate researcher at the China Institute of International Studies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Beijing&amp;#39;s role in mediation should not be overlooked when examining the booming drive of reconciliation in the Arab world earlier this year, she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;China&amp;#39;s push for rapprochement between Iran and Saudi Arabia is good evidence supporting the fact that a thorny issue could be eventually resolved if parties involved could move toward the same goal and create a benign, coolheaded atmosphere despite the enormous complexity of the contradictions,&amp;quot; Su said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Niu Xinchun, director of the China Institutes of Contemporary International Relations&amp;#39; Institute of Middle East Studies, warned that as the conflict expands, there is a possibility that it could spill over to areas outside the Gaza region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;If the conflict expands into Lebanon or Syria, the volatility in the Middle East would be aggravated dramatically, creating a new dilemma for peace in the Middle East,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:52:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>