<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>中国日报</title><description>中国日报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Pivotal role of women hailed at congress]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0e4ed50d203d2ca11fc.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 周一，中国女性因其“关键角色”而受到赞扬。表彰他们在扶贫、科技创新等广泛领域的表现，以及他们在抗击COVID-19大流行中的英勇精神，并敦促他们进一步投身于中国的现代化事业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这一信息是中国共产党中央委员会在北京举行的第十三届全国妇女代表大会开幕式上传达的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国家主席、同时也是全国妇女代表大会总书记的习近平中共中央政治局委员、中央军委主席李强、赵乐际、王沪宁、蔡奇、李希等党和国家领导人等约1800名代表致贺电。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 中共中央政治局常委丁薛祥代表中共中央在大会上讲话时表示，中国妇女必须以更强的历史自觉、更加坚强的历史意识，同党紧密团结、同向前进。更加积极的态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还指出了女性在家庭和社区中的积极作用、她们对维护法律和秩序的奉献精神以及她们在体育舞台上的出色表现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “妇女的社会主体作用得到充分彰显，妇女发展全面进步”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 丁恳切要求各级妇联始终坚持党的全面领导，主动服务国家大计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 代表和维护妇女权益，促进性别平等，保障妇女全面发展，是妇联组织的根本职能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 各组织要加强法律保障要把妇女儿童权益贯穿于整个人民民主制度之中，把维权工作常态化，定期深入基层走访检查，发现问题、反映问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 山东省代表何培英表示，习近平和丁的讲话体现了党的最高领导层对赋予妇女权力和保护妇女权利的重视。&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>; “我一直相信女性可以在任何工作中表现出色。我们需要全社会相信这一点，并进一步赋予妇女权力。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她表示，这次大会将为各级加强对妇女儿童权利的保护、促进性别平等提供契机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国妇女代表大会每五年召开一次，是中国各级妇女联合会的最高权力机关。据中华全国妇女联合会统计，全国有68.5万个妇女联合会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;xuwei@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - High-tech radar to help in fight against relic crimes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0e7ed50d203d2ca11fd.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 一种常用于航空航天和国防工业的高科技雷达系统有朝一日可以帮助中国保护其文物免受犯罪分子，特别是盗墓者的侵害。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 研究人员陕西省正在探索使用相控阵雷达的可行性，该雷达能够大范围监视和跟踪移动目标，防止户外文物被盗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 雷达不仅能够保持实时- 24/7全天候对目标进行时间标签，还可以触发对可疑人员、车辆或活动的精确警报，以便更有效地打击文物犯罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陕西，被认为是重要的发源地对于中华文明来说，拥有无法移入博物馆保管的无价历史文物。其中包括古建筑、墓葬、石窟寺、石刻等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 据陕西省文物局介绍，全省共有不可移动文物49058处，其中国家级重点文物保护单位270处。由于其分布广泛，有时覆盖面积较大，其保护和管理非常困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 例如，始建于公元684年的乾陵，占地230万平方米。该遗址包括唐朝第三位统治者高宗皇帝（618-907 年）和中国历史上唯一的女皇帝武则天的联合陵墓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 其他一些遗迹群也具有复杂性&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 韩建武表示，与之前用于保护这些遗迹的视频监控或地动监测技术相比，相控阵雷达更加灵活可靠。陕西省文物保护研究院副院长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 雷达抗干扰能力更强，对复杂环境的适应能力更强。负责该研究项目的韩说，它的功能不受雨、雪或光线的影响，有助于防止夜间盗窃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “该设备可以检测一定范围内的车辆。” 10公里范围内，5公里范围内人员，可以低成本实现大规模监控。”他说。而且，它可以同时捕捉和跟踪128组目标，并提供它们的距离、速度、角度、类别和轨迹。所有这些都减少了遗漏监控区域可疑活动的机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 高效雷达可以搜索 10 公里范围内的目标，并在几秒钟内向左或向右平移 45 度，从而使快速检测并报告人类活动。韩说，它还可以检测监控区域内缓慢移动的个体，最小检测速度为每秒0.3米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凭借紧凑的电池板和小型存储设备，雷达可以24小时工作全年每天 7 小时、每周 7 天。由于它没有机械扫描组件，因此在现场部署时需要零维护。这些功能都有助于推动该设备在基层的使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 韩说，该雷达经过多次实验证明了可行性，并补充说，研究团队正在进行更多的测试，以确保更加确定。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “未来，相控阵雷达安防系统将能够补充现有安防技术，提供主动、智能的预警功能，进一步提高打击文物犯罪的有效性。” ; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 陕西省政府承诺，通过采用新的安全技术，在警方和社会的共同努力下，加强文物保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据2022年5月的新闻发布会显示，国家和省级重点文物保护单位数量持续减少，2020年和2021年没有发生此类犯罪案件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;chenmeiling@chinadaily.com.cn&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Off to good start]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0eaed50d203d2ca11fe.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-24/001/20231024_001_03_114.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;桨手谢茂三展示她的周一，在浙江省杭州市举行的第四届亚洲残疾人运动会上，她在女子 KL1 皮划艇比赛中获得金牌。谢勇获得了亚洲残疾人运动会的首枚金牌。参见故事，第 4 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Xi: Step up building of skilled, innovative workforce]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0eded50d203d2ca11ff.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 习近平主席周一强调，要大力建设知识技能型创新型劳动队伍，服务国家高质量发展，同时强调共产党的重要性中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在同中共中央军委新一届领导集体谈话时指出中华全国总工会是地方总工会和国家总工会的领导机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平表示，中国的工人运动是在总工会的领导下发展起来的。党、工会是党领导下的工人阶级组成的群众组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他强调，要坚持党对工会的全面领导。任何时候、任何情况下，都要坚持全心全意依靠工人阶级的根本原则，充分调动广大劳动人民的积极性、主动性、创造性，习近平强调，要积极投身建设强国、实现民族复兴的伟大事业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他强调，要在工会系统贯彻落实党中央决策部署，紧密团结在党的周围，为实现党的中心任务而奋斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 习近平要求，开展形式多样的劳动竞赛和技能竞赛，激发广大劳动者的积极性。职工的积极性和创造性。要大力弘扬劳模精神、工匠精神，激励广大职工通过艰苦奋斗、诚实劳动、创新劳动实现梦想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他还强调，要着力深化体制改革加强产业劳动力队伍建设，加快建设知识型、技能型、创新型产业工人队伍，培养更多工匠和高技能职业工人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 随着工人阶级和广大劳动群众习近平指出，推动共同富裕的重大成就首先要体现在全国亿万劳动者身上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 工会是工人阶级的代表和维护者他说，要切实履行维护职工权益、解决事关职工切身利益的实际问题的基本责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 新一届中华全国总工会领导班子联合会第十八次全国代表大会于10月12日在北京闭幕。王东明当选为该组织主席。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;caodesheng@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Peace at heart]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0f0ed50d203d2ca1200.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-24/001/20231024_001_05_61.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;男孩坐在一颗心上周日，加沙地带南部城市汗尤尼斯的一个形状装置。他们身后是被以色列空袭摧毁的建筑物。周一，第三批救援卡车从埃及通过拉法过境点进入被围困的巴勒斯坦领土。查看更多内容，第 8、9、10 页&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - Beijing, Tokyo vow to relive spirit of landmark treaty]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0f3ed50d203d2ca1201.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; 作为具有里程碑意义的《中日和平友好条约》缔结45周年庆祝活动的高潮，双方领导人承诺重温条约精神并展望未来发展&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国务院总理李强和日本首相岸田文雄周一互致贺电，庆祝条约签署45周年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李克强在贺电中表示，北京和#39愿与日方共同“牢牢把握两国发展正确方向”关系”致力于建设适应新时代要求的中日关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1978年8月，两国领导人作出战略决策，签署了该条约，这是四大里程碑式双边条约之一1972年中日邦交正常化以来签署的政治文件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该条约以法律议定书的形式，确定了两国关系和平共处、友好相处的大方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 李克强在周一发给东京的电报中称该条约是“两国关系发展进程中的一个重要里程碑”两国”并表示中方愿与日方共同努力，“重温条约精神”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总理表示，过去45年来中日关系的发展“来之不易”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 他表示，两国关系取得的进展“增进了两国人民的福祉，为地区和世界的和平、稳定与繁荣作出了积极贡献”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>; 岸田表示，“日方愿与中方重温条约精神，努力推动日中关系取得更大发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 日本首相表示，这一点很重要双方共同努力构建建设性、稳定的日中关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “日中两国对地区和世界的和平与繁荣负有重要责任，在国际事务中具有合作潜力”广泛的领域，”日本外务大臣上川洋子周一在东京举行的纪念招待会上发表讲话时指出，日本和中国面临着许多挑战，“我们必须重申我们的决心，进一步发展我们的愿望” ”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“重要的是要将这些愿望传递给对日本和中国的未来负责的下一代，并确保这一点条约将永远保持其光彩。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 王毅外长与上川外长当天也互致贺电。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 双方互致贺电“传递了坚持中美关系的重要积极信息”外交部发言人毛宁表示：“中日和平、友好、合作”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 条约的核心内容，如互不干涉内政、 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 观察人士表示，当前中日关系正处于改善发展的关键阶段，面临诸多风险挑战，双方要切实维护好两国关系的政治基础。中日友好协会常务副会长、中国前驻日本大使程永华表示，中日关系近期，日本频频发出战略封锁中国、经济“脱钩”的负面信号，令日本经济受到打击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “东京不应该忘记自己的条约义务，需要重新思考两国关系在日本的发展中扮演的角色”。外交战略。发展经济、改善民生是中日两国特别是后疫情时代的共同任务。”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 日本目前是中国第五大贸易伙伴，中国是日本第一大贸易伙伴、出口目的地和进口来源地。据商务部统计，去年双边贸易额为 3574.24 亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 约 61.5% 的中国受访者和 53.1% 的日本受访者认可人文交流对改善双边关系的重要性，据中国外文局和日本智库Genron NPO最近的一项调查显示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhangyunbi@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[001FRONT - NANNIES OPT TO GO BACK TO THE CLASSROOM]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_001_6536d0f6ed50d203d2ca1202.htm#001FRONT]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-24/001/20231024_002_02_46.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;徐怡媛在上海做了15年的保姆，照顾新生儿、幼儿和新妈妈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她最近开始上网课——以及尽可能离线的——攻读学士学位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年42岁的江苏连云港人，是上海开放大学第五批家政专业的学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;与所有其他职业一样，更好的教育背景通常可以帮助毕业生获得更有价值的职业机会。客户的对管家的总体需求，特别是与儿童教育相关的需求，正在增加。”徐说，并补充说她想“更进一步”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我高中时学习成绩优异，但因为家庭经济状况没有上大学。现在，我的大学梦终于实现了。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2019年中央发文从质和量上支持家政行业发展后，上海大学成为国内首家开设本科专业的高等院校。 2021 年 3 月开设该学科的 39;s 学位课程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 第一批 95 名毕业生完成了五个学期的学习，于 7 月从大学毕业。上海是家政服务标准最高的城市之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海开放大学公共管理学院院长陆奇表示：“家政管理是一个被误解的职业”许久。我们的目标不是培养大学生成为保姆，而是培养保姆成为大学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “上海家政行业从业人员有75万人，但市场对保姆的需求很大。”能够提供高质量服务的员工，特别是担任管家和“成长伙伴”角色的员工；对于儿童和外籍家庭来说，” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 该项目负责人杨婉玲表示，高等教育让学习者改变思维方式，这是短期教学无法实现的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学习者只有通过系统、整体的学术学习，才能在日常工作中找到发现问题、思考原因、寻求解决方案的新方法。这种变化比手工技能更有价值。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 上海市家庭服务行业协会的数据显示，2015年，全市有35%的家庭需要家庭服务人员，去年这一比例上升至53%。该协会预测，到2025年，家政服务市场规模将达到600亿元人民币（82.3亿美元）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国家庭服务行业协会会长王淑霞表示，家政服务出现新发展近年来在很多方面。这些进步的原因包括人口老龄化、父母越来越追求改善孩子的教育以及人们渴望过上更好的生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 家政服务不仅仅是清洁和烹饪——还包括清洁和烹饪。过去流行的一种信仰。王说，受益者包括新生儿、幼儿、学生、年轻夫妇、老年人和残疾人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “它已成为一个更加多元化的行业，涵盖家庭教育、家政、营养餐饮、婴幼儿智力开发。行业活力进一步增强。”她补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐的工作经历支持王的评论。徐先是在上海一家家政服务机构接受月嫂培训。后来，她参加了婴儿食品制作、幼儿认知发展和幼儿早期教育课程。徐随后决定成为一名幼儿保姆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我什至学会了开车，成为我们家里第一个这样做的成员，”徐说，并补充说，开车使她能够找到需要开车送孩子上学的工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但她认为，学士学位对于寻找“成长伙伴”的客户来说更具影响力。 ;帮助孩子在幼儿园和小学学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 因此，她报名了大学项目，学生每人支付 2,000 多元人民币（273 美元）的费用五个学期的时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杨老师说：“学生们表现出很高的学习热情，总是主动学习。他们对提高整体能力有非常明确的目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我们老师强烈地感觉到我们也在向学生学习。他们经常和我们讨论自己的观察、感受、想法以及工作中遇到的最新困难。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 杨说，学生分为三类。一半以上是一线家政服务人员，其余为家政服务机构的管理人员和关心家庭生活质量的人士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 学生年龄层以40至45岁为主，其中两三分之一的人高中毕业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 与上海开放大学2014年推出的家政专业更注重技能相比，学士学位课程更注重知识，杨&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “例如，工人们需要做的不仅仅是做出看起来吸引人、闻起来香、味道鲜美的菜肴。”学士学位的学习使他们能够获得营养和健康管理方面的知识，从而更好地搭配食材，为不同的人准备更好的饮食。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 提供普通、基础和专业课程。家政机构管理人员的学生通常学习现代服务科学发展、家政管理企业运作、人力资源等课程。一线家政工寻求更好的职业发展，参加了家庭健康管理、家庭美学、消费指导等课程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 课程分为线下和线上两种。学生需要完成70多个学时的学习，并在两年半内通过不同课程的理论和实践考试，并完成毕业论文才能毕业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 徐说，她对这门课程印象深刻沟通与礼仪课程中以非暴力沟通为主题的课程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她说，她曾经与一位客户发生争执。 “那天我很努力照顾客户的孩子，所以当她问我一些事情时，我就直接回答了她。客户告诉我，我经常通过反问来回答她，但我没有意识到这一点，” ”徐说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在课堂上，我的老师举了很多涉及辱骂性语言的对话例子。这对我改变说话方式有很大帮助，我现在会尝试更礼貌地说话。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;更有信心&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhu 47岁的春楠在上海做了15年多的管家，今年夏天本科毕业。她说，增强自信是学习最大的收获。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 朱女士是安徽人，她说自己以前有一种自卑感，但读完学位后，她开始审视自己。以及她的工作从不同的角度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我现在更加确信，我的报酬是因为我在这个领域的辛勤工作和专业知识。”我越来越强烈地意识到我与我的客户享有平等的地位。”朱说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “这些课程也让我更有信心选择为之工作的客户，而不是等待被选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 这种增强的信心也让朱能够更好地表达自己并解释她的工作方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我现在能够给出搭配食物成分的原因以及家居整理背后的逻辑。我更有信心向客户提出建议，我的建议也更容易被接受。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 一名35岁的孙姓学生表示，关于家庭生命周期的课程让她深受感动。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; “中国人没有接受太多关于婚姻、家庭生活以及家庭成员之间的联系和亲密的教育。我的课程让我花一些时间思考家人对我的支持和爱。当我完成课程后，我更加感激我的丈夫。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 孙现在是一名销售员，一年前当了妈妈。她报名参加这个项目是出于个人兴趣，为了给家人提供更好的照顾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 来自家政机构的信息显示，越来越多的年轻人加入到家政服务行业，其中40岁到40岁的年轻人比例越来越高。 55岁年龄段下降。后者群体历来是行业的主导力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 国内日常生活服务平台58同城的数据显示，通过该平台经营家政服务机构的企业家平均年龄下降与 2021 年相比，今年增长了 15%。1995 年及之后出生的人已成为该领域创业的主力军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 尽管许多行业面临经济挑战，但现在管家的薪酬更高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海爱君家政服务机构经理殷紫紫表示，“刚从事照顾新生儿和新妈妈工作的保姆，在大城市，月薪过万，轻松赚到三成”。至六个月” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “有良好工作经验和信誉的保姆月薪至少2万元。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhouwenting@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/跨度>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - Teacher benefits from career switch to maternity matron and nanny]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_002_6536d0f9ed50d203d2ca1203.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-24/002/20231024_002_01_56.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;王玉兰，35 岁，一名教师转型为家政员和培训师&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我本科专业是汉语言文学，研究生专业是汉语教学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我梦想以学校教师为职业。一辈子，但我只在家乡山东省青岛市的一所中学当了18个月的老师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 学校对孩子的评价与我的价值观不同，更重要的是工资很低。 2013年，我每月收入4000元人民币（549美元），付完公寓抵押贷款后，几乎所剩无几。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 然后我了解到了月嫂这个职业，这个职业的薪水相当高。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 职场新人只需要去妇产保健中心看看经验丰富的工作人员是如何照顾新生儿的。与保姆必须具备照顾婴儿和幼儿的一整套技能不同，月嫂可以很快掌握工作所需的技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在我作为月嫂的第一份工作中，我月入8000元——低于这项工作的平均工资，因为客户不需要我晚上照顾孩子。不过，薪水还是令人满意的，我不再面临经济压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 在为不同的新手父母工作了一年后，我开始思考自己的职业前景。我决定成为一名保姆，因为这个工作主要围绕儿童心理、儿童识别、幼儿教育等不同学校进行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 从事这个行业多年，我发现这个行业仍然缺乏系统的规定和规范。工人们的标准各不相同，许多人根据自己的日常生活经验和习惯提供家政服务。 2021年，我决定成为上海家政服务机构Shine Services的一名培训师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 家政是一项特殊的工作，因为它与客户的个人和家庭生活密切相关。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 培训从第一次到达客户家时如何迎接客户、为孩子准备食物以及如何分享客户的想法开始。在欢乐和悲伤的时刻，与他们保持一定的距离，尊重他们的隐私。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 客户尊重我们，因为我们提供照顾婴儿的专业知识和技能。然而，有些保姆日夜呆在客户家里感到不舒服。除了身体上的疲劳，他们还感到精神上的压力，所以我们经常告诉他们，这份工作需要很高的情商，类似于处理亲密的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 多年来，政策覆盖了整个行业更加完善，大公司带头建立专业标准，社会对这个职业的认可度也越来越高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 我对自己的工作有很强的认可度，期待在这个行业工作一段时间。很长一段时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王玉兰正在与周文婷交谈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[002PAGE TWO - NANNIES OPT TO GO BACK TO THE CLASSROOM]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_002_6536d0f9ed50d203d2ca1204.htm#002PAGE TWO]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-24/002/20231024_002_02_46.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;徐怡媛在上海做了15年的保姆，照顾新生儿、幼儿和新妈妈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 她最近开始上网课——以及尽可能离线的——攻读学士学位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 今年42岁的江苏连云港人，是上海开放大学第五批家政专业的学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;与所有其他职业一样，更好的教育背景通常可以帮助毕业生获得更有价值的职业机会。客户的对管家的总体需求，特别是与儿童教育相关的需求，正在增加。”徐说，并补充说她想“更进一步”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “我高中时学习成绩优异，但因为家庭经济状况没有上大学。现在，我的大学梦终于实现了。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2019年中央发文从质和量上支持家政行业发展后，上海大学成为国内首家开设本科专业的高等院校。 39;s degree program in the discipline in March 2021.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first cohort of 95 graduates, who completed five semesters of study, graduated from the university in July. Shanghai is among those cities with the highest standards for housekeeping services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lu Qi, dean of Shanghai Open University&amp;#39;s School of Public Administration, said: &amp;quot;Household management is a profession that has been misunderstood for a long time. Our goal is not to cultivate college students to become nannies, but to cultivate nannies to become college students.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Some 750,000 people work in the household service industry in Shanghai, but there is a significant market need for workers who can provide high-quality service, especially in the roles of stewards and &amp;#39;growth partners&amp;#39; for children, and in expatriate families,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Wanling, who is in charge of the program, said higher education empowers learners to change their ways of thinking, which cannot be achieved through short-term instruction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Only through systematic and holistic academic study can learners develop a new approach to discover problems, think about reasons, and seek solutions in their everyday work. Such changes are more valuable than manual skills,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data from the Shanghai Home Service Industry Association show that 35 percent of the city&amp;#39;s families required home service workers in 2015, and the proportion rose to 53 percent last year. The association has forecast that the scale of the home service market will reach 60 billion yuan ($8.23 billion) in 2025.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Shuxia, chairwoman of the China Family Service Industry Association, said domestic services have witnessed new developments in many respects in recent years. The reasons for these advances include an aging population, parents increasingly pursuing improved education for their children, and people&amp;#39;s desire to lead better lives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Domestic service is not only about cleaning and cooking &amp;mdash; a popular belief in the past. Those benefiting from such service include newborns, toddlers, students, young couples, the elderly and the physically challenged, Wang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It has become a more diversified industry, covering family education, household management, nutritional catering, and the intellectual development of infants and young children. The industry&amp;#39;s vitality has been further enhanced,&amp;quot; she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xu&amp;#39;s work experience supports Wang&amp;#39;s comments. Xu first trained as a maternity matron at a housekeeping service agency in Shanghai. Later, she took classes in making food for infants, cognitive development in young children, and early education for toddlers. Xu then decided to become a nanny for young children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I even learned to drive, becoming the first member of my family to do so,&amp;quot; Xu said, adding that driving enables her to obtain work that involves taking children to school by car.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But she thought that a bachelor&amp;#39;s degree would hold more sway with clients looking for &amp;quot;growth partners&amp;quot; to help with their children&amp;#39;s studies at kindergarten and primary school.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a result, she signed up for the university program, for which students pay fees of more than 2,000 yuan ($273) for each of the five semesters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang said: &amp;quot;The students appear to have a high level of enthusiasm for learning, and they always take the initiative to learn. They have very clear goals for improving their overall abilities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;We teachers feel strongly that we&amp;#39;re also learning from the students. They often discuss with us their observations, feelings, thoughts and the latest difficulties with their work.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang said there are three types of students. More than half are frontline domestic service workers, and the remainder comprise managers of housekeeping service agencies and those interested in the quality of family life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most of the students are in the 40 to 45 age group, and two out of three graduated from senior high schools.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared with the household management program launched by Shanghai Open University in 2014, which focuses more on skills, the bachelor&amp;#39;s degree program centers more on knowledge, Yang said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;For example, workers need to do more than just cook dishes that look appealing, smell good, and taste delicious. The bachelor&amp;#39;s degree studies enable them to acquire knowledge of nutrition and health management, so that they will better mix and match ingredients and prepare better diets for different people,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; General, basic and professional courses are on offer. Students who are managers at housekeeping agencies usually take classes that include the development of modern service science, the operations of domestic management enterprises, and human resources. Front-line domestic workers seeking better career development take classes that include family health management, family aesthetics, and consumption guidance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Courses are given offline and online. To graduate, students need to complete more than 70 learning hours and pass theoretical and hands-on exams for different classes, along with a graduation thesis within two and a half years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xu said she was highly impressed by a lesson themed on nonviolent communication during a course on communication and etiquette.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She said she once had a dispute with a client. &amp;quot;I worked hard taking care of the client&amp;#39;s baby that day, so when she asked me about something, I gave her a straightforward answer. The client told me I often answered her by posing rhetorical questions, but I didn&amp;#39;t realize this,&amp;quot; Xu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;In class, my teacher cited many examples of dialogue involving abusive language. This helped me a lot to change the way in which I talked, and I will now try to speak more politely.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;b>;More confidence&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhu Chunnan, 47, who has worked as a housekeeper in Shanghai for more than 15 years, graduated from the bachelor&amp;#39;s degree program this summer. She said that boosting her confidence was the biggest gain from her studies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A native of Anhui province, Zhu said she used to have a sense of inferiority, but after taking the degree program, she began to view herself and her work in a different light.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m now more convinced that I&amp;#39;m being paid for my hard work and professional knowledge in this field. I have an increasingly strong sense that I have equal status to my clients,&amp;quot; Zhu said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The lessons also gave me more confidence in choosing clients to work for, rather than waiting to be selected.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This increased confidence also allows Zhu to better express herself and explain the way in which she works.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m now able to give the reasons for matching food ingredients, and the logic behind home organizing. I&amp;#39;m more confident about making suggestions to clients, and my suggestions are better accepted,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A 35-year-old student taking the degree program, who only wanted to be named as Sun, said she was deeply moved by a class about a family&amp;#39;s life cycle.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Chinese people do not receive that much education about marriage, family life and connections and intimacy between family members. My class allowed me to spend some time thinking about the support and love I have from my family. When I completed the course, I became more grateful to my husband,&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun, who now works as a salesperson, became a mother a year ago. She signed up for the program out of personal interest to provide better care for her family.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Information from housekeeping agencies shows that more young people are joining the home service industry, with the proportion of those in the 40 to 55 age group falling. The latter group of workers has traditionally been the dominant force in the industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data from 58.com, a domestic daily life service platform, show that the average age of entrepreneurs operating home service agencies with the platform fell by 15 percent this year compared with 2021. Those born in and after 1995 have become the major force launching startups in this field.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Housekeepers are now better paid, despite the economic challenges that many industries face.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yin Zizi, a manager at Shanghai Aijun Home Service Agency, said, &amp;quot;A nanny new to the job of taking care of newborns and new mothers can easily earn more than 10,000 yuan a month in big cities after gaining three to six months&amp;#39; work experience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;Nannies with a good working experience and reputation can earn at least 20,000 yuan a month.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;zhouwenting@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Archaeologists call for deeper intl cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_003_6536d0fced50d203d2ca1205.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Amid calls for deeper international cooperation in the field of archaeology and contribution toward building a community with a shared future for mankind, the 4th Chinese Archaeology Congress began in Xi&amp;#39;an, Shaanxi province, on Monday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three-day event is jointly organized by the Society for Chinese Archaeology, the Institute of Archaeology at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, Shaanxi Provincial Cultural Heritage Administration and the city-level government of Xi&amp;#39;an.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The biennial event, one of the highest-level academic forums for archaeological studies in China, is being attended by more than 800 professionals from 31 provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region and Taiwan, and nine foreign countries including Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy and Japan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The theme for the congress this year is &amp;quot;The formation and development of a unified multiethnic country&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Xingcan, director of the Institute of Archaeology, CASS, said that since the last congress held in 2021, China&amp;#39;s archaeological community has further researched the importance of archaeological studies in the development of the country, continued to explore and make innovations, and achieved remarkable progress.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen said that programs on important academic issues are held regularly; the pace of international cooperation in archaeology has become more determined; archaeometry and underwater archaeology are developing rapidly; and a number of archaeological programs are being broadcast, expanding the influence of achievements.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These efforts have been injecting spiritual strength into the construction of a modern Chinese civilization, he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The congress this year includes 27 professional committees, which will together submit 564 reports in 27 parallel sessions focusing on different historical periods and different fields of archaeological studies, such as underwater archaeology, environment science archaeology and archaeometry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Four new committees have been introduced this year. The committees are on archaeological heritage, archaeological studies on tombs, the Great Wall and the Grand Canal, respectively, reflecting deepening of the research content, said Chen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;The congress has been successfully held three times, each focusing on a major academic issue. It serves as a platform for communication between archaeologists at home and abroad,&amp;quot; said Chen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;It has showcased the latest discoveries and research progress of Chinese archaeological studies, and enhanced the comparative studies on ancient civilizations of different regions across the world,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Miyamoto Kazuo, a professor at Kyushu University in Fukuoka, Japan, said the studies on Chinese civilization is important for other East Asian countries as well.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;East Asian countries such as Japan and the Republic of Korea were strongly influenced by Chinese civilization. The nations were born in the process of communications with China, with different history and backgrounds. Therefore, the exploration of Chinese civilization is not only important for China, but also for the entire East Asia,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Qun, director of the National Cultural Heritage Administration, highlighted the importance of international cooperation in archaeology. &amp;quot;Efforts should be made to promote open cooperation in archaeology. ... We should cooperate with overseas high-level research institutions to tackle problems, focus on international academic trends, advance joint archaeological efforts related to the Belt and Road Initiative, and promote high-quality development of research on ancient civilizations worldwide,&amp;quot; said Li.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp;quot;By facilitating cultural exchanges based on mutual respect and mutual learning, we can contribute Chinese wisdom and strength to the building of a community with a shared future for mankind,&amp;quot; he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following the opening ceremony, six scholars were invited to make keynote speeches introducing some latest archaeological discoveries in China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gao Jiangtao, a researcher with the Institute of Archaeology, elaborated on new findings of 4,000-year-old Taosi sites in Xiangfen county, Shanxi province.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said the excavation on the No 1 palace foundation of Taosi, which was being carried out from 2018, unveiled the largest known prehistoric single rammed earth architectural foundation, which covers 6,500 square meters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As part of the event, 27 public lectures have also been organized, so that people can take part in this academic and cultural feast, said Guan Qiang, deputy director of the National Cultural Heritage Administration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;wangru1@chinadaily.com.cn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[003TOP NEWS - Pomp and glory]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/html5/2023-10/24/content_003_6536d0ffed50d203d2ca1206.htm#003TOP NEWS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mobile.chinadaily.com.cn/cn/resfile/2023-10-24/003/20231024_003_02_30.png&quot; />;&lt;p>;People participate in a grand ceremony in Jinyun, Zhejiang province, on Monday to commemorate the Yellow Emperor, a legendary figure who is widely regarded as the ancestor of Chinese people. The annual event was marked by traditional music and dance, and ancient rituals including a symbolic sacrifice and offerings to show respect to the emperor.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:21:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>