<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[九日黄楼作 | 苏轼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231031]]><description> &lt;h2>;Nine Days in Huang Lou Zuo&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Su Shi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Last year during the Double Ninth Festival, it was unspeakable that thousands of people were dying in the middle of the night in Nancheng. &lt;br />;The water penetrated the city and thundered, and the mud filled the city and the rain fell. &lt;br />;No one asks for Huanghua Baijiu. I come back at dusk to wash my boots and socks. &lt;br />;How could I know that this year would come again? &lt;br />;Don’t be afraid that the wine is thin, red and pink, it will eventually win the battle in the mud. &lt;br />;The new walls of the Huanglou have not yet dried up, and the clear river has already been covered with frost. &lt;br />;The white dew is like drizzle in the morning, and there is no Qianxun Temple in Nanshan. &lt;br />;There is a vast sea in front of the building, and there are oars and crows in the air downstairs. &lt;br />;In the cold, old age is scary. Pour hot wine on the intestines first to suppress the gas. &lt;br />;After the smoke disappears and the sun rises, we can see the fishing village and the distant water and the scaly mountains. &lt;br />;Poets and warriors are mixed with dragons and tigers, Chu dances and Wu songs are mixed with geese and ducks. &lt;br />;A cup of wine belongs to you, don’t say goodbye, this situation is so clear and clear. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;① This poem was written after the completion of the Huanglou in the first year of Yuanfeng. The author recalls the floods last year and rejoices in today&#39;s festival. &lt;br />;②Last year on the Double Ninth Festival, the author had expected his friend to come to celebrate the festival. Since the visitors were blocked by the water, the host was also busy fighting with the water, so it is said that it cannot be said, which means that there is no way to talk about it. &lt;br />;③Retting, accumulation of water. Thousands of liters of water are said to be extremely powerful. &lt;br />;④Yellow, chrysanthemum. During the Double Ninth Festival, you should enjoy chrysanthemums and drink alcohol. Here, &quot;yellow flower white wine&quot; represents the Double Ninth Festival. &lt;br />;⑤Red pink, suspected to be the Geisha who is having a drink here. &lt;br />;⑥Here it is said that Gaosha is covered with white mist and cannot be seen. &lt;br />;⑦ Bohanzhong (pronounced zhòng) person means that a person is cold. &lt;br />;⑧齾齾 (pronounced yà), with uneven teeth, describes the jagged peaks. &lt;br />;⑨霅(zhá), the name of the water, is the Peixi River flowing into Taihu Lake. The last sentence is actually the author&#39;s words recalling and imagining Jiangnan. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/sushi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Su Shi, (January 8, 1037 - August 24, 1101), courtesy name Zizhan and Hezhong, also known as Tieguan Taoist and Dongpo layman, known as Su Dongpo and Su Xian in the world, Han nationality, Meizhou A native of Meishan (Meishan City, Sichuan Province), his ancestral home is Luancheng, Hebei Province. He is a famous writer, calligrapher and painter in the Northern Song Dynasty and a famous figure in water control in history. Su Shi was a literary leader in the mid-Northern Song Dynasty and made great achievements in poetry, lyrics, prose, calligraphy, and painting. His writing is bold and unbridled; his poems are broad in subject matter, fresh and vigorous, good at using exaggerated metaphors, and have a unique style. Together with Huang Tingjian, he is called &quot;Su Huang&quot;; His prose writings are grand and bold. Together with Ouyang Xiu, he is called &quot;Ou Su&quot; and is one of the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Su Shi was good at calligraphy and one of the &quot;Four Masters of the Song Dynasty&quot;; he was good at literati painting, especially ink bamboo, strange rocks, dead wood, etc. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan and Ouyang Xiu, they are known as the &quot;Four Great Masters of Eternal Writing&quot;. His works include &quot;Dongpo Seven Collections&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yi Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yuefu&quot;, &quot;Xiaoxiang Bamboo and Stone Picture Scroll&quot;, &quot;Old Trees and Strange Stones Picture Scroll&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一剪梅·花秋无月 | 辛弃疾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231021]]><description> &lt;h2>;One Cut of Plum Blossoms, No Moon in Autumn&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Xin Qiji &lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Recalling the flowers in the autumn osmanthus bush, the flowers are in the cup of flowers, and the moon is in the cup of flowers. Tonight, the same person upstairs, the screen window is wet with clouds and the screen window is wet with rain. (The moon is also in the cup of flowers, a work: The moon is also in the cup of flowers)&lt;br />;I want to take advantage of the wind to ask about chemical engineering, but the road is difficult and the letter is also difficult to pass. The whole hall is only filled with red candles, drinking and singing calmly. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Recalling the flowers and autumns of the past, I was surrounded by fragrant osmanthus bushes. The shadows of the flowers are reflected in the wine glass flowers, and the bright moon is also reflected in the wine glass flowers. Tonight I also raised a glass to admire the moon on the balcony, but the clouds were thick and the rain soaked the screens, so there was no moonlight anywhere. &lt;br />;I just want to ride the wind to heaven to question God, but there is no way to get through to heaven, even if I want to send a letter, it is difficult to get through. There is no moon in the painting hall, only red candles are shining brightly. Let us drink a few glasses of wine slowly and sing the song slowly to the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Zun: Same as &quot;zun&quot;, wine glass. &lt;br />;Hunyu: I just want to. Chemical industry: refers to the creator of nature. &lt;br />;Calm: leisurely, unhurried. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first part of the poem describes the poet’s recollection of a sunny autumn day, surrounded by osmanthus flowers, with the shadows of the moon waves rippling in the flowers. Wine glasses and flowers, but tonight the clouds and rain have wet the screen window, and only the candles are shining. The next part describes the poet who wants to ride the wind to the sky to question the heavenly palace, but the road is difficult and the letter is difficult, so he has to drink slowly under the candlelight. The scene of singing expresses the poet&#39;s resentment at having unrealized ambitions and unrewarded talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last film, I use a contrasting technique to write about the regret of tonight’s flowers and autumn without the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first two sentences are in retrospect, thinking about the past because of the present. When I started to write the title, I recalled the autumn night of previous years, when the sky was cloudless and the moon was bright. The shadows of osmanthus were whirling and the fragrance of osmanthus was floating. I leaned against the osmanthus and admired the moon while drinking wine. &quot;The flowers are in the cup of flowers and the moon is in the cup of flowers.&quot; I felt so happy and contented. situation. The two sentences &quot;Huazai&quot; are extremely well-written, revealing an ethereal, tranquil state and a feeling of joy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three sentences &quot;Tonight&quot; are twisted to write that tonight I am admiring the moon in the flower and autumn tower. People are still drinking, but there is no bright moon. The reason is that &quot;clouds wet the screens and rain wets the screens.&quot; Tonight is a rainy night. The song expresses the dull and regretful feeling of admiring the moon but not seeing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next film is about the loneliness and sadness of a moonless night. Change the head to tightly support the upper piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three sentences &quot;Hunyu&quot; describe the mood of looking forward to the moon of autumn flowers. &quot;Hun Yu wants to ride the wind to inquire about chemical engineering&quot; expresses the eagerness of looking forward to the moon, which also shows the depth of his regret. This sentence reveals the poet&#39;s hatred for being left idle by the imperial court and unable to serve his country. He wanted to &quot;ride the wind&quot; to question the emperor why he was treated like this. &quot;The road is difficult to pass. The letter is also difficult to pass.&quot; The resentment is obvious when writing about the helpless situation where wishes cannot be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last three sentences end with a scene, describing the loneliness and sadness of the moonless night in autumn. In desperation, the poet had no choice but to use red candles as his companion, drown his sorrows with wine, sing slow songs and drink alone, and talk about masturbation to pass the long moonless night. His loneliness and suffering are still vivid in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the poem &quot;Flowers&quot;, the author expressly laments that &quot;there are no moons in the autumn of flowers&quot;, but in fact, he laments the end of the hero. The whole poem is a blend of scenery and lyricism, with clear and clear language, subtle melodies and endless charm. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The poem was written from 1182 AD (the ninth year of Chunxi reign of Xiaozong of Song Dynasty) to 1192 AD (the third year of Shaoxi reign of Emperor Guangzong of Song Dynasty). When Xin Qiji lived in Daihu, the exact year cannot be determined. The poet&#39;s grief and indignation of having no way to serve the country, no hope of helping the world, and no hope of fulfilling his ambition are all poured into asking about the flower of the &quot;moon&quot;, which is expressed through this word. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/xinqiji.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Xin Qiji (May 28, 1140 - October 3, 1207), originally named Tanfu, later changed to You&#39;an, also known as Jiaxuan after the Flower Year, Shandong East Road, Jinan A native of Licheng County (now Licheng District, Jinan City, Shandong Province). He was an official, general, writer and poet of the Bold and Unconstrained School in the Southern Song Dynasty. He was known as the &quot;Dragon of Ci Flowers&quot;. Together with Su Shi, he is called &quot;Su Xin&quot;, and together with Li Qingzhao, he is called &quot;Jinan Er&#39;an&quot;. When Xin Qiji was born, Huayuan was already occupied by Jin soldiers. At the age of 21, he joined the anti-Jin rebel army and soon returned to the Southern Song Dynasty. He has successively served as the pacifier of Hubei, Jiangxi, Hunan, Fujian, and eastern Zhejiang. He devoted his life to resisting gold. He once published &quot;Ten Comments on Meiqin&quot; and &quot;Nine Discussions&quot; to lay out strategies for war and defense. His poems express the patriotic enthusiasm of trying to restore the unity of the country, express the sorrow and indignation of unrealized aspirations, and condemn the humiliation of the then rulers for peace; there are also many works that praise the country&#39;s mountains and rivers. The subject matter is broad and he is good at using allusions from previous generations into the lyrics. The style is majestic and heroic yet not lacking in delicacy and tenderness. Because Xin Qiji&#39;s anti-golden ideas were inconsistent with the political views of the peace faction in power, he was later impeached and dismissed from office, and retired to Daihu, Jiangxi. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>