<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[南安军 | 文天祥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310131]]><description> &lt;h2>;Nan&#39;an Army&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Wen Tianxiang&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Meihua Road North and South, wind and rain wet the clothes. &lt;br />;Who did you go out with when you came out of the mountain? Such a homecoming! (Such a saying: if not)&lt;br />;Mountains and rivers have been there through the ages, but cities have changed for a while. &lt;br />;My ambition is to starve to death, and I pick weeds in my dream. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Walking through Dayuling Pass from south to north, my clothes were wet by wind and rain along the way. &lt;br />;Thinking of the companions I had when I went to Nanling, but when I returned home, I was a prisoner. &lt;br />;The rivers and mountains of the motherland will last for thousands of years, but the city will only fall into the hands of the enemy temporarily. &lt;br />;It is my true wish to die on hunger strike. In my dream, I also imitated Boyi and Shuqi, eating wild vegetables to satisfy my hunger and waiting to die. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Meihua North and South Road: Many plum blossoms are planted on Dayu Ridge, so it is named Meiling. It is bounded by Nanxiong County in Guangdong to the south and Dayu County in Jiangxi to the north. &lt;br />;Plucking Wei: Boyi and Shuqi, sons of Lord Guzhu at the end of Shang Dynasty, when King Wu of Zhou attacked Zhou, they buckled their horses and remonstrated. Shang died and fled into Shouyang Mountain. They swore not to eat millet from Zhou Dynasty, so they picked Wei to eat. ,starve. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two couplets of this poem describe the places and scenery during the trip, as well as the author&#39;s emotions, and express the sorrow of this trip. Feeling. The neck couplet compares the eternal existence of the motherland&#39;s mountains and rivers with the temporary fall of the city, highlighting the poet&#39;s belief in restoring the country of the Song Dynasty and his contempt for the people of the Yuan Dynasty. The tail couplet expresses his attitude: he is determined to starve to death and die for his country, fulfilling his wish of &quot;the first hill&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Meihua North and South Road, wind and rain wet clothes.&quot; Briefly mention the places and scenery on the itinerary. When the author arrived at Nan&#39;an Army, he was crossing the north and south routes of Dayuling (Meiling). The plum blossoms mentioned here are not real scenes, but plum blossoms are mentioned because of Meiling. This is used to contrast with &quot;wind and rain&quot;, which initially shows the heavy mood during the trip. The plum blossoms in Meiling swayed in the wind and rain, soaking the uniforms of the soldiers who were escorting Wen Tianxiang, who was captured after the defeat and went to Dadu for trial. At this time, a burst of ice hit his heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Who did you go out with? Returning home is like never returning home!&quot; Two sentences, the first sentence refers to the loneliness of the journey, but it is written in a questioning tone, which seems particularly sad. The next sentence says that during this trip north, I could have returned to my hometown of Luling, but I was imprisoned and could not be free. Although I passed through my hometown, I felt like I had never returned. These two sentences express the miserable mood during this trip, and the repeated comparison of the two characters &quot;out&quot; and the two characters &quot;return&quot; makes the emotions even more exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mountains and rivers have been there forever, but the city walls have changed for a while.&quot; Wen Tianxiang stood on the ridge, looking at the Xihua Mountain of Nan&#39;an Army and Zhangjiang River in the distance, lamenting that the mountains and rivers will always exist, while the city walls will change from what they were when they left the ridge. The city wall of the Song Army has become a city wall occupied by the Yuan Army, and the flags hanging there will also change accordingly. This sentence is an allusion to Du Fu&#39;s &quot;The country is broken and the mountains and rivers are here&quot; and Ding Lingwei&#39;s &quot;I have been away from home for thousands of years and now I have returned, but the people in the city are still in trouble.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;My true ambition is to starve to death, and I pick weeds in my dream.&quot; The poet Wen Tianxiang would rather go on a hunger strike and starve to death in his hometown than cooperate with the Yuan soldiers. The poet often dreams that he makes a living by picking wild vegetables in Shouyang Mountain like Boyi and Shuqi. This poem uses the story of Boyi and Shuqi. After the fall of the Shang Dynasty, two clan members, Boyi and Shuqi, refused to eat Zhousu millet and fled into Shouyang Mountain, picking wild vegetables to satisfy their hunger. Finally, they starved to death on the mountain. Starting in Guangdong, Wen Tianxiang began a hunger strike, preparing to starve to death in his hometown. After eight days of hunger strike, he continued to eat when he still felt fine. On the night of the first day of October of the same year when Wen Tianxiang wrote &quot;Nan&#39;an Army&quot;, Wen Tianxiang was escorted to Yuandadu and died heroically after being a prisoner for three years, two months and nine days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem uses Du Fu&#39;s poems to express his own mind, show his strong patriotic feelings and show the national righteousness. This poem progresses step by step, with stirring voices and emotions. It does not pretend to be ornamental, but shows its own skill. The author has made great efforts to Du Fu&#39;s poems, and his style is quite similar, that is, he can see the profound temperament in the simplicity. It can be said that it is a work written with blood and tears. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In 1279 AD (the second year of Emperor Xiangxing&#39;s reign), Yashan in the Southern Song Dynasty was captured by the Yuan army and the Song Dynasty was destroyed. Wen Tianxiang was captured the year before and went north. He wrote this poem when he left Dageng Mountains on May 4th and passed through the Nan&#39;an Army (the administrative seat of today&#39;s Dayu, Jiangxi Province). &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wentianxiang.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wen Tianxiang (1236.6.6-1283.1.9), also known as Lushan and Songrui, named himself Wenshan and was a Taoist from Fuxiu. Han nationality, native of Luling, Jizhou (now Ji&#39;an County, Jiangxi Province), minister, writer and national hero in the late Southern Song Dynasty. In the fourth year of Baoyou&#39;s reign (1256), he was promoted to Jinshi, and became Prime Minister and Privy Envoy. He was sent to the Yuan army&#39;s camp to negotiate and was detained. After escaping the danger, he passed through Jizhuang, Gaoyou, to Tangwan, Tai County, and returned south from Nantong, persisting in resisting the Yuan Dynasty. In the first year of Xiangxing (1278), he was defeated and captured by Zhang Hongfan. He persisted in fighting in prison for more than three years, and then died calmly in Chaishi. He is the author of &quot;Crossing the Lingding Ocean&quot;, &quot;Wenshan Poetry Collection&quot;, &quot;Guide Record&quot;, &quot;Guide Post Record&quot;, &quot;Song of Righteousness&quot; and other works. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 07:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[纥干狐尾 | 佚名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310132]]><description> &lt;h2>;Hegan Foxtail&lt;/h2>;[Unknown] Anonymous&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>; Those who have Hegan in Bingzhou are good at drama. There are rumors that there is a fox spirit in the city, which makes people panic. One day, He found a fox tail. The fox was hidden behind his clothes. He came to his wife and sat on his side to expose it. His wife suspected that he was a fox charm, so she took an ax and tried to kill it. He Qianqi said: &quot;I am not charming.&quot; His wife did not believe it. He walked to the neighbor&#39;s house, and the neighbor chased him away with swords and sticks. He Qian kowtowed and thanked him: &quot;I, He Qian, am the first dramatist. Why do you want to kill me?&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation &lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; There was a man named He Qian in Bingzhou (now Taiyuan, Shanxi) who liked to joke. There are local rumors that a fox is haunted, and everyone is panicked. One day, He Gan got a fox tail and sewed it on the back of his clothes. He came to his wife&#39;s side and sat sideways, deliberately exposing the fox&#39;s tail. When his wife saw him, she secretly suspected that he was a vixen, so she quietly picked up an ax and struck at him. He hurriedly said: &quot;I&#39;m not a vixen!&quot; His wife didn&#39;t believe it. He Gan ran to his neighbor&#39;s house, and the neighbors picked up knives and sticks to chase him. He kowtowed and apologized and said: &quot;I am Hegan. This is just a joke. Why do you want to kill me?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Yi: local; county里&lt;br />;panic: panic&lt;br />;for: yes&lt;br />;urgent: immediately, immediately&lt;br />;walk: run&lt;br />;xie: admit mistake, apologize&lt;br />;The first drama ear, what does it mean Kill Me: This is just a joke, why are you bent on killing me? &lt;br />;Fox: sewing with needle and thread&lt;br />;Drama: joking&lt;br />;Fox: fox pretending to be a ghost&lt;br />;Charm: ghost&lt;br />;Cut: chop&lt;br />;No.: only, just&lt;br />; br />;Good: hobbies, preferences&lt;br />;Zhi: pronoun, referring to fox tail&lt;br />;Ear: that’s all&lt;br />;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;Also known as anonymous, it refers to a person whose identity is unknown or whose name has not yet been learned. Literary and musical works originating from ancient times or among the people and whose author is unknown will be named anonymously. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>