<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[无闷·催雪 | 吴文英]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310111]]><description> &lt;h2>;No Boring · Pushing Snow&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Wu Wenying&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The colorful festivals fly with beautiful flowers, the luan rides on the jade, and the plain clouds and weak water disappear. Qian Haohe passed the letter, and Aunt Wei called out. Don&#39;t wait for the dawn to condense on the Fenhe River, take advantage of the night moon and the flying Yaosheng to wear it. The donkey is dancing, the stove is cold, and the door of the wine pavilion is closed. &lt;br />;Goliath. Panbis ant. Put half hooks on the embroidered curtain, and build the treasure platform next to it. I need to borrow Dongjun, the spring spirit of Baling. Xiaomeng first fascinated Chu Die, and the early wind and heavy cold invaded the quilt. I&#39;m also afraid of covering up the pear blossoms in the deep courtyard, and making people shed tears. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xu Feiqiong, the maid next to the Queen Mother of the West, is about to arrive in a car with neon banners and ceremonial guards. After Nong Yu ascends to heaven, he will also fly back on a Luan and Phoenix. Ask the calligrapher Wei Maoyi to summon Feixue, and ask the emperor to issue an edict to summon Feixue. The Snow God took advantage of the darkness of night to rain down heavy snow, and before dawn, the earth was covered in silver. I want to take advantage of the heavy snow early in the morning to ride a weak little donkey and go alone in the snow to sing &quot;Snow Song&quot; repeatedly. At this time, the teahouses and wine shops along the road were temporarily closed due to the cold weather and no one was around. &lt;br />;The door curtain in the room is half hung, and a banquet is set up on the steps. The guests are waiting for the snow to fall while the singing is clear and green tea is sipped. People half-open the embroidered curtains and approach the jade steps of the Baotai. If they can invite the Spring God, they can use his power to send away the Snow God and revive all things. The wind was blowing hard and the snow was dense. I woke up from the freezing cold and saw only a few snowflakes outside. In my confusion, I thought they were flying butterflies I saw in my dream. After getting up, I hurried to the garden to enjoy the snow. I saw that everything in the garden was white, but I was afraid that it would snow too much. The snow turned into water and sprinkled on the pear blossoms, turning into the tears of an old friend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Wumen: the name of the word brand. A &quot;snow rusher&quot;. Double tone, ninety-nine characters, the first part has ten lines with four oblique rhymes, and the second part has nine lines with six oblique rhymes. The eighth sentence in the previous film is a four-character sentence, while the word &quot;Mengchuang&quot; is a five-character sentence, so the whole word is one hundred words long, with a changed pattern. This word was created by Jiang Baishi, so Jiang Ci is the correct style. The fourth sentence of the first part and the third sentence of the second part are all four sentences. The purpose of the title &quot;to urge the snow&quot; is to make the snow fall faster, to show the thoughts and emotions of man&#39;s determination to conquer the sky. The poet is looking forward to the early arrival of &quot;Spring in Baling&quot;.&lt;br />;Ni Festival: Ni Jing, ancient times A guard of honor when the emperor travels. Feiqiong: Xu Feiqiong. The legendary maid of the Queen Mother of the West.&lt;br />;Nongyu: It is said that she was the daughter of Duke Mu of Qin in the Spring and Autumn Period. She married Xiao Shi, who was good at playing the flute, and Duke Mu built a phoenix platform to live in. Later, the couple flew to the immortals on a phoenix. See Liu Xiang&#39;s &quot;Biography of Immortals&quot;. &quot;Fei Qiong&quot; and &quot;Nong Yu&quot; both describe snow.&lt;br />;Separation: that is, the separation of weak water. Far and away Places that cannot be reached.&lt;br />;Heshu: The name of the calligraphy style. It is often used as an edict to recruit wise men, also known as the Crane Head Book.&lt;br />;Aunt Wei: a calligrapher of the Jin Dynasty, named Shuo, courtesy name Maoyi, Wei Heng ( Calligrapher) niece, wife of Ruyin prefect Li Ju. She is good at calligraphy, especially official script, and studied under Zhong Yao. Calling: refers to stirring up the ice of the jade pot.&lt;br />;Powder River Ningxia: refers to the Milky Way disappearing at dawn . Fenhe: Milky Way.&lt;br />;Huanpei: Women’s round jade pendant.&lt;br />;Jian (jiǎn) Donkey: a lame donkey. Yinying: refers to a poet who rides a donkey and sings in the wind and snow.&lt;br />;Bi Ant: that is, &quot;green ant&quot;. Ant, the foamy scum of wine, looks like an ant. Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;Ask Liu Shijiu&quot;: &quot;Green clams make new fermented wine, and a small red mud stove.&quot; &quot;&lt;br />;Dong Jun: God of Spring.&lt;br />;Baling: Emperor Wen of the Han Dynasty built and buried this place, so it was named Baling, located in the east of Chang&#39;an County. &quot;Baling breaks willows&quot;, which has been an allusion to seeing off guests since the Han and Tang Dynasties. &lt;br />;Violence: Violence.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is a poem about scenery. The first rhyme &quot;Nijie Feiqiong&quot; is adapted from myths and legends , a metaphor for the snow that is about to fall. The title of the poem is &quot;to urge the snow&quot;. The two sentences of &quot;Nijie&quot; use the white color of the two characters &quot;Qiong&quot; and &quot;Yu&quot; to describe snow, and &quot;Nijie&quot; and &quot;Luanjia&quot; are used to describe snow. Flying. Such a personification technique not only makes the colors simple and elegant, but also writes the snow in a beautiful and elegant mood. It creates a mythical artistic conception at the beginning of the chapter. &quot;The separation between the plain clouds and the weak water&quot; is transformed into the &quot;weak water separation&quot; It is an allusion to say that it is far away and difficult to reach. This sentence changes the pen and writes that the snow will not fall, which is the root of the word &quot;urge&quot;. The rhyme of &quot;Qian Haohe Chuan Shu&quot; has the word &quot;urge&quot; written on the front, and the poet further Expand your imagination, the idea here is unique and the wording is novel. &quot;Crane Script&quot; is an ancient calligraphy style specially used to write edicts for recruiting magi. In the ci, Bai Xue is compared to a magi, and it is conveyed in Crane Script, and in &quot;Crane Script&quot; Add the word &quot;Hao&quot; before &quot;&quot;, compare it with &quot;Snow&quot;, and change the &quot;Crane Book&quot; into a white crane. It has become a bird that can fly and pass messages. Here, inanimate objects are turned into animate objects, which seems It is more vivid and expressive. The ice in the jade pot in the poem is compared to the white snow. The word &quot;urge&quot; is written on the front of &quot;chuanshu&quot; and &quot;call out&quot;. &quot;Don&#39;t wait for the powder river to condense at dawn&quot; rhymes, &quot;Don&#39;t wait&quot; means sincerity. &quot;Yao Sheng&quot; &quot;Fei Huan Pei&quot; echoes the words &quot;Fei Qiong&quot; and &quot;Nong Yu&quot; at the beginning, still using fairies to compare snow. Imagine fairies flying into the world under the moonlit night, playing Sheng music like the sound of Huan Pei Yu ornaments. Here not only will Inanimate objects are compared to humans, and they are vivid and ethereal. The rhyme of &quot;the donkey is singing its shadow&quot; also uses allusions related to snow, giving snow its inherent elegance and white social essence. This rhyme refers to the fall of snow. The sentence &quot;Jian donkey&quot; is adapted from the story of Zheng Wei recorded in Sun Guangxian&#39;s &quot;Bei Meng Suoyan&quot;. Someone asked the Prime Minister Zheng Wei: &quot;Has the Prime Minister written any new poems recently?&quot; Said: &quot;The poem is on a donkey in the wind and snow in Baqiao. How can I get it here?&quot; &quot;Only when riding a donkey in the wind and snow can one have poetic thoughts, and when serving as an official in the court, there is a poetic feeling.&quot; The two sentences of &quot;tea smoke and stove are cold&quot; are used by Yuan An before he arrived. There was a heavy snowfall that closed the door, but the smoke was cold and the stove was cold at home. A story about lying down and defending oneself in poverty. Yang Tiefu commented on these two rhymes and said: &quot;It serves as a counter-challenge for the following text. &quot; (&quot;Explanation of Selected Notes on Mengchuang Ci&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the film, the second rhyme of &quot;Ge Li&quot; appeared. Yang Tiefu commented on this rhyme and said: &quot;It has changed to a lively state again.&quot; &quot; (&quot;Explanation of Selected Notes of Mengchuang Ci&quot;) The poet changed this lively state to contrast the tranquility and tranquility when the snow falls. The three rhymes of &quot;Putting the Embroidered Curtain Half Hook&quot; after the film all have the word &quot;urge&quot; written from the side. &quot;It is necessary to borrow Dongjun&quot; rhyme, with the word &quot;urge&quot; written on the front, it is necessary to borrow the spring breeze from the east to urge the snow. &quot;Spring breeze in Baling&quot; once again uses the phrase &quot;poems are on donkeys in the wind and snow in Baqiao&quot; by Zheng Xi. , connects snow with poetry, and paints snow with poetic color. &quot;Dawn of dawn first confuses dream of butterfly&quot; rhyme, which is adapted from Zhuangzi&#39;s dream of turning into a butterfly. When he woke up, he didn&#39;t know whether he was transformed by a butterfly or himself. The story was written in a confused dream. The wind was howling, the snow was flying, and the heavy cold air invaded the quilt tent. The snow has fallen, which completes the word &quot;urge&quot; in the title of the poem. Finally, it ends with &quot;I am still afraid of covering the pear blossoms in the deep courtyard.&quot; A rhyme is used as the postscript of the title, and the snow is changed into another artistic conception, creating a sad state of pear blossoms with rain and a beautiful woman crying. Yang Tiefu said: &quot;I also fell into a level of Dharma. ” (&quot;Explanation of Selected Notes on Mengchuang Ci&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This word is cleverly conceived, and the rhetoric is wonderful. For example, flying snow is compared to two fairies, &quot;Fei Qiong&quot; and &quot;Nong Yu&quot; arriving in a luan. , the whiteness of &quot;Qiong&quot; and &quot;Jade&quot; is more appropriate than snow, and it is compared with fairies. The image is vivid and full of ethereal and elegant beauty. When writing &quot;Jiu Xue&quot; on the front, the crane body used to write imperial edicts and the jade pot ice body of Aunt Wei are used In comparison, it is both solemn and beautiful. When it is written about waiting for snow, &quot;the embroidered curtain is half hooked, and the treasure platform is being built&quot;. The words are beautiful, and it has the charm of a beautiful lady waiting for the one she likes. It writes about the psychology of looking forward to the snow but being afraid of the heavy snow. , but said &quot;I am still afraid of covering up the pear blossoms in the courtyard, and making old friends shed tears&quot;, creating the beautiful image of &quot;the rain hits the pear blossoms and closes the door&quot; and &quot;a branch of pear blossoms brings rain in spring&quot;. The words are both dense and beautiful, just as Kuang Zhouyi said : “In the secret place of the dream window, there can be countless beautiful words, which are vivid and dancing, like thousands of flowers for spring. &quot;(&quot;Hui Feng Ci&quot;)&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; The specific time of creation of this poem is unknown. Wu Wenying&#39;s life had almost no expectations of making a contribution and a positive career. His pursuit of life is relatively narrow, and he has many dreamy works. The sentence &quot;Zhuang Shengxiao is obsessed with butterflies in his dream&quot; in Li Shangyin&#39;s &quot;Jin Se&quot; has a dream-like and illusive feeling of confusion in life. I liked this very much. So I used Lekuo in various ways in my lyrics many times. This song &quot;No Boredom·Driving Snow&quot; is his representative work. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the Author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; &lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wuwenying.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Wu Wenying (about 1200~1260), character Junte, also known as Mengchuang, and later Jueweng, was born in Siming (today&#39;s Ningbo, Zhejiang). He was originally named Weng, and later heir to the Wu family. He was friendly with Jia Sidao. There is a collection of Mengchuang Ci, which is extant. There are more than 340 ci poems, divided into four volumes and one volume. His ci works are abundant in quantity, elegant in style, and contain many poems that respond to grief, grief, and mourning. They are called &quot;Li Shangyin in Ci&quot;. However, later generations have praised him very much. There is controversy.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[归雁 | 钱起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310112]]><description> &lt;h2>;Gui Yan&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Qian Qi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Why don&#39;t you go back to Xiaoxiang in leisure time? The water is clear and the sand is bright with moss on both sides. &lt;br />;Twenty-five strings are played on the night moon, and all the resentment comes flying. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Why did you come back from such a beautiful place as Xiaoshui and Xiangshui so easily? The stream there is clear, the sand and stones are clear, and there is moss on the shore for you to forage for. Why don&#39;t you want to stay? &lt;br />;Dayan replied: The harp tune played by the God of Xiangling on the moonlit night was too sad. I couldn&#39;t stand the sad and resentful tune, so I had to leave Xiaoxiang and fly back to the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Xiaoxiang: the name of Ershui, in present-day Hunan. &lt;br />;Easy: easy and casual. &lt;br />;Shui Bi Sha Ming: moss, food for birds, especially geese. &lt;br />;Twenty-five strings: finger harp. &lt;br />;Sheng (sound shēng): bear. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 1&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Although this song &quot;Returning Wild Geese&quot; was written in the north, it is about the spring geese returning from the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem chants &quot;Returning Geese&quot;. Geese are migratory birds. They fly to the south to spend the winter in late autumn and fly back to the north in the warm spring. The ancients believed that geese flying south in autumn do not cross Huiyan Peak in Hengshan Mountain, Hunan. They fly to the north of the peak and inhabit the lower reaches of the Xiangjiang River, and then fly back to the north after winter. Based on this understanding, the author thought of the Xiangjiang River, the habitat before their return, from the returning geese, and from the Xiangjiang River, he thought of the myth that the goddess of the Xiangjiang River was good at playing the harp. Then, based on the harp song &quot;Guiyan Cao&quot;, he combined the harp and the harp with the wild geese. The return of the poem is connected, thus forming the whimsical thoughts in the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Why wait to return to Xiaoxiang? The water is clear and the sand is bright with moss on both sides.&quot; The first two sentences are inverted. The ancients generally did not know much about the living habits of wild geese, and believed that they would stop flying south when they fly to Huiyan Peak in the south of Hengyang County, Hunan Province, and return north when the flowers bloom in the spring of the next year. Xiaoxiang is located in the south of Dongting Lake, with warm water, sufficient food, and a good climate. The ancients thought it was a good place for wild geese to spend the winter, so the poet imagined that returning geese flew from Xiaoxiang. As a migratory bird, it is a normal natural phenomenon for wild geese to return from the south to the north whenever spring comes. However, the poet insisted on asking a question, using two sentences in a row. This is contrary to the common practice of poets in the past who took the return of spring geese to the north as a matter of course. He deliberately expressed his confusion about the return of the wild geese and asked why they were willing to leave the Xiangjiang River with beautiful environment and abundant water and grass and come back. This sudden inquiry immediately leads the reader&#39;s thinking to the track arranged by the poet - ignoring the habits of the wild geese, and exploring the reasons for the wild geese&#39;s return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The author answered on behalf of Yan in the third and fourth sentences: &quot;Twenty-five strings play the moon at night, and all the grievances fly away.&quot; The goddess of the Xiangjiang River plays the harp (twenty-five strings) under the moonlit night. , the sad and plaintive sound of the whistle, the wild geese couldn&#39;t bear to listen to it any longer, so they flew back to the north. These two sentences use the legend of Xiangling drum and harp. According to ancient legend, the goddess of the Xiangshui River was good at playing the harp. The harp originally had fifty strings, but because the goddess played it with a sad and sorrowful tone, God ordered it to be changed to twenty-five strings. The poet used his rich imagination and used beautiful myths to show readers the sad artistic conception of the God of Hunan and the harp, and deliberately created the image of the wild goose who is sentimental and knowledgeable in music. So why did the poet write the Xiang God&#39;s drum and harp in such a sad way? Why are the wild geese so &quot;unbearable&quot;? In fact, the wild geese described by the poet are derived from the phrase &quot;Chu guests are unbearable to listen to&quot;. The author created the image of the traveling geese living in the Xiangjiang River based on the &quot;Chu guests&quot; who were demoted to other places. When the traveling geese heard Xiang Ling&#39;s mournful whistle, they felt homesick and unbearable, and resolutely left the beautiful and rich Xiangjiang River and flew back to the north. The poet uses the wild geese filled with the sorrow of traveling to euphemistically express the sorrow of traveling in a foreign country. From the returning geese, I thought of their habitat before their return, and also thought of the myth that the goddess of the Xiangjiang River was good at playing the harp, and then based on the harp song &quot;Guiyan Cao&quot; and then connected the harp with the return of the geese, thus forming the poem. of fantastic ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A short four-line poem with novel ideas and rich imagination. Although the night view of Xiaoxiang and the sound of the whistle in the poem are all imaginary words, through such questions and answers, the geese are described as beings who understand music and are full of emotions. This poem appears to be about wild geese, but it is actually about the poet&#39;s feelings on a spring night. The poem does not directly say what this feeling is. It is precisely because it is not stated clearly that it leaves readers with unlimited room for imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The sentence &quot;The grievances are flying away&quot; in &quot;Guiyan&quot; turns out to be this seven-character quatrain with ingenious and novel conception, rich imagination, ethereal writing style, tactful lyricism, and interesting meaning. With its unique artistic features, it has become one of the most eye-catching and famous poems about chanting wild geese. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Sentimentality is a characteristic of ordinary poets. But just being sentimental without being able to express this emotion appropriately and beautifully to arouse the resonance of others is not a successful poet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Qi&#39;s poem &quot;The Return of the Wild Goose&quot; is a masterpiece that uses the question and answer between the poet and the wild goose to reveal a certain feeling on a spring night. It embodies deep emotions in a tactful and fluent form. Here, the poet&#39;s own travel sadness and homesickness are the driving force behind the poem, while the wild geese coming from the south, or the song related to the returning wild geese, are the opportunity for the poet to get inspiration and turn the erratic inspiration into a vivid image. The abundant emotions in the poet&#39;s heart give birth to his creative passion, and once this passion finds the appropriate language form, it will become a beautiful poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first couplet is the poet&#39;s inquiry about Guiyan. Legend has it that wild geese fly south for the winter and turn back when they reach Huiyan Peak in Hengshan Mountain. So the poet has this question: Oh, geese from the south, why did you leave Xiaoxiang, a quiet and fertile place with clear water and clear sand and covered with berries and moss, and fly all the way back to the north? The second couplet is Dai Guiyan&#39;s answer: Because there is Xiang Ling playing the harp under the moonlight, and I couldn&#39;t help the coldness and sadness of the tune, so I turned back. Of course, this answer is completely imaginary, but such an answer secretly (rather than directly or explicitly) leads to the legend of Xiangling Guzi, allowing the reader to close his eyes and imagine someone playing music by the river on a moonlit night. The image of a woman pouring out her sorrows creates an unbearable reaction. As a result, the reader understands the reason why the wild geese &quot;fly away&quot; (that is, turns back and flies), and further, through the poet&#39;s questions and answers with Tong Guiyan, a visitor from the south, he can experience the poet&#39;s feelings of being in the north and missing his hometown in the south. And this is what Qian Qi really wanted to express when he wrote this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/qianqi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Qian Qi (722?-780), courtesy name Zhongwen, Han nationality, from Wuxing (now Huzhou City, Zhejiang Province), was a poet of the Tang Dynasty. He failed several examinations in his early years. He became a Jinshi in the tenth year of Tang Tianbao (751) and was the uncle of the great calligrapher Huai Su. At first, he was the secretary of the Provincial School Secretary and the captain of Lantian County. Later, he served as the Secretary of the Department of Xun Yuan, the Doctor of Kao Gong, and the Hanlin Bachelor. He once served as a doctor who took the exam and was known as &quot;Qian Kao Gong&quot; in his old life. In Daizong&#39;s Dali, he was a Hanlin bachelor. He is one of the ten talented men in the Dali calendar and an outstanding one among them. He is known as &quot;the crown of the ten talented men in the Dali calendar&quot;. He was also as famous as Lang Shiyuan, and was called &quot;Qian Lang&quot;. At that time, it was said that &quot;there was Shen Song before him, and Qian Lang after him.&quot;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>