<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[三姝媚·过都城旧居有感 | 吴文英]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310161]]><description> &lt;h2>;San Shumei·Impressions after passing the old residence in the capital city&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Wu Wenying&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Hushan is used to being drunk. The spring clothes are stained, and there are endless traces of crying and wine. Visiting Chang&#39;an again, I sighed with my broken lapel and loose sleeves, and who was dusty. Ziqumen is deserted, along the long well, the wind shakes the green vines. To the east, there is still Zeng&#39;s nest and two swallows in Xie Tang. &lt;br />;Spring dreams in the human world must be discontinued. But it&#39;s strange that dreams were short-lived back then. Qin Zheng in the embroidered house, favored by Haitang, had a banquet late at night. The dance stops and the song subsides, the flowers remain undiminished and the beauty changes first. I have been standing on the river bridge for a long time and am about to leave. The setting sun fills me with tears. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;I have long been used to getting drunk among the lakes and mountains. At that time, my clothes were stained Tear stains, stains of wine. Now that I have come to Lin&#39;an, the capital, to stay as a guest again, I lament that my clothes are torn, but who will wash them for me? The familiar Fangqu Gate is already desolate, with only the green vines covering the edge of the dry well swaying in the wind. What is whispering to each other between the adjacent beams in the east is probably the twin swallows that nested in Huatang in the old days! &lt;br />;The erotic dream in this world will always have to be completed. I also know that the strange thing is that the dream-like relationship was so short-lived. I still remember the scene of you caressing Qin Zheng in the embroidery room. What I particularly like is the banquet held under the crabapple flowers late at night. I can no longer see you dancing, and your singing has been silent since then. The flowers are still as beautiful as before, but their flower-like appearance has long since withered. I stood on the river bridge for a long time. When I was about to leave, the sunset shed its afterglow, and my eyes were filled with tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;San Shumei: the name of the word brand. Shi Dazu created the tune. The name of the tune comes from the ancient Yuefu &quot;Three Women in Beauty&quot;. Double tone, 94 characters, oblique rhyme. Mao Xianshu&#39;s &quot;Explanation of the Name of the Lyrics&quot; says: &quot;The ancient Yuefu poem &quot;San Fu Yan&quot; is derived from its name, and it is also called the song &quot;San Shu Mei&quot;.&quot;&lt;br />;Hushan: refers to the West Lake and the mountains beside the lake. &lt;br />;Stain: stain. &lt;br />;Broken collar and loose sleeves: refers to broken clothes. &lt;br />;Pocket: Collar. &lt;br />;裾: The beginning of clothing. &lt;br />;Huan: washing. &lt;br />;Ziqu: refers to the square where prostitutes live. &lt;br />;In the embroidered house, Qin Zheng, next to Haitang, had a banquet late at night: it refers to the song, banquet and wine banquet in peacetime. &lt;br />;Xiuwu: refers to a gorgeous residence. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a nostalgic poem. The wandering poet Wu Mengchuang passed by the capital Lin&#39;an (now Hangzhou) one day and came to When I visited the residence where I once lived, I saw weeds filling the door and the well wall decaying. I couldn&#39;t help but have mixed feelings and feelings, so I chanted this poem to express my feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last column focuses on describing the current desolate scene of the former residence. The first three sentences explain his wandering life in the past many years since leaving his former residence: &quot;Hushan is used to being drunk.&quot; A few five words give a vivid summary. &quot;Hushan&quot; means wandering around the world; &quot;Drunk&quot; means drinking to drown sorrows and being unhappy; and &quot;Habit&quot; means that such a life has become routine and has become a habit. In order to further visualize it, the poet described it in detail as &quot;stained spring clothes, endless traces of crying and wine&quot;. Lu Fangweng&#39;s poem &quot;The clothes are dusty and mixed with wine stains, and I feel ecstasy everywhere when I travel far away.&quot; Here, the poet expresses his wandering life by using the wine stains and wet stains on his spring shirt. It is more weighty than Lu&#39;s poem, and its level of sadness is also higher. Even better. &quot;Visiting Chang&#39;an again&quot; is the keynote of &quot;passing the capital&quot;. &quot;Chang&#39;an&quot; is just a metaphor, which actually refers to Lin&#39;an, the capital of Song Dynasty. The two lines &quot;Sighing for his broken lapel and loose robes&quot; paint an image of the poet in embarrassment and desolation: his clothes are ragged and stained with dust, and there is no one to clean and wash them for him. According to the poet Wu Wenying, he had never been an official in his life, and had only held a small position in charge of documents. His life was often poor and abject. He once expressed his embarrassment in his situation with the words &quot;several roads were impoverished and cars were dead&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The following three sentences of &quot;Ziqu Huangmen&quot; describe the scene of the decline of my former residence today: &quot;Ziqu&quot; is the name of an alley in Kyoto. It is full of grass, the well platform in the courtyard is dilapidated, and the overgrown grass is swaying in the wind... It is even more sad. The three lines &quot;Dong Neighbor&quot; in the dialogue are based on Liu Yuxi&#39;s allusion of &quot;In the old days, the swallows in front of the king&#39;s palace flew into the homes of ordinary people.&quot; It refers to the fact that the gate of the east neighbor of the old residence has also grown up and is now inhabited by common people. The nest in the nest The swallows under the beautiful house are still there. The poem not only writes about the desolation of his old home, but also about the changes in his eastern neighbor. This describes the vicissitudes of world affairs and the strife of the court in a broader way, hinting at the internal conflicts and struggles of the Southern Song Dynasty and its increasing decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lower part focuses on describing the prosperity of the former residence, looking back from the present to the past, and also showing the inner pain of the poet. &quot;Spring dreams must be interrupted&quot; is a warning full of philosophical connotations, and it is also a deep sigh of the poet after paying tribute to his old home: Spring dreams are short-lived, and their interruption is inevitable. &quot;How can there be a feast that never ends in the world?&quot; This is a truth that has existed throughout the ages and is independent of human will. No one can blame the fleeting nature of dreams, but after all, memories of the past are nostalgic. The three lines of &quot;Qin Zheng in the embroidered house&quot; are a display of the beautiful memories of the past: the sound of the zither in the embroidered house; the begonia flowers blooming so beautifully beside people in front of the steps; the banquets are held late at night; the singing and dancing add to the beauty of the past. The atmosphere of joy was created... The three lines of &quot;Dancing breaks and singing falls&quot; recall the emotional changes of that year: At that time, the singing stopped, the dancing stopped, and the flowers were still blooming. For some reason, she changed her heart, and she never looked back again. No information... Alas, the joys and sorrows of the past have passed away like a dream, and will never return like water flowing in the east. The poet who had been standing by the river bridge for a long time looking at his former residence overgrown with grass was about to leave, but he was reluctant to leave. In the shadow of the setting sun, the poet&#39;s eyes were full of bitter and bitter tears. &quot;Standing on the river bridge for a long time, about to leave, and the setting sun is full of tears&quot; is really a beautiful ending. It not only finally clarifies the direction and distance of the poet&#39;s former residence, but also allows us to see the poet&#39;s figure alone and in condolences. &quot;Standing for a long time, about to leave, and full of tears. It contains environment, time, action, and emotion. The two blend and penetrate to create a distinct and unique artistic conception full of poetry and rich connotation!&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Wu Wenying lived in the capital Lin&#39;an several times in his life. His concubine lived here, and the relationship between the two has always been very good. But unfortunately, after the separation, Ai Ji passed away. This poem was written to commemorate the deceased concubine when the author revisited her old residence in Hangzhou. The words are sentimental and sad, which reflects the lyrical artistic characteristics of Mengchuang Ci. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Hushan is accustomed to being drunk.&quot; At the beginning, facing the beautiful scenery of lakes and mountains, the poet couldn&#39;t help but recall the joyous scenes of drinking drunkenly on the lake with Ai Ji in the past. &quot;Spring stained clothes, stained by tears and endless wine stains&quot; means that the stains of tears and dots of wine stains that still remain on the clothes are the vivid records of the joys and sorrows of the past. Yan Jidao has a poem that says: &quot;The words in the poem are filled with wine stains on the clothes, and the lines are always desolate.&quot; (&quot;Butterfly Loves Flowers&quot;) The dream window was born from this, and the meaning of the poem is richer and more subtle, and on the surface it is written about the past. Joy actually implies sadness at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Visiting Chang&#39;an again&quot; is back in front of us again. Chang&#39;an refers to Lin&#39;an. Then the word &quot;sigh&quot; turns to the theme of grief and mourning, &quot;With broken collar and sleeves, who will care about the dust?&quot; Two sentences, on the one hand, describe one&#39;s miserable state of being wandering and dusty, on the other hand, they express the loss of Aiji. painful emotions. &quot;Who washes the dust?&quot; is a rhetorical question, tactfully revealing the honesty and simplicity of the relationship with Shou Ji in the past. It means: Every time I came to Lin&#39;an in the past, I would have Ai Ji wash the dust and wash clothes for me, and she was gentle and considerate. Unparalleled; this time I returned to the old place, but the house was empty, and I could no longer see anyone who cared for me. This is indeed similar to He Zhu&#39;s eulogy &quot;Lying on an empty bed listening to the rain outside the south window, who will turn on the lamp to mend clothes at night&quot; (&quot;Half-Dead Tong&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the old love cannot be restored, the old home can still be found. &quot;Ziqumen is deserted, along the long well, and the wind shakes the green vines. To the east, there is still Zeng&#39;s nest, and there are two swallows in mourning.&quot; The narrative is about the experience and feelings of revisiting the old residence, which is the key part of the whole poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ziqu, in the old days, referred to Fangqu where prostitutes lived. These places used to be places with a constant flow of passers-by, but now they are deserted and desolate. In the yard, there is only one long well, with green vines covering the well platform, swaying gently in the breeze. There is deathly silence all around, only the two swallows whispering to each other still perch on the old beams in the east (seemingly telling all kinds of misfortunes in the world). Here, there are five consecutive sentences describing the scene. Among them, the dialogue between the winding green vines and the two swallows uses a dynamic and static description technique, which has a very good artistic effect. The words &quot;Xie Tang&#39;s Swallows&quot; come from Liu Yuxi&#39;s poem &quot;Wo Yi Xiang&quot;, &quot;In the old days, the king Xie Tang&#39;s swallows flew into the homes of ordinary people.&quot; In addition to expressing the vicissitudes of human life, it also uses pairs of swallows to contrast the situation. My loneliness and sadness after losing my partner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the next film, Xie Tang Shuangyan evokes the beautiful memories of the past love life. The life of love is like a spring dream: sweet and gentle, but erratic and short-lived. Mengchuang says directly here: &quot;Spring dreams in the human world must be discontinued&quot;, must, should, must. According to the law of development of things, no matter how perfect the marriage or the happiest love, sooner or later it will end. Then, he went a step further and said: &quot;But it&#39;s strange that the dream relationship can be short-lived!&quot; What&#39;s strange is just: how could the fate between himself and Aiji be so short-lived! Neng means the same as &quot;恁&quot;. Although the passing dream is short, it is infinitely nostalgic. The following text will focus on the memory of the word &quot;dream&quot; and unfold it. Looking back on those days, there was a beautiful woman hiding in the embroidered house, and her delicate fingers pressed against the Qin Zheng. The most unforgettable thing is that the two of them stayed close to the flower branches, held a banquet late at night, and got drunk among the flowers. At this time, the wind has passed and the clouds have dispersed, and &quot;the dance has stopped and the song has subsided.&quot; Although the red flower is still beautiful, the flower-like human face has long since withered. Where can I find her graceful dancing posture and melodious singing voice! This memory chooses the beautiful scene of the Begonia Night Banquet, uses contrast and foil techniques, and uses flowers to set off the people. It focuses on expressing the poet&#39;s nostalgia and condolences for the beautiful family like flowers. The sadness is overflowing with words and has a strong appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last two sentences return to reality and express love with the scenery. I don’t know when the lyricist has quietly moved and stood on the bridge, with tears on his breasts and tears in his eyes, lingering in the afterglow of the setting sun. Shirdi bid farewell to his old residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Wenying is an expert at expressing erotic feelings. He is good at quoting the thoughts in his heart and singing songs of love and melancholy in a loop. He is also good at embodying feelings in scenery, placing his feelings on things, and using the scenery to express himself. true emotions. The layout of this poem is detailed and coherent throughout, starting with lakes and mountains, and ending with rivers and bridges. The writing is as delicate as a pearl, and it shows the best of what a talented person can do. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 1&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; When Wu Wenying lived in Hangzhou, he once had a concubine who was good at singing and dancing and fell in love with her deeply. Unfortunately, she died shortly after parting with her. This poem was written as a mourning poem for the time when he returned to his old residence and commemorated the death of his concubine in Hangzhou. The first film describes the withered scene seen when revisiting the old place, while the second film recalls the joy and happiness of the past life. In contrast, it expresses the sorrow of the sad times and highlights the sentimental feelings of loss. The first three sentences are written from the time of separation, connecting the present and the past. Chen Xuan&#39;s &quot;Hai Xiao Shuo Ci&quot; says: When I visit my former residence, I miss my homeland. After reading this word, it can be seen that the traces of wine and crying when the author said goodbye are still there, and the traces of the joys and sorrows of the past are still there. The following is also an emotional setting. The three lines of &quot;Visiting Chang&#39;an again&quot; are extremely sad and euphemistic, euphemistically showing the former beloved concubine&#39;s thoughtfulness and tenderness towards the author, as well as the poet&#39;s deep memory for the deceased. The following part of &quot;Purple Song&quot; writes about the experience and deep feelings of revisiting the old residence. It not only expresses the feeling of right and wrong, but also expresses the decline and chaos of the times in a subtle way. The last sentence uses twin swallows to contrast the loneliness of the poet, and also leads to the memory of the happy life of two people in the past in the next film. There are three sentences in &quot;Xiuwu&quot;, one is about indoors and the other is about night. It is joyful all the time and everywhere. The last few sentences came to mind. Use scenery to express feelings. The author bid farewell to his old home in the sunset with tears on his breast, tears in his eyes, and sadness in his heart. The situation is all present, and the aftertaste is long. This poem has two lyrical clues: one is the poet&#39;s personal love, that is, the love of recalling Ji; the other is the expression of the public anger of the people at that time, that is, the fear of national subjugation. Combining personal feelings of life experience with concern for the prosperity and survival of the country is the characteristic of this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wuwenying.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wu Wenying (approximately 1200-1260), whose courtesy name was Junte, also known as Mengchuang, and in his later years also known as Jueweng, was born in Siming (now Ningbo, Zhejiang). The original surname was Weng, and later he was the descendant of Wu. Be friendly with Jia Sidao. There is a &quot;Mengchuang Ci Collection&quot;, which contains more than 340 poems, divided into four volumes and one volume. His Ci poems are abundant in quantity, elegant in style, and contain many poems that respond to grief, grief, and memories, and are known as &quot;Li Shangyin in Ci&quot;. However, later generations&#39; criticisms are controversial. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[善哉行·伤古曲无知音 | 贯休]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310152]]><description> &lt;h2>;Shan Zaixing·Sad to Ancient Songs and No Sound&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Guan Xiu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;There is a beautiful person, graceful as green. Recognize the music and distinguish the sounds, making the posture brilliant. &lt;br />;Embroidered sleeves and holding the harp, I ascend to the gentleman&#39;s hall. Like the day lily, it makes me forget. &lt;br />;I would like to give him a purple jade ruler and a silver pan. Long time no see, the Xiang River is vast. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;① Qingyang: refers to the beauty of a woman’s eyebrows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;②Sentimental, attached to appearance. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/guanxiu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Guan Xiu (832-912), whose common surname was Jiang and whose courtesy name was Deyin, was from Lanxi, Wuzhou (now Yangtiantian, Youbu Town, Lanxi City, Zhejiang Province). He was a painting monk and poet monk in the former Shu during the late Tang Dynasty and the Five Dynasties. He became a monk at the age of seven and became a monk in He&#39;an Temple. He read thousands of words of scriptures every day and had a photographic memory. Tang Tianfujian entered Shu and was named &quot;Master Zenyue&quot; by the former lord of Shu, Wang Jian, and was given purple clothes. Guanxiu is good at poetry, and his poetry is famous for its high verses, which Yu Neixian knows well. There is a saying that goes: &quot;If you grow old with a bottle and a bowl, you can get it from thousands of rivers and mountains.&quot; At that time, he was called &quot;Monk Dede&quot;. There is &quot;Zenyueji&quot; in existence. He is also good at painting, especially the Arhats whose appearance is ancient and unconventional, with strong brushwork. The characters have thick eyebrows, big eyes, plump cheeks and high noses, and the image is exaggerated, so-called &quot;Sanskrit appearance&quot;. In the history of Chinese painting, it has a high reputation. The surviving &quot;Sixteen Arhats&quot; is his representative work. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:23:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>