<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[双双燕·咏燕 | 史达祖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239251]]><description> &lt;h2>;Shuangshuangyan·Yongyan&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Shi Dazu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;I have passed the Spring Society, and I spent the last year in the middle of the curtain, dusty and cold. If you want to stay in the wrong place, try to merge into the old nest. There is also a Diaoliang caisson. Also soft-spoken and indecisive. The floating flowers are blowing quickly, and the green tail separates the red shadow. &lt;br />;Fragrant path. Celery mud is moistened by rain. They love to stick to the ground and fight to fly, competing to praise their beauty. Returning to the Red Mansion late, I can see the dim willow trees and dim flowers. You should live in a stable and fragrant environment. Then I forgot, Tianya Fangxin. Worried about the loss of the two moths of Cuidai, I draw alone every day. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Spring Society Day has just passed, and you are flying through the curtains of the pavilion. The beams were covered with dust from the old year and were deserted. I parted my wings and wanted to stop, and then I tried to get into the old nest and sleep together. He looked curiously at the Diaoliang caisson, and murmured softly to discuss it. Suddenly, it floats up and passes over the flower tips, and the cut green tail cuts through the red flower shadow. &lt;br />;The aroma fills the path, and the spring rain melts the celery mud. They like to stick to the ground and compete with each other, as if they are competing to see who is more handsome and light. It was getting late when I returned to the Red Mansion, and I had seen enough of the shadows of willow branches and flowers in the dim light. But I only cared about resting safely in my nest, and I forgot to read the letter from the wanderer from the end of the world. This makes the haggard beauty in the boudoir very sad. She looks through her eyes and draws fences every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Chunshe: A social day in ancient spring to worship the Earth God. On the fifth Wu day after the beginning of spring. &lt;br />;Degree: through. Curtain: In ancient times, wealthy people hung many curtains in their courtyards. &lt;br />;Cī Chi: When swallows fly, they fly first and then later, with the tail fins stretched. &quot;The Book of Songs·Beifeng·Yanyan&quot;: &quot;The swallow is flying, but its feathers are incomparable.&quot;&lt;br />;Phase (xiàng): look at it, look carefully. Carved beams: roof beams with carved or painted patterns. Caijing: A ceiling decorated with colorful patterns, shaped like a well railing, so it is called a caisson. &lt;br />;Soft words: the murmuring of swallows. &lt;br />;Cuiwei: green swallowtail. Red shadow: flower shadow. &lt;br />;Fragrant Path: a path with flowers and grass. &lt;br />;Celery mud: the soil where celery grows near the water. &lt;br />;Red Mansion: The residence of wealthy people. &lt;br />;The willows are dim and the flowers are dim. Ming: The sky is dim. &lt;br />;Qixiang: The habitat is sweet and sleeps well. &lt;br />;Tianya Fangxin: Deliver letters from far away to your loved ones. In ancient times, there was a saying about Shuangyan passing down letters. &lt;br />;Cuidai Shuangmo: refers to the young woman in the boudoir. &lt;br />;Dai moth: Luozi Dai is the pigment used by women to paint their eyebrows. Its color is blue and black, or it can be used to replace eyebrows. The eyebrows are as thin as moth whiskers, which are called moth eyebrows. Some even use eyebrows to refer to beauty. &lt;br />;Painting: carved railing. Ping: rely on. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Swallow is a commonly used image in ancient poetry, such as poems by Du Fu, poems such as Yan Shu, etc. However, the beauty of swallows is that the whole poem in classical poetry As for lyrics, the first one to recommend is &quot;Shuang Shuang Yan&quot; by Shi Dazu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The description of swallows in this poem is extremely wonderful. The word &quot;Yan&quot; does not appear in the whole article, but every sentence is written about &quot;Yan&quot;, which is extremely beautiful and full of beauty. And it doesn’t feel complicated. &quot;It&#39;s time to celebrate the Spring Festival&quot;, &quot;Spring Club&quot; is around the vernal equinox, which is the season when spring flowers bloom. According to legend, swallows return from the south to the north at this time. The poet only points out the festival time, so that readers can naturally think of the return of swallows. The wonderful thing here is that there is a hint of preparedness for a rainy day, which not only saves words, but also makes the poem implicit and implicit, mobilizing the reader&#39;s imagination. &quot;In the middle of the curtain&quot; further hints at the return of the swallow. &quot;Last year the dust was cold&quot; implies the return of the old Yan and new changes. In the beautiful spring scenery of nature, the swallows returning from the north fly into the curtain of their old home. The red mansions and the carved beams and caissons are still the same, but the difference is that there is no one in the empty house and the eyes are full of dust, which inevitably makes the swallows feel a little desolate and desolate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The four sentences &quot;I want to live in the wrong place&quot; describe the scene of Shuangyan wanting to live but hesitating. Because it has been some time since the swallows left their old nests, and the &quot;last year was cold and dusty&quot;, there seems to be some changes, so they must first &quot;walk&quot; between the curtains and &quot;experience&quot; them to take a closer look at the familiar environment. After all, the swallows were nostalgic for the old nest, so they &quot;wanted to live in the wrong place and tried to merge with the old nest.&quot; Because he &quot;wanted to live in it&quot; and &quot;tried it in&quot;, he was hesitant, so he looked at the &quot;Diaoliang Caojing&quot; carefully and &quot;weakly discussed it&quot;. The little love story is written in a delicate and tortuous way, like a young couple spending their time at home, which is quite interesting. Shen Jifei commented on these lines and said: &quot;The words &#39;desire&#39;, &#39;test&#39;, &#39;huan&#39;, and &#39;you&#39; are wonderful.&quot; (&quot;The Complete Collection of Caotang Poems&quot;) The beauty lies in these four empty characters. Layer by layer, Shuangyan&#39;s psychological and emotional changes are conveyed vividly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The soft words are undecidable&quot; describes Yan&#39;s murmuring, which is very expressive and wonderful. &quot;Undecided&quot; expresses Shuangyan&#39;s intimate discussion with one sentence for you and one for me. &quot;Soft Words&quot;, with its soft and gentle voice and vivid image of tenderness, depicts the two swallows as a couple full of tenderness and affection. People often use swallows to describe a couple, and this description is very suitable for the characteristics of the swallow couple. Perhaps it was inspired by the wonderful writing of poems! Sure enough, as a result of the &quot;discussion&quot;, the Yan couple decided to settle down here. As a result, they &quot;floated quickly, their green tails separated their red shadows,&quot; and began a busy, tense and happy new life in the beautiful spring scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The path is fragrant, and the celery mud is moist with rain.&quot; Purple swallows often use celery mud to build their nests. Precisely because the weather here is smooth and the celery mud is particularly moist, it is really a good place to settle down and set up a business. The swallows are in the right place, and both are happy. Soaring down from the sky and flying close to the ground, you chase each other, as if competing to see who can fly more lightly and beautifully. The vast and fertile north is far more than just qinni. There are flowers, willows, everything here, and the scenery is endless. The swallow was intoxicated, flying around for sightseeing, playing until dark before flying back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When I return home late from the Red Mansion, I can see the willows dim and dim.&quot; The spring scenery is so beautiful, and their lives are so happy, free, and perfect. Returning in the evening, living and breathing in both places, it is endless fun. However, with this joy, &quot;I forgot about the wonderful news from the end of the world.&quot; Before Shuangyan returned, a wanderer from the far end of the world asked them to bring back a letter to his family, but they all forgot about it! This sudden stroke of fortune was unexpected. With this turning point, the scene of a missing woman in a red building leaning on the railing and gazing out appeared: &quot;Sorrowful about the loss of the emerald green moths, I draw the railing alone every day.&quot; Because of Shuangyan&#39;s negligence, the recipient was sad and disappointed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These last two sentences seem to have left the swallows chanted throughout the article and turned to writing about the missing wife in the Red Mansion. It seems to be off topic, but it is not. This is the originality of the poet. Just imagine why the poet spent so much pen and ink describing the swallows lingering in the old nest, wanting to stay but still resting? For Yanzi, he felt the new change of &quot;last year&#39;s cold dust&quot;. In fact, this was a personnel change that suggested that people left the world and became lonely in the boudoir, but it was never revealed. At the end, the meaning is pushed aside a layer, and it blends into the boudoir feeling and has a lingering charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It turns out that when the poet described the two swallows, he intended to write them in the cold environment of the Red Mansion, where he misses his wife and misses his spring. He uses the happy life of the two swallows inseparable, secretly and thinking He contrasts the lonely life of the woman who is &quot;alone with the painting fence&quot;; then he writes about a pair of swallows enjoying the beautiful scenery of nature, secretly contrasting it with the fate of the missing woman who is &quot;sorrowful about the loss of the two moths.&quot; Obviously, the author&#39;s description of Yanzi&#39;s free, happy and happy life implies some kind of emotion and sustenance of life. This writing method breaks the convention of writing about people as the main subject in the theme structure of Song Dynasty poems, and writes about Yan as the main subject and people as the guest; writing about the sorrow of the missing woman in the Red Mansion is just to contrast the happy life of Shuang Yan, giving people a refreshing feeling. Readers will naturally think of human tragedy from Yan&#39;s happiness, but the author intentionally leaves it to the readers to experience it themselves. This kind of writing is full of charm because of the extra twists and turns, so it can reflect life more implicitly and profoundly, which is really unique. However, when writing about swallows and people, they are in contrast to each other and are closely connected, neither inseparable nor inseparable. This is indeed a desperate situation in the poem about swallows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a poem about things, &quot;Two Swallows&quot; has received the highest praise from its predecessors. Wang Shizhen said: &quot;To this point in chanting things, man&#39;s ingenuity is extremely ingenious!&quot; (&quot;Flowers and Grass&quot;) This poem successfully portrays the beautiful image of swallows living and sleeping in love and admiration. While personifying swallows, Describing their movements and expressions, and striving to match the characteristics of swallows in every aspect, to the point where they are similar in form and spirit, the swallows are really brought to life. For example, the same story depicts the flight of swallows, with several different postures. &quot;Floating quickly, brushing the flower tips, and the green tail separates the red shadow&quot; describes the situation of swallows catching insects in flight and passing by the branches of flowers and trees. &quot;Piaoran&quot; not only expresses the lightness of the swallow, but it is not flying aimlessly in the sky, but hunting for food, so it is also said to be &quot;quickly flying to spend money&quot;. Precisely because swallows fly lightly and are small in size, when they fly, their green tail is like an open pair of scissors passing over the &quot;flower tips&quot;, as if &quot;parting the red shadow&quot;. &quot;Love to stick to the ground and fight to fly&quot; is another unique flying posture of swallows. When the sky is cloudy and it is about to rain, swallows fly very low. It can be seen that the poet&#39;s observation of swallows is extremely delicate and his words are very precise. The poem describes the habit of swallows chewing mud to build nests, and the soft whispering sounds, both of which are unflattering. &quot;Curtain&quot;, &quot;Carved beam caisson&quot;, &quot;Fragrant path&quot;, &quot;Qinniyu moistening&quot;, etc. are also common examples of describing swallows in poetry. &quot;Cai Chi wants to live&quot;, the word &quot;Cai Chi&quot; originally comes from &quot;The Book of Songs·Beifeng·Yanyan&quot;: &quot;Yanyan is flying, and it is a waste of its feathers.&quot; &quot;Qinni is moistened by rain&quot;, &quot;Qinni&quot; comes from Du Fu&#39;s &quot;Xu Bu&quot; &quot;Poetry: &quot;The celery mud follows the swallow&#39;s mouth.&quot; &quot;Then I forgot about the fragrant letter from the end of the world&quot; is an adaptation of the poetic meaning of &quot;Miscellaneous Poems: Pretending Captain Li to Join the Army&quot; by Jiang Yan of the Liang Dynasty in the Southern Dynasty, &quot;But I am thousands of miles away, and my hair is knotted and I don&#39;t see each other; I have short sleeves, and I would like to send two flying swallows.&quot; Shuangyan forgot to send a book to write. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem depicts the two swallows, and has the merits of Huan Qi Jingmai. It is worthy of being a top-notch poem about things. As for seeking a deeper metaphor, there is no such thing. Some commentators believe that the four sentences &quot;Returning to the Red Mansion at Night&quot; have an overtone metaphor for the events of Han Guanzhou. Although an explanation can be prepared, it will inevitably go too deep, which will damage the story. The first poem has a profound and detailed rhythm. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/shidazu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Shi Dazu 1163～1220? Nian, named Bangqing and named Meixi, from Bian (Kaifeng, Henan). He never passed the exam and served as a staff member in his early years. When Han Yuzhou was in power, he was the most trusted official and was responsible for writing documents. Han was defeated, Shi Lian was tattooed and died in poverty. Shi Dazu&#39;s poems are mostly composed of poems about objects, including a sense of life experience. He also exercised gold in Ningzong&#39;s northward direction. This part of the Northbound Ci is full of a sad feeling of home and country. Today there is &quot;Meixi Ci&quot;. There are 112 words saved. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公无渡河 | 李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239242]]><description> &lt;h2>;Gong Wu Crosses the River&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Li Bai&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The Yellow River comes from the west to conquer Kunlun, roaring for thousands of miles and touching the Dragon Gate. &lt;br />;The waves surged into the sky, and Yao sighed. &lt;br />;Dayu managed hundreds of rivers, but his children could not see home when they cried. &lt;br />;Kill the turbulence and drown the flood, and silkworms begin to grow in Kyushu. &lt;br />;The harm is gone, and the wind and sand are at a loss. &lt;br />;The old man was mad and crazy, and he wanted to laugh at him early in the morning. &lt;br />;Others don’t hesitate to let their wives stop him, but the public has no intention of crossing the river and has to cross the river. &lt;br />;The tiger can be fought, but the river is difficult to rely on. The male fruit drowns in the Mekong River. &lt;br />;There is a long whale with white teeth like snow-capped mountains, hanging among them. &lt;br />;Honghou’s sorrow was not returned. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The water of the Yellow River comes from the west, it breaks through Kunlun, roars for thousands of miles, and impacts Gantry. &lt;br />;Emperor Yao once lamented over this monstrous flood. &lt;br />;In order to control the Jutian flood that flooded hundreds of rivers, Dayu ran away from home regardless of his children&#39;s cries. &lt;br />;During the days of flood control, he passed through the house three times without entering, and he worked hard for the public good. Only then did the floods get under control, and people all over the world returned to a peaceful life where men farmed and women weaved. &lt;br />;Although the water damage was eliminated, the disaster of wind and sand remained. &lt;br />;In ancient times, there was a crazy man. He rushed out early in the morning with disheveled hair to cross the river on foot. &lt;br />;Others just watched the excitement, and only his wife went to stop him, shouting from behind to ask him not to cross the river, but he insisted on jumping into the river. &lt;br />;Although the tiger can be restrained, the river cannot be crossed. As expected, the madman was drowned in the water, and his body drifted with the current to the sea. &lt;br />;Being swallowed by the long whale with white teeth like mountains. &lt;br />;The wife played the harp and sang tragic songs. Unfortunately, her husband never came back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Kunlun: Kunlun Mountain. &lt;br />;Longmen: Longmen Mountain is located fifty miles northeast of Hancheng, Shaanxi Province, with the Yellow River flowing through it. &lt;br />;Li: that is, governance. People in the Tang Dynasty avoided the taboo of Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty and changed &quot;governance&quot; to &quot;li&quot;. &lt;br />;Peering into the home: Dayu went out to control floods for eight years, but failed to enter his home three times. &lt;br />;Wind and sand, this sentence means that although the water will not cause monstrous disasters, it will still be harmed by wind and sand. &lt;br />;By: Crossing the river on foot. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; At the beginning of Li Bai&#39;s poem &quot;The Public Does Not Cross the River&quot;, he extends his huge pen to the vast and distant past - &quot;The Yellow River comes west to decide... Kunlun, roaring for thousands of miles, touches the dragon gate!” The poem uses words of sudden exclamation to describe how it instantly clashed with the Kunlun Mountains, a symbol of power and momentum that spans the sky and the earth; then with a thunderous &quot;roar&quot;, it hit the &quot;Dragon Gate&quot; &quot;thousands of miles away&quot; (Today&#39;s northwest of Hejin County, Shanxi). With only two strokes, the poet showed the infinite prestige of the Yellow River &quot;coming from the west&quot; amidst the vibrations of &quot;Kunlun&quot; and &quot;Longmen&quot;. &quot;The waves surged into the sky, and Yao Zhi groaned&quot;! The huge waves swallowed up countless living people, and the vast wilderness of ancient times was suddenly filled with the awe-inspiring sighs of Emperor Yao Fangxun: Because the poem uses short sentences of three words, the sigh sounds more passionate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Then, &quot;Dayu&quot; appeared. The myth and legend of Dayu&#39;s flood control could have inspired many strange thoughts in poets. However, this section focuses on describing the Yellow River, so the poem only uses four lines of &quot;Dayu managed all the rivers&quot; to show how the unruly and violent floods were tamed under the feet of this hero. However, in the close scene of &quot;killing the flood&quot;, the poet added a few words of &quot;son of Yu&quot; &quot;son cry&quot;, &quot;son cries but does not return home&quot;, just five words make a man forget his own selfishness and &quot;three faults&quot;. The heroic demeanor of flood control &quot;without entering the house&quot; emerges vividly from this. The ancient harm of the Yellow River has since been eliminated, but when its waves returned in a turbulent way, they left behind &quot;borderless wind and sand&quot; on both sides! The above section starts from the ancient river damage to the relief of monstrous floods. It not only shows the majestic state of the Yellow River in the west &quot;defeating Kunlun&quot; and the east &quot;touching the Dragon Gate&quot;, but also allows readers to appreciate its unique violent and raging nature from its &quot;roaring waves&quot; historical harm. It lays the foundation for what follows. Now, the white-haired old man wants to cross the river &quot;by the river&quot; (wading across the river). Isn&#39;t he afraid of being swallowed up by it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last stanza of the poem, Zheng, with great confusion, calls out to the tragic hero: &quot;The old man who was attacked is crazy and crazy, and he wants to laugh at him in the morning?&quot; This cry seems to be &quot;Crazy man&quot; &quot;My wife suddenly exclaimed! Because the poet immediately introduced the affectionate wife who &quot;others do not hesitate to stop&quot; after the mad husband &quot;comes to love&quot;. As a result, the scene of the whole poem undergoes an astonishing sudden change: amidst the roaring waves, the poet himself disappears, leaving only a shaggy-haired woman mourning and singing in front of him: &quot;Tiger can be fought, but rivers are difficult to rely on.&quot; . The male fruit drowned in the waves of the sea (waterside). There is a long whale with white teeth like a snow mountain, male! Male! Hanging in the middle!&quot; The poem uses exaggerated pen and ink to sing about the drowning of the crazy old man in the waves, and finally writes He killed the whale-toothed ghost as huge as a &quot;snow mountain&quot;. The sight was horrific. What&#39;s more, it is written from the wailing of the mad husband&#39;s wife who &quot;sings to the help of the harp and harp&quot;, and it feels even more tragic that the world is spinning and the earth is spinning, wailing pitifully. The cry of &quot;Gonghu! Gonghu&quot; trembles in the readers&#39; ears, which is really unbearable to listen to. At the end, the poet suddenly changed from a double line to a single line. He seemed to be enveloped in grief and indignation, and could not say anything more, so he threw up his pen and sighed: &quot;The sorrow of Kong Hou is not returned!&quot; The whole poem ends like this. The waves on the cracked bank of the Yellow River are still raging, but the pitiful cries of the &quot;crazy husband&#39;s&quot; wife still overwhelm the waves and echo throughout the world! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Judging from the description of the Yellow River in the poem, its violent and raging shape, which harms the people, seems to be quite symbolic; as for the &quot;long whale&quot; with &quot;white teeth like snow-capped mountains&quot;, it seems to be something else. Something pointed out. If it is a metaphor for the Anshi Rebellion that was rampant in &quot;Hebei&quot; (such as the poem &quot;Northward Journey&quot;, which uses &quot;running whales across the Yellow River&quot; as a metaphor for the Anlu Mountain rebellion), then the &quot;distribution of hair&quot; of &quot;linliu&quot; and &quot;by the river&quot; Who does &quot;the old man&quot; refer to? Or is this just a tragic song that expresses the &quot;ability&quot; of &quot;The Public Does Not Cross the River&quot; without any other sentiments? It is certain that the story of the &quot;white-headed madman&quot; crossing the river in the ancient song has a stronger tragic color after Li Bai&#39;s re-creation. The &quot;crazy and crazy&quot; old man with disheveled hair seemed to be pursuing something hard. There are traces of poets persistently pursuing their ideals. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The specific year of creation of this poem is difficult to verify. Most people believe that this poem was written before An Lushan&#39;s rebellion, when Li Bai went to Youzhou (Beijing) to conduct detective work at his own expense. Some people also think that it may have been written after King Yong Li Lin was suppressed, when King Yong&#39;s envoy Wei Zichun came with five hundred taels of gold to invite Li Bai down the mountain. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/libai.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Li Bai (701-762), also known as Taibai, also known as Qinglian Jushi, also known as &quot;The Exiled Immortal&quot;, was a great romantic poet in the Tang Dynasty and was hailed as the &quot;Poetry Immortal&quot; by later generations. &quot;, together with Du Fu are called &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, namely &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively called &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. According to the &quot;New Book of Tang&quot; records, Li Bai was the ninth grandson of Emperor Xingsheng (Liang Wuzhao King Li Hao) and the same clan as the kings of Li and Tang Dynasties. He is a cheerful and generous person who loves drinking, writing poetry, and making friends. Li Bai was deeply influenced by Huang Lao Liezhuang&#39;s thoughts. The &quot;Collection of Li Taibai&quot; has been handed down from generation to generation. Most of his poems were written when he was drunk. His representative works include &quot;Wang Lushan Waterfall&quot;, &quot;The Road is Difficult&quot;, &quot;The Road to Shu is Difficult&quot;, &quot;About Wine&quot; and &quot;Morning&quot;. &quot;Fa Baidi City&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 05:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>