<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[冀州道中 | 王冕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310292]]><description> &lt;h2>;In the middle of Jizhou Road&lt;/h2>;[Yuan Dynasty] Wang Mian&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;I walked along Jizhou Road and meditated on the ancient imperial capital. &lt;br />;The water and soil may be different from the past, and the Yu tribute book is also different. &lt;br />;The city wall is like a village dock, and the rain and snow are heavy. &lt;br />;The thin bushes gather frozen birds, and the foxes roar withered trees. &lt;br />;Cold clouds cover my scarf, and cold wind tears my undershirt. &lt;br />;As soon as Xu Heng exhaled, his mustache was covered with ice. &lt;br />;Cheng Cheng watched the fireworks, and there were few people living along the road. &lt;br />;You can’t buy millet, and you can’t get glutinous rice. &lt;br />;The roots of the mulberry tree in the earthen house look like wine. &lt;br />;Wander around and ask Mr. Ye, can you lend me the kitchen? &lt;br />;Ye Laoxin welcomes me with a smile, and comes close to hold my skirt. &lt;br />;The hot water warms my hands, and the fire warms my body. &lt;br />;Don&#39;t wash your face, as washing your face will damage your skin. &lt;br />;I know the old man is kind-hearted and slowly drives away the servants. &lt;br />;Asking Lao He clan? Yun is Yi Shiru. &lt;br />;Since the coming of the great dynasty, what I have learned has become the first to become a bandit. &lt;br />;The people were recruited to fight for the garrison, and they were all bow and arrow disciples. &lt;br />;Even if we have good children and grandchildren, they are no different than dogs and pigs. &lt;br />;Now that I am an old man, I cannot read a word. &lt;br />;There are no allusions, so where are the etiquette and righteousness? &lt;br />;When I talk about my grandfather, I feel pain in my bones. &lt;br />;I heard the sudden sigh of relief, holding my hand empty and hesitated. &lt;br />;Hesitating towards the sky, when will I find hope again? &lt;br />;Crying and unable to bear words, I flutter my sleeves in the southwest corner. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;I was walking on the road in Jizhou, silently missing the capital of my motherland. &lt;br />;Maybe the current geographical environment is different from the past; maybe the geographical divisions in &quot;Yu Gong&quot; are very different from now. &lt;br />;The city is as desolate as a village, despite the heavy rain and snow. &lt;br />;There are frozen birds gathering in the woods, and foxes howl beside the dead trees. &lt;br />;The low cold clouds seemed to be pressing down on my hat, and the cold wind tore my clothes. &lt;br />;Sometimes when I look up, the white breath coming out of my mouth turns into ice slag and is covered with beards. &lt;br />;I walked one step at a time, hoping to find someone else’s home, but there were very few people living on both sides of the road. &lt;br />;There is no place to buy millet, and no wine. &lt;br />;Beside the bent and dry roots of the mulberry tree in front, a low earthen house appeared, which looked like a hotel. &lt;br />;I hesitated and asked Ye Lao: Can you borrow the kitchen for me to use? &lt;br />;When Ye Lao saw us, he greeted us with a smile and held my lapel. &lt;br />;He brought me hot water to warm my hands and asked me to sit on the hot bed. &lt;br />;And I have been repeatedly warned not to wash your face with water, because if your face has been frozen for a long time, it will easily break when exposed to water. &lt;br />;I was very touched by the old man&#39;s hospitality and slowly sent the servant away so that we could talk in secret. &lt;br />;I quickly asked Ye Lao which family he was born into? He replied: &quot;Our family has been scholars for generations.&lt;br />;Since the Mongolian nobles came, the rules and systems have been completely different from the original ones.&lt;br />;When the people registered to fight, they all became archers.&lt;br />; />;No matter how good the children and grandchildren are, they are just like pigs and dogs.&lt;br />;An old man like me doesn’t even know a word of the word.&lt;br />;All morals and laws are not excessive, and etiquette and justice are not restricted.&lt;br / >;When I talk about my grandfather and father, the sadness is still deep in my bones!”&lt;br />;After hearing the old man’s tearful words, I sighed and held his hand, but I was speechless. &lt;br />;For a long time, I can only ask the sky, when will we die and be resurrected! &lt;br />;We all sobbed and cried, getting angry facing the southwest corner of the room where the gods are worshipped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Jizhou: the area in the south-central part of present-day Hebei Province, the western end of Shandong Province, and the northern end of Henan Province. &lt;br />;Ancient imperial capital: Jizhou is one of the nine ancient states. According to &quot;Yu Gong&quot;, the nine states are Jizhou, Yanzhou, Qingzhou, Xuzhou, Yangzhou, Jingzhou, Liangzhou, Yongzhou and Yuzhou. According to &quot;Historical Records: The Chronicles of the Five Emperors&quot;, after the Yellow Emperor killed Chiyou, the princes revered him as the emperor, and &quot;the city was located in Zhuolu&quot;. Zhuolu also belonged to the ancient Jizhou area, so it was called the ancient imperial capital. &lt;br />;Yugong: An article in &quot;Shangshu&quot; is China&#39;s earliest geographical work, recording the mountains, rivers, geographical transportation, products and other conditions mainly in the Yellow River Basin. &lt;br />;Cunwu: Village in the mountains, the sentence means that the once prosperous city is now like a desolate and desolate mountain village. &lt;br />;Zai Tu: full of roads. &lt;br />;Congbu: The place where vegetation grows. &lt;br />;Rú (rú): short coat, combined coat. &lt;br />;Xū (xū) Heng: Raise your eyebrows and raise your eyes. Xu, open your eyes and look up. Heng, above the eyebrows. &lt;br />;Lingling: ice. &lt;br />;醪(láo): turbid wine.酤: means “gu” to buy wine. &lt;br />;Lú (lú): The earthen platform where the wine jars are placed in the hotel. &lt;br />;Ju (jū): the front and back parts of clothing. &lt;br />;Drive the servant away: Send the servant away so that he can have a heart-to-heart talk with the old man. &lt;br />;Yi Shiru: A scholar who has been a scholar for generations. Yi, tired, heavy. &lt;br />;Dachao: refers to the Yuan Dynasty. &lt;br />;Liang: Same as &quot;forgiveness&quot;, true and honest. &lt;br />;Registration: Registered in the book. The common people were conscripted into the army. &lt;br />;More than bone marrow: There is more than enough in the bone marrow, which means the pain is deep. &lt;br />;Hesitation (chóu chú): the appearance of being unable to stop. &lt;br />;Su (sū): The recovery of the sick body is called &quot;Su&quot;, which means recovery here. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem not only depicts the poverty and depression in northern rural areas, but also writes about the hospitable, sincere and simple character of northern farmers, criticizing The Mongol rulers destroyed Han culture. The language of this poem is simple, almost colloquial. It directly expresses what it sees and feels without any refinement. It is sincere and caring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I am walking on the Jizhou Road, thinking of the ancient imperial capital.&quot; At the beginning of the poem, the author points out the title - Jizhou Road. Then, the word &quot;meditation&quot; extends the brush strokes to the vast and vicissitudes of history, describing the antiquity and long history of Jizhou. In these two sentences, the author switches from historical contemplation to speculation on changes in the past and present, creating a clever transition for the following description of his experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fourteen sentences from &quot;a city wall is like a village dock&quot; to &quot;like a wine tree&quot; are the author&#39;s description of what he saw on the road to Jizhou. &quot;A city wall is like a village dock, and the rain and snow carry the journey hard.&quot; In the past, it was the location of a prosperous capital city, but now, the city is as decayed as the villages in the mountains; desolate, rainy and snowy, blocking the roads, making travelers miserable. In these two sentences, the author uses the decaying city and the cold rain and snow to show the desolation and desolation of Jizhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following two sentences are, &quot;The thin bushes gather frozen birds, and the foxes roar withered trees.&quot; Following the previous sentence, it further exaggerates and highlights the ruin of Jizhou. In the thickets of vegetation, frozen birds were gathering in groups, and among the dead trees, foxes also let out long and sad roars. This is the situation of birds and foxes on Jizhou Road. Then, the author changed his writing style and wrote about people from frozen birds and foxes. &quot;Cold Wind&quot; In four sentences, the poet outlines the harsh cold of midwinter in just a few strokes. The word &quot;zhu&quot; vividly describes the heavy rain and snow; the word &quot;crack&quot; vividly highlights the strength of the cold wind; and the two sentences &quot;Xu Heng exhaled, and his mustache was covered with ice&quot;. The unusually cold weather is vividly depicted through the description of a specific action. On the journey with howling foxes, howling wind, rain and snow, the poet longed to see a spark of fireworks and find some rice and wine to relieve the coldness in his body and get rid of the hunger in his belly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, &quot;Cheng Cheng watched the fireworks, and there were few people living on the roadside. There was no millet to buy, and no glutinous rice to drink.&quot; Here, the word &quot;Cheng Cheng&quot; is used very cleverly. It depicts both The author&#39;s longing psychology also shows the distance the poet traveled and the depth of hunger and cold he endured. He walked from station to station, but still could not see a trace of fireworks, a grain of rice, or a drop of wine. In these four sentences, the author adds to the misery and desolation of the road through the description of the sparsely populated area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The roots of the mulberry tree in the earth house look like wine.&quot; Suddenly, next to the bent and dry roots of the mulberry tree in front, a low earth house appeared, which looked like a hotel. In these two sentences, the author uses &quot;mulberry tree roots in the earth house&quot; to very vividly reproduce the unique and simple scenery of the northern countryside. The word &quot;as if&quot; not only describes the short and inconspicuous earth house, but also describes the wind and snow. The whole land is vague and difficult to see clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Above, the author vividly shows people the dilapidation, desolation and desolation of Yizhou from the aspects of urban decay, sparse population, and food shortage, and profoundly reveals the rulers of the Yuan Dynasty’s attitude towards this area. The looting of towns and cities severely damaged the agricultural economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Wandering around asking the old man in the field&quot; to &quot;the pain reaches my bones&quot; are the author&#39;s descriptions of what he heard on the Yizhou Road. The poet focused on describing a character who was reduced from a scholar to a wild old man. Through his words and deeds, he complained with sorrow and anger about the destruction and devastation of the Han culture caused by the war. It was sincere and moved people to tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I wandered around and asked the old man if I could lend him my kitchen.&quot; The hungry and cold poet finally found a house, but what he saw on the way made him hesitate. The horrific catastrophe made Yizhou desolate. The poet could not bear to disturb this wild old man who was surviving the disaster. The word &quot;wandering&quot; very truly describes the poet&#39;s inner conflict. But Ye Lao was beyond the poet&#39;s expectation. He smiled happily and stepped forward to roll up the poet&#39;s sleeves, as if he were a friend reunited after a long absence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the eight sentences of &quot;Ye Lao Xin welcomes you with a smile&quot;, the author uses &quot;smile&quot;, &quot;brace&quot;, &quot;warmth&quot;, &quot;warmth&quot;, &quot;admonition&quot; and &quot;I know&quot; to vividly depict Ye Lao&#39;s simple kindness and kindness. Kindness, after reading it, the image of the old man seems to be ready to emerge. Such a kind old man, the place where he lives and the family where he was born. The poet asked sincerely. The sentence &quot;Yun is Yi Shiru&quot; relieved the poet&#39;s doubts. It turns out that this old man was born in a family where generations of scholars have been studying. &quot;Since the coming of the great dynasty&quot; are the words of the old man. He exposed the rulers of the Yuan Dynasty&#39;s contempt for culture and spurred the continuous war. &quot;Even if you have good children and grandchildren, they are just like dogs and pigs.&quot; In these two sentences, the author uses the words of the old man to powerfully reveal the ignorance and ignorance of the people under the autocratic rule of the Yuan Dynasty. &quot;When talking about my grandfather, it hurts to the core of my bones.&quot; Through the old man&#39;s memories of the past, it shows the poet&#39;s nostalgia and yearning for a peaceful country and a peaceful, culturally advanced and etiquette-prosperous society. It also further highlights the poet&#39;s grief, anger and hatred for reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The following is the author&#39;s feeling. &quot;I heard the sudden sigh and hesitated with empty hands.&quot; The author couldn&#39;t help but sigh deeply after listening to the old man&#39;s narration and discussion. He sympathized with the old man&#39;s experience and hated the darkness and absurdity of this reality. He held his hand tightly. The old man&#39;s hand stopped but he couldn&#39;t stop. Here, the author describes three actions in succession: &quot;breathing&quot;, &quot;holding hands&quot; and &quot;hesitating&quot;. Each action strongly highlights the poet&#39;s inner misery. &quot;Hesitating toward the sky, when will I be able to recover again?&quot; The poet stopped, looked up, and asked the vast sky; when will this suffocating rule end and the prosperous era resume. Between the lines, there is infinite sorrow. The last two sentences were, &quot;Crying and unable to bear words, I waved my sleeves to the southwest corner.&quot; The author pushed his grief to a climax. Tears streamed down his face, and he swallowed his voice. He couldn&#39;t bear to say more sad words, so he had to walk toward the southwest alone, brushing his sleeves. go. The phrase &quot;Flick your sleeves in the southwest corner&quot; contains an air of anger in addition to grief. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a narrative poem that seems straightforward, but is actually full of emotion and strict logic. They are arranged in chronological order, and each has its own emphasis. We grasp the key points and fully describe them, revealing the theme layer by layer. First write about the desolation in the north, and then write about the specific situation of cultural destruction. From the outside to the inside, it climaxes with the poet&#39;s grief and indignation and ends abruptly. The sincerity and simplicity of the old man are written in the middle, which makes people see the excellence of traditional cultural upbringing and deepens the hatred of destruction. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; The poet traveled north to Yanjing from 1335 to 1340 AD (from Emperor Shun of the Yuan Dynasty to the first year of the Yuan Dynasty), and the poem may have been written at this time. Wang Mian was born in a peasant family, but because he gave up his official career, he wandered around the world. Jizhou is one of the nine ancient states. It is located in the Central Plains. It was originally prosperous. However, after years of war and the brutal rule of the Yuan and Mongolian nobles, its prosperity has long been gone and it is full of devastation. The poet traveled here and lamented the contrast between the past and the present. He could not help but be filled with anger and wrote this poem. This poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wangmian.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wang Mian (1287-1359), named Yuanzhang, also known as Zhuishishanong, also known as Shizhongweng, Meihua Housekeeper, etc., was born in Fengqiao, Zhuji, Shaoxing City, Zhejiang Province, and was a famous painter and poet in the Yuan Dynasty. , Seal engraver. He was born into a poor family and worked as a herdsman for others when he was young. He became a self-taught man. There are 3 volumes of &quot;Zhuzhai Collection&quot; and 2 volumes of sequels. He has loved plum blossoms all his life, planted plum blossoms, chanted plum blossoms, and painted plum blossoms. The plum blossoms painted are densely packed with branches, full of life, strong and powerful, and have a great influence on future generations. The surviving paintings include &quot;Spring Morning in Nanzhi&quot;, &quot;Dark Plum Blossoms&quot;, &quot;Three Gentlemen&quot;, etc. He was able to seal seals, and he created seals using flower milk stones, and his seal writing skills were exquisite. There is a biography in &quot;History of Ming Dynasty&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[诉衷情·永夜抛人何处去 | 顾夐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310281]]><description> &lt;h2>;Telling one’s true feelings·Where will Yong Ye leave people?&lt;/h2>;[Five Dynasties] Gu Kui&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Where will Yong Ye leave people? Absolute sound. The fragrant pavilion is hidden, the eyebrows are furrowed, and the moon is about to sink. &lt;br />;Be patient and not seek each other? Resent the lonely quilt. Change my heart for yours, and we will know each other deeply and remember each other deeply. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Where did you go when you left me in the long night? No news. The Xiang Pavilion door is closed tightly, the eyebrows are furrowed tightly, and the moon is about to set in the west. &lt;br />;How can I bear not to pursue you so hard? I resent sleeping alone. Only if you change my heart and become yours, will you know how deep this lovesickness is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Revealing one’s true feelings: Tang Jiaofang’s song title. Because Mao Wenxi&#39;s lyrics include &quot;peach blossoms flowing vertically and horizontally&quot;, it is also called &quot;Peach Blossom Water&quot;; because of Gu Kui&#39;s original lyrics, it is also called &quot;Yuangu Quilt&quot;. &lt;br />;Eternal Night: Long Night. &lt;br />;Brow frown: refers to the frowning and sad look. &lt;br />;Strive for tolerance: How to endure. &lt;br />;Guqian: metaphor for sleeping alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a monotonous little order. The first five sentences play the main theme of emotional sound - resentment. The two sentences &quot;Eternal Night&quot; remind me of the whereabouts of the betrayed person. &quot;The night is long, heartless person, where have you left me?&quot; I asked myself and answered again: &quot;I have no news, what can I do!&quot; The word &quot;Jue&quot; points out the lack of faith and heartlessness of the resentful person. The three lines of &quot;Xiang Pavilion Cover&quot; are based on the situation of the people in the boudoir. They describe the environment (the boudoir door is closed), the expression (the brows are furrowed), and the passage of time (the moon is about to set, the long night is about to end). It describes the unbearability of sitting and waiting all night. These two things boil down to one thing - resentment against the weak and resentful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the sentence &quot;Struggle for Endurance&quot;, there is a new wave in the heart. The two sentences &quot;Strive for Endurance&quot; are the first wave, characterized by endless thoughts and feelings of love and resentment. &quot;How can I bear not to pursue it so hard?&quot; This inner monologue shows that there is love in her resentment, and her love is incomprehensible. But upon further investigation, the boudoir door was closed, and there was nothing to be found in the room. The action of &quot;searching&quot; just shows that she has fallen into a confused and confused mental state. When she regained consciousness, she had to face the heartbreaking reality of being alone in a quilt, so the word &quot;resentment&quot; came to mind again. The three sentences &quot;Change my heart&quot; are the second wave, which is characterized by falling in love and suddenly speaking foolishly. Wang Shizhen of the Qing Dynasty once pointed out in &quot;Flowers and Grasses&quot;: &quot;Gu Taiwei&#39;s &#39;Change my heart for yours, and I will know that we remember each other deeply&#39;, which is a deeply affectionate saying. Xu Shanmin&#39;s concubine&#39;s heart is moved to the king&#39;s heart, only then will he know that he is hated.&quot; &quot;Shen&#39; is all about this.&quot; The word &quot;shift&quot; in Xushan&#39;s folk poems is also the true meaning of the word &quot;change&quot; in Gu&#39;s poem. To change one&#39;s mind is to change one&#39;s mind. How the protagonist hopes to put his heart into the other person&#39;s heart in order to gain the other person&#39;s understanding of how deeply he misses him. It seems unreasonable to talk about things and change one&#39;s mind, but the protagonist&#39;s crazy thoughts just show the depth of his love and the trueness of his feelings. This is the so-called &quot;irrational yet sentimental&quot;. Of course, despite this, the tragic fate of the protagonist will be inevitable. On this point, Tang Xianzu of the Ming Dynasty made it clear in his commentary on &quot;The Collection of Flowers&quot;: &quot;If you want to change your mind, it may not be good to switch to him.&quot; However, the ideological tendency of the work is very clear, and the sympathy is entirely focused on the tortured person. On the side of the weak woman who was harmed, this also slapped the thugs from the side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word Gu Kui is famous for being good at making love words. The recent scholar Wang Guowei once regarded this word as one of the outstanding examples of &quot;someone who specializes in writing love words and is exquisite&quot; in &quot;Human Words&quot;, and said: &quot;Such words are rarely seen among ancient and modern people&#39;s words.&quot; .&quot; This shows the high evaluation. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Through the heroine’s spoken inner monologue, this poem reveals the consequences of being a weak woman who was tortured by a heartless person. The psychological trauma reflects one aspect of the love tragedy in the old society. The protagonist has love in his resentment, both love and resentment, and has complicated emotions. The work shows great ingenuity in artistic conception and expression techniques, and has been highly praised by later generations of lyric critics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Where will the person go in the eternal night? Jue Laiyin.&quot; &quot;Yongye&quot; means the long night; the word &quot;throw&quot; hints at the woman&#39;s worry about her own fate. The first sentence of the question not only reveals the root cause of the woman&#39;s sorrow and resentment, but also writes about her anxiety, depression, uneasiness and doubts caused by long-awaited non-return. &quot;Jue Lai Yin&quot; is continued below, indicating that the beloved&#39;s failure to return late at night is not a forced act, but a deliberate cold reception. One sentence writes that the night is quiet and silent, highlighting the woman&#39;s loneliness; at the same time, it reveals that she is alone. During the long night, in the silence of the empty boudoir, she had been listening intently to the uneasy feeling of the sounds outside. Every sound outside the door, even the slightest, would arouse her hope, make her excited and happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The incense pavilion hides the eyebrows, and the moon is about to sink.&quot; When the fire of hope ignited and extinguished in her heart again and again, she finally understood that tonight was hopeless. The words show her inner despair. The word &quot;cover&quot; shows her emotional connection. She doesn&#39;t want to shut out the ruthless man, but still keeps the door open for him, sitting in the empty boudoir alone in front of the lonely lamp, waiting for him. &quot;Brows furrowed&quot; is the uncontrollable expression of the resentment she can&#39;t suppress deep in her heart. However, until the moon was about to set in the west, he did not give her any news or come back to accompany her. The sentence &quot;the moon is about to sink&quot; not only points out that tomorrow will dawn, it not only implies that the quiet moonlight does not bring any comfort to people, but only increases the woman&#39;s sorrow, it also reveals that the woman is suffering from resentment and has a sleepless night. , the scenes of loving each other and accompanying each other in the past are all before our eyes, adding a bit of loneliness and desolation to the desolation of sleeping alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Fighting forbearance but not finding each other? I resent the loneliness.&quot; There was complaint and grievance in her tone. The word &quot;struggle forbearance&quot; was asked rhetorically, which showed that there was love in her resentment, and the love was incomprehensible. I can&#39;t bear to be harsh, but I can&#39;t help but feel resentful. After careful consideration, it seems that I want the other party to show mercy. Tolerance or intolerance is not due to natural emotions or uncontrollable feelings, but from the idea of ​​compassion. However, upon further investigation, the door to the boudoir was closed, and the room was clearly visible and there was nothing to be found. The action of &quot;searching&quot; just shows that she has fallen into a confused and trance-like mental state. When she regained consciousness, she had to face the heartbreaking reality of being alone. The sentence &quot;resentment to the lonely quilt&quot; is short but powerful. The loneliness of being unable to sleep for a long night, and the pain of being attached to one&#39;s own emotions but not getting the corresponding response, are finally revealed directly in the word &quot;resentment&quot;. &quot;Resentment&quot; is the hatred born of love, the hatred that dares not break up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;If I change my heart for yours, we will know and remember each other deeply.&quot; She is in love and suddenly speaks foolishly. This is a woman&#39;s confession from the bottom of her heart and her sincere call to the person who has betrayed her heart. Heart-changing is also called heart-changing. The protagonist hopes to transfer his heart into the other person&#39;s heart in order to gain the other person&#39;s understanding of how deeply he misses him. If the other person is completely heartless, he will never change his mind no matter what. Even so, when the words are written like this, the emotions become more and more angry and helpless, with deep sorrow and deep pain, and the deepest sorrow. There is not only resentment towards men here, but also a deep affection for women, which makes people linger endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lyrics describe the expectations, love and resentment of an infatuated woman towards her unfaithful man. The heart cannot be replaced, so one is obsessed with love, so one wants to replace it, but the replacement cannot be obtained, which increases the resentment and sorrow. The writing of boudoir&#39;s resentment reaches this point, the image is vivid and vivid, and it cannot be added. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gu Hong, a poet of the Five Dynasties. The dates of birth and death, place of origin and trade name are unknown. During the reign of Emperor Jiantongzheng of the former Shu Dynasty (916), he sent a small minister to serve in the inner court. He saw a vulture flying on the Maha Pond, wrote a poem and stabbed it, and suffered several unexpected disasters. Later he was promoted to the governor of Maozhou. After entering Hou Shu, he was promoted to Taiwei. Gu Kui is good at poetry and lyrics. &quot;Flower Room Collection&quot; contains 55 of his poems, all of which are about erotic love between men and women. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 05:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>