<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[诉衷情·永夜抛人何处去 | 顾夐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310281]]><description> &lt;h2>;Telling one’s true feelings·Where will Yong Ye leave people?&lt;/h2>;[Five Dynasties] Gu Kui&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Where will Yong Ye leave people? Absolute sound. The fragrant pavilion is hidden, the eyebrows are furrowed, and the moon is about to sink. &lt;br />;Be patient and not seek each other? Resent the lonely quilt. Change my heart for yours, and we will know each other deeply and remember each other deeply. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Where did you go when you left me in the long night? No news. The Xiang Pavilion door is closed tightly, the eyebrows are furrowed tightly, and the moon is about to set in the west. &lt;br />;How can I bear not to pursue you so hard? I resent sleeping alone. Only if you change my heart and become yours, will you know how deep this lovesickness is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Revealing one’s true feelings: Tang Jiaofang’s song title. Because Mao Wenxi&#39;s lyrics include &quot;peach blossoms flowing vertically and horizontally&quot;, it is also called &quot;Peach Blossom Water&quot;; because of Gu Kui&#39;s original lyrics, it is also called &quot;Yuangu Quilt&quot;. &lt;br />;Eternal Night: Long Night. &lt;br />;Brow frown: refers to the frowning and sad look. &lt;br />;Strive for tolerance: How to endure. &lt;br />;Guqian: metaphor for sleeping alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a monotonous little order. The first five sentences play the main theme of emotional sound - resentment. The two sentences &quot;Eternal Night&quot; remind me of the whereabouts of the betrayed person. &quot;The night is long, heartless person, where have you left me?&quot; I asked myself and answered again: &quot;I have no news, what can I do!&quot; The word &quot;Jue&quot; points out the lack of faith and heartlessness of the resentful person. The three lines of &quot;Xiang Pavilion Cover&quot; are based on the situation of the people in the boudoir. They describe the environment (the boudoir door is closed), the expression (the brows are furrowed), and the passage of time (the moon is about to set, the long night is about to end). It describes the unbearability of sitting and waiting all night. These two things boil down to one thing - resentment against the weak and resentful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the sentence &quot;Struggle for Endurance&quot;, there is a new wave in the heart. The two sentences &quot;Strive for Endurance&quot; are the first wave, characterized by endless thoughts and feelings of love and resentment. &quot;How can I bear not to pursue it so hard?&quot; This inner monologue shows that there is love in her resentment, and her love is incomprehensible. But upon further investigation, the boudoir door was closed, and there was nothing to be found in the room. The action of &quot;searching&quot; just shows that she has fallen into a confused and confused mental state. When she regained consciousness, she had to face the heartbreaking reality of being alone in a quilt, so the word &quot;resentment&quot; came to mind again. The three sentences &quot;Change my heart&quot; are the second wave, which is characterized by falling in love and suddenly speaking foolishly. Wang Shizhen of the Qing Dynasty once pointed out in &quot;Flowers and Grasses&quot;: &quot;Gu Taiwei&#39;s &#39;Change my heart for yours, and I will know that we remember each other deeply&#39;, which is a deeply affectionate saying. Xu Shanmin&#39;s concubine&#39;s heart is moved to the king&#39;s heart, only then will he know that he is hated.&quot; &quot;Shen&#39; is all about this.&quot; The word &quot;shift&quot; in Xushan&#39;s folk poems is also the true meaning of the word &quot;change&quot; in Gu&#39;s poem. To change one&#39;s mind is to change one&#39;s mind. How the protagonist hopes to put his heart into the other person&#39;s heart in order to gain the other person&#39;s understanding of how deeply he misses him. It seems unreasonable to talk about things and change one&#39;s mind, but the protagonist&#39;s crazy thoughts just show the depth of his love and the trueness of his feelings. This is the so-called &quot;irrational yet sentimental&quot;. Of course, despite this, the tragic fate of the protagonist will be inevitable. On this point, Tang Xianzu of the Ming Dynasty made it clear in his commentary on &quot;The Collection of Flowers&quot;: &quot;If you want to change your mind, it may not be good to switch to him.&quot; However, the ideological tendency of the work is very clear, and the sympathy is entirely focused on the tortured person. On the side of the weak woman who was harmed, this also slapped the thugs from the side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word Gu Kui is famous for being good at making love words. The recent scholar Wang Guowei once regarded this word as one of the outstanding examples of &quot;someone who specializes in writing love words and is exquisite&quot; in &quot;Human Words&quot;, and said: &quot;Such words are rarely seen among ancient and modern people&#39;s words.&quot; .&quot; This shows the high evaluation. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Through the heroine’s spoken inner monologue, this poem reveals the consequences of being a weak woman who was tortured by a heartless person. The psychological trauma reflects one aspect of the love tragedy in the old society. The protagonist has love in his resentment, both love and resentment, and has complicated emotions. The work shows great ingenuity in artistic conception and expression techniques, and has been highly praised by later generations of lyric critics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Where will the person go in the eternal night? Jue Laiyin.&quot; &quot;Yongye&quot; means the long night; the word &quot;throw&quot; hints at the woman&#39;s worry about her own fate. The first sentence of the question not only reveals the root cause of the woman&#39;s sorrow and resentment, but also writes about her anxiety, depression, uneasiness and doubts caused by long-awaited non-return. &quot;Jue Lai Yin&quot; is continued below, indicating that the beloved&#39;s failure to return late at night is not a forced act, but a deliberate cold reception. One sentence writes that the night is quiet and silent, highlighting the woman&#39;s loneliness; at the same time, it reveals that she is alone. During the long night, in the silence of the empty boudoir, she had been listening intently to the uneasy feeling of the sounds outside. Every sound outside the door, even the slightest, would arouse her hope, make her excited and happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The incense pavilion hides the eyebrows, and the moon is about to sink.&quot; When the fire of hope ignited and extinguished in her heart again and again, she finally understood that tonight was hopeless. The words show her inner despair. The word &quot;cover&quot; shows her emotional connection. She doesn&#39;t want to shut out the ruthless man, but still keeps the door open for him, sitting in the empty boudoir alone in front of the lonely lamp, waiting for him. &quot;Brows furrowed&quot; is the uncontrollable expression of the resentment she can&#39;t suppress deep in her heart. However, until the moon was about to set in the west, he did not give her any news or come back to accompany her. The sentence &quot;the moon is about to sink&quot; not only points out that tomorrow will dawn, it not only implies that the quiet moonlight does not bring any comfort to people, but only increases the woman&#39;s sorrow, it also reveals that the woman is suffering from resentment and has a sleepless night. , the scenes of loving each other and accompanying each other in the past are all before our eyes, adding a bit of loneliness and desolation to the desolation of sleeping alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Fighting forbearance but not finding each other? I resent the loneliness.&quot; There was complaint and grievance in her tone. The word &quot;struggle forbearance&quot; was asked rhetorically, which showed that there was love in her resentment, and the love was incomprehensible. I can&#39;t bear to be harsh, but I can&#39;t help but feel resentful. After careful consideration, it seems that I want the other party to show mercy. Tolerance or intolerance is not due to natural emotions or uncontrollable feelings, but from the idea of ​​compassion. However, upon further investigation, the door to the boudoir was closed, and the room was clearly visible and there was nothing to be found. The action of &quot;searching&quot; just shows that she has fallen into a confused and trance-like mental state. When she regained consciousness, she had to face the heartbreaking reality of being alone. The sentence &quot;resentment to the lonely quilt&quot; is short but powerful. The loneliness of being unable to sleep for a long night, and the pain of being attached to one&#39;s own emotions but not getting the corresponding response, are finally revealed directly in the word &quot;resentment&quot;. &quot;Resentment&quot; is the hatred born of love, the hatred that dares not break up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;If I change my heart for yours, we will know and remember each other deeply.&quot; She is in love and suddenly speaks foolishly. This is a woman&#39;s confession from the bottom of her heart and her sincere call to the person who has betrayed her heart. Heart-changing is also called heart-changing. The protagonist hopes to transfer his heart into the other person&#39;s heart in order to gain the other person&#39;s understanding of how deeply he misses him. If the other person is completely heartless, he will never change his mind no matter what. Even so, when the words are written like this, the emotions become more and more angry and helpless, with deep sorrow and deep pain, and the deepest sorrow. There is not only resentment towards men here, but also a deep affection for women, which makes people linger endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lyrics describe the expectations, love and resentment of an infatuated woman towards her unfaithful man. The heart cannot be replaced, so one is obsessed with love, so one wants to replace it, but the replacement cannot be obtained, which increases the resentment and sorrow. The writing of boudoir&#39;s resentment reaches this point, the image is vivid and vivid, and it cannot be added. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gu Hong, a poet of the Five Dynasties. The dates of birth and death, place of origin and trade name are unknown. During the reign of Emperor Jiantongzheng of the former Shu Dynasty (916), he sent a small minister to serve in the inner court. He saw a vulture flying on the Maha Pond, wrote a poem and stabbed it, and suffered several unexpected disasters. Later he was promoted to the governor of Maozhou. After entering Hou Shu, he was promoted to Taiwei. Gu Kui is good at poetry and lyrics. &quot;Flower Room Collection&quot; contains 55 of his poems, all of which are about erotic love between men and women. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 05:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[渡易水歌 | 佚名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310282]]><description> &lt;h2>;Song of Crossing the Yishui&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Anonymous&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The wind is rustling and the Yishui is cold, and the strong men will never return once they are gone. (Return to the first work: Fufan)&lt;br />;Enter the tiger&#39;s den and enter the dragon&#39;s palace, look up to the sky and exhale and a white rainbow will appear. (This sentence is suspected to be a later addition) &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The wind blows rustlingly, and the water changes The cold air is blowing, and the strong man is leaving here. I swear I will not return until I complete my mission! &lt;br />;Assassinating the King of Qin is as dangerous as going to the tiger&#39;s den or the dragon&#39;s palace, but our hero&#39;s heroic spirit can make a white rainbow even when he exhales to the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xiao Xiao: refers to the sound of wind. Yishui: refers to the name of water, originating from Yixian County, Hebei Province, which was the southern boundary of Yan State at that time. &lt;br />;Xi: modal particle. &lt;br />;The strong man: here refers to Jing Ke. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The previous sentence describes the wind and cold water, exaggerating the desolate and solemn atmosphere. The next sentence expresses the desperate feelings, knowing that there is no way back, but resolutely going there and never looking back. The sound of &quot;wind rustling&quot; audibly exaggerates the tragedy of parting; &quot;Yishuihan&quot; is bone-piercing, describing the desolation of the environment from the sense of feeling; up and down, the world is extremely miserable, further highlighting Jing Ke&#39;s &quot;gentleman&quot; &quot;Die your confidant&quot;, the awe-inspiring and upright spirit of generously going to the national calamity. Although it has only fifteen words, it is &quot;sad, intense, full of character and emotion&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;The wind is rustling and the water is cold, and a strong man will never return once he is gone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jing Ke used this It got its name, and the two short poems will last forever. The difficulty in expressing majestic emotions in poetry lies in being convincing rather than being arrogant and exaggerated; it is in being able to express the more permanent and universal sentiments hidden behind the temporary feelings rather than in the momentary impulse. Perhaps tragic words are often used emotionally, and it is difficult for people to distinguish truth from falsehood when they are emotional, so the words not only deceive others, but also deceive themselves. Many works that are exciting at the moment are boring when you read them afterwards. It is precisely because of the performance that you deceive yourself. &quot;Song of Yishui&quot;, with its two gentle lines, has become an eternal masterpiece. When we read it, we must know Jing Ke&#39;s life experience. This is the universality of art, which transcends time and space and appeals to the eternal sentiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word &quot;xiaoxiao&quot; is commonly seen in poems. Ancient poem: &quot;The white poplars are full of sorrow and the wind is sad, and the rustling of the wind kills people.&quot; The three words &quot;wind and rustling&quot; naturally bring out the meaning of high autumn. The ancients said, &quot;When you climb a mountain and reach the water, you will see the general return home&quot;, and here it is said: &quot;A strong man will never return once he is gone.&quot; There seems to be a comparison between them, and it seems to be an explanation. It is inconvenient for us to say what it is, but we can I found some other verses. Here we first remember the vastness of &quot;the bright moon shining on the snow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The bright moon shines on the snow&quot;, which is clean and cold. The so-called &quot;Qionglou Yuyu, the height is not cold&quot;. &quot;Song of Yi Shui&quot; mentions the word &quot;cold&quot;, but Xie&#39;s poem does not mention it, but both are high because of the cold, and more emotional because of the high. Du Shi said, &quot;The wind is strong and the sky is high, and the apes are screaming in mourning.&quot; Naturally, we can&#39;t explain why the apes roar in mourning. However, don&#39;t we see that &quot;the new wind is strong and sad&quot;? The new wind is the north wind, so it is naturally very strong, but this word &quot;sorrow&quot; is the expressive part of this poem. So how can a strong man return once he is gone? When he is gone, it is written as a word of strength, but when he is gone, it is also a word of sorrow. Coincidences in the world must have a reason, not to mention that they are all famous sentences, not to mention that they are not related to each other. They are not related but have a deeper unity. This is the universality of art. Whenever the Qiuyuan is vast, the cold water is clear, and we are independent among the rustling wind, even if we are not strong men, we must have the mind of a strong man, so this poem exists without Jing Ke. Although it was spoken by Jing Ke, it belongs to everyone. &quot;Withered mulberry trees know the wind in the sky, and sea water knows the cold weather.&quot; This little understanding between us people, this little understanding between us people and nature, seems to be possible to say, but it seems impossible to say, but it is It brings our souls to a broader world. The vast wilderness is where life comes from. We have long forgotten it in our narrow life, but we have come to know it again in literature and art. Although our life is short, it has the meaning of eternal life here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhuan Zhu assassinated the King of Wu, but died and succeeded. Jing Ke stabbed the King of Qin, died but failed. However, we have forgotten Zhuan Zhu for a long time and are praising Jing Ke. Scholars cannot be judged on success or failure, and why we miss Jing Ke even more, isn’t it precisely because of this short poem? The poet created poetry, and at the same time he created himself. It belongs to Jing Ke and to all people. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 3&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This short song expresses the story of Jing Ke when he went to assassinate the King of Qin by exaggerating the external scenery with the rustling wind and the cold water. The tragic feelings and the firm will not to return until the mission is completed. Some people renovated the meaning to express the heroic spirit of revolutionaries who risked their lives to fight against the enemy. This poem was quoted in the movie &quot;The Five Heroes of Langya Mountain&quot; to inspire the revolutionary warriors to have the courage to fight against the enemy, and to exaggerate the generous and tragic atmosphere of fighting for the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This history has been compiled into a beautiful story, which is the book &quot;The Bright Moon in the Qin Dynasty - Jing Ke&#39;s Biography&quot;, in which the beautiful story of Jing Ke and Li Ji is written in vivid and beautiful language, which is worth reading. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 4&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; There are only two sentences in this poem. At first glance, it is easy to understand and straightforward. However, if you taste it carefully, it has profound meaning. , upright, and quite artistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem imitates the &quot;Xing&quot; technique in &quot;The Book of Songs&quot;, which &quot;prefaces other things to trigger the words to be chanted&quot;. First, it uses the west wind to change the water, and then draws out the warrior&#39;s ambition and feelings, and it is coherent. , quite impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first sentence explains the time and place of the expedition. The rustling autumn wind, the cold and changing water, are all natural scenery with no emotion at all, but here Jing Ke expresses his heart&#39;s emotions on the scenery in front of him. His emotions are full of wind, and his meaning is overflowing in the water, giving it a strong emotional color. . The choice of the onomatopoeia &quot;xiaoxiao&quot; and the adjective &quot;han&quot; is very unique and exciting. The former appeals to hearing, and the latter appeals to touch, creating a solemn, melancholy, and tragic natural and social atmosphere, which lays the artistic foundation for the emergence of the theme of the next sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last sentence follows the first sentence. Clarify the purpose of this poem. Because the previous sentence has sufficient momentum, this sentence expresses the heart directly, singing the heroic and dignified feelings of a strong man who sacrifices his life for righteousness and regards death as if he is home. Jing Ke knew very well that using his own meager strength to fight against the King of Qin, who was in charge of thousands of troops and had been familiar with swordsmanship since childhood, would be like hitting an egg against a stone, and the hope of survival would be almost zero. There is a great enemy at hand, and the fate of the country is uncertain, which is tragic; when we are weak against a strong enemy, the outcome is unpredictable, which is sad; when we know that it is difficult to survive, we die generously, which is heroic! Jing Ke&#39;s heroic act of &quot;knowing that there are tigers in the mountains, but preferring to go to the tiger mountains&quot; could not have been accomplished without extraordinary courage and courage. Therefore, even though he stopped abruptly after singing the sentence &quot;A strong man has gone and never comes back&quot; without another word, it still made those who saw him off &quot;all their eyes were filled with anger and their fingers were stretched out&quot; (see &quot;Historical Records&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jing Ke got his name from this poem, and the two short lines of the poem will last forever. The difficulty in expressing majestic emotions in poetry lies in being convincing rather than being arrogant and exaggerated; it is in being able to express the more permanent and universal sentiments hidden behind the temporary feelings rather than in the momentary impulse. Perhaps tragic words are often used emotionally, and it is difficult for people to distinguish truth from falsehood when they are emotional, so the words not only deceive others, but also deceive themselves. Many works that are exciting at the moment are boring when you read them afterwards. It is precisely because of the performance that you deceive yourself. &quot;Song of Yishui&quot;, with its two gentle lines, has become an eternal masterpiece. When we read it, we must know Jing Ke&#39;s life experience. This is the universality of art, which transcends time and space and appeals to the eternal sentiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This unembellished and extremely simple lyric &quot;can describe the misery of heaven and earth, and the feeling of a strong man returning home even after death&quot; (&quot;Suihantang Poetry&quot;) precisely because of Jing Ke&#39;s Emotions are moved in the text and expressed in words, giving it the ability to feel the autumn wind, move the water, shake the world, weep ghosts and gods, be generous and passionate, and show a huge charm that is heart-stirring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The language of this poem is very plain and concise. It uses scenes to express emotions and blends scenes. By rendering the external scenery with the rustling wind and cold water, it expresses Jing Ke’s tragic feelings and unhappiness when he went to assassinate the King of Qin. A firm will to complete the mission and never give it back. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Also known as anonymous, it refers to a person whose identity is unknown or whose name has not yet been learned. Literary and musical works originating from ancient times or among the people and whose author is unknown will be named anonymously. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>