<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[四时田园杂兴·其三十一 | 范成大]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310181]]><description> &lt;h2>;Pastoral Miscellany in Four Seasons·Thirty-One&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Fan Chengda&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;Working in the fields during the day and planting hemp at night, the children of the village are responsible for their own affairs . &lt;br />;Children and grandsons are still engaged in farming and weaving, and they also learn to grow melons near the mulberry tree. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Go to the fields to work in the fields during the day, and twist twine at home at night. Men and women in the village each have their own housework. &lt;br />;Although the children did not know how to plow and weave, they still learned to grow melons under the shade of the mulberry trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Farming: generally refers to farming and weeding, and engaging in field work. &lt;br />;Ji Ma: twist hemp into thread. &lt;br />;Each person is in charge: Each person has a certain job. &lt;br />;Unsolved: Don’t understand. &lt;br />;For: to engage in, to participate in. &lt;br />;Pong: close. &lt;br />;Yin: shade. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem describes a scene in rural summer life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first sentence &quot;I work in the fields during the day and work on hemp at night&quot; means: I go to the fields to weed during the day and twist the hemp thread at night. &quot;Tilting&quot; means weeding. In early summer, the rice seedlings need to be weeded. This is what men do. &quot;Ji Ma&quot; means that after women finish other work during the day, they knead twine and weave it into cloth at night. This sentence directly describes the labor scene. In the second sentence, &quot;The children of the village are responsible for their own families.&quot; &quot;Children&quot; refers to men and women. The whole poem uses the tone of old farmers, and &quot;children&quot; refers to young people. &quot;Head of the family&quot; means that both men and women have no time to spare, and each has his or her own business. The third sentence &quot;Children and grandchildren are not yet available for plowing and weaving.&quot; &quot;Children and grandchildren&quot; refers to those children. They don&#39;t know how to farm or weave, but they are not idle either. They have been exposed to it since they were young, so they &quot;learned to grow melons under the shade of mulberry trees&quot;, that is, they learned to grow melons under the lush mulberry trees. This is a common phenomenon in rural areas, but it is quite unique. The conclusion expresses the innocence of rural children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poet uses a fresh style of writing to give a more detailed description of the tense labor atmosphere in the countryside in early summer, which is very interesting to read. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/fanchengda.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Fan Chengda (1126-1193), also known as Shihu layman, was named Zuneng. Han nationality, from Wuxian County, Pingjiang (now Suzhou, Jiangsu Province). Poet of the Southern Song Dynasty. Posthumous title Wenmu. Starting from the Jiangxi School, he later studied the poetry of the Middle and Late Tang Dynasties, inherited the realism spirit of the New Yuefu poets such as Bai Juyi, Wang Jian, and Zhang Ji, and finally became his own school. The style is simple, fresh and charming. Poetry has a wide range of themes, and the works that reflect the content of rural social life are the most successful. Together with Yang Wanli, Lu You and You Miao, he is known as the &quot;Four Great ZTE Poets&quot; of the Southern Song Dynasty. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[醉太平·寒食 | 王元鼎]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310172]]><description> &lt;h2>;Drunken Taiping·Hanshi&lt;/h2>;[Yuan Dynasty] Wang Yuanding&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The crow cries loudly, and the life breaks the Shaohua. The light rain in the night moistens the sand on the embankment, and the fragrant breeze blows through thousands of houses. The mandarin duck tiles in the painting building are washed, and the colored ropes are half wet and the swing is fragrant. When I wake up to the red sun, I put up the window screen and listen to the apricot blossoms being sold on the street. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;One after another, the little crow kept shouting for joy, breaking the dark night and welcoming Here comes the glory of spring. The slight spring rain last night moistened the soft sand on the river bank, and the fragrant breeze filled thousands of homes. I washed the mandarin duck tiles in the painting building clean and wetted the swing with colorful ropes tied with incense. When I woke up, the red sun was already shining on the window screen, and I heard someone selling apricot blossoms on the street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Cold Food: The day before Qingming Festival is the Cold Food Festival, and fire is prohibited for three days in memory of Jie Zitui. &lt;br />;Milk crow: young crow. &lt;br />;Sheng: Yes, no matter what. Shaohua: Good times, leading to spring. &lt;br />;Yuanyang tiles: paired tiles. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Cold food occurs in the early third month of the lunar calendar, one or two days before Qingming, when spring is already halfway through. Wang Yuanding&#39;s set of &quot;Cold Food&quot; consists of four poems, and this is the second of them. The other three poems mainly describe the rich and complex feelings caused by the passing spring in the author&#39;s heart, which may cause inexplicable sleepiness, lingering emotions, or the desire to have timely pleasure. The subjective color is relatively strong. This song is different. The author does not express his emotions directly. Instead, he adopts a subtle and implicit lyrical technique that blends his emotions with the scenery, completely melting his joy for spring into a vibrant and interesting sound and light picture. among. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this little order, &quot;the crow crows&quot;, &quot;the rain moistens the sand on the embankment&quot;, &quot;the painted building has clean tiles&quot;, &quot;the colorful rope is half wet&quot; and &quot;the red sun goes up the window screen&quot;, &quot; &quot;Apricot blossoms are sold on the street&quot; and so on, which outline the vibrant and interesting scene of the cold food season and express the author&#39;s joy for spring. The language is fresh and elegant. Although it uses famous poetic lines from previous generations in many places, it is natural and smooth without any feeling of being forced or outdated. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang Yuanding: Zili, lived during the Dade period of Chengzong in the Yuan Dynasty (around 1302 AD), at the same time as Aluwei, and became a Hanlin bachelor. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 05:23:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>