<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[梅花绝句二首·其一 | 陆游]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239142]]><description> &lt;h2>;Two Plum Blossom Quatrains·Part 1&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Lu You&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;I heard that the plum blossoms were blowing in the morning breeze, and the snow was all over the mountains. &lt;br />;How can one transform into hundreds of billions, just like a young man standing in front of a plum tree? (First work before plum blossom: plum blossom)&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;I heard that the plum blossoms on the mountain have already welcomed the plum blossoms. They bloom in the morning breeze, and from a distance, the plum trees on the surrounding mountains look like piles of white snow. &lt;br />;Is there any way to transform yourself into hundreds of millions of figures? Let there be a Lu You always in front of every plum tree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Wen Dao: Hearing and hearing. &lt;br />;Chè: to split. Here it means to bloom. &lt;br />;Zhu Xiaofeng: It opens in the morning breeze. &lt;br />;Snowdrift: Refers to plum blossoms blooming like snowdrifts. &lt;br />;He Fang: Is there any way? &lt;br />;Qianyi: refers to being able to turn into tens of millions of Fangweng (Lu You&#39;s name Fangweng, Ziwuguan). &lt;br />;Plum blossoms: One work is &quot;in front of plum blossoms&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is the first in a series of poems. It was written in January of 1202 AD (the second year of Jiatai) when Lu You retired to his hometown of Shanyin. Lu You was seventy-eight years old. At this time, it was the Southern Song Dynasty. Lu You was on the edge of political power and could not be reused by the establishment for a long time, but he did still have expectations in his heart. The author was inspired when he saw the plum blossoms. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; The first sentence of this poem &quot;I heard the plum blossoms blowing in the morning wind, and the snow piles are all over the four mountains.&quot; It describes the scene of plum blossoms blooming. For example, the word &quot;坼xiaofeng&quot; in the first sentence highlights the proud attitude of plum blossoms that are not afraid of the severe cold; in the second sentence, the plum blossoms are compared to white snow, which not only describes the characteristics of plum blossoms&#39; pure whiteness, but also expresses the grand scene of plum blossoms all over the mountains and plains. . The language is clear and the scene is broad. And the three or four sentences &quot;How can I transform into hundreds of billions of people, just a plum blossom tree and a man blooming.&quot; It is even more unexpected, noble and refined. I would like to transform into hundreds of billions of land tourists, and there is a plum tree in front of each land travel, so that the obsessed My love for Mei was vividly expressed. &lt;p>; In the following two sentences, a sudden thought came to mind: &quot;How can one transform into hundreds of billions, one plum blossom and one plum blossom?&quot; This means, how can one use a method to transform into tens of millions of plum blossoms? Everyone is there to enjoy it. The idea of ​​being able to incarnate hundreds of billions of people is amazing. The plum blossoms correspond face to face with the poet. Who is Meyer? Who is he? It is difficult to tell easily at the moment. This is another peculiarity of the poet&#39;s life style. Although these two sentences are inspired by Liu Zongyuan&#39;s poetic meaning of &quot;If I could transform into hundreds of billions, I would spread out on the top of the mountain and look at my hometown&quot;, it is not appropriate to use them in the world of plum blossoms where &quot;snow piles are all over the mountains&quot;. Natural, and the scenes are very interesting. There are at least three reasons: As a 78-year-old poet, facing the sea of ​​flowers and trees in Meishan with different postures, of course he can&#39;t search for them one by one, so he can appreciate them in their incarnations. This is one of his wonderful ideas. In addition, although Lu You was old, his childlike innocence was still intact. He often attracted attention with his &quot;extraordinary&quot; behavior of &quot;plum blossoms weighing heavily on the brim of his hat, dragging his stick and singing songs in the spirit of immortality&quot;. At this time, he suddenly had a strange idea and wanted to imitate the immortal&#39;s behavior. The clone method is also inspired by childish innocence and is very consistent with psychology. This is the second one. Moreover, Lu You often compares himself with plum blossoms, and he always has a feeling of indifference among the best. Now facing thousands of plum blossoms in full bloom, the poet is naturally not willing to look up at them with his whole body. He has to transform into hundreds of billions to compete with them. Proportionate, Fang lives up to the poet&#39;s feelings for plum blossoms. Looking at these three aspects, although this sentence has reference points on the surface, if you deeply understand it, it is actually a sentence that reflects the situation. Just like Lin Bu inspired Jiang Wei to write the poem &quot;Plum Blossom&quot;, it has been re-created by the poet and integrated with the ancient poetry of Tao Zhu. And it comes from its own ideas and can come up with new ideas, making the poem more poetic and charming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two sentences about plum blossoms serve as a foil for the last two sentences about people. Facing the wonderful scene of plum blossoms in full bloom, the poet suddenly had a whim and wished to transform into hundreds of billions of land tourists, and there would be a plum blossom tree in front of each of them. This rich and bold imagination vividly expresses the poet&#39;s love for plum blossoms, and also expresses the poet&#39;s elegant and refined character. Try to imagine the feeling of the last sentence in your mind, it can make people smile knowingly. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/luyou.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Lu You (November 13, 1125 - January 26, 1210), named Wuguan, nicknamed Fangweng, Han nationality, was from Shanyin, Yuezhou (now Shaoxing, Zhejiang), Shangshu Right The grandson of Cheng Lu Dian, a writer, historian and patriotic poet of the Southern Song Dynasty. Lu You was born when the Northern Song Dynasty was overthrown, and he was deeply influenced by his family&#39;s patriotism when he was young. During the reign of Emperor Gaozong of the Song Dynasty, he participated in the examination of the Ministry of Rites, but his official career was not smooth because he was rejected by Qin Hui, the prime minister. During the reign of Emperor Xiaozong, he was granted a Jinshi background. He entered Shu in middle age and devoted himself to military life. In the second year of Jiatai (1202), Emperor Ningzong of the Song Dynasty ordered Lu You to come to Beijing and preside over the compilation of Xiaozong&#39;s and Guangzong&#39;s &quot;Records of the Two Dynasties&quot; and &quot;History of the Three Dynasties&quot;. In his later years, he retired to his hometown. There are more than 9,000 poems in existence today, and they are extremely rich in content. He is the author of &quot;Jiannan Poetry Manuscript&quot;, &quot;Weinan Collected Works&quot;, &quot;Southern Tang Book&quot;, &quot;Laoxue&#39;an Notes&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 05:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[子衿 | 诗经·国风·郑风]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239141]]><description> &lt;h2>;Zi Jin&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] The Book of Songs·Guo Feng·Zheng Feng&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The green Zi Jin is in my heart. Even if I don&#39;t go, will Zi Ning have no heir? &lt;br />;The green zipai makes me think about it for a long time. Even if I don&#39;t go, Zi Ning won&#39;t come? &lt;br />;It is difficult to find a way to reach the city. Not seeing each other for one day is like three months! &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The green color is your collar, the leisurely color is my state of mind . Even though I never came to see you, wouldn&#39;t you send me a message? &lt;br />;The green ones are what you wear, the long ones are my feelings. Even if I never go to see you, can&#39;t you come to me? &lt;br />;Walking around and looking around, on this high observation tower. A day without seeing you seems like a few months! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Zi Jin: The clothing of scholars in the Zhou Dynasty. Zi, a good name for a man, here refers to &quot;you&quot;. Jin, the handover of clothes. &lt;br />;Yuyou: She looks constantly worried. &lt;br />;Ning (nìng): Qi, could it be? &lt;br />;Si (sì) sound: keep the message. Si: continue, continue. &lt;br />;Pei: This refers to the ribbon that holds the jade. &lt;br />;Tiāo (pronounced tāo) Xi Da (tà) Xi: The appearance of wandering alone. Pick, also known as &quot;佻&quot;. &lt;br />;Chengque: the viewing towers on both sides of the city gate. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Guofeng·Zheng Feng·Zijin&quot; is a poem in the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;, the first poetry collection in ancient China. The poem has three chapters, each chapter has four lines. This poem is about unrequited love, describing a woman missing her sweetheart. Whenever a woman sees something green, she will think of her sweetheart’s green collar and green jade. So she climbed onto the city gate tower just to see her sweetheart. If she can&#39;t see her for one day, she will feel like it&#39;s been three months. The whole poem uses the technique of flashback to fully describe the psychological activities of a woman&#39;s unrequited love. It is lifelike and has a beautiful artistic conception. It is a rare and beautiful love song and has become a classic work describing lovesickness in the history of Chinese literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem consists of three chapters, using flashback technique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two chapters use the tone of &quot;I&quot; to describe my love for others. &quot;Qing Qing Zi Jin&quot; and &quot;Qing Qing Zi Pei&quot; refer to the lover&#39;s clothes and ornaments. The other person&#39;s clothes left such a deep impression on her that she couldn&#39;t forget them. You can imagine how much she missed him. Now I am unable to go to the appointment due to obstacles, so I have to wait for my lover to come over to meet me, but there is no trace of her through the autumn water. The deep love cannot help but turn into melancholy and resentment: &quot;Even if I didn&#39;t go to you, why can&#39;t you send me a message? Even if I didn’t go looking for you, why couldn’t you take the initiative to come?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third chapter points out the location and writes that she was upset on the tower because her lover who had been waiting for a long time did not come, and went back and forth. As we walked non-stop, I felt that although we hadn&#39;t seen each other for only one day, it seemed like three months of separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whole poem is less than 50 words long, but the heroine&#39;s anxious state of waiting for her lover seems to be present. The achievement of this artistic effect lies in the poet&#39;s use of a large amount of psychological description in his creation. In the poem, only the words &quot;pick&quot; and &quot;da&quot; are used to express the woman&#39;s actions, and the main words are used to describe her psychological activities, such as the complaints about her lover who has no information and has disappeared in the first two chapters. , the monologue at the end of the chapter &quot;One day is like three months without seeing each other&quot;. The two paragraphs of complaints are contrasted with &quot;Longme&quot; and &quot;Zi Ning&quot;. There is a reserved attitude in the eagerness, which makes people have unlimited imagination. It can be said that there are few words but many meanings. The inner monologue at the end uses exaggerated rhetorical techniques to create a contrast between subjective time and objective time, thereby vividly expressing its strong emotional psychology. It can be said that it is amazing because of the exaggeration and embellishment. The technique of psychological description has been fully developed in the literary world of later generations, and tracing back to its origin, this poem has pioneered it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem is one of the more representative works of love poetry in the Book of Songs. It clearly embodies the independent, independent, and equal ideas and spiritual essence of women of that era. , the heroine boldly expresses her emotions in the poem, that is, her longing for her lover. This is rare in the literary works of the past dynasties after the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; Regarding the background of this poem, modern scholars generally believe that it is a love song. The singer was passionately in love with a young man. They made an appointment to meet at the city gate, but after a long wait, the singer couldn&#39;t wait. He walked back and forth anxiously, complaining that his lover didn&#39;t come to the appointment, and even blamed him for not sending a letter. So he sang this poem to express his gratitude to his lover. Emotions. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>