<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[人有负盐负薪者 | 李延寿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310102]]><description> &lt;h2>;There are people who bear salt and salary.&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Li Yanshou&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>; There are people who bear salt and salary. When we were young, we were walking together, fighting for a sheepskin, and each of them asked for something to borrow on his back. After a long time without success, he sued the official. When Hui sent the contenders out, Guzhou Jigang said: &quot;Can you know the master with this sheepskin?&quot; There was no reply from the crowd. Hui ordered him to place it on the sheepskin mat, hit it with his stick, and when he saw a few salt flakes, he said: &quot;It&#39;s true.&quot; The person who made the argument looked at it, and the person who paid the salary fell down and committed the crime. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />; There are two people carrying salt and firewood, and they put them down at the same time. Burdens rest in the shade. After resting for a while, he was about to leave, fighting for a sheepskin, which he said was his shoulder pad. The dispute lasted for a long time with no result, so I went to report it to the official. Li Hui asked them to go out, looked at the chief register of the state capital and said, &quot;Can the owner of this sheepskin be found out?&quot; None of the subordinate officials could answer. Li Hui asked someone to put the sheepskin on the seat, beat it with a stick, and when he found a little salt, he said: &quot;We have the truth!&quot; Then he asked the two parties to come in to see, and the person carrying the firewood fell on the ground and admitted his crime. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Negative: Back. &lt;br />;Fuel: firewood. &lt;br />;Relieving the burden together: (two people) letting go of the burden at the same time. Tong, together at the same time; release, let go. &lt;br />;And: will. &lt;br />;Borrow: cushion, lining&lt;br />;Hui: Li Hui, a native of Zhongshan (now Mancheng, Dingxian, Hebei), was the governor of Yongzhou during the reign of Emperor Taiwu of the Northern Wei Dynasty. &lt;br />;Send: make, order, let. &lt;br />;State Chronicle: The chief register of the state capital. &lt;br />;Copy: torture. &lt;br />;Under the group: subordinates. &lt;br />;Xian: Du. &lt;br />;Salt crumbs: powdered salt. Crumbs, broken pieces&lt;br />;Real: Facts. &lt;br />;Nai: Cai&lt;br />;Fu: Lying face down and back up. &lt;br />;Confession of sin: Admission of sin. &lt;br />;OK: Go. &lt;br />;Xi: Take a rest. &lt;br />;Gu: Look back, look back. &lt;br />;Short time: a while. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Principle&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; 1. Careful observation of real life and rigorous logical reasoning. Everything in the world has certain laws. As long as you think more and observe more, you can see the essence through the phenomena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2. People must be treated in a friendly manner when interacting with others, and they must not be greedy for small gains, blinded by interests, and engage in bad behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 3. To deal with problems, you need to have rich life knowledge and experience, coupled with careful observation, and be good at thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 4. Observe more and think more when doing things, and don’t be greedy for small gains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 5. Reason rationally and draw correct conclusions. Do not reason blindly. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/liyanshou.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Li Yanshou, the year of birth and death is yet to be determined. A historian of the Tang Dynasty, he was born in Anyang City, Henan Province today. During the Zhenguan period, he served as Prince Dianshan Cheng and Bachelor of Chongxian Hall. Later, he served as the chief registrar of Yushitai. He was promoted to Fu Xilang and also studied national history. He once participated in the official compilation of &quot;Sui Shu&quot;, &quot;Five Dynasties History&quot; (i.e. &quot;Jing Ji Zhi&quot;), &quot;Jin Shu&quot; and the history of the country. He also independently wrote &quot;Southern History&quot; and &quot;Northern History&quot; and &quot;Taizong Zhengdian&quot; (lost). &quot;New Book of Tang&quot; spoke highly of the two books, saying that &quot;their books are quite organized and have omissions and phrases, which is much better than this book.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 05:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[会稽郡楼雪霁 | 张继]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310101]]><description> &lt;h2>;It snowed in the towers of Kuaiji County&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Zhang Ji&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The snow in Jiangcheng last night was like flowers, and the guests from Ying climbed up the tower to look at China. &lt;br />;There are still buildings gathered in front of the altar of Xia Yu, and gauze is floating on Xishi Pu. &lt;br />;The curtains are open to the late cold weather, and the early clear scenery is slanted. &lt;br />;The twilight in several places is inexhaustible, and the clear lakes and mountains reflect people’s homes. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;It snowed heavily in Yuezhou City last night. Today I climbed up the tower and watched the sky clear after the snow. of beautiful scenery. &lt;br />;The snow piled up in front of the Xia Yu altar outside the city is like a white building, and Xishi Pu in the distance seems to be covered with a hazy veil. &lt;br />;Between the windows under the curtains of the city tower, a cold wind blew strongly at dusk, and the setting sun outside the city wall cast slanting light on the tower. &lt;br />;Looking far into the distance, there are still a few dim lights in the cold twilight, and the green shadows of the lakes and mountains reflect the homes in this area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Yingke: refers to the poet. &lt;br />;Curtains: Curtains and window panels. &lt;br />;Looking squinting: looking squinting, showing arrogance. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Climbing high to look far, drinking wine and composing poems have been the hobbies of literati throughout the ages. After the chest is full of joy, anger, sorrow, and daydream, it often becomes one with the things in front of you, forgetting both things and myself, and thus entering a wonderful realm. It&#39;s just that the emotions expressed by ancient poets were more sad, sad, and lost, and less joyful, exciting, and happy. Xie Lingyun was frustrated in his official career. He went upstairs to the pond in early spring and fell in love with the beautiful scenery of &quot;spring grass grows in the pond and willows in the garden turn into songbirds&quot;. He retreated and meditated, but he lamented that &quot;it is easy to live in isolation forever, but it is difficult to live in isolation&quot;, which was quite self-pitying. the taste of. Xie Tiao, Li Bai&#39;s favorite poet, is very famous for his &quot;Climbing Three Mountains at Night and Looking at the Capital City&quot;. He admired the beautiful scenery of &quot;The noisy birds cover the spring continent, and the miscellaneous heroes fill the fields&quot;. However, when thinking of his own experience, he longed for his hometown. However, when I was born, I had the sorrow of &quot;How sad is the good time, my tears are like falling raindrops&quot;. When Chen Ziang climbed up to Youzhou Terrace, his eyes were filled with desolation and vastness, and his resentment for not being able to recognize his talent was palpable. Du Fu had been wandering for many years, suffering from old age, illness, and loneliness. His feeling when he climbed up was that he was &quot;a frequent guest in the sad autumn for thousands of miles, and he came to the stage alone after suffering from a hundred years of illness.&quot; When Li Bai ascended the Phoenix Tower, Jiang Liu&#39;s history was ridiculed by the government; when Cui Hao ascended the Yellow Crane Tower, everything he saw turned into nostalgia. Empress Li was the king who had subjugated his country. He &quot;went up to the west tower alone without a word&quot;, and looked at each other, making anyone who saw him sad. Wang Anshi was a man of reform, &quot;he came to see him off, it was the late autumn of his homeland, and the weather was beginning to be calm.&quot; Ying Huai Those who only have feelings of concern for the country and the people. Zhang Ji&#39;s life did not have many ups and downs, but due to the times, society and other reasons, it was difficult for him to overcome sadness and sadness when he climbed high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Ji is good at describing scenes. He often embodies sincere emotions in his vivid descriptions. When Xue Ji climbs a building, his emotions, scenes, images and images are perfectly combined in his writing, making them completely indistinguishable. realm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the clouds were clearing and the snow was falling, the poet climbed up to the ancient county city tower and took a closer look and a distant view. The building was made of silver and was white, beautiful and quiet. It was as if he was in a fairyland. His soul was purified and he was very happy. However, the Ying Chu wanderers who were &quot;alone as strangers in a foreign land&quot; took refuge in Wuyue County. Although they were overjoyed, they had a special realization: on Wolong Mountain not far away, there is the tomb of Wenzhong, a great master in the Spring and Autumn Period. Thinking back to those days, He made great contributions to the revival of the Yue Kingdom, but in the end he was given a sword by Gou Jian to commit suicide. From a distance, in front of Xia Yu&#39;s mausoleum, there are clearly snow-covered buildings, which are extremely beautiful. This man had great merit in controlling floods, and then went east to hunt for Kuaiji and died. The ancient sages were loved and respected by the people. Looking from another direction, the waterside of Xishi Huansha seems to have plain silk and white gauze swaying in front of the eyes. It is a pity that this peerless beauty who was appointed to the national crisis was still criticized and criticized by the world after she sold her house and died. The poet writes about the scenery due to love, and has entered the realm of self. His emotions are extremely complicated and difficult to describe. He combines admiration, admiration, and regret in one ink, and then he is worried about the chaotic life of taking refuge in Jiangnan after the Anshi Rebellion. It alludes to the declining Tang Dynasty. Therefore, in the evening, I feel so cold that I have to put down the curtains and have no intention of admiring the &quot;red-clad scenery&quot; under the afterglow of the setting sun. At this time, the red sun gradually disappears, and the scenery of Wolong Mountain and Jinghu Lake are still clearly distinguishable. , making the poet feel sad and happy. It can be said that &quot;there is a true meaning in this, but I have forgotten to tell it&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first couplet is &quot;rising&quot;, and the scenery is so beautiful and pleasant that even a person who is desperate and seeking refuge cannot turn a blind eye; the chin couplet is &quot;fu&quot;, mourning the past and regretting the present, and admiring at the same time; the neck couplet is &quot;fu&quot; again , facing the reality, the relationship seems to have hit the bottom; the last couplet is slightly &quot;rising&quot;, which echoes the first couplet, with &quot;twilight&quot; and &quot;clear reflection&quot;, which gives some comfort. It&#39;s really hard to tell whether it&#39;s love or scenery. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Zhang Ji (about 715~about 779), courtesy name Yisun, Han nationality, was from Xiangzhou (now Xiangyang, Hubei). A poet of the Tang Dynasty, little is known about his life. According to various records, we only know that he was a Jinshi in the twelfth year of Tianbao (AD 753). In the Dali calendar, Wai Lang, a member of the Jixiao Temple, was the salt and iron judge of Hongzhou (now Nanchang City, Jiangxi). His poems are hearty and exciting, without any refinement, deep in metaphor, and both logical and logical. They have a great influence on later generations. But unfortunately, less than 50 songs have been handed down. His most famous poem is &quot;Mooring at Night on Maple Bridge&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>