<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[珍珠帘 | 陈祥道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231061]]><description> &lt;h2>;Pearl Curtain&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Chen Xiangdao&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The east wind blows the rain and touches the grass and trees in the air. &lt;br />;I remember that on the day when there was a noise in the three palaces, the bead curtain was half-cast in the sky. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The east wind blew by, the drizzle was thin, and the grass and trees were soaked by the drizzle. &lt;br />;I still remember that it rained for three whole days. The sound of rain came into the palace, and I thought it was a curtain of pearls falling from half the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xianxian: slender appearance; soft appearance. &lt;br />;Suspicious: as if. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chen Xiangdao (1042-1093) was a native of Fuzhou (now Fujian), and Chen Yang was his younger brother. In his early years, he was given the name Youzhi, and later he changed his name to it. He became a Jinshi in the fourth year of Emperor Yingzong&#39;s reign (1067). He served as secretary of the provincial government, corrected characters, and collated Guange. He was a famous Confucian scholar and thinker in the Northern Song Dynasty. He knows almost everything about the classics and history, and is especially good at the Analects of Confucius and the study of rituals. He has written more than ten kinds of classics, but unfortunately only 10 volumes of &quot;Analects of Confucius&quot; and 150 volumes of &quot;Book of Rites&quot; have been handed down to the world. Among them, &quot;Book of Rites&quot; has played a relatively important role in the history of traditional Chinese rituals and culture. academic status and influence. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 07:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蝶恋花·出塞 | 纳兰性德]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231062]]><description> &lt;h2>;Die Lian Hua·Chu Si&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Nalan Xingde&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;There is no definite basis for ancient and modern rivers and mountains. Amid the sound of horns being drawn, horses come and go frequently. Who can talk about the desolation? The west wind blows the old red maple tree. &lt;br />;In the past, there were countless grievances. The iron horse fights, the road to Qingzhong at dusk. How deep is the love? The sunset in the deep mountains and the deep autumn rain. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;From ancient times to the present, the rise and fall of the country has been uncertain. Before our eyes, it seems as if war horns are blowing, beacon smoke is billowing, and war horses are billowing. Who can say that the yellow sand covers the sun and the desolation is everywhere when galloping back and forth? The autumn wind was blowing, and only a few maple trees had their leaves blown red again. &lt;br />;In the past, there were endless sad and desolate memories. In the land of gold and iron, it was Zhaojun who sacrificed his life to seek peace. How deep was the love once? It is like the continuous autumn rain in the deep mountains under the afterglow of the setting sun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;No definite basis: There is no certainty. Mao Kai of the Song Dynasty wrote a poem in &quot;The Fisherman&#39;s Proud Ci Danyang Recalls an Old Friend&quot;: &quot;It is unbearable that there is no fixed date of return, and the end of the world has already been heard.&quot;&lt;br />;Huajiao: an ancient wind instrument, passed down from Xiqiang. It is called because of the painted surface. It makes a mournful and high-pitched sound and is shaped like a bamboo tube. It is thin in nature and large in size at the end. It is made of bamboo wood or leather. In ancient times, it was often used in the army to warn people at dusk, boost morale and suppress the appearance of troops. When the emperor went on patrol, he also used it to call for martial law. &lt;br />;Herding horses: refers to war horses used in ancient battles. &lt;br />;Who can talk: Does anyone want to talk to me? &lt;br />;Grudges in the past: wars between various ethnic groups and tribes in the past. &lt;br />;Iron Horse and Jin Ge: describes the majestic soldiers and horses. Refers to war. Military affairs. &lt;br />;Green Tomb: A grave covered with weeds. This refers to the tomb of Wang Zhaojun. It is said that the grass on the tomb is evergreen, hence the name. Du Fu&#39;s poem &quot;Ode to Ancient Relics&quot;: &quot;Once I go to the purple terrace and the desert, I am left alone with the green tomb facing the dusk.&quot;&lt;br />;How deep is the love: paraphrased from Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;Butterfly Love Flower&quot;: &quot;How deep is the courtyard?&quot; The meaning of the sentence . How much: How much. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem expresses feelings about the rise and fall of past dynasties and historical changes through the description of the ancient battlefield outside the Great Wall. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first part of the poem describes the scene, describing the desolate scene of the ancient battlefield outside the Great Wall. &quot;There is no definite basis for ancient and modern rivers and mountains.&quot; The first sentence starts with a discussion. The simple words have a sense of historical depth and form an atmosphere that envelopes the entire article. The word &quot;modern and ancient&quot; includes the past and present. Facing the great rivers and mountains, many influential people competed for it, occupying it for a long time or temporarily, but no one occupied these places permanently. &quot;Amidst the sound of the horn being drawn, the herding horses come and go frequently.&quot; Two lines of line drawing paint a picture of peace beyond the Great Wall. The sound of the horn is drawn, and the vigorous herding horses come and go frequently. &quot;Who can talk about the desolation? The old red maple trees are blowing in the west wind.&quot; The two sentences are still descriptive. Looking around, the entire northern part of the Great Wall is covered with flat sand for thousands of miles. The desert is desolate, and it is difficult to find even a person to speak. The west wind blew, and only a few maple trees had their leaves turned red again. It reminds people of the tragic scenes of fierce fighting for this land, with corpses strewn across the fields and rivers of blood flowing. These red leaves once again bring people into the memory of history, deepening the deep sense of history in the work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second part of the poem is lyrical, describing your own feelings of being out of trouble. &quot;There used to be countless grievances.&quot; The first sentence of discussion is directly derived from Shangqiu&#39;s description of the ancient battlefield. Facing the desolate scenery of the ancient battlefield, the sorrow and hatred in my heart cannot be calculated. Just as Li Qi of the Tang Dynasty said in &quot;Ancient Military Journey&quot;: &quot;Pedestrians fight against the wind and sand, and the princess plays the pipa with many grievances.&quot; The next two sentences of the narrative: &quot;Golden arms and iron horses, on the road to the green tomb at dusk.&quot; &quot;Golden arms and iron horses&quot; represent war. &quot;Qingzhong Dusk Road&quot; uses the story of the marriage between King Zhaojun of Han Dynasty to represent the marriage. The two sentences summarize the two methods of war and peace. It shows that since ancient times, in order to compete for the country, war and peace, or both, are used. This is history. &quot;How deep is love? The sunset in the mountains and the autumn rain.&quot; The last two sentences combine love with scenery, expressing the author&#39;s feelings: Looking back on history, facing this ancient battlefield outside the Great Wall, the poet has a deep love for his motherland. This deep feeling is like the continuous autumn rain in the deep mountains under the afterglow of the setting sun. The meaning of the words is deep and implicit, with hidden meanings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; During the reign of Emperor Yuan of the Han Dynasty, Zhaojun was ordered to go to Fortress and Fan. With her communication and mediation, the Xiongnu and the Han Dynasty lived in harmony for sixty years. After her death, she was buried in Hudi. Because her tomb is close to Daqingshan and the Yellow River, Zhaojun&#39;s tomb is also called the &quot;Green Tomb&quot;. Du Fu wrote a poem, &quot;When I go to Zitai Lianshuo Desert, I leave the Green Tomb alone to the dusk.&quot; &quot; Nalan thought of Wang Zhaojun from the Qingzhong and asked her: &quot;How deep can the passion be? Is it as deep as the sunset in the mountains and the bitter rain in late autumn?&quot; As the personal bodyguard of Emperor Kangxi, the author often has to follow the saints He went on a patrol, so his heart was filled with the desire to serve the country, but he obviously did not want to achieve his ideals and ambitions through the method of &quot;one general succeeds and thousands of bones wither&quot;, so in the last sentence the author returned to his sentimental nature, he Ending with the scene language, I integrate my infinite deep feelings into the silent scenery, which contains both boldness and tenderness, and we can even experience a little desolation and helplessness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; This poem depicts the desolate peaceful scene in front of the poet through his &quot;out of the fortress&quot;. Looking back on history, he summarizes the two situations of war and peace. It is a regular summary of the replacement of dynasties in Chinese history. Therefore, Mao Zedong commented: &quot;See the rise and fall&quot;, which affirmed the ideological significance of this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Xie Zhangqing once said in &quot;Words of Gambling and Chess Villa&quot;: &quot;It is difficult to combine long and short tunes. The only ones in the country are Zhutuo, Jialing, and Rongruohu. Zhutuo is won by learning. Jialing wins with talent, Rongruo wins with emotion.&quot; After reading the author&#39;s desolate and generous poem, we can know that Xie&#39;s words are true. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by Nalan Xingde in August 1682 AD (the 21st year of Kangxi) when he was ordered to talk to Vice President Lang It was composed on the way to Suolong after leaving the fortress. The poet was twenty-eight years old at the time. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/nalanxingde.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Nalan Xingde (1655-1685), a Manchurian with the courtesy name Rongruo and Lengya Mountain native, was one of the most famous poets in the Qing Dynasty. His poem &quot;Nalan Ci&quot; enjoyed a high reputation in the Qing Dynasty and even the entire Chinese poetry circle, and also occupied a glorious place in the history of Chinese literature. He lived during the period of integration of Manchu and Han Dynasties, and the rise and fall of his aristocratic family was typically related to the state affairs of the dynasty. Although he serves the emperor, he longs for ordinary experiences. The special living environment and background, coupled with his personal extraordinary talent, give his poetry creation a unique personality and distinctive artistic style. The &quot;Magnolia Order·Ancient Judgment&quot; that has been passed down to this day - &quot;If life is only as it was when we first met, why is the autumn wind sad and painted on the fan? It is easy to change the heart of the old, but it is said that the heart of the old is easy to change.&quot; Full of artistic conception, it is one of his many representative works one. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>