<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[夏日绝句二首·其二 | 姚鼐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310291]]><description> &lt;h2>;Two Summer Quatrains·Part 2&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Yao Nai&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The tall trees on the wall are green and the sky is green, and the remaining flowers are gone but the cicadas are not noisy. &lt;br />;Watching the clouds as the afternoon passes, several birds sing in front of the wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The big trees beside the stone wall towered into the sky, dyeing the sky green. The flowers bloom and fade accompanied by the cicadas chirping. &lt;br />;Close the book in the afternoon and watch the shadows of the trees move, and hear the sound of wind and birdsong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Close the book: close the book. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/yaonai.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Yao Nai (nài) (1731-1815) was a famous essayist in the Qing Dynasty. He was known as the &quot;Three Patriarchs of Tongcheng&quot; together with Fang Bao and Liu Dakui. The courtesy name is Ji Chuan, the other name is Meng Gu, and his room name is Xibao In the 28th year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1763), he became a Jinshi and served as director of the Ministry of Rites and compiler of Sikuquanshu. At the age of forty, he resigned and returned to the south. He successively gave lectures at academies in Yangzhou Meihua, Jiangnan Ziyang, Nanjing Zhongshan and other places for forty years. for many years. He is the author of The Complete Works of Xibao &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:23:10 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冀州道中 | 王冕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310292]]><description> &lt;h2>;In the middle of Jizhou Road&lt;/h2>;[Yuan Dynasty] Wang Mian&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;I walked along Jizhou Road and meditated on the ancient imperial capital. &lt;br />;The water and soil may be different from the past, and the Yu tribute book is also different. &lt;br />;The city wall is like a village dock, and the rain and snow are heavy. &lt;br />;The thin bushes gather frozen birds, and the foxes roar withered trees. &lt;br />;Cold clouds cover my scarf, and cold wind tears my undershirt. &lt;br />;As soon as Xu Heng exhaled, his mustache was covered with ice. &lt;br />;Cheng Cheng watched the fireworks, and there were few people living along the road. &lt;br />;You can’t buy millet, and you can’t get glutinous rice. &lt;br />;The roots of the mulberry tree in the earthen house look like wine. &lt;br />;Wander around and ask Mr. Ye, can you lend me the kitchen? &lt;br />;Ye Laoxin welcomes me with a smile, and comes close to hold my skirt. &lt;br />;The hot water warms my hands, and the fire warms my body. &lt;br />;Don&#39;t wash your face, as washing your face will damage your skin. &lt;br />;I know the old man is kind-hearted and slowly drives away the servants. &lt;br />;Asking Lao He clan? Yun is Yi Shiru. &lt;br />;Since the coming of the great dynasty, what I have learned has become the first to become a bandit. &lt;br />;The people were recruited to fight for the garrison, and they were all bow and arrow disciples. &lt;br />;Even if we have good children and grandchildren, they are no different than dogs and pigs. &lt;br />;Now that I am an old man, I cannot read a word. &lt;br />;There are no allusions, so where are the etiquette and righteousness? &lt;br />;When I talk about my grandfather, I feel pain in my bones. &lt;br />;I heard the sudden sigh of relief, holding my hand empty and hesitated. &lt;br />;Hesitating towards the sky, when will I find hope again? &lt;br />;Crying and unable to bear words, I flutter my sleeves in the southwest corner. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;I was walking on the road in Jizhou, silently missing the capital of my motherland. &lt;br />;Maybe the current geographical environment is different from the past; maybe the geographical divisions in &quot;Yu Gong&quot; are very different from now. &lt;br />;The city is as desolate as a village, despite the heavy rain and snow. &lt;br />;There are frozen birds gathering in the woods, and foxes howl beside the dead trees. &lt;br />;The low cold clouds seemed to be pressing down on my hat, and the cold wind tore my clothes. &lt;br />;Sometimes when I look up, the white breath coming out of my mouth turns into ice slag and is covered with beards. &lt;br />;I walked one step at a time, hoping to find someone else’s home, but there were very few people living on both sides of the road. &lt;br />;There is no place to buy millet, and no wine. &lt;br />;Beside the bent and dry roots of the mulberry tree in front, a low earthen house appeared, which looked like a hotel. &lt;br />;I hesitated and asked Ye Lao: Can you borrow the kitchen for me to use? &lt;br />;When Ye Lao saw us, he greeted us with a smile and held my lapel. &lt;br />;He brought me hot water to warm my hands and asked me to sit on the hot bed. &lt;br />;And I have been repeatedly warned not to wash your face with water, because if your face has been frozen for a long time, it will easily break when exposed to water. &lt;br />;I was very touched by the old man&#39;s hospitality and slowly sent the servant away so that we could talk in secret. &lt;br />;I quickly asked Ye Lao which family he was born into? He replied: &quot;Our family has been scholars for generations.&lt;br />;Since the Mongolian nobles came, the rules and systems have been completely different from the original ones.&lt;br />;When the people registered to fight, they all became archers.&lt;br />; />;No matter how good the children and grandchildren are, they are just like pigs and dogs.&lt;br />;An old man like me doesn’t even know a word of the word.&lt;br />;All morals and laws are not excessive, and etiquette and justice are not restricted.&lt;br / >;When I talk about my grandfather and father, the sadness is still deep in my bones!”&lt;br />;After hearing the old man’s tearful words, I sighed and held his hand, but I was speechless. &lt;br />;For a long time, I can only ask the sky, when will we die and be resurrected! &lt;br />;We all sobbed and cried, getting angry facing the southwest corner of the room where the gods are worshipped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Jizhou: the area in the south-central part of present-day Hebei Province, the western end of Shandong Province, and the northern end of Henan Province. &lt;br />;Ancient imperial capital: Jizhou is one of the nine ancient states. According to &quot;Yu Gong&quot;, the nine states are Jizhou, Yanzhou, Qingzhou, Xuzhou, Yangzhou, Jingzhou, Liangzhou, Yongzhou and Yuzhou. According to &quot;Historical Records: The Chronicles of the Five Emperors&quot;, after the Yellow Emperor killed Chiyou, the princes revered him as the emperor, and &quot;the city was located in Zhuolu&quot;. Zhuolu also belonged to the ancient Jizhou area, so it was called the ancient imperial capital. &lt;br />;Yugong: An article in &quot;Shangshu&quot; is China&#39;s earliest geographical work, recording the mountains, rivers, geographical transportation, products and other conditions mainly in the Yellow River Basin. &lt;br />;Cunwu: Village in the mountains, the sentence means that the once prosperous city is now like a desolate and desolate mountain village. &lt;br />;Zai Tu: full of roads. &lt;br />;Congbu: The place where vegetation grows. &lt;br />;Rú (rú): short coat, combined coat. &lt;br />;Xū (xū) Heng: Raise your eyebrows and raise your eyes. Xu, open your eyes and look up. Heng, above the eyebrows. &lt;br />;Lingling: ice. &lt;br />;醪(láo): turbid wine.酤: means “gu” to buy wine. &lt;br />;Lú (lú): The earthen platform where the wine jars are placed in the hotel. &lt;br />;Ju (jū): the front and back parts of clothing. &lt;br />;Drive the servant away: Send the servant away so that he can have a heart-to-heart talk with the old man. &lt;br />;Yi Shiru: A scholar who has been a scholar for generations. Yi, tired, heavy. &lt;br />;Dachao: refers to the Yuan Dynasty. &lt;br />;Liang: Same as &quot;forgiveness&quot;, true and honest. &lt;br />;Registration: Registered in the book. The common people were conscripted into the army. &lt;br />;More than bone marrow: There is more than enough in the bone marrow, which means the pain is deep. &lt;br />;Hesitation (chóu chú): the appearance of being unable to stop. &lt;br />;Su (sū): The recovery of the sick body is called &quot;Su&quot;, which means recovery here. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem not only depicts the poverty and depression in northern rural areas, but also writes about the hospitable, sincere and simple character of northern farmers, criticizing The Mongol rulers destroyed Han culture. The language of this poem is simple, almost colloquial. It directly expresses what it sees and feels without any refinement. It is sincere and caring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I am walking on the Jizhou Road, thinking of the ancient imperial capital.&quot; At the beginning of the poem, the author points out the title - Jizhou Road. Then, the word &quot;meditation&quot; extends the brush strokes to the vast and vicissitudes of history, describing the antiquity and long history of Jizhou. In these two sentences, the author switches from historical contemplation to speculation on changes in the past and present, creating a clever transition for the following description of his experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fourteen sentences from &quot;a city wall is like a village dock&quot; to &quot;like a wine tree&quot; are the author&#39;s description of what he saw on the road to Jizhou. &quot;A city wall is like a village dock, and the rain and snow carry the journey hard.&quot; In the past, it was the location of a prosperous capital city, but now, the city is as decayed as the villages in the mountains; desolate, rainy and snowy, blocking the roads, making travelers miserable. In these two sentences, the author uses the decaying city and the cold rain and snow to show the desolation and desolation of Jizhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following two sentences are, &quot;The thin bushes gather frozen birds, and the foxes roar withered trees.&quot; Following the previous sentence, it further exaggerates and highlights the ruin of Jizhou. In the thickets of vegetation, frozen birds were gathering in groups, and among the dead trees, foxes also let out long and sad roars. This is the situation of birds and foxes on Jizhou Road. Then, the author changed his writing style and wrote about people from frozen birds and foxes. &quot;Cold Wind&quot; In four sentences, the poet outlines the harsh cold of midwinter in just a few strokes. The word &quot;zhu&quot; vividly describes the heavy rain and snow; the word &quot;crack&quot; vividly highlights the strength of the cold wind; and the two sentences &quot;Xu Heng exhaled, and his mustache was covered with ice&quot;. The unusually cold weather is vividly depicted through the description of a specific action. On the journey with howling foxes, howling wind, rain and snow, the poet longed to see a spark of fireworks and find some rice and wine to relieve the coldness in his body and get rid of the hunger in his belly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, &quot;Cheng Cheng watched the fireworks, and there were few people living on the roadside. There was no millet to buy, and no glutinous rice to drink.&quot; Here, the word &quot;Cheng Cheng&quot; is used very cleverly. It depicts both The author&#39;s longing psychology also shows the distance the poet traveled and the depth of hunger and cold he endured. He walked from station to station, but still could not see a trace of fireworks, a grain of rice, or a drop of wine. In these four sentences, the author adds to the misery and desolation of the road through the description of the sparsely populated area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The roots of the mulberry tree in the earth house look like wine.&quot; Suddenly, next to the bent and dry roots of the mulberry tree in front, a low earth house appeared, which looked like a hotel. In these two sentences, the author uses &quot;mulberry tree roots in the earth house&quot; to very vividly reproduce the unique and simple scenery of the northern countryside. The word &quot;as if&quot; not only describes the short and inconspicuous earth house, but also describes the wind and snow. The whole land is vague and difficult to see clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Above, the author vividly shows people the dilapidation, desolation and desolation of Yizhou from the aspects of urban decay, sparse population, and food shortage, and profoundly reveals the rulers of the Yuan Dynasty’s attitude towards this area. The looting of towns and cities severely damaged the agricultural economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Wandering around asking the old man in the field&quot; to &quot;the pain reaches my bones&quot; are the author&#39;s descriptions of what he heard on the Yizhou Road. The poet focused on describing a character who was reduced from a scholar to a wild old man. Through his words and deeds, he complained with sorrow and anger about the destruction and devastation of the Han culture caused by the war. It was sincere and moved people to tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I wandered around and asked the old man if I could lend him my kitchen.&quot; The hungry and cold poet finally found a house, but what he saw on the way made him hesitate. The horrific catastrophe made Yizhou desolate. The poet could not bear to disturb this wild old man who was surviving the disaster. The word &quot;wandering&quot; very truly describes the poet&#39;s inner conflict. But Ye Lao was beyond the poet&#39;s expectation. He smiled happily and stepped forward to roll up the poet&#39;s sleeves, as if he were a friend reunited after a long absence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the eight sentences of &quot;Ye Lao Xin welcomes you with a smile&quot;, the author uses &quot;smile&quot;, &quot;brace&quot;, &quot;warmth&quot;, &quot;warmth&quot;, &quot;admonition&quot; and &quot;I know&quot; to vividly depict Ye Lao&#39;s simple kindness and kindness. Kindness, after reading it, the image of the old man seems to be ready to emerge. Such a kind old man, the place where he lives and the family where he was born. The poet asked sincerely. The sentence &quot;Yun is Yi Shiru&quot; relieved the poet&#39;s doubts. It turns out that this old man was born in a family where generations of scholars have been studying. &quot;Since the coming of the great dynasty&quot; are the words of the old man. He exposed the rulers of the Yuan Dynasty&#39;s contempt for culture and spurred the continuous war. &quot;Even if you have good children and grandchildren, they are just like dogs and pigs.&quot; In these two sentences, the author uses the words of the old man to powerfully reveal the ignorance and ignorance of the people under the autocratic rule of the Yuan Dynasty. &quot;When talking about my grandfather, it hurts to the core of my bones.&quot; Through the old man&#39;s memories of the past, it shows the poet&#39;s nostalgia and yearning for a peaceful country and a peaceful, culturally advanced and etiquette-prosperous society. It also further highlights the poet&#39;s grief, anger and hatred for reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The following is the author&#39;s feeling. &quot;I heard the sudden sigh and hesitated with empty hands.&quot; The author couldn&#39;t help but sigh deeply after listening to the old man&#39;s narration and discussion. He sympathized with the old man&#39;s experience and hated the darkness and absurdity of this reality. He held his hand tightly. The old man&#39;s hand stopped but he couldn&#39;t stop. Here, the author describes three actions in succession: &quot;breathing&quot;, &quot;holding hands&quot; and &quot;hesitating&quot;. Each action strongly highlights the poet&#39;s inner misery. &quot;Hesitating toward the sky, when will I be able to recover again?&quot; The poet stopped, looked up, and asked the vast sky; when will this suffocating rule end and the prosperous era resume. Between the lines, there is infinite sorrow. The last two sentences were, &quot;Crying and unable to bear words, I waved my sleeves to the southwest corner.&quot; The author pushed his grief to a climax. Tears streamed down his face, and he swallowed his voice. He couldn&#39;t bear to say more sad words, so he had to walk toward the southwest alone, brushing his sleeves. go. The phrase &quot;Flick your sleeves in the southwest corner&quot; contains an air of anger in addition to grief. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a narrative poem that seems straightforward, but is actually full of emotion and strict logic. They are arranged in chronological order, and each has its own emphasis. We grasp the key points and fully describe them, revealing the theme layer by layer. First write about the desolation in the north, and then write about the specific situation of cultural destruction. From the outside to the inside, it climaxes with the poet&#39;s grief and indignation and ends abruptly. The sincerity and simplicity of the old man are written in the middle, which makes people see the excellence of traditional cultural upbringing and deepens the hatred of destruction. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; The poet traveled north to Yanjing from 1335 to 1340 AD (from Emperor Shun of the Yuan Dynasty to the first year of the Yuan Dynasty), and the poem may have been written at this time. Wang Mian was born in a peasant family, but because he gave up his official career, he wandered around the world. Jizhou is one of the nine ancient states. It is located in the Central Plains. It was originally prosperous. However, after years of war and the brutal rule of the Yuan and Mongolian nobles, its prosperity has long been gone and it is full of devastation. The poet traveled here and lamented the contrast between the past and the present. He could not help but be filled with anger and wrote this poem. This poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wangmian.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wang Mian (1287-1359), named Yuanzhang, also known as Zhuishishanong, also known as Shizhongweng, Meihua Housekeeper, etc., was born in Fengqiao, Zhuji, Shaoxing City, Zhejiang Province, and was a famous painter and poet in the Yuan Dynasty. , Seal engraver. He was born into a poor family and worked as a herdsman for others when he was young. He became a self-taught man. There are 3 volumes of &quot;Zhuzhai Collection&quot; and 2 volumes of sequels. He has loved plum blossoms all his life, planted plum blossoms, chanted plum blossoms, and painted plum blossoms. The plum blossoms painted are densely packed with branches, full of life, strong and powerful, and have a great influence on future generations. The surviving paintings include &quot;Spring Morning in Nanzhi&quot;, &quot;Dark Plum Blossoms&quot;, &quot;Three Gentlemen&quot;, etc. He was able to seal seals, and he created seals using flower milk stones, and his seal writing skills were exquisite. There is a biography in &quot;History of Ming Dynasty&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>