<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[京兆府栽莲 | 白居易]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231111]]><description> &lt;h2>;Planting lotuses in Jingzhao Prefecture&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Bai Juyi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The ditches store turbid water, and the leaves on the water are fields. &lt;br />;I sighed and realized it was Dongxilian. &lt;br />;There is green mud underneath, and the fragrance cannot be restored. &lt;br />;There is red dust on it and the color is not bright. &lt;br />;The nature of things is like this, and so is the nature of people. &lt;br />;It&#39;s better to be abandoned than to root if it&#39;s not its rightful place. &lt;br />;I used to sit in the stream, and the flowers and leaves were beautiful and clear. &lt;br />;This year I have no land, in front of the Haggard Mansion. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;①Written in the second year of Yuanhe (807). &lt;br />;②Tian Tian: The appearance of floating water grass leaves. An ancient Yuefu poem &quot;Jiangnan&quot;: &quot;Lotus can be picked in the south of the Yangtze River, and there are fields with lotus leaves.&quot;&lt;br />;③Get the place: Tang colloquialism, it means to get the place. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by Bai Juyi for the Weuchu Mansion of Zhou Zhi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poet saw a lotus in front of the mansion, and the lotus branches failed miserably. The first eight sentences described the scene, describing the pale scene of the lotus. The ninth and tenth sentences aroused discussion and exclamation, and also It plays the role of turning point - &quot;the nature of things is the same, and the nature of people is also the same.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The eleventh sentence and the twelfth game express their feelings by borrowing objects, &quot;It is better to be abandoned if it is not the right place.&quot; The living place is not a good place, expressing Bai Juyi&#39;s dissatisfaction with the status quo and the current environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The thirteenth and fourteenth sentences serve as foils and are also lyrical in the form of borrowing objects. They use the beautiful time when lotus flowers were in the stream to express their nostalgia for the past life&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; The last two sentences have a sudden change of tone, &quot;This year I have no land, and I am in front of the haggard mansion.&quot; The poet feels that he has the same fate as the lotus. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/baijuyi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Bai Juyi (772-846), whose courtesy name was Letian, also known as Xiangshan Jushi, and Mr. Zuiyin, was originally from Taiyuan. He moved to Xiagui when his great-grandfather was there. He was born in Xinzheng, Henan. He was a great realist poet in the Tang Dynasty and one of the three major poets in the Tang Dynasty. Bai Juyi and Yuan Zhen jointly advocated the New Yuefu Movement, known as &quot;Yuan Bai&quot; in the world, and &quot;Liu Bai&quot; together with Liu Yuxi. Bai Juyi&#39;s poetry has a wide range of themes, diverse forms, and simple and popular language. He is known as the &quot;Poetry Demon&quot; and the &quot;Poetry King&quot;. He became a bachelor of the Hanlin Academy and a doctor of Zuo Zanshan. In 846 AD, Bai Juyi died in Luoyang and was buried in Xiangshan. There is &quot;Bai&#39;s Changqing Collection&quot; handed down from generation to generation, and his representative poems include &quot;Song of Everlasting Sorrow&quot;, &quot;Charcoal Seller&quot;, &quot;Pipa Play&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 11:23:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[秋夜 | 朱淑真]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231112]]><description> &lt;h2>;Autumn Night&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Zhu Shuzhen&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The autumn air is clear for a long time without sleep, and the candles are frequently cut for the third time. &lt;br />;The bed is filled with cold parasol trees, and the moon shines brightly in the places where the parasol trees are missing. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;It was difficult to fall asleep after tossing and turning at night, and the night air in autumn was cool. After cutting the candlesticks many times, it&#39;s almost midnight. &lt;br />;The shadow of the moon between the sycamore trees outside the window is mottled on the cold bed mat, but the moon seen from the sycamore trees is still so bright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Autumn air: refers to the desolate and chilling air of autumn. &lt;br />;Candleflower: The flower-like object formed by burning the wick of a candle. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two sentences are narrative. The first sentence goes straight to the title of the poem, with the words &quot;night&quot; and &quot;autumn&quot; dotted between them, explaining the time, mentality, and environment. &quot;Long sleepless nights&quot; have already seen the resentful woman full of sorrow, and now it is autumn. The autumn wind is bleak, the night air is cool, the brocade quilt is thin, and the beautiful lady cannot sleep at night, adding a layer of sorrow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second sentence follows &quot;Sleepless&quot; and writes about personnel activities. Since it is difficult to fall asleep after tossing and turning, it is difficult to pass the long night. The empty room was lonely, the red candles were burning high, and she was bored, so she had no choice but to cut candle flowers to relieve her loneliness. &quot;Candleflower&quot; refers to lanterns. The ancients believed that lanterns were a sign of happy events. Du Fu&#39;s poem says: &quot;How can we be so happy with the lights and flowers? The wine and greenery are the perfect match&quot; (&quot;Drinking Alone into a Poetry&quot;). The lanterns and lights were pleasing to the eye, but she couldn&#39;t resolve the gloomy and painful mood in front of her. The word &quot;frequency&quot; is used to describe the heroine&#39;s anxiety and uneasiness. &quot;The third watch of desire&quot; continues the word &quot;Yejiu&quot;, which expresses the suffering of loneliness and loneliness of the missing woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last two sentences describe the scene. The third sentence makes a twist, writing about the moon shadow on the bed. One &quot;cool&quot; is unique, which is the poetic eye of the whole poem. It echoes the &quot;clear autumn air&quot; in the first sentence and writes the visual image in a tactile state. The shadow of the dancing moon filtered through the cracks of the plane trees outside the window was mottled and covered with cold, empty bed mats. No one would bring her warmth tonight. This scene is heart-wrenching. On the surface, the word &quot;man&quot; refers to the density of light and shadow, but in fact, it refers to the feeling of being full of worries and depressing things. This sentence clearly expresses the sadness and beauty of the moonlight in the house, and implicitly expresses the loss of people&#39;s hearts. The virtual and the real are intertwined, and the charm is far-reaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last sentence writes about the moon outside the window and ends with a scene language, leaving the reader with endless space for imagination. This sentence is a continuation of the previous sentence, with a true transition from the moonlight and tree shadows on the bed to the bright moon in the sky, expressing the poet&#39;s sudden joy and worry when looking at the moon and cherishing people. &quot;The moon shines brightly in the missing part of the phoenix tree&quot;, showing a lofty and sparse picture of the moonlight on an autumn night. Under the bright moonlight, she seems to have recalled the sweetness and romance of the past when &quot;the willow trees were above the moon, and people made appointments after dusk&quot;; but now, at the moment of &quot;losing weight for another night&quot;, no one can &quot;cut the hair together&quot; with her. Window Candle&quot;. I want to be detached but cannot. The brightness of the &quot;moon&quot; just illuminates the indelible gloom deep in the human heart. &quot;The missing part of the sycamore tree&quot;, the freeze-frame of this background image, implies the sorrow of the missing woman who cannot be reunited with the person she loves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is in order, starting from the outside (the autumn air is clear) to the inside (the candles are frequently cut), and then from the inside (the bed is cool) to the outside (the moon is bright in the missing place), layer by layer. Repeatedly exaggerating the depression of being alone. The stitches are fine, the four sentences are closely connected, and the connection is smooth. There is no word &quot;love&quot; and there is no emotion anywhere. The imagery is clear and prominent, the artistic conception is empty and quiet, and the details are concise and vivid, giving people endless aftertaste. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/zhushuzhen.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Zhu Shuzhen (about 1135~about 1180), also known as Youqi Jushi, was a female poet in the Song Dynasty and one of the female writers with the richest surviving works since the Tang and Song Dynasties. He was alive in the early years of the Southern Song Dynasty. His ancestral home was Shezhou (now Shexian County, Anhui Province). According to &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot;, he was &quot;a native of Haining, central Zhejiang&quot;, and one said he was from Qiantang, Zhejiang (now Hangzhou, Zhejiang). Born into a family of officials. The husband was a minor grammar official, but due to different interests and disharmony between the couple, he eventually died of depression and early death. It is also said that after Shuzhen passed away, her parents burned her manuscripts during her lifetime. The rest of his life cannot be examined and is inconclusive. The existing &quot;Collection of Broken Heart Poems&quot; and &quot;Hancheang Ci&quot; have been handed down to the world, and they are the remaining chapters after the calamity. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 04:23:13 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>