<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[生查子·旅思 | 吴伟业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310171]]><description> &lt;h2>;Shengchazi·Lvsi&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Wu Weiye&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;One ​​foot crosses the river and the mountain, and thousands of Huai trees grow. The water gurgled on the rocks and flowed into the green stream. &lt;br />;The north wind is cold in June, and the leaves fall without morning or evening. Duyue and Chuanyun are walking around in the dark forest. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One foot: describes the low mountains in the distance. &lt;br />;Changhuai: Huaihe River. &lt;br />;Qingxi: The East Canal dug by the Wu State during the Three Kingdoms period passed through present-day Nanjing and entered the Qinhuai River. &lt;br />;Duyue: Passing through the shade of trees. Yue: shady trees beside the road. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This word expresses the thoughts of traveling by describing the scenery. The distant mountains and trees gradually recede into the distance, and the clear spring water beside me flows over the rocks and merges into the green stream. Even though it was midsummer in June, when Duyue passed through the clouds on the gloomy mountain road, he still felt cold and windy, the forest was dark, and it was difficult to distinguish between morning and dusk. &quot;Lvsi&quot; is not written clearly, but &quot;Lvsi&quot; appears by itself. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wuweiye.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wu Weiye (1609～1672), courtesy name Jungong and Meicun, alias Lu Qiaosheng, Guanyin Master, Dayun Taoist, lived in Kunshan, Jiangsu Province for a long time, his grandfather first moved to Taicang, Jiangsu Province, Han nationality, native of Taicang, Jiangsu Province , Chongzhen Jinshi. A famous poet in the late Ming and early Qing dynasties, he is known as the &quot;Three Great Masters of Jiangzuo&quot; along with Qian Qianyi and Gong Dingzi. He is also the founder of the Loudong Poetry School. He is good at seven-character singing. He first learned the &quot;Changqing style&quot; and later developed his own new chant, which later generations called &quot;Meicun style&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[宣城见杜鹃花 | 李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310162]]><description> &lt;h2>;Seeing azaleas in Xuancheng&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Li Bai&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The Shu Kingdom once heard Zigui birds, and azaleas were seen again in Xuancheng. &lt;br />;One scream, one ileum and one rupture, recalling Sanba in three springs and three months. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;In my distant hometown, I once heard the sad cry of the Zigui bird; now in a foreign land In Xuancheng, we saw azaleas in full bloom again. &lt;br />;Zigui screams sadly, making people heartbroken. In late spring in March, when birds are singing and flowers are blooming, the wanderer is missing his hometown of Sanba. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xuancheng: Today it belongs to Anhui. &lt;br />;Shu: refers to Sichuan. Zigui Bird: Also known as cuckoo, it is commonly known as the heartbroken bird because of its shrill and shrill song that makes people homesick. It is the most common bird in Shu. Legend has it that it was transformed after the death of Du Yu, the ancient king of Shu. &lt;br />;Azalea: Azalea blooms in late spring every year, when the cuckoo is singing, hence the name azalea. &lt;br />;Sanchun: refers to spring. Sanba: the three counties of Bajun, Badong and Basi, refer to the Kingdom of Shu, present-day Sichuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; There are two main theories about the creation time of this poem. According to Pei Fei&#39;s &quot;Compendium of Li Bai Chronicles&quot;, this poem was written in the spring of the 14th year of Tianbao&#39;s reign (755) by Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, when Li Bai was in Xuancheng County. Another theory is represented by Xue Tianwei, who believes that this poem was written after Li Bai returned from exile and was pardoned. When he wrote this poem, Li Bai was already in his twilight years. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is inspired by the feeling of things. &quot;Zigui birds were heard in Shu, and azaleas were seen in Xuancheng.&quot; In late spring, in March, Li Bai, who was staying in Xuancheng, felt that his dim eyes suddenly reflected a burst of red. Looking carefully, it turned out to be azaleas in bloom. This rhododendron seems to be the flower of my hometown. The poet&#39;s homesickness was touched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Sichuan, whenever the azaleas bloom, the cuckoo bird begins to sing. Zigui bird, also known as cuckoo, the flower and bird have the same name, which is also a reason why the poet evokes the association. This bird is said to be the spirit of Du Yu, the ancient Shu emperor. Du Yu was known as Emperor Wang, but he thought he had little virtue, so he abdicated the throne and went into exile. After his death, he turned into a cuckoo. In late spring, it began to cry sadly, as if calling: &quot;It&#39;s better to go back! It&#39;s better to go back!&quot; Day and night, it kept crying until blood dripped from its mouth. At this moment, the sound of the hooves of the Zigui bird seemed to ring in the poet&#39;s ears, calling him back one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first and second sentences of the poem form a natural contrast. From the comparison and connection of geography and time, they truly reproduce the process of touching homesickness. The word order of these two sentences is reversed: originally, I saw the azaleas in Xuancheng first, and then I thought of the Zigui bird in Shu. However, the poet reversed it, writing first the virtual scene in his memory, and then the real scene in front of him. In this way, the thought of the motherland is placed in a prominent position, indicating that the thought of the motherland is originally smoldering in the heart. Once it is evoked at this time, it will be very miserable and intense. However, the poet, tortured by homesickness, cannot return to his hometown at the moment. In his youth, he &quot;went to his country with a sword, said goodbye to his relatives and traveled far away&quot;, and wanted to realize his grand ambitions in the vast world beyond his hometown. I wanted to become famous and then return to my hometown. Unexpectedly, his achievements were unsuccessful, and he ended up in this situation when he was old. He felt that he had no face to see his elders in Shu. What&#39;s more, Li Bai is currently trapped in Xuancheng, dragging his old and sick body and unable to embark on the journey. The poet, who wandered all his life, not only had no destination in politics and career, but also had nothing to rely on in his life. Looking at his hometown thousands of miles away, one can imagine the sadness in his heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third and fourth sentences follow the first and second sentences respectively, further exaggerating the strong nostalgia. The first sentence says &quot;I have heard it&quot;, and the third sentence emphasizes how real it is: the common name of the Zigui bird is the broken-hearted bird, &quot;when it cries, its ileum is broken,&quot; it crows endlessly, which makes the poet feel sad. Broken into inches. The last sentence points out the season, and uses the four words &quot;three springs and three months&quot; to supplement the second sentence; the three words &quot;recalling Sanba&quot; highlight the theme of homesickness, integrating the blooming azaleas, Zigui&#39;s sad cry and the poet&#39;s heartbroken pain In one body, the whole poem is enveloped in a vast and boundless melancholy. The three or four lines of the poem seem to be in contrast, but in fact they are not quite right. The poem connects the two words &quot;one&quot; and &quot;three&quot; together, making people feel the incomparable sadness and pain when homesickness strikes. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/libai.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Li Bai (701-762), also known as Taibai, also known as Qinglian Jushi, also known as &quot;The Exiled Immortal&quot;, was a great romantic poet in the Tang Dynasty and was hailed as the &quot;Poetry Immortal&quot; by later generations. &quot;, together with Du Fu are called &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, namely &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively called &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. According to the &quot;New Book of Tang&quot; records, Li Bai was the ninth grandson of Emperor Xingsheng (Liang Wuzhao King Li Hao) and the same clan as the kings of Li and Tang Dynasties. He is a cheerful and generous person who loves drinking, writing poetry, and making friends. Li Bai was deeply influenced by Huang Lao Liezhuang&#39;s thoughts. The &quot;Collection of Li Taibai&quot; has been handed down from generation to generation. Most of his poems were written when he was drunk. His representative works include &quot;Wang Lushan Waterfall&quot;, &quot;The Road is Difficult&quot;, &quot;The Road to Shu is Difficult&quot;, &quot;About Wine&quot; and &quot;Morning&quot;. &quot;Fa Baidi City&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>