<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[长干曲四首·其一 | 崔颢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239221]]><description> &lt;h2>;One of Four Changqian Songs&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Cui Hao&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Where does the Jun family live? I live in Hengtang. &lt;br />;The boat stopped for a while to ask, maybe he is from the same hometown. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Brother, where is your home? My family lives in Hengtang, Jiankang. &lt;br />;Stop the boat and let me ask you a question. Judging from our accents, I think we are from the same hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Changganxing: the name of Yuefu music. It is a folk song from the Changqianli area, which is south of today&#39;s Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;br />;Jun: An ancient honorific title for men. &lt;br />;Concubine: A modest word for an ancient woman to call herself. &lt;br />;Hengtang: now Jiangning District, Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;br />;Temporarily: for the time being, tentatively. &lt;br />;Excuse me: Please ask. &lt;br />;Or fear: maybe. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This lyric poem captures a dramatic moment in life, using the technique of line drawing and a few strokes to make the characters, The scene comes to life on the page. It does not use any color to highlight it, just like an ink stroke; it does not need any decoration to highlight it, it is a sketch; it does not rely on any scenery, just like a male and female duet; it cuts off the beginning and the end to highlight the main body, and it is very like a one-act play. The subject matter is ordinary, but the expression technique is extraordinary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A girl who lived in Hengtang heard the voice of a man in a neighboring boat while rafting, so she innocently asked: Are you from the same hometown as me? It is such a simple plot, using only five words &quot;I live in Hengtang&quot; to clarify the speaker&#39;s gender and residence through the heroine&#39;s words. The word &quot;stop boat&quot; is also used to indicate that it is a chance encounter on the water, and the word &quot;jun&quot; is used to indicate that the other person is a male. The narrative in front of the title has been completely omitted using this technique of killing two eggs with one stone. The poem goes straight to the point at the beginning, allowing the heroine to ask questions and appear on the page, and the reader hears her voice as if she sees the person, and there is no sense of being clueless. From the perspective of literary description skills, &quot;co-production of voices and forms&quot; has reached the artistic height of &quot;everything should be included, and there should be no end&quot;, which is both condensed and concentrated yet exquisite and clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In just two words, the poet only used his tone of voice to express the heroine&#39;s voice and smile vividly. He did not write &quot;Ping Ping curled up for more than thirteen years&quot; like Du Mu, nor did he point out &quot;fifteen years ago, weeping in the spring breeze, swinging on the back&quot; like Li Shangyin. He just asked the question and without waiting for the other party&#39;s reply, he eagerly reported that &quot;I live in Hengtang&quot;, which naturally reflected the age of the heroine from the naive and innocent tone. The hero didn&#39;t speak, but the reason why the little girl had the idea that she might be from the same hometown was because she heard the other person&#39;s words with a local accent. Here the poet omits the link of &quot;asking each other because of hearing the sound&quot;. This is a description outside of words, the so-called &quot;writing without writing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem also expresses the heroine’s situation and inner loneliness. Just from the fact that she was eager to &quot;stop the boat&quot; to ask questions when she heard the local accent, it can be seen that she left her hometown and stayed in the water, alone and without anyone to talk to. Therefore, I was overjoyed to hear the sounds of my hometown in a foreign land and regard it as my hometown. The poet not only reproduced the heroine&#39;s voice and smile on paper, but also deeply explored her personality and heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The language of the poem is simple and natural, like a folk song. But it has endless artistic appeal. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/cuihao.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Cui Hao (hào) (704-754), a native of Bianzhou (now Kaifeng City, Henan Province), was a poet of the Tang Dynasty. In the 11th year of Kaiyuan of Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty (AD 723), he became a Jinshi and became the Prime Minister of Taipu Temple. He was appointed as Si Xun Yuan Wai Lang in Tianbaozhong. The most praised piece is his &quot;Yellow Crane Tower&quot;. It is said that Li Bai wrote for it, and once praised it, &quot;Cui Hao wrote a poem on top of the scenery before his eyes.&quot; &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot; contains forty-two poems. He has an upright nature and quick thinking. His works are passionate, bold and magnificent. He is the author of &quot;The Collection of Cui Hao&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江村 | 杜甫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239211]]><description> &lt;h2>;Jiangcun&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Du Fu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The Qingjiang River embraces the village, and everything in the Changxia River Village is quiet. &lt;br />;The swallows on the beams come and go, and the gulls in the water are close to each other. (Liang Shang&#39;s first work: Tang Shang)&lt;br />;The old wife draws paper to make a chess game, and the child knocks needles to make fishing hooks. &lt;br />;But if you have an old friend to offer you Lumi, what more can you ask for in addition to your tiny body? &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The clear water of Huanhua Creek flows windingly around the village, in the long In the summer, everything seems quiet and leisurely. &lt;br />;The swallows on the beams flew freely, and the white gulls in the water stayed close to each other, accompanying each other. &lt;br />;My wife who has been with him for many years drew a chessboard on paper, and my young son bent a steel needle to make a fishhook. &lt;br />;As long as an old friend gives me some money and rice, what else can I ask for? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Jiangcun: a village by the river. &lt;br />;Qingjiang: clear river water. Jiang: Refers to the Jinjiang River, a tributary of the Minjiang River. A section in the western suburbs of Chengdu is called Huanhua Creek. Song: twists and turns. Hug: embrace, surround. &lt;br />;Chang Xia: long summer. You: tranquility, ease. &lt;br />;Ziwenjilai: Come and go freely, without restraint. &lt;br />;Be close to each other: be close to each other. &lt;br />;Draw paper as a chess game: draw a chessboard on paper. &lt;br />;Zhizi: young son. &lt;br />;Lumi: The salary of ancient officials, here refers to money and rice. The sentence &quot;but you&quot; is said to be &quot;drugs are the only thing needed for many diseases&quot;. &lt;br />;Small body: The humble body is the author’s self-effacing words. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Analysis of &quot;medicines are needed for many illnesses&quot; and &quot;but there are old friends who provide Lumi&quot;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The last couplet of the poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot;, There are two versions. As for the advantages and disadvantages of the two versions, some people say:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Let&#39;s first look at the sentence &quot;The only thing needed for many diseases is medicine&quot;. Above we have already perceived the happiness and joy of the poet living in a secluded Jiangcun. Leisure is only superficial. The poet couldn&#39;t help but think to himself: The only medicine needed by the old and sick body can satisfy this meager hope. What else can a man with a humble body ask for? And we understand: In a world of chaos and separation, life is like an ant. , what&#39;s the use of medicine, it&#39;s just to linger on; it&#39;s just the temporary peace and family reunion that makes me think of cherishing life so that the hard-earned happiness can continue. This should be a very simple, humble and last resort hope. . But can this hope be satisfied? If you read the last sentence of the last couplet &quot;What else can you ask for in addition to a small body&quot;, you will find that it is just an extravagant hope. After reading this and thinking of this, will we feel sorry for Lao Du? Shedding tears of sympathy for the hard and difficult living conditions?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look again at the sentence &quot;But there are old friends offering Lumi&quot;. It makes us understand that the peaceful and peaceful life described above is based on &quot;Old friends offering Lumi&quot;. &quot;Lumi&quot;. And when the two sentences of the last couplet are read together, the inner emotion is not so much luck, but a kind of helplessness and bitterness. After wandering around for most of his life, persistent pursuit, he was The currents of society are colliding and turbulent, and I have ended up with no life and no belonging. Although my old friend Yan Wu cares about me, the sense of failure in life cannot be said to not tightly suppress the strong heart of a self-respecting man, let alone This kind of refuge is only temporary and unstable. Once the condition of &quot;old friends providing Lumi&quot; is lost, life will fall into hardship and wandering. Therefore, the faint worry about the future and endless sadness still torment the poet from time to time. His heart made him still have a strong dream-like feeling even in the situation where his family was reunited.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If we only analyze it from the pros and cons, in fact, after the war in the Central Plains, Du Fu Finally settled in Chengdu Thatched Cottage, I should feel relieved at this time. In Shu, everyone from Jiannan Jiedushi to county magistrates and governors came to visit Du Fu, which made Du Fu&#39;s poems at this stage full of a peaceful and natural atmosphere, such as &quot;Walking Alone by the River Looking for Flowers&quot;, among which: &quot;The Song of Thatched Cottage Broken by the Autumn Wind&quot; is just an example. Du&#39;s poem emphasizes individual emotions, and the emotion expressed in the last sentence should be the cherishment of today&#39;s peace and stability as he looks back on the turbulent years in the past. Therefore, in the emotional nature of the two sentences &quot;Many illnesses require only medicine&quot; and &quot;But there are old friends who provide Lumi&quot;, it is obvious that &quot;Many illnesses require only medicine&quot; is better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, if you look at the time of appearance of each version and the rhyme of the previous sentence, it should be the sentence &quot;But there is an old friend offering Lumi&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Commentary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a plain and natural seven-character poem. The author uses a pure and simple style of writing and simple and unpretentious language to embody Huan. The beautiful and tranquil natural scenery by the Huaxi River and the leisurely and comfortable taste of village life depict the most common and distinctive scenes of Jiangcun Village in summer in a vivid, natural and lovely way, with an idyllic, tranquil, elegant and simple charm. Cai Mengbi of the Song Dynasty commented in his &quot;Cottage Poems&quot;: &quot;The reason why he is greater than others is that he is ordinary. Although it sounds like a common thing, it is actually the matter before his eyes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first half of the poem is about people and their relationship. The harmony of nature is pleasing to the eye, and people feel free, cordial and harmonious in nature. The neck couplet is full of joyful and vibrant family life scenes, which deeply conveys the poet&#39;s joy and cherishment of family happiness. The last two sentences are Not seeking the plain state of mind of being an official. This is a rare and cheerful work in Du Fu&#39;s poems. Huang Sheng&#39;s &quot;Du Shi Shuo&quot; in the Qing Dynasty said that &quot;Du&#39;s rhythm is not difficult for the old and healthy, but difficult for the relaxed. This poem is free and elegant. To&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In the summer of 760 AD (the first year of Emperor Suzong’s reign in the Tang Dynasty), the poet Du Fu, with the support of his friends, went to the countryside outside Chengdu, Sichuan. A thatched cottage was built on the bank of Huanhua River. After suffering from the war, life temporarily gained peace. This poem was written during this period. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; After suffering many hardships and being displaced, the author Du Fu finally found a temporary place to live. In a peaceful atmosphere, this poem delicately describes the beautiful and tranquil scenery, casually describes the leisurely and warm life, and shows the author Du Fu&#39;s rare satisfaction and joy in a stable life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Qingjiang River hugs the village, and the Changxia River is quiet.&quot; In the village in early summer, a winding river flows quietly around the village. The water is clear and there are fish in the water. Playing, coming and going were silent, everything in the whole village was so quiet. A Qingjiang River brings peace and tranquility to the village. This &quot;Qingjiang&quot; is Huanhua Creek in Chengdu. The poet named it &quot;Qing&quot;, probably because he likes it to flow leisurely around the village. So give it a good name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Baocunliu&quot; uses personification to describe its cuteness, and it also echoes the title of the poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot;. The first two sentences set the atmosphere of the whole poem and convey the purpose of the whole poem. Everything is going smoothly, and the poet who has gone through hardships no longer has worries and sorrows, and can enjoy the scenery of the village with ease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The swallows on the beams come and go, and the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; Look, the newly built thatched cottage has just been completed, and there are naughty little swallows flying briskly over and over. No one pays attention to them, but They play so happily, just like lively children. The poet stroked his beard and laughed, strolling to the riverside. There were two white gulls floating softly on the river. They were in front or behind, sometimes crowing with their necks crossed, sometimes chasing each other and circling on the water - they They must be a couple who love each other. He Xun, a poet of the Southern Dynasties, once wrote a sentence about &quot;Pityful twin gulls, swimming on the water day and night&quot;. Du Fu once studied He Xun&#39;s poems. When he saw this scene, he must have felt something and forgotten about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The old wife draws paper to make a chess game, and the child knocks needles to make fishing hooks.&quot; The poet walked slowly home with a happy mood, and saw his wife sitting in the shade of the tree in front of the door, writing on the paper What was painted on it, when I looked closer, I saw it was a chess game. The sound of &quot;ding ding&quot; came, and the youngest son was immersed in tapping a needle seriously. This playful child wanted to make a fishhook by himself so that he could go fishing on the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scenes like this are probably common in the village, but for the author Du Fu, who experienced the Anshi Rebellion, suffered many setbacks, and spent half his life, it was a rare and precious blessing, which made him heartbroken. A warm one. He had never imagined such a warm moment when he was &quot;a wealthy man in the morning, and a fat horse in the evening. Broken cups and cold dishes, everywhere lurking sadness&quot; (&quot;Twenty-two Rhymes from Wei Zuo Chengzhang&quot;). These two sentences capture the most ordinary scenes in life, conveying a universal warmth of family affection and the leisurely beauty of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;But if an old friend gives me rice, what more can I ask for in addition to a small body?&quot; The poet sighed from the peaceful life scene in front of him: An old friend gave me food and his salary, and I, an ordinary person, What more can a lowly man ask for? These two sentences seem to express happiness and satisfaction, but if you read them carefully, you will find that they actually contain much sadness and bitterness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Fu was able to live in a thatched cottage in Chengdu only because of the help of his friends. Although he had such happiness and tranquility in front of him, it was based on his dependence on others. The great poet who was revered by later generations as the &quot;Saint of Poetry&quot; had to rely on gifts from others to survive, and he also said that he &quot;wanted nothing more&quot;, that is, he had no other requirements. The calmer and calmer this language is, the more sad and sad it makes readers cry. His ambition was to &quot;serve the emperors Yao and Shun, and then make the customs pure&quot; (&quot;Twenty-two Rhymes of Presenting to Wei Zuocheng&quot;). However, dozens of spring and autumn years have passed, and now in his old age, people only require one vegetable and one meal. The poet spoke so casually, as if he no longer had the haze of life in his heart and no longer wanted to face the turmoil and noise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the artistic point of view of poetry, this poem is rigorously written but flows naturally; the words are concise, the description is subtle, and it is invisible. This is the sophistication of Du Fu&#39;s rhymed poetry. The first line of the last couplet is &quot;But there are old friends who offer Lumi&quot;, and the first line is &quot;The only medicine needed for many illnesses&quot;. From a plain and poetic point of view, the sentence &quot;But there is&quot; is better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is intertwined with each other, and the echoes are tight: &quot;Liang Shangyan&quot; belongs to the &quot;village&quot;, and &quot;gull in the water&quot; belongs to the &quot;river&quot;: &quot;chess game&quot; is the same as &quot;Long Summer&quot;, and &quot;fishing hook&quot; also implies &quot;Qingjiang&quot; &quot;. The chin couplet &quot;Since going and coming, the swallows on the beams, the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; The two characters &quot;zi&quot; and the two characters &quot;xiang&quot; are in the same sentence; &quot;go&quot;, &quot;lai&quot;, &quot;ki&quot; and &quot;near&quot; are in the same sentence. right. Corresponding to itself and to each other, it reads briskly and wanderingly. The characters for &quot;painting&quot; and &quot;knocking&quot; on the neck couplet are both ready-made. Both sentences use a simple tone, which best expresses the artistic conception of a husband and wife who respect each other as they grow older, and a child who is foolish and stubborn, and who knows no difference between the wise and the foolish. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Artistic Features&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Don’t repeat the word repetition: In the two sentences of the first couplet of this poem, the word &quot;江&quot; and the word &quot;村&quot; appear twice. Second-rate. According to the general rules for writing rhymed poetry, compound characters should not be included in the same couplet of the chin and neck couplets. Although the requirements for the first and last couplets of loose sentences are not so strict, compound words should be avoided as much as possible. This poem uses a pair of compound characters, which gives it a light and elegant feeling, and does not feel like it is a repetition. This situation is like the obfuscation in the rhythmic sentences. Obvious sentences must be corrected with oblique sentences, and complex characters must be used to make up for complex characters. What&#39;s more, the second sentence contains two other repeated words &quot;things&quot;. As a result, when the first two sentences of the poem are read, there is no sense of support at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is intertwined with each other, and the echoes are tight: &quot;Liang Shangyan&quot; belongs to the &quot;village&quot;, and &quot;gull in the water&quot; belongs to the &quot;river&quot;: &quot;chess game&quot; is the same as &quot;Long Summer&quot;, and &quot;fishing hook&quot; also implies &quot;Qingjiang&quot; &quot;. The chin couplet &quot;Since going and coming, the swallows on the beams, the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; The two characters &quot;zi&quot; and the two characters &quot;xiang&quot; are in the same sentence; &quot;go&quot;, &quot;lai&quot;, &quot;ki&quot; and &quot;near&quot; are in the same sentence. right. Corresponding to itself and to each other, it reads briskly and wanderingly. The characters for &quot;painting&quot; and &quot;knocking&quot; on the neck couplet are both ready-made. Both sentences use a simple tone, which best expresses the artistic conception of a husband and wife who respect each other as they grow older, and a child who is foolish and stubborn, and who knows no difference between the wise and the foolish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The conclusion suddenly turns sad: Du Fu has two lines of poems in which he talks about the joys and sorrows of writing poetry. He said that &quot;poetry is the source of great sorrow, but poetry becomes desolate when it is chanted&quot; (&quot;Towards the End&quot;). This poem was originally about a leisurely state of mind, but as he wrote it, at the end of the poem, he could not help but reveal his loneliness and unhappiness, making people feel melancholy. Many of Du Fu&#39;s impromptu poems are almost all like this. The predecessors called Du&#39;s poems &quot;depressive&quot;, and the opportunity may lie here. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written in the first year of Shangyuan (760) by Emperor Suzong of Tang Dynasty. A few months ago, after four years of exile, the poet traveled from Tongzhou via Mianzhou to the banks of Huanhua Creek on the outskirts of Chengdu, a prosperous hometown in the southwest that had not been harassed by war and had remained quiet for the time being. The thatched cottage that he worked hard to manage with the help of relatives and friends has begun to take shape; the poet, who has experienced the pain of leaving his hometown and the hardships of displacement, finally found a temporary place to live. It&#39;s early summer, and by the Huanhua River, the river is winding, the water and trees are clear, and it&#39;s a quiet and elegant pastoral scene. The poet picked up the title of the poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot; and wrote about it. It is conceivable that he felt happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three words &quot;everything is quiet&quot; in the second sentence of the first couplet of this poem are the key words of the whole poem and bring out a purpose. The four sentences in the middle closely follow &quot;Everything is quiet&quot; and are narrated all the way. The swallows in the beams come and go freely and at ease; the white gulls on the river, far and near, accompany each other. From the poet&#39;s point of view, both swallows and gulls have a sense of forgetfulness and adaptability to the crowd. Things are so quiet, and the interesting human affairs especially make the poet happy: the infatuation and naivety of the old wife drawing paper for a chess game is lovable; the innocence of the child knocking needles to make fishing hooks is endearing. The chess game is the best place to spend the summer, and the Qingjiang River is just right for fishing, so the villagers have fun and everything goes well. After a long period of separation, why wouldn&#39;t the poet feel happy and satisfied when he regained the joy of a family and children? The concluding sentence, &quot;If you have an old friend to offer you Lumi, what more can you ask for than a small body?&quot; Although it is a happy word on the surface, it contains a lot of sadness in the heart. Saying &quot;but there is&quot; does not guarantee that there will be something; saying &quot;what more should we ask for&quot; just means that we have already asked for something. Du Fu has indeed not forgotten that the leisurely and leisurely life in front of him is built on the basis of &quot;offering Lumi to old friends&quot;. This is a very sensitive tender point. Once there is a problem with the distribution of money and rice, everything will be out of the question. Therefore, we might as well say that the last two sentences of this conclusion are not so much words of luck as words of bitterness. A generation of poets who struggled with poverty and relied on others to survive temporarily found a place to live and Du Fu was able to live in peace. At the same time, he uttered such sad words, which is really a strong indictment of the feudal ruling class&#39;s destruction of talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The four sentences in the central couplet fully describe the quiet things in Jiangcun in terms of physical and human relations. Then, in the concluding sentence, the sentence &quot;what else can you ask for&quot; is used to connect &quot;everything is quiet&quot; and conclude. It completes the theme of an article, is the simplest and most stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot; also has unique features in its artistic treatment:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First, do not repeat the repetition of characters. In the two sentences of the first couplet of this poem, the characters &quot;jiang&quot; and &quot;village&quot; are found twice. According to the general rules for writing rhymed poems, compound characters should be avoided in the same couplet of chin and neck. Although the requirements for sentences with loose lines in the first and last couplets are not so strict, compound characters should be avoided as much as possible. Nowadays, using a pair of compound characters gives a light and elegant feeling, and does not feel like it is a repetition. This situation is very similar to the obsessive sentences in rhythmic sentences. Obvious sentences must be corrected with oblique sentences, and complex characters must be compensated with complex characters. What&#39;s more, the second sentence contains two other repeated words &quot;things&quot;. In this way, when the first two sentences of the poem are read, there is no sense of support at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Secondly, the whole poem is meshed forward and backward, and the echoes are compact. &quot;Liang Shangyan&quot; belongs to &quot;village&quot;, and &quot;Oll in the Water&quot; belongs to &quot;river&quot;: &quot;Chess Game&quot; directly represents &quot;Changxia&quot;, and &quot;fishing hook&quot; also implies &quot;Qingjiang&quot;. The chin couplet &quot;Since going and coming, the swallows on the beams, the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; The two characters &quot;zi&quot; and the two characters &quot;xiang&quot; are in the same sentence: &quot;go&quot;, &quot;come&quot;, &quot;ki&quot; and &quot;near&quot; are in the same sentence. Corresponding to itself and to each other, it reads briskly and wanderingly. The characters for &quot;painting&quot; and &quot;knocking&quot; on the neck couplet are both ready-made. Both sentences use a simple tone, which best expresses the artistic conception of a husband and wife who respect each other as they grow older, and a child who is foolish and stubborn, and who knows no difference between the wise and the foolish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third is the conclusion, which suddenly turns sad and has the characteristics of Du Fu&#39;s poetry. Du Fu has two lines of poems in which he describes the joys and sorrows of writing poetry, saying that &quot;the extreme sorrow is brought about by poetry, but when poetry becomes chanting, it becomes desolate&quot; (&quot;Towards the End&quot;). This poem was originally about a leisurely state of mind, but as he wrote it, at the end of the poem, he could not help but reveal his loneliness and unhappiness, making people feel melancholy. Many of Du Fu&#39;s impromptu poems are almost all like this. The predecessors called Du&#39;s poems &quot;depressive&quot;, and the opportunity may lie here. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/dufu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Du Fu (712-770), whose courtesy name is Zimei, calls himself Shaoling Yelao, is also known as &quot;Du Gongbu&quot;, &quot;Du Shaoling&quot;, etc., Han nationality, Fugong County, Henan (now Henan Province Gongyi City), a great realist poet in the Tang Dynasty, Du Fu is respected by the world as the &quot;Sage of Poetry&quot;, and his poems are called &quot;the history of poetry&quot;. Du Fu and Li Bai are collectively known as &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, known as &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively known as &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. He was concerned about the country and the people, and had a noble personality. About 1,400 of his poems have been preserved. His poetic skills are exquisite, and he is highly respected in Chinese classical poetry and has far-reaching influence. He lived in Chengdu from 759 to 766, and is commemorated by Du Fu&#39;s Thatched Cottage in later generations. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 07:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>