<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[塞下曲 | 卢纶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239282]]><description> &lt;h2>;Saixiaqu&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Lu Lun&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The wild geese fly high in the moonlight, and the Chanyu escapes at night. &lt;br />;I want to chase Qingqi away, but the heavy snow covers my bow and sword. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;In the dead of night, dark clouds cover the moon, and wild geese fly in the sky. Shanyu’s army wants to To escape quietly under the cover of night. &lt;br />;Just as he was about to lead the light cavalry in pursuit, heavy snow fell on his bows and knives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Foreign Song: A military song from the ancient frontier fortress. &lt;br />;Dark Moon: No moonlight. &lt;br />;Chan Yu (chán yú): leader of the Huns. This refers to the supreme commander of the invaders. &lt;br />;Escape: escape. &lt;br />;Will: lead. &lt;br />;Light cavalry: light and fast cavalry. &lt;br />;Chasing: chasing. &lt;br />;Man: full. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Song under the Fortress&quot; is an old title of Han Dynasty Yuefu and belongs to &quot;Hengchui Songs&quot;. The content is mostly about the frontier fortress. There were originally six poems in total, and Hengtang retired scholars selected four of them. This is the third poem in Lu Lun&#39;s poem &quot;Song under the Sai&quot;. Lu Lun once served as a marshal judge in the shogunate and had experience in military life. His poems describing this kind of life are relatively substantial and vigorous in style. This poem describes the general&#39;s heroic and heroic preparations to lead his troops to chase the enemy on a snowy night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem begins with a description of the scene. &quot;Moonlight and black geese flying high&quot; is not the scene in the eyes, but the scene in the mind. The snowy night and dark moon were not a normal time for wild geese to fly; but the startled flying geese revealed that the enemy was taking action. These five words not only indicate that the time is winter, but also highlight the tense atmosphere before the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Chan Yu fled at night&quot;, the enemy moved at night, not leading troops to attack, but fleeing hastily under the cover of moonlight. The tone of the poem is affirmative, the judgment is clear, and it is full of contempt for the enemy and our army&#39;s belief in victory, which makes readers excited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last two sentences describe the scene of the general preparing to chase the enemy, which is extraordinary. &quot;In order to drive the light cavalry away&quot;, the general discovered that the enemy was absconding and wanted to lead the light cavalry to pursue him; not only because the light cavalry was fast, but also showed a high degree of confidence. When the warriors lined up and prepared to set off, a heavy snow began to fall. Although they could not stand for a moment, the bows and knives were covered with snowflakes in an instant. The cold light that obscured their weapons. They are like arrows about to leave the string. Although they have not yet set off, they are full of confidence that they will win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last sentence, &quot;The bows and knives are covered with heavy snow&quot; is a description of the severe cold scene, which highlights the hardship of the battle and the brave spirit of the soldiers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although this poem only has twenty words, it describes the actual situation at that time: Chanyu led his army to flee under the scene of &quot;black moon and wild geese flying high&quot;, and the general was in &quot;heavy snow full of bows and swords&quot;. Prepare to lead the army to attack under extremely cold weather conditions. The escape and pursuit exaggerated the tense atmosphere. Although the poem does not directly describe a fierce battle scene, it leaves readers with a broad imagination and creates an atmosphere of long-lasting meaning in the poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; When the author wrote this poem, his life and career were extremely difficult. After the Zhusi Rebellion, King Hunyang of Xianning came out of Zhenhezhong and promoted Lu Lun to be the judge of the Marshal&#39;s Mansion. In the military camp, all Lu Lun saw were the majestic and solemn frontier fortress scenes, and all he came into contact with were rugged and heroic soldiers, so he composed this frontier fortress poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a poem about the guards chasing deserters at night. It is the third poem in Lu Lun&#39;s &quot;Song under the Sai&quot; group. head. This poem is only 20 words long, but it contains a lot of information and inspires readers&#39; endless imagination. The author did not directly describe the battle scene, but by reading the poem, one can completely understand the poetic meaning and enrich the imagination, and draw a picture of the war with both iron and steel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem begins with a description of the scene: &quot;The wild geese fly high in the dark moon.&quot; Such a scene is difficult to describe: if the moon is dark, nothing can be seen; if the geese are flying high, there is no trace to be found. The geese fly high. It is perceived by sound. This kind of scenery is not the scenery in the eyes, but the scenery in the mind. Snowy night and dark moon are not a normal time for wild geese to fly. Su Yan&#39;s frightened flight revealed that the enemy was taking action. These five words not only tell the time, but also heighten the tense atmosphere before the battle, directly forcing the next sentence &quot;Shan Yu escapes at night&quot;. Shanyu was originally the monarch of the ancient Xiongnu, here he refers to the commander-in-chief of the enemy army. There should be every possibility for the enemy to move at night. However, the poet said that &quot;Chan Yu fled at night&quot;. When I read the poem, I suddenly felt a sense of heroism coming over me. When the enemy moves at night, he does not lead his troops to attack, but flees in panic under the cover of night. The tone of the poem is affirmative, the judgment is clear, and it is full of contempt for the enemy and the belief that our army will win. It is enough to excite readers and make them startled in the mysterious atmosphere created by the previous sentence. When the enemy chief fled, our army sent troops to pursue him. This was a natural development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Three or four sentences describe the situation of our own army preparing to pursue, showing the mighty spirit of the soldiers. &quot;I want to chase the Qingqi away&quot; means that the pursuing troops are about to attack but have not yet done so. Not using a large army but only sending &quot;light cavalry&quot; was not only due to speed, but also showed a high degree of self-confidence, as if the enemy was already a turtle in the urn, and only a small number of &quot;light cavalry&quot; were needed to pursue and suppress it, and they could be captured easily. When the warriors lined up to set off. Although he could only stand for a moment. But the heavy snow actually covered the bow and knife. The sentence &quot;The heavy snow is full of bows and knives&quot; is full of surprise and excitement, pushing the artistic conception of the whole poem to a climax. In the vast darkness of night, on the pure white snow, a group of light cavalry was gathering. Snowflakes instantly covered their bodies, covering up the cold light of their weapons. They are like arrows about to leave the string. Although they have not yet set off, they are already full of confidence that they will win. This is a very moving picture: there is a cry in the silence, and there is lightning brewing in the darkness. Although it was a dark night, the heroic figures of the warriors outlined by the white snow were still &quot;eye-catching&quot;. Judging from this poem, Lu Lun is very good at capturing images and opportunities. He can not only capture typical images, but also express them at the most artistically effective moment. The poet does not describe how the army attacks, nor does he tell readers whether it has caught up with the enemy. He only describes a scene of preparations for pursuit, which effectively highlights the atmosphere and emotions at the time. &quot;If you want to drive away the light cavalry, the heavy snow will cover your bow and sword.&quot; This is not the climax of the battle, but the moment approaching the climax. This moment is like an arrow on the string, about to be fired, and it has the most attractive power. Although the results are not explained, it is more enlightening and can arouse readers&#39; imagination and imagination. This is called exhaustive words but endless meaning. The dragon&#39;s head but not its tail does not mean that it has no tail. The tail is looming in the clouds, which is more interesting and charming. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/lulun.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Lulun (739-799), whose courtesy name was Yunyan, was from Puzhou in Hezhong (now Yongji County, Shanxi). A poet of the Tang Dynasty, he was one of the ten talented men in Dali. In the last years of Emperor Xuanzong&#39;s Tianbao reign of the Tang Dynasty, he was promoted to Jinshi, but he failed in the chaos. In the Tang Dynasty, Zong Dynasty applied for the imperial examination again, but failed in repeated attempts. In the sixth year of Dali, he was recommended by Prime Minister Yuan Zai and was awarded the title of Lieutenant of Xiangxiang. Later, Prime Minister Wang Jin recommended him as Bachelor of Jixian, Secretary of the Provincial School, and promoted to Supervisory Censor. He was promoted to Hucao in Shaanzhou and magistrate of Mi County in Henan. Later, Yuan Zai and Wang Jin were convicted and implicated. During the Dezong Dynasty of Tang Dynasty, he was restored as the magistrate of Zhaoying County and served as the judge of Hunyang Mansion, Marshal in Hezhong. His official position was as a doctor in the household department of the school inspection department. Died soon. Author of &quot;Collection of Poems by Lu Hubu&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[将归旧山留别孟郊 | 鲍溶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239281]]><description> &lt;h2>;Returning to the old mountains and leaving Mengjiao behind&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Bao Rong&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;There is no sharp edge in choosing wood, and there is no skill in choosing fish. &lt;br />;How to underestimate your ability and end up in poverty. &lt;br />;The former is never tired of farming and never leaves his relatives for a day. &lt;br />;Now that I am thousands of miles away, my heart is not in my body. &lt;br />;You have a loving motherly heart, and you only wish that you can be like a human being. &lt;br />;How much sericulture can be done, clothes are always new. &lt;br />;How can anyone see such diligence when he spits out ruler wire after eating. &lt;br />;The other king went back to the plow and burned the wheels with fire. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;I want to chop wood but I don’t have an axe, I want to catch fish and shrimp but I don’t have a fishing net. Fishing gear. &lt;br />;Why am I so overestimating my abilities and asking for trouble and suffering the poverty on this journey? &lt;br />;It turns out that I am not tired of farming because I can enjoy the warmth of Mother Cheng Huan’s knees every day. &lt;br />;&amp;nbsp;Now that I am thousands of miles away, my heart is not here. &lt;br />;With my long and loving mother&#39;s heart, I just hope that everything goes as I wish for her to be healthy and well. &lt;br />;The silk produced by tiny silkworms is not much, but it allows us to change our clothes frequently. &lt;br />;Just like a silkworm who only needs a meal but spins out silk to benefit others. Who has ever seen a person in the world who does not ask for anything in return like a mother. &lt;br />;That’s all, I’d better say goodbye to my friends and go back to farming! Remove the wheels from the vehicles and use them as firewood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Lun: fishing thread. &lt;br />;Wei: only, only. &lt;br />;Wish: Pray, hope. &lt;br />;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/baorong.jpg &quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Bao Rong, courtesy name Deyuan, whose dates of birth and death are unknown and his place of origin is unknown, was a Jinshi scholar in the fourth year of Yuanhe and was an important poet in the mid-Tang Dynasty. Zhang Wei, a poet and poetry critic of the late Tang Dynasty, wrote &quot;Pictures of Poets&#39; Hosts and Guests&quot; and respected Bao Rong as &quot;the Master of Bo Jie Hong Ba&quot;. He is ranked with Bai Juyi, the &quot;Master of Guangdong Enlightenment&quot;, Meng Yunqing, &quot;Master of Gaogu Aoyi&quot;, Li Yi, &quot;Master of Qingqi Yazheng&quot;, Meng Jiao, &quot;Master of Qingqi, secluded and suffering&quot;, and Wu Yuanheng, &quot;Master of Wonderful Beauty&quot;. One of the &quot;Six Lords&quot;. Ouyang Xiu, Zeng Gong and others in the Song Dynasty also appreciated his poetry. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>