<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[雨夜读书 | 陆游]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231042]]><description> &lt;h2>;Reading on a rainy night&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Lu You&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;A lamp is like a gurgling firefly, and the old man is reading in the room. &lt;br />;But when we meet the ancients face to face, we hate the beauty withered in the mirror. &lt;br />;Fame and fame are our own business, so why waste others’ money on others? &lt;br />;When you see a doctor, you are so thin that you are exposed, and you don’t think about fighting, but you think about Tianshan. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;A lamp is like a bean inside the curtain, the sound of rain is pattering, and I am reading in the tent room . &lt;br />;Immersed in the book, I met the ancients, looked at myself in the mirror, and saw that my face was aging, but I regretted that I had not achieved fame. &lt;br />;Fame is originally the pursuit of people like me, but life is full of frustrations. Why is God so stingy to me? &lt;br />;Although he is like a sickly and thin Qiji, he does not want to serve in court, but wants to make contributions to the Tianshan frontier fortress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Gurgling: describes the sound of rain. &lt;br />;Being frustrated: a metaphor for being frustrated. &lt;br />;Xing: stingy. &lt;br />;Zhaoxia: To refer to the court. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/luyou.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Lu You (November 13, 1125 - January 26, 1210), with the courtesy name Wuguan and the nickname Fangweng, Han nationality, was from Shanyin, Yuezhou (now Shaoxing, Zhejiang), Shangshu Right The grandson of Cheng Lu Dian, a writer, historian and patriotic poet of the Southern Song Dynasty. Lu You was born when the Northern Song Dynasty was overthrown, and he was deeply influenced by his family&#39;s patriotism when he was young. During the reign of Emperor Gaozong of the Song Dynasty, he participated in the examination of the Ministry of Rites, but his official career was not smooth because he was rejected by Qin Hui, the prime minister. During the reign of Emperor Xiaozong, he was granted a Jinshi background. He entered Shu in middle age and devoted himself to military life. In the second year of Jiatai (1202), Emperor Ningzong of the Song Dynasty ordered Lu You to come to Beijing and preside over the compilation of Xiaozong&#39;s and Guangzong&#39;s &quot;Records of the Two Dynasties&quot; and &quot;History of the Three Dynasties&quot;. In his later years, he retired to his hometown. There are more than 9,000 poems in existence today, and they are extremely rich in content. He is the author of &quot;Jiannan Poetry Manuscript&quot;, &quot;Weinan Collected Works&quot;, &quot;Southern Tang Book&quot;, &quot;Laoxue&#39;an Notes&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 07:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长信怨 | 王昌龄]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231041]]><description> &lt;h2>;Chang Xin Yuan&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Wang Changling&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The leaves of Jinjing sycamore are yellow in autumn, and the bead curtains are not rolled up by the night frost. &lt;br />;The jade pillow in the fumigated cage has no color. I lie down and listen to Nangong Qing&#39;s long leakage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The autumn anvil in the high hall rings late at night, and the deep frost still reminds me of the cold clothes. &lt;br />;The silver lantern Qingsuo tailor rested and looked at the Mingzhu of Jincheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The golden palace is opened in the Ming Dynasty. For the time being, the fans will be hanging around together. &lt;br />;The jade color is not as beautiful as the color of a jackdaw, but still carries the shadow of the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been thinking about it for a long time, but I dreamed that the king was suspicious. &lt;br />;The fire shines in the West Palace and you know when you drink at night, you can clearly see the time of restoration and grace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The moon is bright in the Mid-Autumn Festival in Changxin Palace, and the sound of His Royal Highness Zhaoyang&#39;s clothes is pounding. &lt;br />;There are traces of grass in the white dew hall, and there is overwhelming emotion in the red tent. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The autumn leaves of the phoenix tree beside the golden well are gradually turning yellow, and it can be seen that the bead curtain is not rolled up Frost at night. &lt;br />;The jade pillow in a smoked cage is like a haggard face, lying quietly and worrying, listening to the long leaking sound of Nangong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In autumn, the sound of pounding clothes in the high palace resounds through the night, and the heavy frost at night still reminds me of the cold clothes of the emperor. &lt;br />;It was even quieter before he stopped tailoring under the silver lamp, and his eyes turned to Miyagi Akira. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn, I would pick up a broom to sweep the dust from the Golden Palace. When I was bored, we would wander around together holding a fan. &lt;br />;The beautiful face is not as good as the appearance of a crow, which can also fly with the shadow of the sun in Zhaoyang Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As expected, he became a miserable man and fell into deep thought for a long time. He saw the king again in his dream and felt suspicious when he woke up. &lt;br />;The lights in the west palace were shining brightly, and I knew it was during the night when I was drinking, and the time when I was restored to grace and favor appeared clearly before my eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only the autumn moon was still bright in Changxin Palace, and the sound of His Highness Zhaoyang&#39;s clothes being pounded could be heard. &lt;br />;The Bailu Hall is full of traces of weeds, and the red tent over there is full of affection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Chang Xinqiu Ci: Also known as &quot;Chang Xin Qiu&quot;, &quot;Hanshu Biography&quot; records that Ban Jieyu entered the palace with her talents and learning, and became the Zhao Feiyan was jealous and asked to support the Queen Mother in Changxin Palace. This is where the phrase &quot;Long Faith and Resentment&quot; comes from. Changxin: the name of Han Palace. &lt;br />;Golden Well: A well with carved decorations on the well railing. Generally used to refer to wells in palace gardens. One of the poems &quot;Traveling is Difficult&quot; written by Liang Feichang of the Southern Dynasty: &quot;I only heard that there are crows in the dumb city, and the jade railings and golden wells lead the windlass.&quot;&lt;br />;Pearl curtain: a curtain made of or decorated with pearls. Volume 2 of &quot;Miscellaneous Notes of Xijing&quot;: &quot;Beads are woven into the curtains of the Zhaoyang Palace, and when the wind blows, they ring, like the sound of a pendant.&quot; The cage is used for incense or drying. Xun: One word is &quot;gold&quot;. Cage: one is &quot;furnace&quot;. Jade pillow: that is, pillow. &lt;br />;Nangong: refers to the residence of the emperor. One is &quot;In the Palace&quot;. Clear drain: The drain is an ancient timekeeping instrument that uses dripping water and scales to indicate the time. Qinglei refers to the sound of a copper pot dripping late at night. Bao Zhao of the Southern Song Dynasty wrote a poem &quot;Looking at the Solitary Stone&quot;: &quot;The whistle and song are clear and the leakage is over, and the lingering view of the morning is over.&quot;&lt;br />;Autumn anvil (zhēn): the sound of pounding clothes in autumn. Yu Xin of the Northern Zhou Dynasty wrote a poem &quot;Listening to the Beating of Clothes at Night&quot;: &quot;The autumn anvil adjusts the rhythm, and the chaotic pestle becomes a new sound.&quot; Ye Lan: the end of the night; the night is about to end. Cai Yan of the Han Dynasty&#39;s &quot;Eighteen Beats of Hujia&quot;: &quot;The mountains are high and wide, and I have no chance to see you; even late at night, I dream of you.&quot;&lt;br />;Royal clothes: clothes made by the emperor. Li Qiao of the Tang Dynasty wrote a poem titled &quot;Spring Day in the Garden with Joyful Rain in Response to the Imperial Order&quot;: &quot;The dense rain welcomes the steps of the immortals, and the low rain ruffles the imperial clothes.&quot;&lt;br />;Qingsuo: A green interlocking pattern that decorates the doors and windows of the palace. &quot;Book of Han·Biography of the Empress of the Yuan Dynasty&quot;: &quot;The Hougen of Quyang was arrogant and extravagant, and his red hair was green and trivial.&quot;&lt;br />;Jincheng: the city where the emperor lived. Mingzhu: A wise monarch. &quot;Zuo Zhuan·The 29th Year of Duke Xiang&quot;: &quot;How beautiful it is! It&#39;s big and graceful, dangerous but easy to do. If you supplement it with virtue, you will know the master.&quot;&lt;br />;Feng broom: holding a broom to sweep. Many concubines fall out of favor and are left out in the cold. Pingming: refers to dawn. Golden Palace: refers to the palace. One is &quot;Autumn Palace&quot;. &lt;br />;Uanfan: a round fan. Ban Jieyu once wrote &quot;Poetry on a Round Fan&quot;. Temporary: One is &quot;and&quot;. Total: One is &quot;temporary&quot;. &lt;br />;Jade face: refers to a face as beautiful as jade, which here alludes to Ban Jieyu herself. Jackdaw: A cold crow; a cold crow. Alluding to the Zhao Feiyan sisters who are secretive and cruel. &lt;br />;Zhaoyang: The name of the palace in the Han Dynasty, referring to the place where the sisters Zhao Feiyan and Emperor Cheng of the Han Dynasty lived. &lt;br />;Bad fate: bad luck; bad luck. &quot;The Book of Han·Xiaochengxu·Queen Xiaochengxu&quot;: &quot;I am not lucky, but I would rather live in front of you.&quot; Xunsi: think; consider. Bai Juyi of the Tang Dynasty wrote a poem called &quot;Nanchi in Early Spring,&quot; a poem: &quot;I leaned on the wooden raft and suddenly thought about the company I had on the pool last year.&quot;&lt;br />;West Palace: The place where the emperor had banquets. &lt;br />;Complex Road: The passage between the two-story attic. &quot;Mozi·Hao Ling&quot;: &quot;There are three complexes guarding the palace. The outer ring is the tower, the inner ring is the tower, and the tower is five feet into Bao Palace, which is the compound road.&quot;&lt;br />;Zhaoyang Palace: refers to the Zhao Feiyan sisters and The palace where Emperor Cheng of the Han Dynasty lived. &lt;br />;Bailutang: refers to the place where a disgraced concubine or palace maid lives. &lt;br />;Hongluo: red light soft silk fabric. &quot;The Book of Han · Biography of the Wife · Xiaocheng Banzedan&quot;: &quot;The curtains are red and the ruffles are red, and the silk curtains are colorful and plain.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;First one&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem of palace resentment uses deep and subtle writing methods and adopts the technique of using scenery to express feelings, writing about a person who was deprived of youth, freedom and happiness. A scene of a young girl lying alone in a desolate and lonely palace, listening to uterine leakage. This is a sleepless night cut from the girl&#39;s tragic life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this sleepless night, the person in the poem is full of worries and knots of sorrow. She should be filled with endless resentment. There are only four lines in this poem, with a total of twenty-eight words. It can be said that even if every word is filled with resentment, I am afraid it still cannot express her resentment. However, the author did not hesitate to use the first three sentences to describe the scenery, leaving only the last sentence to describe the characters, and there was no explicit expression of resentment in this last sentence. Written in this way, at first glance it seems that it has strayed away from the theme of the poem, but in fact it is more powerful in terms of artistic effect and expresses the theme more profoundly. This is because: although the first three sentences describe the scene, they do not describe the scene for the sake of describing the scene. They serve the appearance of the final character. As far as the whole poem is concerned, the four lines of the poem are integrated into a whole. Regardless of the description of the scene or the person, they all serve to express resentment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Part Two&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second poem describes the tragic scene of the lonely woman in the palace in the desolate environment of late night and heavy frost. She couldn&#39;t sleep all night, thinking about the days since entering the palace that she couldn&#39;t bear to look back on. She longed for the king&#39;s favor and stayed under the silver lamp until late at night, but ended up disappointed. This poem is more direct in its emotional expression and more vivid in its psychological portrayal, fully expressing the resentment of the disgraced woman in the palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is an article &quot;Song of Resentment&quot; in the ancient Yuefu poems. The words are: &quot;The newly cracked Qi Wansu is as bright as frost and snow. It is cut into an acacia fan, and the clusters are like the bright moon. When you go in and out of your arms, The breeze is shaking. I am always afraid that the autumn festival is coming, and the coolness will overtake the heat. Abandon the donation basket, and the kindness will be cut off.&quot; This poem is said to have been written by Ban Jieyu, using the abandonment of the autumn fan as a metaphor for the interruption of the king&#39;s kindness. Wang Changling exaggerated the moral of &quot;Song of Resentment&quot; and used the story of &quot;Long Letter&quot; to reflect the life of court women in the Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It was late at night and the frost was heavy, and the sound of wood and stone hitting the autumn anvil resounded through the cold night. In such a lonely night, the disgraced woman in the palace still worried about whether the monarch had added more clothes. Under the dim silver lamp, she cut and mended alone, knowing that the monarch would not favor her, but she still cherished a deep feeling in her heart. look forward to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This poem is famous for its profound psychological description and direct lyricism. In just a few words, a woman who has fallen out of favor in the palace longs for the monarch&#39;s favor, cares about the monarch&#39;s warmth and warmth, and is mixed with her disregard for the monarch&#39;s abandonment of herself. The wishful thinking turns a blind eye to the resentment and pain. It vividly expresses the unspeakable resentment of a woman who has fallen out of favor in the palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Third&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the first two sentences of the third poem, it is said that the sky is dawning and the Golden Palace has been opened, so he picks up the broom and starts cleaning. It is a daily routine of work and life; after cleaning, there is nothing else to do, just holding a fan in hand and wandering together, which is a moment of leisure and contemplation. Wandering refers to the uncertainty of mood, and fanning means the sadness of falling out of favor. Saying &quot;Qiejiang&quot; shows loneliness and boredom. Only the fan in the sleeve has the same fate, and we can just wander around and share it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last two sentences further use a clever metaphor to express the grievances of the palace maid, still following the story of Ban Jieyu. Zhaoyang, Han Palace, is where Sister Zhao Feiyan lives. It was autumn, so the crow was called jackdaw. In ancient times, the sun was used as a metaphor for the emperor, so the shadow of the sun refers to the king&#39;s kindness. Jackdaws can fly over the Zhaoyang Palace, so they still have the shadow of Zhaoyang&#39;s sun on their bodies. However, they live deep in Changxin and the king never pays attention to them. Although they have a face as white as jade, they are not as good as the old crows who are all black. . What she resents is that she is not only inferior to other people of the same kind, but also inferior to an alien creature - a small, ugly crow. According to the general situation, &quot;personification must be based on its ethics&quot;, that is, the beautiful is compared with the beautiful, and the ugly is compared with the ugly. However, the whiteness of the jade face and the blackness of the crow&#39;s feathers are extremely different; not only are they not similar, but they are opposite. Comparison enhances the expression effect. Because if they are both jade-faced, even though they are slightly superior to each other, they may not be very different. Then, her resentment and unwillingness will not be so profound. The upper word is &quot;less than&quot;, and the lower word is &quot;yue&quot;. ”, expressing what is actually a very deep resentment in a euphemistic and implicit way. All these make this poem a masterpiece of palace resentment poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Fourth&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It also expresses the resentment of disgraced concubines and expresses their deep inner pain. In Wang Changling&#39;s works, there are few artistic similarities. repeat. The fourth poem has more direct lyricism and detailed psychological characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first sentence goes straight to the point, describing the inner activities of the disgraced concubine. &quot;What a bad fate&quot; means that he unexpectedly turned out to be a disgraced person with an unfortunate fate. This beginning seems a bit abrupt, making people feel that there are many omissions. It seems that she was the favored one not long ago. However, whether a concubine is favored or not often depends on the monarch&#39;s temporary likes and dislikes, or purely by chance. Therefore, these concubines who have no control over their own destiny especially believe in fate. If you gain favor, you will be lucky; if you lose favor, you will have bad luck. And even when he is favored, he always lives in fear, fearing that the bad luck of falling out of favor will suddenly befall him. The four words &quot;truly a miserable life&quot; are just like a heavy sigh deep in the heart of this disgraced palace concubine. She is always worried about bad luck, but when the bad luck finally befalls her, it is both unbelievable and painful. The complex psychology of admission was revealed. This kind of psychological portrayal is very inclusive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the fate of falling out of favor came, she fell into long thought. Entering the &quot;dream&quot; due to &quot;thinking&quot;, the dream relives the joy of the past, expresses the hope for destiny, the fantasy of the monarch, and reweaves the phantom of being favored in one&#39;s own heart. But after all, dreams cannot replace reality. When I wake up, what I see in front of me is still the lonely Changxin Palace, the autumn leaves of sycamore trees, the bead curtains with night frost, and what I hear is still the long and desolate sound of the copper pot leaking. Then I had to suspect that my lucky hope was just an unrealizable dream. The above two sentences depict the heroine&#39;s tortuous and complex psychology in a meticulous and layered way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the moment when this disgraced person was wandering from thoughts to dreams, from dreams to doubts, and was suffering from mental pain, a brightly lit scene appeared to her not far away from the West Palace. Needless to say, at this moment, the West Palace was having an all-night banquet, reenacting the scene of &quot;Pingyang Singing and Dancing for New Favorites&quot;. This scene was so familiar to her that it suddenly evoked the memory of her &quot;new favor&quot;, as if she had returned to the days when she was favored by the monarch in Fudao. But all this has become so far away at this moment. Although the scene of Cheng Chong is repeated, the gorgeous Nishi Palace has changed to a new owner. The word &quot;Mingming&quot; has a lot of meaning and is very interesting. It contains the vivid memories and infinite pursuit of the past in the loneliness and desolation of the disgraced person. It also contains the deep emotion and infinite regret that the past cannot be restored. It also reveals the profound sadness that cannot be looked back on the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Part 5&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a poem expressing palace resentment. Zhaoyang Palace is the palace where Zhao Feiyan lived when he was favored in the Western Han Dynasty. Later, Zhaoyang Palace was used to refer to the favored concubines. Changxin Palace was the palace where Ban Jieyu, the concubine who fell out of favor when Zhao Feiyan was favored, lived. Later, it generally referred to the concubine who fell out of favor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last two sentences use contrast to describe the completely different gap between falling out of favor and gaining favor. The thin traces of grass in the Bailu Hall refer to the coldness, overgrown weeds, and desolation of the palace of the concubine who fell out of favor, which makes the characters look very Resentment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The overwhelming feeling in the red tent refers to the favored concubine who hangs a red tent in the palace and talks softly to the king, feeling very comfortable and endlessly affectionate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From a female perspective, Wang Changling used contrast to vividly depict the world of difference between a concubine who fell out of favor and a concubine who gained favor, which is a rare subject in palace resentment poems. My deepest sympathy to those concubines. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Due to inconsistent records of Wang Changling’s place of origin, year of birth and death, and other important life events, most of his works cannot be dated. , it is difficult to know exactly when the &quot;Five Poems of Changxin Autumn&quot; was written. In the fifteenth year of Kaiyuan (727), he became a Jinshi in his thirties. Was demoted twice. This group of five poems was probably written during the reign of Tianbao (reign of Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, 742-756), before he was demoted for the second time. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wangchangling.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Wang Changling (698-756), courtesy name Shaobo, was born in Jinyang, Hedong (now Taiyuan, Shanxi). A famous frontier poet in the prosperous Tang Dynasty, he was known as the &quot;Seven Masters&quot; by later generations. In his early years, he was poor and humble, trapped in farming, but in the third year of his life, he became a Jinshi. He first served as secretary of the Provincial School, and became a scholar and scholar. He was awarded the rank of Sishui Lieutenant. He was demoted to Lingnan due to some affairs. He had close friendships with Li Bai, Gao Shi, Wang Wei, Wang Zhihuan, Cen Shen, etc. At the end of Kaiyuan, he returned to Chang&#39;an and was granted the title of Jiang Ningcheng. He was slandered and relegated to Long Biaowei. An Shi rebellion broke out and he was killed by Lu Qiu Xiao, the governor. His poems are famous for his seven unique poems, especially the frontier fortress poems he wrote when he went to the northwest frontier fortress before he ascended the imperial throne. He is known as &quot;Wang Jiangning, the poet&#39;s master&quot; (there is also the saying of &quot;Wang Jiangning, the poet&#39;s emperor&quot;). &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 04:23:10 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>