<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[善哉行·伤古曲无知音 | 贯休]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310152]]><description> &lt;h2>;Shan Zaixing·Sad to Ancient Songs and No Sound&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Guan Xiu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;There is a beautiful person, graceful as green. Recognize the music and distinguish the sounds, making the posture brilliant. &lt;br />;Embroidered sleeves and holding the harp, I ascend to the gentleman&#39;s hall. Like the day lily, it makes me forget. &lt;br />;I would like to give him a purple jade ruler and a silver pan. Long time no see, the Xiang River is vast. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;① Qingyang: refers to the beauty of a woman’s eyebrows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;②Sentimental, attached to appearance. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/guanxiu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Guan Xiu (832-912), whose common surname was Jiang and whose courtesy name was Deyin, was from Lanxi, Wuzhou (now Yangtiantian, Youbu Town, Lanxi City, Zhejiang Province). He was a painting monk and poet monk in the former Shu during the late Tang Dynasty and the Five Dynasties. He became a monk at the age of seven and became a monk in He&#39;an Temple. He read thousands of words of scriptures every day and had a photographic memory. Tang Tianfujian entered Shu and was named &quot;Master Zenyue&quot; by the former lord of Shu, Wang Jian, and was given purple clothes. Guanxiu is good at poetry, and his poetry is famous for its high verses, which Yu Neixian knows well. There is a saying that goes: &quot;If you grow old with a bottle and a bowl, you can get it from thousands of rivers and mountains.&quot; At that time, he was called &quot;Monk Dede&quot;. There is &quot;Zenyueji&quot; in existence. He is also good at painting, especially the Arhats whose appearance is ancient and unconventional, with strong brushwork. The characters have thick eyebrows, big eyes, plump cheeks and high noses, and the image is exaggerated, so-called &quot;Sanskrit appearance&quot;. In the history of Chinese painting, it has a high reputation. The surviving &quot;Sixteen Arhats&quot; is his representative work. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:23:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[点绛唇·访牟存叟南漪钓隐 | 周晋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310151]]><description> &lt;h2>;Dian Jiangchun·Visiting Mou Cunsuo Nanyi Diaoyin&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Zhou Jin&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;After returning from the noon dream for the first time, the curtains are rolled up to let away the sorrow of spring. The day is long and there is no companion, so I talk to the oriole. &lt;br />;There are shadows and fragrant apples, spring is everywhere. Move the boat. Before a new sentence is formed, a pear blossom rains. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Wake up from a dream in the afternoon, roll up the curtains and fill the room with spring sorrow Disperse. The days are long, there is no one to keep company, and it is very boring. I can only speak to the oriole in the tree alone. &lt;br />;Catkins are flying in the air, and the fragrance of apples is faintly heard. The spring that cannot be found is here! Taking a small boat to visit old friends, the two of them were contemplating ideas under the pear tree. A drizzle of rain knocked down the pear blossoms and covered the inkstone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Inkstone: Inkstone. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;When I first return to my noon dream, the rolling curtain lets go of the spring sorrow.&quot; The spring weather makes people sleepy, and the poet fell into a drunken dream in the afternoon. , after waking up, I felt that the room was unusually quiet, and the air seemed to be stagnant. This kind of environment makes people depressed. So the poet opened the curtains, and the bright sunshine and fresh air poured into the room, making him feel relaxed. &quot;The rolling curtain lets go of the sorrow of spring.&quot; Spring sorrow is an invisible thing. When the curtain is rolled up, it is let out like a bird. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This sentence is very distinctive, and the author successfully gives abstract things a vivid feeling. &quot;The day is long and there is no companion, so I say to the oriole.&quot; The lonely poet can only talk to the oriole, but he writes about his lonely mood in a leisurely and interesting way. It is annoying that the spring scenery is getting better at the beginning of the day. In the long day, the poet has no poets or wine lovers, and he feels extremely bored. It&#39;s really strange to think that the oriole can talk to you. This highlights the loneliness of being without a partner, and also reflects the stillness of leisure and sorrow. The so-called &quot;letting go of spring sorrow&quot; actually does not let go. The beauty of the words lies in their subtlety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the spring sorrow is difficult to deal with, and because there is no one to talk to, the poet moved a boat to visit friends, and it was a natural transition to Xiaqing. &quot;The shadows and apples are fragrant, spring is everywhere.&quot; The poet has left the room and merged into the embrace of nature. In late spring, catkins are flying, and the scenery is extremely beautiful under the sunlight. The place with floating shadows and the fragrance of apples is naturally full of spring. I looked for spring but didn&#39;t see it, but it turned out that spring was here. The poet was filled with joy. At this point, the endless spring sorrow was truly released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Moving the boat. Before I could write a new sentence, there was a rain of pear blossoms.&quot; The end of the poem was a visit to Yi&#39;s Garden. &quot;Move the boat&quot; is written leisurely and gracefully. The poet only captured one scene in the garden - a big pear tree next to the Shuoguoxuan; he only wrote about one elegant thing - a poem under the tree. Just as he and the owner of the garden were contemplating the idea, but before the poem could be completed, it suddenly started raining. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/zhoujin.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Zhou Jin (date of birth and death unknown), named Mingshu and named Xiaozhai, was originally from Jinan (now Shandong) and lived in Wuxing (now Huzhou, Zhejiang) since his ancestors. In the fourth year of Jin Dynasty in Shaoding (1231), he was an official of Fuyang Order. At the end of Jiaxi and the beginning of Chunyou, he was an official of Fujian Transport Envoy. He was imprisoned repeatedly in Quzhou and sentenced to Keshan. In the third year of Baoyou&#39;s reign (1255), he knew Tingzhou. Jin Fu collected books and Gongci. Most of the lyrics are lost. The third volume of &quot;Exquisite Good Ci&quot; contains three of his poems, namely &quot;Dian Crimson Lips&quot;, &quot;Qing Ping Le&quot;, and &quot;Willow Shao Qing&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 04:23:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>