<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[子衿 | 诗经·国风·郑风]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239141]]><description> &lt;h2>;Zi Jin&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] The Book of Songs·Guo Feng·Zheng Feng&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The green Zi Jin is in my heart. Even if I don&#39;t go, will Zi Ning have no heir? &lt;br />;The green zipai makes me think about it for a long time. Even if I don&#39;t go, Zi Ning won&#39;t come? &lt;br />;It is difficult to find a way to reach the city. Not seeing each other for one day is like three months! &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The green color is your collar, the leisurely color is my state of mind . Even though I never came to see you, wouldn&#39;t you send me a message? &lt;br />;The green ones are what you wear, the long ones are my feelings. Even if I never go to see you, can&#39;t you come to me? &lt;br />;Walking around and looking around, on this high observation tower. A day without seeing you seems like a few months! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Zi Jin: The clothing of scholars in the Zhou Dynasty. Zi, a good name for a man, here refers to &quot;you&quot;. Jin, the handover of clothes. &lt;br />;Yuyou: She looks constantly worried. &lt;br />;Ning (nìng): Qi, could it be? &lt;br />;Si (sì) sound: keep the message. Si: continue, continue. &lt;br />;Pei: This refers to the ribbon that holds the jade. &lt;br />;Tiāo (pronounced tāo) Xi Da (tà) Xi: The appearance of wandering alone. Pick, also known as &quot;佻&quot;. &lt;br />;Chengque: the viewing towers on both sides of the city gate. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Guofeng·Zheng Feng·Zijin&quot; is a poem in the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;, the first poetry collection in ancient China. The poem has three chapters, each chapter has four lines. This poem is about unrequited love, describing a woman missing her sweetheart. Whenever a woman sees something green, she will think of her sweetheart’s green collar and green jade. So she climbed onto the city gate tower just to see her sweetheart. If she can&#39;t see her for one day, she will feel like it&#39;s been three months. The whole poem uses the technique of flashback to fully describe the psychological activities of a woman&#39;s unrequited love. It is lifelike and has a beautiful artistic conception. It is a rare and beautiful love song and has become a classic work describing lovesickness in the history of Chinese literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem consists of three chapters, using flashback technique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two chapters use the tone of &quot;I&quot; to describe my love for others. &quot;Qing Qing Zi Jin&quot; and &quot;Qing Qing Zi Pei&quot; refer to the lover&#39;s clothes and ornaments. The other person&#39;s clothes left such a deep impression on her that she couldn&#39;t forget them. You can imagine how much she missed him. Now I am unable to go to the appointment due to obstacles, so I have to wait for my lover to come over to meet me, but there is no trace of her through the autumn water. The deep love cannot help but turn into melancholy and resentment: &quot;Even if I didn&#39;t go to you, why can&#39;t you send me a message? Even if I didn’t go looking for you, why couldn’t you take the initiative to come?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third chapter points out the location and writes that she was upset on the tower because her lover who had been waiting for a long time did not come, and went back and forth. As we walked non-stop, I felt that although we hadn&#39;t seen each other for only one day, it seemed like three months of separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whole poem is less than 50 words long, but the heroine&#39;s anxious state of waiting for her lover seems to be present. The achievement of this artistic effect lies in the poet&#39;s use of a large amount of psychological description in his creation. In the poem, only the words &quot;pick&quot; and &quot;da&quot; are used to express the woman&#39;s actions, and the main words are used to describe her psychological activities, such as the complaints about her lover who has no information and has disappeared in the first two chapters. , the monologue at the end of the chapter &quot;One day is like three months without seeing each other&quot;. The two paragraphs of complaints are contrasted with &quot;Longme&quot; and &quot;Zi Ning&quot;. There is a reserved attitude in the eagerness, which makes people have unlimited imagination. It can be said that there are few words but many meanings. The inner monologue at the end uses exaggerated rhetorical techniques to create a contrast between subjective time and objective time, thereby vividly expressing its strong emotional psychology. It can be said that it is amazing because of the exaggeration and embellishment. The technique of psychological description has been fully developed in the literary world of later generations, and tracing back to its origin, this poem has pioneered it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem is one of the more representative works of love poetry in the Book of Songs. It clearly embodies the independent, independent, and equal ideas and spiritual essence of women of that era. , the heroine boldly expresses her emotions in the poem, that is, her longing for her lover. This is rare in the literary works of the past dynasties after the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; Regarding the background of this poem, modern scholars generally believe that it is a love song. The singer was passionately in love with a young man. They made an appointment to meet at the city gate, but after a long wait, the singer couldn&#39;t wait. He walked back and forth anxiously, complaining that his lover didn&#39;t come to the appointment, and even blamed him for not sending a letter. So he sang this poem to express his gratitude to his lover. Emotions. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[登柳州城楼寄漳汀封连四州 | 柳宗元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239131]]><description> &lt;h2>;Climb the Liuzhou city tower and send it to Zhangting to seal the four states&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Liu Zongyuan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The tall buildings on the city are connected to the wilderness, and the sea and the sky are full of sorrow and thoughts. &lt;br />;The trembling wind stirred up the hibiscus water, and the dense rain slanted into the vast wall. &lt;br />;The trees on the ridge cover thousands of miles of sight, and the river flows like nine ileum. &lt;br />;We came to Baiyue Tattoo Place together, but our music and writings were still stagnant in the same hometown. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Ascending the high-rise building, what you can see is a desolate and deserted desert, such as A sea of ​​sadness arises spontaneously. &lt;br />;The strong wind stirred up the lotus flowers randomly in the water, and the heavy rain hit the wall covered with grass. &lt;br />;The cascading distant mountains obscure the distant view, and the winding Liujiang River is like my knotted heart. &lt;br />;We came to this remote and wild land together. How could it be that we were cut off from music and music, and everyone was separated from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Liuzhou: Today it belongs to Guangxi. &lt;br />;Zhangzhou and Tingzhou: today belong to Fujian. &lt;br />;Fengzhou and Lianzhou: Today they belong to Guangdong. &lt;br />;Provincial governor: The chief executive of a state, equivalent to the prefect in later generations. &lt;br />;Connect: connect. As soon as you say it, you can see it with your eyes. &lt;br />;Dahuang: generally refers to remote and remote areas. &lt;br />;Haitian&#39;s sorrow: The sorrow is like the sea and the sky. &lt;br />;Jingfeng: strong wind; strong wind. &lt;br />;Luansha (zhǎn): blowing. &lt;br />;Hibiscus: refers to lotus. &lt;br />;Xu Mang: a creeping plant, also called magnolia. Heavy masking: masking layer by layer. &lt;br />;Thousand Mile Eyes: This refers to the distant sight. &lt;br />;Jiang: refers to Liujiang River. &lt;br />;Nine ileum: Nine turns of sorrow, describing the tangled and intractable melancholy. &lt;br />;Gonglai: refers to being demoted to a distant place at the same time as Han Tai, Han Ye, Chen Jian, and Liu Yuxi. Baiyue: Baiyue refers to the ethnic minority areas south of Wuling at that time. &lt;br />;Tattoo: In ancient times, southern ethnic minorities had the custom of tattooing patterns on their bodies. Wen: Tong &quot;wen&quot;, used as a verb. &lt;br />;Yu Zi: Still. &lt;br />;Message: message. &lt;br />;Stagnation: obstruction. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This lyric poem has comparisons in the verses, excitement in the images, and a blend of scenes, which is sad and moving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First write one or two sentences about what you see and feel when you climb the stairs. The word &quot;high&quot; in &quot;high buildings on the city&quot; shows the poet&#39;s eagerness to climb up the tower to see his friends as soon as he arrived in Liuzhou. The higher you stand, the farther you can see, which shows how deeply you think. Because the five of them were persecuted together, their fates were closely related, and their friendship was sincere. Although they were far apart, they couldn&#39;t help but miss each other. &quot;Jie Dahuang&quot; writes about what he saw, saying that Liuzhou City is surrounded by desolate and remote places, and writes about the hardships of their exile. As far as the eye can see, the sea and the sky meet in a vast expanse. On the one hand, it is written that the places that the four of them derogated were all close to the sea. On the other hand, it also implies that their &quot;sorrows&quot; are as endless as the &quot;sea and sky&quot;. This is a way of writing from reality to virtuality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three or four sentences &quot;The trembling wind disturbed the hibiscus water, and the dense rain slanted into the vast wall&quot; are written about what was seen close up. But it is a close-up view, so it can be seen clearly, so it is written in detail. In terms of describing the scene of violent wind and rain, this is a &quot;Fu&quot; pen, and Fu also contains Bixing. There is a saying in Qu Yuan&#39;s &quot;Li Sao&quot;: &quot;I made lotus flowers to make clothes, and gathered hibiscus to make clothes. I didn&#39;t know that they were already gone, but I still love them and believe in their fragrance.&quot; It also said: &quot;Gather the roots of the wood to make tadpoles, and they will fall through the vast expanse of grass. The pistil; the fungus and the osmanthus are used to embroider the hui, and the rope is tied to the genggen. I practice it in front of my Dharma, which is not subject to the world.&quot; Here, hibiscus and Xiumang symbolize the beauty and purity of personality. Climbing the tower and looking nearby, I picked out Hibiscus and Ximang from among the people I saw. It was obviously their situation in the storm that made the poet&#39;s soul tremble. The wind is called shock, the rain is called dense, the roar is called chaos, and the invasion is called slanting, which shows that the poet&#39;s feelings are projected on objective things. When the hibiscus comes out of the water, why is it hindered by the wind, but the sudden wind will still blow randomly; the thick grass covers the wall, and the rain is difficult to invade, but the dense rain will invade diagonally. This can&#39;t help but make the poet think and feel sad. Here, the emotion in the scenery, the meaning in the environment, and the excitement in the poem are like salt in the water, leaving no trace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Write five or six sentences about the vision. It is also &quot;Fu&quot; and has both &quot;Bi&quot; and &quot;Xing&quot;. Take a look at the endless mountains and forests. This is a realistic representation of the scenery in the southwest. Doesn’t it also symbolize the layers of siege and imprisonment by stubborn forces? Doesn&#39;t the meandering flow of the river also remind us of the twists and turns of the author&#39;s life and future? Sima Qian of the Han Dynasty said in his &quot;Report to Ren An&quot; that after being tortured, his &quot;intestines returned nine times a day&quot;, describing his extremely depressed mood; Wang Zhihuan of the Tang Dynasty&#39;s &quot;Ascending the Stork Tower&quot; expressed a feeling of &quot;wanting to see a thousand miles away and reach a higher level&quot;. Heroic spirit. This poem is more developed. Although the mountains are covered with trees, he can still overcome obstacles because he can see far away from a high place. He can look thousands of miles away and his sight is not blocked. The answer can be obtained from the description of looking at the Jiuzhui River from a distance in the next sentence. Despite the twists and turns of the river, the river is still rushing forward. This can be seen from the word &quot;liu&quot;. Therefore, the two sentences reflect that the author has encountered many obstacles and setbacks, but still has the indomitable will to break through the cage. The exquisite duality is both melancholy and bold, and the artistic conception is far-reaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last two sentences come from the previous couplet. In addition to expressing the melancholy of caring about the situation of friends and turning a blind eye, they also have a deeper meaning: turning a blind eye naturally leads to the thought of mutual visits or exchange of messages; When looking at the land route, the mountains overlap, and when looking at the water route, the rivers flow meanderingly. Not to mention that it is not easy to visit each other, even exchanging messages is also very difficult. This naturally comes down to the fact that &quot;music and books are stagnant in one village&quot;. However, it ends like this, with a shallow and direct style. The author’s brilliance. Because he first used &quot;Come to a hundred Guangdong tattoo places&quot; as a pad, and then used &quot;Yu Zi&quot; to conclude that &quot;music and writing are stagnant in a hometown&quot;, he received a melancholy artistic effect. The sentence &quot;Gonglai&quot; not only corresponds to the &quot;Dahuang&quot; in the first sentence, but also unites the &quot;Liuzhou&quot; and &quot;Zhang, Ting, Feng, and Lianzhou&quot; in the title. It was painful enough to be banished to the wilderness together, but they were also isolated from each other, and even the news could not be sent. The lingering rhyme is lingering and the aftertaste is endless, and the spirit of the word &quot;send&quot; in the title also comes from this song. This shows the poet&#39;s skill in using his pen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem uses the technique of &quot;comparison in the poem&quot; to express interest in the scene through the description of the scene in front of the eyes, and uses &quot;shocking wind&quot; and &quot;dense rain&quot; to describe evil forces, with the intention of criticizing political opponents; The &quot;ridges and trees&quot; are heavy and the &quot;river flow&quot; is more difficult to look at and the pain of longing. The sadness and sorrow are beyond words, and the feeling of depression and frustration is shocking! &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was probably written in Liuzhou in the autumn of 815 AD (the tenth year of Emperor Xianzong of the Tang Dynasty). Liu Zongyuan, Han Tai, Han Ye, Chen Jian, and Liu Yuxi were all demoted for participating in the Yongzhen reform movement led by Wang Shuwen. In the tenth year of Yuanhe, Liu Zongyuan and others were summoned to the capital as usual and were demoted to the governor of Bianzhou again. After the poet arrived in Liuzhou, when he climbed up the stairs, facing the foreign scenery, he couldn&#39;t help but have mixed feelings and wrote this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/liuzongyuan.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Liu Zongyuan (773-819), courtesy name Zihou, was a native of Hedong (now Yuncheng, Shanxi) in the Tang Dynasty. He was an outstanding poet, philosopher, Confucianist and even an outstanding politician. He was one of the Eight Great Masters of the Tang and Song Dynasties. . Famous works include &quot;Eight Notes of Yongzhou&quot; and more than 600 articles, which were compiled into 30 volumes by later generations, called &quot;Liuhe East Collection&quot;. Because he was from Hedong, he was called Liu Hedong, and because he was finally appointed as the governor of Liuzhou, he was also called Liuliuzhou. Liu Zongyuan was born in the Liu family in Hedong. He was called &quot;Liu Liu&quot; with Liu Yuxi, &quot;Han Liu&quot; with Han Yu, and &quot;Wang Meng Wei Liu&quot; with Wang Wei, Meng Haoran and Wei Yingwu. Liu Zongyuan wrote more than 600 poems and essays in his lifetime, and his achievements in writing were greater than those in poetry. There are nearly a hundred parallel prose pieces. The prose is highly argumentative, sharp and satirical. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 06:23:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>