<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[江村 | 杜甫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239211]]><description> &lt;h2>;Jiangcun&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Du Fu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The Qingjiang River embraces the village, and everything in the Changxia River Village is quiet. &lt;br />;The swallows on the beams come and go, and the gulls in the water are close to each other. (Liang Shang&#39;s first work: Tang Shang)&lt;br />;The old wife draws paper to make a chess game, and the child knocks needles to make fishing hooks. &lt;br />;But if you have an old friend to offer you Lumi, what more can you ask for in addition to your tiny body? &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The clear water of Huanhua Creek flows windingly around the village, in the long In the summer, everything seems quiet and leisurely. &lt;br />;The swallows on the beams flew freely, and the white gulls in the water stayed close to each other, accompanying each other. &lt;br />;My wife who has been with him for many years drew a chessboard on paper, and my young son bent a steel needle to make a fishhook. &lt;br />;As long as an old friend gives me some money and rice, what else can I ask for? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Jiangcun: a village by the river. &lt;br />;Qingjiang: clear river water. Jiang: Refers to the Jinjiang River, a tributary of the Minjiang River. A section in the western suburbs of Chengdu is called Huanhua Creek. Song: twists and turns. Hug: embrace, surround. &lt;br />;Chang Xia: long summer. You: tranquility, ease. &lt;br />;Ziwenjilai: Come and go freely, without restraint. &lt;br />;Be close to each other: be close to each other. &lt;br />;Draw paper as a chess game: draw a chessboard on paper. &lt;br />;Zhizi: young son. &lt;br />;Lumi: The salary of ancient officials, here refers to money and rice. The sentence &quot;but you&quot; is said to be &quot;drugs are the only thing needed for many diseases&quot;. &lt;br />;Small body: The humble body is the author’s self-effacing words. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Analysis of &quot;medicines are needed for many illnesses&quot; and &quot;but there are old friends who provide Lumi&quot;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The last couplet of the poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot;, There are two versions. As for the advantages and disadvantages of the two versions, some people say:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Let&#39;s first look at the sentence &quot;The only thing needed for many diseases is medicine&quot;. Above we have already perceived the happiness and joy of the poet living in a secluded Jiangcun. Leisure is only superficial. The poet couldn&#39;t help but think to himself: The only medicine needed by the old and sick body can satisfy this meager hope. What else can a man with a humble body ask for? And we understand: In a world of chaos and separation, life is like an ant. , what&#39;s the use of medicine, it&#39;s just to linger on; it&#39;s just the temporary peace and family reunion that makes me think of cherishing life so that the hard-earned happiness can continue. This should be a very simple, humble and last resort hope. . But can this hope be satisfied? If you read the last sentence of the last couplet &quot;What else can you ask for in addition to a small body&quot;, you will find that it is just an extravagant hope. After reading this and thinking of this, will we feel sorry for Lao Du? Shedding tears of sympathy for the hard and difficult living conditions?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look again at the sentence &quot;But there are old friends offering Lumi&quot;. It makes us understand that the peaceful and peaceful life described above is based on &quot;Old friends offering Lumi&quot;. &quot;Lumi&quot;. And when the two sentences of the last couplet are read together, the inner emotion is not so much luck, but a kind of helplessness and bitterness. After wandering around for most of his life, persistent pursuit, he was The currents of society are colliding and turbulent, and I have ended up with no life and no belonging. Although my old friend Yan Wu cares about me, the sense of failure in life cannot be said to not tightly suppress the strong heart of a self-respecting man, let alone This kind of refuge is only temporary and unstable. Once the condition of &quot;old friends providing Lumi&quot; is lost, life will fall into hardship and wandering. Therefore, the faint worry about the future and endless sadness still torment the poet from time to time. His heart made him still have a strong dream-like feeling even in the situation where his family was reunited.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If we only analyze it from the pros and cons, in fact, after the war in the Central Plains, Du Fu Finally settled in Chengdu Thatched Cottage, I should feel relieved at this time. In Shu, everyone from Jiannan Jiedushi to county magistrates and governors came to visit Du Fu, which made Du Fu&#39;s poems at this stage full of a peaceful and natural atmosphere, such as &quot;Walking Alone by the River Looking for Flowers&quot;, among which: &quot;The Song of Thatched Cottage Broken by the Autumn Wind&quot; is just an example. Du&#39;s poem emphasizes individual emotions, and the emotion expressed in the last sentence should be the cherishment of today&#39;s peace and stability as he looks back on the turbulent years in the past. Therefore, in the emotional nature of the two sentences &quot;Many illnesses require only medicine&quot; and &quot;But there are old friends who provide Lumi&quot;, it is obvious that &quot;Many illnesses require only medicine&quot; is better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, if you look at the time of appearance of each version and the rhyme of the previous sentence, it should be the sentence &quot;But there is an old friend offering Lumi&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Commentary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a plain and natural seven-character poem. The author uses a pure and simple style of writing and simple and unpretentious language to embody Huan. The beautiful and tranquil natural scenery by the Huaxi River and the leisurely and comfortable taste of village life depict the most common and distinctive scenes of Jiangcun Village in summer in a vivid, natural and lovely way, with an idyllic, tranquil, elegant and simple charm. Cai Mengbi of the Song Dynasty commented in his &quot;Cottage Poems&quot;: &quot;The reason why he is greater than others is that he is ordinary. Although it sounds like a common thing, it is actually the matter before his eyes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first half of the poem is about people and their relationship. The harmony of nature is pleasing to the eye, and people feel free, cordial and harmonious in nature. The neck couplet is full of joyful and vibrant family life scenes, which deeply conveys the poet&#39;s joy and cherishment of family happiness. The last two sentences are Not seeking the plain state of mind of being an official. This is a rare and cheerful work in Du Fu&#39;s poems. Huang Sheng&#39;s &quot;Du Shi Shuo&quot; in the Qing Dynasty said that &quot;Du&#39;s rhythm is not difficult for the old and healthy, but difficult for the relaxed. This poem is free and elegant. To&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In the summer of 760 AD (the first year of Emperor Suzong’s reign in the Tang Dynasty), the poet Du Fu, with the support of his friends, went to the countryside outside Chengdu, Sichuan. A thatched cottage was built on the bank of Huanhua River. After suffering from the war, life temporarily gained peace. This poem was written during this period. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; After suffering many hardships and being displaced, the author Du Fu finally found a temporary place to live. In a peaceful atmosphere, this poem delicately describes the beautiful and tranquil scenery, casually describes the leisurely and warm life, and shows the author Du Fu&#39;s rare satisfaction and joy in a stable life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Qingjiang River hugs the village, and the Changxia River is quiet.&quot; In the village in early summer, a winding river flows quietly around the village. The water is clear and there are fish in the water. Playing, coming and going were silent, everything in the whole village was so quiet. A Qingjiang River brings peace and tranquility to the village. This &quot;Qingjiang&quot; is Huanhua Creek in Chengdu. The poet named it &quot;Qing&quot;, probably because he likes it to flow leisurely around the village. So give it a good name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Baocunliu&quot; uses personification to describe its cuteness, and it also echoes the title of the poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot;. The first two sentences set the atmosphere of the whole poem and convey the purpose of the whole poem. Everything is going smoothly, and the poet who has gone through hardships no longer has worries and sorrows, and can enjoy the scenery of the village with ease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The swallows on the beams come and go, and the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; Look, the newly built thatched cottage has just been completed, and there are naughty little swallows flying briskly over and over. No one pays attention to them, but They play so happily, just like lively children. The poet stroked his beard and laughed, strolling to the riverside. There were two white gulls floating softly on the river. They were in front or behind, sometimes crowing with their necks crossed, sometimes chasing each other and circling on the water - they They must be a couple who love each other. He Xun, a poet of the Southern Dynasties, once wrote a sentence about &quot;Pityful twin gulls, swimming on the water day and night&quot;. Du Fu once studied He Xun&#39;s poems. When he saw this scene, he must have felt something and forgotten about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The old wife draws paper to make a chess game, and the child knocks needles to make fishing hooks.&quot; The poet walked slowly home with a happy mood, and saw his wife sitting in the shade of the tree in front of the door, writing on the paper What was painted on it, when I looked closer, I saw it was a chess game. The sound of &quot;ding ding&quot; came, and the youngest son was immersed in tapping a needle seriously. This playful child wanted to make a fishhook by himself so that he could go fishing on the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scenes like this are probably common in the village, but for the author Du Fu, who experienced the Anshi Rebellion, suffered many setbacks, and spent half his life, it was a rare and precious blessing, which made him heartbroken. A warm one. He had never imagined such a warm moment when he was &quot;a wealthy man in the morning, and a fat horse in the evening. Broken cups and cold dishes, everywhere lurking sadness&quot; (&quot;Twenty-two Rhymes from Wei Zuo Chengzhang&quot;). These two sentences capture the most ordinary scenes in life, conveying a universal warmth of family affection and the leisurely beauty of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;But if an old friend gives me rice, what more can I ask for in addition to a small body?&quot; The poet sighed from the peaceful life scene in front of him: An old friend gave me food and his salary, and I, an ordinary person, What more can a lowly man ask for? These two sentences seem to express happiness and satisfaction, but if you read them carefully, you will find that they actually contain much sadness and bitterness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Fu was able to live in a thatched cottage in Chengdu only because of the help of his friends. Although he had such happiness and tranquility in front of him, it was based on his dependence on others. The great poet who was revered by later generations as the &quot;Saint of Poetry&quot; had to rely on gifts from others to survive, and he also said that he &quot;wanted nothing more&quot;, that is, he had no other requirements. The calmer and calmer this language is, the more sad and sad it makes readers cry. His ambition was to &quot;serve the emperors Yao and Shun, and then make the customs pure&quot; (&quot;Twenty-two Rhymes of Presenting to Wei Zuocheng&quot;). However, dozens of spring and autumn years have passed, and now in his old age, people only require one vegetable and one meal. The poet spoke so casually, as if he no longer had the haze of life in his heart and no longer wanted to face the turmoil and noise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the artistic point of view of poetry, this poem is rigorously written but flows naturally; the words are concise, the description is subtle, and it is invisible. This is the sophistication of Du Fu&#39;s rhymed poetry. The first line of the last couplet is &quot;But there are old friends who offer Lumi&quot;, and the first line is &quot;The only medicine needed for many illnesses&quot;. From a plain and poetic point of view, the sentence &quot;But there is&quot; is better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is intertwined with each other, and the echoes are tight: &quot;Liang Shangyan&quot; belongs to the &quot;village&quot;, and &quot;gull in the water&quot; belongs to the &quot;river&quot;: &quot;chess game&quot; is the same as &quot;Long Summer&quot;, and &quot;fishing hook&quot; also implies &quot;Qingjiang&quot; &quot;. The chin couplet &quot;Since going and coming, the swallows on the beams, the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; The two characters &quot;zi&quot; and the two characters &quot;xiang&quot; are in the same sentence; &quot;go&quot;, &quot;lai&quot;, &quot;ki&quot; and &quot;near&quot; are in the same sentence. right. Corresponding to itself and to each other, it reads briskly and wanderingly. The characters for &quot;painting&quot; and &quot;knocking&quot; on the neck couplet are both ready-made. Both sentences use a simple tone, which best expresses the artistic conception of a husband and wife who respect each other as they grow older, and a child who is foolish and stubborn, and who knows no difference between the wise and the foolish. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Artistic Features&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Don’t repeat the word repetition: In the two sentences of the first couplet of this poem, the word &quot;江&quot; and the word &quot;村&quot; appear twice. Second-rate. According to the general rules for writing rhymed poetry, compound characters should not be included in the same couplet of the chin and neck couplets. Although the requirements for the first and last couplets of loose sentences are not so strict, compound words should be avoided as much as possible. This poem uses a pair of compound characters, which gives it a light and elegant feeling, and does not feel like it is a repetition. This situation is like the obfuscation in the rhythmic sentences. Obvious sentences must be corrected with oblique sentences, and complex characters must be used to make up for complex characters. What&#39;s more, the second sentence contains two other repeated words &quot;things&quot;. As a result, when the first two sentences of the poem are read, there is no sense of support at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is intertwined with each other, and the echoes are tight: &quot;Liang Shangyan&quot; belongs to the &quot;village&quot;, and &quot;gull in the water&quot; belongs to the &quot;river&quot;: &quot;chess game&quot; is the same as &quot;Long Summer&quot;, and &quot;fishing hook&quot; also implies &quot;Qingjiang&quot; &quot;. The chin couplet &quot;Since going and coming, the swallows on the beams, the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; The two characters &quot;zi&quot; and the two characters &quot;xiang&quot; are in the same sentence; &quot;go&quot;, &quot;lai&quot;, &quot;ki&quot; and &quot;near&quot; are in the same sentence. right. Corresponding to itself and to each other, it reads briskly and wanderingly. The characters for &quot;painting&quot; and &quot;knocking&quot; on the neck couplet are both ready-made. Both sentences use a simple tone, which best expresses the artistic conception of a husband and wife who respect each other as they grow older, and a child who is foolish and stubborn, and who knows no difference between the wise and the foolish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The conclusion suddenly turns sad: Du Fu has two lines of poems in which he talks about the joys and sorrows of writing poetry. He said that &quot;poetry is the source of great sorrow, but poetry becomes desolate when it is chanted&quot; (&quot;Towards the End&quot;). This poem was originally about a leisurely state of mind, but as he wrote it, at the end of the poem, he could not help but reveal his loneliness and unhappiness, making people feel melancholy. Many of Du Fu&#39;s impromptu poems are almost all like this. The predecessors called Du&#39;s poems &quot;depressive&quot;, and the opportunity may lie here. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written in the first year of Shangyuan (760) by Emperor Suzong of Tang Dynasty. A few months ago, after four years of exile, the poet traveled from Tongzhou via Mianzhou to the banks of Huanhua Creek on the outskirts of Chengdu, a prosperous hometown in the southwest that had not been harassed by war and had remained quiet for the time being. The thatched cottage that he worked hard to manage with the help of relatives and friends has begun to take shape; the poet, who has experienced the pain of leaving his hometown and the hardships of displacement, finally found a temporary place to live. It&#39;s early summer, and by the Huanhua River, the river is winding, the water and trees are clear, and it&#39;s a quiet and elegant pastoral scene. The poet picked up the title of the poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot; and wrote about it. It is conceivable that he felt happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three words &quot;everything is quiet&quot; in the second sentence of the first couplet of this poem are the key words of the whole poem and bring out a purpose. The four sentences in the middle closely follow &quot;Everything is quiet&quot; and are narrated all the way. The swallows in the beams come and go freely and at ease; the white gulls on the river, far and near, accompany each other. From the poet&#39;s point of view, both swallows and gulls have a sense of forgetfulness and adaptability to the crowd. Things are so quiet, and the interesting human affairs especially make the poet happy: the infatuation and naivety of the old wife drawing paper for a chess game is lovable; the innocence of the child knocking needles to make fishing hooks is endearing. The chess game is the best place to spend the summer, and the Qingjiang River is just right for fishing, so the villagers have fun and everything goes well. After a long period of separation, why wouldn&#39;t the poet feel happy and satisfied when he regained the joy of a family and children? The concluding sentence, &quot;If you have an old friend to offer you Lumi, what more can you ask for than a small body?&quot; Although it is a happy word on the surface, it contains a lot of sadness in the heart. Saying &quot;but there is&quot; does not guarantee that there will be something; saying &quot;what more should we ask for&quot; just means that we have already asked for something. Du Fu has indeed not forgotten that the leisurely and leisurely life in front of him is built on the basis of &quot;offering Lumi to old friends&quot;. This is a very sensitive tender point. Once there is a problem with the distribution of money and rice, everything will be out of the question. Therefore, we might as well say that the last two sentences of this conclusion are not so much words of luck as words of bitterness. A generation of poets who struggled with poverty and relied on others to survive temporarily found a place to live, and Du Fu was able to live in peace. At the same time, he uttered such sad words, which is really a strong accusation against the feudal ruling class for destroying talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The four sentences in the central couplet fully describe the quiet things in Jiangcun in terms of physical and human relations. Then, in the concluding sentence, the sentence &quot;what else can you ask for&quot; is used to connect &quot;everything is quiet&quot; and conclude. It completes the theme of an article, is the simplest and most stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Jiangcun&quot; also has unique features in its artistic treatment:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First, do not repeat the repetition of characters. In the two sentences of the first couplet of this poem, the characters &quot;jiang&quot; and &quot;village&quot; are found twice. According to the general rules for writing rhymed poetry, compound characters should be avoided in the same couplet of the chin and neck couplets. Although the requirements for sentences with loose lines in the first and last couplets are not so strict, compound words should be avoided as much as possible. Nowadays, using a pair of compound characters gives a light and elegant feeling, and does not feel like it is a repetition. This situation is very similar to the obsessive sentences in rhythmic sentences. Obvious sentences must be corrected with oblique sentences, and complex characters must be compensated with complex characters. What&#39;s more, the second sentence contains two other repeated words &quot;things&quot;. In this way, when the first two sentences of the poem are read, there is no sense of support at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Secondly, the whole poem is meshed forward and backward, and the echoes are compact. &quot;Liang Shangyan&quot; belongs to &quot;village&quot;, and &quot;Oll in the Water&quot; belongs to &quot;river&quot;: &quot;Chess Game&quot; directly represents &quot;Changxia&quot;, and &quot;fishing hook&quot; also implies &quot;Qingjiang&quot;. The chin couplet &quot;Since going and coming, the swallows on the beams, the gulls in the water are close to each other.&quot; The two characters &quot;zi&quot; and the two characters &quot;xiang&quot; are in the same sentence: &quot;go&quot;, &quot;come&quot;, &quot;ki&quot; and &quot;near&quot; are in the same sentence. Corresponding to itself and to each other, it reads briskly and wanderingly. The characters for &quot;painting&quot; and &quot;knocking&quot; on the neck couplet are both ready-made. Both sentences use a simple tone, which best expresses the artistic conception of a husband and wife who respect each other as they grow older, and a child who is foolish and stubborn, and who knows no difference between the wise and the foolish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third is the conclusion, which suddenly turns sad and has the characteristics of Du Fu&#39;s poetry. Du Fu has two lines of poems in which he describes the joys and sorrows of writing poetry, saying that &quot;the extreme sorrow is brought about by poetry, but when poetry is chanted, it becomes desolate&quot; (&quot;Towards the End&quot;). This poem was originally about a leisurely state of mind, but as he wrote it, at the end of the poem, he could not help but reveal his loneliness and unhappiness, making people feel melancholy. Many of Du Fu&#39;s impromptu poems are almost all like this. The predecessors called Du&#39;s poems &quot;depressive&quot;, and the opportunity may lie here. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/dufu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Du Fu (712-770), whose courtesy name is Zimei, who calls himself Shaoling Yelao, is also known as &quot;Du Gongbu&quot;, &quot;Du Shaoling&quot;, etc., Han nationality, Fugong County, Henan (now Henan Province Gongyi City), a great realist poet in the Tang Dynasty, Du Fu is respected by the world as the &quot;Sage of Poetry&quot;, and his poems are called &quot;the history of poetry&quot;. Du Fu and Li Bai are collectively known as &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, known as &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively known as &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. He was concerned about the country and the people, and had a noble personality. About 1,400 of his poems have been preserved. His poetic skills are exquisite, and he is highly respected in Chinese classical poetry and has far-reaching influence. He lived in Chengdu from 759 to 766, and is commemorated by Du Fu&#39;s Thatched Cottage in later generations. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 07:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[浣溪沙·簌簌衣巾落枣花 | 苏轼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239212]]><description> &lt;h2>;Huanxisha · Jujube Blossoms Falling on Clothes and Scarves&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Su Shi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;Xumen Shitan Xie Yu, composed five poems on the road. The pond is twenty miles east of the city, and it often corresponds to the increase or decrease in the clarity and turbidity of the Surabaya River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jujube flowers are falling on clothes and towels, a milling wheel is ringing in the south of the village and in the north of the village, and cucumbers are sold by ancient willows in water clothes. (町通:环)&lt;br />;I am sleepy after being drunk for a long time, and I am thirsty and thinking about tea when I am high in the sun. Knock on the door and ask the savages. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Jujube flowers fell on the lapels of passers-by, and the sound sounded from the south of the village to the north. There was the sound of a wheel reeling silk, and a farmer in coarse cloth was selling cucumbers under the old willow tree. &lt;br />;The road is far away, the drunkenness is on my mind, I feel dizzy and just want to take a nap, the sun is high, I am tired and thirsty, I want to drink some tea to quench my thirst. So I knocked on the door of a villager&#39;s house in the wild and asked if I could give him a bowl of tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Xumen: Xuzhou. &lt;br />;Xie Yu: Thank God after the rain. &lt;br />;簌猌: The appearance of falling one after another. It is pronounced as &quot;甔茌&quot; with the same pronunciation and meaning. &lt;br />;Reeling wheel: spinning wheel. Reeling, making a &quot;reeling&quot;, soaks the silkworm cocoon in hot water and pulls out the silk. &lt;br />;Water clothing: coir raincoat and the like. This generally refers to clothes made of burlap. &quot;Han Shu. Food and Huo Zhi&quot; has a saying that &quot;poor people often wear clothes like water and horses&quot;. &lt;br />;Mansi Tea: I want to find some tea anywhere. Romantic, casual, one word is &quot;詩&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by the 43-year-old Su Shi when he was the prefect of Xuzhou (now Jiangsu). In the spring of 1078 AD (the first year of Yuanfeng in the Northern Song Dynasty), a severe drought occurred in Xuzhou. As a local official, Su Shi once led his people to a stone pond twenty miles east of the city to pray for rain. After it rained, he went to Shitan with the people to thank him for the rain. Su Shi wrote the poem &quot;Huanxi Sand&quot; on his way to Xie Yu in Shitan, Xumen. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The poem &quot;Huanxisha&quot; was written by Su Shi when he was 43 years old when he was the prefect of Xuzhou. In the spring of 1078 AD (the first year of Yuanfeng), a severe drought occurred in Xuzhou. As a local official, Su Shi once led his people to a stone pond twenty miles east of the city to pray for rain. After it rained, he went to Shitan with the people to thank him for the rain. Su Shi composed the poem &quot;Huanxi Sand&quot; on his way to Xie Yu in Shitan, Xumen. This is the fourth of five poems in total. The work describes his experiences and feelings in the countryside. It is artistically ingenious. The words start from typical things commonly seen in rural areas, and express the honest rural flavor in an interesting way. Fresh and simple, clear as words, vivid and lifelike, are the distinctive features of this word. The first part of this poem describes the scenery, and the second part is lyrical. It should be pointed out that the scene described in this poem is not a unified picture formed through visual images in general, but a scene reflected on the screen of the poet&#39;s consciousness through various different sounds transmitted to the ear drum. A series of continuous memories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem was written by Su Shi when he was an official in Xuzhou (in today&#39;s Jiangsu Province). According to the superstitious customs at that time, a local official who was concerned about farming would ask the &quot;Dragon Lord&quot; for rain when there was a severe drought; when it rained, he would also thank the &quot;Dragon Lord&quot; for the rain. This poem is one of the things Su Shi recorded when he passed through the countryside to thank Yu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The jujube flowers are falling off the clothes and towels&quot;, according to the literary meaning, it should be &quot;the dates are falling off the clothes and towels.&quot; When ancient people wrote poetry, they often adjusted the order of sentence components according to the needs of meter and rhetoric, as is the case here. &quot;簌簌&quot; describes the appearance of jujube flowers falling one after another. &quot;Yijie&quot; refers to clothes and headscarves. In ancient clothing, men often wore headscarves. Jujube trees bloom small yellow-green flowers in early summer. The author did not see the falling jujube flowers from the side, but walked under the jujube tree or stood under the jujube tree so that the jujube flowers could fall on the clothes and towels. Next, &quot;the sound of reeling in the south of the village and the north of the village&quot;. &quot;缩[sāo]车&quot;, a hand-operated tool for extracting silk. The sound of silk reeling was heard from the south end to the north end of the village. It turned out that the silkworm farmers were working nervously. Here, there are jujube flowers scattered, there are winding cars singing, and under the ancient willow trees on the roadside, there is also a farmer wearing a water jacket selling cucumbers. &quot;Water clothing&quot; is a kind of fabric made of hemp or grass and used to cover the water body. Here it refers to things like coir raincoat. There are three sentences in the film, each of which describes an aspect of the scenery. This time Su Shi came to the countryside by chance and sensitively captured these characteristics, especially things with seasonal characteristics such as jujube flowers, silk reeling, and cucumbers, and sketched them. With just a few strokes, a custom painting of a rural area in early summer was painted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem not only describes the scenery, but also remembers the events. In the next film, it turns into the writer&#39;s own activities. At this time, he was already &quot;drunk but sleepy after a long journey&quot;. &quot;Drunk from alcohol&quot; means sleepiness after drinking, indicating that he drank before going on the road. &quot;The road is long&quot;, it seems, has traveled a long distance, but is still far away from the destination. &quot;Wei&quot;, only. This sentence expresses the sleepiness of his journey. &quot;People in Rigao are thirsty and think about tea.&quot; &quot;Sun Gao&quot; means the sun has risen very high. While driving under the early summer sun, I felt hot and thirsty, and I couldn&#39;t help but want to drink a cup of tea to soothe my throat and quench my thirst. &quot;Man&quot; here means can&#39;t help it. If you are thirsty, you need tea; if you are sleepy, you probably want tea to relieve your sleepiness. So he &quot;knocked on the door and asked the savages.&quot; &quot;Savage family&quot; refers to rural people, that is, ordinary people in the countryside. Su Shi was the chief executive of a state at the time. He called local farmers &quot;savage families&quot; in his writings, which was just out of his official tone. But the word &quot;question&quot; shows that he has no official air. He did not order his attendants to ask for it, but he himself knocked on the door of a common man&#39;s house and politely discussed with them: &quot;Fellow, can you give me some tea to quench my thirst?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this way, with a few simple sentences, he not only painted a picture of a rural area full of life, but also recorded an experience of knocking on the door of a fellow villager to ask for tea. It’s something that you can’t touch in other places, so it feels fresh and interesting. This poem seems to have been written casually, but in fact the words are vivid and expressive, giving this short poem a narrative style an artistic life. This is the &quot;inexhaustible meaning, seen beyond the words&quot; that is emphasized in classical poetry. Why does the author want to &quot;knock on the door and ask questions&quot;? 1. He is a good parent official who is considerate of the people and loves them as his own son. He is modest and polite and will not rush into the farmhouse; 2. He just asked for rain after the drought. The owner may be out farming in the fields and not at home, so he wants to test the family. Is anyone there? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the poem &quot;Huanxisha&quot;, the sentence &quot;Jujube flowers rustle on clothes and towels fall off&quot; is actually the reverse text of &quot;Jujube flowers rustle off clothes and towels&quot;; in Du Fu&#39;s poem &quot;Autumn Xing&quot; there is &quot;Fragrant rice&quot; The original meaning is: Parrots peck at the remaining fragrant rice grains, and the phoenix perches on the old phoenix branches. While the subject and object are inverted, the objects &quot;fragrant rice grains&quot; and &quot;biwu branches&quot; are also split into the positions of the subject and the guest. Regarding the inversion of verses in classical poetry, Hong Liangji from the Qing Dynasty said: &quot;Poets often use inversion to find it strange and vivid.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem of &quot;Huanxisha&quot; contains scenery and people, tangible and colorful, and has a strong local flavor. The sun is high, the road is long, the person is drunk, and the person is thirsty. It literally represents the fatigue of the journey, but it still conveys joy and joy, and conveys the spirit of the protagonist, the county magistrate, who is considerate of the people. This poem not only paints a realistic picture of rural life in early summer, but also records the author&#39;s experiences and feelings during the journey, opening up a new world for the social content of Northern Song Dynasty poems. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by Su Shi when he was an official in Xuzhou. According to the superstitious customs at that time, a local official who was concerned about farming would ask the &quot;Dragon Lord&quot; for rain when there was a severe drought; when it rained, he would also thank the &quot;Dragon Lord&quot; for the rain. This poem is one of the things Su Shi recorded when he passed through the countryside to thank Yu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This word describes his experiences and feelings in the countryside. It is artistically ingenious. The words start from typical things commonly seen in rural areas, and express the honest rural flavor in an interesting way. Fresh and simple, clear as words, vivid and lifelike, are the distinctive features of this word. The first part of this poem describes the scenery, and the second part is lyrical. It should be pointed out that the scene described in this poem is not a unified picture formed through visual images in general, but a scene reflected on the screen of the poet&#39;s consciousness through various different sounds transmitted to the ear drum. A series of continuous memories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Jujube flowers are falling on clothes and towels&quot; begins with the sound of date flowers falling on clothes and towels, reflecting the joy of a prefect who cares about people&#39;s lives for the new scene in the countryside after the rain. The author was on the &quot;Xie Yu Road&quot;. After a long journey, he was still drunk and sleepy, so he couldn&#39;t help but feel a little tired. Suddenly, a &quot;swishing&quot; sound came to my ears, and it seemed like something was hitting my body and headscarf. Only then did he realize: it was a jujube flower falling on him. The sound of jujube blossoms falling on the clothes and scarves is slight, but it is so real to the author&#39;s ears. Then, there was another squeaking sound in my ears. The further I walked, the stronger the sound became. It came from the south, from the north, and from all directions. There was no need to look or ask. This was the sound of the reeling car that the author was familiar with. sound. &quot;South of the village and north of the village&quot; summarizes the sound of &quot;reeling&quot;, which shows how seriously, how carefully and how excited the author listened. From the sound, the author realized that he had entered the village. At this time, a sudden burst of hawking sound reached my ears. I looked closely and saw that it was a farmer wearing a &quot;water coat&quot; sitting in the shade of an ancient willow tree with a pile of cucumbers in front of him. &quot;Shuiyi Guliu&quot;, the author changes his perspective to write about his joy at the vegetable harvest. Three sentences, three images, seemingly scattered and completely unrelated. But when strung together with the line &quot;Xie Yu&#39;s Road&quot;, people feel that this comic strip has a strong three-dimensional sense. This group of pictures is not only beautiful in color, but also beautiful in music. Whether it is the sound of falling flowers, the buzzing sound of cars, or the cries of melon farmers, they are all full of rich flavor of life, vividly showing the prosperous scene of the countryside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first part describes the busy scene of rural production and labor, and the second part turns to the hardships of Xie Yu’s journey, highlighting the author’s feelings and conscious activities. &quot;Drunk but sleepy after a long journey&quot; is a supplement to the previous film. Structurally, this sentence is a flashback. It shows that the reason why the first three sentences were written from the auditory perspective is mainly because the drunkenness has not passed, the journey is long, and the body is tired, so what is written down is just a snippet that was heard in a sleepy state. , is not a complete and unified picture of visual composition. The two sentences &quot;The sun rises and people are thirsty&quot;, although they describe the conscious activities of eager to find water at farmers&#39; homes due to thirst, they also reflect the author&#39;s informal and happy-go-lucky character. Walking from village to village, it was already hot and sunny, and people were thirsty and sleepy due to the wine. They couldn&#39;t help but think of tea to quench their thirst and refresh themselves. The word &quot;question&quot; is used very carefully. It not only expresses the author&#39;s full hope of asking for a cup of tea to quench his thirst, but also worries that there will be no one in the farm during the busy farming season and it will be inconvenient for him to rush in. The letter is written without any polish, but it is lifelike, portraying the image of a humble and approachable magistrate, and describing the relationship between a prefect and ordinary farmers in a cordial and natural way. &quot;Knock on the door and ask the savages&quot;, the words stopped abruptly here. What was the result of the poet&#39;s knocking on the door, whether he got tea, and how the farmers entertained him? There is no explanation in the poem, leaving it to the reader&#39;s imagination, which leaves an endless aftertaste. This is the &quot;inexhaustible meaning, seen beyond the words&quot; that is emphasized in classical poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the poem &quot;Huanxisha&quot;, the sentence &quot;Jujube flowers rustle on clothes and towels fall off&quot; is actually the reverse text of &quot;Jujube flowers rustle off clothes and towels&quot;; in Du Fu&#39;s poem &quot;Autumn Xing&quot; there is &quot;Fragrant rice&quot; The original meaning is: Parrots peck at the remaining fragrant rice grains, and the phoenix perches on the old phoenix branches. While the subject and object are inverted, the objects &quot;fragrant rice grains&quot; and &quot;biwu branches&quot; are also split into the positions of the subject and the guest. Regarding the inversion of verses in classical poetry, Hong Liangji from the Qing Dynasty said: &quot;Poets often use inversion to find it strange and vivid.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is vivid and lifelike, and the narrative is fresh and elegant, full of emotion, which contributed to the expansion of the realm of Song poetry. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/sushi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Su Shi, (January 8, 1037 - August 24, 1101), also known as Zizhan and Hezhong, also known as Tieguan Taoist and Dongpo layman, known as Su Dongpo and Su Xian in the world. Han nationality, a native of Meishan, Meizhou (Meishan City, Sichuan Province), his ancestral home is Luancheng, Hebei Province, a famous writer, calligrapher, and painter in the Northern Song Dynasty, and a celebrity in water control in history. Su Shi was a literary leader in the mid-Northern Song Dynasty and made great achievements in poetry, lyrics, prose, calligraphy, and painting. His writing is bold and unbridled; his poems are broad in subject matter, fresh and vigorous, good at using exaggerated metaphors, and have a unique style. Together with Huang Tingjian, he is called &quot;Su Huang&quot;; His prose writings are grand and bold. Together with Ouyang Xiu, he is called &quot;Ou Su&quot; and is one of the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Su Shi was good at calligraphy and one of the &quot;Four Masters of the Song Dynasty&quot;; he was good at literati painting, especially ink bamboo, strange rocks, dead wood, etc. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan and Ouyang Xiu, they are known as the &quot;Four Great Masters of Eternal Writing&quot;. His works include &quot;Dongpo Seven Collections&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yi Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yuefu&quot;, &quot;Xiaoxiang Bamboo and Stone Picture Scroll&quot;, &quot;Old Trees and Strange Stones Picture Scroll&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>