<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[残菊 | 曹雪芹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231051]]><description> &lt;h2>;Canju&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Cao Xueqin&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The dew and frost are gradually falling, and the feast has just passed the light snow. &lt;br />;The pedicle has a lingering fragrance of gold and is indifferent, and the branches are not all covered with green leaves. &lt;br />;The moon falls on the bed and the crickets sound sick, thousands of miles of cold clouds and wild geese arrive late. &lt;br />;The autumn wind will see us again next year, so don’t miss us if we break up for the time being. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;When the cold dew and frost are getting heavier and heavier, the chrysanthemum branches gradually tilt, feast and enjoy the chrysanthemums It’s just passed and it’s the light snow solar term again. &lt;br />;The petals on the receptacle have not yet fallen off, but their color has gradually become lighter. The leaves on the branches have gradually fallen off, leaving them scattered and scattered. &lt;br />;A waning moon half shines in front of the bed, the chirping of crickets gradually becomes fainter, and the flight of the geese becomes slower in the sky covered with cold clouds. &lt;br />;We will definitely meet again next fall. Please don’t miss us too much after we break up for now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Qing Jie (qī): refers to the chrysanthemum leaning sideways. &lt;br />;Xiaoxue: a solar term after the beginning of winter. &lt;br />;Yuxiang: It actually means &quot;remaining petals&quot;, which is a metaphor for the beautiful girls who grew up under the shadow of this noble family. &lt;br />;Indifferent: refers to a dull color. &lt;br />;Li Phi: also means &quot;Phi Li&quot;, looking scattered. &lt;br />;Zhi See You Again: &quot;I don&#39;t know if I can see you again&quot; means. Autumn Wind: Cheng Gao&#39;s &quot;Autumnal Equinox&quot; in &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot; refers to the season, and there is not much difference between the two. But if the author has a moral, then each word has a different meaning. Since Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty wrote the poem &quot;Autumn Wind Ci&quot;, &quot;There is so much joy but so much sorrow, and when you are young and old, you are so helpless.&quot; In order to facilitate the inference of the original meaning, we will refer to the fat version. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Chrysanthemum Poetry&quot; concludes with &quot;Remnant Chrysanthemum&quot;, which &quot;summarizes the prosperity of the previous title&quot; (Baochai&#39;s words). It is an irresistible law of nature to prosper and then decline, and it is the same in the human world. This poem uses the description of the broken chrysanthemum to hint at the decline of the Jia family and the ending of everyone&#39;s separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the first couplet, &quot;The dew is heavy with frost&quot; indicates that the crisis faced by Jia&#39;s family is getting more and more serious. The building is already crumbling, but everyone is unaware and still feasting and having fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second couplet hints at the fate of everyone after the decline of the Jia family. They once lived a life of fine clothing and fine food, but now they are scorched and dull, losing their former color. Not only them, but the entire family will &quot;disperse and go their separate ways.&quot; &quot;Jin Danbo&quot; and &quot;Cui Li Phi&quot; not only describe the dazzling and prosperous scene of the past, but also vividly depict the later dilapidated situation, which shows the author&#39;s skill in choosing words and phrases. No wonder Baoyu was convinced by these words. This couplet of chrysanthemums has been described to the most vivid degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The neck couplet turns to write about people. &quot;Talent comes from being shrewd and ambition comes from being high.&quot; As a talented and ambitious girl, Tanchun had already been aware of the lurking crisis in her family, but she was unable to save herself. He married in a foreign land, which made her worry about her family members day and night, so much so that she could not sleep at night. She listened to the chirping of autumn insects outside the window getting weaker and weaker. In the sky, the belated geese flew slowly against thousands of miles of cold clouds, leaving behind A shrill wail. In this gloomy background picture, Jia Tanchun cheered up, comforted the chrysanthemums, and comforted himself: &quot;Next autumn, there will be a time to meet again. This is just a temporary separation, so there is no need to be too lovesick.&quot; This makes readers I am reminded of Tan Chun&#39;s tone in &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions: Dividing Flesh and Bones&quot;: &quot;Since ancient times, poverty and prosperity have all been determined. How can there be no fate for separation and reunion? From now on, we are divided into two places, each keeping safe. If you go, please don&#39;t get involved!&quot; But next year&#39;s chrysanthemums , is no longer the chrysanthemum of this year. As Zhen Shiyin sang in &quot;Commentary to the Good Song&quot;: &quot;Withered grass and withered poplars, it was once a singing and dancing venue.&quot; Life is like a dream, but it is not a dream; what disappears will disappear forever, and the new arrival does not know when it will come. The play is still going on, but the protagonists change again and again. The loneliness after the play is over can only be experienced by the person involved alone. Cheng Ben&#39;s continuation of the book hints at the ending of &quot;Lan Gui Qi Fang&quot; for readers. This is just like Tan Chun&#39;s wish to &quot;temporarily break up&quot;, which is nothing more than an expression of a good wish. Real life is often full of hope and helplessness. Facing the intertwined reality of sentimentality and ruthlessness, readers experience a more profound sadness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first six sentences of this poem gradually describe the extremely vital chrysanthemum, which is now in ruins, revealing Tanchun&#39;s calm insight into the tragic fate of Qunfang. However, among all the girls in the Grand View Garden, Tanchun is the most positive. She is not decadent when facing Canju. In the last couplet, she expresses the feeling that there is no need to be sad about the dead flowers, &quot;the flowers will bloom only when they fall, and they will be fragrant for the coming year.&quot; She places her hope in the future. Later, she angrily stated that she wanted to break out of this declining family and go out to &quot;build a career&quot; as evidenced by this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Judging from the overall concept of &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot; and &quot;Chrysanthemum Poems&quot;, &quot;Remnant Chrysanthemum&quot; contains the meaning of &quot;Endgame&quot;. The entire life course of the chrysanthemum implies the rise and decline of the Jia family, and the tragic life course of the young people in the Grand View Garden. It has far-reaching connections and is intricately linked. It is not enough to read it as an isolated poem. . &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem comes from the 38th chapter of &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, &quot;Lin Xiaoxiang&#39;s Chrysanthemum Poem, Xue Hengwu&#39;s Satire and Crab Ode&quot;. After the inscription of the Grand View Garden, through the Begonia Poetry Society and the Chrysanthemum Poetry Society, this period seemed to be the &quot;peaceful and prosperous age&quot; of the Grand View Garden, but fierce battles between orthodoxy and heresy, and life-and-death struggles between concubines and concubines, had occurred one after another. The feudal aristocracy and its younger generation enjoy flowers and drinks in this &quot;paradise&quot; that is actually full of dangers, and the premonition of decline is also invading their hedonistic life. For this event, Shi Xiangyun and Xue Baochai drafted the topic. There were a total of twelve topics, limited to seven rhymes, but not limited to rhyme. Baoyu, Daiyu, Baochai, Xiangyun, Tanchun and other five people were free to choose the topics. Jia Tanchun is &quot;talented and ambitious&quot;. He has already discovered the hidden crisis in his family, but he is unable to save the family. Jia Tanchun chose the title &quot;The Broken Chrysanthemum&quot; to imply that the family will end in ruins. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/caoxueqin.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Cao Xueqin (about May 28, 1715 - about February 12, 1763), named Zhan, also named Mengruan, also known as Xueqin, also known as Qinxi and Qinpu, is the author of the Chinese classic &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot; The author&#39;s ancestral home is disputed (Liaoyang, Liaoning, Fengrun, Hebei, or Tieling, Liaoning). He was born in Jiangning (now Nanjing). Cao Xueqin was born in the Zhengbai Banner wrapping family of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Qing Dynasty. He was the grandson of Cao Yin, a weaver in Jiangning, and the son of Cao Yong (one theory is that Cao Fu&#39;s son). In the twenty-seventh year of Qianlong (1762), his youngest son died young. He fell into excessive sadness and grief and became bedridden. He died on New Year&#39;s Eve (February 12) in the 28th year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1763) due to poverty and illness without medical treatment. Regarding the year of Cao Xueqin&#39;s death, there are also theories about New Year&#39;s Eve in the 29th year of Qianlong (February 1, 1764) and the early spring of Jiashen (1764). &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 08:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[闲居初夏午睡起·其一 | 杨万里]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231052]]><description> &lt;h2>;Relaxing in early summer and taking a nap·Part 1&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Yang Wanli&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The plums are left with sour teeth, and the bananas are divided into green and window screens. &lt;br />;The day is long and I fall asleep with no thoughts, watching children catching willow flowers. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;After eating the plums, the residual acid still remains between the teeth, and the green of the plantains reflects On the window screen. &lt;br />;On a long summer day, I woke up from my nap and didn’t know what to do. I just lazily watched the children chasing catkins flying in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Plum: A very sour fruit. &lt;br />;Soft teeth: one means splashing teeth, which means that the sour smell of plums penetrates the teeth. &lt;br />;Plantains are green: The green of plantains is reflected on the screen window. &lt;br />;And the window screen: &quot;Chengzhai Collection&quot; of &quot;Four Parts&quot; is called &quot;window screen&quot;, which is based on &quot;Selected Works of Yang Wanli&quot;. With, meaning to give. &lt;br />;Emotionless: Having no emotions means being at a loss and not knowing what to do. Thoughts, intentions, emotions. &lt;br />;Catching willow flowers: Playing with catkins flying in the air. Willow flowers are catkins. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The author of this poem had just woken up from a nap and was listless. When he saw the children chasing catkins, his childish innocence returned and he couldn&#39;t help but I was immersed in it expectantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The banana trees are green, the willows are dancing, the poet&#39;s feelings are also there, the scenery is fresh and leisurely, full of childishness. Children catch willow flowers, and the willow flowers seem to have infinite childlike innocence, playing hide and seek with the children in the wind. From time to time there was laughter, which should have awakened the poet from his sleep. The first two sentences mark the summer season in the early Ming Dynasty, and the last two sentences indicate the long days in summer and the boredom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem uses plums, bananas, willow flowers and other objects to express the seasonal characteristics of early summer. The poet lives leisurely in the countryside. After taking a nap in early summer, he leisurely watches children catching and playing with catkins flying in the air, feeling happy. The word &quot;soft&quot; is used in the poem to express his leisurely mood; the word &quot;fen&quot; is also very expressive, with profound connotations but not sticky; especially the word &quot;xian&quot; not only vividly expresses the tranquility, leisure and harmony in the poet&#39;s heart The love for rural life is shown and echoes the title of the poem very cleverly. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/yangwanli.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Yang Wanli (October 29, 1127 - June 15, 1206), named Tingxiu and Chengzhai. A native of Jishui, Jizhou (now Kuantang Village, Huangqiao Town, Jishui County, Jiangxi Province). A famous poet and minister in the Southern Song Dynasty, he is known as the &quot;four great poets of Zhongxing&quot; together with Lu You, You Miao and Fan Chengda. Because Song Guangzong once personally wrote the word &quot;Chengzhai&quot; to him, scholars called him &quot;Mr. Chengzhai&quot;. Yang Wanli wrote more than 20,000 poems in his lifetime, and has 4,200 poems handed down from generation to generation. He is known as the master of poetry of his generation. He created the &quot;Chengzhai style&quot; with simple, clear, fresh and natural language and full of humor. Most of Yang Wanli&#39;s poems describe natural scenery, and he is famous for this. He also has many works that reflect the suffering of the people and express patriotic feelings. He is the author of &quot;Chengzhai Collection&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 04:23:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>