<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[采莲曲二首 | 王昌龄]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310141]]><description> &lt;h2>;Two Lotus Picking Songs&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Wang Changling&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;Wu Ji, the more beautiful Princess Chu, fights over the lotus boat and wets her clothes. &lt;br />;When you come, you will be greeted by Pukou flowers, and you will be sent home after picking them up in the first month of the Yangtze River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lotus leaf skirt is cut in one color, with hibiscus slit to both sides of the face. &lt;br />;He entered the pool without being able to see him, but when he heard the song, he felt that someone was coming. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The lotus-picking girls are all beautiful and moving, like the beauty of Wuyue and Chu The princesses and concubines competed to row the lotus-picking boats, and their clothes were wet by the lake water. &lt;br />;Lotus flowers welcomed them into the river mouth when they came, and after picking them, the bright moon sent them back to the riverside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The green skirt of the lotus-picking girl blends into the fields of lotus leaves, as if one color, and the face of the lotus-picking girl contrasts with the blooming lotus. &lt;br />;He disappeared into the lotus pond and only realized someone was coming when he heard singing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Lotus Picking Song: the name of an ancient song. The content mostly describes the scenery of the water country in the south of the Yangtze River and the working and living mood of the lotus picking women. &lt;br />;&quot;Wu Ji&quot; sentence: In ancient times, the three kingdoms of Wu, Yue, and Chu (now the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River and northern Zhejiang) were popular in the drama of picking lotus. Therefore, this sentence says that the lotus picking girls are all beautiful, like the beauty of Wu and Yue, and like the king of Chu. Concubines. &lt;br />;Pu (pǔ)kou: the meeting place of rivers and lakes. Pu, waterside. &lt;br />;Luo skirt: a skirt made of soft and porous silk fabric. One-color tailoring: It seems to be cut from the same color of clothing. &lt;br />;Hibiscus: refers to lotus. &lt;br />;Invisible: It means that you can’t tell which is the green leaves and red flowers of the hibiscus, and which is the red dress of the girl. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first poem describes the lotus-picking activities of girls in the water town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three words Wu Ji, Yue Yan, and Princess Chu are used together to create a scene of lotus girls vying for beauty and beauty. The second sentence is about the activity of picking lotus. Judging from the &quot;fighting about the lotus boat&quot;, it seems to be a competition game of picking lotus. Ruxun of the Tang Dynasty said: &quot;The drama of picking lotus flourished in the Three Kingdoms, so it was promoted together.&quot; (&quot;Explanation of Tang Poetry&quot;) Because he had to row a boat to pick it, he didn&#39;t care about the water getting his clothes wet. The competitive, lively and cheerful mood of the lotus picking girl is expressed through the detail of &quot;wet clothes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They rowed a lotus boat and came to a world of flowers, and the last two sentences pointed out that they did not go back until the moon was over the river. The poet is not in a hurry to write about the return journey, but narrates the situation of the lotus-picking girls. When they came, they were greeted by flowers. It can be seen that the flowers were happy to be visited by them, and there was a hidden layer of writing about their feelings about the activity of picking lotus. I love it very much, almost enjoying it. When they went back, the moon was actually a flower, so they reluctantly sent it to them. &quot;Flowers welcome people&quot; and &quot;moon sends home&quot; use personification techniques to bring the entire lotus-picking activity to life, which is very poetic. The lotus greets the lotus-picking girl and the moon bids farewell to the lotus-picking girl. In fact, it is for expression. The cuteness of the lotus-picking girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem vividly expresses the lively and cheerful character of a lotus-picking girl through several verbs, and uses flowers, moons, boats, and water to set off the woman&#39;s appearance. It can be said that this is A small movie that depicts characters very vividly and has a unique charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second poem can be said to be a &quot;Picture of Lotus Picking&quot;, and the center of the picture is naturally the girls picking lotus. However, the author did not let them appear clearly in this moving picture from beginning to end. Instead, they were mixed in the fields of lotus leaves and bright lotus bushes, looming or absent, making the lotus-picking girl and the beautiful lotus The integration of nature gives the whole poem a unique and beautiful artistic conception that attracts people&#39;s imagination. This kind of artistic conception is unique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The lotus leaf skirt is cut in one color, and the hibiscus is slit to both sides of the face.&quot; At the beginning of the poem, a beautiful picture of harmony and unity between people and the environment is shown. The skirt of the lotus picking girl is as green as the color of the lotus leaves. Although the metaphor is not new, its use here has an unexpected effect. It not only depicts the lotus leaves in the fields, but also writes about the beautiful clothes of the lotus picking girl. The two set off each other and seem to be one. Especially the word &quot;cut&quot; is used very cleverly. The skirt is cut out, but here it is also used on the lotus leaf, which seems to be from He Zhizhang&#39;s &quot;Ode to the Willow&quot; poem &quot;I wonder who cuts out the thin leaves? The spring breeze in February is like scissors.&quot; &quot;I got inspiration from the sentence, which makes people feel that the lotus leaf and the skirt are not only the same color, but also seem to be made of the same material by the same pair of skilled hands. From this, people can&#39;t help but think of Qu Yuan&#39;s &quot;Li Sao&quot; &quot;making lotus flowers to make clothes, gathering hibiscus to make clothes&quot;, and feel the lotus-like souls of these women. The delicate hibiscus flowers seem to be blooming towards the beautiful face of the lotus-picking girl. The lotus is clearly written, but in fact it is to bring out the beauty of people. The beauty of the lotus-picking girl is not the stunning beauty of a woman who is shy of the moon, but is as healthy and warm as the sun. It seems to be able to encourage the lotus flowers in the pond to bloom. These two lines of poetry are originally from the &quot;Jasper Poems&quot; written by Emperor Yuan of Liang Dynasty, &quot;Lotus flowers are in confusion on the face, and lotus leaves are mixed with fragrance in clothes.&quot; Wang Changling&#39;s poem is better and more meaningful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You can&#39;t see anyone entering the pool, but you can only feel someone coming when you hear the song.&quot; The third sentence of the poem, &quot;Invisible in the pool,&quot; is a supplement and in-depth explanation of the first two sentences. It has two meanings: one is to highlight the density of the lotus field, making it more real and credible for people to distinguish the lotus; the other is to highlight the feelings and psychological activities of the spectators. The word &quot;chaos&quot; is used very delicately. The last sentence &quot;I heard someone coming when I heard the song.&quot; In addition to explaining from the other side that the girl is covered and melted by the lotus field, making it difficult for onlookers to see, it also writes a kind of beauty of sound, adding to the lively interest of the poem. The word &quot;Luan&quot; is both It refers to the scene where lotus-picking girls enter the pond one after another, laughing and having fun. It can also refer to the feeling that people and flowers are equally delicate and difficult to distinguish. The feeling of being &quot;invisible&quot; in front of the eyes echoes the above, and also adds to the imagination of the lotus leaf skirt and the human face of hibiscus. At the same time, it also describes the scene of luxuriant flowers and leaves in the lotus pond, with people looming in it, and leads to the following sentence: &quot;When I heard the song, I felt that someone was coming.&quot; This sentence is described in a delicate and subtle way, as if the reader can experience the poet personally. The real feelings at that time. &quot;Begin to awaken&quot; echoes the &quot;invisible&quot; sentence in the previous sentence, and together create an artistic conception of &quot;lotus flowers passing over people&#39;s heads&quot;. &quot;Wen Ge&quot; also echoes the word &quot;Luan&quot;. The melodious and beautiful singing voice shows their lively and cheerful nature, and also adds a touching touch to the whole lotus picking scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem is closely connected with each other and has far-reaching meaning. It is meticulously crafted but gives people a sense of elegance and nature. It can be seen that Wang Changling&#39;s superb skills in refining words and meanings are very important to the poetry of the late Tang Dynasty. has an important impact. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written in the summer of 748 AD (the seventh year of Tianbao reign of Emperor Xuanzong of Tang Dynasty), when Wang Changling was demoted to Longbiao. At that time, Wang Changling had been serving as the captain of Longbiao for some time. Once, Wang Changling was playing alone outside Longbiao City. In the lotus pond of Dongxi, he saw the local chief&#39;s princess, the barbarian girl Aduo, picking lotus flowers and singing in the lotus pond. Deeply attracted by it, he composed &quot;Lotus Picking Song&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wangchangling.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wang Changling (698-756), courtesy name Shaobo, was born in Jinyang, Hedong (now Taiyuan, Shanxi). A famous frontier poet in the prosperous Tang Dynasty, he was known as the &quot;Seven Masters&quot; by later generations. In his early years, he was poor and humble, trapped in farming, but in the third year of his life, he became a Jinshi. He first served as secretary of the Provincial School, and became a scholar and scholar. He was awarded the rank of Sishui Lieutenant. He was demoted to Lingnan due to some affairs. He had close friendships with Li Bai, Gao Shi, Wang Wei, Wang Zhihuan, Cen Shen, etc. At the end of Kaiyuan, he returned to Chang&#39;an and was granted the title of Jiang Ningcheng. He was slandered and relegated to Long Biaowei. An Shi rebellion broke out and he was killed by Lu Qiu Xiao, the governor. His poems are famous for his seven unique poems, especially the frontier fortress poems he wrote when he went to the northwest frontier fortress before he ascended the imperial throne. He is known as &quot;Wang Jiangning, the poet&#39;s master&quot; (there is also the saying of &quot;Wang Jiangning, the poet&#39;s emperor&quot;). &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南安军 | 文天祥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310131]]><description> &lt;h2>;Nan&#39;an Army&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Wen Tianxiang&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Meihua Road North and South, wind and rain wet the clothes. &lt;br />;Who did you go out with when you came out of the mountain? Such a homecoming! (Such a saying: if not)&lt;br />;Mountains and rivers have been there through the ages, but cities have changed for a while. &lt;br />;My ambition is to starve to death, and I pick weeds in my dream. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Walking through Dayuling Pass from south to north, my clothes were wet by wind and rain along the way. &lt;br />;Thinking of the companions I had when I went to Nanling, but when I returned home, I was a prisoner. &lt;br />;The rivers and mountains of the motherland will last for thousands of years, but the city will only fall into the hands of the enemy temporarily. &lt;br />;It is my true wish to die on hunger strike. In my dream, I also imitated Boyi and Shuqi, eating wild vegetables to satisfy my hunger and waiting to die. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Meihua North and South Road: Many plum blossoms are planted on Dayu Ridge, so it is named Meiling. It is bounded by Nanxiong County in Guangdong to the south and Dayu County in Jiangxi to the north. &lt;br />;Plucking Wei: Boyi and Shuqi, sons of Lord Guzhu at the end of Shang Dynasty, when King Wu of Zhou attacked Zhou, they buckled their horses and remonstrated. Shang died and fled into Shouyang Mountain. They swore not to eat millet from Zhou Dynasty, so they picked Wei to eat. ,starve. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two couplets of this poem describe the places and scenery during the trip, as well as the author&#39;s emotions, and express the sorrow of this trip. Feeling. The neck couplet compares the eternal existence of the motherland&#39;s mountains and rivers with the temporary fall of the city, highlighting the poet&#39;s belief in restoring the country of the Song Dynasty and his contempt for the people of the Yuan Dynasty. The tail couplet expresses his attitude: he is determined to starve to death and die for his country, fulfilling his wish of &quot;the first hill&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Meihua North and South Road, wind and rain wet clothes.&quot; Briefly mention the places and scenery on the itinerary. When the author arrived at Nan&#39;an Army, he was crossing the north and south routes of Dayuling (Meiling). The plum blossoms mentioned here are not real scenes, but plum blossoms are mentioned because of Meiling. This is used to contrast with &quot;wind and rain&quot;, which initially shows the heavy mood during the trip. The plum blossoms in Meiling swayed in the wind and rain, soaking the uniforms of the soldiers who were escorting Wen Tianxiang, who was captured after the defeat and went to Dadu for trial. At this time, a burst of ice hit his heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Who did you go out with? Returning home is like never returning home!&quot; Two sentences, the first sentence refers to the loneliness of the journey, but it is written in a questioning tone, which seems particularly sad. The next sentence says that during this trip north, I could have returned to my hometown of Luling, but I was imprisoned and could not be free. Although I passed through my hometown, I felt like I had never returned. These two sentences express the miserable mood during this trip, and the repeated comparison of the two characters &quot;out&quot; and the two characters &quot;return&quot; makes the emotions even more exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mountains and rivers have been there forever, but the city walls have changed for a while.&quot; Wen Tianxiang stood on the ridge, looking at Nan&#39;an Army&#39;s Xihua Mountain and Zhangjiang River in the distance, lamenting that the mountains and rivers will always exist, while the city walls will change from what they were when they left the ridge. The city wall of the Song Army has become a city wall occupied by the Yuan Army, and the flags hanging there will also change accordingly. This sentence is an allusion to Du Fu&#39;s &quot;The country is broken and the mountains and rivers are here&quot; and Ding Lingwei&#39;s &quot;I have been away from home for thousands of years and now I have returned, but the people in the city are still in trouble.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;My true ambition is to starve to death, and I pick weeds in my dream.&quot; The poet Wen Tianxiang would rather go on a hunger strike and starve to death in his hometown than cooperate with the Yuan soldiers. The poet often dreams that he makes a living by picking wild vegetables in Shouyang Mountain like Boyi and Shuqi. This poem uses the story of Boyi and Shuqi. After the fall of the Shang Dynasty, two clan members, Boyi and Shuqi, refused to eat Zhousu millet and fled into Shouyang Mountain, picking wild vegetables to satisfy their hunger. Finally, they starved to death on the mountain. Starting in Guangdong, Wen Tianxiang began a hunger strike, preparing to starve to death in his hometown. After eight days of hunger strike, he continued to eat when he still felt fine. On the night of the first day of October of the same year when Wen Tianxiang wrote &quot;Nan&#39;an Army&quot;, Wen Tianxiang was escorted to Yuandadu and died heroically after being a prisoner for three years, two months and nine days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem uses Du Fu&#39;s poems to express his own mind, show his strong patriotic feelings and show the national righteousness. This poem progresses step by step, with stirring voices and emotions. It does not pretend to be ornamental, but shows its own skill. The author has made great efforts to Du Fu&#39;s poems, and his style is quite similar, that is, he can see the profound temperament in the simplicity. It can be said that it is a work written with blood and tears. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In 1279 AD (the second year of Emperor Xiangxing&#39;s reign), Yashan in the Southern Song Dynasty was captured by the Yuan army and the Song Dynasty was destroyed. Wen Tianxiang was captured the year before and went north. He wrote this poem when he left Dageng Mountains on May 4th and passed through the Nan&#39;an Army (the administrative seat of today&#39;s Dayu, Jiangxi Province). &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wentianxiang.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Wen Tianxiang (1236.6.6-1283.1.9), also known as Lushan and Songrui, named himself Wenshan and was a Taoist from Fuxiu. Han nationality, native of Luling, Jizhou (now Ji&#39;an County, Jiangxi Province), minister, writer and national hero in the late Southern Song Dynasty. In the fourth year of Baoyou&#39;s reign (1256), he was promoted to Jinshi, and became Prime Minister and Privy Envoy. He was sent to the Yuan army&#39;s camp to negotiate and was detained. After escaping the danger, he passed through Jizhuang, Gaoyou, to Tangwan, Tai County, and returned south from Nantong, persisting in resisting the Yuan Dynasty. In the first year of Xiangxing (1278), he was defeated and captured by Zhang Hongfan. He persisted in fighting in prison for more than three years, and then died calmly in Chaishi. He is the author of &quot;Crossing the Lingding Ocean&quot;, &quot;Wenshan Poetry Collection&quot;, &quot;Guide Record&quot;, &quot;Guide Post Record&quot;, &quot;Song of Righteousness&quot; and other works. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 07:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>