<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[悲青坂 | 杜甫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310231]]><description> &lt;h2>;Bei Qingban&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Du Fu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Our army is at Qingban at the east gate, and we drink from Ma Taibai Cave in the cold weather. &lt;br />;Huang Tou Xi&#39;er is heading west on the sun, riding several horses with bows bent and daring to gallop forward. &lt;br />;The mountains, snow, rivers, and ice fields are desolate, and the green is like white bones in the smoke of war. &lt;br />;How can I attach a book to bend our army and wait for next year? Don’t rush. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />; Our army is stationed at Qingban outside the east gate of Wugong County. The weather is very cold and all the soldiers are there. Horses drink in the spring caves of Taibai Mountain. The yellow-headed Xi soldiers were advancing westward every day. Only a few cavalrymen dared to bend their bows and shoot arrows to attack our army. At this time, there was snow on the mountains, ice in the river, and a bleak atmosphere in the wilderness. The green ones are the beacon smoke that raised the alarm, and the white ones are the bones of the soldiers who died in battle. How can we ask someone to bring a message to our army, instructing them to be patient for the time being and wait until next year to counterattack again? Don&#39;t be impatient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;East Gate: refers to the east gate of the county where Qingsaka belongs. &lt;br />;Taibai Grottoes: the main peak of the Qinling Mountains, located in today&#39;s Wugong and Taibai counties of Shaanxi. It is said here that Qingban is located in Taibai Grottoes. The mountains are high and the weather is cold. It is difficult to drink horses and the conditions are extremely difficult. &lt;br />;Huangtou Xi&#39;er: Many of An Lushan&#39;s troops are from Xi and Khitan tribes. &lt;br />;Sunward to the West: Advancing westward day by day. Qingban is west of Chentao. &lt;br />;Chitu: Flying cavalry makes a breakthrough, describing the courage to fight. &lt;br />;Mountain snow and river ice: Snow and ice are both verbs, referring to snow on mountains and frozen rivers. &lt;br />;Wild desolation: refers to the cold wind and howling. &lt;br />;⑧Beacon smoke: beacon fire, a signal of military emergency. &lt;br />;How can I attach a letter? How can I entrust a letter? &lt;br />;Haste: haste. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In the fifteenth year of Tang Xuanzong Tianbao&#39;s reign (756), Fang Guan was defeated in two battles. More than 40,000 people were killed and injured, and only a few thousand remained. people. At this time, Du Fu fell in Chang&#39;an City. When he heard the news, he wrote two poems, &quot;Sorrow for Chen Tao&quot; and &quot;Sorrow for Qingban&quot;. These two poems reflect the fact that the Tang army was defeated. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The words &quot;shuqi&quot; and &quot;dare&quot; in this poem are both tempered words. In just three words, the strength of Anlushan&#39;s rebels and the cowardice of the officers and soldiers were expressed. The sentence &quot;green is the smoke of the beacon fire and white is the bones of the human being&quot; should have been said &quot;green is the smoke of the beacon fire and white is the bones of the human being&quot;. To reduce it to seven sentences, I had to omit the word &quot;yes&quot;. There is a saying in &quot;Tong Google&quot; that &quot;the goose flies in front and the eagle flies behind&quot;. It originally meant &quot;the goose flies in front and the eagle flies behind&quot;. The word &quot;fly&quot; is omitted. There is also a sentence in &quot;Li Chao&#39;s Bafen Xiaozhuan Song&quot; that &quot;Qin had Li Si, Han and Cai Yong&quot;, omitting the word &quot;you&quot;. This kind of syntax is only seen in seven-character ancient poems and is absolutely impossible to find in five-character poems. It is also rare in seven-character rhyme poems. &quot;Green is the white bones of the beacon smoke&quot; is not only a descriptive sentence, but &quot;white bones&quot; is also an exaggeration. The bodies of fallen soldiers were left exposed in the wilderness for at least several months until nothing was left but a pile of bones. Du Fu&#39;s sentence only expresses the scene of &quot;dead bodies everywhere&quot;. He has a poem &quot;Relief from Boredom&quot;, in which there is a couplet: &quot;The jackals block the road and cut off all people, and the beacon fire illuminates the night with corpses.&quot; It is also about the wilderness after the war. It is two ways of writing the same artistic conception as &quot;Green is the white bones in the beacon smoke&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second couplet of this poem describes the strength of An Lushan&#39;s troops, and the third couplet is the aftermath, so it writes about the tragic death of the officers and soldiers. In another poem &quot;Sorrowful Chen Tao&quot; that narrates the same incident, the second couplet describes the officers and soldiers&#39; morale is weak and lacks combat effectiveness; the third couplet is the consequences of this, so it describes the domineering &quot;qunhu&quot;. It can be seen that Du Fu&#39;s artistic method of describing the same event from two different perspectives. The fourth couplet is about the people trapped in Chang&#39;an City and the author&#39;s own thoughts and feelings. After Chen Taoxie&#39;s defeat, the people in Chang&#39;an City were crying bitterly and hoped that the government troops would counterattack again immediately. However, after Qingsaka was defeated again, the people knew that the enemy&#39;s and our own forces were far apart, so they had to give up the idea of ​​&quot;watching the troops day and night&quot;. When Du Fu heard the news of the defeat of the Tang army in Chang&#39;an City, he was very anxious. Instead, we had to imagine asking someone to bring a message to the officers and soldiers, hoping that they would reorganize their forces and counterattack next year. The concluding sentences of these two poems profoundly express the logical changes in the people&#39;s thoughts and feelings towards the officers and soldiers who have experienced repeated successes and failures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Du Shi Jingquan&quot; quoted Shao Zixiang&#39;s comment: &quot;Watching the officers and soldiers day and night, this is the human sentiment; wait patiently for the next year and don&#39;t rush, this is the military aircraft. The reason why this Du is the history of poetry.&quot; This comment , reflecting that Shao Zixiang believed that the two conclusions were contradictory, so he said that the conclusion of &quot;Bei Chen Tao&quot; was the people&#39;s feelings; he said that the conclusion of &quot;Bei Qingban&quot; was that the military situation required it. He thought this could explain the contradiction. In fact, it is specious. You know, &quot;Military aircraft are like this&quot; is also the understanding and emotion of the people in Chang&#39;an City after hearing about the defeat of Qingban. Du Fu wrote about the changes in people&#39;s thoughts and feelings. It is impossible to think that the endings of the two poems are contradictory. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/dufu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Du Fu (712-770), whose courtesy name is Zimei, who calls himself Shaoling Yelao, is also known as &quot;Du Gongbu&quot;, &quot;Du Shaoling&quot;, etc., Han nationality, Fugong County, Henan (now Henan Province Gongyi City), a great realist poet in the Tang Dynasty, Du Fu is respected by the world as the &quot;Sage of Poetry&quot;, and his poems are called &quot;the history of poetry&quot;. Du Fu and Li Bai are collectively known as &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, who are known as &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively known as &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. He was concerned about the country and the people, and had a noble personality. About 1,400 of his poems have been preserved. His poetic skills are exquisite, and he is highly respected in Chinese classical poetry and has far-reaching influence. He lived in Chengdu from 759 to 766, and is commemorated by Du Fu&#39;s Thatched Cottage in later generations. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[六州歌头·东风著意 | 韩元吉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310222]]><description> &lt;h2>;Liuzhou Getou·Dongfeng is interested&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Han Yuanji&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The east wind is interested, first go up to the small peach branch. Red and pink, delicate as drunk, leaning against the red leaf. When I remember the year, I can see the newly painted face, facing the water bank. It is almost half spring, the clouds are warm and the sun is warm, and the inclined bridge turns to the west of the city. The grass is soft and the sand is flat, the horses are crossing with hanging poplar trees, and the jade poles are neighing. Recognize the eyebrows, condense the smiling face, and brush the swallow fat. The embroiderer once peeped and hated Yiyi. &lt;br />;Together we hold hands, the fragrance is like mist, the red color follows every step, and we complain about the late spring. Who can ask about weight loss? Only flowers know, tears fall empty. In front of the old hall, Yan and Yanyu flew together again. People grow old, have good spring, and have good dreams. I visited Liu Lang in the past, and in a romantic place, the flowers should also be sad. But in the dim dusk, with Wuling River as far as the eye can see, it is difficult to trace the past. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The east wind flew up to the small peach branches with affection. The beauty is delicate in pink, charming and charming, leaning against the vermilion door. I remember last year, her new makeup lined her face with hibiscus, which faintly contrasted with the peach blossoms. She came to the water bank, half of spring had passed, the clouds were warm and the sun was melting, and she turned along the inclined bridge until she reached the west side of Jiacheng. The green grass is soft and flat, the horses are running happily, the weeping willows are dancing on the ferry, and Yule&#39;s horses are neighing and galloping to be the first. I recognized her beautiful eyebrows, the smiling face that glanced attentively, and the light rouge on her cheeks. The beauty who once secretly peeped in front of the embroidered window is no longer seen today, and her longing for her is endless. &lt;br />;Where we traveled hand in hand, the peach blossoms were still as fragrant as mist, and the falling red on the ground danced with the steps, resenting that the spring had come to an end. People in Xichun are also losing weight, so who can they rely on to express their condolences? Only the peach blossom knows the heart, and the sky will be filled with clear tears. The swallows that built their nests in front of the old hall flew back to their old homes with the misty spring rain. People who cherish spring are aging in vain, and the spring scenery renewed every year will always be beautiful. I hope that the dream-like good times will come again with spring. Liu Lang is here again. How many traces of the former romantic place are left? Seeing this, the peach blossoms should also feel sad and distressed. I could only see the misty clouds at dusk, the Wuling River was no longer visible, and the past was hard to look back on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Zhuó: carry. &lt;br />;Zhu Fei: Vermilion door. &lt;br />;Suō: grass name, Cyperus rotundus. &lt;br />;Bama: galloping horse. &lt;br />;Yule: A horse title made of jade, also generally refers to a horse. &lt;br />;Mo Mei: This refers to beautiful women. &lt;br />;Xiuhu: refers to a woman’s boudoir. &lt;br />;To save Liu Lang in the past: It is adapted from Liu Yuxi’s poem and Liu Chen and Ruan Zhaoren’s encounter with fairies in Tiantai Mountain. This is the author’s own reference. &lt;br />;Wuling River: Using the story of Tao Yuanming&#39;s &quot;Peach Blossom Spring&quot;, it also alludes to Liu Chen and Ruan Zhao&#39;s troubles. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is titled &quot;Peach Blossom&quot;. It tells a fragrant and sad love story by writing about peach blossom, combining chanting flowers and cherishing people. Combined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The east wind is interested, and it first climbs up the small peach branch. It is red and pink, delicate as drunk, leaning against the red leaf.&quot; The opening chapter is the touching image of peach blossoms. The spring light is bright, the warm wind is blowing, and the little peaches are blooming, handsome and fragrant. &quot;Red and pink, delicate as drunk, leaning against the red leaf.&quot; The author uses people to compare flowers to show the beauty and loveliness of peach blossoms. The blossoming peach blossoms, delicate and delicious, red and fragrant, dazzle the windows. Isn&#39;t this just like a beauty who is covered with pink and white, charming and drunk, leaning against the red door? The word &quot;greasy&quot; highlights the beauty of red, and the word &quot;zui&quot; expresses the charm of Xiaotao. The author&#39;s metaphor is clever and ingenious, but it is also appropriate, natural and precise. Writing in this way not only gives the still life people beauty and vitality, but also pave the way for the following writing by Hua Capture, and then bring out the &quot;time of remembering years&quot; naturally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Remembering the Year&quot; to &quot;Thin-faced Sweeping Swallow Branches&quot; are all memories of the beautiful woman, and the author unfolds the narrative with delicate writing. At that time, the spring was beautiful and warm. The grass was luxuriant and the weeping willows curled up. The poet was riding a horse and inadvertently caught a glimpse of the beautiful lady&#39;s face. On the shore of the water, it was faintly set against the peach blossoms. &quot;Le Zheng hisses&quot;, he stopped and stared. The two sentences &quot;Recognizing the eyebrows and smiling&quot; are the elegant image of a beautiful woman. She has graceful eyebrows, a smile as bright as a flower, a little bit of makeup, and a graceful appearance that makes the author fall in love with her. However, the author suddenly inserted the sentence &quot;The embroidered household once peeked. Hate Yiyi&quot;, which is worth savoring and appreciating. This implies the twists and turns of his love experience with a beautiful woman. &quot;The Embroidered House Peeped&quot; is a picture of him searching for and pursuing a beautiful woman; &quot;Hate Yiyi&quot; describes his lonely mood of missing someone or not being able to fulfill his wish. The author&#39;s words are vague and implicit, which is correct. It coincided with his subtle mood at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next chapter transitions from memories to reality. The three desolate lines of &quot;Hand in Hand&quot; reveal the vast differences between the past and the present. The peach blossoms used to be delicate and beautiful, but now their fragrance is as thin as mist, and their redness fades slowly. They have lost their past beauty and charm, which makes people feel pity for them. The author Bu Nan complains about the late spring because it brings too much sadness. &quot;Those who have lost weight. Who can ask? Only flowers know. Tears are hanging down&quot; is the poet&#39;s embrace at this time. The beauty is gone and the love is far away, but he still persists in reminiscing and becomes haggard in the sorrow of separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The sentence &quot;The Yan in front of the old hall&quot; comes from Liu Yuxi&#39;s &quot;Woyi Lane&quot; of the Tang Dynasty, but the author changed its meaning to highlight not the changes in world affairs of &quot;flying people in ordinary people&#39;s homes&quot;, but &quot;flying together with mist and rain&quot; &quot;The cold loneliness. Swallows can also stay and fly together, inseparable, but people are alone and solitary. The contrast is strong and breathtaking. The three sentences &quot;people grow old&quot; are written in a desolate way. The spring is still good, but people are getting old, and their official career can only be dreamed of. &quot;I lived with Liu Lang before, and my son was promised a romantic place, and he should be sad after his death.&quot; This is a metaphor from Liu Yuxi&#39;s &quot;Revisiting Xuandu Temple&quot;: &quot;The hundred-acre courtyard is half covered with moss, and the peach blossoms are all gone and the cauliflowers are blooming. Where do Taoist priests who grow peach go? &quot;I came here to visit Liu Lang today.&quot; It also contains an allusion to Liu Chen&#39;s return to Tiantai Mountain, once again capturing the peach blossoms and expressing the sorrow and loss of things. After some lingering chanting, the author finally concludes with &quot;But in the vast dusk, my eyes are broken by Wuling River. The past is difficult to recover&quot;, which highlights the theme that the past is sad and the old dream is difficult to continue. The appearance of &quot;Wuling&quot; is not sudden. It is an allusion to Liu Chen&#39;s visit to Tiantai Mountain. He once strayed into Wuling River, and later he was often called &quot;Wuling man&quot;, such as &quot;In the morning, the way back was lost, and the green peach turned to Wuling.&quot; &quot;Stream&quot; (&quot;Melancholy Poems&quot; by Tang Gonghuan), so this is still consistent with the title &quot;Peach Blossom&quot;. The poet has long built a beautiful paradise for his soul, carrying all his dreams, but living in the vast dusk and looking through the Wuling stream, he cannot find the graceful warmth at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem begins with a peach blossom and ends with a peach blossom. The chanting of flowers is intertwined with writing about people. It expresses emotions through borrowing objects and cherishes people through borrowing objects. The emotions are graceful and lingering, and the language is charming and moving. In the poem, the poet&#39;s memories constantly change with the seasons. This writing method of time and space is a major feature of Chinese classical poetry. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In the leap November of the second year of Longxing (1164), Han Yuanji went to Zhenjiang to visit his mother as the new Poyang Shou. At that time, Lu You happened to be Zhenjiang Tong. Judgment. The two of them had known each other for a long time, and when they met in Zhenjiang this time, they visited the country together, drank together, and even sang together. From the leap eleventh month of the second year of Longxing to the first month of Qiandao Kaiyuan, there were a total of 30 songs and poems sung by them, among which this poem was written. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Han Yuanji (1118～1187), a poet in the Southern Song Dynasty. The courtesy name is Wujiu and the nickname is Nanjian. Han nationality, from Yongqiu, Kaifeng (now Kaifeng City, Henan Province), and one from Xuchang (now Henan Province). Han Yuan&#39;s auspicious poems mostly express the feelings of mountains and forests. He is the author of &quot;Jianquan Collection&quot;, &quot;Jianquan Diary&quot;, &quot;Nanjian A and B Manuscripts&quot;, and &quot;Nanjian Poems&quot;. There are more than 80 poems in existence. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:23:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>