<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[江上 | 王安石]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310311]]><description> &lt;h2>;On the River&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Wang Anshi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The autumn clouds in the north of the Yangtze River are half open, and the evening clouds contain rain but linger low. (Wan Yun&#39;s first work: Xiao Yun)&lt;br />;The green mountains are surrounded by no way, and suddenly I see thousands of sails looming. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;North of the river, half of the thick autumn clouds have been torn apart by the autumn wind; The heavy rainy clouds moved slowly. &lt;br />;The green mountains on both sides of the bank were overlapping and twisting, seeming to block the way of the river. The boat turned a corner and saw the endless river again, with white sails on the river gradually approaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Wan Yun: One work is &quot;Xiao Yun&quot;. Low wandering: This refers to thick dark clouds moving slowly. Wandering means &quot;hui&quot;. &lt;br />;Wrap around: rotate in a loop. &lt;br />;Hidden reflection: faintly revealed. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written after Wang Anshi&#39;s one-day trip to the Yangtze River after he resigned and retired to Jinling after the failure of the political reform. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; In his later years, Wang Anshi lived in Zhongshan, Jinling, &quot;reciting poems and talking about Buddhism&quot; (Su Shi&#39;s words), pursuing peace of mind. In line with this, a large number of elegant and delicate quatrains appeared in his creations. In this condensed and light form, he expressed his calm and tranquil mood. This little poem is an example of this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Poems about the scenery seen while boating on the river. I wrote about the autumn clouds, the clouds and the rain, the green mountains and the shadowy sails in the distance. They are all very open and grand objects. However, the artistic realm created by the whole poem is not majestic and heroic, but empty and dim. , the key lies in the word far. The poet took in various distant views to compose his picture. In the sentence &quot;The autumn clouds in the north of the Yangtze River are half open&quot;, after the rain, the sky is clear, the clouds are half open, and a touch of blue sky has brought the glow of the sunset, giving people a distant feeling. The sentence &quot;The evening clouds contain rain but linger low&quot; brings the clouds at dusk to life. &quot;Low wandering&quot; originally refers to people&#39;s wandering and contemplation, but here it is used to express the low and slow movement of rainy dusk clouds, which is full of interest and movement in silence. In these two sentences, the poet outlines a picture of autumn river and dusk clouds. It has the hazy and implicit beauty of Mijia&#39;s landscape. The picture is not bright and clear, but seems to be deliberately pursuing a state of half-light and half-darkness, with divine light coming and going: the gloomy autumn sky is not entirely cheerful but &quot;half-open&quot;. It can be seen that the light is not too bright; the clouds in the evening are not bright and bright, but have a rainy feel. They are not the rolling black clouds before the storm, but they are low and calm, leisurely and quiet. Therefore, remoteness and elegance have become the keynote of this picture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third and fourth sentences move from the clouds to the green mountains by the river. The mountains are tangled and winding, as if they are blocking the poet&#39;s way forward. However, the shadows of sails that flicker in the distance are telling The poet has a long future and endless roads. These two sentences describe the special feelings of traveling by the river. There are not only scenery, but also people in the scenery. There is meaning in the scenery. They contain profound philosophy in the ordinary scenery, which is thought-provoking and thought-provoking. Later, Lu You&#39;s famous sentence &quot;The mountains are poor and the rivers are doubtful and there is no way out, but the willows are dark and the flowers are bright and there is another village.&quot; This is the famous sentence that originated from this. The twists and turns of the green mountains here, and the disappearing and appearing of the sail shadow, also constitute a distant picture, which is integrated with the above two sentences. The deeper meaning of this poem is not to submit to darkness, but to resist darkness. Resisting the darkness can open up the perspective of thousands of sails racing. This is a certain philosophy of life or political philosophy that the poet experienced through the changes in the mountains and waters. Therefore, this poem is based on dialectical thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When Su Shi commented on Wang Wei&#39;s poems and paintings, he said that &quot;there are paintings in poems, and there are poems in paintings&quot;, combining the poetic realm with the artistic conception. The close combination of poetry and painting was perfectly combined in the landscape poetry and paintings of the Tang Dynasty. The landscape pastoral poems of Wang Wei, Meng Haoran and others all have the temperament and charm of painting. The landscape poetry and paintings of the Tang Dynasty focused on the beauty of nature. The landscape paintings of the Song Dynasty emphasized quality and expressed real life through temporal order and layout. Landscape poems also advocated freshness and implication, requiring true feelings to be expressed through objective description. Wang Anshi&#39;s landscape poems grasp this point very well. This poem about a trip to the river lays out a broad picture on a gray background, supplemented by deep brushwork, which is consistent with Mi Fu&#39;s landscape painting techniques, expressing an implicit and hazy beauty. At the same time, the poet expressed his melancholy about the long journey and the changing winds through the description of the scenery, and added subjective thoughts to the landscape poem, enriching the theme of the poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wanganshi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Wang Anshi (December 18, 1021 - May 21, 1086), named Jiefu, nicknamed Banshan, posthumous title, and named Duke of Jing. The world also calls him King Jinggong. Han nationality, a native of Linchuan, Fuzhou in the Northern Song Dynasty (now a native of Dengjia Lane, Linchuan District, Fuzhou City, Jiangxi Province), a famous politician, thinker, writer, and reformer in the Northern Song Dynasty of China, and one of the Eight Great Masters of the Tang and Song Dynasties. Ouyang Xiu praised Wang Anshi: &quot;There are three thousand romantic poems in the Imperial Academy and two hundred years of articles in the official department. I still have self-pity in my old age, and who will compete with my son in the future.&quot; The handed down collections of works include &quot;Wang Linchuan Collection&quot;, &quot;Linchuan Collection Supplements&quot; and so on. He is good at all styles of poetry and prose. Although he does not have many words, he is also good at it. He has famous works such as &quot;Guizhixiang&quot; and so on. The most popular poem by Wang Jinggong is &quot;The spring breeze is green again on the south bank of the river. When will the bright moon shine on me again.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[终风 | 诗经·国风·邶风]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310301]]><description> &lt;h2>;Final Wind&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin Dynasty] The Book of Songs·Guo Feng·Bei Feng&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The final wind is violent, but I will smile when I look after me. Jian Lang laughs at Ao, but the center is mourning. &lt;br />;At the end of the wind and haze, Hui Ran is willing to come. Don&#39;t go there, don&#39;t come back, I&#39;ll think about it for a long time. &lt;br />;The wind is windy at the end of the day, and it will be windy soon. If you don&#39;t want to talk, you won&#39;t sleep; if you want to talk, you will sneeze. &lt;br />;Zhao is its yin, and the scorpion is its thunder. If you don&#39;t talk, you won&#39;t sleep, but if you want to talk, you will be pregnant. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The wind blows all day long, strong and urgent, and sometimes he turns back to me and just smiles A smile. It was all teasing, debauchery, ridicule and arrogance, which made me feel deeply sad and lonely. &lt;br />;The wind is blowing all day long and the rain and mist cover the air. Is he willing to come home happily? This heartless person never comes or goes, leaving me missing him for so long and far away. &lt;br />;The wind has been blowing all day long and the sky is gloomy. It was gloomy the day before yesterday and I felt dizzy for a few days. As soon as I wake up from the dream, it is difficult to fall asleep again. I miss you so much when I catch a cold. &lt;br />;The wind was miserable, the sky was dark and the ground was dark, and the thunder could be heard faintly in the distance. When I woke up from my dreamland, I couldn&#39;t fall asleep again. I couldn&#39;t relieve my sadness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;End: One talks about the end of the day, the other talks about the end. Violent: sudden, violent. &lt;br />;谑(xuè) langxiaiaoao: joking: teasing, teasing. Lang, debauchery. Ao, indulgence. &lt;br />;Center: the heart. It&#39;s mourning: mourning is. Mourning, sadness and fear. &lt;br />;Haze (mái): haze. Turbidity caused by large amounts of smoke and dust suspended in the air. &lt;br />;Hui: Shun. &lt;br />;Don&#39;t go back and don&#39;t come back: don&#39;t interact with each other. &lt;br />;曀 (yì): cloudy and windy. &lt;br />;No sun: no sun. Yes, same as &quot;you&quot;. &lt;br />;寤: Awake. Words: Me. Meng: fall asleep. &lt;br />;Sneeze (tì): sneeze. There is a folk proverb that &quot;when you sneeze, someone thinks.&quot; &lt;br />;曀怀: The sky is dark and dark. &lt;br />;虺 (huǐ): describes the sound of thunder. &lt;br />;Huai: missing. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem has four chapters in total. In a woman&#39;s voice, she was devastated by her husband&#39;s wanton teasing, but after her husband left, she turned to hatred and worried that he would never come back. She had trouble sleeping late at night, hoping that her husband would repent and miss her too. His emotions change again and again, truly conveying the ambivalence of hating and loving, knowing that there is no hope but being unable to let go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first chapter, about entertainment, is written from the perspective of both men and women. &quot;Jie Lang laughs at Ao&quot;, &quot;Lu Shi&quot; says: &quot;Jie means joking. Lang means cuteness. Laughter means joy. Ao means comfort.&quot; Four verbs are used to describe the man&#39;s indulgence and roughness, and his intention is For the joy of the time. &quot;The center is mourning.&quot; mourning means worry and worry. It means that the woman is worried about being abandoned in the future and is focused on the fear of the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second chapter uses &quot;mourning&quot; to describe the woman&#39;s mood after being abandoned. &quot;Hui Ran is willing to come&quot;, the doubtful tone is filled with a woman&#39;s hope; &quot;Don&#39;t go and never come&quot;, the affirmative answer is filled with a woman&#39;s despair. &quot;Longer I&#39;m Thinking&quot; leads to the second level of emotional thoughts, which also leads to the following two chapters in terms of structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third and fourth chapters show the depth of &quot;thinking&quot;. &quot;If you wish to speak, you will sneeze&quot; and &quot;If you wish to speak, you will be pregnant&quot; are written in a tortuous way, which means that the woman imagines whether the man misses her. And when it comes down to men, it corresponds to the story about men having fun in the first chapter. The structure of the whole poem is natural and regular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Each chapter of the poem adopts the expression technique of &quot;comparison&quot;. Inspired by the comparison, the poem shows horrifying scenes such as the rushing wind, flying dust, lack of light from the sun and moon, and the faint sound of thunder, which set off the tragic fate of the heroine and has a strong artistic impact. This is unique among ancient poems about love and marriage. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; Regarding the background of this poem, &quot;Mao&#39;s Preface&quot; believes that it was written when Zhuang Jiang was bullied by Zhouxu, the son of Duke Zhuang&#39;s concubine. Zhu Xi believed that Zhuang Jiang was bullied by his husband, Duke Zhuang of Wei. Modern scholars generally believe that this poem describes a woman&#39;s experience of being teased, ridiculed, and abandoned by her husband. It should come from a folk song and has nothing to do with Zhuang Jiang. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:23:10 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>