<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[春思 | 方岳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231072]]><description> &lt;h2>;Spring Thoughts&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Fang Yue&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The spring breeze is too busy to grow, and the lace willows will grow together for laymen. &lt;br />;Working with swallows and bees to make honey, it rains lightly and then the weather clears. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;How busy the spring breeze is! Always accompanied by red flowers and green willow trees. You warm the earth and provide the soil for swallows to build their nests; you also blow open the flowers in a hurry so that bees can collect nectar and turn it into nectar. The clouds had just blown in and there was a drizzle, then the dark clouds were sent away again, bringing sunny weather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Duoke: How capable it is. &lt;br />;Busy: Busy. Sheng, auxiliary word, unintentional. &lt;br />;With: substitute, help. &lt;br />;Must: Yes. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Song people like to use personification in their quatrains. Poets imagine that nature and everything in nature have emotions like humans, so they can&#39;t help but treat nature as humans and move their emotions into nature. Writing in this way brings a human touch to things that are not originally alive, making them feel friendly and moved. Fang Yue&#39;s poem &quot;Spring Thoughts&quot; adopts this artistic technique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Using an anthropomorphic style and describing the spring scenery, the author enthusiastically praises the vibrant spring breeze. The style of the poem is fresh and does not use allusions. It is personified throughout, full of movement, subtle details, and very charming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Wing Chun Thoughts&quot; does not describe the various thoughts and feelings caused by spring, such as regretting spring, cherishing spring, etc.; it describes the emotions of spring itself. When chanting specifically, the representative of spring - spring breeze was chosen to express it, and the theme of the chant was fixed on the word &quot;busy&quot;. The first sentence is about why the spring breeze is so busy. The poet analyzed that it is because the spring breeze is &quot;many&quot;. With many permissions and willingness to meet the requirements of various objects, Chunfeng is of course &quot;too busy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following three sentences specifically describe the busyness of the spring breeze. In spring, the poet believes that the biggest changes, the first to gain popularity, and the most prominent ones are red flowers and green willows. So the poem writes that the spring breeze has been accompanying Hualiu and served Hualiu wholeheartedly. This sentence is written in plain language, and readers can naturally imagine that throughout the spring, the flowers first sprout leaves, then form stamens, and then bloom into buds, and finally bloom in full bloom, until they fall one after another; think of the willow tree from sprouting and sprouting to ten thousand threads. The green strips danced wildly in the wind, and finally the catkins were flying, and the green shade was thick. During this whole process, the spring breeze is omnipresent and non-stop. This is the &quot;too busy life&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Talking about flowers and willows is, of course, not in isolation, but rather summarizes the role that the spring breeze plays on plants in the entire nature. The next two sentences describe how the spring breeze cares for birds and insects, and the other describes how the spring breeze regulates the climate. The poem says that the spring breeze blows away the cold and thaws the earth, allowing swallows to build nests with mud and raise the next generation. It also blows open the flowers and allows bees to brew sweet honey. It copes with the various needs of nature. It has just arranged a light rain to moisten the earth, and then arranged a sunny day. Writing in such an all-round way highlights the exhaustion of the spring breeze, and the poet&#39;s praise of spring is expressed in subtle ways through the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Spring breeze is originally a very vague and broad concept. Fang Yue organized various images and explained them in a detailed way, which is refreshing. The delicacy and rationality of Song poetry are reflected in this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/fangyue.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Fang Yue (1199～1262), a poet and lyricist of the Southern Song Dynasty. The name is Jushan and the name is Qiuya. A native of Qimen (now part of Anhui). In the fifth year of Shaoding (1232), he became a Jinshi and was awarded the title of Huaidong Appeasement Division Officer. In Chunzhong, Zhao Kui served as the counselor of the Huainan curtain with the official Langguan of the Ministry of Industry. Later, he was transferred to the Nankang Army. Later, he was transferred to Shaowu Army for offending Huguang Commander-in-Chief Jia Sidao. Later we learned that Yuanzhou was impeached and dismissed from office because he offended the powerful Ding Daquan. Later, he was appointed to Fuzhou again, but his appointment was canceled due to old suspicions with Jia Sidao. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[珍珠帘 | 陈祥道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231061]]><description> &lt;h2>;Pearl Curtain&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Chen Xiangdao&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The east wind blows the rain and touches the grass and trees in the air. &lt;br />;I remember that on the day when there was a noise in the three palaces, the bead curtain was half-cast in the sky. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The east wind blew by, the drizzle was thin, and the grass and trees were soaked by the drizzle. &lt;br />;I still remember that it rained for three whole days. The sound of rain came into the palace, and I thought it was a curtain of pearls falling from half the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xianxian: slender appearance; soft appearance. &lt;br />;Suspicious: as if. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chen Xiangdao (1042-1093) was a native of Fuzhou (now Fujian), and Chen Yang was his younger brother. In his early years, he was given the name Youzhi, and later he changed his name to it. He became a Jinshi in the fourth year of Emperor Yingzong&#39;s reign (1067). He served as secretary of the provincial government, corrected characters, and collated Guange. He was a famous Confucian scholar and thinker in the Northern Song Dynasty. He knows almost everything about the classics and history, and is especially good at the Analects of Confucius and the study of rituals. He has written more than ten kinds of classics, but unfortunately only 10 volumes of &quot;Analects of Confucius&quot; and 150 volumes of &quot;Book of Rites&quot; have been handed down to the world. Among them, &quot;Book of Rites&quot; has played a relatively important role in the history of traditional Chinese rituals and culture. academic status and influence. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 07:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>