<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[梦中作 | 欧阳修]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310302]]><description> &lt;h2>;Written in a Dream&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Ouyang Xiu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Playing the flute in the cold night, thousands of mountains and moonlight, the dark road is charming and charming with hundreds of flowers. &lt;br />;After playing chess, I don’t know how people have changed. When I’m in the wine market, I feel helpless and homesick. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The night is as cool as water, the moon covers thousands of mountains, and the lonely sound of the flute drifts into the distance; on the road It was dark, and thousands of flowers were scattered all over the ground, confusing people&#39;s vision. &lt;br />;After playing a game of chess, I discovered that the world has changed, and I don’t know how many years have passed. I have exhausted my drinking to drown my sorrows, and I can’t relieve my deep homesickness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Qianshan: It is said that there are many mountains. Liu Zongyuan&#39;s poem &quot;Jiang Xue&quot; of the Tang Dynasty: &quot;Thousands of mountains and birds have disappeared, and thousands of people have disappeared.&quot;&lt;br />;The sentence &quot;Chess is over&quot;: the story of secretly using Wang Zhi. Liang Renfang of the Southern Dynasty said in &quot;Shu Yi Ji&quot;: During the Jin Dynasty, Wang Zhi went to the mountain to collect wood. When he saw two boys playing chess, he put his ax and watched. The boy gave Wang Zhi something like a date stone. He put it in his mouth and he didn&#39;t feel hungry. After the game of chess was over, the boy urged him to go back. Wang Zhi saw that his ax handle was also rotten. After returning home, all my relatives and friends have passed away and have long since changed their lives. &lt;br />;Jiu Lan: It means that the wine feast is about to end. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem describes what was seen in a dream and is contained in Volume 12 of &quot;Ji Shi Ji&quot;. The original annotations of the two poems before and after it are marked as 1049 AD. Year (the first year of Emperor Renzong of Song Dynasty), it may have been written at the same time. At that time, the author was demoted to Yingzhou for supporting the Qingli New Deal led by Fan Zhongyan. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is about a dream. The dream is hazy, confusing and full of mystery. The theme is not easy to grasp. What the poet expresses here is a tortuous and complex feeling. , seems to imply the poet&#39;s ideological contradiction of wanting to be born in the extraordinary world but also being very nostalgic for the human world. The whole poem is one sentence at a time, each of which is independent, depicting four different artistic conceptions of autumn night, spring night, chess game, and wine court. It is like four single-axis paintings, but they are completely natural; Seamless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first sentence describes the scenery of a quiet night. From the words &quot;cool&quot; and &quot;moon&quot;, we can tell that the time is around autumn. A bright moon illuminates the mountains near and far like daylight. The author plays the flute in the cool night and the silence. The surrounding environment seems particularly peaceful. The three words &quot;Moon over Thousand Mountains&quot; are already spacious, giving people a sense of exquisiteness and clarity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second sentence depicts another realm. &quot;The road is dark&quot; indicates that the time is also at night, and &quot;hundred kinds of flowers&quot; are mentioned below, which means that the season at this time is changed to spring when hundreds of flowers are blooming. The road here is dark and the flowers are abundant. The scenery of the spring night is so confusing, just like the scene of writing poems in a dream. These two sentences have a hazy artistic conception and meaningful language, which set off the next two sentences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third sentence uses a legend to describe the changes in the world. Ren Fang of the Liang Dynasty said in &quot;Shu Yi Ji&quot;: During the Jin Dynasty, Wang Zhi went to the mountain to collect wood. When he saw two boys playing chess, he put his ax and watched. The boy gave Wang Zhi something like a date stone. He put it in his mouth and he didn&#39;t feel hungry. After the game of chess was over, the boy urged him to go back. Wang Zhi saw that his ax handle was also rotten. After returning home, all my relatives and friends have passed away and have long since changed their lives. This sentence reflects the author&#39;s transcendence from the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last sentence of the poem describes the mood of drinking, and homesickness arises spontaneously. It shows that although the poet wants to be detached, he cannot forget his feelings in the world, which is consistent with what Su Shi said in &quot;Shui Diao Ge Tou&quot; &quot;I want to ride on the wind.&quot; When I go back, I am afraid that the beautiful buildings and jade buildings will be too cold at high places.&quot; The mood is similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the four-line poem describes four different artistic conceptions, they form a harmonious unity, implying the poet&#39;s contradictory thoughts of wanting to transcend time and space while still lingering on the human world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Poetry expresses ambition&quot;. By the end of the poem, the meaning gradually becomes clear. The poet&#39;s depression and trance were related to his political frustration at that time. When Ouyang Xiu wrote this poem, he was still in Yingzhou and had not yet been reused by the imperial court. So these four sentences express the emotions in my heart. The beauty of them is that they do not express these emotions directly. This kind of implicit technique requires careful observation to understand its true meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another characteristic of this poem is that the antitheses are ingenious and seamless, with the front and back couplets facing each other. This is influenced by Du Fu&#39;s poem &quot;Queju&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/ouyangxiu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Ouyang Xiu (August 6, 1007 - September 8, 1072), courtesy name Yongshu, nicknamed Zuiweng, late nicknamed Liuyi Jushi, was born in Yongfeng, Luling, Jizhou, Jiangnan West Road ( A native of Yongfeng County, Ji&#39;an City, Jiangxi Province today, he was born in Mianzhou (now Mianyang City, Sichuan Province) in the fourth year of Jingde (1007). He was a politician and writer in the Northern Song Dynasty. Ouyang Xiu became a Jinshi in the eighth year of Tiansheng&#39;s reign (1030) of Renzong in the Song Dynasty. He served in Renzong, Yingzong and Shenzong dynasties, reaching Hanlin bachelor&#39;s degree, deputy envoy to the privy council, and participating in political affairs. After his death, he was given many gifts to the Grand Master and Duke of Chu, and was given the posthumous title &quot;Wenzhong&quot;. In his later life, he was called Ouyang Wenzhong Gong. Ouyang Xiu was the earliest literary leader to create a generation of literary style in the literary history of the Song Dynasty. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan, Su Shi, Su Xun, Su Che, Wang Anshi, and Zeng Gong, he was known as the &quot;Eight Great Masters of the Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan, and Su Shi, he was known by later generations. Together they are known as the &quot;Four Masters of Eternal Articles&quot;. He led the poetry innovation movement in the Northern Song Dynasty and inherited and developed Han Yu&#39;s ancient prose theory. His high achievements in prose creation complemented his correct ancient prose theory, thus creating a generation of writing style. While Ouyang Xiu changed his writing style, he also innovated the style of poetry and poetry. In terms of history, he also has high achievements. He once majored in &quot;New Tang Dynasty&quot; and wrote &quot;New History of the Five Dynasties&quot;. There is &quot;Ouyang Wenzhong Gongji&quot; handed down from generation to generation. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[夏日绝句二首·其二 | 姚鼐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310291]]><description> &lt;h2>;Two Summer Quatrains·Part 2&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Yao Nai&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The tall trees on the wall are green and the sky is green, and the remaining flowers are gone but the cicadas are not noisy. &lt;br />;Watching the clouds as the afternoon passes, several birds sing in front of the wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The big trees beside the stone wall towered into the sky, dyeing the sky green. The flowers bloom and fade accompanied by the cicadas chirping. &lt;br />;Close the book in the afternoon and watch the shadows of the trees move, and hear the sound of wind and birdsong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Close the book: close the book. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/yaonai.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Yao Nai (nài) (1731-1815) was a famous essayist in the Qing Dynasty. He was known as the &quot;Three Patriarchs of Tongcheng&quot; together with Fang Bao and Liu Dakui. The courtesy name is Ji Chuan, the other name is Meng Gu, and his room name is Xibao In the 28th year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1763), he became a Jinshi and served as director of the Ministry of Rites and compiler of Sikuquanshu. At the age of forty, he resigned and returned to the south. He successively gave lectures at academies in Yangzhou Meihua, Jiangnan Ziyang, Nanjing Zhongshan and other places for forty years. for many years. He is the author of The Complete Works of Xibao &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:23:10 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>