<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[题榴花 | 韩愈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310271]]><description> &lt;h2>;Inscribed on pomegranate flowers&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Han Yu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;In May, the pomegranate flowers illuminate the eyes, and the seeds are beginning to appear among the branches. &lt;br />;It&#39;s a pity that there are no carriages and horses here, and the moss is upside down and the flowers are falling. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The fiery pomegranate flowers in May are particularly vivid and can be seen between the branches and leaves. To the first small fruits. &lt;br />;It&#39;s a pity that no dignitaries came here to appreciate it, so the gorgeous pomegranate flowers had to be scattered on the moss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Shining: still dazzling. Describes the brightness or luminosity of an object. &lt;br />;Occasionally: common. Zi: refers to pomegranate. &lt;br />;Pity: What a pity. &lt;br />;No carriages and horses: No dignitaries came to enjoy the scenery in carriages or horses. &lt;br />;Inverted: spinning and flipping, with multiple fingers and a confused mind. &lt;br />;绛(jiàng): bright red. &lt;br />;Jiangying: This refers to the pomegranate petals falling to the ground. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two sentences of this poem point out the season and outline the lush and brilliant scene in May when the pomegranate flowers bloom; the last two sentences point out the location. , indicating that no one is visiting the pomegranate flowers so that the beautiful scenery is lonely and scattered, euphemistically expressing the poet&#39;s lonely mood. The whole poem describes the fresh and natural scenery, and embodies the philosophy of life in the description of the objective scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In May, pomegranate flowers illuminate your eyes, and you can always see the beginning of growth among the branches.&quot; Two sentences point out the season, and a few words outline the lush and brilliant scene of pomegranate flowers in May, especially The three words &quot;illuminate the eyes&quot; are vivid and expressive. The poet not only wrote about flowers, but also about the happy mood of people who look at them. The last two sentences indicate the location. This is a pomegranate that grows in a remote place. No one climbs or breaks its flower branches to damage it. The bright red pomegranate flowers fall on the moss in large numbers. The red and green contrast with each other. The picture is very beautiful, making people feel how cute it is. and regret. In fact, the poet loves it because no tourists come to admire it, and he loves the &quot;moss&quot; and &quot;red flowers&quot; all over the ground. If someone comes to admire it, it will be trampled under the ruts and horse hooves. It is better to let the flowers bloom and fall, and the fruits are ripe and rotten. Naturally, it euphemistically expresses the poet&#39;s lonely mood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two sentences of this poem describe the scenery, and the last two sentences express feelings. The author does not describe the scenery directly, but uses people&#39;s feelings to highlight the gorgeousness of the pomegranate flowers. But no matter how beautiful the flowers bloom, they still fall silently. The poet laments that no one comes to appreciate the flowers, which is a metaphor for a friend who is full of talents, but is relegated to a remote place by the ruler and unable to display them. The word &quot;inverted&quot; is even more so. It effectively criticizes the rulers&#39; ignorance of talents and the resentment of poets and authors who have not been recognized for their talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem describes the scenery as fresh and natural, from which we can see the poet&#39;s rich interest and thoughtful and rich literary thoughts. However, the sudden changes in poetic meaning and description are all contained in sentences that seem to be light and heavy in reality, making the poetic meaning suddenly become deeper, and also showing the changing characteristics of &quot;hills and hills are uneven&quot; in writing. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was titled at Zhang Shiyi’s Hotel, and the specific time of creation is unknown. Zhang Shiyi is a good friend of the author. When the author wrote this poem, both Zhang Shiyi and he were demoted. The poet wrote this poem because of his feelings. In &quot;Poems of a Thousand Families&quot;, the author of this poem is Zhu Xi in the engravings of the past dynasties, which has been erroneously corrected by later generations. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/hanyu.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Han Yu (768-December 25, 824), also known as Tuizhi, was a native of Heyang, Henan (now Mengzhou City, Henan Province). He claimed to be his &quot;ancestral home in Changli County&quot; and was known as &quot;Han Changli&quot; in the world. &quot;Mr. Changli&quot;. A minister in the mid-Tang Dynasty, a writer, thinker, politician, and the son of Secretary Lang Han Zhongqing. In the twelfth year of Yuanhe (817), he served as prime minister Pei Du and marched to Sima to quell the &quot;Huaixi Rebellion&quot;. He bluntly remonstrated with the Buddha&#39;s bones and was demoted to be the governor of Chaozhou. With the ups and downs of the officialdom, he moved to the Ministry of Officials and became a minister, known as the &quot;Han Officials Department&quot;. In the fourth year of Changqing (824), Han Yu died of illness at the age of fifty-seven. He was given the posthumous title &quot;Wen&quot; by the Minister of Rites, so he was called &quot;Han Wen Gong&quot;. In the first year of Yuanfeng (1078), he was granted the title of Uncle of Changli County and worshiped in the Confucius Temple. As an advocate of the ancient prose movement in the Tang Dynasty, Han Yu ranked first among the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot; and was known as &quot;The Great Master of Articles&quot; and &quot;The Master of Literature for a Hundred Generations&quot;. Together with Liu Zongyuan, he is known as &quot;Han Liu&quot;, and together with Liu Zongyuan, Ouyang Xiu and Su Shi, he is known as &quot;the four great writers through the ages&quot;. He advocated writing theories such as &quot;the unity of literature and Taoism&quot;, &quot;the words are powerful and the words are appropriate&quot;, &quot;the things are more important than the statements&quot;, and &quot;the words are consistent with the words&quot;, which have guiding significance for future generations. He is the author of &quot;Collection of Han Changli&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新年作 | 刘长卿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310261]]><description> &lt;h2>;New Year&#39;s Work&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Liu Changqing&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The heart of my country is full of new year, and the sky is alone with tears. &lt;br />;When you grow old, you live among others, and when you return in spring, you come first. &lt;br />;The mountains and apes share the same day and night, and the rivers and willows share the wind and smoke. &lt;br />;Already like Changsha Fu, a few years from now. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;As the New Year approaches, I feel homesick especially, and I can’t help crying when I think of myself wandering abroad. &lt;br />;When I get old, I am relegated to other places and live below others. Even spring walks in a hurry before me. &lt;br />;In the morning and evening in Lingnan, you can only stay with the apes and monkeys, or bear the wind and smoke with the willows by the river. &lt;br />;I have suffered the same fate as Jia Yi, who was demoted to Changsha Taifu. I wonder how many years will it take before he can return home? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Tianbian: Tianbian refers to Panzhou Nanba, which is now Maoming, Guangdong. &lt;br />;游(shān) Ran: the look of crying. &lt;br />;Below others: Refers to officials, who are below others. &lt;br />;Ke: The poet refers to himself. &lt;br />;Ling: refers to five ridges. The author was demoted to Nanba in Panzhou and passed this ridge. &lt;br />;Changsha Fu: refers to Jia Yi. He was once slandered and demoted to the position of Prince Taifu of Changsha. Here he uses it as a metaphor for himself. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem is a New Year&#39;s song written by the author after he was demoted to Nanba Lieutenant. In the spring of 758 AD (the third year of Emperor Suzong&#39;s reign in Tang Dynasty), the author was demoted from Suzhou Captain to Nanba Lieutenant in Panzhou (now Maoming City, Guangdong Province). This poem was written the year after moving to Panzhou, that is, the second year of Qianyuan (759). &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; In the Tang Dynasty, the area south of Changsha was very desolate. The hardships in Panzhou can be imagined. The poet was wronged and demoted. The beautiful Suzhou in Jiangnan was moved to the remote Panzhou, and the grievances are self-evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;My hometown is full of nostalgia for the new year, and the sky is alone with my tears.&quot; These two sentences mean that the New Year is here, and I am thousands of miles away from my relatives, so my homesickness is naturally even more intense. &quot;Hometown&quot; refers to the feeling of homesickness; &quot;New Year&quot; refers to the New Year. During the festive season, the poet&#39;s homesickness becomes more urgent and uncontrollable when he misses his relatives more than ever. &quot;Tianpan&quot; refers to the horizon, here refers to Lingnan; &quot;moaning&quot; refers to the appearance of tears; being alone in a foreign land and on the New Year, how can a poet who is homesick not feel sad and shed tears? The words &quot;cut&quot; and &quot;lone&quot; at the beginning set the emotional tone of loneliness and sorrow in the whole poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When you grow old, you live under others, and when you return in spring, you come first&quot; is derived from Xue Daoheng&#39;s &quot;When people return after the wild geese, their thoughts are in front of the flowers&quot;. It is integrated into the simple homesickness of the predecessors and is integrated into the officialdom. The sense of life experience expands the capacity and enhances the thickness of emotion. &quot;Old&quot; and &quot;living under others&quot; are the poet&#39;s self-expression; the word &quot;to&quot; is full of the bitterness of losing time in old age and the grief and indignation of frustrated career: he was upright and upright, but he ended up being framed and living under someone else&#39;s roof! The sad feeling is even more painful when expressed plainly; &quot;guest&quot; refers to the poet himself; &quot;spring returns&quot; means spring returns to the earth and hometown, which is personified; the word &quot;Xian&quot; expresses envy: if only I could be like spring Same, it would be great to return to my hometown early! There are even more complaints: I am still wandering at the end of the world, why does spring return first? Frustrated in old age, spring has returned to oneself, which is the reason for the poet&#39;s &quot;randomness&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two sentences &quot;Apes in the mountains share the same day and night, rivers and willows share the wind and smoke&quot; describe the scenery of the barren mountains and rivers on the horizon. The cry of apes accumulates sad poetic images. &quot;Ling Yuan&quot; refers to the apes in the mountains of Lingnan; &quot;Dan Du&quot; refers to morning to evening; &quot;Wind Smoke&quot; refers to the morning breeze and evening mist; the words &quot;Tong&quot; and &quot;Gong&quot; describe the poet&#39;s loneliness and confusion. Yi&#39;s miserable state: exiled in a foreign land, can only associate with heartless animals, can only associate with indifferent plants, the apes in the mountains mourn, the rivers and willows are confused, even if they have all kinds of worries, where can they talk about it? The misery he encountered and the confusion of his uncertain future are all in the scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Already like a master in Changsha, how many years will it take from now?&quot; Here I borrow an allusion from Jia Yi. Jia Yi, a talented man from Luoyang, had the ambition to help the world and the country. For Changsha Taifu. When the poet was demoted this time, it was because of his fault that he had failed. He was depressed and lamented, and sometimes expressed: &quot;The earth is far away and the Mingjun abandons it, and the sky is high and the cruel officials bully him&quot; (&quot;First Demotion from Nanba to Poyang, Inscribed on Li Jiayou Jiangting&quot;), so Jia Yi is quoted as the same tune. , and there is a feeling of &quot;similarity&quot; of &quot;the same people who have fallen into the world&quot;. However, since he disobeys the powerful family and worries that he will never be able to return, he will inevitably have the worry of &quot;how many years from now on&quot;. At this point, the poet craned his neck to look at Chang&#39;an in the distance, his heart returning, and his lingering back seemed to be right in front of him; he seemed to be able to hear deep sighs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Any poem that describes a scene and expresses emotions is always very particular about the choice of words. Either one sentence describes the scenery and one sentence expresses emotion, or one sentence describes both scenery and emotion, or the first couplet describes the scenery and the last couplet describes the emotion. This poem has more sad elements, so it has more lyrical sentences. The first two lines are about feelings, the third lines are about sceneries, the fourth lines are about scenes and feelings, the fifth and sixth lines are about feelings arising from the scene, and the seventh and eighth lines are about lyrical feelings. Among them, &quot;New Year&quot; refers to scenery, and &quot;Several Years&quot; refers to love. The infinite sorrow of separation is vividly displayed on the paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emotion of the poem is profound and sorrowful, the couplets are full of emotions, and there are sighs from beginning to end. Only the neck couplet describes the scene, which is light and dense but not brilliant, and the mood is pathos. The whole poem has a deep structure, with the style of &quot;the threads are lingering and continuous, the taste is connoted and the purpose is strengthened by chanting&quot; (Lu Wenzhao&#39;s words). In terms of his character, he belongs to the Dali family, showing signs of sudden decline. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/liuchangqing.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Liu Changqing (zhǎng) (709-789), courtesy name Wenfang, Han nationality, from Xuancheng (now Anhui), was a poet of the Tang Dynasty. Later he moved to Luoyang, where he became the county commander in Hejian (now part of Hebei Province). He was a Jinshi during the Tianbao reign of Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty. Su Zong served as the imperial censor in De Zhongguan, the county captain of Changzhou County in Suzhou, and the transfer envoy judge in Daizong Dali. After knowing that Huaixi and Eyue were transferred to stay, he was falsely accused and demoted to Sima Muzhou again. He was relegated twice because of his stubbornness. During the Jianzhong period of Dezong, he was appointed governor of Suizhou and was known as Liusuizhou in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:23:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>