<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[摽有梅 | 诗经·国风·召南]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310252]]><description> &lt;h2>;There are plum blossoms&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin Dynasty] The Book of Songs·Guofeng·Zhaonan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;There are plum blossoms there, but they are actually seven. I beg you, a common man, for good luck. &lt;br />;There are plum blossoms, but they are actually three plum blossoms. I beg you, a common man, to be like today. &lt;br />;There are plum blossoms, and they are scattered in baskets. Ask me, a common man, to call him. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The plums fell to the ground one after another, but 70% was still left on the tree. &lt;br />;If you want to ask to marry my son, please don’t waste your time. &lt;br />;The plums are falling to the ground one after another, and only 30% of the branches are left. &lt;br />;I want to marry my son, but don’t wait any longer. &lt;br />;The plums fall to the ground one after another, and you need to use a dustpan to clean them up. &lt;br />;If you want to ask to marry my son, please speak up quickly without any further hesitation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;潽(biào): fall. &lt;br />;There are: auxiliary words. &lt;br />;Seven: A non-real number. The ancients used seven to ten to express more, and three or less to express less. Or 70%, that is, there are still 70% of the plums that have not fallen on the tree. &lt;br />;Shu: numerous. &lt;br />;Shi: an unmarried man. &lt;br />;訨 (dài): to take advantage of. &lt;br />;Ji: Good days. &lt;br />;Today: now. &lt;br />;Qing basket: A shallow basket with a slanted mouth, just like today’s dustpan. &lt;br />;勡 (jì): One means taking, the other means giving. &lt;br />;Predicate: One talks about gathering; the other talks about speaking. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a tactful and bold courtship poem. &quot;Plum Blossoms&quot;, as the first sung by the ancestors, is simple and fresh, clear and affectionate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poetic purpose, poetic technique and customary background of this article have been basically outlined by predecessors. &quot;Preface to Mao&#39;s Poems&quot; says: &quot;&quot;There are Plum Blossoms&quot;, men and women are in time. The country of Zhaonan was transformed by King Wen, so men and women can be in time.&quot; The four words &quot;men and women in time&quot; have already stated the purpose of the poem; the following words are The scribe&#39;s attachment should be omitted. &quot;Zhou Li·Mian Shi&quot; says: &quot;In the month of mid-spring, men and women are ordered to meet. At this time, those who run can&#39;t help it. If you do not use the order without reason, you will be punished. Men and women who do not have a husband&#39;s family will be reunited.&quot; Understand. This marriage custom of our ancestors makes it easy to understand this urgent and bold courtship poem. Chen Huan gave a concise explanation of the ingenious parallelism in this chapter: &quot;The plum blossoms grow and decline, just like the age of men and women. The plum blossoms and the match have the same sound, so the poet gets excited when he sees the plum blossoms&quot; (&quot;Shi Mao&quot;) &quot;Shi Chuan Shu&quot;). Gong Cheng&#39;s &quot;Original Meaning of Poetry&quot; said that &quot;&quot;Plum Blossoms&quot; means a son-in-law is anxious.&quot; The word &quot;urgent&quot; captures the emotional tone of this poem and also reveals the melody and rhythm of the whole poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are three chapters in the whole poem, three encounters with &quot;common men&quot;. &quot;庶&quot; means many; &quot;庶士&quot; means many young men. It can be seen that this girl has not found her lover yet. She is searching, urging, and calling for love from the entire male world. Youth is priceless, but time is fleeting. &quot;True youth, the youth of chaste young age, the youth whose whole body is filled with fresh blood, whose body is light and inviolable, only lasts a few months&quot; (&quot;Rodin&#39;s Theory of Art: Female Beauty&quot;). Nowadays, the plums are yellow and ripe, the wedding period is coming to an end, and there is still no husband to be found, which cannot help but make people anxious. The passage of youth is compared with the falling plum blossoms. &quot;In fact Qi Xi&quot;, &quot;In fact three Xi&quot;, and &quot;Qingwang Zhuanzhi&quot; have declined from luxuriance; this is also reminding the &quot;common people&quot; over and over again: &quot;Flowers can be broken and must be broken; don&#39;t wait until there are no flowers to break.&quot; .&quot; The worry of &quot;no flowers and empty branches&quot; in Tang Dynasty&#39;s &quot;Golden Thread Song&quot; seems to be deeply rooted in the legacy of &quot;Plum Blossoms&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Judging from the subjective mentality of the lyrical protagonist, &quot;urgency&quot; means that youth is passing away and a husband is not found. Judging from the artistic structure of the poem, &quot;Ji&quot; means &quot;Ji&quot; is repeated in three chapters and pressed one step at a time. Repeating chapters and singing is the basic structure of the Book of Songs. However, from the perspective of poetic expression, there are two different forms, namely the emphasis on chapters and the step-by-step approach. &quot;Plum Blossoms&quot; belongs to the step-by-step process of heavy chapters. The three chapters are repeated, but they are pressed one by one, vividly and powerfully showing the protagonist&#39;s urgent psychological process. The first chapter, &quot;It&#39;s auspicious to come&quot;, still has the meaning of treating each other calmly; the second chapter, &quot;It&#39;s coming now&quot;, already shows the anxious feeling of urging; in the last chapter, &quot;It&#39;s said to be true&quot;, it can be said that the true feelings are revealed and we can&#39;t wait. . After three repetitions, hearing the sound is like seeing a person. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; According to the records of &quot;Zhou Li Matchmaking Style&quot;, in the pre-Qin Dynasty, in the Zhaonan area, every mid-spring, the local matchmaker would let Wei Married young people go on a tryst. This poem should be a song sung by young women in collective carnivals such as March 3rd, where men and women meet freely. The purpose is to attract the attention of the opposite sex and find a tryst partner. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 05:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[芙蓉池作 | 曹丕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310251]]><description> &lt;h2>;Hibiscus Pond Zuo&lt;/h2>;[Wei and Jin Dynasties] Cao Pi &lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>; took a chariot at night and walked leisurely in the West Garden. &lt;br />;The two canals irrigate each other, and the beautiful trees go around the river. &lt;br />;The humble branches brush the feather cover, and the pruning strips touch the sky. &lt;br />;The wind blows, and the birds fly before me. &lt;br />;The bright moon is sandwiched between the Danxia clouds, and the Chinese star emerges from the clouds. &lt;br />;The sky is filled with light, and the five colors are so fresh. &lt;br />;Who can win the immortality except Song Qiao? &lt;br />;Wandering makes your mind happy, and you will protect yourself for a hundred years. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;When you get out at night, take a carriage and come to the West Garden for a stroll. &lt;br />;Two canals have watered the garden, and beautiful trees surround the canals. &lt;br />;The short branches sweep the feather cover, and the slender branches stretch into the blue sky. &lt;br />;The strong wind pushed the wheels from behind the car and flew away, while the birds circled happily in front. &lt;br />;A bright moon rises in the red clouds, and stars flash in the sky. &lt;br />;The beautiful light hangs from the sky, how fresh the colors are! &lt;br />;We are not Chisong or Ziqiao. Who can live longer than a cultivator? &lt;br />;It’s a pleasure to play like this, and maybe it will keep me alive for a hundred years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Furong Pond: a scene in the Bronze Bird Garden in Yecheng (now Linzhang, Hebei Province). Tongque Garden is located in the west of Yecheng. It is named after the Tongque Terrace. It is Cao Cao&#39;s royal garden. Hibiscus means lotus. &lt;br />;Chaan (niǎn): the car used by emperors and concubines. Travel: One word is &quot;Wandering&quot;. &lt;br />;Irrigation: one means &quot;irrigation&quot;. &lt;br />;Jiamu: refers to the lush and beautiful forest trees. Tongchuan: water flow in the garden. This sentence says that trees are planted densely along both sides of the river in the garden. &lt;br />;Bizhi: low-hanging tree branches. Whisk: Gently pass over. Feather cover: A hood decorated with feathers. &lt;br />;Repair: long. MO: Contact. &lt;br />;Jingfeng: A strong wind caused by a speeding car. Hub (gǔ): The log in the center of the wheel, connected to one end of the spokes around it. There is a round hole in the middle for inserting the shaft. This &quot;hub&quot; refers to the axle head of the wheel. &lt;br />;Danxia: sunset glow, red. &lt;br />;Hua Xing: A star that shines with brilliance. &lt;br />;Xiutian: from the sky down. &lt;br />;The five colors: green, red, yellow, white, and black were regarded as the correct colors in ancient times. This refers to the many colors of the rainbow. Yihe: How. &lt;br />;Songqiao: Chisongzi and Prince Qiao are two legendary immortals. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two sentences indicate the time and place of the tour and swimming pool, and describe the joyful mood of taking a night tour of the West Garden. The word &quot;night&quot; highlights the poet&#39;s strong interest in traveling and is also the basis for the description of the scenery in the following text. &quot;Walking in the West Garden&quot; also expresses the poet&#39;s relaxed and happy mood at that time. It is precisely because of this carefree journey that the scenery described below is so pleasing to the eye and intoxicating. &quot;West Garden&quot; is where Furong Pond is located, where poets often gather. Cao Zhi&#39;s poem &quot;Public Banquet&quot;: &quot;The prince respects his guests and is tireless all night long. He travels to the West Garden in the clear night, followed by flying canopies.&quot; That is to say, he writes about them There is a joyous scene here day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ten sentences in the middle continue the revision of the article, writing about what was seen during the trip, linking &quot;night travel&quot; and &quot;freedom&quot;, and focusing on describing the beautiful and moving night scene of Furong Pond. &quot;Double canals irrigate each other, and beautiful trees flow around the river&quot;, which always describes the elegance of the situation and environment here. Then the two sentences &quot;Bizhi&quot; are used to describe Jiamu in detail: Dense and verdant trees grow around the canal, setting off each other. The lower branches and leaves grow horizontally, blocking the road, and the repairers cover the sky and the sun, reaching to the cloud surface. Later, he continued to write about what he saw during the trip and the pleasant feeling at that time with &quot;The trembling wind turned the wheel, and the birds flew before me&quot;. All living and inanimate objects seemed to be vying for the poet&#39;s arrival. The trembling wind The breeze seems to be supporting the poet&#39;s chariot, and the flying birds seem to be leading the way for the poet. The leisurely and contented mood is vividly displayed in the paper repair. Because it is a night tour, the beautiful scenery of Furong Pond is not described in detail here. Instead, the outline of the Furong Pond is outlined with thick lines and uses a combination of movement and stillness to express a beautiful artistic conception and show the infinite vitality of Furong Pond. The last four sentences turn to write about the beauty of the night sky. A bright moon is embedded in the colorful sunset, and the crystal stars in the sky appear and disappear between the clouds, twinkling and shining, forming a colorful picture. In this elegant and picturesque scenery, the poet has simply been placed in a fairyland and forgotten his own existence. He unconsciously sighed, &quot;The sky is shining with brilliance, and the five colors are so fresh.&quot; These sentences use bright colors to depict the night scene of Furong Pond in a bizarre and colorful way, which shows a major feature of his creative creations. This is consistent with his emphasis on &quot;poetry is about beauty&quot; in &quot;Classics and Essays&quot;. Liu Zhen&#39;s poem &quot;Public Banquet&quot;: &quot;The chariots and chariots are flying with plain covers, and the entourage is full of people on the roadside. The moonrise illuminates the garden, and the precious trees are lush and green. The Qingchuan flows through the stone canal, and the flowing waves are fish protection.&quot; The scenery written is similar to this poem. , but the use of diction is much inferior to this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last four sentences, the pen turns and writes about the feelings of traveling. &quot;Song&quot;, Chisongzi, the legendary Yan Emperor Shennong Shiyu Master, later became an immortal together with the Yan Emperor girl. &quot;Qiao&quot;, Prince Qiao, is the Prince of Zhou Ling and Prince Jin. It is said that he likes to play the sheng to make the phoenix sing. Later, the Taoist priest Fuqiu Gong took over to cultivate Songshan and became an immortal. Cao Pi has never believed in the fairy alchemists. In his &quot;The Walking of the Willows&quot;, there is a sentence &quot;Wang Qiao&#39;s false words, and the red pine trees hang empty words.&quot; It&#39;s not believable. Therefore, he reminds us of the fact that no one can truly become a god in the real world, and expresses his desire to enjoy himself in this picturesque scenery, make his body and mind happy, and seek longevity. &quot;Wandering makes your mind happy, and protecting yourself for a hundred years&quot; is a plain and optimistic attitude. This association further contrasts the beauty of the scenery of Furong Pond and the endless fun of visiting the garden, which made the poet so intoxicated that he never wanted to leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the banquet poems of the Jian&#39;an period, this one can be said to be the most outstanding. Its series of characteristics, such as the increase in scene descriptions, the use of antithetical sentences, the gorgeous rhetoric, and the spectacular scenery, all reflect some important changes in the poetic style at that time. Therefore, it has special merits in the history of poetry. The poem spends most of its space describing garden scenery, which also had an influence on later garden poetry and landscape poetry. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In the 16th year of Jian&#39;an (211), the 16th year of Emperor Xian of the Han Dynasty, Cao Pi was appointed as a lieutenant general with five sense organs, established an official office, and became deputy prime minister. The whole world admires you, and there are like clouds of guests. At that time, a group of scribes gathered in Yecheng, the base camp of Cao Wei, forming the Ye literati group with him as the core. Cao Pi was the leader, Cao Zhi was an important member, and most of the &quot;Seven Sons of Jian&#39;an&quot; participated. On their free days, they feasted, traveled, sang and composed poems. This poem is believed to have been written when Cao Pi was appointed Wu Guan Zhonglang General or a few years later. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/caopi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Cao Pi, Emperor Gaozuwen of Cao Wei (winter 187 - June 29, 226), courtesy name Zihuan, was a famous statesman and writer during the Three Kingdoms period and the founding emperor of Cao Wei. He reigned from 220 to 226 AD. . During his reign, border troubles were quelled. Defeat Xianbei, repair with Xiongnu, Di, Qiang and other foreign barbarians, and restore the Han Dynasty&#39;s establishment in the Western Regions. In addition to military affairs, Cao Pi was fond of literature since childhood and made achievements in poetry, fu, and literature. He was especially good at five-character poems. Together with his father Cao Cao and his younger brother Cao Zhi, he was also known as the Three Caos. There are two volumes of &quot;Collection of Emperor Wen of Wei&quot;. In addition, Cao Pi authored &quot;Classics&quot;, of which &quot;Thesis&quot; is the first systematic literary criticism monograph in the history of Chinese literature. After his death, he was given the temple name Gaozu (as Shizu in &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot;), posthumous title Emperor Wen, and was buried in Shouyang Mausoleum. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 04:23:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>