<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[渡黄河 | 宋琬]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239272]]><description> &lt;h2>;Crossing the Yellow River&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Song Wan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;It only takes a moment for the Milky Way to pour down. &lt;br />;There are more winds and dangers in the world, and talking about the Yellow River is a daunting journey. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;I often hear that the Milky Way has diarrhea. It is difficult to tell whether it is true or not. Now I see it. The Yellow River can turn into turbid waves in an instant. &lt;br />;The storms in the world are more dangerous than this, but people say that the dangerous path is only in the middle of the Yellow River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Pour down the Milky Way: Water in the Milky Way pours down. &lt;br />;For a moment: all of a sudden. &lt;br />;Translate: say instead. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In 1661 AD (the 18th year of Shunzhi), Song Wan was accused by his tribe of being in contact with Yu Qi, the leader of the rebel army, and his family members were searched. He was escorted to Beijing by car. He was released from prison after three years and spent another eight years in disgrace. During this period, he had a profound understanding of the recurrence of human relationships and the dangers of the world. This poem was written after Wan of the Song Dynasty was released and returned home. He suffered a great setback in his life in his later years, so he also used the opportunity to cross the Yellow River to sing a tragic song generously. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two sentences of this poem describe the turbid waves of the Yellow River rushing to the sky, and use the hope of the Milky Way in the sky as a foil to describe its danger; the last two sentences say Human feelings are more dangerous than the turbid waves of the Yellow River, so we should not say that the Yellow River is a dangerous road. This poem uses the technique of contrast to express the understanding of social life. It is very profound. It contains feelings of sorrow for the world, poverty, sorrow, loneliness and anger. The poem style is mature and the writing is strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two sentences say that once people come to the shore of the majestic Yellow River, which flows thousands of miles away, they will inevitably be frightened by the mysterious legend that it &quot;flows down the Milky Way&quot;. The poet has great contempt for such people who are hesitant and timid. Of course, there is some danger in crossing the Yellow River, but it is just a matter of enduring the &quot;turbulent waves&quot; that can shake the sky &quot;for a moment&quot;. In the eternal time and space, human life is just like a small boat in the dangerous peaks of the rapids: when the huge waves of life crash down overwhelmingly, no one can foresee it in advance, and no one can know how long this disaster will last. . Song Wan was once a poet with a rare reputation. He was a high school scholar in his early years. When he was an official, he also benefited a lot from politics and was deeply loved by the people. But he didn&#39;t want to be framed, so that he would be &quot;immediately arrested and imprisoned&quot; and &quot;taken as a wife&quot;. During the three years of imprisonment, he almost suffered unexpected disasters. It is no wonder that he would use the topic of &quot;crossing the Yellow River&quot; to sigh heavily that &quot;the world is more dangerous.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last two sentences describe the turbulent Yellow River. The ancients did not know its origin and thought it was caused by the Milky Way in the sky turning upside down. Therefore, there is a saying that &quot;the water of the Yellow River comes from the sky&quot;. It has sky-shaking waves, but it doesn&#39;t take long to get over it. The risk of rough waves is very short-lived, and you can usually get through it. The real risk is in the human world. Ordinary people in this dangerous world are accustomed to a life of intrigues, intrigues, rampant wolves, darkness, evil, and conscience-killing. They are not aware of its dangers. Instead, they say that the dangers and waves of the Yellow River are the most terrifying and they dare not cross it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Song Wan believed that the poet was in poverty and had a &quot;gloomy&quot; feeling in his heart, so he was prone to &quot;generous tragic songs&quot;. (&quot;Preface to Dong Langshi&#39;s Poems&quot;) The Yellow River is a dangerous path in nature, but no matter whether it &quot;waters down the Milky Way&quot; or &quot;raises the turbid waves in the sky&quot;, in the eyes of the poet, compared with the path of life that is full of intrigues and conflicts, All insignificant. The poet uses a contrasting technique to express his understanding of social life, which is very profound. It contains feelings of sorrow for the world and sounds of poverty, sorrow, loneliness and anger. The poem style is mature and the writing force is strong, which shows one aspect of his poetic style. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/songwan.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Song Wan (1614-1674) was a famous poet in the early Qing Dynasty and one of the eight great poets of the Qing Dynasty. The courtesy name is Uncle Yu, the nickname is Lishang, Han nationality, and a native of Laiyang (now Shandong). In the fourth year of Shunzhi, he became a Jinshi and was appointed as the head of the household department. He moved to Yongping Bingpu Road and Ningshaotai Road. Because of a long-standing regret, the clan&#39;s son falsely accused him of conspiring with Wen and was imprisoned for three years. For a long time, he got Bai and lived between Wu and Yue. He found an envoy in Sichuan. Wan poetry entered the houses of Du and Han, and was as famous as Shi Runzhang. He had the purpose of Southern Shi and Northern Song Dynasty. Together with Yan Hang, Shi Runzhang, Ding Peng, etc., he was collectively known as the Seven Sons of Yantai. He was the author of &quot;Anya Tang Ji&quot; and &quot;Er Xiang Ting Ci&quot; 》. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[春思 | 方岳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239271]]><description> &lt;h2>;Spring Thoughts&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Fang Yue&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The spring breeze is too busy to grow, and the lace willows will grow together for laymen. &lt;br />;Working with swallows and bees to make honey, it rains lightly and then the weather clears. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;How busy the spring breeze is! Always accompanied by red flowers and green willow trees. You warm the earth and provide the soil for swallows to build their nests; you also blow open the flowers in a hurry so that bees can collect nectar and turn it into nectar. The clouds had just blown in and there was a drizzle, then the dark clouds were sent away again, bringing sunny weather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Duoke: How capable it is. &lt;br />;Busy: Busy. Sheng, auxiliary word, unintentional. &lt;br />;With: substitute, help. &lt;br />;Must: Yes. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Song people like to use personification in their quatrains. Poets imagine that nature and everything in nature have emotions like humans, so they can&#39;t help but treat nature as humans and move their emotions into nature. Writing in this way brings a human touch to things that are not originally alive, making them feel friendly and moved. Fang Yue&#39;s poem &quot;Spring Thoughts&quot; adopts this artistic technique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Using an anthropomorphic style and describing the spring scenery, the author enthusiastically praises the vibrant spring breeze. The style of the poem is fresh and does not use allusions. It is personified throughout, full of movement, subtle details, and very charming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Wing Chun Thoughts&quot; does not describe the various thoughts and feelings caused by spring, such as regretting spring, cherishing spring, etc.; it describes the emotions of spring itself. When chanting specifically, the representative of spring - spring breeze was chosen to express it, and the theme of the chant was fixed on the word &quot;busy&quot;. The first sentence is about why the spring breeze is so busy. The poet analyzed that it is because the spring breeze is &quot;many&quot;. With many permissions and willingness to meet the requirements of various objects, Chunfeng is of course &quot;too busy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following three sentences specifically describe the busyness of the spring breeze. In spring, the poet believes that the biggest changes, the first to gain popularity, and the most prominent ones are red flowers and green willows. So the poem writes that the spring breeze has been accompanying Hualiu and served Hualiu wholeheartedly. This sentence is written in plain language, and readers can naturally imagine that throughout the spring, the flowers first sprout leaves, then form stamens, and then bloom into buds, and finally bloom in full bloom, until they fall one after another; think of the willow tree from sprouting and sprouting to ten thousand threads. The green strips danced wildly in the wind, and finally the catkins were flying, and the green shade was thick. During this whole process, the spring breeze is omnipresent and non-stop. This is the &quot;too busy life&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Talking about flowers and willows is, of course, not in isolation, but rather summarizes the role that the spring breeze plays on plants in the entire nature. The next two sentences describe how the spring breeze cares for birds and insects, and the other describes how the spring breeze regulates the climate. The poem says that the spring breeze blows away the cold and thaws the earth, allowing swallows to build nests with mud and raise the next generation. It also blows open the flowers and allows bees to brew sweet honey. It copes with the various needs of nature. It has just arranged a light rain to moisten the earth, and then arranged a sunny day. Writing in such an all-round way highlights the exhaustion of the spring breeze, and the poet&#39;s praise of spring is expressed in subtle ways through the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Spring breeze is originally a very vague and broad concept. Fang Yue organized various images and explained them in a detailed way, which is refreshing. The delicacy and rationality of Song poetry are reflected in this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/fangyue.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Fang Yue (1199～1262), a poet and lyricist of the Southern Song Dynasty. The name is Jushan and the name is Qiuya. A native of Qimen (now part of Anhui). In the fifth year of Shaoding (1232), he became a Jinshi and was awarded the title of Huaidong Appeasement Division Officer. In Chunzhong, Zhao Kui served as the counselor of the Huainan curtain with the official Langguan of the Ministry of Industry. Later, he was transferred to the Nankang Army. Later, he was transferred to Shaowu Army for offending Huguang Commander-in-Chief Jia Sidao. Later we learned that Yuanzhou was impeached and dismissed from office because he offended the powerful Ding Daquan. Later, he was appointed to Fuzhou again, but his appointment was canceled due to old suspicions with Jia Sidao. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>