<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[九歌·湘夫人 | 屈原]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231131]]><description> &lt;h2>;Nine Songs·Mrs. Xiang&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Qu Yuan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The emperor&#39;s son descended to Beizhu, his eyes dim and worried. &lt;br />;The autumn wind is blowing, and the waves are flowing under the wooden leaves in the Dongting. (Niao Niao&#39;s first work: Niao Niao)&lt;br />;Climb the white weeds and look forward to the beautiful scenery. &lt;br />;Why are the birds gathering among the apples, and why are the weeds gathering on the trees? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are zhi in the garden and orchids in the river. I miss the young master but dare not speak. &lt;br />;Looking far into the desolate landscape, watching the murmuring water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why does the elk eat in the garden? Why is the Jiao descended from the water? &lt;br />;In the morning, my horse rides towards Jianggao, and in the evening, my horse comes to Xixi. &lt;br />;I heard that the beautiful woman came to call me, and I will fly away together. &lt;br />;The house is built in the water, and the lotus cover is used to repair it. &lt;br />;A purple altar is placed on the wall, and a hall is built with fragrant peppers. &lt;br />;Guidong is decorated with orchids, and Xinyi lintel is located at the pharmacy. &lt;br />;The curtains are made of plucked flowers, and the curtains are stretched. &lt;br />;The white jade is the town, and the sparse rocks are the orchids. &lt;br />;The lotus house is full of flamboyance, and Du Heng is the dizzying place. &lt;br />;The real courtyard is filled with hundreds of grasses, and the veranda gate is fragrant and fragrant. &lt;br />;Nine Yis come together to welcome you, and the spirits come like clouds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Donate the remaining clothes in the river, and leave the remaining mattresses in Lipu. &lt;br />;If you visit Du Ruo in Tingzhou, you will leave behind those who are far away. &lt;br />;The time cannot come suddenly, and it is easy to talk freely. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Mrs. Xiang landed on Beizhou, looking far into the distance. I feel melancholy. &lt;br />;The trees are swaying gently, the cool autumn breeze is coming, the waves are rising in the cave, and the leaves are falling. &lt;br />;Stepping on the white weeds, looking around, meeting the beautiful lady tonight. &lt;br />;Why do birds gather in water plants? Why are the fishing nets hung on the treetops? &lt;br />;The grass of Yuanshui is green and the orchids of Lishui are fragrant. I miss Mrs. Xiang but I dare not say it openly. &lt;br />;Looking into the distance in a daze, I saw only the river flowing slowly. &lt;br />;Why do elk forage in the yard? Why are dragons wandering near the water? &lt;br />;In the early morning I rode my horse along the river bank, and in the evening I crossed to the west side of the river. &lt;br />;I heard that Mrs. Xiang is calling me, and I will drive with her. &lt;br />;I want to build my house in the middle of the water, and put lotus leaves on the roof. &lt;br />;Sungrass decorates the walls, purple clams pave the courtyard. The walls are sprinkled with peppers to decorate the hall. &lt;br />;Cinnamon trees make the pillars, magnolia trees serve as the rafters, Xinyi trees decorate the door lintels, and Angelica dahurica flowers decorate the bedrooms. &lt;br />;The curtains are made of weaving sedge, and the canopy made of split cypress has been put up. &lt;br />;The town mats are made of white jade, and stone orchids are displayed everywhere to create a fragrant fragrance. &lt;br />;Cover the lotus house with rhizome grass and wrap it with duheng in all directions. &lt;br />;Gather all kinds of flowers and plants to fill the courtyard and build a fragrant porch. &lt;br />;All the gods from Jiuyi Mountain came to welcome Mrs. Xiang, and they crowded around her like clouds. &lt;br />;I threw the sleeves into the river, and I threw the unlined garment by the Lishui River. &lt;br />;I am picking Du Ruo on the small island, and will use it to give gifts to girls far away. &lt;br />;The wonderful time is rare, I am just wandering around leisurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Nine Songs: The collective name of Qu Yuan’s eleven works. &quot;Nine&quot; refers to a general term, not a real number. &quot;Nine Songs&quot; is originally the name of an ancient piece of music. Wang Yi&#39;s &quot;Chapter of Chu Ci&quot; believes: &quot;In the past, in the city of Nanying in the Chu Kingdom, between Yuan and Xiang, the people believed in ghosts and loved temples. In their temples, they would compose songs and music to encourage the gods. Qu Yuan was exiled and lurked in his territory. Worry is poisonous, melancholy and thoughts are boiling, and I see the common people offering sacrifices, singing and dancing, and their words are crude. Because they are composed in the song &quot;Nine Songs&quot;, the upper part expresses the respect of God, and the lower part shows the injustice done by oneself, and entrusts it with the wind. Remonstrance.&quot; Some people think that Qu Yuan made it based on folk sacrificial songs. There are many disputes about who Mrs. Xiang and Jun Xiang are. There is no doubt that the two are the gods of the Xiang River. &lt;br />;Emperor’s son: refers to Mrs. Xiang. Concubine Shun was the daughter of Emperor Yao, so she was called the emperor&#39;s son. &lt;br />;眇燇(miǎo): the appearance of not being able to see. &lt;br />;Chou Yu: Makes me sad. &lt;br />;Niao Niao (niǎo): endless appearance. &lt;br />;Wave: generate waves. whereabouts. &lt;br />;薠(fán): a kind of aquatic autumn grass. To look: to look across one&#39;s eyes. &lt;br />;Jia: beautiful lady, refers to Mrs. Xiang. Period: Period. Zhang: Furnishings. &lt;br />;Collection: collection. Birds are supposed to be gathered on trees, but they are said to be among water plants. &lt;br />;羾(zēng): net for fishing. Originally it was supposed to be in the water, but instead it was said to be on a tree. It is a metaphor for not being able to get what you want and losing its proper place. &lt;br />;Yuan: Yuanshui, in today’s Hunan Province. Li (lǐ): Lishui, in today&#39;s Hunan Province, flows into Dongting Lake. Zhi (zhǐ): Angelica dahurica, a kind of herb. &lt;br />;Gongzi: refers to Mrs. Xiang. In ancient times, nobles were called dukes, and children of nobles could be called &quot;gongzi&quot; regardless of gender. &lt;br />;Huanghu: Indistinct appearance. &lt;br />;Gurgling: The appearance of water flowing. &lt;br />;Elk: The name of the animal, like a deer. &lt;br />;Water Origin: Waterside. This name means that the dragon should be in the abyss and not near the water. A metaphor for an abnormal situation. &lt;br />;Gao: highland by the water. &lt;br />;澨 (shì): waterside. &lt;br />;Tengjia: driving a horse-drawn carriage at full speed. Pass away together: go together. &lt;br />;Repair: Weave straw to build a house. Cover: refers to the roof. &lt;br />;Sun wall: Decorate the wall with sun grass. Sun (sūn): a kind of herb. Purple: Purple shell. Altar: Atrium. &lt;br />;Pepper: a kind of fragrant wood. &lt;br />;Dong: House building, roof spine. &lt;br />;毑 (lǎo): roof rafter (chuán). &lt;br />;Xinyi: The name of the tree, the flowers rise in early spring. Lintel: the beam above the door. Medicine: Angelica dahurica. &lt;br />;罔: Connect the &quot;net&quot; to resolve knots. Xili; a kind of herb that grows on trees. Curtain: Curtain. &lt;br />;擗 (pǐ): break apart. Hui: a kind of herb.拋(mián): partition fan. &lt;br />;Town: A thing that suppresses sitting. &lt;br />;Sparse: divided into sparse, divided into Chen. Shilan: a herb. &lt;br />;Liao: winding. Duheng: a kind of vanilla. &lt;br />;He: gather together. Baicao: refers to many fragrant grasses. Real: substantial. &lt;br />;Xin: A fragrance that can be smelled from afar.庑(wǔ): Corridor. &lt;br />;Jiuyi (yí): the name of the mountain, the legendary burial place of Shun, in the south of Xiangshui River. This refers to the Jiuyi Mountain God. Bin: Shengduo looks like. &lt;br />;Spirit: God. Ruyun: describes many things. &lt;br />;袂(mèi): Sleeves. &lt;br />;褋(dié): &quot;Dialect&quot;: Zen clothes, called &quot;褋&quot; among Jianghuai and Southern Chu. Zen clothes are women&#39;s underwear and are a token given by Madam Xiang to Lord Xiang. This was the custom of women&#39;s love life in ancient times. &lt;br />;Ting: flat land in or near water. Duro: a kind of herb. &lt;br />;Far away: refers to Mrs. Xiang. &lt;br />;Suddenly: obtained several times, obtained repeatedly. &lt;br />;Xiaoyao: Play. Yongyu: leisurely look. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Nine Songs·Mrs. Xiang&quot; is one of the eleven poems in the &quot;Chu Ci·Nine Songs&quot;. It is dedicated to the goddess of Xiangshui. Poetry is a companion piece to &quot;Nine Songs of Xiangjun&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem describes the feelings of longing and sorrow that the King of Hunan feels when he waits for Mrs. Hunan but does not come. The poem is written in the tone of Mr. Xiang missing Mrs. Hunan, depicting the kind of longing and longing for Mrs. Xiang. Come, the melancholy of looking forward to but not seeing. The whole poem describes a man&#39;s lovesickness, and the emotions expressed are lingering and pathos; in addition, the work absorbs the straightforward lyrical style of folk love songs and uses traditional comparison techniques, which further strengthens its artistic appeal and has a great impact on later generations of literary creation. Big impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first sentence, &quot;The emperor&#39;s son descended to Beizhu&quot; is more difficult to understand. &quot;Emperor&#39;s son&quot; has always been interpreted as the daughter of the Emperor of Heaven, and was later attached to mean the two daughters of Yao, but there is no doubt that it refers to the goddess of Xiangshui. This sentence is generally said to mean that the emperor&#39;s son has arrived in Beizhu, which is derived from &quot;Xiang Jun Xiang Beizhu&quot; in &quot;Xiangjun&quot;; but this is inconsistent with the whole article that Xiangjun expected her to come but did not see her. The content is inconsistent. So some people interpreted this sentence as an invitation from King Xiang (see Zhan Antai&#39;s &quot;Qu Yuan&quot;), so that the meaning of the text becomes smoother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first paragraph of the poem writes that Mr. Xiang has been wandering on the shore of Dongting Lake for a long time with pious expectations, longing for the arrival of Mrs. Xiang. This is a picture with a very thought-provoking environment and atmosphere: the cool autumn wind is blowing constantly, the water in Dongting Lake is rippled, and the leaves are falling on the shore. Mr. Xiang, who looked over the autumn water and saw no beauty, hesitated and scratched his head. Sometimes he came to see her off, and sometimes he made arrangements. However, things went against his expectations, and Mrs. Xiang still didn&#39;t come until dusk. This situation has been compared to the abnormal phenomenon of &quot;how do birds gather among apples, and why do weeds hang on trees?&quot;, which further highlights the disappointment and confusion that fills the characters&#39; hearts, and the meaning of futility and futility. . Among them, &quot;The autumn wind is blowing, and the waves in the Dongting are under the wooden leaves&quot; is a famous sentence that describes the scenery. It is very effective in exaggerating the atmosphere and mood, so it was deeply appreciated by future generations of poets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Based on this, the second paragraph further deepens Xiangjun&#39;s desire. Using the herbs by the waterside to evoke the silent yearning for the beautiful woman, and using the slow flow of water to hint at the passage of time in the distance, this is a typical artistic technique of pre-Qin poetry. Its advantage is that the characters are related to each other and the scene is unified. Very contagious. The following two anomalous phenomena are the moose eating in the atrium and the dragon stagnating by the water. Like the previous description of the bird and the net, they are also metaphorical metaphors, once again emphasizing that love without seeing is contrary to the wish. Then the same as Mrs. Xiang. In the anxiety of waiting for a long time, he also rode horseback to search from morning to night. The result was slightly different from Mrs. Xiang: in his eager search, he suddenly had the idea of ​​hearing the beauty&#39;s call and riding with her. The illusion of driving away. So the work has the following most imaginative and romantic touch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third paragraph is purely about the scene in Mr. Xiang’s fantasy of meeting Mrs. Xiang as he wished. This is a dazzling and magical world: the courtyards built in the middle of the water are decorated with exotic flowers, exotic plants and fragrant trees. Its colors and fragrance are unparalleled. The work lists more than ten kinds of plants in one go, such as lotus, sunflower root, pepper, cinnamon, orchid, magnolia, medicine, sage, cymbidium, stone orchid, peony, and Duheng, to express the beauty of the meeting place. Its purpose is to use the radiant external environment to set off and reflect the joy and happiness that fills the characters&#39; hearts. Therefore, when the gods of Jiuyi Mountain came to pick up Xiangjun&#39;s lover, he suddenly realized that he woke up from this dream-like beauty and fell into the pain of lovesickness again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last paragraph and the ending of &quot;Xiangjun&quot; not only have the same number of sentences, but also the exact same sentence structure. In despair, Mr. Xiang was as emotional as Mrs. Xiang, and abandoned each other&#39;s gifts to the river and the bank, but his apparent determination could not suppress his inner love. He finally regained his composure, and planned to go through the difficult psychological journey of falling in love and missing each other with patient waiting and expectation. He picked the fragrant Du Ruo on Tingzhou and prepared to give it to Mrs. Xiang who came from afar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of emotional structure, this poem responds to the &quot;expectation horizon&quot; in a &quot;calling way&quot;. Since &quot;Madame Xiang&quot; is a song to welcome the gods, it must be a way of summoning to pray for the coming of the gods. The whole poem starts with summoning Mrs. Xiang to come, and the mentality of expectation runs through it. The first half of the poem mainly describes Mr. Xiang&#39;s expectant mood when he misses Mrs. Xiang but cannot see her and misses her. In the process, he experienced emotional fluctuations such as sadness, regret, regret, and trance. These are the emotional turmoil caused by unfulfilled expectations. The second half of the poem describes how Mr. Xiang was overjoyed when he learned that Mrs. Xiang was coming as promised. He was busy preparing for the wedding in the anticipation of meeting her but not yet. At the end of the poem, the Hunan lady appears, and the purpose of the summons is achieved, making the previous series of expectant descriptions echo this. In fact, the description in the second half is just Xiangjun&#39;s fantasy state. The emergence of this illusory state is also due to eager expectations. The entire poem describes the process of expectation, with beginnings, contradictions, developments, highs, lows, and lulls. The lines of consciousness are clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem also has a double-layered structure of light and dark. The protagonist&#39;s emotional expression is both light and dark, a combination of light and dark. Lyrical objects can be both literal and symbolic. When describing the real situation, the protagonist&#39;s emotions are superficial, with clear meaning, clear instructions, clear language, clear emotional color, high and low, strong and weak, all in a transparent state. For example, the second half of the poem describes the scenes of building a room, building a church, decorating the bridal chamber, decorating the facade, and welcoming guests. It is superficial, that is, written clearly. From &quot;Building a room in the water&quot; to &quot;Building a sparse stone with fragrance&quot;, it goes from the outside to the inside, from big to small; from &quot;Building a house with lotus flowers in it&quot; to &quot;Building a veranda with fragrance and fragrance&quot;, it goes from the inside to the outside again . The lines are clear, the facts are clear, the emotional catharsis is explicit, it is a way of showing the heart, hearty, unrestrained, less implicit, and the flow of emotions is synchronized with the external form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking at the deep structure, this poem also has an expression that combines emotion with scenery. The scenery is not its original appearance, such as &quot;where is the bird&quot;, &quot;where is the dragon&quot;, &quot;where is the moose&quot;, &quot;where is the dragon&quot;, etc.; or the scenery is emotional, such as the description of autumn wind, autumn water, and autumn leaves. The flow of emotion is more subtle, subtle, and deep, like the undercurrent of the seabed, which is difficult to detect. Therefore it needs to be understood through surface imagery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This double-layer structure, with light and dark corresponding to each other, complements each other, forming a state of blending of scenes. The advantage of this structure is that it can increase the capacity of emotion and make the expression of emotion three-dimensional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, the objects described and the language used in the whole poem are all Chu-style, with distinctive local characteristics of Chu. Such as Yuanshui, Xiangshui, Lishui, Dongting Lake, Angelica dahurica, Dahurica, Dahurica, Du Heng, Xin Yi, Gui, Hui, lotus, elk, birds, white jade and other natural landscapes, animals, plants and minerals, and more The folk customs, myths and legends, unique romantic color, religious atmosphere, etc. of Chu region all have the distinctive characteristics of Chu region. The house architecture and furnishings conceived in the poem are very distinctive and are based on the natural environment, social customs and cultural and psychological structure of the Chu region. Otherwise, this conception would not be possible. The language also has the characteristics of Chuhua. A large number of dialects and idioms are used in Chu Ci, and &quot;Madam Xiang&quot; is no exception, such as &quot;洴&quot; (verb), &quot;袂&quot;, &quot;褋&quot; (noun), etc. The most prominent thing is the extensive use of the word &quot;xi&quot; - there is a word &quot;xi&quot; in every line of the poem. This modal particle is equivalent to the word &quot;ah&quot; spoken today. Its function is to adjust the syllables, increase the transitions and jumps in semantics and tone, and enhance the expressiveness of the language. &quot;Mrs. Xiang&quot; is mainly written in dialect, with five or seven dialects included. The sentence structure is flexible. This kind of &quot;Sao style&quot; poetry is a new free verse that appeared after the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;. It is a remarkable innovation in the history of the development of ancient Chinese poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To sum up, &quot;Xiang Jun&quot; and &quot;Xiang Madam&quot; are two tragedies caused by the time error of a date, but together they are a scene of two people in love and loyalty. Yu&#39;s comedy. They are said to be tragedies because both parties missed the meeting time and were unable to extricate themselves from missing each other, and their hearts and emotions suffered for a long time. They are said to be comedies because they are in love with each other. Sincere and profound, despite slight setbacks, they have not given up their pursuit and expectations, so it is only a matter of time before a happy ending appears. When they finally meet each other after waiting patiently and calmly for each other, the misunderstanding and troubles caused by first coming, first arriving will inevitably disappear in an instant, and what will greet them will be the joy and happiness that Xiangjun felt in his hallucination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One of these two works is about a woman&#39;s love, and the other is about a man&#39;s lovesickness. They take different angles, but the lyrical meaning is equally lingering and pathos; in addition, the work absorbs the straightforward lyrical method of folk love songs and traditional The use of Bixing techniques further strengthens their artistic appeal. Therefore, although this kind of passionate, bold, sincere and persistent love is wrapped in the shell of religious rituals, it itself has a strong core of life, but it continues to release infinite energy, allowing readers and authors of all ages to learn from it. Continuously gain great motivation to pursue ideals and love without fear of hardships. This can be best confirmed by the countless pieces of history that have been deeply influenced by subsequent generations. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; It is generally believed that Mrs. Xiang is the female god of Xiangshui River, and she and Xiangjun, the male god of Xiangshui River, are the consort gods. The Xiangshui River is the largest river unique to Chu State. The pair of gods, Lord Xiang and Lady Xiang, reflect the ideology of primitive people worshiping natural gods and the concept of &quot;love between gods and humans&quot;. Chu folk literature and art has a strong religious atmosphere, and the altar is actually a &quot;drama altar&quot; or a &quot;literary altar&quot;. Take &quot;The King of Xiang&quot; and &quot;Mrs. Xiang&quot; as an example: when people sacrifice to King Xiang, they play the role of female singers or worshipers to welcome King Xiang; Mrs. Xiang, everyone expresses their deep love and affection. They use gods as objects to entrust the simple and sincere love in the world; at the same time, they also reflect the harmony between the people of Chu and nature. Because the Xiang River that irrigates Southern Chu has a flesh-and-blood relationship with the people of Chu, she is like a loving mother, nurturing the people of Chu from generation to generation. People place deep love on the Xiangshui River and regard the Xiangshui River as a river of love and happiness, thus personifying the description of the Xiangshui River. The images of gods also play out stories of joys and sorrows like those of humans, and the gods in people&#39;s minds are specifically cast in the shadow of historical and legendary figures. Lord Xiang and Lady Xiang are based on the legend of Shun and his two concubines (Ehuang and Nvying). In this way, the image of God is not only richer and more vivid, but also more emotionally close to people in real life, making people feel approachable and humane. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the title of the poem is &quot;Mrs. Xiang&quot;, the protagonist in the poem is King Xiang. The main theme of this poem is to describe the life and death of lovers, who have no fate to meet. The work always uses the clue of waiting for the person who does not come, expressing deep resentment to the other person in the confusion, but it is consistent that the love between them remains unswerving. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; It is generally believed that Mrs. Xiang is the female god of the Xiangshui River, and she and Xiangjun, the male god of the Xiangshui River, are the consort gods. The Xiangshui River is the largest river in Chu State. The pair of gods, Lord Xiang and Lady Xiang, reflect the ideology of primitive people worshiping natural gods and the concept of &quot;love between gods and humans&quot;. Chu folk literature and art has a strong religious atmosphere, and the altar is actually a &quot;drama altar&quot; or a &quot;literary altar&quot;. Take &quot;The King of Xiang&quot; and &quot;Mrs. Xiang&quot; as an example: when people sacrifice to King Xiang, they play the role of female singers or worshipers to welcome King Xiang; Mrs. Xiang, everyone expresses their deep love and affection. They use gods as objects to entrust the simple and sincere love in the world; at the same time, they also reflect the harmony between the people of Chu and nature. Because the Xiang River that irrigates Southern Chu has a flesh-and-blood relationship with the people of Chu, the Chu people have a deep love for the Xiang River and regard the Xiang River as a river of love and happiness, thus personifying the description of the Xiang River. The images of gods also play out stories of joys and sorrows like those of humans, and the gods in people&#39;s minds are specifically cast in the shadow of historical and legendary figures. Lord Xiang and Lady Xiang are based on the legend of Shun and his two concubines (Ehuang and Nvying). In this way, the image of God is not only richer and more vivid, but also more emotionally close to people in real life and full of human touch. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/quyuan.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Qu Yuan (about 340 BC - 278 BC), surnamed Mi, surname Qu, given name Ping, courtesy name Yuan, also named Zhengze, courtesy name Lingjun, was born in Danyang, Chu State Zigui (now Yichang, Hubei) was a poet and politician of the Chu State during the Warring States Period. Because he was excluded and slandered by the nobles, he was exiled to northern Han Dynasty and Yuanxiang River Basin. After the Chu State&#39;s Yingdu was conquered by the Qin army, he sank into the Miluo River and died for the Chu State. He is a great patriotic poet in Chinese history, the founder of Chinese romantic literature, the founder and representative writer of &quot;Chu Ci&quot;, and pioneered the tradition of &quot;Vanilla Beauty&quot;. He is known as the &quot;ancestor of Chu Ci&quot;. Song Yu, Tang Le and Jing Chai, the famous poets and poets of Chu State, were all influenced by Qu Yuan. According to legend, the day when Qu Yuan committed suicide by throwing himself into the river was the fifth day of the fifth lunar month, which is the Dragon Boat Festival. The Dragon Boat Festival was originally a festival for the Chinese people to cure diseases and prevent epidemics. Before the Spring and Autumn Period in the Wuyue area, there was a custom of holding tribal totem sacrifices in the form of dragon boat races on the fifth day of the fifth lunar month. Later, because Qu Yuan died on this day, it evolved into a traditional festival for the Chinese people to commemorate Qu Yuan. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 09:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[邴原泣学 | 李贽]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231132]]><description> &lt;h2>;Bingyuan Weeping Study&lt;/h2>;[Ming Dynasty] Li Zhi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Bingyuan Shaogu, when he was several years old, passed the bookstore and wept. The teacher said: &quot;Why do you cry, boy?&quot; The original saying is: &quot;A lonely person is easily hurt, and a poor person is easily affected. Anyone who has learned a book has relatives. One is to hope that he will not be alone, and the other is to envy him to learn. The center I feel sad, so I cry.&quot; The teacher said sympathetically: &quot;I want to write a book!&quot; The original said: &quot;I have no money.&quot; The teacher said: &quot;The boy is ambitious, and I will teach you, and I don&#39;t ask for money.&quot; So he started writing. . During the winter, I recited &quot;The Classic of Filial Piety&quot; and &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot;. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Bing Yuan lost his father when he was young. When he was a few years old, he passed by a book school. He started to cry. The teacher of the book school asked him: &quot;Child, why are you crying?&quot; Bing Yuan replied: &quot;People who have lost their parents are easy to be sad, and poor people are easy to be sentimental. Anyone who can study has parents. Children. The first thing I envy is that they have parents, and the second thing is that they can go to school. I feel very sad inside, so I cried.&quot; After hearing Bing Yuan&#39;s words, the private school teacher sympathized with him and said: &quot;(You) want to study, just go Read it!&quot; Bing Yuan said: &quot;(I) have no money to pay tuition.&quot; The private school teacher then said to him: &quot;If you really have this ambition, I will treat you as my apprentice and won&#39;t charge you tuition.&quot; From then on, Bing Yuan So he entered school to study. After one winter passed, Bing Yuan could memorize &quot;The Classic of Filial Piety&quot; and &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Bookhouse: Book School. &lt;br />;Center: In the heart. &lt;br />;Pity: pity, sympathy. &lt;br />;Guoshi: Outstanding talents in the country. &lt;br />;Go to school: start learning. &lt;br />;Why: why. &lt;br />;Shaogu: Lost his father when he was young. &lt;br />;Go to school: go to a private school (study). &lt;br />;Orphan: Lost parents in childhood. &lt;br />;Pao: pass by. &lt;br />;Cry: cry quietly. &lt;br />;Compassion: Sadness in the heart. &lt;br />;Parents: parents. &lt;br />;Envy: envy. &lt;br />;It: they refer to the students in the library. &lt;br />;De: able. &lt;br />;Center: In the heart&lt;br />;Sense: Sadness. &lt;br />;Injury: sadness. &lt;br />;Gou: If, if. &lt;br />;Wish: admire. &lt;br />;Book: Study. &lt;br />;Apprentice: Free, here means no charge. &lt;br />;Capital: expenses. &lt;br />;Sui: Just do it. &lt;br />;Pu: Finally. &lt;br />;Chan: recite. &lt;br />;Jiu: close, here refers to studying, that is, going to school. &lt;br />;Fan: Anything. &lt;br />;With: use. &lt;br />;So: reason; reason. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Inspiration&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;We must be eager to learn and cherish our hard-won opportunities to study. &lt;br />;You should also learn from teachers in the text, selflessly help others in their studies, and respect people who love learning and have ambitions. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Introduction&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Bing Yuan, a native of the Three Kingdoms period, was a famous scholar and celebrity at that time. Together with Guan Ning and Hua Xin, he was known as the &quot;Three Heroes of Liaodong&quot;. Although he lost his father at a young age and lived in extreme poverty, he still determined to learn cultural knowledge. He eventually moved the teachers in the school and created a good story about learning and teaching. The word &quot;cry&quot; expresses Bingyuan&#39;s strong desire to study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This article uses a sequential narrative to explain how Bingyuan, a young boy from a poor family, cried out to study. After getting the opportunity to go to school, he studied hard and was able to recite two classics proficiently in just one winter. Clearly, the image of a young child who is determined to study and has achieved outstanding results stands before us vividly. The article adopts touching dialogue descriptions and focuses on describing the process of Bing Yuan&#39;s weeping studies. The full text is concise and concise. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/lizhii.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Li Zhi (1527～1602), Han nationality, was born in Quanzhou, Fujian. An official, thinker, and writer of the Ming Dynasty, he was a master of the Taizhou School. Li Zhi&#39;s first surname was Lin, and his given name was Zai Zhi. Later, he changed his surname to Li, his given name was Zhi, his courtesy name was Hongfu, his nickname was Zhuowu, and his nicknames were Wenling Jushi, Baiquan Jushi, etc. During the Li Gongcheng period, he was a doctor of Imperial College, and during Wanli period he was the prefect of Yao&#39;an. He abandoned his official position and settled in Huang&#39;an (now Hong&#39;an County, Hubei Province) and Zhifo Temple in Macheng, Hubei Province. When he was giving lectures in Macheng, there were thousands of followers, including many women. In his later years, he traveled between Beijing and the South, and was eventually falsely accused and imprisoned. He committed suicide in prison. His important works include &quot;Collection of Books&quot;, &quot;Extension of Collection of Books&quot;, &quot;Book Burning&quot;, &quot;Extension of Book Burning&quot;, and &quot;Review of the Historical Outline&quot;. He has commented on &quot;Water Margin&quot;, &quot;The Romance of the West Chamber&quot;, &quot;The Story of Huan Sha&quot;, &quot;Moon Worship Pavilion&quot;, etc., which are still popular today. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>