<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[两小儿辩日 | 列子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231122]]><description> &lt;h2>;Two children arguing on the day&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Liezi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Confucius traveled eastward and saw two children arguing and asked why. (Part 1 of Debate: Debating the Sun)&lt;br />;Yi&#39;er said: &quot;When the sun begins to rise, people are near, but when the sun is at midday, people are far away.&quot; &lt;br />;Yi&#39;er said: &quot;I think when the sun begins to rise, people are far away. And when the sun is noon, it is close.&quot;&lt;br />;One son said: &quot;At the beginning of the sun, it is as big as a car hood, and at noon, it is like a pan. Isn&#39;t this why the far ones are small and the near ones are big?&quot;&lt;br />;1 The son said: &quot;At the beginning of the day, it is cool in Cangcang, and in the middle of the day, it is like exploring the soup. Isn&#39;t it hot when you are near, and cool when you are far?&quot;&lt;br />;Confucius couldn&#39;t decide. &lt;br />;The two children laughed and said: &quot;Who knows more about you?&quot; &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />; Confucius traveled eastward and saw two children arguing. He asked them the reason for their argument. &lt;br />;A child said: &quot;I think the sun is close to people when it just rises, but it is far away from people at noon.&quot;&lt;br />;Another child said: &quot;I think when the sun just rises, it is far away from people. It is far away from people, but it is closer to people at noon.&quot;&lt;br />;A child said: &quot;When the sun first rises, it is as big as the hood of a car, but by noon it is as small as a plate. This is not far away. Is it true that the small is near the big?&quot;&lt;br />;Another child said: &quot;It&#39;s cool when the sun first comes out, but at noon it&#39;s as hot as putting your hand into hot water. Do you think it’s cool?”&lt;br />;After hearing this, Confucius couldn’t judge who was right and who was wrong. &lt;br />;The two children smiled and said to Confucius: &quot;Who said you are wise?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;East: the east. &lt;br />;Travel: travel, study tour. &lt;br />;See: see. &lt;br />;Baidu: Debate, argue.&lt;br />;Baidu: Fight. &lt;br />;Its: pronoun, they. &lt;br />;Gru: reason, reason. &lt;br />;With: think. &lt;br />;Shi: Just now, just now. &lt;br />;Go: away; distance. &lt;br />;Sunday: noon. &lt;br />;At the beginning: just now. &lt;br />;Car hood: The hood on the car in ancient times was round like an umbrella. &lt;br />;And: to. &lt;br />;Then: Just. &lt;br />;Pan Yu: A container for holding things. The round one is called a plate, and the square one is called a bowl. &lt;br />;For: Yes. &lt;br />;Cangcang Liangliang: describes the feeling of coolness. Cangcang: means cold. &lt;br />;Exploring the soup: Put your hand into the hot water. Soup, hot water, boiling water. (In ancient times, it also specifically referred to hot water for bathing.) In the text, it means that the weather is very hot. &lt;br />;Jue: decision, judgment, judgment. &lt;br />;Which: Who. &lt;br />;For: same as &quot;predicate&quot;, say, think. &lt;br />;Ru: You. &lt;br />;Zhi: zhì, Tongjiazi. &quot;Zhi&quot; is connected with &quot;Zhi&quot;, which means &quot;cleverness&quot; and &quot;wisdom&quot;. &lt;br />;Laughing: This is not a mockery, it highlights the innocence and cuteness of the children&lt;br />;Cangcang Liangliang: Describes cool and slightly chilly. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief description&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; From the center of the sun to a fixed point on the earth&#39;s surface, the distance is definitely longer in the morning and shorter at noon. It&#39;s just that this change in distance is not enough to cause it to be hot at noon and cool in the morning. Hot at noon and cool in the morning is caused by the angle of incidence of the sun, which is not the truth mentioned in &quot;Two Children Debating the Sun&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This article is a fable. The article describes that in ancient times, two children relied on their own intuition. One believed that the sun was close to people in the morning, and the other believed that the sun was close to people at noon. For this reason, they each held their own opinions and couldn&#39;t argue. Even a learned man like Confucius Nothing can be done. This story illustrates that in order to understand nature and explore objective truth, one must dare to think independently and question boldly; it also illustrates that the universe is infinite and knowledge is infinite, and even the most knowledgeable people will not know something, and learning is endless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The story can be understood in three parts. First, it writes about Confucius&#39; encounter with two children arguing on the road, and points out the time, place, characters and causes of the story. The two children expressed two completely different views on the issue of how far the sun is from the earth at different times. Then write about two children using the intuition (visual, tactile) that people can experience in daily life to clarify their opinions to refute the other party&#39;s opinions. Finally, it is written that Confucius was unable to make a decision when facing the argument between the two children, which caused the two children to &quot;laugh&quot;. The full text is only about a hundred words, but it can give people many enlightenments. It is characterized by language expression to express characters and unfold the storyline through dialogue description, which expresses the innocence and loveliness of the two children and the scientific attitude of Confucius&#39; modesty, prudence, and seeking truth from facts. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;After-class questions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; 1. What do you think of the two children laughing at Confucius? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is certainly wrong for the two children to ridicule Confucius, but on the other hand, the knowledgeable Confucius still cannot answer the question, which reflects that there is no end to learning, so we must live to learn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ⒉What inspiration does this story have for you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The meaning of the above question is roughly the same, which means that people should live to learn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 1. The two characters are in the last sentence: wei-shuo, zhi-zhi-wisdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2. Its——refers to the matter of two children debating the sun and——waiting——decision, judgment, decision&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cangcang——the feeling of cold weather&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; 3. I think that the sun is close to people when it first rises, but it is far away from people at noon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 4. Why is the sun so bright when you look at it in the morning and evening? Especially small at noon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the morning and evening, the angle of the sun is low, and the atmosphere it penetrates is very thick. It is greatly affected by the gradient refractive index of the atmosphere, and the light path is significantly curved, so the sun is seen by people. At noon, the angle of the sun is large, and it penetrates The transparent atmosphere is relatively thin, and is less affected by the gradient refractive index of the atmosphere. The bending of the light path is not as obvious as in the morning and evening, so the sun seen by people feels smaller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, when the sun rises from the ground in the morning, the houses or mountains in the distance are in sharp contrast to the big sun, which is smaller and larger, but there is no east rise around noon. Compared with it, it will obviously look small. This is because our naked eyes deceive us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; You draw two circles of the same size, then draw a larger circle outside one circle and a smaller circle outside the other. You will feel that the two circles that are originally the same size seem to be different sizes. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This article reflects the ancient Chinese people&#39;s understanding of natural phenomena by describing two children arguing about the distance between the sun and people in the morning and noon. The valuable spirit of exploration and independent thinking, bold questioning, and pursuit of truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This short story is run through dialogue. The full text uses Confucius&#39;s inability to decide as a running clue, and narrates the process of the two children&#39;s debate about the sun in a very orderly manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First, write two children&#39;s clear opinions on the distance between the sun and people, which makes people think. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Then the basis is presented separately. The two refused to give in to each other, and both used rhetorical questions to capture the word &quot;debate&quot; in the title and enhance the argumentative nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Laugh&quot; obviously means &quot;ridicule&quot; in the original text. As for whether you should &quot;laugh&quot; or not, you can look at it from many aspects. From the perspective that the author is a Taoist and Confucius is a Confucian, it is obvious that Confucius should be &quot;laughed&quot;; but from the perspective of Confucius&#39; attitude, it is not appropriate to &quot;laugh&quot;, because Confucius seeks truth from facts and &quot;knows what he knows, and does not know what he doesn&#39;t know.&quot; There is no &quot;strong ignorance and ignorance&quot;, so why should you &quot;laugh&quot; at him? &quot;Confucius cannot decide&quot; tells people that a person should seek truth from facts and cannot pretend to understand; &quot;Confucius cannot decide&quot; also tells us that a great scholar like Confucius still has problems that cannot be solved. From this point of view, knowledge is useless. To the end, everyone should keep learning and never give up exploring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Confucius once said: Knowing something is knowing it, and not knowing it is not knowing. This is knowing. Confucius did not make any hasty decisions when facing the argument between the two children, which reflected his scientific attitude of seeking truth from facts. The two children are good at observing common life phenomena, discovering problems from them, and triggering thinking. It can also be seen from the fact that the two children observe and understand things from different angles, and the results are naturally inconsistent. This shows that they usually pay attention to observing life and comprehend life, and they are diverse. scientific thinking; at the same time, they also have the scientific spirit of independent thinking and bold questioning. This article also profoundly elaborates on the principle that &quot;learning has no end&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, modern science has a scientific explanation for this phenomenon: in the morning and evening, the angle of the sun is low, the atmosphere it penetrates is very thick, it is greatly affected by the gradient refractive index of the atmosphere, and the optical path is significantly bent. , so the sun that people see is bigger; at noon, the angle of the sun is large, the atmosphere it penetrates is relatively thin, and it is less affected by the gradient refractive index of the atmosphere. The bending of the light path is not as obvious as in the morning and evening, so the sun that people see feels smaller. . In addition, when the sun rises from the ground in the morning, and the houses or mountains in the distance are in sharp contrast to the big sun, smaller and larger, and there is nothing around to contrast with it at noon, it will obviously appear Small, this is our naked eyes deceiving us. Moreover, due to natural factors such as the shape of the earth, the atmosphere, and the laws of operation, it is impossible to give a correct explanation simply by using the laws of life or common sense. But making a correct explanation is a long process, and what is needed is the spirit of independent thinking, bold questioning, and seeking truth from facts of the &quot;two children&quot; and Confucius. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Reference materials&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; 1. This article is selected from Liezi Tangwen. Liezi is said to have been written by Lieyu Kou (approximately 450 BC - 375 BC) from the Zheng State during the Warring States Period. It contains many excellent fables and folk tales from the pre-Qin era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2. Confucius (551 BC - 479 BC), whose name was Qiu and whose courtesy name was Zhongni. A native of Zouyi of the state of Lu (now southeast of Qufu, Shandong), he was a thinker, politician, educator and founder of the Confucian school in the late Spring and Autumn Period. His words and deeds throughout his life were compiled into the book &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot; by his students and passed down to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 3. When does the sun get closer to people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Is the sun closer to people at noon? Or is it closer to people in the morning and evening? The fact that the sun is brighter in the morning and evening than at noon is due to people&#39;s misconception; the sun at noon is hotter than in the morning and evening because the sun is directly shining at noon. The distance traveled by the sun in the atmosphere is shorter and less heat is absorbed. First, we should understand why people observe the sun from different distances at noon and in the morning and evening. There are many reasons: (1) The earth is spherical and constantly rotating. If the earth has no other motion except rotation, and the axis of rotation is perpendicular to the straight line between the sun and the earth, then for a person on the equator, the sun will always be closer at noon than in the morning and evening. That is to say, the closer distance is equivalent to the earth&#39;s radius of 6,400 kilometers. . (2) Depending on the latitude of the earth, the observer may not be on the equator. The greater the latitude, the further away from the equator, the smaller the distance difference between the sun at noon and morning and evening. (3) The earth not only rotates, but also orbits the sun. The axis of rotation and the axis of revolution form an angle of 235°. The direction of the spin axis changes very slowly. Therefore the height of the sun at noon in the sky changes throughout the year. (4) The earth’s orbit is elliptical, so the distance between the earth’s center and the heliocenter changes day by day. (5) The sunrise and sunset times change day by day throughout the year, and the sunrise and sunset times on the same day vary with latitude. (6) Due to the slow change in the direction of the Earth&#39;s rotation axis and the impact of planetary gravity on the Earth&#39;s orbit, the date when the geocenter and the heliocenter are closest is not fixed. (At present, the closest distance between the heliocenter and the earth&#39;s center is January 2, and thereafter it advances by 17 and a half days every thousand years.) Taking into account the above reasons, appropriate formulas can be derived to calculate the distance between the sun and the observer at noon, morning and evening Difference. The necessary information can be found in the astronomical almanac. The calculation results are as follows: For a city such as Beijing with a latitude of 40 degrees north, currently from January 22 to June 5 at noon every year, the sun is farther than when it rises. It is 1,000 kilometers farther in early February, 4,000 kilometers farther in early March, and 4,000 kilometers farther in early March. At the beginning of the month it was as far as 6,400 kilometers, and later the difference was reduced to zero. After June 5th, the sun is closer at noon than at sunrise. It is nearly 5,800 kilometers in early July and 16,000 kilometers in mid-September. After that, the difference decreases to January 22nd of the following year. The difference between noon and evening is very different. From August 1st to December 15th, noon is farther than evening, and in the remaining seven and a half months, noon is closer than evening. In mid-April, the distance reaches 17,000 kilometers. …The above calculations were made in 1954. However, since the sixth cause has little impact in a short period of time, the above calculation results are still applicable to the next hundred years. It can be seen that all phenomena must be explained by science to be correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; (Devense &quot;Is the sun closer to us at noon than in the morning and evening&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 4. What&#39;s the reason why it&#39;s cold when it&#39;s close in the morning and hot when it&#39;s far away at noon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The sun looks bigger in the morning than at noon. Is it because the sun is closer to us in the morning and farther away from us at noon? no. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under certain conditions, people&#39;s vision of objects will cause illusions. An object will appear larger among some small objects, and an object will appear larger among some large objects. Smaller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Similarly, in the morning sun, only a corner of the horizon is the sky, while the rest is backed by trees, houses, etc. At noon, the sun is extremely large above the head. The sky serves as its backing, so the sun at noon appears smaller than the sun in the morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, we see white graphics larger than black graphics of the same size. This is called &quot;light penetration&quot; in physics. When the sun first rises, the surrounding sky is dark, so the sun appears bright. However, at noon, the surrounding sky is very bright. In contrast, the brightness difference between the sun and the background is not that great. This also makes us look The reason why the sun is larger in the morning than at noon. In short, the distance of the sun from us is the same in the morning and at noon, so its size is also the same. The fact that the sun in the morning seems larger than at noon is an illusion of the eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Also, it is hotter at noon than in the morning. Is it because the sun is closer to us at noon than in the morning? Neither. So why? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is hotter at noon than in the morning because the sun shines directly on the ground at noon, while in the morning the sun shines obliquely on the ground. It can be seen that when the sun shines directly on the ground, the ground and the air are at the same time. The same area receives more radiant heat from the sun than when the morning sun is slanting, so the heating is the strongest. Therefore, it is hotter at noon than in the morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, the hot or cold weather is mainly determined by the air temperature. The main factor affecting air temperature is determined by the radiation intensity of the sun, but solar heat is not the main reason that directly increases the temperature. Because the heat energy directly absorbed by the air is only a small part of the total heat energy of solar radiation, most of which is absorbed by the ground. After the ground absorbs solar radiation heat, it is then conducted upward to the air through heat transfer methods such as radiation and convection. This is the main reason for the increase in temperature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In short, it is hotter at noon and colder in the morning every day, not because the sun is far or near from our ground. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This article is excerpted from Chapter 7 of &quot;Liezi·Tangwen&quot;, and the title was added by later generations. This article records the story of two children during the Spring and Autumn Period and Confucius, a great scholar at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Teaching Suggestions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; 1. Before class, teachers can review the scientific knowledge involved in the text. You can also assign students pre-class homework: Does the distance between the sun and the earth change throughout the day? Why does the sun look bigger in the morning and smaller at noon? Why does it feel cooler in the morning and hotter at noon?&quot; Collect information on your own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 2. Although this article is concise, the different meanings of ancient and modern words are still a difficulty for students to read and understand. For example, the modal particle &quot;hu&quot;, which rarely appears in modern texts, appears three times in the article. Solve this problem It is recommended to divide a difficult point into three steps. (1) After students read the text, they can initially understand the meaning of each sentence based on the annotations. For students who do not understand, the teacher can give a little guidance so that students can understand the context. (2) Read it repeatedly to understand the content of the story . ⑶ Tell this story in your own words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 3. This story contains profound truth. Teachers can organize students to discuss and share what they think of after reading this text. Students should be encouraged to speak freely and start from Gain insights from multiple angles. For example, the two children like to explore, and their spirit is commendable; the two children understand things from different angles, and the results are different; Confucius can correctly treat the questions raised by the children, not knowing what is not known, and seeking truth from facts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As for the end of the article, Confucius &quot;cannot solve it&quot;, students should know that many natural phenomena are common scientific knowledge to us, but in ancient times they were mysteries that were difficult to solve due to underdeveloped science and technology, so Confucius &quot;Unable to decide&quot; is understandable. It can be seen that the universe is huge and the knowledge is vast, up and down. Even a wise man cannot know everything. Confucius did not &quot;pretend to know what you don&#39;t know&quot;, but in the spirit of &quot;knowing what you know, knowing what you don&#39;t know&quot; &quot;I don&#39;t know&quot; attitude of seeking truth from facts. Therefore, when teaching, do not take the joke about Confucius as the main theme.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 4. When learning classical Chinese, repeated reading is the most important method. When learning this article, you should still pay attention to guided reading. When reading this article aloud, you can read the pauses in the sentences according to the following tips.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Confucius traveled eastward and saw two children arguing and asked why.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One son said: &quot;I /When the sun begins to rise/people are close to you, but when /at the middle of the day/people are far away. &quot;One son said: &quot;When the sun rises at the beginning of the day, it is far away, and when the sun rises at the middle of the day, it is close.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One of the children said: &quot;When the sun rises at the beginning of the day, it is as big as a car hood, and when it reaches the middle of the day, it is as big as a pan. This is not the case. / The ones far away are small / and / the ones close / are big?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One son said: “The first sunrise / Cang Cang is cool and cool, and the middle of the day / is like exploring the soup, which is not / the one close / hot / And / is it cold when it is far away?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Confucius can&#39;t decide.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two children laughed and said: &quot;Who / do you know how much?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The description of the language and dialogue of the two children is the focus of the teacher&#39;s guidance of students in reading.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the second natural paragraph, the two children presented completely different views on the distance between the sun and the earth at different times. Students should be guided to use The affirmative tone shows that the two children hold their own opinions and refuse to give in to each other.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the third and fourth natural paragraphs, the two children put forward reasons to prove their own opinions and refute each other&#39;s opinions based on their own feelings and experiences. The two paragraphs have the same sentence pattern and structure, and both end with a rhetorical question. Pay attention to the reading of the rhetorical question. Among them, &quot;as big as a car hood&quot; and &quot;like exploring soup&quot; should be emphasized, and &quot;like a plate bowl&quot; and &quot;cangcang cool&quot; should be read. Read it lightly and make it read with a contrasting tone, so that it will form a climax where the two peaks are in confrontation, arguing and needing to be resolved.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the fifth natural paragraph, the two children saw that the sage Confucius could not make a decision, so they laughed and said: &quot;Who knows how much you know?&quot; also uses a rhetorical question format. It should be made clear that the children&#39;s laughter is not sarcastic, and students should be guided to read it in a lively and relaxed tone to express the innocence and cuteness of the children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When instructing students to read classical Chinese texts, they should pay attention to standard reading and comprehension. On the basis of students understanding the content of the article and being able to read the full text emotionally, students will be guided to read aloud in different roles, striving to achieve recitation in class.&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 5. After-school extension. It is recommended to arrange a language practice activity and perform &quot;Newly Edited Two Children Debating Day&quot;. Before the activity, the teacher provides an idea for the activity: A modern teenager traveled through time and space to the distant ancient times, and met two children debating the day. The two children asked the teenager to make a decision. During the activity, students were first asked to create and perform in groups, and then communicated with the class.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt; center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/lieyukou.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>; Liezi (about 450 BC - 375 BC, the Warring States Period (Year 75 years old), a representative figure of Taoism in the early Warring States Period. Ming Kou, also known as Yu Kou (&quot;Liezi&quot; is the honorific title given to him by later generations), a Chinese nationality, a native of Putian, Zhengguo (now Zhengzhou City, Henan Province) in the Zhou Dynasty, an ancient After the emperor Li Shan, he was one of the ten great figures in the pre-Qin world, a famous Taoist scholar, thinker, philosopher, writer, and educator. He had a profound influence on later generations of philosophy, aesthetics, literature, science and technology, health, music, and religion. He is the author of &quot;Liezi&quot;, its theory is based on the Yellow Emperor and Laozi, and is attributed to Laozi and Zhuangzhuang. Founded the Guixu School (Liezixue), a school of pre-Qin philosophy. He is an important inheritor of the Taoist school between Laozi and Zhuangzi. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鹊桥仙·纤云弄巧 | 秦观]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231121]]><description> &lt;h2>;Magpie Bridge Immortal·Xianyun Nongqiao&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Qin Guan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Xianyun makes tricks, flying stars spread hatred, and the distance between Yinhan and Han is dark. Once the golden wind and jade dew meet, they will win over countless others in the world. &lt;br />;Tenderness is like water, good times are like dreams, and I can’t bear to look at the magpie bridge on my way back! If the love lasts for a long time, how can it last day and night? &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The light colorful clouds transform into various ingenious patterns in the sky, and the meteors in the sky convey With the sorrow and resentment of lovesickness, I quietly cross the vast and distant Milky Way tonight. Meeting on the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day in the autumn wind and white dew is better than those couples in the world who stay together forever but seem to be inseparable. &lt;br />;The lingering tenderness is as continuous as flowing water, the reunion date is as ethereal and illusory as a dream, and when we part ways, I can&#39;t bear to look at the Magpie Bridge Road. If two people are in love with each other and will remain together until death, why should they covet the happiness of each other in the morning and evening? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Xianyun: light clouds. &lt;br />;Miscellaneous: refers to the clouds turning into various clever patterns in the sky. &lt;br />;Flying Star: Meteor. One theory refers to the two stars Morning Glory and Weaver Girl. &lt;br />;Yinhan: Milky Way, Tianhe. &lt;br />;Far away: distant appearance. &lt;br />;Darkness: Pass quietly. &lt;br />;Golden Wind and Jade Dew: refers to the white dew in the autumn wind. &lt;br />;Can&#39;t bear to look back: How can I bear to look back. &lt;br />;Morning and evening: refers to getting together day and night. The words come from Song Yu&#39;s &quot;Gaotang Fu&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Borrowing the story of the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl to express the joys and sorrows of the world in a superhuman way, which has been around since ancient times, such as &quot;Nineteen Ancient Poems: Far Away Altair&quot;, Cao Pi&#39;s &quot;Yan Ge Xing&quot;, Li Shangyin&#39;s &quot;Xinwei Qixi&quot; and so on. Ouyang Xiu, Zhang Xian, Liu Yong, Su Shi and others in the Song Dynasty also chanted this theme. Although the words and sentences were different, they all followed the traditional theme of &quot;joy is short&quot;, with a sad and sad style. In contrast, Qin Guan&#39;s words can be said to be unique and witty, with lofty intentions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; This is a stanza preface to the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day. The beginning of the sentence shows the unique lyrical atmosphere of the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day. &quot;Qiao&quot; and &quot;hate&quot; combine the theme of &quot;begging for cleverness&quot; in the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day and &quot;Cowherd, Cowherd,&quot; The tragic characteristics of the story &quot;Weaver Girl&quot; are clear, sophisticated and poignant. The story of the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl&#39;s joys and sorrows is used to sing the praises of steadfast and sincere love. The concluding sentence &quot;If love lasts for a long time, how can it last day and night&quot; is the most profound. These two sentences not only refer to the characteristics of the love model of Cowherd and Weaver Girl, but also express the author&#39;s view of love. They are highly condensed quotes. Good sentences. This poem therefore has aesthetic value and artistic taste across eras and countries. This poem combines scenery, lyricism and discussion, narrating the mythical story of the love between the Morning Glory and the Weaver Girl. It gives the fairy couple a strong human touch and sings the praises of sincere, delicate, pure and steadfast love. The poem clearly describes the twin stars in the sky, and implicitly describes the lovers in the world; its lyrical expression uses happy scenes to describe sorrow, and sad scenes to describe joy, doubling the sorrow and joy. It is soul-stirring and touching when read. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; At the beginning of the poem, it says &quot;Slender clouds make clever things&quot;. The soft and colorful clouds change into many beautiful and clever patterns, showing how exquisite the Weaver Girl&#39;s craftsmanship is. However, such a beautiful person cannot live a beautiful life with the one he loves. &quot;Flying stars convey hatred&quot;, those shining stars seem to convey their sorrow and hatred, flying across the sky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Regarding the Milky Way, &quot;Nineteen Ancient Poems&quot; says: &quot;The river is clear and shallow, how far apart is it? It is full of water, and the pulse is speechless.&quot; The water is full of water, so close that it seems to be connected to each other. His expression and voice are all astonishing. Here, Qin Guan wrote: &quot;The Milky Way and Han Dynasty are so far apart&quot;, using the word &quot;far away&quot; to describe the vastness of the Milky Way and how far apart the Milky Way is. This change makes the relationship deeper and highlights the pain of lovesickness. The vast distance of the Milky Way separates two people who love each other. How difficult it is to meet each other! The word &quot;darkness&quot; not only embodies the meaning of the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, but also closely links to the word &quot;hate&quot;. They walked at night and came all the way to meet each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Next, the poet started writing and praised with emotional comments: &quot;Once the golden wind and jade dew meet, they will win countless people in the world!&quot; A long-separated couple on the golden wind and jade dew night, the blue sky We met on the bank of the Milky Way. This beautiful moment is worth meeting thousands of times in the world. The poet passionately praises an ideal holy and eternal love. &quot;Golden Wind and Jade Dew&quot; is based on Li Shangyin&#39;s poem &quot;Xinwei Qixi&quot;: &quot;I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s a good time to say goodbye to the immortal family, so I teach you to make a good time. It comes from the blue sky beside the Milky Way, and it&#39;s the golden wind and jade dew.&quot; It is used to describe the time when we meet on the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day. The scenery, but also has a profound meaning. The poet sets this precious meeting against the background of golden wind, jade dew, ice and pure jade, showing the noble purity and otherworldliness of this kind of love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Tenderness is like water&quot;, the affection between two lovers is like the silent flowing water, so gentle and lingering. &quot;Tenderness is like water&quot;, &quot;like water&quot; echoes &quot;Yinhan is far away&quot;, it is a metaphor based on the scene, which is very natural. How could it not be heart-breaking that the one-night-long wedding suddenly passed away like a dream, only to see each other and then be separated again? &quot;A good time is like a dream&quot;, in addition to describing the short time of meeting, it also describes the complex emotions of lovers when they meet. &quot;Endurance to look at the magpie bridge and the way back&quot; is a transliteration of separation. The magpie bridge where we just met has suddenly become the way back to separate from the lover. Not saying that I couldn&#39;t bear to leave, but saying that I couldn&#39;t bear to see the Magpie Bridge on my way back. The euphemistic meaning contained infinite feelings of farewell and infinite bitter tears. Looking back on the tryst during the wedding day, I doubted whether it was true or false, it was like a dream or an illusion. When we went to the Magpie Bridge to say goodbye, our love was at its peak. At this point, the word pen suddenly turned around and burst out with a high-pitched sound: &quot;If the love lasts for a long time, how can it last day and night!&quot; Qin Guan&#39;s two lines reveal the true meaning of love: love must withstand long-term separation. The test of love, as long as we can sincerely love each other, even if we are separated all year round, it is much more valuable than the vulgar taste of being together day and night. These two highly emotional comments have become an eternal masterpiece among love hymns. They echo the discussion in the first film. In this way, the upper and second films have the same structure, with narrative and discussion alternating, thus forming a continuous and ups and downs of emotion in the whole article. This correct view of love and this noble spiritual realm far exceed similar works in ancient times and are very commendable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The discussion of this poem is free and smooth, easy to understand, but also elegant and subtle, with endless aftertaste. The author combines the finishing touch of argumentation and prose syntax with beautiful images and deep emotions to sing the ups and downs of the beautiful love in the world, achieving excellent artistic effects. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; Regarding the creative background of this word, Liu Yonggang, a professor at Yangzhou University, believes that this word was written by Qin Guan in Chenzhou, southern Hunan, to express his feelings for Changsha. , the time is the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day in the fourth year of Emperor Zhezong&#39;s reign in the Song Dynasty (AD 1097). In the spring of 1096 AD (the third year of Shaosheng&#39;s reign), Qin Guan took charge of Chenzhou by supervising the prefecture&#39;s wine tax and cutting the state&#39;s wine tax. Changsha was the only way to go. Regarding Changsha&#39;s righteousness advocacy, Volume 2 of Hong Mai&#39;s &quot;Yijian Zhibu&quot; has a more detailed description: &quot;The righteousness advocate is from Changsha, and I don&#39;t know his surname. He has a family background and is good at praising. He is especially fond of Qin Shaoyue Mansion and gets a title. &quot;Psalms, often written or spoken,&quot; Qin Guan moved south, passing by Changsha, visiting the local customs of Tan, and met this geisha. Qin Guan saw that her appearance was beautiful and her words were sincere, so she revealed her identity. The geisha was surprised and happy, and she entertained Shao You attentively and sang all over the Huaihai Yuefu. Qin Guan was in love with her for several days. When she was leaving, the geisha expressed her wish to serve her. Qin Guan promised her that he would meet again when he returned to the north and it would be the day of Yu Fei. After several years of separation, Qin Guan died in Teng County, Guangxi. Geisha traveled hundreds of miles to pay tribute to Qin Guan and died in mourning. The story of the geisha &quot;is still passed down by Hunan people as a strange thing.&quot; Hong Mai mentioned that Changzhou school official Zhong Jiangzhi was inspired by the incident and wrote a biography of the geisha, which was named &quot;Yi Shang Zhuan&quot;. At that time, Qin Guan&#39;s road to relegation was still going south, and he and the Changsha singer had to say goodbye in tears. After arriving in Chenzhou, Qin Guan missed his lover day and night, but with his sinful body and life in danger, it was not easy to get together. In fact, the heavy sigh in the last two sentences of &quot;Tasha Xing·Chenzhou Hostel&quot; &quot;The Chenjiang River has fortunately circled Chenshan Mountain, for whom did it flow down to Xiaoxiang&quot; also contains the longing for the geisha in Changsha. On the Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day in 1097 AD (the fourth year of Shaosheng&#39;s reign), Qin Guan wrote the song &quot;Magpie Bridge Immortal&quot; in Chenzhou. He expressed his love for the Changsha singing girl through the Magpie Bridge meeting between the ox and the girl. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/qinguan.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Qin Guan (1049-1100), also known as Taixu and Shaoyou, was also nicknamed Hangou Jushi and known as Mr. Huaihai in the world. Han nationality, a native of Gaoyou (now Jiangsu) in the Northern Song Dynasty. He was an official and became a doctor of Taixue. He was an editor of the National History Museum. Qin Guan had a rough life, and the poems he wrote were ancient and heavy, reflecting his life experience and deeply touching. Wherever Qin Guan traveled during his lifetime, there are many relics. For example, Qin Shaoyou Temple in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province, Qin Shaoyou Statue, Mr. Huaihai Temple, and Yinghua Pavilion in Lishui; Qin Xueshi Temple in Qingtian; Sanjue Monument in Chenzhou, Hunan; Haitang Pavilion, Zuixiang Pavilion, Huaihai Hall, Huaihai Academy, etc. in Hengxian County, Guangxi. Qin Guan&#39;s tomb is located on Canshan Mountain in the north of Huishan in Wuxi. The tombstone has the characters &quot;Qin Long Tu Tomb&quot; written on it. There are Qinjia Village, Qinjia Courtyard and Ancient Literature Tour Platform, a provincial cultural relic protection unit. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>