<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[春思 | 方岳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239271]]><description> &lt;h2>;Spring Thoughts&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Fang Yue&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The spring breeze is too busy to grow, and the lace willows will grow together for laymen. &lt;br />;Working with swallows and bees to make honey, it rains lightly and then the weather clears. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;How busy the spring breeze is! Always accompanied by red flowers and green willow trees. You warm the earth and provide the soil for swallows to build their nests; you also blow open the flowers in a hurry so that bees can collect nectar and turn it into nectar. The clouds had just blown in and there was a drizzle, then the dark clouds were sent away again, bringing sunny weather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Duoke: How capable it is. &lt;br />;Busy: Busy. Sheng, auxiliary word, unintentional. &lt;br />;With: substitute, help. &lt;br />;Must: Yes. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Song people like to use personification in their quatrains. Poets imagine that nature and everything in nature have emotions like humans, so they can&#39;t help but treat nature as humans and move their emotions into nature. Writing in this way brings a human touch to things that are not originally alive, making them feel friendly and moved. Fang Yue&#39;s poem &quot;Spring Thoughts&quot; adopts this artistic technique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Using an anthropomorphic style and describing the spring scenery, the author enthusiastically praises the vibrant spring breeze. The style of the poem is fresh and does not use allusions. It is personified throughout, full of movement, subtle details, and very charming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Wing Chun Thoughts&quot; does not describe the various thoughts and feelings caused by spring, such as regretting spring, cherishing spring, etc.; it describes the emotions of spring itself. When chanting specifically, the representative of spring - spring breeze was chosen to express it, and the theme of the chant was fixed on the word &quot;busy&quot;. The first sentence is about why the spring breeze is so busy. The poet analyzed that it is because the spring breeze is &quot;many&quot;. With many permissions and willingness to meet the requirements of various objects, Chunfeng is of course &quot;too busy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following three sentences specifically describe the busyness of the spring breeze. In spring, the poet believes that the biggest changes, the first to gain popularity, and the most prominent ones are red flowers and green willows. So the poem writes that the spring breeze has been accompanying Hualiu and served Hualiu wholeheartedly. This sentence is written in plain language, and readers can naturally imagine that throughout the spring, the flowers first sprout leaves, then form stamens, and then bloom into buds, and finally bloom in full bloom, until they fall one after another; think of the willow tree from sprouting and sprouting to ten thousand threads. The green strips danced wildly in the wind, and finally the catkins were flying, and the green shade was thick. During this whole process, the spring breeze is omnipresent and non-stop. This is the &quot;too busy life&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Talking about flowers and willows is, of course, not in isolation, but rather summarizes the role that the spring breeze plays on plants in the entire nature. The next two sentences describe how the spring breeze cares for birds and insects, and the other describes how the spring breeze regulates the climate. The poem says that the spring breeze blows away the cold and thaws the earth, allowing swallows to build nests with mud and raise the next generation. It also blows open the flowers and allows bees to brew sweet honey. It copes with the various needs of nature. It has just arranged a light rain to moisten the earth, and then arranged a sunny day. Writing in such an all-round way highlights the exhaustion of the spring breeze, and the poet&#39;s praise of spring is expressed in subtle ways through the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Spring breeze is originally a very vague and broad concept. Fang Yue organized various images and explained them in a detailed way, which is refreshing. The delicacy and rationality of Song poetry are reflected in this poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/fangyue.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Fang Yue (1199～1262), a poet and lyricist of the Southern Song Dynasty. The name is Jushan and the name is Qiuya. A native of Qimen (now part of Anhui). In the fifth year of Shaoding (1232), he became a Jinshi and was awarded the title of Huaidong Appeasement Division Officer. In Chunzhong, Zhao Kui served as the counselor of the Huainan curtain with the official Langguan of the Ministry of Industry. Later, he was transferred to the Nankang Army. Later, he was transferred to Shaowu Army for offending Huguang Commander-in-Chief Jia Sidao. Later we learned that Yuanzhou was impeached and dismissed from office because he offended the powerful Ding Daquan. Later, he was appointed to Fuzhou again, but his appointment was canceled due to old suspicions with Jia Sidao. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[秦楼月·芳菲歇 | 向子諲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239261]]><description> &lt;h2>;Qin Lou Yue·Fang Fei Xie&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Xiang Ziqi &lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Fang Fei Xie, the old garden is broken and heartbroken. Heartbroken, boundless smoke and water, endless mountain scenery. &lt;br />;As we get closer to the Qianlong Festival, our eyes are filled with tears and blood. The sky is crying with blood, outside the sound of Zigui, the dawn wind is waning and the moon is waning. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;In late spring, when the fragrance is falling, I climb high and look at my motherland in the distance, feeling sad and aching in my heart. The blurred smoke and hazy mountain scenery made me even more heartbroken. &lt;br />;What is even more unbearable is that the Qianlong Festival is coming soon. Looking back on the past, tears run down from my eyes, crying out blood like a cuckoo bird. Beyond the mournful sounds of the regulations, there are the ruined rivers and mountains of the motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Qin Louyue: also known as Yi Qin&#39;e. Double tone, forty-six characters. The first paragraph has five sentences, three oblique rhymes, one repeated sentence, and twenty-one characters. The second paragraph has five sentences, three oblique rhymes, one repeated sentence, and twenty-five words. &lt;br />;Fangfeixie (xiē): refers to the scene of the dying flowers in spring. Xin Qiji&#39;s &quot;Congratulations to the Bridegroom: Farewell to the Twelfth Brother of Maojia&quot;: &quot;I can&#39;t find a place to cry when I return in spring, and I hate my beauty and have a rest.&quot;&lt;br />;Hometown: This refers to the occupied land. &lt;br />;Looking ahead: Looking ahead. &lt;br />;Kān: What’s more. &lt;br />;Qianlong Festival: April 13th is the birthday of Emperor Qinzong Zhao Huan of the Song Dynasty, so it is named Qianlong Festival. &lt;br />;Cry (tí) for blood: Chen Zangqi&#39;s &quot;Supplementary Materials on Materia Medica&quot; states that the cuckoo &quot;crows until the blood comes out&quot;. This refers to the poet&#39;s extreme grief. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; In the &quot;Jingkang Incident&quot; in 1127 AD, the two emperors Hui and Qin were kidnapped by the Jin people and went north, and the Central Plains was lost. In this current situation, all the people with lofty ideals in both the government and the public drew their swords to cut the ground and gnashed their teeth. As a result, a number of works were produced in the world of poetry that are generous and sad after reading, and whose generous and upright spirit can still be seen hundreds of years later. Xiang Ziyi&#39;s poem &quot;Moon in the Qin Lou&quot; has the same theme. Although it is short in length, its emotional capacity is not small. In addition, the performance of this poem also has its own characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The structure of the whole poem is divided into upper and lower columns, and the meaning of the words can be divided into three levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three characters &quot;Fangfeixie&quot; at the beginning describe the scene of the disappearing spring, which seems real but virtual. Because the poet is not reciting the preface and expressing the general feelings of sadness about spring and farewell, I will not describe the scenery below. In this late spring and early summer season, what is lingering in the heart of the poet? It is &quot;the hometown is broken and the heart is broken&quot;. The &quot;hometown&quot; in this sentence can be interpreted as hometown, but Xiang Ziyi&#39;s home in Linjiang, Jiangxi Province did not fall into the hands of the Jin people. This obviously refers to the lost land. The poet climbed high and looked at his homeland in the north, but the homeland was invisible. For a poet who was crossing to the south with a patriotic feeling, how could he not feel sad and painful? This sentence is a direct expression of the poet&#39;s inner feelings. But if you let your emotions drive you and write along this line of thinking, you will be in trouble. The lyrics are chanting, but it is best to refer to specific things. At this point, the poet&#39;s pen moves from straight to curved, about to vomit and then stop. Instead of expressing emotion, he writes about the scenery: &quot;Boundless smoke and water, endless mountain scenery.&quot; What the poet sees in his eyes is only blurred smoke and water, and hazy mountains. color. This scene not only enriches and expands the meaning of &quot;My hometown is broken&quot;, but also visualizes the psychological activity of &quot;sadness&quot;; at the same time, the boundless natural landscape appropriately conveys the poet&#39;s emotions at this time and place. Distant melancholy. Therefore, after reading this, the reader can hardly tell whether the poet is describing scenery or expressing emotions. Scenery and emotion are combined, emotion is born from scenery, scenes blend together, &quot;sadness and joy are also revealed in things&quot; (Wang Fu&#39;s words), which is the beauty of &quot;boundless smoke and water, endless mountain scenery&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word &quot;Kekan&quot; in Xiayu means unbearable. This is the poet&#39;s deliberate effort. It is these two words that deepen the feeling of &quot;the hometown is broken and heartbroken&quot;. Why does the poet miss his motherland in late spring and early summer? Because it is &quot;closer to Qianlong Festival&quot;. &quot;Yi Qian&quot;: &quot;Nine Five, Feilong Tian.&quot; The Qian hexagram uses dragon as its image, so the ancients used &quot;Qianlong&quot; to describe the emperor. Qianlong Festival is the birthday of Zhao Heng, Qinzong of the Northern Song Dynasty. According to the &quot;History of the Song Dynasty·Book of Rites&quot;: &quot;On April 13th of the first year of Jingkang, Grand Prime Minister Xu Churen and others invited him to celebrate the Qianlong Festival.&quot; From the records, we can imagine that on this day, the ministers in the court congratulated the emperor on his birthday, and Qin Zong gave him a gift. Banquet, what a grand birthday banquet! At this time, it is April again, and the Qianlong Festival is approaching. However, at this time, China is in a state of chaos, and the mountains and rivers are changing hands. How could the poet endure such drastic changes when looking back at the present and recalling the past? So thousands of feelings turned into words that people can&#39;t bear to read: &quot;The tears in the eyes are empty and the blood is crying.&quot; This sentence is sad and sad, and it is soul-stirring. Xiang Ziyi was a general who advocated resistance to the Jin Dynasty. In 1130 AD (the fourth year of Emperor Jianyan&#39;s reign), the Jin soldiers marched southward in large numbers, killing all the way to Jiangxi and Hunan. At this time, when Xiangzi was appointed as the magistrate of Zhengtan Prefecture (now Changsha), someone suggested that he should temporarily avoid the enemy&#39;s attack. He shouted: &quot;What kind of disloyalty is there! Let one or two of Xiangzhi&#39;s counties be able to defend the country. The enemy is here? The imperial court asked me to guard Panye, and it is unjust to leave here!&quot; (See Wang Yingchen&#39;s &quot;Xiang Gong&#39;s Epitaph&quot; and Hu Hong&#39;s &quot;Xiang Shilang&#39;s Departure&quot;) He personally led the army and the people to fight in bloody battles for several days, and finally The city was destroyed due to lack of strength. Afterwards, his good friend Chen Yuyi gave him a poem, in which he praised &quot;Zhu Tian&#39;s meritorious deeds are due to you&quot; (&quot;Picture of Xiang Bo Gong&#39;s Crossing the Gorge&quot;). However, the poet thought about the destruction of the family and the country, the humiliation of the king and the humiliation of his ministers, but he was unable to recover, and his heart could not help but be filled with extreme resentment and sorrow. Such deep and difficult emotions are stagnating in my chest, and they cannot be extinguished by just &quot;the eyes are full of tears and the blood is crying&quot;. The above is the second level of word meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Immediately afterwards, the poet associated the human &quot;empty cry of blood&quot; with the rules of nature, and his emotions took on another level. According to the requirements of the tone of &quot;Qin Lou Yue&quot;, &quot;empty crying blood&quot; is inherited from the previous sentence. It is not a simple repetition of the sentence, but is used to evoke the meaning of the following sentence. The poet set up the scene according to the situation, and ended the whole poem with such a sad and desolate artistic conception as &quot;outside the sound of Zigui, the dawn wind is waning and the moon is waning&quot;. Zigui is the cuckoo bird. Zigui cries for blood is commonly used in ancient poetry, such as Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;Pipa Xing&quot;: &quot;What did I hear at dawn and dusk? The cuckoo crows and the blood ape screams.&quot; Li Shanfu&#39;s &quot;Wen Zigui&quot;: &quot;I miss my homeland with a broken heart, and the blood splashes on the branches when I cry.&quot; &quot;The dawn wind is waning and the moon is waning&quot; is a famous line in Liu Yong&#39;s poem &quot;Yulin Ling&quot;. Although this poem is a transfer, the poet obviously transformed the connotation of &quot;cuckoo cries blood&quot;. What this word expresses is no longer the sorrow of parting, but the longing for the homeland caused by the destruction of the country and the death of the family. &quot;Beyond the sound of Zigui, the dawn wind is waning and the moon is waning&quot;, the scenery is set up due to emotion, which is what Wang Guowei calls &quot;viewing things with me, all old things have my color&quot;, &quot;a state of self&quot;. With its rich connotation, it conveys the infinite sadness in the poet&#39;s heart and hits the readers&#39; hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is full of sincere emotions and blends with scenes. In &quot;Wine Side Ci&quot;, it is a successful poem. But in the end, it is more loyal and indignant than bold, and the artistic conception in the poem is less original and lacks freshness, which inevitably affects its artistic appeal and is not the best among Song Dynasty poems. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written in the late spring after the Jingkang Incident (1126-1127), when the second Huiqin clan was kidnapped by the Jin people. The Central Plains fell into the hands of the Jin people, while the Southern Song Dynasty court stayed in a corner and did not want to regain the lost territory and welcomed back the two Huiqin sects. The poet wrote this poem to express the sadness and resentment of his family and country. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Xiang Ziyi (yīn) (1085-1152), courtesy name Bo Gong, also known as Xianglin Jushi, was born in Linjiang (now Qingjiang County, Jiangxi Province). In the third year of Yuanfu (1100) of Zhezong, he supplemented his official position with Yin. During the reign of Emperor Huizong&#39;s Xuanhe period, he served as deputy transit envoy to the capital and deputy shipping envoy. Gaozong Jianyan was appointed as the shipping envoy to the Yangtze River and Huaihe River. Su and Li Gang were good, Li Gang was dismissed as prime minister, and Zi Yan was also dismissed. After learning about Tanzhou, the following year Jin soldiers surrounded Tanzhou, and Ziyi led the army and civilians to hold on for eight days. In Shaoxing, he was a minister of the Ministry of Household Affairs and knew Pingjiang Prefecture. He was dismissed from his post because he opposed Qin Hui&#39;s peace proposal and lived in Linjiang. His poems were bounded by the southern crossing. The style of the early period was gorgeous. After the southern crossing, many of his poems were about sadness and concern for the country. There are two volumes of &quot;Wine Bian Ci&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 10:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>