<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[芙蓉池作 | 曹丕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310251]]><description> &lt;h2>;Hibiscus Pond Zuo&lt;/h2>;[Wei and Jin Dynasties] Cao Pi &lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>; took a chariot at night and walked leisurely in the West Garden. &lt;br />;The two canals irrigate each other, and the beautiful trees go around the river. &lt;br />;The humble branches brush the feather cover, and the pruning strips touch the sky. &lt;br />;The wind blows, and the birds fly before me. &lt;br />;The bright moon is sandwiched between the Danxia clouds, and the Chinese star emerges from the clouds. &lt;br />;The sky is filled with light, and the five colors are so fresh. &lt;br />;Who can win the immortality except Song Qiao? &lt;br />;Wandering makes your mind happy, and you will protect yourself for a hundred years. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;When you get out at night, take a carriage and come to the West Garden for a stroll. &lt;br />;Two canals have watered the garden, and beautiful trees surround the canals. &lt;br />;The short branches sweep the feather cover, and the slender branches stretch into the blue sky. &lt;br />;The strong wind pushed the wheels from behind the car and flew away, while the birds circled happily in front. &lt;br />;A bright moon rises in the red clouds, and stars flash in the sky. &lt;br />;The beautiful light hangs from the sky, how fresh the colors are! &lt;br />;We are not Chisong or Ziqiao. Who can live longer than a cultivator? &lt;br />;It’s a pleasure to play like this, and maybe it will keep me alive for a hundred years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Furong Pond: a scene in the Bronze Bird Garden in Yecheng (now Linzhang, Hebei Province). Tongque Garden is located in the west of Yecheng. It is named after the Tongque Terrace. It is Cao Cao&#39;s royal garden. Hibiscus means lotus. &lt;br />;Chaan (niǎn): the car used by emperors and concubines. Travel: One word is &quot;Wandering&quot;. &lt;br />;Irrigation: one means &quot;irrigation&quot;. &lt;br />;Jiamu: refers to the lush and beautiful forest trees. Tongchuan: water flow in the garden. This sentence says that trees are planted densely along both sides of the river in the garden. &lt;br />;Bizhi: low-hanging tree branches. Whisk: Gently pass over. Feather cover: A hood decorated with feathers. &lt;br />;Repair: long. MO: Contact. &lt;br />;Jingfeng: A strong wind caused by a speeding car. Hub (gǔ): The log in the center of the wheel, connected to one end of the spokes around it. There is a round hole in the middle for inserting the shaft. This &quot;hub&quot; refers to the axle head of the wheel. &lt;br />;Danxia: sunset glow, red. &lt;br />;Hua Xing: A star that shines with brilliance. &lt;br />;Xiutian: from the sky down. &lt;br />;The five colors: green, red, yellow, white, and black were regarded as the correct colors in ancient times. This refers to the many colors of the rainbow. Yihe: How. &lt;br />;Songqiao: Chisongzi and Prince Qiao are two legendary immortals. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two sentences indicate the time and place of the tour and swimming pool, and describe the joyful mood of taking a night tour of the West Garden. The word &quot;night&quot; highlights the poet&#39;s strong interest in traveling and is also the basis for the description of the scenery in the following text. &quot;Walking in the West Garden&quot; also expresses the poet&#39;s relaxed and happy mood at that time. It is precisely because of this carefree journey that the scenery described below is so pleasing to the eye and intoxicating. &quot;West Garden&quot; is where Furong Pond is located, where poets often gather. Cao Zhi&#39;s poem &quot;Public Banquet&quot;: &quot;The prince respects his guests and is tireless all night long. He travels to the West Garden in the clear night, and flies to follow each other.&quot; That is to say, they were written There is a joyous scene here day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ten sentences in the middle continue the revision of the article, writing about what was seen during the trip, linking &quot;night travel&quot; and &quot;freedom&quot;, and focusing on describing the beautiful and moving night scene of Furong Pond. &quot;Double canals irrigate each other, and beautiful trees flow around the river&quot;, which always describes the elegance of the situation and environment here. Then the two sentences &quot;Bizhi&quot; are used to describe Jiamu in detail: Dense and verdant trees grow around the canal, setting off each other. The lower branches and leaves are horizontal, blocking the road, and the repairers cover the sky and the sun, reaching the cloud surface. Later, he continued to write about what he saw during the trip and the pleasant feeling at that time with &quot;The trembling wind turned the wheel, and the birds flew before me&quot;. All living and inanimate objects seemed to be vying for the poet&#39;s arrival. The trembling wind The breeze seems to be supporting the poet&#39;s chariot, and the flying birds seem to be leading the way for the poet. The leisurely and contented mood is vividly displayed in the paper repair. Because it is a night tour, the beautiful scenery of Furong Pond is not described in detail here. Instead, the outline of the Furong Pond is outlined with thick lines and uses a combination of movement and stillness to express a beautiful artistic conception and show the infinite vitality of Furong Pond. The last four sentences turn to write about the beauty of the night sky. A bright moon is embedded in the colorful sunset, and the crystal stars in the sky appear and disappear between the clouds, twinkling and shining, forming a colorful picture. In this elegant and picturesque scenery, the poet has simply been placed in a fairyland and forgotten his own existence. He unconsciously sighed, &quot;The sky is shining with brilliance, and the five colors are so fresh.&quot; These sentences use bright colors to depict the night scene of Furong Pond in a bizarre and colorful way, which shows a major feature of his creative creations. This is consistent with his emphasis on &quot;poetry is about beauty&quot; in &quot;Classics and Essays&quot;. Liu Zhen&#39;s poem &quot;Public Banquet&quot;: &quot;The chariots and chariots are flying with plain covers, and the entourage is full of people on the roadside. The moonrise illuminates the garden, and the precious trees are lush and green. The Qingchuan flows through the stone canal, and the flowing waves are fish protection.&quot; The scenery written is similar to this poem. , but the use of diction is much inferior to this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last four sentences, the pen turns and writes about the feelings of traveling. &quot;Song&quot;, Chisongzi, the legendary Yan Emperor Shennong Shiyu Master, later became an immortal together with the Yan Emperor girl. &quot;Qiao&quot;, Prince Qiao, is the Prince of Zhou Ling and Prince Jin. It is said that he likes to play the sheng to make the phoenix sing. Later, the Taoist priest Fuqiu Gong took over to cultivate Songshan and became an immortal. Cao Pi has never believed in the magic of magical alchemists. In his &quot;Xing Yangliu Xing&quot;, there is a sentence &quot;Wang Qiao&#39;s false words, red pine trees hang empty words&quot;. In &quot;Dian Lun·On Alchemy&quot;, he pointed out the magical alchemists through specific facts. It&#39;s not believable. Therefore, he reminds us of the fact that no one can truly become a god in the real world, and expresses his desire to enjoy himself in this picturesque scenery, make his body and mind happy, and seek longevity. &quot;Wandering makes your mind happy, and protecting yourself for a hundred years&quot; is a plain and optimistic attitude. This association further contrasts the beauty of the scenery of Furong Pond and the endless fun of visiting the garden, which made the poet so intoxicated that he never wanted to leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the banquet poems of the Jian&#39;an period, this one can be said to be the most outstanding. Its series of characteristics, such as the increase in scene descriptions, the use of antithetical sentences, the gorgeous rhetoric, and the spectacular scenery, all reflect some important changes in the poetic style at that time. Therefore, it has special merits in the history of poetry. The poem spends most of its space describing garden scenery, which also had an influence on later garden poetry and landscape poetry. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In the 16th year of Jian&#39;an (211), the 16th year of Emperor Xian of the Han Dynasty, Cao Pi was appointed as a lieutenant general with five sense organs, established an official office, and became deputy prime minister. The whole world admires you, and there are like clouds of guests. At that time, a group of scribes gathered in Yecheng, the base camp of Cao Wei, forming the Ye literati group with him as the core. Cao Pi was the leader, Cao Zhi was an important member, and most of the &quot;Seven Sons of Jian&#39;an&quot; participated. On their free days, they feasted, traveled, sang and composed poems. This poem is believed to have been written when Cao Pi was appointed Wu Guan Zhonglang General or a few years later. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/caopi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Cao Pi, Emperor Gaozuwen of Cao Wei (winter 187 - June 29, 226), courtesy name Zihuan, was a famous statesman and writer during the Three Kingdoms period and the founding emperor of Cao Wei. He reigned from 220 to 226 AD. . During his reign, border troubles were quelled. Defeat Xianbei, repair with Xiongnu, Di, Qiang and other foreign barbarians, and restore the Han Dynasty&#39;s establishment in the Western Regions. In addition to military affairs, Cao Pi was fond of literature since childhood and made achievements in poetry, fu, and literature. He was especially good at five-character poems. Together with his father Cao Cao and his younger brother Cao Zhi, he was also known as the Three Caos. There are two volumes of &quot;Collection of Emperor Wen of Wei&quot;. In addition, Cao Pi authored &quot;Classics&quot;, of which &quot;Thesis&quot; is the first systematic literary criticism monograph in the history of Chinese literature. After his death, he was given the temple name Gaozu (as Shizu in &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot;), posthumous title Emperor Wen, and was buried in Shouyang Mausoleum. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 04:23:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与诸子登岘山 | 孟浩然]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310241]]><description> &lt;h2>;Climbing Mount Xian with the Masters&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Meng Haoran&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;People and affairs change over time, and exchanges become ancient and modern. &lt;br />;The mountains and rivers have left traces of their beauty, and we will come here again. &lt;br />;The fish beam is shallow when the water falls, and the dream is deep when the weather is cold. &lt;br />;The Yanggong Monument is still there, and I shed tears after reading it. (Shang Yi&#39;s work: Zi Zai) &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;People and things in the world change, and summer passes When the cold comes, time passes, forming history from ancient times to the present. &lt;br />;We can now climb and visit the scenic spots and historic sites preserved throughout the country. &lt;br />;When the water falls and the rocks come out, Yuliangzhou is clear and shallow; when the weather is cold and the trees fall, Yunmengze is vast and boundless. &lt;br />;The monument to Yang Hu of Jin Dynasty is still standing majestically. After reading the inscription, my clothes were wet with tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Xianshan: A Xianshou Mountain, located south of present-day Xiangyang City, Hubei Province. Zhuzi: refers to several friends of the poet. &lt;br />;Metabolism: alternating changes. &lt;br />;Coming and going: the old goes and the new comes. &lt;br />;Revisiting: For Yang Hu, he once climbed to Xian Mountain. Climb: Climb a mountain to watch. &lt;br />;Yuliang: the name of a sandbar located in the Mianshui River of Lumen Mountain in Xiangyang. &lt;br />;Mengze: Yunmengze, ancient Daze, now Jianghan Plain. &lt;br />;Word: One is &quot;Shang&quot;. &lt;br />;Yanggong Monument: Built by later generations to commemorate the famous general Yang Hu of the Western Jin Dynasty. When Yang Hu was guarding Xiangyang, he often went to Xian Mountain with his friends to drink wine and write poems. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a touching and sentimental piece. Xian Mountain is a famous scenic spot in Xiangyang. Meng Haoran paid tribute to the past and the present here, and expressed his gratitude for his life experience. He once again expressed the ancient theme of feeling sad about the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first couplet &quot;People change, and exchanges become ancient and modern&quot; is an ordinary truth. From the change of dynasties to the rise and fall of a family, as well as people&#39;s birth, old age, illness and death, joys and sorrows, human affairs are always changing, and no one has not felt it. Human society is always developing and changing. The waves behind the Yangtze River push the waves ahead, and a new generation replaces the old. This is an irreversible law of nature. Everything in the past is gone, and everything today will soon become the past. From ancient times to the present, year after year, day after day, cold comes and summer comes, spring goes and autumn comes, time is passing ruthlessly forever. The two sentences in the first couplet were written out of thin air, seemingly without a title, but they reveal the poet&#39;s confusion and infinite melancholy, and are full of a deep sense of vicissitudes of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The chin couplet closely follows the first couplet. &quot;The scenic spots left in the country&quot; are inherited from the &quot;ancient&quot;, and &quot;I will come again&quot; are inherited from the &quot;present&quot;. &quot;Significant sites&quot; refer to the Yanggong Monument on the mountain and Yuliangzhou at the foot of the mountain. The author&#39;s sad mood comes from today&#39;s arrival. When you climb Xian Mountain, the first thing you see is the Yanghu Temple and the Monument of Tears. Yang Hu had great political achievements in guarding Xiangyang and won the hearts of the people. After his death, the people of Xiangyang missed him and erected a temple and a monument in Xian Mountain. &quot;Everyone who looks at his monument sheds tears. Du Yu named it the &#39;tears of tears&#39; monument.&quot; Looking at the monument, I was filled with emotion, thinking of the legacy of my predecessors and my own obscurity, which made me feel sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The neck couplet writes about what you see while climbing. Looking from a distance when climbing the mountain, you can see the water is falling, the vegetation is withering, and it is a depressing scene. The author captured the unique scenery of the place at that time and extracted it, which can not only show that the time sequence is severe winter, but also heighten the sadness of the author&#39;s mood. &quot;Shallow&quot; refers to water. Due to the &quot;water falling&quot;, more of Yuliang Island is exposed to the water, so it is called &quot;shallow&quot;. When you see Yuliangzhou, you will naturally think of the hermit Gao Xian Pang Degong who was friends with Sima Hui and Zhuge Liang and refused Liu Biao&#39;s invitations several times. &quot;Deep&quot; refers to the farther distance, the endless, vast and far-reaching Yunmengze unfolds before our eyes. The weather is cold, the water is clear, and the air-conditioning is eerie, which makes the lake even more &quot;deep&quot;. In ancient times, &quot;Yunmeng&quot; was collectively called &quot;Yunze&quot; in the south and north of the Yangtze River in Hubei Province. The south of the Yangtze River was called &quot;Mengze&quot; and the north of the Yangtze River was called &quot;Yunze&quot;. Later, most of it was silted up and became land. Today, dozens of lakes such as Honghu Lake and Liangzi Lake are all Yunmeng Ruins. Mengze cannot be seen in Xianshan, but it is used to refer to general lakes and swamps. These two lines of poetry describe a depressed and desolate mood, used to set off the context. When the poet climbed up to Xian Mountain, he could not help but feel the withering of late autumn, which made him lament that &quot;how much life is there&quot; and &quot;the past days have been so bitter&quot;. Another year has passed in the blink of an eye, and he has no talent but nowhere to display it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last couplet, &quot;The Yanggong Monument is still there&quot;, the word &quot;Shang&quot; is very powerful, and it contains complex content. Yang Hu was guarding Xiangyang in the early Jin Dynasty, but Meng Haoran wrote this poem in the prosperous Tang Dynasty. There were more than four hundred years between them. The change of dynasties and the changes in personnel were so huge! However, the Yanggong Monument still stands on Xianshou Mountain, which is admirable. At the same time, it also contains the author&#39;s sad emotions. More than 400 years ago, Yang Hu served the country (referring to the Jin Dynasty) and did some good things for the people, so his reputation will last forever and be passed down from generation to generation. Thinking that he is still a &quot;commoner&quot; and has done nothing, he will inevitably be lost after his death. It is said that the contrast between this and the &quot;still existing&quot; Yanggong Monument is sad, so it is inevitable that I will &quot;cry after reading it&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem was written because the author was depressed when he was seeking an official position. The poet climbed to Xian Mountain, paid homage to the Yanggong Monument, missed the past and regretted the present, and expressed his emotions. Thinking that he had no ambition, he felt extremely sad and wet with tears. Placket. The whole poem draws on ancient times to express feelings, integrating scene description, lyricism and reasoning. The feelings are sincere and deep, and the profoundness is seen in the plain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two couplets of the poem have a certain philosophical nature, and the first four sentences of the poem summarize Yang Hu&#39;s words. &quot;Personnel affairs&quot;, characters and their deeds, are subject to metabolism. One generation passed away, and another generation took over. This became ancient and modern. The landscape is still a scenic spot today, but it is our generation’s turn to visit it. The last two couplets not only describe the scenery, are rich in images, but also are full of the author&#39;s passion, making it a poem of a poet rather than a poem of a philosopher. &quot;Annihilation into obscurity&quot; is a true portrayal of the poet&#39;s own experience. The scene evoked emotion, made him feel sad, and made him shed tears. Thinking that I have no ambition, I feel extremely sad and my clothes are wet with tears. The whole poem feels the shortness of life and expresses the sadness of unrecognized talents. At the same time, the language is easy to understand, the emotions are sincere and touching, and he is known for being plain and profound. Shen Deqian of the Qing Dynasty commented on Meng Haoran&#39;s poems: &quot;I got it from quiet enlightenment. The words are light but the taste is not thin.&quot; This poem does have such interest. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written while the poet was studying in seclusion in his hometown and writing poems for his own entertainment. The specific time is unknown. The poet and a few friends went up to Xian Mountain to play. They paid homage to the Yanggong Monument and remembered what Yang Hu said: &quot;Since the universe has existed, there has been this mountain. Since then, sages and victors have climbed here and looked into the distance, just like me and you, everything is annihilated.&quot; The words &quot;hearing makes people sad&quot; are consistent with the poet&#39;s situation. Therefore, I wrote this poem to express my feelings through ancient times. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/menghaoran.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Meng Haoran (689-740), courtesy name Haoran, nicknamed Mengshan, was a native of Xiangyang, Xiangzhou (now Xiangyang, Hubei Province). He was a famous landscape pastoral poet in the Tang Dynasty and was known as &quot;Meng Xiangyang&quot; in the world. Because he had never been an official, he was also called &quot;Mengshan Man&quot;. Meng Haoran was born in the prosperous Tang Dynasty. In his early years, he had ambitions to serve the world. After being difficult and painfully disappointed in his official career, he was still able to respect himself, did not flatter the world, and practiced Taoism and lived in seclusion for the rest of his life. He once lived in seclusion in Lumen Mountain. When he was 40 years old, he traveled to Chang&#39;an and failed to win the imperial examination. He once wrote poems in Taixue, and became famous among the officials. He was so impressed that he wrote for him. In the twenty-fifth year of Kaiyuan (737), Zhang Jiuling attracted the shogunate and lived in seclusion. Most of Meng&#39;s poems are five-character short stories, mostly describing landscapes, pastoral scenes, the joy of living in seclusion, and the mood of traveling and traveling. Although there are some cynical words in it, it is more of the poet&#39;s self-expression. Meng Haoran&#39;s poems have unique artistic attainments. Later generations called Meng Haoran and Wang Wei, another landscape poet in the prosperous Tang Dynasty, &quot;Wang Meng&quot;. There are three volumes of &quot;Meng Haoran Collection&quot; handed down to the world. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 05:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>