<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[秋词二首·其一 | 刘禹锡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310182]]><description> &lt;h2>;Two Autumn Poems·Part 1&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Liu Yuxi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Since ancient times, autumn has been sad and lonely. I say that autumn is better than spring. &lt;br />;A crane flies above the clouds in a clear sky, bringing poetry to the blue sky. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Since ancient times, poets and poets have lamented the depression of autumn, but I say that autumn is far better than spring. . &lt;br />;On an autumn day when the sky is clear and a crane flies up through the clouds, it triggers my poetry to soar into the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Sadness and loneliness: Lamenting depression. &lt;br />;Chun Dynasty: Spring. &lt;br />;Paiyun: means to push away the clouds. &lt;br />;Pai: Push, which means breakthrough. &lt;br />;Bixiao: blue sky. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Liu Yuxi&#39;s &quot;Autumn Poems&quot; is unconventional and takes a new approach. It sings the beauty of autumn with the greatest enthusiasm. What is even more rare and valuable is that &quot;Autumn Poems&quot; was written after the poet was demoted to Langzhou, which makes people admire Liu Yuxi&#39;s way of dealing with others. There are two original poems, this is the first of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Since ancient times, autumn has been sad and lonely. I say that autumn is better than spring.&quot; Since Song Yu left a famous sentence in &quot;Nine Bian&quot;, &quot;It is sad, autumn is also the spirit&quot;, sadness has become It has become a color and an emotion of autumn; sadness has become the autumn in my heart. However, the poet started with a discussion, categorically denying the previous concept of mourning the autumn, and showing an exciting and upward poetic sentiment. &quot;I say&quot; expresses the poet&#39;s self-confidence. Although this self-confidence is tainted with an unfortunate color, the poet&#39;s broad mind remarkably dissolves this misfortune. &quot;Victory in the Spring Dynasty&quot; is the poet&#39;s fullest recognition of the autumn scenery. This kind of recognition is by no means just a momentary emotional impulse, but is integrated into the poet&#39;s higher-level rational thinking about autumn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;A crane flying over the clouds in the clear sky brings poetry to the blue sky.&quot; The poet grasped the &quot;a crane flying over the clouds&quot; in autumn. The description of this unique landscape shows the crisp air in autumn and the clear sky. An open view of floating white clouds. The crane flying in the clouds also carries the poet&#39;s poetry and flies to the sky together. Although this crane is lonely, the momentum it displays is extraordinary. The profound meaning contained in the word &quot;Pai&quot; cannot be expressed in words. Perhaps, the poet refers to himself as &quot;crane&quot;, or perhaps the poet regards &quot;crane&quot; as the embodiment of unyielding. Here, there are philosophical implications and artistic charm, which are thought-provoking and chantable. What it gives readers is not only the vitality and plain color of autumn, but also a noble spirit and noble sentiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When reading such poems, what fills our hearts is by no means a sad atmosphere. Following the poet&#39;s &quot;poetry&quot; and with the help of the wings of the poet&#39;s imagination, we gallop through the blue sky like a flying horse. As a result, the cranes soar into the sky, the poetry is far-reaching, &quot;real&quot; and &quot;virtual&quot; are merged together, and what is obtained is an inspirational and emotional beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is powerful and magnificent, integrating emotions, scenery and principles. It shows a high spirit and broad mind, and sings an extraordinary autumn song, leaving a legacy for our descendants. What is left is a rare spiritual wealth. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; In 805 AD (the first year of Yongzhen), Shunzong ascended the throne and appointed Wang Shuwen to reform the government. Liu Yuxi also participated in this reform movement. Failure is demoted. But he has a strong desire for differences and wants to be different in everything he does, and refuses to follow what others say. &quot;Two Autumn Poems&quot; was written by Sima Shi, who was demoted to Langzhou. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/liuyuxi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Liu Yuxi (772-842), courtesy name Mengde, was born in Luoyang, Henan, and in Xingyang, Zhengzhou, Henan. He said that he was a descendant of King Jing of Shanzhong Mountain in Hanzhong. During the Tang Dynasty, he was a minister, writer, and philosopher, and was known as the &quot;Poetry Hero&quot;. His family is a scholarly family with Confucianism passed down from generation to generation. He advocated political innovation and was one of the central figures in the political innovation activities of Wang Shuwen School. Later, Yongzhen&#39;s reform failed and he was demoted to Sima of Langzhou (now Changde, Hunan). According to Mr. Zhou Xinguo, a historian and collector in Changde, Hunan, Liu Yuxi was demoted to Sima of Langzhou and wrote the famous &quot;Spring View of Han Shou City&quot; during his demotion. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 05:23:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四时田园杂兴·其三十一 | 范成大]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310181]]><description> &lt;h2>;Pastoral Miscellany in Four Seasons·Thirty-One&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Fan Chengda&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;Working in the fields during the day and planting hemp at night, the children of the village are responsible for their own affairs . &lt;br />;Children and grandsons are still engaged in farming and weaving, and they also learn to grow melons near the mulberry tree. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Go to the fields to work in the fields during the day, and twist twine at home at night. Men and women in the village each have their own housework. &lt;br />;Although the children did not know how to plow and weave, they still learned to grow melons under the shade of the mulberry trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Farming: generally refers to farming and weeding, and engaging in field work. &lt;br />;Ji Ma: twist hemp into thread. &lt;br />;Each person is in charge: Each person has a certain job. &lt;br />;Unsolved: Don’t understand. &lt;br />;For: to engage in, to participate in. &lt;br />;Pong: close. &lt;br />;Yin: shade. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brief Analysis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem describes a scene in rural summer life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first sentence &quot;I work in the fields during the day and work on hemp at night&quot; means: I go to the fields to weed during the day and twist the hemp thread at night. &quot;Tilting&quot; means weeding. In early summer, the rice seedlings need to be weeded. This is what men do. &quot;Ji Ma&quot; means that after women finish other work during the day, they knead twine and weave it into cloth at night. This sentence directly describes the labor scene. In the second sentence, &quot;The children of the village are responsible for their own families.&quot; &quot;Children&quot; refers to men and women. The whole poem uses the tone of old farmers, and &quot;children&quot; refers to young people. &quot;Head of the family&quot; means that both men and women have no time to spare, and each has his or her own business. The third sentence &quot;Children and grandchildren are not yet available for plowing and weaving.&quot; &quot;Children and grandchildren&quot; refers to those children. They don&#39;t know how to farm or weave, but they are not idle either. They have been exposed to it since they were young, so they &quot;learned to grow melons under the shade of mulberry trees&quot;, that is, they learned to grow melons under the lush mulberry trees. This is a common phenomenon in rural areas, but it is quite unique. The conclusion expresses the innocence of rural children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poet uses a fresh style of writing to give a more detailed description of the tense labor atmosphere in the countryside in early summer, which is very interesting to read. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/fanchengda.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Fan Chengda (1126-1193), also known as Shihu layman, was named Zuneng. Han nationality, from Wuxian County, Pingjiang (now Suzhou, Jiangsu Province). Poet of the Southern Song Dynasty. Posthumous title Wenmu. Starting from the Jiangxi School, he later studied the poetry of the Middle and Late Tang Dynasties, inherited the realism spirit of the New Yuefu poets such as Bai Juyi, Wang Jian, and Zhang Ji, and finally became his own school. The style is simple, fresh and charming. Poetry has a wide range of themes, and the works that reflect the content of rural social life are the most successful. Together with Yang Wanli, Lu You and You Miao, he is known as the &quot;Four Great ZTE Poets&quot; of the Southern Song Dynasty. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>