<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[纥干狐尾 | 佚名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310132]]><description> &lt;h2>;Hegan Foxtail&lt;/h2>;[Unknown] Anonymous&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>; Those who have Hegan in Bingzhou are good at drama. There are rumors that there is a fox spirit in the city, which makes people panic. One day, He found a fox tail. The fox was hidden behind his clothes. He came to his wife and sat on his side to expose it. His wife suspected that he was a fox charm, so she took an ax and tried to kill it. He Qianqi said: &quot;I am not charming.&quot; His wife did not believe it. He walked to the neighbor&#39;s house, and the neighbor chased him away with swords and sticks. He Qian kowtowed and thanked him: &quot;I, He Qian, am the first dramatist. Why do you want to kill me?&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation &lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; There was a man named He Qian in Bingzhou (now Taiyuan, Shanxi) who liked to joke. There are local rumors that a fox is haunted, and everyone is panicked. One day, He Gan got a fox tail and sewed it on the back of his clothes. He came to his wife&#39;s side and sat sideways, deliberately exposing the fox&#39;s tail. When his wife saw him, she secretly suspected that he was a vixen, so she quietly picked up an ax and struck at him. He hurriedly said: &quot;I&#39;m not a vixen!&quot; His wife didn&#39;t believe it. He Gan ran to his neighbor&#39;s house, and the neighbors picked up knives and sticks to chase him. He kowtowed and apologized and said: &quot;I am Hegan. This is just a joke. Why do you want to kill me?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Yi: local; county里&lt;br />;panic: panic&lt;br />;for: yes&lt;br />;urgent: immediately, immediately&lt;br />;walk: run&lt;br />;xie: admit mistake, apologize&lt;br />;The first drama ear, what does it mean Kill Me: This is just a joke, why are you bent on killing me? &lt;br />;Fox: sewing with needle and thread&lt;br />;Drama: joking&lt;br />;Fox: fox pretending to be a ghost&lt;br />;Charm: ghost&lt;br />;Cut: chop&lt;br />;No.: only, just&lt;br />; br />;Good: hobbies, preferences&lt;br />;Zhi: pronoun, referring to fox tail&lt;br />;Ear: that’s all&lt;br />;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;Also known as anonymous, it refers to a person whose identity is unknown or whose name has not yet been learned. Literary and musical works originating from ancient times or among the people and whose author is unknown will be named anonymously. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[忆母 | 倪瑞璿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310121]]><description> &lt;h2>;Memory of the Mother&lt;/h2>;[Qing Dynasty] Ni Ruixuan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The river is difficult to navigate and I can’t cross it. I don’t know whether it will be safe or not. How about it? &lt;br />;I shed tears of missing my loved ones every now and then, fearing that I will shed more tears of missing my son. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The river is wide, but it is difficult for ships to navigate. It is not my fault. , I wonder how you are doing recently, are you safe? &lt;br />;I often cry secretly because I miss my mother, but I’m afraid my mother will shed even more tears when she misses me! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Navigation: sailing. &lt;br />;Guo: fault. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A native of Suqian, Jiangnan, Xu Qitai’s second wife. ○ It is a woman&#39;s virtue to be docile and serve her duty. She can only express her hidden potential, punish traitors and scold sycophants. Is there such a person among women? Every time I read it, I am in awe. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:23:20 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>