<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[卜算子·雪月最相宜 | 张孝祥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239231]]><description> &lt;h2>;Bu Suanzi·The snow and moon are most suitable&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Zhang Xiaoxiang&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The snow and moon are the most suitable, and the plum and snow are all clear. Last year, when there was snow in the south of the Yangtze River, plum blossoms appeared at the end of the month. This year&lt;brthis/>;The plum blossoms bloomed early this year, and they remain the same year and month. The cold and solitary light is bright, and all I need is some snow. Today&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The end of the month: the end of the month. &lt;brJin/>;Some: A little bit. Today&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; If the three of plain snow, bright moon, and delicate plum trees are present, the scenery will be clear and beautiful. However, it is difficult to have all three at once, so comparing this year with last year cannot be without regrets. This word expresses feelings about the scene. It seems to be diluted, but it contains infinite feelings of the past and present. The predecessors said that Zhang Xiaoxiang&#39;s poems have &quot;the grace of being free from the dust, as free as the pen of God&quot;, and it is true. Today&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/zhangxiaoxiang.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt; /center>;&lt;/div>;Zhang Xiaoxiang (1132-1170), whose courtesy name was Anguo and also nicknamed Yuhu Jushi, was born in Wujiang, Liyang (now Wujiang Town, He County, Anhui Province), and lived in Yinxian County, Mingzhou (now Ningbo, Zhejiang Province). A famous poet and calligrapher in the Southern Song Dynasty. The seventh generation grandson of Zhang Ji, a poet of the Tang Dynasty. Zhang Xiaoxiang is good at poetry and prose, especially at ci. His style is grand and bold, and he is one of the representative writers of the &quot;Bold and Bold School&quot;. There are &quot;Collected Works of Yuhu Layman&quot; and &quot;Yuhu Ci&quot; handed down from generation to generation. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江城子·江景 | 苏轼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239222]]><description> &lt;h2>;Jiangchengzi·Jiangjing&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Su Shi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;On the lake, he and Zhang Xian wrote the same poem, and sometimes they heard playing the zither&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was raining in Phoenix Mountain The sky is clear at first, the water and wind are clear, and the sunset is bright. A hibiscus bloomed gracefully. A pair of egrets flew from nowhere, admiring Pingting if you wanted to. &lt;br />;Suddenly I heard mourning kites being played on the river, expressing sorrow and emotion. Who can listen to them! The smoke gathers and the clouds gather, it is Xiang Ling as promised. I want to wait until the end of the song to ask for it, but no one can see it, and the peaks are green. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Under the Phoenix Mountain, it is clear after the rain, the clouds are clear, the wind is clear, and the sunset glow Bright. A lotus flower, although it has bloomed, is still beautiful and pure. A pair of egrets flew by somewhere, and they also came to admire the beauty of the kite player. Suddenly I heard the sad tune on the river, full of sorrow, who could bear to listen to it. The mist is restrained by it, and the clouds are faded by it. This song is like the goddess of Xiangshui playing the harp to express her sorrow. When the song ends, she has drifted away, and only the green mountain peaks are still standing quietly. By the lake, it seems that the sad music is still rippling in the mountains and waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Lake: refers to the West Lake in Hangzhou. Zhang Xian: a famous poet in the Northern Song Dynasty. &lt;br />;Phoenix Mountain: south of West Lake in Hangzhou. &lt;br />;Fuyu: Lotus. &lt;br />;Pingting: Beautiful posture, this refers to a beautiful woman. &lt;br />;Jiang Shang: Yuan Wen of the Song Dynasty quoted it as &quot;Feast on the Banquet&quot; in &quot;Weng Wan Xian Commentary&quot;. &lt;br />;Zheng: stringed instrument, long wooden shape. Before the Han and Jin Dynasties, the zither had twelve strings, and later it was increased to thirteen, fifteen, sixteen and twenty-one strings. &lt;br />;Xiang Ling: The goddess of Xiangshui. According to legend, she was originally the concubine of Shun. &quot;Chu Ci·Nine Songs&quot; contains &quot;Mrs. Xiang&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This word was written by Su Shi from the fifth year to the seventh year of Xining (1072) when he was appointed as the Tong magistrate of Hangzhou and he was over eighty years old at that time. It was written by the famous Zhang Xian (990-1078) when he visited the West Lake with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The author interestingly sticks to the title &quot;hearing the zheng played&quot; and describes the beauty of the zheng player and the moving music from many aspects. In the poem, the zither player is placed in the clear lakes and mountains after the rain and the beautiful sunset, so that the characters and the scenery complement each other, and the music and the mountains and rivers complement each other. In the description of the characters, the author uses metaphors and foil techniques. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first three sentences describe the scenery of mountains and lakes, which are just background images of the characters. The two sentences &quot;a hibiscus&quot; follow immediately, which not only describe the lotus on the water surface, but also use the hibiscus out of the water as a metaphor for the beauty playing the kite, which has the artistic effect of pun. From a structural point of view, this scene is described on the surface, but in fact it turns to the description of the kite player. It can be said that it is seamless. According to &quot;Mozhuang Manlu&quot;, the kite player is in her thirties, &quot;elegant and graceful, and full of attitude.&quot; Here, the metaphor of &quot;a flower blooming over Shang Yingying&quot; is not only accurate, but also very interesting. Then the egret seemed to be admiring intentionally to highlight the beauty of the kite player. The two egrets in the poem actually refer to the situation of two guests staring blankly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next film focuses on music. It is written based on the overall melody of the music, so it is called &quot;Ai Zheng&quot;. It is written based on the emotions conveyed by the music, so it is said that &quot;bitter (very, extremely) contains emotions&quot;; it is said &quot;who can be sent to listen&quot;, which means that the music is sad, who Can bear to listen, is written from the perspective of the listener; here we further exaggerate the sadness of the music, saying that the ignorant nature is also moved by it: the mist is restrained by it, and the clouds are faded by it; finally, to sum up, this sadness The music is like the goddess of Xiangshui pouring out her sorrow. Xiang Ling is an allusion to Emperor E and Nvying. The lyrics are written here, pushing the sad and moving music to the highest peak step by step. It seems that such sad and moving music does not belong to the world, but can only come from the hands of gods like the goddess of Xiangshui. At the same time, the phrase &quot;according to the agreement is Xiang Ling&quot; is a metaphor for the beauty of the kite player being like Xiang Ling. At the end of the poem, the sentence &quot;according to the promise&quot; is waiting to be written about the person, but it adopts a hard-to-get approach. Not only does it not describe the person from the front, but it writes that the person playing the kite has drifted away, and only the green mountain peaks are still standing quietly. By the lake, it seems that the sad music is still rippling in the mountains and waters. The two lines &quot;when no one is there, one can count the green peaks&quot; are taken from the poem &quot;Provincial Examination of Xiangling Gusel&quot; written by Qian Qi, a poet from the Tang Dynasty. &quot;At the end of the song, when no one is there, one can count the green peaks on the river&quot;, it is so natural, appropriate and without revealing any trace. It not only has a moving image, but also implicitly inherits the sentence &quot;Yi Yue is Xiang Ling&quot; in structure, combining the upper and lower allusions. &quot;Several peaks are green&quot; echoes the beginning of the poem &quot;It begins to clear after rain in Phoenix Mountain&quot; describing the scene of rain passing through the green mountains, which can be said to be said forever. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/sushi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Su Shi, (January 8, 1037 - August 24, 1101), also known as Zizhan and Hezhong, also known as Tieguan Taoist and Dongpo layman, known as Su Dongpo and Su Xian in the world. Han nationality, a native of Meishan, Meizhou (Meishan City, Sichuan Province), his ancestral home is Luancheng, Hebei Province, a famous writer, calligrapher, and painter in the Northern Song Dynasty, and a celebrity in water control in history. Su Shi was a literary leader in the mid-Northern Song Dynasty and made great achievements in poetry, lyrics, prose, calligraphy, and painting. His writing is bold and unbridled; his poems are broad in subject matter, fresh and vigorous, good at using exaggerated metaphors, and have a unique style. Together with Huang Tingjian, he is called &quot;Su Huang&quot;; His prose writings are grand and bold. Together with Ouyang Xiu, he is called &quot;Ou Su&quot; and is one of the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Su Shi was good at calligraphy and one of the &quot;Four Masters of the Song Dynasty&quot;; he was good at literati painting, especially ink bamboo, strange rocks, dead wood, etc. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan and Ouyang Xiu, they are known as the &quot;Four Great Masters of Eternal Writing&quot;. His works include &quot;Dongpo Seven Collections&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yi Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yuefu&quot;, &quot;Xiaoxiang Bamboo and Stone Picture Scroll&quot;, &quot;Old Trees and Strange Stones Picture Scroll&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:23:10 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>