<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[玉蝴蝶·望处雨收云断 | 柳永]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239192]]><description> &lt;h2>;Jade Butterfly·Looking at the place where the rain has gathered and the clouds have broken off&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Liu Yong&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Looking at the place where the rain has gathered and the clouds have broken up, quietly watching the autumn light. The desolate evening scene makes Song Yu feel desolate. The water is gentle and the wind is gentle, the apple blossoms are getting older, the moon is cold and the dew is cold, and the phoenix leaves are turning yellow. Feeling sad. Where is the old friend? The smoke and water are vast. &lt;br />;Unforgettable, we have a wine party, a few lonely romances, many times changing into stars and frost. The sea is vast and the mountains are far away, and it is unknown where Xiaoxiang is. Thinking of the two swallows, it is difficult to rely on distant faith, pointing to the dusk sky and empty consciousness to return home. Looking at each other sadly. In the sound of broken Hong, the setting sun rises. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;I quietly leaned on the railing and stared, the rain had stopped, the clouds had dispersed, and I watched The autumn colors fade into the horizon. In the autumn evening, the scenery is bleak and desolate, which really makes people sigh with Song Yu&#39;s sorrow for autumn. The gentle breeze blows over the water, and the white apple blossoms gradually wither and fade. The cool moon freezes the dew. The sycamore tree cannot withstand the invasion of the cold dew on the moonlit night, and its leaves have withered and turned yellow. This situation makes one feel lonely and sentimental. My old friends, where are you? All I can see in front of me is the endless autumn water, and the smoke is confusing. &lt;br />;The elegant gathering of literati and the indulgent feast are still vivid and unforgettable. After parting, we have let down so many romantic moments, and the stars have passed, all because of the distance between you and me, separated by the sky. The sea is so far away, the mountains are so far away, I don’t know where and what year we meet? It makes people feel miserable and hesitant. Thinking of the swallows flying away in pairs, it is difficult to rely on them to send messages and messages to old friends; looking forward to the return of old friends, pointing to the vast sky and identifying the returning ships, who knows that all the thousands of sails have failed, and it is also a vain hope. I stood silently, looking at each other sadly, only to see that the setting sun had faded, and the mournful cry of the lone wild goose was still floating in the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Jade Butterfly, the name of the brand. This tune has two types: Xiaoling and long tune. The Xiaoling was created by Wen Tingyun of the Tang Dynasty. It is a double tune. The upper part has four lines, rhymed with Sanping rhyme, with 21 characters; the lower part has four lines, rhymed with Sanping rhyme, with twenty-one characters. There are four characters in total. Eleven words. The long tune originated from Liu Yong of the Song Dynasty, also known as &quot;Jade Butterfly Slow&quot;. It has a double tune, ninety-nine characters, and a flat rhyme. There are also ninety-eight fonts. &lt;br />;The rain has stopped and the clouds have dispersed: the rain has stopped and the clouds have dispersed. &lt;br />;Desolate: cold and scattered, sparse. Kan: Okay. &lt;br />;Song Yu&#39;s desolation: refers to Song Yu&#39;s &quot;Nine Bian&quot;, which is extended to the sad autumn. Song Yu&#39;s &quot;Nine Bian&quot; said: &quot;What a tragedy! Autumn is the air, and the grass and trees are bleak and decaying!&quot;&lt;br />;Apple blossom: a kind of duckweed with small white flowers in summer and autumn. &lt;br />;Sentiment: sad. Send: make. &lt;br />;Literary wine party: a gathering where literati meet to drink wine and compose poems. Period: approx. &lt;br />;Jigu Fengyue: I have let down so many beautiful scenery. Ji: How many times. Gu: means &quot;to live up to&quot;, to let down. Fengyue: beautiful scenery. &lt;br />; Repeated changes in star frost: It has been several years. Star Frost: A star has one day every year, and frost falls every year. Therefore, it is called one star frost per year, and it is also used as a metaphor for the year and month. &lt;br />;Xiaoxiang: Another name for Xiangjiang River. This refers to the place where the person you miss lives. &lt;br />;Mutian: evening. &lt;br />;Empty: in vain. Return: A ship returning. &lt;br />;Standing under the setting sun: Standing under the setting sun in the evening for a long time until the sun sets. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is mainly lyrical, integrating scenery and narrative, recalling the past and nostalgia, travel and farewell, time and space. It forms a complete artistic whole with strong artistic appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Looking at the place where the rain has gathered and the clouds have broken down&quot; is a description of the scenery that can be seen with the naked eye. You can see the traces of the changing wind and clouds in the distance, making the autumn scenery even more sparse. The four words &quot;quietly by the lantern&quot; describe the worries of leaning alone in the lantern and looking into the distance. This kind of feeling is again based on &quot;watching the autumn light&quot;. &quot;Quietly&quot;, looking sad. Facing the desolate autumn scenery at dusk, it is natural to feel the sadness of autumn and think of the poet Song Yulai, the ancestor of the eternal sadness of autumn. &quot;The evening scene is desolate and desolate, which makes Song Yu feel desolate.&quot; The following sentence summarizes this feeling. Song Yu&#39;s sad autumn feelings and emotions about life experience all rushed into Liu Yong&#39;s heart and resonated with him. He suppressed thousands of thoughts, looked from far to near, selected the things that best expressed the characteristics of the autumn scenery, and made detailed descriptions. &quot;The water breeze is gentle, the apple blossoms are growing old, the moon dew is cold, and the phoenix leaves are floating yellow.&quot; The two sentences seem to be a very poetic picture taken with a close-up lens: I saw the autumn wind gently blowing on the water surface, and the white apple blossoms were blooming. The flowers are getting older. In autumn, when the moon is cold and the dew is cold, the sycamore leaves turn yellow and are gently floating down leaf by leaf. The desolate and rustling autumn night naturally gives people a sense of desolation and silence. The words &quot;light&quot; and &quot;cold&quot; describe the feeling of autumn. &quot;The apple blossoms grow old&quot; not only describes the scenery before the eyes, but also embodies the poet&#39;s feelings about the world and the growing beauty. The word &quot;yellow&quot; in &quot;The Wu leaves are falling yellow&quot; is used well, highlighting the image of the falling Wu leaves. The word &quot;gone with the wind&quot; has a sound, and the word &quot;yellow&quot; has a color. The word &quot;gone with the yellow&quot; is written in a vivid and colorful way. The word &quot;yellow&quot; exaggerates the atmosphere and embellishes the autumn scenery. The author captures the most typical autumn scenery such as water wind, apple blossoms, moon dew, and phoenix leaves, and uses the four words &quot;light&quot;, &quot;old&quot;, &quot;cold&quot; and &quot;yellow&quot; to highlight it, interweaving it into a deserted and lonely autumn scene. The pictures of objects fully pave the way for the following lyricism. The sentence &quot;removing feelings and hurting&quot; comes from the description of the scenery above. From the scenery to the feelings, there is a turning point in the word. After describing the scenery, the poet introduces the two sentences &quot;Where is the old friend, the smoke and water are vast&quot;, which not only connects the previous and the following, but also unifies the whole article, which is the main theme of the whole poem. &quot;The vastness of smoke and water&quot; refers to the misty and invisible scenery, which is vast and rich. It is also the confused emotion caused by missing the old friend. Here, emotion and scenery are intertwined. These few sentences are short and solemn, saturated with large strokes, full of ups and downs of emotion, and are the essence of the whole article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word &quot;unforgettable&quot; in the change of head evokes memories and expresses the feeling of missing the old friend, which is ups and downs and well-proportioned. The poet recalled the &quot;Wenqi Drinking Party&quot; when he was with his friends. It was a pleasant event that is still unforgettable. After the separation, things have changed, the stars have changed, the autumn light has changed several times, and I don’t know how many beautiful moments have passed in vain because I didn’t care to watch them. &quot;Several orphans&quot; and &quot;repeated changes&quot; refer to the long separation and are intended to strengthen the feeling of sadness after separation. The sentence &quot;The sea is vast and the mountains are far away&quot; turns from memories to the thoughts in front of me. &quot;Xiaoxiang&quot; here refers to the place where friends live. Since I don&#39;t know where my old friend is, it is said that &quot;I don&#39;t know where Xiaoxiang is.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Thinking of the two swallows, it is difficult to rely on distant faith, pointing to the dusk sky, and returning to the sky.&quot; It writes about the helpless mood caused by not being able to meet the person I miss. The swallows flying in front of you cannot deliver news to old friends, so if you want to communicate with friends, no one can trust you. Looking forward to the return of friends, but failed again and again, so the saying &quot;refers to the dusk sky, and the empty consciousness returns home&quot;. This sentence expresses the deep and sincere feelings of missing a friend with great affection. Seeing Guizhou in the sky, I suspected that it was an old friend returning, but in the end it was a misunderstanding. Guizhou was just an in vain to arouse lovesickness, as if mocking his own infatuation. The word &quot;empty&quot; brings to life the feeling of eagerly awaiting the return of friends. It pushes the feeling of missing friends to the climax and climax. The poet thinks about the other person and writes from the other person&#39;s perspective, thus reflecting his own feelings of wandering and wandering for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following &quot;looking at each other sadly&quot;, the pen turns back to itself. The poet uses Duanhong&#39;s wail to set off his loneliness and melancholy, which can be described as a wonderful combination of boundless beauty and a sad voice. The four words &quot;standing up to the setting sun&quot; draw the image of the lyrical protagonist. He stands in the sunset for a long time, as if in a daze, and his emotions are completely immersed in memories and longing. The two words &quot;Li Jin&quot; mean standing on the railing for a long time, thinking deeply about people far away, thus making the unbearable hardship of traveling alone appear outside the words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yong&#39;s poem has clear layers, complete structure and smooth context, which effectively conveys the rhythm of the poet&#39;s emotions. At the same time, the rhetoric is neither polished nor frivolous, but elegant in the vulgar, strange in the ordinary, meaningful and meaningful, so it can be appreciated by both refined and popular people. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The poem &quot;Jade Butterfly·Watching the Rain and Gathering the Clouds&quot; was written by the author in memory of his old friends in central Hunan. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/liuyong2.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Liu Yong (about 984-about 1053) was a famous poet in the Northern Song Dynasty and a representative of the graceful school. Han nationality, from Chong&#39;an (now Wuyishan, Fujian), originally named Sanbian, with the courtesy name Jingzhuang, and later changed his name to Yong, with the courtesy name Qiqing. He ranked seventh, also known as Liu Qi. He was a Jinshi in the Zhenzong Dynasty of the Song Dynasty, and became a tuntian Yuanwailang. In his old life, he was called Liu tuntian. He calls himself &quot;Liu Sanbian, who writes lyrics on orders&quot;, devotes his whole life to composing lyrics, and prides himself on being &quot;the prime minister in white clothes&quot;. Most of his poems describe the city scenery and the life of singing girls. He is especially good at expressing the feelings of traveling and traveling, and he is unique in creating slow poems. The narration is detailed, the scenes are blended, the language is popular, and the melody is harmonious. It was widely circulated at that time. It was said that &quot;anyone who has a well to drink can sing Liu Ci&quot;. He is one of the most representative figures of the Wanyue School and has an important influence on the development of Song Ci. It has great influence, and his representative works are &quot;Yulin Ring&quot; and &quot;Eight Sounds of Ganzhou&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:23:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[驱车上东门 | 佚名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239191]]><description> &lt;h2>;Drive up to the east gate&lt;/h2>;[Han Dynasty] Anonymous&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;Drive up to the east gate and look at the tomb of Guo Bei in the distance. &lt;br />;The white poplars are fluttering, and the road is wide between pines and cypresses. &lt;br />;There are dead people below, and they will be in the dark forever. &lt;br />;Hibernating under the Yellow Spring, it will last for thousands of years. &lt;br />;The yin and yang are shifting, and life is like morning dew. &lt;br />;Life is like sending it away suddenly, and there is no solid stone in life. &lt;br />;Long live the changes that come one after another, and no sage can save them. (Item 1: Send)&lt;br />;Taking food to seek immortality is often caused by medicine. &lt;br />;It is better to drink fine wine and be convinced of the wanness and plainness. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;We drove to the east gate of Luoyang City and looked at the numerous tombs on Mang Mountain in the distance. &lt;br />;The path to the tomb is filled with the sound of poplars and pines, and the atmosphere is gloomy. &lt;br />;The dead people have been lying around in the tomb for a long time, just like falling into the dark night and never getting light. &lt;br />;Lying silently under the Yellow Spring, I will never wake up for thousands of years. &lt;br />;The four seasons run without stopping, and life is like the morning dew that lasts in a short time. &lt;br />;Life is as hasty as a boarding house, how can life be as strong as stone? &lt;br />;Since ancient times, life and death have changed, and sages have struggled with life and death. &lt;br />;Thinking of taking elixirs to become an immortal, but they are often deceived by elixirs. &lt;br />;It is better to have fun, drink fine wine, and wear silk and brocade before your eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Upper East Gate: The northernmost gate of the three east gates of Luoyang City. &lt;br />;Guobei: North of the city. There are many ancient tombs on Beimang Mountain in the north of Luoyang City. &lt;br />;Polar: In ancient times, trees such as poplar, pine, and cypress were often planted on tombs as symbols to facilitate the sacrifices of descendants. &lt;br />;Chen Shiren: a person who has been dead for a long time. Chen, long. &lt;br />;杳杳: dark appearance. That is: Just, it still means &quot;being present&quot;. Changdu: long night. This sentence means that when a person dies and is buried in a grave, it is like being in darkness forever. &lt;br />;Qian sleep: deep sleep. &lt;br />;寤(wù): wake up. &lt;br />;Haohao: appearance. Yin and Yang: The ancients regarded spring and summer as yang, and autumn and winter as yin. This sentence means that the passage of time is like a river flowing eastward, endless. &lt;br />;Year: It still means &quot;life span&quot;. &lt;br />;Sudden: sudden appearance. Send: sojourn. &lt;br />;Update: change. Long live: I still say &quot;since ancient times&quot;. This sentence means that since ancient times, life and death have changed, and one generation has sent another generation away. &lt;br />;Du: too far, still means &quot;beyond&quot;. This sentence means that even sages cannot transcend the law of &quot;life must lead to death.&quot; &lt;br />;Quilt: Same as &quot;draped&quot;, worn. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is written in the form of a lyrical protagonist expressing his true feelings. It expresses a part of the people who lived a prosperous life during the great turmoil in the late Eastern Han Dynasty. The desolate mentality of intellectuals who cannot find a way out in politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Luoyang, the capital of Eastern Han Dynasty, has a total of twelve city gates. There are three gates to the east, and the one to the north is called the &quot;upper east gate&quot;. Guo, outer city. In the Han Dynasty, the old custom was followed, and most of the dead were buried in Guobei. Beishan Mountain in the north of Luoyang City is a place of mass burials; the &quot;Guobei Tomb&quot; in the poem refers to the Mangshan Tombs. The protagonist drove out of the upper east gate, looked to the north of the city, and saw the trees in the Mangshan Cemetery. He couldn&#39;t help but feel sad, so he wrote about what he saw and felt with two sentences: &quot;The poplars are swaying, and the pines and cypresses are sandwiched between the wide roads.&quot; &quot;Xiao Xiao&quot; is the sound of leaves. The protagonist parked his car outside the Shangdong Gate, which was still some distance away from the Beimang Cemetery. He should not have heard the rustling of the poplars on the tomb. The reason why the poplar leaves rustle is the result of the swaying of the long wind; but the scene of the wind shaking the poplar branches and the turning of the leaves can be seen from a distance. Looking at its shape, thinking about its sound, and forming synaesthesia, the visual image and the auditory image are combined into one. There is another layer: the protagonist originally lived in Luoyang City, and had nothing to do, but he wanted to leave the city, and he happened to go out of the upper east gate. As soon as he left the city gate, he &quot;looked at Guobei Tomb in the distance&quot;, which showed that he had already left the city. Negatively thinking about the fate of life, I feel very sad. Therefore, when he saw the poplars and cypresses, he first fell in love with the scene, and then he was moved by the scene. &quot;How&quot; is used as an adverbial before &quot;Xiao Xiao&quot;, which has a very strong emotional color. The sentence that writes &quot;pines and cypresses&quot; seems to be relatively plain, but only the tombs of wealthy people have broad tomb passages. Nowadays, there are only pine and cypresses on &quot;Jiaguang Road&quot;, and the scene of Xiaoqin can also be vaguely imagined. So I thought of the dead people under the tomb from the trees on the tomb, and said it in ten lines:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When a person dies, it is like falling into a long night, sleeping under the underworld, for thousands of years, never to wake up again . Spring, summer, autumn, and winter flow endlessly; but human life is like morning dew, which disappears as soon as the sun shines. Life is like a hotel where a traveler spends a night, walks out of the hotel, and never returns. Human life is not as solid as gold and stone, and cannot withstand many stumbles. As the years pass by, they are replaced by new ones, and the cycle continues endlessly; even saints and sages cannot surpass it and live forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Taoist classics, &quot;life is like a message&quot; is a metaphor, which means that life is temporary, like returning home from a journey; while Tao is eternal, like one&#39;s own home. Taoists believe that everything in the world is nothing but the transformation of one Qi. When Qi gathers, life occurs, and when Qi disperses, death occurs. Therefore, &quot;Xi Zi&quot; quotes &quot;Lao Lai Zi&quot; as saying: &quot;Life is sent between heaven and earth. Those who send it return together. The ancients said that the dead are the people who return, and their lives also exist, and their deaths also die, and their lives are also small. Yes, and the years pass by quickly.&quot; &quot;Lieh-tzu&quot; says: &quot;Death and life go in and out of the same direction, so those who die in this way know that they will not be reborn in the other.&quot; &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; says: &quot;If life and death are shortened, How can we force it? If we do evil, we know that rejoicing in life is not because of delusion. If we do evil, we know that it is evil to die because we are weak and lost and do not know how to return. If we do evil, we know that the dead will not regret the original life.&quot; Some scholars believe that these are Buddhist ideas of reincarnation. In fact, this statement is intended to prove that the Taoist idea of ​​​​equalizing life and death belongs to the idea of ​​&quot;equalizing things&quot;, which is consistent with what &quot;Zhuangzi Zhibeiyou Chapter&quot; said: &quot;Life is also the disciple of death, and death is also the beginning of life. Who knows it?&quot; Similar to &quot;Ji&quot;, the Taoist theory of biochemistry is a pure theory of biochemistry of all things without any religious overtones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Here, the poet discussed in great detail the natural law that life is inevitable, and no matter who it is, the result is the same. This lays the foundation for further explaining that those who &quot;take food to seek immortality&quot; want to live forever but cannot achieve it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Everyone hopes that they will live forever. At that time, it was very popular to make elixirs and ask for medicines to seek immortality. In this regard, the poet said: &quot;Taking food to seek immortality is mostly mistaken for medicine. It is better to drink fine wine and be taken to be rich and simple.&quot; These four sentences mean that even if you take elixirs and seek immortality, you will not be able to live forever. In this case, it is better to drink fine wine, wear silk and satin, enjoy the happiness in front of you, and live a short life happily. Here, on the surface, the poet feels wistful about the shortness of life. In fact, the poet&#39;s lament about life not only expresses the decadent thoughts and desolate mentality of the intellectuals at that time, but also implies his love for life. The reason why the poet said this is not only a kind of anger, but also a kind of helplessness. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is one of the &quot;Nineteen Ancient Poems&quot;. Modern people comprehensively examine the emotional tendencies expressed, the social life situations reflected in &quot;Nineteen Ancient Poems&quot; and its sophisticated artistic skills. It is generally believed that the age of these nineteen poems should be several dozen years before Emperor Xian&#39;an in the late Han Dynasty. Years. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Also known as anonymous, it refers to a person whose identity is unknown or whose name has not yet been learned. Literary and musical works originating from ancient times or among the people and whose author is unknown will be named anonymously. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 04:23:17 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>