<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[感遇十二首·其二 | 张九龄]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239302]]><description> &lt;h2>;Twelve poems about encounters·Part 2&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Zhang Jiuling&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The lonely man returns home and lies alone, washing away his worries. &lt;br />;I thank the tall bird for this, and spread my love for you. &lt;br />;With empty thoughts day and night, who feels the most spiritual? &lt;br />;Fei Chenli is separated from himself, how can I comfort my sincerity? &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Since I retired to this quiet mountain forest, I have been lying alone under the forest spring every day. The accumulated worries were washed away. &lt;br />;I want to use these to thank the high-flying bird, because I want her to convey my distant feelings. &lt;br />;I carry this infinite affection day and night, but who can understand my sincere affection? &lt;br />;The flying bird and the sinking fish are originally different in love, so how can they comfort my feelings? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Tall Bird: A bird that flies high. &lt;br />;Feishen: refers to birds and fish. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is a five-character poem. The third character of each sentence is a verb, and the contrast between the upper and lower words is neat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; The poet in the first couplet explains that he lives in a place far away from the officialdom and further than the secluded forest. He is alone as a sleeping dragon with empty time. Such days seem to mock his aloofness and purity. The words &quot;return&quot; and &quot;wash&quot; in the sentence seem like a kind of punishment, but the author still &quot;returns&quot; to his mountain home, and is not afraid of the lonely &quot;wash&quot; to return home and become Mr. Wolong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; The author of the couplet uses metonymy, referring to the tall bird as the slanderer, and the distant sentiments as the poet&#39;s firm stand. The words &quot;thank you&quot; and &quot;chuan&quot; here are ironic, otherwise why would the poet thank those who said bad things about him? Set up a foreshadowing in the first sentence, saying that you want to thank them, and then say thank you to them in the second sentence to convey your profound attitude. This shows the author&#39;s inner disgust for those tall birds, but at the same time he expresses his gratitude to those people on the surface. There seems to be a sense of insincerity here, but given the author&#39;s situation at the time, this is all he can do. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; In the neck couplet and the tail couplet, the poet continuously asks questions, expressing &quot;who knows my loyalty?&quot;, which is quite similar to &quot;Although I am good at repairing my hair, I will replace it overnight, and even though I will die nine times, It means &quot;I still haven&#39;t regretted it&quot;. The words &quot;sensation&quot; and &quot;comfort&quot; in the sentence are quite touching, which fully reflect the author&#39;s feeling of being unable to express his sufferings and feeling heartbroken after drinking wine. &quot;Rixi&quot; and &quot;feishen&quot; refer to the state in which the laws of nature are constantly being carried out, and refer to Refined, even in this tasteless life, the poet still has a pure state of mind, shielding his attitude and being Mr. Wolong, only hoping that one day he will still have the opportunity to meet &quot;Liu Bei&quot; and return to officialdom to revitalize it. Then he sighed, &quot;Whoever feels the most profound will comfort me sincerely.&quot; &quot;It can be seen that the poet still hopes to be reused by Xuanzong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; The whole poem talks about his aloofness and seeks for close friends, expressing the poet&#39;s feeling that although he is old and helpless, he is ambitious for a thousand miles. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/zhangjiuling.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>; Zhang Jiuling (678-740) was the prime minister and poet of Kaiyuan in Tang Dynasty. His courtesy name was Zishou, a natural history scholar, Han nationality, from Qujiang, Shaozhou (now Shaoguan City, Guangdong). He was a Jinshi during the Chang&#39;an period. He became the Minister of Zhongshu and Pingzhang under Zhongshu&#39;s family. Later, he resigned as prime minister and became the governor of Jing. His poetry style is light. There is &quot;Qujiang Collection&quot;. He is a courageous and far-sighted famous politician, writer, poet, and famous prime minister. He is loyal, conscientious, and impartial. He spoke out, dared to admonish, selected talents, did not bend the law for personal gain, did not follow the crowd, dared to fight against evil forces, and made a positive contribution to the &quot;Kaiyuan rule&quot;. His five-character ancient poems, with simple and simple language, have far-reaching sustenance His life aspirations made a great contribution to eradicating the Six Dynasties poetic style followed in the early Tang Dynasty. He is known as &quot;the first person in Lingnan&quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS: &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 06:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[沁园春·寒食郓州道中 | 谢枋得]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239301]]><description> &lt;h2>;Qinyuan Chun·Cold Food Yunzhou Road&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Xie Fangde&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;For fifteen years, everyone has been at the end of the world during the Cold Food Festival. I sigh that the rain is wet with dew, but I still think about the cypress trees. The wind is soft and the sun is beautiful, and I am ashamed to see the flying flowers. Wheat rice and paper money, chickens fighting for wine, and crows making noise in the forest. Tian smiled and said, This is not up to me, nor is it up to him. &lt;br />;The cinnabar is cooked in the cauldron. Make Zifu Qingdu one family. I think of my predecessors who often traveled to Jiangque and saw the cicadas sloughing off. How could I fall in love with the yellow sand? The emperor ordered the tombs to be guarded, the king ordered the tombs to be repaired, and the man was right and wrong. Why bother, stay at home and go to the tomb, where the books and brocade are prosperous. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;For the past fifteen years, every Cold Food Festival, I have been far away from home and wandering in the world. In rainy weather, I miss the cypress trees on the tomb; in sunny weather, I am ashamed to see flying flowers. During the Cold Food Festival, I cannot offer wheat rice, paper money, chickens, or wine to my ancestors, and the magpies and crows in the forest are waiting in vain! God smiled and said: This is not because of me, nor is it because of the invasion of the Yuan army. &lt;br />;I have already thought deeply about it and am as confident as the cinnabar in a cauldron. I am ready to ascend to heaven at any time and make the Zifu Qingdu Immortal World my home. I think of the past when immortals rode cranes and often traveled around the Jiangque in the sky. Our worldly bodies were discarded like cicadas shedding their shells. How can we linger on the dusty world? The emperor ordered his ministers to guard the tombs and repair the cemeteries. Men should serve the king in this way. Why wait until you return home to visit your grave, displaying your splendor just like returning home in fine clothes during the day! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Qinyuanchun: Ci brand name, also known as &quot;Dongxian&quot;, &quot;Shouxingming&quot;, &quot;Dongting Spring&quot;, etc. &lt;br />;Yunzhou: The name of the state in the Northern Song Dynasty. The city where it was governed was now Dongping, Shandong. The old name of the Northern Song Dynasty is used here to show that we do not forget our homeland. &lt;br />;Zaibai: The cypress tree on the tomb is also called Zaishu or Zaimu. &lt;br />;Feihua: Qiehan Food Festival. &lt;br />;Chickens fighting for wine: both refer to sacrifices. &lt;br />;Occasionally, the crows in the forest were noisy: after the sacrifices were swept, the crows and magpies in the forest could come to eat the sacrifices. Since they had not been able to sweep the sacrifices for many years, the crows and magpies were delayed. Several, many times. &lt;br />;Zifu Qingdu: Taoists call the place where immortals live Zifu; Qingdu refers to the official residence of the Emperor of Heaven. &lt;br />;Jiangque: refers to the Palace of Immortals. Su Shi&#39;s &quot;Shui Long Yin&quot;: &quot;In ancient times, the sea of ​​clouds was vast, and where was the Jiangque on Daoshan Mountain?&quot; &lt;br />;Huangsha: means the dusty world. &lt;br />;Playing house and going to the grave: Go back to your hometown and visit the grave. This is not a general term, but refers specifically to returning home to pay homage to the ancestors on the emperor&#39;s order and to show the emperor&#39;s favor. &lt;br />;Shu Jin: means returning home after wealth. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by Xie Fangde when he visited Yunzhou. After the fall of the Song Dynasty, the Yuan Dynasty continued its southern expedition. During this period, the author lived in seclusion in central Fujian until the twenty-sixth year of the Yuan Dynasty (1289), when the rulers of the Yuan Dynasty forced the poet to go north. During the Cold Food Festival on the way, he wrote this poem. The poet arrived in Yanjing in April, but eventually went on a hunger strike and died at the age of sixty-four. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first film mainly expresses the poet&#39;s homesickness. It has been fifteen years since I went home to celebrate the Cold Food Festival, which shows that the poet has been wandering away for a long time. &quot;They are all in Tianzhou&quot; is an exaggeration, which shows that the poet is deeply homesick. It also implies that the country was destroyed and the family was destroyed, and the people suffered from displacement. . Although the writer of the four lines &quot;Sighing on the Rain&quot; has left his hometown, he misses his family all the time. He has not returned home for fifteen years to sweep the tombs of his ancestors and pay homage to his ancestors. Even &quot;Zai Bai&quot; makes the poet miss him endlessly. But in the sunny season, the poet is ashamed to see &quot;flying flowers&quot;, and he does not want to know the reason for his shame. &quot;Flying flowers&quot; here refers to a place where warmth and prosperity are common. When the country is ruined and the family is destroyed, as a minister, he is unable to save the building. It is so shameful that it is about to fall. The three lines of &quot;Maifan&quot; describe the happy crows in the forest who could have eaten the sacrificial things, but because I have not sacrificed them for many years, even they have to wait in vain. On the surface, the poet is pitying the crows , in fact, he is lamenting his own misfortune. In the last sentence, the poet euphemistically expresses his indignation towards the rulers of the Yuan Dynasty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next film changes from the sad and melancholy style of the first film to expressing heroic feelings. Beginning In these two sentences, the poet borrows Taoist theory to reveal that he has already seen through life and death and is willing to become a family with the gods and emperors. It shows that the poet sticks to his integrity and regards death as home. The four sentences &quot;thinking about what others have done before&quot; further illustrate that the poet does not love the poem. In this mortal world, one does not want to live an ignoble existence, and even longs to be like his predecessors, to fly around on a crane after liberation, and be free and at ease. &quot;The emperor ordered to guard the tomb, the king ordered to repair the tomb, this is what men should do.&quot; In the three lines, the poet once again made it clear that he was determined to die. Loyal to the Song Dynasty, one would rather die than surrender. It is precisely because of this idea that &quot;a loyal minister will not serve the two masters&quot;, so the poet finally said that although he was forced by the Yuan people to go north this time, he had made up his mind and they could not do anything about it. . Again emphasizing his firm belief.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem was written from the Cold Food Festival. The poet first wrote about his homesickness, and then went from home to country, showing that he would never be a traitor who betrayed his trust and country. , even if you risk your life, you must preserve your integrity, thus sublimating the ideological realm of the whole poem and enhancing the artistic appeal of the poem.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>; &lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/xiefangde.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Xie Fangde (1226~1289): Jinshi of the Southern Song Dynasty, A native of Yiyang, Xinzhou, Jiangxi Province, his courtesy name was Junzhi, his nickname was Dieshan, and his alias was Yizhai. He served as the Minister of the Six Ministries. He was extremely intelligent and had excellent articles. He learned the &quot;Six Classics&quot; and was involved in hundreds of schools. He led the rebel army to fight against the Yuan Dynasty in Jiangdong. He was captured unyieldingly and died for his country in Beijing. His works are included in &quot;Dieshan Collection&quot;.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>