<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[与李十二白同寻范十隐居 | 杜甫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231032]]><description> &lt;h2>;Looking for Fan Shi to live in seclusion with Li Twelve Bai&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Du Fu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Li Hou has good sentences, which often sound like a shadow. &lt;br />;Yu Yidong is a stranger, and he pities you like a brother. &lt;br />;Drunk and sleep in autumn together, walking hand in hand through the day. &lt;br />;I want to be in a secluded place even more, and I am looking for Bei Guosheng. &lt;br />;The entrance is happy and the child is clear. &lt;br />;When the scenery falls, we hear the cold pestle, and the clouds surround the ancient city. &lt;br />;I have always chanted the praises of oranges, but who wants to ask for water shield soup? &lt;br />;I don’t want to talk about hairpins and wats, but I love the sea. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Li Bai often writes very beautiful poems, and his writing is as good as Yin Keng . &lt;br />;I can be regarded as a hermit in Lu County, and I love him like my own brother. &lt;br />;After getting drunk, you can sleep under the same quilt and play together during the day. &lt;br />;Remembering that we still had a date for seclusion, we went to look for Mr. Chengbei Guo together. &lt;br />;You will feel elegant as soon as you enter the door, and even young children will feel elegant. &lt;br />;I didn’t want to say goodbye until the sun set in the west and the night clouds enveloped the ancient city. &lt;br />;Just like the high-character people in &quot;Ode to Orange&quot;, who would be greedy for the beauty of their hometown? &lt;br />;We don’t want to discuss career matters, but just enjoy the pure friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Li Hou: refers to Li Bai. Excellent lines: refers to wonderful sentences in poems, and also refers to beautiful poems. &lt;br />;Yin Keng (kēng): a Southern Dynasty writer named Zijian. He served as the prefect of Chen Jinling and as a regular servant outside Sanqi. He was good at five-character poetry, and his rhythm was close to that of Tang rhythm poetry. He was praised by Du Fu. &lt;br />;Eastern Mongolians: generally refers to virgins and hermits. Dongmeng refers to the area around Lujun (now Yanzhou, Shandong). &lt;br />;Pity: love. &lt;br />;Sharing the quilt: Sleeping with the same quilt means being as close as brothers. &lt;br />;Day: one is &quot;month&quot;. &lt;br />;Youth period: a period of seclusion. &lt;br />;Bei Guosheng: The provincial name for &quot;Mr. Bei Guo&quot; refers to a hermit. &lt;br />;Happiness: elegant mood. &lt;br />;Kidong: a young male servant. &quot;Du Zui&quot;: When you see the handsomeness of a child, you know that the master is good. &lt;br />;Lujing (yǐng): sunset. Scenery is the same as &quot;shadow&quot;. &lt;br />;Hanchu: the sound of pestle in cold autumn. &lt;br />;Tunyun: accumulated clouds. &lt;br />;Ode to Orange: The title of &quot;Chu Ci·Nine Chapters&quot; was written by Qu Yuan, a native of Chu during the Warring States Period. &lt;br />;Who: One is &quot;Wei&quot;. Desire: One word is &quot;and&quot;. &lt;br />;Chún soup: soup cooked with water shield. &lt;br />;簰 (zān) 笏 (hù): Crown hairpin and hand tablet, used by officials in ancient times as a metaphor for officials or official positions. &lt;br />;Youyou: An easy appearance. Love in the sea: It means that there is no desire to restore the hairpin and wat, but to express love in the rivers and seas. It is also the meaning of Confucius&#39; &quot;If you can&#39;t do it, you will float in the sea on a raft&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written around AD 745 (the fourth year of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty). In the autumn, Du Fu once again came to the place where he had visited a few years ago. He used to travel to Lu County (now Yanzhou, Shandong), and at this time Li Bai&#39;s family was staying in Rencheng County, Lu County (now Jining, Shandong). The two made an appointment to visit the layman Fan Shi in the north of Lu County. It is at the same time as Li Bai&#39;s &quot;Xunlu City North Fan Jushi lost his way and fell into the cockleburs. Seeing Fan Zhijiu and picking cockleburs&quot;, they can be mutually referenced. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem first describes the author&#39;s deep friendship with Li Bai, then describes his visit to Fan Shi&#39;s seclusion with Li Bai, and then writes it impromptu at Fan&#39;s residence. Reciting Qu Yuan&#39;s &quot;Ode to Orange&quot;, the three people at the table had a strong resonance in their hearts, expressing the feelings of connected hearts between friends. The whole poem contains the cherishment of true friendship, the harmonious resonance of hearts and minds, and the melancholy of having no return in life. The style is ancient, the interest is elegant, and the situation is exquisite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whole poem can be divided into three parts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first six sentences are the first part, describing the author&#39;s friendship with Li Bai. The two traveled together and were as close as brothers. &quot;Yu Yidong welcomes guests and pities you as a brother.&quot; It can be seen that the author came here as an invitation to have a happy gathering. &quot;Drunk in autumn and sleep together under the quilt, walking hand in hand in the sun.&quot; Seeing that it is autumn here, we can see the deep friendship between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The middle six sentences are the second paragraph, describing the two people seeking Fan Shi to live in seclusion together. &quot;I want to be in a secluded place even more, and I&#39;m still looking for Bei Guosheng&quot;, describing what happened on the way. The two sentences &quot;I am happy when I enter, and I wait for the little boy to be clear&quot; are written about a visit to Fan Ju. &quot;When the scenery falls and we hear the cold pestle, and the clouds gather in front of the ancient city,&quot; two sentences describe their stay until late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last four sentences are the third paragraph, which is composed of &quot;Ode to Orange&quot;, reflecting on living in seclusion and thinking about traveling outside the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the poem contains praise for Li Bai, it is more of a simple and subtle sketch of friendship. &quot;Bedding together in autumn&quot;, &quot;walking together in the sun&quot;, &quot;looking for Beiguo&quot;, &quot;happy at the beginning&quot;, &quot;tunyun to the ancient city&quot;, &quot;long love for the sea&quot;, night, day, leaving the city, returning home, looking at the sky, asking about the sea, this kind of emotion , the love of brotherhood, the connection between hearts and minds, will not be easily severed throughout life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Chenweng thought that the two sentences &quot;When one enters the school, he will be happy and prosperous, and he will serve Xiao Chongqing&quot;. Jin Lingsheng wrote an article and believed that this is what the Caodong Sect calls &quot;not violating the right position&quot;. . In the two sentences &quot;I have always chanted tangerine songs, who asked for water shield soup&quot;, Zhu Yizun said that &quot;the word &#39;who&#39; is suspected to be the word &#39;wei&#39;, which means it is obtained.&quot; Jin Lingsheng believed in poetry that &quot;who&quot; should be the leader. This couplet has both positive and negative aspects. The first sentence says that Fan Shi lives in seclusion to protect his integrity, just like the &quot;Su Shi is independent, horizontal but not flowing&quot; chanted in &quot;Ode to Orange&quot;; the second sentence is rhetorical, who wants to be greedy? What about the beauty of the scenery in my hometown? If &quot;wei&quot; is used, the meaning is repeated with the conjunction &quot;I don&#39;t want to talk about hairpins and wats, and I have long-lasting love for the sea&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem contains only a few lines about the layman Xunfan. It has an ancient style, elegant interest, and a clear and wonderful situation. It is indeed rare and valuable. In terms of the authenticity of the narrative, the vividness of the details, the expressiveness of the images, and the humor of the language, they are not as good as Li Bai&#39;s contemporary work &quot;Fan Jushi in the North of Xunlu City Lost His Path and Lost Xanthium. Seeing Fan Zhijiu and Picking Xanthium.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/dufu.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Du Fu (712-770), whose courtesy name is Zimei, who calls himself Shaoling Yelao, is also known as &quot;Du Gongbu&quot;, &quot;Du Shaoling&quot;, etc., Han nationality, Fugong County, Henan (now Henan Province Gongyi City), a great realist poet in the Tang Dynasty, Du Fu is respected by the world as the &quot;Sage of Poetry&quot;, and his poems are called &quot;the history of poetry&quot;. Du Fu and Li Bai are collectively known as &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, known as &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively known as &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. He was concerned about the country and the people, and had a noble personality. About 1,400 of his poems have been preserved. His poetic skills are exquisite, and he is highly respected in Chinese classical poetry and has far-reaching influence. He lived in Chengdu from 759 to 766, and is commemorated by Du Fu&#39;s Thatched Cottage in later generations. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 06:23:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九日黄楼作 | 苏轼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231031]]><description> &lt;h2>;Nine Days in Huang Lou Zuo&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Su Shi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Last year during the Double Ninth Festival, it was unspeakable that thousands of people were dying in the middle of the night in Nancheng. &lt;br />;The water penetrated the city and thundered, and the mud filled the city and the rain fell. &lt;br />;No one asks for Huanghua Baijiu. I come back at dusk to wash my boots and socks. &lt;br />;How could I know that this year would come again? &lt;br />;Don’t be afraid that the wine is thin, red and pink, it will eventually win the battle in the mud. &lt;br />;The new walls of the Huanglou have not yet dried up, and the clear river has already been covered with frost. &lt;br />;The white dew is like drizzle in the morning, and there is no Qianxun Temple in Nanshan. &lt;br />;There is a vast sea in front of the building, and there are oars and crows in the air downstairs. &lt;br />;In the cold, old age is scary. Pour hot wine on the intestines first to suppress the gas. &lt;br />;After the smoke disappears and the sun rises, we can see the fishing village and the distant water and the scaly mountains. &lt;br />;Poets and warriors are mixed with dragons and tigers, Chu dances and Wu songs are mixed with geese and ducks. &lt;br />;A cup of wine belongs to you, don’t say goodbye, this situation is so clear and clear. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;① This poem was written after the completion of the Huanglou in the first year of Yuanfeng. The author recalls the floods last year and rejoices in today&#39;s festival. &lt;br />;②Last year on the Double Ninth Festival, the author had expected his friend to come to celebrate the festival. Since the visitors were blocked by the water, the host was also busy fighting with the water, so it is said that it cannot be said, which means there is no way to talk about it. &lt;br />;③Retting, accumulation of water. Thousands of liters of water are said to be extremely powerful. &lt;br />;④Yellow, chrysanthemum. During the Double Ninth Festival, you should enjoy chrysanthemums and drink alcohol. Here, &quot;yellow flower white wine&quot; represents the Double Ninth Festival. &lt;br />;⑤Red pink, suspected to be the Geisha who is having a drink here. &lt;br />;⑥Here it is said that Gaosha is covered with white mist and cannot be seen. &lt;br />;⑦ Bohanzhong (pronounced zhòng) person means that a person is cold. &lt;br />;⑧齾齾 (pronounced yà), with uneven teeth, describes the jagged peaks. &lt;br />;⑨霅(zhá), the name of the water, is the Peixi River flowing into Taihu Lake. The last sentence is actually the author&#39;s words recalling and imagining Jiangnan. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/sushi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Su Shi, (January 8, 1037 - August 24, 1101), courtesy name Zizhan and Hezhong, also known as Tieguan Taoist and Dongpo layman, known as Su Dongpo and Su Xian in the world, Han nationality, Meizhou A native of Meishan (Meishan City, Sichuan Province), his ancestral home is Luancheng, Hebei Province. He is a famous writer, calligrapher and painter in the Northern Song Dynasty and a famous figure in water control in history. Su Shi was a literary leader in the mid-Northern Song Dynasty and made great achievements in poetry, lyrics, prose, calligraphy, and painting. His writing is bold and unbridled; his poems are broad in subject matter, fresh and vigorous, good at using exaggerated metaphors, and have a unique style. Together with Huang Tingjian, he is called &quot;Su Huang&quot;; His prose writings are grand and bold. Together with Ouyang Xiu, he is called &quot;Ou Su&quot; and is one of the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Su Shi was good at calligraphy and one of the &quot;Four Masters of the Song Dynasty&quot;; he was good at literati painting, especially ink bamboo, strange rocks, dead wood, etc. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan and Ouyang Xiu, they are known as the &quot;Four Great Masters of Eternal Writing&quot;. His works include &quot;Dongpo Seven Collections&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yi Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yuefu&quot;, &quot;Xiaoxiang Bamboo and Stone Picture Scroll&quot;, &quot;Old Trees and Strange Stones Picture Scroll&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>