<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[人皆有不忍人之心 | 孟子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231022]]><description> &lt;h2>;Everyone has a heart that cannot bear others&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Mencius&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>; Mencius said: &quot;Everyone has a heart that cannot bear others. The ancient kings had a heart that could not bear others. There is an intolerable government. With an intolerable heart, you implement an intolerable government and govern the world in the palm of your hand. That’s why it is said that everyone has an intolerable heart: Today, when people first see a child about to fall into a well, they are all frightened. The heart of compassion is not because of friendship with the child&#39;s parents, not because of wanting to be praised by friends in the township party, and not because of hating his voice. From this point of view, without a heart of compassion, it is not a human being; without a heart of shame or disgust , non-human; without a heart of resignation, it is not a human; without a heart of right and wrong, it is not a human being. The heart of compassion is the root of benevolence; the heart of shame and disgust is the root of righteousness; the heart of resignation is the root of etiquette; right and wrong The heart is the end of wisdom. Human beings have four ends, just like they have four bodies. Those who have four ends and claim that they cannot do so are committing treason; those who claim that the ruler is incapable of doing so are committing treason against the ruler. If there are four ends in me, I know that they are all expanded and filled, just like the beginning of fire, the beginning of spring. If I can fill it, it will be enough to protect the world; if I fail to fill it, I will not be able to serve my parents.&quot; &lt;/div>;&lt;h3 >;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />; Mencius said: &quot;Everyone has compassion and consideration for others. The ancient sage kings had compassion and consideration for others. That’s why there is politics that is compassionate and considerate of the people. If you use compassion and considerate the feelings of others and implement politics that are compassionate and considerate of the people, governing the world will be as easy as moving things in the palm of your hand. The reason why it is said that everyone has the feeling of compassion and consideration for others. , because if someone suddenly sees a child falling into a well today, he will definitely feel fear and sympathy - this is not because he wants to have a relationship with the child&#39;s parents, or because he wants to make friends with his neighbors. It is not because he dislikes the cry of this child that he has such fear and sympathy. From this point of view, without sympathy, he is simply not a human being; without shame, he is simply not a human being; without humility, he is simply not a human being. Not a human being; without a mind of right and wrong, simply not a human being. Compassion is the origin of benevolence; shame is the origin of righteousness; humility is the origin of propriety; a mind of right and wrong is the origin of wisdom. People have these four origins, just like they have limbs The same. Anyone who has these four origins but thinks that he can&#39;t do it is a person who has given up on himself; anyone who thinks that his monarch is not capable is a person who has abandoned his monarch. Anyone who has these four origins knows to expand and enrich them. Like a fire that has just begun to burn, and a spring that has just begun to flow. If you can expand them, it will be enough to stabilize the world. If you cannot expand them, even supporting your parents will be a problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong >;&lt;br />;Intolerance: compassion, sympathy. &lt;br />;Zha: suddenly, suddenly. &lt;br />;Be wary: frightened. Compassion: sorrow, sympathy. &lt;br />;Internal communication, internal communication means making friends, internal communication is the same as &quot;acceptance&quot;. &lt;br />;Reputation: gain reputation. &lt;br />;End: beginning, origin, source. &lt;br />;I: same as &quot;Ji&quot;. &lt;br />;Ran, the same as &quot;burn&quot;. &lt;br />;Bao: stability, stability. Yun: movement, rotation. &lt;br />;Township Party: fellow countryman. &lt;br />;It’s not because I hate the sound of the child: It’s not because I hate the sound of a child crying. &lt;br />;Shame: Feeling ashamed of one’s own bad deeds and hating others’ bad deeds. &lt;br />;Resign: humbly give in. &lt;br />;Tetrabodies: four limbs. &lt;br />;Thief: damage. &lt;br />;Da: circulation, refers to spring water gushing out. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Politics can be deduced from the premise of human nature. Specifically, benevolent politics can be deduced from the benevolence that everyone has &quot;the heart of being intolerable to others.&quot; Since this &quot;unbearable heart&quot; is inherent in human beings, benevolent government should also be a matter of course. This is Mencius&#39;s thinking. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Mencius’ derivation is still to promote his lifelong pursuit, that is, the ideal of “benevolent government”. But his derivation itself does not seem to have had a great impact, but the premise of his derivation - &quot;Everyone has a heart that cannot bear others&quot; has had a huge impact, especially the &quot;benevolence, justice, propriety and wisdom&quot; proposed on this basis. This view of &quot;being intolerant of others&quot; has become the theoretical basis and pillar of the &quot;theory of good nature&quot; in ancient Chinese philosophy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Confucius once said: &quot;Sex is similar, but habits are far apart.&quot; (&quot;The Analects of Confucius Yang Huo&quot; means that human nature is originally similar, but because of different upbringing, it is very different. But Confucius neither said what similar human nature is, whether it is good or evil, nor did he elaborate on it. Moreover, from our understanding, Confucius mainly emphasized the aspect of acquired education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Mencius It&#39;s different. He not only elaborated and pointed out that the similar human nature is the &quot;unbearable heart&quot; that originates from benevolence, justice, propriety and wisdom, but also gave vivid examples to prove that this &quot;unbearable heart&quot; is inherent in human beings. Without it, there is simply no human being. From this perspective, Mencius’ theory of human nature is indeed “transcendental” and subjective idealism. Because he described social moral concepts such as “benevolence, justice, propriety, and wisdom” as Inherent in human nature, innate, and even physiological.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; But on the other hand, Mencius did not completely deny the role of nurture. Because he believed &quot;The heart of intolerance&quot; includes four aspects, namely, the heart of &quot;compassion, shame, resignation, right and wrong&quot;, which is referred to as the &quot;four hearts&quot;. And these &quot;four hearts&quot; are just the four moral categories of &quot;benevolence, justice, etiquette and wisdom&quot;. The origin, or the &quot;four ends&quot;. These &quot;four ends&quot; are like a fire that has just burned or a spring that has just flowed out. It needs to be &quot;expanded and replenished&quot; before it can flourish. Otherwise, it will be extinguished or dried up. &quot;Expand&quot; &quot;And fill it&quot; is the acquired cultivation, that is, &quot;Xi Xiangyuan&quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Therefore, from a theoretical basis, Mencius indeed derived the theory of innate morality (&quot;Four Hearts&quot;) from the theory of innate goodness (&quot;Four Hearts&quot;). &quot;Four Ends&quot;), and then derived &quot;the government of intolerance&quot; (benevolent government). But in practice, he still attaches great importance to the role of acquired efforts (&quot;expanding it&quot;). Moreover, regardless of the question of nature or nurture, The abstract discussion of idealism or materialism can be viewed historically in relation to the social conditions of the Warring States Period where Mencius lived. He advocates that human nature is inherently good, emphasizes innate morality, and promotes benevolent politics. These are all of positive significance.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/mengzi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt; /div>; Mencius (about 372 BC - 289 BC), whose name was Ke and whose courtesy name was Ziyu, was from the state of Zou (southeast of today’s Zoucheng, Shandong Province). He was a philosopher, thinker and educator during the Warring States Period. After Confucius, Xunzi The former representative of the Confucian school was known as &quot;Confucius and Mencius&quot; together with Confucius. Mencius advocated &quot;benevolent government&quot; and was the first to propose the idea of ​​&quot;the people are valued more than the monarch&quot;. He was listed by Han Yu as a figure who inherited Confucius&#39; &quot;tradition&quot; among the pre-Qin Confucians, and was posthumously granted the title by the Yuan Dynasty. He is the &quot;lesser sage&quot;. Mencius&#39;s speeches and works are collected in the book &quot;Mencius&quot;. Among them, &quot;Fish I Want&quot;, &quot;If You Gain the Tao, You Will Get Many Helps, but If You Lose the Tao, There Will Be Few Helps&quot;, &quot;Ignorant People Are in a Country&quot; and &quot;Born in Worry, Die in Peace&quot; &quot; and other articles are included in Chinese textbooks for primary and secondary schools. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 04:23:11 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九日置酒 | 宋祁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231011]]><description> &lt;h2>;Purchasing wine for nine days&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Song Qi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;In the late autumn and good morning, the emphasis is on the beauty of things, and on the high platform, the account is placed in China. &lt;br />;Ao Huan lets the wind fall before the hat, promotes drinking and fights to blow the wine to make the flowers bloom. &lt;br />;The stream is clear and clear after the first rain, and the sun marks are light but not cloudy. &lt;br />;The White-headed Prefect is so stupid that he plants dogwood all over the place to ward off evil spirits. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;I especially value the beautiful scenery on this beautiful morning of September 9th in late autumn. Double curtains were raised on the high platform, allowing the band to play the beautiful harps and pipa. &lt;br />;Pursue happiness and let your hats fall in the wind, and persuade each other to drink and blow the chrysanthemums in the cups. &lt;br />;The shape of the stream after the rain is so clear and bright, and the pale sunlight of the early clearing day cannot be reflected into colorful clouds. &lt;br />;I, the white-headed prefect, am so foolish that I planted dogwood trees all over my temples in the hope of warding off evil spirits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Nine Days: Double Ninth Festival on the ninth day of the ninth lunar month. Set up wine: Arrange a banquet. &lt;br />;Wuhua: natural scenery. &lt;br />;Double account: double curtain. Stay: stay. Huajia (jiā): generally refers to playing music. Jia, Hu Jia, is the name of an ancient wind instrument. It was popular among ethnic minorities in the Western Regions during the Han Dynasty. It was first played with reed leaves, which harmonized with the instrument, and was later made of bamboo. &lt;br />;Invite happiness: seek happiness. Falling Wind Front Hat: Use Meng Jiashi. &quot;Book of Jin·Biography of Meng Jia&quot;: &quot;Meng Jia joined the army for Huan Wen. On September 9, he held a warm banquet at Longshan, and his subordinates gathered together. When the wind blew, Jia&#39;s hat fell to the ground, and Jia didn&#39;t realize it... Wen Ming Sun Sheng wrote and mocked Jia.&quot;&lt;br />;Promote drinking: urge people to drink. Flowers on wine: refers to chrysanthemums. Liang Zongmao of the Southern Dynasty wrote in &quot;The Chronicles of Jingchu Years&quot;: &quot;On September 9th, I wore dogwood, ate bait, and drank chrysanthemum wine.&quot;&lt;br />;Stream status: still a stream. &lt;br />;Sun marks: sunlight. &lt;br />;Baitou Taishou: The author refers to himself. &lt;br />;The sentence &quot;Manchu&quot;: In ancient times, it was customary to wear dogwood on the Double Ninth Festival, September 9, to dispel evil and avoid disasters. Cornus officinalis, the name of the plant, includes three types: Cornus officinalis, Cornus officinalis, and Cornus officinale. They grow in Sichuan Valley and have a strong flavor. Pi, the same as &quot;avoid&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; Song Qi went abroad in his later years and knew military states such as Shou, Chen, Xu, Bo, Chengde, Ding, Yi and Zheng. The poet was fond of guests, banquets, and luxury all his life, but he was able to deal with the ups and downs of officialdom with an open mind and an open-minded attitude. This poem was written after a banquet. It reflects the poet&#39;s positive and optimistic mental outlook. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Chen Yan, a recent scholar, said: &quot;I climbed high for nine days without any words of emotion. It seems that this is the only poem.&quot; (&quot;The Essence of Song Poetry&quot;) commented very highly good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first couplet of the poem breaks the title. The starting and ending points make the festival clear, and the tone is high. The gorgeous things and the pleasant autumn colors make the poet fascinated. The word &quot;heavy&quot; reveals the poet&#39;s lingering mood and leads the whole poem. Writing about the autumn morning similarly, &quot;the clouds are clear and the dawn is flowing, and the palaces of the Han Dynasty are moving in the high autumn&quot; (Zhao Gu&#39;s &quot;Autumn View of Chang&#39;an&quot;), which expresses the sadness of seeing off the autumn; &quot;The white wild geese flying south are about to frost, the wind and rain are rustling and the Double Ninth Festival&quot; ( Lu Yuan&#39;s &quot;Chongjiu&quot;), there is a feeling of nostalgia for the country. However, Song Qi&#39;s sentence does not express sadness, but has a new attitude. This is also due to the poet&#39;s situation and temperament. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second sentence is introduced by the word &quot;heavy&quot;. &quot;Gaotai re-account stationed in China&quot; is full of magnificence. It is also a &quot;high platform&quot;, a &quot;complex account&quot;, and a &quot;huaqie&quot;. The scene is magnificent and the atmosphere is warm, vivid and vivid. This is by no means a common people&#39;s climb, but a scene of wealthy people enjoying the autumn. The poet achieved great success at a young age and became prominent throughout his life. He served successively as Zhi Zhi Gao, Minister of the Ministry of Industry, and Imperial Academy Scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The chin couplet follows the above, describing the good day and the meeting, with a vivid image. The first sentence and the couplet describe two scenes: climbing and drinking. The two words &quot;happy&quot; and &quot;drinking&quot; express the grand occasion of being full of guests and drinking wine. &quot;Let the wind fall before the hat&quot; is a useful allusion. &quot;Book of Jin·Biography of Meng Jia&quot;: &quot;Meng Jia joined the army for Huan Wen, and he traveled to Longshan for nine days. When the wind came, he blew his hat, and Wen ordered Sun Sheng to mock him.&quot; The ancients regarded this matter as a romantic event, but Du Fu once opposed it. And it is used as: &quot;I am ashamed to blow my hat with my short hair, but others are smiling and beautiful.&quot; (&quot;Cui&#39;s Village in Lantian in Nine Days&quot;) was highly appreciated by the people of the Song Dynasty. Song Qi also opposed Du&#39;s poems. One uses &quot;shame&quot; and the other uses &quot;live&quot;; one is depressed and the other is free and easy. It shows that the mood is different and the poetic state is also different. &quot;Strive to blow wine and put flowers on it&quot; means competing to drink chrysanthemum wine. Climbing mountains and drinking chrysanthemum wine during the Double Ninth Festival has been a traditional and elegant event since ancient times. The words &quot;Ren Luo&quot; and &quot;Zheng Chui&quot; are opposite to each other. The poet is in a state of great excitement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The neck couplet is turned around, and it is written in the language of scenery, describing what it saw while climbing the mountain. The poet put his wine in the wind and wandered his eyes. He saw only the sky above and below, and it was clear and bright. &quot;The stream is clear and clear after the first rain, and the sun marks are light and not cloudy.&quot; After a lot of autumn rain, the sky is clear and the autumn appearance is light. The second sentence has a broad realm and a magnificent atmosphere. The characters &quot;Ming&quot; and &quot;Qing&quot; express the characteristics of the autumn morning. Its artistic conception is somewhat similar to Han Qi&#39;s &quot;Although the autumn appearance of the old garden is pale, it is also fragrant with the late festival fragrance of yellow flowers&quot; (&quot;Nine Days Water Pavilion&quot;). Qi of the Song Dynasty compiled Tang Shu for more than ten years. In his later years, he &quot;miweijinjing&quot; (&quot;Summary of the General Catalog of Sikuquanshu&quot;). He was &quot;erudite and able to write articles, with abundant talents. He loved to travel and entertain, and he was pleased with his reserve. In his later years, he got to know Chengdu Prefecture, and brought &quot;Tang Shu&quot; to be published and revised at this time... Viewers from far and near all know that Shangshu edited Tang Shu, and they look forward to it. What an immortal.&quot; (&quot;Dongxuan Notes&quot;) The realm of this poem is related to his positive attitude towards life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The final couplet is full of writing power, becoming more and more exciting, and ends with a joyful mood and vivid image. The sentence &quot;The White-headed Prefect is really stupid&quot; is humorous and is a self-portrait of the poet, both in form and spirit. The word &quot;stupid&quot; is self-deprecating on the surface, but in reality it is reserved. &quot;Baitou Taishou&quot; not only depicts the poet&#39;s distinctive appearance, but also shows the poet&#39;s identity as a Taishou. It means that &quot;purchasing wine for nine days&quot; is not an ordinary climb, but a prefect&#39;s banquet. An air of wealth and nobility comes out of it, echoing the first couplet. The concluding sentence &quot;Manjia&quot; provides a footnote for &quot;Foolishness&quot;. The ancients had the custom of climbing up to high places and planting dogwood trees to suppress evil spirits. &quot;Xu Qixie Ji&quot;: &quot;Fei Changfang ordered Huan Jing to pack dogwood on September 9th to climb high to avoid disaster.&quot; The poet therefore used the exaggerated brushwork of &quot;full of dogwood&quot; to depict himself as bohemian, open-minded and cheerful. Du Mu&#39;s line &quot;You must come home with your head full of chrysanthemums&quot; (&quot;Climbing the Mountain in Nine Days&quot;) is a pretense of broad-minded speech and a forced smile; Du Fu&#39;s poem &quot;Cui Shizhuang in Lantian in Nine Days&quot; also ends with dogwood, &quot; &quot;Look carefully at the dogwood when you are drunk&quot; is a poignant statement, expressing the emotion of a wandering life. The reason why Song Qi&#39;s sentence is different is that his life experiences are different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem is elegant and fluent, and is skillfully written, especially the last couplet, which adds a comic atmosphere to the whole poem and a strong sense of life. It was a good time to enjoy the beautiful scenery and enjoy the things. The poet took the opportunity to turn it into a poem and wrote this interesting work. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/songqi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Song Qi (998-1061) was a writer of the Northern Song Dynasty. Zi Jing, born in Anlu, Anzhou (now Anlu, Hubei), later moved to Yongqiu, Kaifeng (now Qixian, Henan). In the second year of Tiansheng&#39;s reign, he was a Jinshi, a bachelor of the Imperial Academy, and a historian. Together with Ouyang Xiu and others, he compiled the &quot;New Book of Tang Dynasty&quot; and completed it. He became the Minister of the Ministry of Industry and became a scholar of Hanlin Academy. His posthumous title was Jingwen, and he had the same literary name as his elder brother Song Xiang, and was called the &quot;Second Song Dynasty&quot; at that time. The language of the poem is beautiful. Because the poem &quot;Spring in the Jade House&quot; contains the sentence &quot;Spring is stirring on the branches of red apricots&quot;, it is known as &quot;The Book of Red Apricots&quot; in the world. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 07:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>