<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[一剪梅·花秋无月 | 辛弃疾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231021]]><description> &lt;h2>;One Cut of Plum Blossoms, No Moon in Autumn&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Xin Qiji &lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Recalling the flowers in the autumn osmanthus bush, the flowers are in the cup of flowers, and the moon is in the cup of flowers. Tonight, the same person upstairs, the screen window is wet with clouds and the screen window is wet with rain. (The moon is also in the cup of flowers, a work: The moon is also in the cup of flowers)&lt;br />;I want to take advantage of the wind to ask about chemical engineering, but the road is difficult and the letter is also difficult to pass. The whole hall is only filled with red candles, drinking and singing calmly. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Recalling the flowers and autumns of the past, I was surrounded by fragrant osmanthus bushes. The shadows of the flowers are reflected in the wine glass flowers, and the bright moon is also reflected in the wine glass flowers. Tonight I also raised a glass to admire the moon on the balcony, but the clouds were thick and the rain soaked the screens, so there was no moonlight anywhere. &lt;br />;I just want to ride the wind to heaven to question God, but there is no way to get through to heaven, even if I want to send a letter, it is difficult to get through. There is no moon in the painting hall, only red candles are shining brightly. Let us drink a few glasses of wine slowly and sing the song slowly to the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Zun: Same as &quot;zun&quot;, wine glass. &lt;br />;Hunyu: I just want to. Chemical industry: refers to the creator of nature. &lt;br />;Calm: leisurely, unhurried. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first part of the poem describes the poet’s recollection of a sunny autumn day, surrounded by osmanthus flowers, with the shadows of the moon waves rippling in the flowers. Wine glass and flowers, but tonight the screen window is wet with clouds and rain, and only the candles are shining. The next part describes the poet who wants to ride the wind to the sky to question the heavenly palace, but the road is difficult and the letter is difficult, so he has to drink slowly under the candlelight. The scene of singing expresses the poet&#39;s resentment at having unrealized ambitions and unrewarded talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last film, I use a contrasting technique to write about the regret of tonight’s flowers and autumn without the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first two sentences are in retrospect, thinking about the past because of the present. When I started writing the title, I recalled the autumn night of the previous years, when the sky was cloudless and the moon was bright. The shadows of osmanthus were whirling and the fragrance of osmanthus was floating. I leaned against the osmanthus and admired the moon while drinking wine. &quot;The flowers are in the cup of flowers and the moon is in the cup of flowers.&quot; I felt so happy and contented. situation. The two sentences &quot;Huazai&quot; are extremely well-written, revealing an ethereal, tranquil state and a feeling of joy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three sentences &quot;Tonight&quot; are twisted to write that tonight I am admiring the moon in the flower and autumn tower. People are still drinking, but there is no bright moon. The reason is that &quot;clouds wet the screens and rain wets the screens.&quot; Tonight is a rainy night. The song expresses the dull and regretful feeling of admiring the moon but not seeing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next film is about the loneliness and sadness of a moonless night. Change the head to tightly support the upper piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three sentences &quot;Hunyu&quot; describe the mood of looking forward to the moon of autumn flowers. &quot;Hun Yu wants to ride the wind to inquire about chemical engineering&quot; expresses the eagerness of looking forward to the moon, which also shows the depth of his regret. This sentence reveals the poet&#39;s hatred for being left idle by the imperial court and unable to serve his country. He wanted to &quot;ride the wind&quot; to question the emperor why he was treated like this. &quot;The road is difficult to pass. The letter is also difficult to pass.&quot; The resentment is obvious when writing about the helpless situation where wishes cannot be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last three sentences end with a scene, describing the loneliness and sadness of the moonless night in autumn. In desperation, the poet had no choice but to use red candles as his companion, drown his sorrows with wine, sing slow songs and drink alone, and talk about masturbation to pass the long moonless night. His loneliness and suffering are still vivid in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the poem &quot;Flowers&quot;, the author expressly laments that &quot;there are no moons in the autumn of flowers&quot;, but in fact, he laments the end of the hero. The whole poem is a blend of scenery and lyricism, with clear and clear language, subtle melodies and endless charm. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The poem was written from 1182 AD (the ninth year of Chunxi reign of Xiaozong of Song Dynasty) to 1192 AD (the third year of Shaoxi reign of Emperor Guangzong of Song Dynasty). When Xin Qiji lived in Daihu, the exact year cannot be determined. The poet&#39;s grief and indignation of having no way to serve the country, no hope of helping the world, and no hope of fulfilling his ambition are all poured into asking about the flower of the &quot;moon&quot;, which is expressed through this word. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/xinqiji.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Xin Qiji (May 28, 1140 - October 3, 1207), originally named Tanfu, later changed to You&#39;an, also known as Jiaxuan after the Flower Year, Shandong East Road, Jinan A native of Licheng County (now Licheng District, Jinan City, Shandong Province). He was an official, general, writer and poet of the Bold and Unconstrained School in the Southern Song Dynasty. He was known as the &quot;Dragon of Ci Flowers&quot;. Together with Su Shi, he is called &quot;Su Xin&quot;, and together with Li Qingzhao, he is called &quot;Jinan Er&#39;an&quot;. When Xin Qiji was born, Huayuan was already occupied by Jin soldiers. At the age of 21, he joined the anti-Jin rebel army and soon returned to the Southern Song Dynasty. He has successively served as the pacifier of Hubei, Jiangxi, Hunan, Fujian, and eastern Zhejiang. He devoted his life to resisting gold. He once published &quot;Ten Comments on Meiqin&quot; and &quot;Nine Discussions&quot; to lay out strategies for war and defense. His poems express the patriotic enthusiasm of trying to restore the unity of the country, express the grief and indignation of unrealized aspirations, and condemn the humiliation of the then rulers for peace; there are also many works that praise the country&#39;s mountains and rivers. The subject matter is broad and he is good at using allusions from previous generations into the lyrics. The style is majestic and heroic yet not lacking in delicacy and tenderness. Because Xin Qiji&#39;s anti-golden ideas were inconsistent with the political views of the peace faction in power, he was later impeached and dismissed from office, and retired to Daihu, Jiangxi. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:23:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人皆有不忍人之心 | 孟子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=231022]]><description> &lt;h2>;Everyone has a heart that cannot bear others&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Mencius&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>; Mencius said: &quot;Everyone has a heart that cannot bear others. The ancient kings had a heart that could not bear others. There is an intolerable government. With an intolerable heart, you implement an intolerable government and govern the world in the palm of your hand. That’s why it is said that everyone has an intolerable heart: Today, when people first see a child about to fall into a well, they are all frightened. The heart of compassion is not because of friendship with the child&#39;s parents, not because of wanting to be praised by friends in the township party, and not because of hating his voice. From this point of view, without a heart of compassion, it is not a human being; without a heart of shame or disgust , non-human; without a heart of resignation, it is not a human; without a heart of right and wrong, it is not a human being. The heart of compassion is the root of benevolence; the heart of shame and disgust is the root of righteousness; the heart of resignation is the root of etiquette; right and wrong The heart is the end of wisdom. Human beings have four ends, just like they have four bodies. Those who have four ends and claim that they cannot do so are committing treason; those who claim that the ruler is incapable of doing so are committing treason against the ruler. If there are four ends in me, I know that they are all expanded and filled, just like the beginning of fire, the beginning of spring. If I can fill it, it will be enough to protect the world; if I fail to fill it, I will not be able to serve my parents.&quot; &lt;/div>;&lt;h3 >;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />; Mencius said: &quot;Everyone has compassion and consideration for others. The ancient sage kings had compassion and consideration for others. That’s why there is politics that is compassionate and considerate of the people. If you use compassion and considerate the feelings of others and implement politics that are compassionate and considerate of the people, governing the world will be as easy as moving things in the palm of your hand. The reason why it is said that everyone has the feeling of compassion and consideration for others. , because if someone suddenly sees a child falling into a well today, he will definitely feel fear and sympathy - this is not because he wants to have a relationship with the child&#39;s parents, or because he wants to make friends with his neighbors. It is not because he dislikes the cry of this child that he has such fear and sympathy. From this point of view, without sympathy, he is simply not a human being; without shame, he is simply not a human being; without humility, he is simply not a human being. Not a human being; without a mind of right and wrong, simply not a human being. Compassion is the origin of benevolence; shame is the origin of righteousness; humility is the origin of propriety; a mind of right and wrong is the origin of wisdom. People have these four origins, just like they have limbs The same. Anyone who has these four origins but thinks that he can&#39;t do it is a person who has given up on himself; anyone who thinks that his monarch is not capable is a person who has abandoned his monarch. Anyone who has these four origins knows to expand and enrich them. Like a fire that has just begun to burn, and a spring that has just begun to flow. If you can expand them, it will be enough to stabilize the world. If you cannot expand them, it will be a problem to even support your parents.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong >;&lt;br />;Intolerance: compassion, sympathy. &lt;br />;Zha: suddenly, suddenly. &lt;br />;Be wary: frightened. Compassion: sorrow, sympathy. &lt;br />;Internal communication, internal communication means making friends, internal communication is the same as &quot;acceptance&quot;. &lt;br />;Reputation: gain reputation. &lt;br />;End: beginning, origin, source. &lt;br />;I: same as &quot;Ji&quot;. &lt;br />;Ran, the same as &quot;burn&quot;. &lt;br />;Bao: stability, stability. Yun: movement, rotation. &lt;br />;Township Party: fellow countryman. &lt;br />;It’s not because I hate the sound of the child: It’s not because I hate the sound of a child crying. &lt;br />;Shame: Feeling ashamed of one’s own bad deeds and hating others’ bad deeds. &lt;br />;Resign: humbly give in. &lt;br />;Tetrabodies: four limbs. &lt;br />;Thief: damage. &lt;br />;Da: circulation, refers to spring water gushing out. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Politics can be deduced from the premise of human nature. Specifically, benevolent politics can be deduced from the benevolence that everyone has &quot;the heart of being intolerable to others.&quot; Since this &quot;unbearable heart&quot; is inherent in human beings, benevolent government should also be a matter of course. This is Mencius&#39;s thinking. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Mencius’ derivation is still to promote his lifelong pursuit, that is, the ideal of “benevolent government”. But his derivation itself does not seem to have had a great impact, but the premise of his derivation - &quot;Everyone has a heart that cannot bear others&quot; has had a huge impact, especially the &quot;benevolence, justice, propriety and wisdom&quot; proposed on this basis. This view of &quot;being intolerant of others&quot; has become the theoretical basis and pillar of the &quot;theory of good nature&quot; in ancient Chinese philosophy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Confucius once said: &quot;Sex is similar, but habits are far apart.&quot; (&quot;The Analects of Confucius Yang Huo&quot; means that human nature is originally similar, but because of different upbringing, it is very different. But Confucius neither said what similar human nature is, whether it is good or evil, nor did he elaborate on it. Moreover, from our understanding, Confucius mainly emphasized the aspect of acquired education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Mencius It&#39;s different. He not only elaborated and pointed out that the similar human nature is the &quot;unbearable heart&quot; that originates from benevolence, justice, propriety and wisdom, but also gave vivid examples to prove that this &quot;unbearable heart&quot; is inherent in human beings. Without it, there is simply no human being. From this perspective, Mencius’s theory of human nature is indeed “transcendental” and subjective idealism. Because he described social moral concepts such as “benevolence, justice, propriety, and wisdom” as Inherent in human nature, innate, and even physiological.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; But on the other hand, Mencius did not completely deny the role of nurture. Because he believed &quot;The heart of intolerance&quot; includes four aspects, namely, the heart of &quot;compassion, shame, resignation, right and wrong&quot;, which is referred to as the &quot;four hearts&quot;. And these &quot;four hearts&quot; are just the four moral categories of &quot;benevolence, justice, etiquette and wisdom&quot;. The origin, or the &quot;four ends&quot;. These &quot;four ends&quot; are like a fire that has just burned or a spring that has just flowed out. It needs to be &quot;expanded and replenished&quot; before it can flourish. Otherwise, it will be extinguished or dried up. &quot;Expand&quot; &quot;And fill it&quot; is the acquired cultivation, that is, &quot;Xi Xiangyuan&quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Therefore, from a theoretical basis, Mencius indeed derived the theory of innate morality (&quot;Four Hearts&quot;) from the theory of innate goodness (&quot;Four Hearts&quot;). &quot;Four Ends&quot;), and then derived &quot;the government of intolerance&quot; (benevolent government). But in practice, he still attaches great importance to the role of acquired efforts (&quot;expanding it&quot;). Moreover, regardless of the question of nature or nurture, The abstract discussion of idealism or materialism can be viewed historically in relation to the social conditions of the Warring States Period where Mencius lived. He advocates that human nature is inherently good, emphasizes innate morality, and promotes benevolent politics. These are all of positive significance.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/mengzi.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt; /div>; Mencius (about 372 BC - 289 BC), whose name was Ke and whose courtesy name was Ziyu, was from the state of Zou (now southeast of Zoucheng, Shandong Province). He was a philosopher, thinker, and educator during the Warring States Period. He was the successor of Xunzi after Confucius. The former representative of the Confucian school was known as &quot;Confucius and Mencius&quot; together with Confucius. Mencius advocated &quot;benevolent government&quot; and was the first to propose the idea of ​​&quot;the people are valued more than the monarch&quot;. He was listed by Han Yu as a figure who inherited Confucius&#39; &quot;tradition&quot; among the pre-Qin Confucians, and was posthumously granted the title by the Yuan Dynasty. He is the &quot;lesser sage&quot;. Mencius&#39;s remarks and works are collected in the book &quot;Mencius&quot;. Among them, &quot;Fish I Want&quot;, &quot;If You Gain the Tao, You Will Get Many Helps, but If You Lose the Tao, There Will Be Few Helps&quot;, &quot;Ignorant People Are in a Country&quot; and &quot;Born in Worry, Die in Peace&quot; &quot; and other articles are included in Chinese textbooks for primary and secondary schools. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 04:23:11 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>