<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[渡荆门送别 | 李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239241]]><description> &lt;h2>;Farewell across Jingmen&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Li Bai&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;crossed Jingmen to visit the Kingdom of Chu. &lt;br />;The mountains end with the plains, and the river flows into the wilderness. &lt;br />;Under the moonlight, there is a flying mirror, and the clouds form a sea tower. &lt;br />;I still feel sorry for the water in my hometown, and send my boat sailing thousands of miles away. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;I took a boat across the river to the distant Jingmen, and came to the Chu State during the Warring States Period. Domestic tours. &lt;br />;The mountains gradually disappear with the emergence of flat and vast wilderness, and the rivers flow in the endless wilderness. &lt;br />;The moonlight on the river is like a mirror flying from the sky, and the clouds create a mirage outside the city. &lt;br />;I still love this water from my hometown, which came all the way to see my eastbound boat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Jingmen: The name of the mountain is located on the south bank of the Yangtze River in the northwest of Yidu County, Hubei Province. It faces Huya Mountain on the north bank. The terrain is dangerous and has been the throat of Chu and Shu since ancient times. say. &lt;br />;Far: far from. &lt;br />;Chu State: Chu Land refers to the Hubei area and belonged to the Chu State during the Spring and Autumn Period. &lt;br />;Pingye: a flat and vast wilderness. &lt;br />;River: Yangtze River. &lt;br />;Great wilderness: vast and endless fields. &lt;br />;Flying Sky Mirror under the Moon: The bright moon reflects in the river, like a flying sky mirror. Down: Move down. &lt;br />;Hailou: mirage, which describes the beautiful scene of clouds on the river. &lt;br />;Still: still. &lt;br />;Pity: love. One book is &quot;Lian&quot;. &lt;br />;Hometown water: refers to the Yangtze River water flowing from Sichuan. Because the poet has lived in Sichuan since he was a child, he calls Sichuan his hometown. &lt;br />;Wanli: means a long journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by Li Bai when he came out of Shu. Li Bai left Shu this time and took a long boat ride by water, passing through Bayu, out of the Three Gorges, and headed straight beyond Jingmen Mountain. The purpose was to visit the hometown of the Chu Kingdom in Hubei and Hunan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Crossing the distance outside Jingmen, coming to travel from the state of Chu&quot; refers to this grand tour. At this time, the young poet was very interested. He sat on the boat and admired the towering mountains on both sides of Wushan Mountain. Along the way, the scenery in front of him gradually changed. When the boat passed the Jingmen area, it was already a plain wilderness, and the field of vision suddenly broadened. Scenery:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The mountains end with the plains, and the rivers flow into the wilderness.&quot; In this couplet, in just ten words, the author describes four scenes: rolling mountains, flat fields, and rushing rivers. Yangtze River, a vast wasteland. Every scene is so vast that it makes people look at it and think about it thousands of miles away. This sentence means that the mountains gradually disappear with the appearance of low plains, and the rivers flow in the endless wilderness. It describes the magnificent scenery of crossing Jingmen and entering the Chu region, and uses a flowing perspective to describe the changes in the scenery. The terrain on both sides of the ship from Shu to Jingmen transitions from mountains to plains. The mountains disappear from the sight little by little, and the river rushes down the mountains toward the river. The vast wilderness rushes away, drawing a majestic picture of the Yangtze River, which is a long-term view. Among them, the word &quot;sui&quot; gradually changes and shifts the position of the mountains and wilderness, truly expressing it and making it vivid, giving people a sense of space and flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How to integrate four scenes into the same picture? The author uses the word &quot;sui&quot; to connect &quot;mountain&quot; and &quot;wild&quot; together, and the word &quot;ru&quot; to connect &quot;river&quot; and &quot;wild&quot; together. The word &quot;sui&quot; depicts the direction and trend of the mountains, with a sense of flow and space, as if a picture is slowly unfolding in front of you. As the mountains go lower and lower, and finally submerge into the earth, the plains become wider and wider, and the poet&#39;s vision becomes wider. The word &quot;end&quot; expresses the joyful feeling of the poet&#39;s eyes suddenly opening up when the mountains disappear and the plains appear. The word &quot;ru&quot; has a strong sense of wedge, depicting the power of the Yangtze River impacting the wilderness, and also inspiring the author&#39;s pride. The author&#39;s inner passion and progress also rush to the distant sky with the current. The word &quot;enter&quot; in Wang Wan&#39;s &quot;Under the Cibeigu Mountain&quot; has the same connotation in &quot;The sun is rising in the sea and the night is lingering, and the spring in the river is entering the old year&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Under the moon, there is a flying mirror, and the clouds form a sea tower.&quot; It means that the reflection of the moon in the water is like a sky mirror flying down from the sky. The clouds rise and change endlessly, forming a mirage. This sentence is a description of a close-up view of the Yangtze River. The &quot;Flying Mirror under the Moon&quot; is what you can see when looking down on a moonlit night. &quot;Yunshengjiehai Tower&quot; is what you can see when you look at it during the day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I still pity the water of my hometown, and it sends me on a long journey thousands of miles away.&quot; It means that I still pity the water of my hometown, which flows thousands of miles to send me on a long journey. This sentence uses the rhetorical technique of personification to personify the water in my hometown. It expresses the poet&#39;s reluctance and longing for my hometown when he leaves his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poet traveled along the Yangtze River to Jingmen, and the Shu land through which the river flowed was the hometown where he had been raised. How could he not be infinitely nostalgic and reluctant to leave when we parted for the first time? But the poet did not say that he missed his hometown, but said that the water of his hometown reluctantly sent me away all the way. With deep affection, he sent me off thousands of miles away. Writing from the opposite side, it became more and more obvious that he was homesick. The poem ends with a strong feeling of nostalgia and farewell, with endless words and endless emotions. The &quot;farewell&quot; in the title of the poem should be a farewell to one&#39;s hometown rather than a farewell to a friend. There is no emotion of farewell to a friend in the poem. Shen Deqian of the Qing Dynasty believed that &quot;there is no farewell meaning in the poem, and the two words can be deleted&quot; (&quot;Tang Poems&quot;), which is not unreasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The beginning and end of this poem are integrated, with lofty artistic conception and vigorous style. &quot;The mountains follow the plains and the fields end, and the river flows into the wilderness.&quot; The writing is lifelike and picturesque, just like a long-axis landscape painting of the Yangtze River emerging from the gorge and crossing Jingmen, and has become a popular saying. If it is said that an excellent landscape painting &quot;should be judged by thousands of miles if it is close at hand&quot;, then this majestic and majestic Five Rhymes can also be said to be able to see the big from the small, and one to ten. It is rich in capacity and encompasses the scenery of mountains and water flows tens of thousands of miles in the middle reaches of the Yangtze River. It has Highly concentrated artistic generalization ability. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written by Li Bai as a farewell to his hometown when he came from Shu to Jingmen in his youth. The specific writing time of this poem is uncertain. There are three specific theories: one is that it was written in 724 (the 12th year of Kaiyuan), the other is that it was written in 725 (the 13th year of Kaiyuan), and the third is that it was written in 726 (the 14th year of Kaiyuan). &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/libai.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Li Bai (701-762), also known as Taibai, also known as Qinglian Jushi, also known as &quot;The Exiled Immortal&quot;, was a great romantic poet in the Tang Dynasty and was hailed as the &quot;Poetry Immortal&quot; by later generations. &quot;, together with Du Fu are called &quot;Li Du&quot;. In order to distinguish them from the other two poets Li Shangyin and Du Mu, namely &quot;Little Li Du&quot;, Du Fu and Li Bai are also collectively called &quot;Big Li Du&quot;. According to the &quot;New Book of Tang&quot; records, Li Bai was the ninth grandson of Emperor Xingsheng (Liang Wuzhao King Li Hao) and the same clan as the kings of Li and Tang Dynasties. He is a cheerful and generous person who loves drinking, writing poetry, and making friends. Li Bai was deeply influenced by Huang Lao Liezhuang&#39;s thoughts. The &quot;Collection of Li Taibai&quot; has been handed down from generation to generation. Most of his poems were written when he was drunk. His representative works include &quot;Wang Lushan Waterfall&quot;, &quot;The Road is Difficult&quot;, &quot;The Road to Shu is Difficult&quot;, &quot;About Wine&quot; and &quot;Morning&quot;. &quot;Fa Baidi City&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 04:23:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大铁椎传 | 魏禧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239232]]><description> &lt;h2>;The Legend of Da Tiezhui&lt;/h2>;[Ming Dynasty] Wei Xi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>; I don’t know who Da Tiezhui was. Chen Zican, his brother from Beiping Province, came to Henan Province and met General Song&#39;s family. In the Song Dynasty, he was a native of Qinghua Town, Huaiqing. He was good at martial arts. All the good people from the seven provinces came to learn martial arts. People praised him as a general of the Song Dynasty because of his strength. Gao Xinzhi, a disciple of the Song Dynasty, was also a native of Huaiqing. He was very powerful and good at shooting. His eldest son Can was seven years old and he was a junior classmate, so he had some experience with the Song general. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, there was a healthy guest sitting in the seat. He looked very sleepy and had a large iron vertebra on his right side, weighing forty or fifty kilograms. The iron handle is folded and the ring is folded, like a lock, and the lead is about ten feet long. He rarely talks to others, and his language is similar to Chu&#39;s. I asked him about his hometown and surname, but he didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; After we slept together, at midnight, the guest said, &quot;I&#39;m leaving!&quot; After saying that, he disappeared. When Zi Can saw that the windows were all closed, he was surprised and asked Xin Zhi. Xinzhi said: &quot;When the guest arrived for the first time, he had no hat or socks. He wrapped his head in a blue handkerchief and wrapped his feet in white cloth. He held nothing except the big iron spine, and his waist was full of platinum. Neither I nor the general dared to ask.&quot; Zican When I wake up from a deep sleep, the guest is snoring and sleeping on the kang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day, he resigned from the Song Dynasty general and said: &quot;I heard your name for the first time and felt proud of it, but it is of no use. I&#39;m leaving!&quot; The general forced him to stay, and said: &quot;I will kill the horse thieves several times. , seize their belongings, so you hate me. If you stay here for a long time, disaster will happen to you. At midnight tonight, I will duel at a certain place.&quot; General Song happily said: &quot;I ride on horseback and carry arrows to help the battle.&quot; The guest said: &quot;Stop! The thieves can and there are many. , I want to protect you, but I am not happy with my wishes.&quot; General Song was so conceited and wanted to observe what the guests did, so he tried his best to entertain the guests. The guest has no choice but to go with me. When they were about to arrive at the battle, they sent the general to the castle and said, &quot;Just watch and be careful not to make any noise, so that the thieves will know.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, the rooster crows and the moon sets, the stars illuminate the wilderness, and people can be seen at a hundred paces. As the guests drove off, they blew several whistles. In a moment, more than twenty thieves on horseback gathered on all sides, and hundreds of followers on foot, carrying bows and arrows. A thief rushed towards the guest with a knife. The guest shouted and waved his spine. The thief fell off his horse and his horse&#39;s head was split open. The thieves circled in and attacked from left and right. The men and horses fell to the ground, killing about thirty people. The general of Song Dynasty held his breath and looked at it with tremors in his chest. Suddenly I heard the guest shouting: &quot;I&#39;m leaving.&quot; The dust was billowing and galloping eastward. Then he never came again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Wei Xi said: The most powerful person in the ovary is the emperor of Qin Dynasty, Bolang Shazhong. Who is the big iron spine? Those who are born strange must be put to some use. I read Chen Tongfu&#39;s &quot;Zhongxing Inheritance&quot; and found out how many heroes, heroes, heroes, and heroes have never seen their fame in the world! How can it be that the creatures of heaven do not need to be used by humans? Is it better to use it naturally? Zican met Da Tiezhui when he was Renyin years old. He thought he was thirty years old, but Da Tiezhui had forty ears this year. Zican also saw him writing posts about market things, and he was very skilled in regular script. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; In November of the Gengxu year, I returned home from Yangzhou and met Chen Zican Same boat. Zican was twenty-eight years old at the time and liked to use guns and sticks. When I was teaching him the art of war in Zuo Zhuan, I took the opportunity to ask: &quot;Have you ever met any strange people in your travels?&quot; Zican asked me. After telling about the story of Da Tiezhui, I wrote &quot;The Legend of Da Tiezhui&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Big iron spine, I don’t know where he is from. Chen Zican from Peiping went to Henan to visit his brother and met Da Tiezhui at the home of General Song. General Song is a native of Qinghua Town, Huaiqing. He is good at martial arts. People who love martial arts from seven provinces come to learn from him. People call him General Song because he is tall and strong. General Song&#39;s apprentice Gao Xinzhi was also from Huaiqing. He was strong and good at archery. He was seven years older than Chen Zican and was his classmate when he was a child. Therefore, Chen Zican once visited General Song with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, there was a guest with a big appetite. He was very ugly. He had a large iron vertebra under his right arm, weighing forty or fifty kilograms. He would not put it down for a moment while eating or bowing his hands. . The iron chain on the handle of the big iron vertebra is folded around, like a chain on a lock, and it is stretched over a foot long. He rarely talked to people, and his accent sounded like that of Chu Di (now Hubei, Hunan). I asked him where his hometown was and what his name was, but he didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; We slept together, and in the middle of the night, the guest said, &quot;I&#39;m leaving.&quot; As soon as he finished speaking, the person disappeared. When Chen Zican saw that the windows and doors were closed, he asked Gao Xinzhi in surprise. Gao Xinzhi said: &quot;When the guest first arrived, he didn&#39;t wear a hat or socks, wrapped his head in a blue handkerchief, and wrapped his feet in white cloth. He didn&#39;t carry anything except a large iron spine, and there was a lot of silver wrapped in his belt. . Neither General Song nor I dared to ask him.&quot; When Chen Zican woke up, the knight was already snoring in bed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day, the knight said goodbye to General Song: &quot;When I first heard about your reputation, I regarded you as a hero. However, your martial arts are of no use. I left.&quot; General Song Trying his best to retain him, he said: &quot;I have repeatedly killed the robbers who blocked the road and seized their property, so they hate me. If I stay here for a long time, disaster will involve you. At midnight tonight, the robbers are making an agreement Come with me to a duel somewhere.&quot; General Song said happily: &quot;I am riding a horse with a bow and arrow to help fight.&quot; The knight said: &quot;Don&#39;t go, the robbers are strong and there are many people. If I want to protect you, I can&#39;t Let&#39;s kill him with all his heart.&quot; General Song always thought he was a great person, and also wanted to see the knight&#39;s skills, so he tried his best to ask the knight to come with him. The knight had no choice but to take him with him. When they were about to arrive at the duel, the knight escorted General Song to a deserted fortress and said, &quot;You can only watch and be silent, lest the robbers discover you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this time, the rooster crows, the moon sets, the stars illuminate the open field, and people can be seen within a hundred steps. The knight galloped down on horseback and blew several whistles. After a while, more than twenty bandits on horseback gathered from all sides, followed by more than a hundred people walking on foot carrying bows and arrows. A robber rushed towards the knight with a knife on his horse. The knight shouted: &quot;Look at the spine.&quot; He waved the iron spine, and the robber fell off the horse, and the horse&#39;s head was smashed into pieces. The group of robbers moved forward to surround them. The knights swung their iron spines and struck left and right. The robbers fell to the ground, including men and horses, and more than thirty people were killed. General Song held his breath while watching this fierce battle. His legs were shaking with fear and he almost fell off the fortress. Suddenly, I heard the knight shout loudly: &quot;I&#39;m leaving!&quot; The dust was billowing and he flew towards the east. He never came back after that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wei Xi commented: Zhang Liang found a strong man and used an iron vertebrae to beat Qin Shihuang at Bolangsha. Is the big iron vertebrae probably the same kind of person? If someone is born with extraordinary talents, there must be a place where they can be used. But when I read Chen Liang&#39;s &quot;Zhongxing Inheritance&quot;, I found that there are so many people with outstanding intelligence, chivalrous spirit, and majesty who are silently unable to show their achievements and reputation in the contemporary era. Why are there so many of them? Is it true that talents born from heaven may not necessarily be appointed by others? Or will there be a certain opportunity for them to be appointed? Chen Zican met Da Tiezhui in the Renyin year. Judging from his appearance, he should be thirty years old, so Da Tiezhui was already forty years old at that time. Zican once saw him writing a shopping list. His regular script was very neat and beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The Biography of Da Tiezhui: Selected from &quot;Wen Shuzi Wenchao&quot;, with some abridgements. The article is a biography. Since I don’t know the name of this person, I used his weapon “big iron awl” instead. &lt;br />;Gengxu: year (the ninth year of Kangxi). &lt;br />;Guangling: the ancient name of Yangzhou. &lt;br />;Chen Zican: Life is unknown. &lt;br />;Zuo&#39;s Art of War: Refers to the texts describing wars in &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;. &lt;br />;Beiping: Beijing. In the early Ming Dynasty, the capital was renamed Peiping, and in 2000 (the first year of Yongle, the founder of the Ming Dynasty), it was renamed Beijing. This is named after the early Ming Dynasty. Province (xǐng) brother Henan: I went to Henan to visit my brother. &lt;br />;Huaiqing: name of the mansion, present-day Qinyang, Henan. &lt;br />;Gong Wushu: Good at martial arts. &lt;br />;Seven provinces: refers to Henan and its neighboring seven provinces of Hebei, Shandong, Shanxi, Shaanxi, Anhui and Hubei. &lt;br />;Shao classmates: classmates in adolescence. &lt;br />;Over: visit. &lt;br />;Jian Wei (dàn light): a large appetite. Eat, eat. &lt;br />;Looking very ugly. Sleep, ugly. &lt;br />;Right side: right armpit. &lt;br />;The sentence &quot;diet&quot; means that the vertebrae are always inseparable from the body. Not leaving for a while: not leaving for a while. &lt;br />;&quot;Handle iron&quot; sentence: The iron handle of the vertebra can be folded around like a chain. Practice and pass the &quot;chain&quot;. &lt;br />;Introduction: elongation. &lt;br />;Language type Chu Sheng: speaking with an accent that sounds like Chu Di. Chu Territory, now Hunan and Hubei, was Chu Territory in ancient times. &lt;br />;Buckle: Use &quot;knock&quot; to ask. &lt;br />;End of speech (qì): Finished. &lt;br />;Platinum: Silver. &lt;br />;Snoring (hān soundly) sleep: sleeping soundly. Snoring, snoring. Kang: A bed made of adobe. &lt;br />;Hao: hero. &lt;br />;Qiang: (qiǎng) try your best to retain. &lt;br />;Horse thieves: Bandits who gang up to rob the road. They blow whistles or shoot rattle arrows before robbing, so they are called thieves. &lt;br />;Qiu: resentment, hatred. &lt;br />;And: will. &lt;br />;Issue: Agreement. &lt;br />;Ability: capable. &lt;br />;My displeasure means: I cannot fight happily. &lt;br />;With companions: Go with (him). &lt;br />;Be careful not to make a sound. &lt;br />;觱篥 (bì lì): an ancient wind instrument. &amp;nbsp; Use bamboo for the pipe and reed for the mouth. It was introduced from the Western Regions in the Han Dynasty. &lt;br />;Enter the circle: siege. &lt;br />;Pu: Fall forward. &lt;br />;Breathe holding: Temporarily suppresses breathing. Screen, suppress. &lt;br />;Twinkles: The legs are shaking. Cherish, tremble, tremble. &lt;br />;Three sentences of &quot;Zifang&quot;: It is said that Da Tiezhu is the same type of person as Zhang Liang&#39;s powerful men in the Han Dynasty. Zifang, Zhang Liang, named Zifang. Qin destroyed Han, and Zhang Liang wanted to avenge Han. Later, he found a strongman who could lift an iron vertebra weighing 120 kilograms and sniped at Qin Shihuang in Bolangsha, but only hit the deputy car (see &quot;Historical Records: Liuhou&quot;) Family&quot;).椤 (yú), a particle, expresses questions, exclamations, rhetorical questions, etc. &lt;br />;Chen Tongfu: Chen Liang of the Southern Song Dynasty, courtesy name Tongfu, was a writer and the author of &quot;Collected Works of Longchuan&quot; and &quot;Ci of Longchuan&quot;. His &quot;Zhongxing Inheritance&quot; is a biography of ministers, generals, dead men, capable ministers, and able figures before and after the Song Dynasty&#39;s southern crossing. Among them, there are two categories: chivalrous and righteous. The characters are similar to big iron spines, so it is said that, To elicit the following sentiments. &lt;br />;泳泯(mǐn): to describe the disappearance of one after another. &lt;br />;Renyinsui: year (the first year of Kangxi). &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; In the late Ming and early Qing dynasties, the creation of biographical essays showed a boom. The reason for this was to praise the loyal and martyrs. , are inseparable from the concept of preserving history through literature, so it has a distinct and complex connotation of the times. It is a concrete manifestation of the complex thoughts of scholars in the early Qing Dynasty (especially the survivors of the Ming Dynasty), of which Wei Xi is a model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wei Xi was the head of the famous literary group &quot;Nine Sons of Yitang&quot; in the early Qing Dynasty. He was famous all over the world for his articles on integrity and was one of the three masters of ancient prose in the early Qing Dynasty. Throughout Wei Xizhi&#39;s ancient prose creation, biographical prose is a very important component. Examining his biographical writings, we can see the complex spiritual trajectory of scholars in the early Qing Dynasty, and we can also interpret the cultural connotations and aesthetic pursuits of the articles in the early Qing Dynasty. Among such biographies, the most widely praised is undoubtedly &quot;The Legend of Da Tiezhui&quot;, which created the image of a legendary &quot;outlander&quot; with superb skills, strange behavior and legendary color. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; Because the author did not know the name of the man, he used his weapon &quot;Big Iron Vertebral&quot; instead. In a delicate and vivid way, the article depicts the &quot;stranger&quot; image of a strong man who is knowledgeable, upright, skilled in martial arts, literate, and capable of using iron vertebrae. It depicts such a heroic figure who could have accomplished a lot at that time. However, he encountered mismatches and had no place to use his skills. He could only fight the thieves in a sad situation. It revealed the author&#39;s dissatisfaction with the rulers and ministers of the Ming Dynasty&#39;s subjugation, expressed his pain of the subjugation, and expressed the author&#39;s hope that someone would rise up to &quot;resist the Qing Dynasty and restore the Ming Dynasty.&quot; Patriotic thoughts. &lt;br />;&lt;br />; &quot;The Legend of Da Tiezhui&quot; belongs to the author&#39;s so-called biography of &quot;the commoner lone traveler&quot;. Iron vertebra (chuí), ancient weapon. It is said that the name of the master is unknown, he is very brave, and he is named after his weapons. The main part of the biography adopts the perspective of a specific character in the biography, describing the biography&#39;s unusual appearance, mysterious actions, and fighting scenes, vividly portraying the image of a heroic figure invisible to the people, like a dragon that sees its head but not its tail. The concluding remarks also leave endless meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The article is a legendary biography. The author is good at raising doubts, making it fascinating to read. But until the end of the article, we only knew that the protagonist was a man with special skills. As for why he came to see General Song, and why he later said that General Song was &quot;not useful&quot;, he was kept secretive. It can be seen from this that the author had some hope in writing this character. General Song set off Da Tiezhu&#39;s character. &quot;General Song&quot; also alluded to those silent old officials of the Ming Dynasty at that time, who had only a false reputation and lacked the courage and strength to resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The language of the biography is very concise, but readers can still feel the hero&#39;s bold and deep character from the appearance, language, actions and other aspects. Da Tiezhui came to visit General Song in order to make friends with real heroes who can do great things. After he carefully observed and discovered that General Song&#39;s martial arts were mediocre and lacked courage, he decisively concluded that &quot;none of them were of any use&quot; and decided to leave. This was a side of his deep character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The part about the starry night duel is the most exciting part of the whole article. Write the environment: the cock crows, the moon sets, and the stars illuminate the wilderness, highlighting the solemn atmosphere of the duel. The large number of people who wrote, the abundance of weapons, the massed steps, and the huge momentum further highlighted the bravery of the &quot;big iron spine&quot;. As for General Song, who was a &quot;skilled martial artist&quot; with a false reputation and was quite conceited, he was watching from the sidelines. He was so frightened that he didn&#39;t dare to breathe. His legs were trembling and he almost fell down. This description further highlights the extraordinary bravery of the &quot;Big Iron Vertebrae&quot; from the side. The front depicts him striking with all his strength, with men and horses falling on the ground on all sides. With just a few strokes, his extraordinary power, superb martial arts, and heroic character are vividly portrayed. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/weixi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Wei Xi (March 2, 1624 - November 17, 1680) was a prose writer in the late Ming and early Qing Dynasties. Together with Wang Wan and Hou Fangyu, he was known as the three major prose writers in the early Qing Dynasty. Rui and Dili are collectively known as the Three Wei Dynasties of Ningdu. The brothers of the Three Wei Dynasties, Peng Shiwang, Lin Shiyi, Li Tengjiao, Yue Weiping, Peng Ren, etc. are collectively known as the Nine Sons of Yitang. His nickname is Uncle Bing, his nickname is Uncle, and his nickname is Yuzhai. A native of Ningdu, Jiangxi Province, he lived in seclusion in Shaoting, Cuiweifeng during the late Ming Dynasty. He was known as Mr. Shaoting. Later, he traveled to the south of the Yangtze River, met friends through literature, spread his teachings of understanding truth, understanding current affairs, respecting integrity and fearing reputation, and recruiting virtuous people in order to recover. His articles mostly praise national integrity and personnel, showing a strong national consciousness. He is also good at commenting on the deeds of the ancients, and has certain opinions on the rights and wrongs, successes and failures of the ancients. He is the author of &quot;Collected Works of Wei Shuzi&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:23:09 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>