<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[题郑所南兰 | 倪瓒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239262]]><description> &lt;h2>;Inscribed on Zheng Suo Nan Lan&lt;/h2>;[Yuan Dynasty] Ni Zan&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;The autumn wind turns orchids into grass, and the desolation of the southern country has disappeared. &lt;br />;Only Suo Nan’s heart remains unchanged, and the tears and ink are used to write about Li Sao. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The autumn wind is fierce, the orchids turn into grass, and the quiet life of Jiangnan is gone remove. &lt;br />;Only Suonan remained loyal and expressed his patriotism with tears and ink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Zheng Suonan: a survivor of the Southern Song Dynasty and a painter. His poems and paintings mostly express his nostalgia for his motherland and his steadfast national integrity. &lt;br />;Lanhui: orchid grass, cymbidium grass. Mao: thatch. &lt;br />;Nanguo: generally refers to the vast area south of the Yangtze River. Qi has disappeared: the vitality of all things has disappeared. This is a metaphor that the remnant’s ambition to restore the country has disappeared. &lt;br />;So-nam’s heart has not changed: Zheng So-nam’s desire to restore the country has never changed. &lt;br />;Fountain of Tears: Tears. &lt;br />;Li Sao: A patriotic poem by the patriotic poet Qu Yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; At the beginning of the poem, he expresses his feelings about the orchids painted by Zheng Suonan. But this feeling was expressed by the author through his own imagination, after transforming the orchid painted by Zheng Suonan. Zheng Suonan paints orchids that have no contact with the earth. The author imagines that the orchids in this painting have turned into thatch in the chilling autumn wind. Here the author uses the poetic meaning in Qu Yuan&#39;s &quot;Li Sao&quot; that &quot;the orchids have changed and become less fragrant, and the water chestnuts have turned into grass; the grass was fragrant in the past, but it is now Xiao Ai.&quot; In this way, it shows that the death of the Song Dynasty After that, not only was the country ravaged by the Mongolian rulers, but many people were tortured, some rebelled, and some had their willpower to resist the Yuan Dynasty and restore the country exhausted. Moreover, the entire &quot;Southern Country&quot; is desolate and lifeless. These two sentences describe how after the fall of the Southern Song Dynasty, under the cruel rule of the Mongols, the struggle to resist the Yuan Dynasty and restore the country had gradually declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next two sentences turn to praise Zheng Suonan. It is said that only Zheng Suonan remained loyal to the Southern Song Dynasty. He used his tears and ink to paint orchids, and wrote another &quot;Li Sao&quot; in the form of painting. This shows Zheng Suonan&#39;s steadfast national integrity and firm patriotic belief. The author praises Zheng Suonan, and actually expresses his national integrity of never succumbing to any violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem uses contrasting techniques. The first two sentences use the method of comparison to show the increasingly depressed scene of people&#39;s struggle to resist the Yuan Dynasty and restore the country under the cruel rule of the Mongolian Yuan Dynasty. The last two sentences describe that Zheng Suonan&#39;s loyalty to the country remains unchanged. The first two sentences are used to contrast the last two sentences, which shows the meaning. The value of Nanjian’s steadfastness and patriotism. As Confucius said: &quot;When the cold comes, the pines and cypresses will wither.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; &quot;Inscribed on Zheng Suo Nanlan&quot; is a poem on painting. It is the Qijue inscribed for the ink orchid painted by Zheng Suonan. Ni Zan knew Zheng Suonan&#39;s heart well, so he wrote this poem to express his national consciousness. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/nizan.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Ni Zan (1301～1374), a painter and poet in the Yuan Dynasty. The first name was Jue, with the courtesy name Taiyu, and later the courtesy name Yuanzhen, with the nicknames Yunlinzi, Jingmanmin, Huanxiazi, etc. A native of Wuxi, Jiangsu. The family is rich, knowledgeable and fond of ancient times, and celebrities from all over the world often come to his door. Emperor Shun of the Yuan Dynasty suddenly dispersed all his wealth and wandered around Taihu Lake. He is good at painting landscapes and ink bamboos. He learned from Dong Yuan and was influenced by Zhao Mengfu. In his early years, his painting style was clear and moist, but in his later years, he changed his style and became plain and naive. The sparse forest on the slope bank is secluded and elegant, the writing is simple and the meaning is far-reaching, and the ink is cherished like gold. Using the side-edge dry brush to make chaffing is called &quot;Zhedai chambraying&quot;. The ink bamboo has an upturned posture and a few strokes, full of energy. His calligraphy came from Li, he has the style of a Jin person, and he is also good at poetry. Together with Huang Gongwang, Wang Meng, and Wuzhen, they are collectively known as the &quot;Four Yuan Families&quot;. His extant works include &quot;Picture of Autumn at Yuzhuang&quot;, &quot;Picture of Six Gentlemen&quot;, &quot;Picture of Rong Xi Zhai&quot;, etc. He is the author of &quot;Qing Zhen Pavilion Collection&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 05:23:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[守岁 | 苏轼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239252]]><description> &lt;h2>;Shou Sui&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Su Shi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;If you want to know that dying of old age is like going to prey on a snake. &lt;br />;The scales are half gone, no one can cover them up. &lt;br />;Kang wants to tie it to the end, but he knows what to do despite his diligence. &lt;br />;The children stayed awake all night and kept each other happy. &lt;br />;Don’t sing the rooster in the morning, even more drums are afraid of Tim Lao. &lt;br />;After sitting for a long time, the lights are dimming, and I watch the Beidou tilt. &lt;br />;There won’t be a year next year, and I’m afraid my worries will be wasted. &lt;br />;You can still praise yourself if you try your best today. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;You must know that the age when you are about to say goodbye is like a long snake swimming into a deep ravine. &lt;br />;Half of the long scales are gone, who can stop the desire to leave! &lt;br />;Not to mention trying to tie its tail end, even though I am diligent and know that there is no way. &lt;br />;Children struggle hard without sleeping, staying with each other laughing and making noise at night. &lt;br />;Morning rooster, please don’t crow, the drums urging you are frightening. &lt;br />;I sat there for a long time and the lanterns were falling. I stood up and saw that the Big Dipper had tilted sideways. &lt;br />;Will there be no New Year&#39;s Eve next year? I&#39;m just afraid that my worries will go wrong again. &lt;br />;Trying to cherish this night, young people can still boast of their spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;End: It’s almost over. &lt;br />;呑(hè): valley. &lt;br />;Scaling: refers to the body of a long snake. &lt;br />;Qiang (qiǎng): reluctantly. &lt;br />;Wow: one means &quot;noisy&quot;. &lt;br />;Lao (zhuā): hit, beat, here refers to the sound of drums. &lt;br />;Dengji (jìn): lamp flower. Embers are the remaining parts of an object after burning. &lt;br />;Beidou Xian: It means it is midnight. &lt;br />;Waste (cuō tuó): Time passes in vain, time is wasted. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written in the seventh year of Renzong Jiayou&#39;s reign (1062). &quot;Farewell&quot;, three poems sent to Su Che. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Shou Sui&quot; has sixteen sentences, which can be divided into three levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first level has six sentences: &quot;If you want to know that you are dying at the end of your life, it is like a snake going to kill you. The scales are half gone, who can cover up the intention? If you want to tie it to its tail, you can do nothing even if you work hard. &quot;A vivid metaphor is used here to illustrate the futility of staying up late, and the topic is approached from the negative side, which is different from the previous two poems. This metaphor is not only vivid, but also shows that the dragon and the snake are the same, and the snake is used to compare the years. It is not a general metaphor. The first four of these six sentences are about the year approaching, and the last two sentences are about trying to save the situation, but it is in vain. Although the literal meaning of &quot;tying its tail&quot; is &quot;Tie a dog by its neck, but now it is tied by its tail&quot; in &quot;Book of Jin·Jia Hou Zhuan&quot;, in the text, it is completely used as a metaphor for &quot;going to kill a snake&quot;: By New Year&#39;s Eve, it is already It’s impossible to pull out the snake upside down since it’s distal end. What’s more, if you only grasp the end of the snake’s tail, how can you tie it? Starting with these six sentences seems to say that this custom is unreasonable. If you want to write about keeping the New Year&#39;s Eve, you should first write that you can&#39;t keep it, and you don&#39;t have to keep it. This is a trick of playing hard to get and making the text more complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The middle six sentences are the second level: &quot;Children are forced not to sleep, and they stay together all night chatting. Don&#39;t sing the morning rooster, more drums are afraid of the sound of the drums. After sitting for a long time, the embers of the lamp are falling, and I watch the Beidou diagonally. .&quot; This level describes the scene of staying up late on New Year&#39;s Eve. The word &quot;strong&quot; describes the characteristics of children celebrating New Year&#39;s Eve: they obviously want to doze off, but they still have to force themselves to have fun. These two sentences are still the author&#39;s recollection of the customs of his hometown, not the scene when he was in Fengxiang. Su Shi was only twenty-six years old that year (his age was twenty-seven), and he had only one son, Su Mai, who was five years old. The scene described in these two sentences could not have happened. The two sentences &quot;morning chicken&quot; describe the psychological state of staying up late at night in detail, and the two lines &quot;sitting for a long time&quot; describe the scene of staying up late at night very realistically. These two sentences are mainly aimed at adults staying up late on the New Year&#39;s Eve. Ji Yun admired these ten words very much and said they were &quot;real scenes&quot;. In fact, this is a feeling that everyone has experienced. He was able to write it down effortlessly, adding a lot of intimacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The last four sentences are the third level: &quot;Will there be no year next year? I&#39;m afraid that worrying about it will be wasted. If you work hard today, you can still be proud of the young man.&quot; This level contrasts with the hard-to-get game of the first level at the beginning, indicating that It makes sense to stay up late and cherish the passing time. Confess positively that you should stay up until the end of New Year’s Eve. The last two sentences use Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;still exaggerated youthfulness&quot; to encourage Su Che. Su Che served his father in the capital, and Su Shi hoped that the two places would stay together and cherish the years together. This conclusion contains a positive and energetic meaning and is the finishing touch, which suddenly lifts the spirit of the whole poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Su Shi&#39;s &quot;Shou Sui&quot; is poetic and easy to understand, aiming to encourage oneself to cherish time like gold. The author uses the image of a snake shedding its skin as a metaphor for not being able to waste time, implying that we must seize the time to do things from beginning to end, lest the time will be over half, and no matter how hard we work, it will be difficult to make up for it. Efforts should start today and don’t let your ambitions go to waste. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/sushi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Su Shi, (January 8, 1037 - August 24, 1101), also known as Zizhan and Hezhong, also known as Tieguan Taoist and Dongpo layman, known as Su Dongpo and Su Xian in the world. Han nationality, a native of Meishan, Meizhou (Meishan City, Sichuan Province), his ancestral home is Luancheng, Hebei Province, a famous writer, calligrapher, and painter in the Northern Song Dynasty, and a celebrity in water control in history. Su Shi was a literary leader in the mid-Northern Song Dynasty and made great achievements in poetry, lyrics, prose, calligraphy, and painting. His writing is bold and unbridled; his poems are broad in subject matter, fresh and vigorous, good at using exaggerated metaphors, and have a unique style. Together with Huang Tingjian, he is called &quot;Su Huang&quot;; His prose writings are grand and bold. Together with Ouyang Xiu, he is called &quot;Ou Su&quot; and is one of the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Su Shi was good at calligraphy and one of the &quot;Four Masters of the Song Dynasty&quot;; he was good at literati painting, especially ink bamboo, strange rocks, dead wood, etc. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan and Ouyang Xiu, they are known as the &quot;Four Great Masters of Eternal Writing&quot;. His works include &quot;Dongpo Seven Collections&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yi Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yuefu&quot;, &quot;Xiaoxiang Bamboo and Stone Picture Scroll&quot;, &quot;Old Trees and Strange Stones Picture Scroll&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 06:23:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>