<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[与诸子登岘山 | 孟浩然]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310241]]><description> &lt;h2>;Climbing Mount Xian with the Masters&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Meng Haoran&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;People and affairs change over time, and exchanges become ancient and modern. &lt;br />;The mountains and rivers have left traces of their beauty, and we will come here again. &lt;br />;The fish beam is shallow when the water falls, and the dream is deep when the weather is cold. &lt;br />;The Yanggong Monument is still there, and I shed tears after reading it. (Shang Yi&#39;s work: Zi Zai) &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;People and things in the world change, and summer passes When the cold comes, time passes, forming history from ancient times to the present. &lt;br />;We can now climb and visit the scenic spots and historic sites preserved throughout the country. &lt;br />;When the water falls and the rocks come out, Yuliangzhou is clear and shallow; when the weather is cold and the trees fall, Yunmengze is vast and boundless. &lt;br />;The monument to Yang Hu of Jin Dynasty is still standing majestically. After reading the inscription, my clothes were wet with tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Xianshan: A Xianshou Mountain, located south of present-day Xiangyang City, Hubei Province. Zhuzi: refers to several friends of the poet. &lt;br />;Metabolism: alternating changes. &lt;br />;Coming and going: the old goes and the new comes. &lt;br />;Revisiting: For Yang Hu, he once climbed to Xian Mountain. Climb: Climb a mountain to watch. &lt;br />;Yuliang: the name of a sandbar located in the Mianshui River of Lumen Mountain in Xiangyang. &lt;br />;Mengze: Yunmengze, ancient Daze, now Jianghan Plain. &lt;br />;Word: One is &quot;Shang&quot;. &lt;br />;Yanggong Monument: Built by later generations to commemorate the famous general Yang Hu of the Western Jin Dynasty. When Yang Hu was guarding Xiangyang, he often went to Xian Mountain with his friends to drink wine and write poems. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This is a touching and sentimental piece. Xian Mountain is a famous scenic spot in Xiangyang. Meng Haoran paid tribute to the past and the present here, and expressed his gratitude for his life experience. He once again expressed the ancient theme of feeling sad about the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first couplet &quot;People change, and exchanges become ancient and modern&quot; is an ordinary truth. From the change of dynasties to the rise and fall of a family, as well as people&#39;s birth, old age, illness and death, joys and sorrows, human affairs are always changing, and no one has not felt it. Human society is always developing and changing. The waves behind the Yangtze River push the waves ahead, and a new generation replaces the old. This is an irreversible law of nature. Everything in the past is gone, and everything today will soon become the past. From ancient times to the present, year after year, day after day, cold comes and summer comes, spring goes and autumn comes, time is passing ruthlessly forever. The two sentences in the first couplet were written out of thin air, seemingly without a title, but they reveal the poet&#39;s confusion and infinite melancholy, and are full of a deep sense of vicissitudes of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The chin couplet closely follows the first couplet. &quot;The scenic spots left in the country&quot; are inherited from the &quot;ancient&quot;, and &quot;I will come again&quot; are inherited from the &quot;present&quot;. &quot;Significant sites&quot; refer to the Yanggong Monument on the mountain and Yuliangzhou at the foot of the mountain. The author&#39;s sad mood comes from today&#39;s arrival. When you climb Xian Mountain, the first thing you see is the Yanghu Temple and the Monument of Tears. Yang Hu had great political achievements in guarding Xiangyang and won the hearts of the people. After his death, the people of Xiangyang missed him and erected a temple and a monument in Xian Mountain. &quot;Everyone who looks at his monument sheds tears. Du Yu named it the &#39;tears of tears&#39; monument.&quot; Looking at the monument, I was filled with emotion, thinking of the legacy of my predecessors and my own obscurity, which made me feel sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The neck couplet writes about what you see while climbing. Looking from a distance when climbing the mountain, you can see the water is falling, the vegetation is withering, and it is a depressing scene. The author captured the unique scenery of the place at that time and extracted it, which can not only show that the time sequence is severe winter, but also heighten the sadness of the author&#39;s mood. &quot;Shallow&quot; refers to water. Due to the &quot;water falling&quot;, more of Yuliang Island is exposed to the water, so it is called &quot;shallow&quot;. When you see Yuliangzhou, you will naturally think of the hermit Gao Xian Pang Degong who was friends with Sima Hui and Zhuge Liang and refused Liu Biao&#39;s invitations several times. &quot;Deep&quot; refers to the farther distance, the endless, vast and far-reaching Yunmengze unfolds before our eyes. The weather is cold, the water is clear, and the air-conditioning is eerie, which makes the lake even more &quot;deep&quot;. In ancient times, &quot;Yunmeng&quot; was collectively called &quot;Yunze&quot; in the south and north of the Yangtze River in Hubei Province. The south of the Yangtze River was called &quot;Mengze&quot; and the north of the Yangtze River was called &quot;Yunze&quot;. Later, most of it was silted up and became land. Today, dozens of lakes such as Honghu Lake and Liangzi Lake are all Yunmeng Ruins. Mengze cannot be seen in Xianshan, but it is used to refer to general lakes and swamps. These two lines of poetry describe a depressed and desolate mood, used to set off the context. When the poet climbed up to Xian Mountain, he could not help but feel the withering of late autumn, which made him lament that &quot;how much life is there&quot; and &quot;the past days have been so bitter&quot;. Another year has passed in the blink of an eye, and he has no talent but nowhere to display it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last couplet, &quot;The Yanggong Monument is still there&quot;, the word &quot;Shang&quot; is very powerful, and it contains complex content. Yang Hu was guarding Xiangyang in the early Jin Dynasty, but Meng Haoran wrote this poem in the prosperous Tang Dynasty. There were more than four hundred years between them. The change of dynasties and the changes in personnel were so huge! However, the Yanggong Monument still stands on Xianshou Mountain, which is admirable. At the same time, it also contains the author&#39;s sad emotions. More than 400 years ago, Yang Hu served the country (referring to the Jin Dynasty) and did some good things for the people, so his reputation will last forever and be passed down from generation to generation. Thinking that he is still a &quot;commoner&quot; and has done nothing, he will inevitably be lost after his death. It is said that the contrast between this and the &quot;still existing&quot; Yanggong Monument is sad, so it is inevitable that I will &quot;cry after reading it&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem was written because the author was depressed when he was seeking an official position. The poet climbed to Xian Mountain, paid homage to the Yanggong Monument, missed the past and regretted the present, and expressed his emotions. Thinking that he had no ambition, he felt extremely sad and wet with tears. Placket. The whole poem draws on ancient times to express feelings, integrating scene description, lyricism and reasoning. The feelings are sincere and deep, and the profoundness is seen in the plain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two couplets of the poem have a certain philosophical nature, and the first four sentences of the poem summarize Yang Hu&#39;s words. &quot;Personnel affairs&quot;, characters and their deeds, are subject to metabolism. One generation passed away, and another generation took over. This became ancient and modern. The landscape is still a scenic spot today, but it is our generation’s turn to visit it. The last two couplets not only describe the scenery, are rich in images, but also are full of the author&#39;s passion, making it a poem of a poet rather than a poem of a philosopher. &quot;Annihilation into obscurity&quot; is a true portrayal of the poet&#39;s own experience. The scene evoked emotion, made him feel sad, and made him shed tears. Thinking that I have no ambition, I feel extremely sad and my clothes are wet with tears. The whole poem feels the shortness of life and expresses the sadness of unrecognized talents. At the same time, the language is easy to understand, the emotions are sincere and touching, and he is known for being plain and profound. Shen Deqian of the Qing Dynasty commented on Meng Haoran&#39;s poems: &quot;I got it from quiet enlightenment. The words are light but the taste is not thin.&quot; This poem does have such interest. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was written while the poet was studying in seclusion in his hometown and writing poems for his own entertainment. The specific time is unknown. The poet and a few friends went up to Xian Mountain to play. They paid homage to the Yanggong Monument and remembered what Yang Hu said: &quot;Since the universe has existed, there has been this mountain. Since then, sages and victors have climbed here and looked into the distance, just like me and you, everything is annihilated.&quot; The words &quot;hearing makes people sad&quot; are consistent with the poet&#39;s situation. Therefore, I wrote this poem to express my feelings through ancient times. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/menghaoran.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Meng Haoran (689-740), courtesy name Haoran, nicknamed Mengshan, was a native of Xiangyang, Xiangzhou (now Xiangyang, Hubei Province). He was a famous landscape pastoral poet in the Tang Dynasty and was known as &quot;Meng Xiangyang&quot; in the world. Because he had never been an official, he was also called &quot;Mengshan Man&quot;. Meng Haoran was born in the prosperous Tang Dynasty. In his early years, he had ambitions to serve the world. After being difficult and painfully disappointed in his official career, he was still able to respect himself, did not flatter the world, and practiced Taoism and lived in seclusion for the rest of his life. He once lived in seclusion in Lumen Mountain. When he was 40 years old, he traveled to Chang&#39;an and failed to win the imperial examination. He once wrote poems in Taixue, and became famous among the officials. He was so impressed that he wrote for him. In the twenty-fifth year of Kaiyuan (737), Zhang Jiuling attracted the shogunate and lived in seclusion. Most of Meng&#39;s poems are five-character short stories, mostly describing landscapes, pastoral scenes, the joy of living in seclusion, and the mood of traveling and traveling. Although there are some cynical words in it, it is more of the poet&#39;s self-expression. Meng Haoran&#39;s poems have unique artistic attainments. Later generations called Meng Haoran and Wang Wei, another landscape poet in the prosperous Tang Dynasty, &quot;Wang Meng&quot;. There are three volumes of &quot;Meng Haoran Collection&quot; handed down to the world. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 05:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雨霖铃·寒蝉凄切 | 柳永]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310242]]><description> &lt;h2>;Rain Lin Ling·The chilling cicadas are mournful&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Liu Yong&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The chilling cicadas are mournful. It is late to the pavilion and the showers have begun to subside. There is no trace of drinking in the tent of the capital, and the place of nostalgia is the orchid boat. Doubted see tears in their eyes, even Yuning choke. The thought goes away, thousands of miles of smoke waves, the dusk is heavy and the sky is vast. &lt;br />;Sentimental sentiments have hurt parting since ancient times, and it is even more embarrassing to be left out of the Qingqiu Festival! Where did you wake up tonight? On the bank of willows, the dawn wind wanes and the moon falls. After so many years, it should be a good time and good scenery. Even if there are thousands of customs, who can tell them? (A piece of good scenery: beautiful scenery) &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The cicada’s cry is sad and urgent. In the evening, Facing the pavilion, the shower had just stopped. We set up a tent on the outskirts of Kyoto for a farewell party, but we were not in the mood to have a drink. When we were reluctant to leave, the people on the boat were already urging us to set off. Holding each other&#39;s hand and looking at each other with tears in their eyes, they were choked and speechless. Thinking of the long journey, thousands of miles of mist, the evening clouds and mist shrouded the sky, deep and vast, with no end in sight. &lt;br />;Since ancient times, passionate people have always been sad about parting, let alone in this deserted and desolate autumn! Who knows where I will be when I wake up tonight? I am afraid that only the bank of willows will face the shrill morning wind and the waning moon at dawn. It&#39;s been a long time since we&#39;ve been together, and I expected that even if we encountered good weather and beautiful scenery, it would be nothing. Even if you are full of affection, who will you tell it to? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>; Chang Pavilion: In ancient times, a long pavilion was built every ten miles along the traffic thoroughfare for pedestrians to rest, also known as the &quot;Ten Mile Long Pavilion&quot;. The long pavilion near the city was often the place where ancient people bid farewell. &lt;br />;Bleak: desolate and urgent. &lt;br />;Showers: heavy showers. &lt;br />;Dumen: the gate of the capital. This refers to Bianjing (now Kaifeng, Henan), the capital of the Northern Song Dynasty. &lt;br />;Tend dining: Set up a farewell party in the suburbs. &lt;br />;No emotion: no emotion. &lt;br />;Lan Zhou: According to ancient legend, Lu Ban once carved a magnolia tree into a boat (&quot;Shu Yi Ji&quot; by Liang Renfang of the Southern Dynasties). It is used here as a good name for the boat.&lt;br />;Condensation and choking: The throat is choked and the words cannot be spoken. &lt;br />;Go to go: Repeat the word &quot;go&quot; to indicate a long journey.&lt;br />;Twilight: the clouds and mists in the evening.&lt;br />;Shen Shen: a deep look.&lt;br />;Chutian: the sky in the south of Chu. .&lt;br />;The dusk is heavy and the sky is wide: the evening clouds and mist cover the southern sky, deep and vast, with no end.&lt;br />;Tonight: Tonight.&lt;br />;Years: year after year.&lt;br />;Vertical: Even. Style: affection. The love between men and women, deep affection. Love: one means &quot;flow&quot;.&lt;br />;Update: one means &quot;waiting&quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; is Liu Yong&#39;s famous masterpiece. This poem was written when the poet was frustrated in his official career and had to leave Kyoto (Bianjing, today&#39;s Kaifeng, Henan). It expresses the feeling of wandering in the rivers and lakes. A representative piece. This poem describes the emotions of separation and reaches the artistic realm of blending scenes. The main content of the poem is to use the desolate and desolate autumn scenery as a backdrop to express the inseparable feelings of separation from the lover. The frustration in the career and the separation from the lover. , the two kinds of pain are intertwined, making the poet feel the bleakness and uncertainty of the future even more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem is divided into two parts, the upper part and the lower part.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The upper part mainly writes about the difficulty of a pair of lovers farewell. The farewell that is hard to leave.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The three sentences at the beginning, &quot;The cicadas are miserable. It&#39;s late in the pavilion, and the showers are beginning to stop.&quot; The three sentences describe the environment, pointing out that the season of farewell is the bleak and cold autumn, and the location is Bianjing City. The specific time of the long pavilion outside is the cold dusk after the rain. However, the poet did not describe the natural scenery purely objectively, but through the description of the scenery and the rendering of the atmosphere, he integrated the emotions into the scenery and implicitly conveyed different meanings. It was autumn, The scene is already desolate; it is getting late, and the twilight is gloomy; and after the torrential rain, there are chilling cicadas: everything the poet sees and hears is desolate. In addition to the sentence &quot;to the Changting night&quot;, the syntactic structure is: 2. 1. The result of swallowing with great frustration more accurately conveys the feeling of this desolate situation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the last two sentences, &quot;drinking in the capital tent&quot; refers to the scene of parting. A banquet was held outside the gate of the capital. &quot;Drinking&quot; implies being frustrated in career and breaking up with your lover. &quot;Wuxu&quot; means that you can&#39;t figure out the clues, which means &quot;continuous cutting, making things messy&quot;. It expresses the thoughts that can&#39;t bear to leave but have to do something else. &quot; &quot;The place of nostalgia, the orchid boat urges the hair&quot;. When it is difficult to separate and leave, the boatman &quot;urges the hair&quot; again and again. It reveals the ruthlessness of reality and the inner pain of the poet.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Looking at each other with tears in each other&#39;s hands. , was speechless and choked.&quot; It was a scene that had to be changed. A pair of lovers held hands tightly, facing each other with tears in their eyes, neither of them could say a word. These two sentences express each other&#39;s grief, attachment and helplessness. It is vivid and vivid. The heartbroken and dejected couple are vividly shown on the paper. This is the line drawing technique, which is called &quot;the words are not surprising, but the meaning is dense&quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Thousands of miles of mist, mist and mist.&quot; The deep and clear sky is vast.&quot; Write the anticipation of missing me after farewell. The gloomy mood of the protagonist in the poem casts a shadow on the color of the sky and water. The word &quot;read&quot; tells the reader that the scenery written below is imaginary. &quot;Go away&quot; means going further and further away. These two words are used very well. You don’t want to go but you have to go, which contains the infinite sadness of leaving someone. As long as the orchid boat sets sail, it will go farther and farther, and the dusk will be deep and the smoke will be thousands of miles along the way, and finally it will drift to the vast and boundless south. The sorrow of separation is deep and the pain of hatred is beyond words. Judging from the structure of the words, these two sentences shift from the actual writing in the upper column to the virtual writing in the lower column, which serves as a link between the previous and the following. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next section rewrites the imaginary sad scene after farewell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the next part, I will start with a general discussion, from the specific to the general, and draw a philosophy of life: &quot;Sentiment has hurt parting since ancient times.&quot; It means to be sad and farewell, which is not the beginning of ourselves, but has been the case since ancient times. The word &quot;since ancient times&quot; starts from individual special phenomena and is promoted to a universal and extensive phenomenon, which expands the meaning of the word. But the next sentence &quot;It&#39;s even more embarrassing to neglect the Qingqiu Festival&quot; emphasizes that he has endured more pain than ordinary people and ancient people. Jiang Yan said in &quot;Farewell&quot;: &quot;The one who is in ecstasy can only say goodbye!&quot; The author melted the ancient people&#39;s feelings into his own words, and added layers of layers to create new ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Where can I wake up from alcohol tonight? The dawn wind is waning on the willow bank and the moon is waning.&quot; This is a description of his state of mind after waking up from alcohol, and also his feelings of wandering in the rivers and lakes. The beauty of these two sentences is that they use scenery to express feelings, truly realizing that &quot;the language of scenery is the language of love&quot;. &quot;Liu&quot; and &quot;Liu&quot; are homophonic, describing the hard-to-stay separation; the cold dawn wind describes the chill after farewell; the waning moon is broken, describing the difficulty of reconciliation in the future. These few sceneries express the desolate, lonely and sad feelings of separation very fully and truly, creating a unique artistic conception. No wonder it is praised by people and has become a famous saying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Let’s think about the long term from now on: &quot;After all these years, good times and good times should be in vain. Even if there are thousands of customs, who should I tell them?&quot; These four sentences further infer that after parting, there will be no joy. situation. How can I survive the long days of loneliness that follow? Even if you have good times and beautiful scenery, it is in vain because you no longer have a loved one to enjoy it with. If you take a step back, even if you can have some feelings about the beautiful scenery, who can you tell it to? In short, everything is not exciting anymore. These few sentences depict the poet&#39;s longing and sadness to the utmost detail, and also convey the feelings of mutual concern. The conclusion is in the form of a question, making the emotion appear stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem of &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; is conceived around the &quot;hurt of parting&quot;. The first part is written before parting, focusing on outlining the environment; the second part is written on the moment of parting, focusing on describing the mood; the third part is written on imagination after parting, and on the depiction. psychology. No matter outlining the environment, describing the mood, or imagining the future, the poet pays attention to the coordination between the front and the back, the complementation of the virtual and the real, and goes deep into the layers, depicting to his heart&#39;s content, and blending the scenes. It reads like flowing clouds, with no trace left in the ups and downs. The mood of this poem is too sad and too low because of the true feelings, but it vividly depicts the poet&#39;s depressed mood and the pain of losing love. People who have suffered from the pain of separation throughout the ages will have a strong resonance when reading this song &quot;Yulin Bell&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Because Liu Yong&#39;s lyrics were disobedient to Zhenzong and failed in many attempts, he felt frustrated and angry. He often visited Qinlou and Chuguan as a singer. Ji wrote the lyrics for the music. This poem should be Liu Yong&#39;s farewell to a lover when he went south from Bianjing. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation Four&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Ci is a special style of poetry in the history of literature. It originated from the ancient Yuefu and emerged in the Tang Dynasty. After the development of the late Tang and Five Dynasties, It developed and became extremely prosperous by the Song Dynasty. &quot;Song Ci&quot; has become a special term in the history of Chinese literature. The Song Dynasty not only had many lyricists, but also had diverse styles. The original style of poetry is mainly graceful, but it was not until Su Shi in the Northern Song Dynasty that he started to create a bold style. Liu Yong is a representative poet of the graceful style of poetry in the Song Dynasty. He inherited and developed the graceful style of poetry that highlights the love between men and women and the sorrow of separation, the &quot;Yan Ke&quot; with red and green leaves, and the charming and gentle &quot;love language&quot;, which became The theme of Liu Ci. &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; is the masterpiece that best embodies this style among Liu Ci. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; was written by the author when he left Bianjing (then the capital of the Northern Song Dynasty) and said goodbye to his lover. From the description in the previous film, readers can imagine this: On a late autumn evening, on the outskirts of Bianliang, the capital of the Northern Song Dynasty (now Kaifeng, Henan), in a temporary tent, a man and a woman were drinking and saying goodbye. Outside the tent, the cicadas were wailing miserably, as if they were crying for their farewell. The long pavilion not far away was already faintly visible, and it could be seen that it was getting late and a heavy rain had just stopped. It was getting late and the rain had stopped. From time to time, the boatman&#39;s voice came from the riverside: &quot;Get on the boat quickly, it&#39;s about to sail!&quot; The two had no choice but to stand up slowly and move out of the tent. At this moment, they were so attached to each other. We really want to break up. You see them hugging each other, looking at each other with tears in their eyes, but they can&#39;t say a word. The ship sailed and the people left, drifting away. The lover stood on the shore, with tears in his eyes and his hands raised, watching the orchid boat disappear into the boundless dusk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is the scene where Liu Yong, a poet in the Northern Song Dynasty, said goodbye to his lover that happened nearly a thousand years ago. This is also the content of the first film of &quot;Yulinling&quot;. The first sentence &quot;cicadas are sad and sad&quot; points out the season - late autumn, &quot;cicadas&quot; are &quot;cold&quot;, and their chirping sounds are &quot;sad and sad&quot;, which exaggerates the sad environment and atmosphere, sets the tone for the farewell chapter that follows, and also sets the emotional tone for the full text. &quot;Towards Changting at night&quot; tells the time and place, and &quot;showers&quot; describes the weather. It&#39;s raining and it&#39;s just the right time to stay; it&#39;s getting late and the stay time is limited. How they hope it won&#39;t stop raining and it&#39;s not too late! &quot;Drinking in the capital tent&quot; can be seen as writing about events in Kyoto and expressing the feelings of separation. There is a table of good wine and good food, but the two are sad to say goodbye, and full of separation sorrow, where can I think about it. In fact, if the food is not delicious and the drink is not smooth, it is called &quot;no emotion&quot;. The &quot;nostalgic&quot; lover on the boat couldn&#39;t bear to say goodbye, while the boatman had to cut off their love and &quot;rush it&quot; when it was getting late. This contradiction between the subjective will and the objective situation brought the farewell to a climax. The two sentences &quot;holding hands&quot; are vivid, delicate, and extremely descriptive. It&#39;s like seeing the protagonist of Dandan on the stage, hugging his hands, shrugging his shoulders, complaining of being speechless, crying silently, more deeply sad than a thousand words, howling loudly. On the surface, it describes the circumstances of their breakup, but in reality, it describes their extremely complex and subtle inner activities. There are thousands of tender feelings and sweet feelings, only in the twinkling of tears. The two sentences &quot;think about it&quot; connect the near and distant views, and blend the virtual and real scenes. The smoke is thousands of miles away, the Chutian is vast, and the end of the world is vast. Where is the return journey? How much are the emotions of separation and farewell? The wind blows and the waves melt into the dusk. This not only expresses the feeling of loneliness and emptiness after farewell, but also hints at the author&#39;s confused future after political failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second part of the poem &quot;Yu&quot; mainly describes the pain after farewell. Sad parting has been a thing since ancient times, but it should never be done in this cold autumn season. How can people bear this? The second sentence echoes the first sentence, &quot;Qingqiu&quot; corresponds to &quot;chilling cicada&quot;, which highlights that my feelings of separation are deeper than those of the ancients, and the meaning is new and unconventional. The two sentences &quot;Tonight&quot; are famous sentences that have been passed down through the ages. &quot;Sobering Up&quot; is directly connected to &quot;Drinking in the Tent&quot; from the previous film. It can be seen that although the mood was &quot;emotionless&quot; at that time, he drank to drown his sorrows and still became intoxicated. Bianzhou was at night, drunk and confused, and suddenly woke up, it must have been dawn. Startled and busy searching, where is my lover? All that can be seen is the dawn wind and the waning moon on the willow bank. The morning breeze of Qingqiu is cool, and the word &quot;moon&quot; is preceded by the word &quot;燧&quot;, which indicates that the state of mind is completely gone. It also brings out the desolate, desolate and desolate state of mind of the poet at that time. The sadness of separation at this moment is like a storm and can&#39;t be stopped. It is really &quot;the sorrow of separation surges to the bank of willows, and the wind of farewell reaches the edge of the waning moon.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The following four sentences of &quot;It&#39;s been a long time since we left&quot; are fictitious words to imagine the scene after farewell. The author thought of &quot;tonight&quot;, &quot;thousands of miles of smoke&quot;, &quot;thousands of customs&quot;, and &quot;speechless&quot;, thought of &quot;who should I tell you more about&quot;. The author left his lover, lonely, desolate, and extremely lonely. From then on, even if there were good times and beautiful scenery, they were only in name only. However, the more good times and beautiful scenery there are, the more it makes people miss and sad. I&#39;m afraid I&#39;ll have to spend the rest of my days in &quot;deserted, desolate, miserable conditions&quot; after we say goodbye. In the last two sentences, one &quot;will&quot; and the other &quot;gentle&quot; express the sincere thoughts and deep love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The poem &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; mainly uses the desolate and desolate autumn scenery to set off the lover&#39;s difficult separation. It can be seen that the author was frustrated in his official career and had to leave Beijing for a long trip. This kind of depression The mood and the pain of losing the comfort of love are intertwined to form the main theme of this poem. Its success lies in the fact that it writes his true feelings, but the style is lower and the mood is too sad. In addition, in terms of expression techniques, this poem is mainly about narrative, and is good at line drawing, outlining the environment and describing the mood, vividly. When describing scenes, close and distant views are connected, and virtual and real scenes are combined; when describing emotions, they are rendered and set off, and advanced layer by layer. Feelings arise with the scenery, scenery changes with the feelings, and the scenes blend together, which is deeply touching. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 7&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; The cicadas are chilling, it is late in the pavilion, and the shower has begun to stop. There is no trace of drinking in the tent of the capital, and the boat is nostalgic for the boat. Doubted see tears in their eyes, even Yuning choke. Thoughts go thousands of miles away, the sky is vast and the mist is heavy at dusk. Since ancient times, sentimental feelings have hurt parting, and even more so, they can’t bear to be left out in the Qingqiu Festival. Where can I wake up from my drunkenness tonight? The dawn wind and the waning moon on the willow bank. After so many years, it should be a good time and good scenery. Even if there are thousands of styles, who should I tell them? &lt;p>; Liu Yong is a romantic poet, a poet in the world, and a professional poet who lives his life with words. He spent his life among musicians, singers and prostitutes, all of whom were related to the lyrics that were mainly used for singing at that time. This kind of life determined that he devoted his life to writing lyrics. Mr. Zheng Zhenduo once said that he had &quot;no writings except Ci, no hobbies except Ci, and no knowledge except Ci&quot; (&quot;History of Chinese Illustrated Literature&quot;). Although this is a bit absolute, it can indeed summarize his basic characteristics as a lyricist who focuses on the creation of lyrics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most of Liu Yong&#39;s lyrics are the product of &quot;singing lightly and singing softly&quot; in his life of &quot;leaning against the red and leaning on the green&quot;. The predecessors said that he &quot;worked in prison travel&quot; (Volume 21 of &quot;Zhizhai Shulu Jieti&quot;). This is an important aspect that makes his poems different from those of his predecessors in terms of subject matter and content. He left his hometown and wandered around the country for a long time, experiencing various hardships in life. As a result, he often had to say goodbye to the people he loved, so he made many complaints and sad words. &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; (Han Cicada&#39;s Sadness) is his masterpiece in this aspect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a farewell song. Before Liu Yong, there were many words expressing the sadness of separation. But because Liu Yong is a wanderer who has been wandering around the world for a long time and has a unique experience of life, the farewell he writes about a pair of lovers is different from the traditional farewell words in the narrow realm of red buildings, deep courtyards, spring flowers and autumn moon, and expresses A kind of scene with vast smoke and wide open sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first part of the film describes the feeling of reluctance when parting. &quot;The cicadas are mournful, it&#39;s late in the pavilion, and the shower has just stopped.&quot; These three sentences say that one evening in late autumn, the shower had just stopped, and a pair of lovers went to the pavilion to say goodbye. This not only explains the time and place, but also creates a strong and desolate atmosphere based on what is heard and seen. In my ears I heard the mournful chirping of cicadas, and in front of me was the depressing rainy dusk. The scene written here already implies the poet&#39;s feelings, and at the same time it foreshadows the summary of the next film &quot;The Cold Autumn Festival&quot;. The four words &quot;the shower has begun to subside&quot; mean that we are about to leave, which naturally leads to the following description of the contradictory and complicated emotions when parting: &quot;During the Dumen tent, there is no trace of drinking, and the orchid boat is nostalgic for the departure.&quot; &quot;Dumen. &quot;tent drinking&quot; refers to setting up a tent outside the city gate of Kyoto to set up wine to say goodbye. Judging from this sentence, this poem was probably written by the author when he left Bianjing for the south and said goodbye to his lover. I was reluctant to leave but had to separate, so I lost my mood; but at this time, Lan Zhou was ruthless and urging people to set off. &quot;Holding hands and looking into each other&#39;s tearful eyes, I was speechless and choked.&quot; These two sentences describe the scene of shaking hands and saying goodbye. They are deeply emotional and poignant. On the occasion of parting, a pair of lovers should have thousands of words to tell and advise, but holding hands, with tears in their eyes, you looked at me and I looked at you, but couldn&#39;t even say a word. Speechlessness is better than words. Precisely because the anger blocks the sound, the sadness in the heart can be seen more clearly. &quot;Think of the mist thousands of miles away, and the mist at dusk sinks deep into the vast sky.&quot; These three sentences use scenery to express feelings, embodying feelings in the scenery. The word &quot;read&quot; precedes it, indicating that the scene written below is just an imagination, not the real scene in front of you. However, the reality can be seen from the imaginary, and the inferred scenes can better express the thoughts and mood of the couple at the moment. Repeating the word &quot;go&quot; indicates a long journey. Who is the subject of the word &quot;read&quot;? There is no explanation in the word. From an emotional point of view, it should include two aspects: the traveler and the person seeing off. After parting, we will see the vast Chutian and endless mist, and pedestrians will disappear into the smoke-shrouded, vast and empty end. The parting scene in the first film has gone through a process of development over time. The scene has grown from small to large, from near to far, and the thoughts and feelings of leaving have become more and more intense, reaching a climax in the last three sentences. Bundle the upper piece and draw out the lower piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next part is about the loneliness and sadness after parting. &quot;Sentiment has hurt parting since ancient times, and it is even more worthy of neglecting the Qingqiu Festival.&quot; These three sentences extend from the personal pain of parting to the general thoughts and feelings of people leaving. They look down on the past and present, and think deeply about people in the unspeakable sadness. Universal emotional experience. However, unlike Su Shi&#39;s ultra-open attitude in his famous Mid-Autumn Festival poem, &quot;People have joys and sorrows, separation and reunion, and the moon waxes and wanes. It is impossible to complete this matter in ancient times.&quot; The poet put his personal tragic separation into the vast time and space of historical development. The more you read, the deeper you fall into the deep sentimentality, and the readers feel the weight of that heavy emotion more and more. &quot;The Qingqiu Festival is neglected&quot; echoes the above three sentences, blending the scenes and enhancing the artistic appeal. &quot;Where can I wake up tonight? The dawn wind is waning on the willow bank.&quot; These two sentences are famous sentences that have been recited by people and are called &quot;wonderful sayings from ancient times to modern times&quot;. The word &quot;sobering up&quot; echoes the previous film&#39;s &quot;Drinking in the Dumen tent without a trace&quot;, making people naturally connect the scene after sobering up with the previous scene of farewell. The beauty is that the poet does not write about emotion but about scenery, embodying emotion in the scenery. He did not directly talk about how lonely he felt after he sobered up. He just named three objects he saw and felt in the drifting boat: the willows on the shore, the cold wind at dawn, the waning moon in the sky, and the sadness and sadness in his heart. His feelings were fully expressed. &quot;After so many years, it should be a mere waste of good times and good scenery.&quot; These two sentences are further pushed away. The more I think about them, the farther away they become, and the farther away they become, the sadder they become. .I have been separated from my beloved for a long time. No matter how good the time is or how beautiful the scenery is, I have no time to appreciate it. &quot;Even if there are thousands of customs, who can I tell them to?&quot; These two sentences echo the two sentences &quot;Holding hands and looking at each other&quot; in the previous film. When parting, there are thousands of words that cannot be said, and after parting, there are thousands of winds and no one can say them. This is In the contrast between the present and the future, reality and speculation, the sincere and deep love and the miserable lovesickness are more fully expressed, and the whole poem is concluded at the climax of emotional development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem uses the autumn scenery to describe the separation, and the scenes blend together; in terms of expression, it is based on the development of time, the virtual and the real, layer by layer, and is completed in one go; the language is natural and clear, not carving, and wins by white description. It indeed expresses the style characteristics of &quot;clearness and clarity&quot;, &quot;intense meaning&quot; (Huang Liaoyuan&#39;s language) and &quot;elegant and quiet&quot; (Zhou Ji&#39;s language). &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; In the dazzling world of Ci poetry in the Northern Song Dynasty, Liu Yong is one of the dazzling stars. Ye Mengde of the Southern Song Dynasty recorded in &quot;Records of Summer Vacation&quot; that &quot;anywhere with well water to drink can sing willow lyrics&quot; as proof. Among the countless Liu Ci poems, &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; is one of the most widely circulated masterpieces. Later generations have a joke that &quot;the willow tree changes in the morning wind and the waning moon, and the left side is softened by dripping powder and kneading it.&quot; Liu Yong went to Bianjing to take the exam when he was young. Because he was good at lyrics and music, he got to know many singing girls and wrote lyrics and composed music for them, showing a prodigal style. At that time, someone recommended him in front of Renzong, but Renzong only approved four words: &quot;Let&#39;s go and write lyrics.&quot; After being hit, Liu Yong had no way out, so he had to jokingly call himself &quot;Liu Sanbian who wrote lyrics on orders&quot; and lived a wandering life in Bianjing, Suzhou, Hangzhou and other cities. Due to frustration and boredom, he wandered around the music industry. Encouraged by musicians and singers, this lyricist who was proficient in music created a large number of new Yuefu (slow lyrics) suitable for singing, which were welcomed by the general public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since ancient times, there have been endless poems, lyrics, and songs that express the feelings of separation between men and women, but Liu Yong’s unique slow poem &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; has endured for a long time and has been recited to this day. This is indeed worthy of study. Looking into the reasons, although it is closely related to the author&#39;s bumpy life experience, the success of &quot;Yulinling&quot; also lies in its unique expression techniques: clear layers, clear semantics, describing the scenery, pouring out feelings, rarely concealing; good at using &quot;Spot dyeing&quot; method, apply repeatedly to render the effect. The following is a brief analysis of &quot;Yulin Ling&quot;: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem about separation can be said to be vivid and complete. The whole word is conceived around &quot;hurt parting&quot;, the level is particularly clear, and the language is concise and clear. The first thing to write before parting is to outline the environment; the second time to write about parting is to describe the mood; the second part to write about the imagination after parting is to focus on describing the psychology. Three levels, each in-depth, and the emotions of separation are written from different levels, which is breathtaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first three sentences of the word indicate the time, place, and scenery. The purpose is to say goodbye to the one you love. In the evening, when the showers stopped, the cicadas made a mournful cry and bid farewell to each other in a long pavilion. How can one endure the pain of parting! The chirping of the cicadas adds to the sadness, and the word &quot;sad&quot; at the beginning sets the tone for this poem. This level unfolds a desolate atmosphere. The two sentences &quot;Dumen&quot; express the mood of farewell in a euphemistic and tortuous way. When the two were in love and couldn&#39;t separate, the passenger ship kept urging them. Psychological ambivalence, desire to drink but no emotion, desire to stay but no desire to stay. From this we can see the depth of nostalgia. The two sentences &quot;holding hands&quot; are further smeared, and the words &quot;holding hands&quot;, &quot;looking at each other&quot; and &quot;speechless&quot; make people even more sad and dejected. This layer expresses the feeling of nostalgia. The above two levels are full of loops, frustrations, and hesitations, which are enough to make people whimper. After &quot;Thinking of it&quot;, it becomes full of energy and flows thousands of miles, like a river flowing out of a gorge, running straight towards Pingchuan, and the words express one&#39;s heart directly. Starting with the leading word &quot;Nian&quot; indicates that the road after farewell is far away, &quot;thousands of miles of smoke, the heavy dusk, and the vast sky.&quot; The vast smoke, the heavy dusk, and the vast sky are all descriptions of scenery. In fact, the whole poem is full of scenery. It contains love, which reflects that the traveler has a bright future, lovers can never meet each other, the scenery is boundless and the love is infinite. The change of head begins with love, sighing that parting has been sad since ancient times. &quot;Sad parting&quot; points out the purpose of this poem. The sentence &quot;It&#39;s even more shameful to neglect the Qingqiu Festival&quot; will be pushed to another level, not to mention that the Qingqiu Festival is being neglected. How unbearable this is! This is a combination of &quot;Farewell&quot; in Jiang Yan&#39;s &quot;Farewell&quot; and Song Yu&#39;s sad autumn sentiments, and refined these two sentences. Melt the feelings of the ancients into your own words and sentences, and give them new meaning. The two sentences &quot;Tonight&quot; further infer the desolation after farewell, but the scenery is clear and clear, just like what the other party saw in the boat after waking up from drunkenness. The beauty of this sentence is that there is emotion in the scene. &quot;I have passed away in the past, and the willows are still there.&quot; (&quot;The Book of Songs: Plucking Wei&quot;) is also a farewell poem. As soon as the departing person sees the willow, he will remember the scene of reluctant parting when parting, and the scene of giving the willow to farewell will emerge, and wisps of separation sadness will surge in his heart. The three characters &quot;Yangliu Bank&quot; expressly describe the foreground and implicitly describe the feelings of farewell, which is implicit and lingering. It&#39;s almost like being in the scene and forgetting what you imagined. The two sentences &quot;I&#39;m leaving here&quot;, and then thinking about the long-term loneliness after farewell, wasting the beautiful years. The two sentences &quot;even if there is&quot;, and then deepening from the experience of the previous two sentences, sighing that it will be difficult to see the future, and the style has no one to tell, artistically pushing the feeling of parting to a climax. The third level above is really &quot;endless hatred and endless aftertaste&quot; (Tang Guizhang&#39;s &quot;A Brief Explanation of Tang and Song Ci&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem describes farewell, farewell, and various thoughts after farewell. It uses line drawing to describe the scenery and express feelings. It has clear layers and clear meaning, and rarely conceals any falsehoods. In particular, the description of the scene after the farewell is more real than reality, and the scenery is used to make people not feel that it is fiction, which shows the superbness of Liu Yong&#39;s artistic techniques. Therefore, some people call it &quot;subtle and thought-provoking, and there is emotion in the scenery...&#39;The dawn wind and the waning moon on the bank of the willows&#39; are so popular.&quot; (Xie Zhangcheng&#39;s &quot;Words on Gambling Villa&quot;) Some people think that &quot;&#39;Thousands of Miles of Smoke&#39; is a farewell The love has flown; &quot;Thousands of customs&quot;, and the long-awaited wishes are on credit. It is really called a person who is good at conveying the spirit.&quot; (Li Panlong&#39;s &quot;Cottage Poetry Yu Jun&quot;) This all shows the beauty of this poem. But Liu Xizai&#39;s theory of &quot;dian dye&quot; in &quot;Yi Gui&quot; is even more worthy of praise. He believes that the poems are a little tainted. The three sentences &quot;read and go&quot; in Qi Qing&#39;s &quot;Yulin Ling&quot; point out the desolation of farewell; the two sentences &quot;tonight&quot; are tainted by the previous three sentences. There must be no other words between the points, otherwise the aphorism will become ashes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  刘熙载的这段评论，实际上是以画法论词，看出在柳词中的加深描绘，反复涂抹的技巧。既精微入里，而又大胆泼墨。也就是柳词中抒情与写景在章法和修辞的巧妙运用，可谓词中有画。而其中抒情，尤寄寓哲理。所谓“多情自古伤离别，更那堪冷落清秋节”，清秋离别，多情那堪？感情极为沉痛，而染以“今宵酒醒何处？杨柳岸、晓风残月”，更是伤心而又凄凉，情景妙合无痕，这一别后之情景，又是加“念去去”三句之点化而得，前后照应，委婉自如。柳词在点染方面的技巧运用，确是达到很高的成就的，在这首词里最为突出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;赏析五&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;  柳永多作慢词，长于铺叙。此词表现作者离京南下时长亭送别的情景。上片纪别，从日暮雨歇，送别都门，设帐饯行，到兰舟摧发，泪眼相对，执手告别，依次层层描述离别的场面和双方惜别的情态，犹如一首带有故事性的剧曲，展示了令人伤心惨目的一幕。这与同样表现离情别绪但出之以比兴的唐五代小令是情趣不同的。北宋时柳词不但都下传唱，甚至远及西夏，“凡有井水饮处，即能歌柳词”（《避暑录话》）。柳词盛行于市井巷陌，同他这种明白晓畅、情事俱显的词风不无关系。下片述怀，承“念”字而来，设想别后情景。刘熙载《艺概》卷四：“词有点有染。柳耆卿《雨霖铃》云&#39;多情自古伤离别，更那堪冷落清秋节。今宵酒酲何处，杨柳岸、晓风残月&#39;。上二句点出离别冷落，&#39;今宵”二句，乃就上二句意染之”确实，“今宵”二句之所以被推为名句，不仅在于虚中有实，虚景实写，更因为以景“染”情、融情入景。“今宵酒醒何处”，遥接上片“帐饮”，足见虽然“无绪”却仍借酒浇愁以致沉醉；“杨柳岸、晓风残月”，则集中了一系列极易触动离愁的意象，创造出一个凄清冷落的怀人境界。“此去”以下，以情会景，放笔直写，不嫌重拙，由“今宵”想到“经年”，由“千里烟波”想到“千种风情”，由“无语凝噎”想到“更与何人说”，回环往复又一气贯注地抒写了“相见时难别亦难”的不尽愁思。宋人论词往往有雅俗之辨，柳词一向被判为“俗曲”。此词上片中的“执手相看泪眼”等语，确实浅近俚俗，近于秦楼楚馆之曲。但下片虚实相间，情景相生，足以与其他著名的“雅词”相比，因此堪称俗不伤雅，雅而不俗。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;赏析六&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;  此词当为词人从汴京南下时与一位恋人的惜别之作。柳永因作词忤仁宗，遂“失意无俚，流连坊曲”，为歌伶乐伎撰写曲子词。由于得到艺人们的密切合作，他能变旧声为新声，在唐五代小令的基础上，创制了大量的慢词，使宋词开始了一个新的发展阶段。这首词调名《雨霖铃》，盖取唐时旧曲翻制。据《明皇杂录》云，安史之乱时，唐玄宗避地蜀中，于栈道雨中闻铃音，起悼念杨贵妃之思，“采其声为《雨霖铃》曲，以寄恨焉”。王灼《碧鸡漫志》卷五云：“今双调《雨霖铃慢》，颇极哀怨，真本曲遗声。 ”在词史上，双调慢词《雨霖铃》最早的作品，当推此首。柳永充分利用这一词调声情哀怨、篇幅较长的特点，写委婉凄侧的离情，可谓尽情尽致，读之令人於悒。 &lt;p>;  词的上片写一对恋人饯行时难分难舍的别情。起首三句写别时之景，点明了地点和节序。《礼记·月令》云：“孟秋之月，寒蝉鸣。 ”可见时间大约在农历七月。然而词人并没有纯客观地铺叙自然景物，而是通过景物的描写，氛围的渲染，融情入景，暗寓别意。时当秋季，景已萧瑟；且值天晚，暮色阴沉；而骤雨滂沱之后，继之以寒蝉凄切：词人所见所闻，无处不凄凉。加之当中“对长亭晚”一句，句法结构是一、二、一，极顿挫吞咽之致，更准确地传达了这种凄凉况味。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  前三句通过景色的铺写，也为后两句的“无绪”和“催发”设下伏笔。“都门帐饮”，语本江淹《别赋》：“帐饮东都，送客金谷。 ”他的恋人在都门外长亭摆下酒筵给他送别，然而面对美酒佳肴，词人毫无兴致。可见他的思绪正专注于恋人，所以词中接下去说：“留恋处、兰舟催发”。这七个字完全是写实，然却以精炼之笔刻画了典型环境与典型心理：一边是留恋情浓，一边是兰舟催发，这样的矛盾冲突何其尖锐！林逋《相思令》云：“君泪盈，妾泪盈，罗带同心结未成，江头潮欲平。 ”仅是暗示船将启碇，情人难舍。刘克庄《长相思》云：“烟迢迢，水迢迢，准拟江边驻画挠，舟人频报潮。 ”虽较明显，但仍未脱出林词窠臼。可是这里的“兰舟催发”，却以直笔写离别之紧迫，虽没有他们含蕴缠绵，但却直而能纤，更能促使感情的深化。于是后面便迸出“执手相看泪眼，竟无语凝噎”二句。语言通俗而感情深挚，形象逼真，如在眼前。寥寥十一字，真是力敌千钧！后来传奇戏曲中常有“流泪眼看流泪眼，断肠人对断肠人”的唱词，然却不如柳词凝炼有力。那么词人凝噎在喉的是什么话呢？“念去去”二句便是他的内心独白。词是一种依附于音乐的抒情诗体，必须讲究每一个字的平仄阴阳，而去声字尤居关键地位。这里的去声“念”字用得特别好。清人万树《词律发凡》云：“名词转折跌荡处，多用去声，何也？三声之中，上、入二者可以作平，去则独异。 ……当用去者，非去则激不起。 ”此词以去声“念”字作为领格，上承“凝噎”而自然一转，下启“千里”以下而一气流贯。“念”字后“去去”二字连用，则愈益显示出激越的声情，读时一字一顿，遂觉去路茫茫，道里修远。“千里”以下，声调和谐，景色如绘。既日“烟波”，又日“暮霭”，更曰“沉沉”，着色可谓浓矣；既曰“千里”，又曰“阔”，空间可谓广矣。在如此广阔辽远的空间里，充满了如此浓密深沉的烟霭，其离愁之深，令人可以想见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  上片正面话别，到此结束；下片则宕开一笔，先作泛论，从个别说到一般，得出一条人生哲理：“多情自古伤离别”。意谓伤离惜别，并不自我始，自古皆然。接以“更那堪冷落清秋节”一句，则为层层加码，极言时当冷落凄凉的秋季，离情更甚于常时。“清秋节”一辞，映射起首三句，前后照应，针线极为绵密；而冠以“更那堪”三个虚字，则加强了感情色彩，比起首三句的以景寓情更为明显、深刻。“今宵”三句蝉联上句而来，是全篇之警策，后来竟成为苏轼相与争胜的对象。据俞文豹《吹剑录》云：“东坡在玉堂日，有幕士善歌，因问：&#39;我词何如柳七？ &#39;对日：&#39;柳郎中词，只合十七八女郎，执红牙板，歌“杨柳岸晓风残月”。学士词，须关西大汉，（执）铜琵琶，铁绰板，唱“大江东去”。 &#39;”这三句本是想象今宵旅途中的况味：一舟临岸，词人酒醒梦回，只见习习晓风吹拂萧萧疏柳，一弯残月高挂杨柳梢头。整个画面充满了凄清的气氛，客情之冷落，风景之清幽，离愁之绵邈，完全凝聚在这画面之中。比之上片结尾二句，虽同样是写景，写离愁，但前者仿佛是泼墨山水，一片苍茫；这里却似工笔小帧，无比清丽。词人描绘这清丽小帧，主要采用了画家所常用的点染笔法。清人刘熙载在《艺概》中说：“&#39;多情自古伤离别，更那堪冷落清秋节。今宵酒醒何处？杨柳岸、晓风残月。 &#39;上二句点出离别冷落，&#39;今宵&#39;二句乃就上二句意染之。点染之间，不得有他语相隔，隔则警句亦成死灰矣。 ”也就是说，这四句密不可分，相互烘托，相互陪衬，中间若插上另外一句，就破坏了意境的完整性，形象的统一性，而后面这两个警句，就将失去光彩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  “此去经年”四句，构成另一种情境。因为上面是用景语，此处则改用情语。他们相聚之日，每逢良辰好景，总感到欢娱；可是别后非止一日，年复一年，纵有良辰好景，也引不起欣赏的兴致，只能徒增帐触而已。“此去”二字，遥应上片“念去去”；“经年”二字，近应“今宵”，在时间与思绪上均是环环相扣，步步推进，可见结构之严密。“便纵有千种风情，更与何人说”，益见钟情之殷，离愁之深。而归纳全词，犹如奔马收缰，有住而不住之势；又如众流归海，有尽而未尽之致。其以问句作结，更留有无穷意味，耐人寻绎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  耆卿词长于铺叙，有些作品失之于平直浅俗，然而此词却能做到“曲处能直，密处能疏，鼻处能平，状难状之景，达难达之情，而出之以自然”（冯煦《六十一家词选例言》论柳永词）。像“兰舟催发”一语，可谓兀傲排鼻，但其前后两句，却于沉郁之中自饶和婉。“今宵”三句，寄情于景，可称曲笔，然其前后诸句，却似直抒胸臆。前片自第四句起，写情至为缜密，换头却用提空之笔，从远处写来，便显得疏朗清远。词人在章法上不拘一格，变化多端，因而全词起伏跌宕，声情双绘，付之歌喉，亦能奕奕动人。&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;作者简介&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/liuyong2.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;柳永，（约984年—约1053年）北宋著名词人，婉约派代表人物。汉族，崇安（今福建武夷山）人，原名三变，字景庄，后改名永，字耆卿，排行第七，又称柳七。宋真宗朝进士，官至屯田员外郎，故世称柳屯田。他自称“奉旨填词柳三变”，以毕生精力作词，并以“白衣卿相”自诩。其词多描绘城市风光和歌妓生活，尤长于抒写羁旅行役之情，创作慢词独多。铺叙刻画，情景交融，语言通俗，音律谐婉，在当时流传极其广泛，人称“凡有井水饮处，皆能歌柳词”，婉约派最具代表性的人物之一，对宋词的发展有重大影响，代表作《雨霖铃》《八声甘州》。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>