<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[杨布打狗 | 列子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310122]]><description> &lt;h2>;Yang Bu beats the dog&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Liezi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>; Yang Zhu&#39;s younger brother called Bu and came out dressed in plain clothes. When it rains, the plain clothes are undressed, and the pure clothes are reversed. The dog didn&#39;t know it and barked at him. Yang Bu was angry and would pounce on him. Yang Zhu said: &quot;You don&#39;t pounce, and you are still like this. Is it not strange that Xiang made your dog white and then came to the black?&quot; &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />; Yang Zhu’s younger brother was named Yang Bu. He went out wearing white clothes. It started to rain, so Yang Bu took off his white clothes and went home in black clothes. His dog didn&#39;t recognize Yang Bu, so he barked at him. Yang Bu was very angry and prepared to beat the dog. At this time Yang Zhu said: &quot;Don&#39;t beat the dog. If it were you, you would do the same thing. If your dog was white before leaving and turned black when it came back, how could you not Are you surprised?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Yang Zhu: a pre-Qin philosopher, a native of Wei during the Warring States Period, with the courtesy name Ziju. &lt;br />;Said: Name. &lt;br />;Clothes: to wear. &lt;br />;Plain: white. &lt;br />;Rain: Rain. &lt;br />;Yi: Top, here refers to clothes. &lt;br />;缁(zī): black. &lt;br />;Reverse: Same as &quot;hui&quot;, return, go home. &lt;br />;Zhi: Understand, know. &lt;br />;And: conjunction, indicating compliance. &lt;br />;Bark: (dog) barks. &lt;br />;Nu: angry, angry. &lt;br />;Will: plan. &lt;br />;Put: hit, knock. &lt;br />;Zi Wu pounces on it, Zi: You&lt;br />;Yue: Like this. &lt;br />;Xiang: Just now. Toward, in the past, in the past. &lt;br />;If: if, if. &lt;br />;Qi: How? &lt;br />;None: Same as &quot;Wu&quot;, no, don&#39;t. &lt;br />;Strange: Feeling strange about.... &lt;br />;Yi Suyi: wearing white clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Implication&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;1. When a friend misunderstands you, don’t get hot-headed or get angry; instead, you should put yourself in other people’s shoes and learn to empathize. , and understand others. &lt;br />;2. It is wrong to see the surface of things without seeing the essence of things with a short-term vision. &lt;br />;3. Things are ever-changing. If you want to understand things correctly, you cannot look at things with an unchanging perspective, let alone be confused by temporary superficial phenomena. You must grasp the essence of things. &lt;br />;4. Whenever you encounter right or wrong, you must first look within yourself and don’t be too busy blaming others! &lt;br />;5. When encountering other people’s unfriendly behavior, you should put yourself in their shoes and ask yourself instead of blaming others blindly. &lt;br />;6. If you change, you can&#39;t blame others for treating you differently. If others look at you differently, you must first find the reason from yourself. Otherwise, you will be like Yang Bu: his clothes have changed, but the dog doesn&#39;t recognize him. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Comments&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Yang Bu was wearing white clothes when he went out. It rained and the environmental conditions changed. He changed into black clothes. Yang Bu was still Yang. cloth. But his dog ignored these changes and barked at Yang Bu who had changed his clothes. It turned out that the dog was only loyal to Yang Bu in white clothes, but ignored Yang Bu in black clothes! Yang Bu&#39;s dog only looked at the clothes but not the person, and ended up biting the wrong person. It’s not funny for dogs to make such mistakes. When people look at problems, if they only pay attention to superficial phenomena and fail to grasp the essential characteristics, they will also make similar low-level mistakes. In real life, nothing remains unchanged. Change is relative and change is absolute. You cannot look at changed things with the old eyes. You must learn to see the essence through phenomena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Center: When others misunderstand us because of superficial phenomena, we must be sober, explain the truth, and eliminate misunderstandings. But you can&#39;t get angry like Yang Bu did, which is not conducive to solving the problem and may intensify the conflict. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Story&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; Once upon a time, in a little-known mountain village, there lived a family named Yang, who lived by planting a piece of mountain land next to the village. . This family has two sons, the eldest son is named Yang Zhu, and the younger son is named Yang Bu. The two brothers help their parents cultivate land and carry water at home, while reading poetry and books diligently. Both brothers were good calligraphers and made a lot of poetry friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day, his younger brother Yang Bu, wearing white and clean clothes, went out to visit friends happily. On the way to his friend&#39;s house, unexpectedly, it suddenly began to rain. The rain became heavier and heavier. Yang Bu was walking on a mountain trail with no village in front and no store behind him. He had no choice but to brave the heavy rain and was caught by the heavy rain. I was so drenched that I ran to my friend&#39;s house. They were good friends who often discussed poetry and reviewed calligraphy and painting together. Yang Bu took off his white coat that was soaked by the rain at his friend&#39;s house and put on his friend&#39;s black coat. A friend&#39;s house hosted Yang Bu for dinner, and the two talked about poetry for a while and commented on the calligraphy and paintings of their predecessors. The more they talked, the more they talked, and the more they played, the happier they were. Unconsciously, it was getting dark, so Yang Bu hung his white coat, which was soaked by the rain, at his friend&#39;s house to dry, and he wore his friend&#39;s black clothes and said goodbye to his friend and went home. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the mountain trail is wet after the rain, there is no accumulated mud because there are many pebbles on the road. The sky gradually darkened, but the winding mountain road was still clearly distinguishable. The evening breeze blew gently, bringing bursts of fragrance of new branches and leaves from the mountains. If it weren&#39;t for the fact that it was getting darker and darker, Yang Bu would really be in the mood of roaming the hills after the rain! He walked, walked, and reached the door of his house, still immersed in the interest of talking with friends during the day. At this time, Yang Bu&#39;s dog didn&#39;t know that its owner was back, and rushed out from the dark ground and barked at him. After a moment, the dog suddenly stood up on its hind legs and raised its front legs, as if it was about to pounce towards Yang Bu. Yang Bu was startled by his dog&#39;s sudden barking and its imminent pounce. He was very annoyed. He immediately stopped and ducked to the side, angrily yelling at the dog: &quot;You&#39;re blind!&quot; You don’t even recognize me!” So ​​he picked up a wooden stick by the door and wanted to beat the dog. At this time, his brother Yang Zhu heard the sound and immediately came out of the house. While stopping Yang Bu from beating the dog with a wooden stick, he called the barking dog and said, &quot;Don&#39;t beat it! You should think about it.&quot; , you went out in white clothes during the day, and came home so late in black clothes. If it were you, would you be able to tell clearly at once? Can you blame the dog?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Bu said nothing more and thought calmly for a while, feeling that what his brother Yang Zhu said made sense. The dog stopped barking, and the family returned to its original happiness. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/lieyukou.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Liezi (about 450 BC - 375 BC during the Warring States Period, died at the age of 75), a representative figure of Taoism in the early Warring States Period. Ming Kou, also known as Yu Kou (&quot;Liezi&quot; is the honorific title given to him by later generations), was a member of the Huaxia clan, a native of Putian, Zhengguo (now Zhengzhou City, Henan Province) in the Zhou Dynasty, and the descendant of the ancient emperor Lieshan. One of the ten great figures in the pre-Qin world, a famous Taoist scholar, thinker, philosopher, writer, and educator. It had a profound impact on later generations&#39; philosophy, aesthetics, literature, science and technology, health care, music, and religion. He is the author of Liezi, whose teachings are based on Huangdi Laozi and attributed to Laozi and Zhuangzhuang. Founded the Guixu School (Liezixue), a school of pre-Qin philosophy. He is an important inheritor of the Taoist school between Laozi and Zhuangzi. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 04:23:10 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[无闷·催雪 | 吴文英]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310111]]><description> &lt;h2>;No Boring · Pushing Snow&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Wu Wenying&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The colorful festivals fly with beautiful flowers, the luan rides on the jade, and the plain clouds and weak water disappear. Qian Haohe passed the letter, and Aunt Wei called out. Don&#39;t wait for the dawn to condense on the Fenhe River, take advantage of the night moon and the flying Yaosheng to wear it. The donkey is dancing, the stove is cold, and the door of the wine pavilion is closed. &lt;br />;Goliath. Panbis ant. Put half hooks on the embroidered curtain, and build the treasure platform next to it. I need to borrow Dongjun, the spring spirit of Baling. Xiaomeng first fascinated Chu Die, and the early wind and heavy cold invaded the quilt. I&#39;m also afraid of covering up the pear blossoms in the deep courtyard, and making people shed tears. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xu Feiqiong, the maid next to the Queen Mother of the West, is about to arrive in a car with neon banners and ceremonial guards. After Nong Yu ascends to heaven, he will also fly back on a Luan and Phoenix. Ask the calligrapher Wei Maoyi to summon Feixue, and ask the emperor to issue an edict to summon Feixue. The Snow God took advantage of the darkness of night to rain down heavy snow, and before dawn, the earth was covered in silver. I want to take advantage of the heavy snow early in the morning to ride a weak little donkey and go alone in the snow to sing &quot;Snow Song&quot; repeatedly. At this time, the teahouses and wine shops along the road were temporarily closed due to the cold weather and no one was around. &lt;br />;The door curtain in the room is half hung, and a banquet is set up on the steps. The guests are waiting for the snow to fall while the singing is clear and green tea is sipped. People half-open the embroidered curtains and approach the jade steps of the Baotai. If they can invite the Spring God, they can use his power to send away the Snow God and revive all things. The wind was blowing hard and the snow was dense. I woke up from the freezing cold and saw only a few snowflakes outside. In my confusion, I thought they were flying butterflies I saw in my dream. After getting up, I hurried to the garden to enjoy the snow. I saw that everything in the garden was white, but I was afraid that it would snow too much. The snow turned into water and sprinkled on the pear blossoms, turning into the tears of an old friend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Wumen: the name of the word brand. A &quot;snow rusher&quot;. Double tone, ninety-nine characters, the first part has ten lines with four oblique rhymes, and the second part has nine lines with six oblique rhymes. The eighth sentence in the previous film is a four-character sentence, while the word &quot;Mengchuang&quot; is a five-character sentence, so the whole word is one hundred words long, with a changed pattern. This word was created by Jiang Baishi, so Jiang Ci is the correct style. The fourth sentence of the first part and the third sentence of the second part are all four sentences. The purpose of the title &quot;to urge the snow&quot; is to make the snow fall faster, to show the thoughts and emotions of man&#39;s determination to conquer the sky. The poet is looking forward to the early arrival of &quot;Spring in Baling&quot;.&lt;br />;Ni Festival: Ni Jing, ancient times A guard of honor when the emperor travels. Feiqiong: Xu Feiqiong. The legendary maid of the Queen Mother of the West.&lt;br />;Nongyu: It is said that she was the daughter of Duke Mu of Qin in the Spring and Autumn Period. She married Xiao Shi, who was good at playing the flute, and Duke Mu built a phoenix platform to live in. Later, the couple flew to the immortals on a phoenix. See Liu Xiang&#39;s &quot;Biography of Immortals&quot;. &quot;Fei Qiong&quot; and &quot;Nong Yu&quot; both describe snow.&lt;br />;Separation: that is, the separation of weak water. Far and away Places that cannot be reached.&lt;br />;Heshu: The name of the calligraphy style. It is often used as an edict to recruit wise men, also known as the Crane Head Book.&lt;br />;Aunt Wei: a calligrapher of the Jin Dynasty, named Shuo, courtesy name Maoyi, Wei Heng ( Calligrapher) niece, wife of Ruyin prefect Li Ju. She is good at calligraphy, especially official script, and studied under Zhong Yao. Calling: refers to stirring up the ice of the jade pot.&lt;br />;Powder River Ningxia: refers to the Milky Way disappearing at dawn . Fenhe: Milky Way.&lt;br />;Huanpei: Women’s round jade pendant.&lt;br />;Jian (jiǎn) Donkey: a lame donkey. Yinying: refers to a poet who rides a donkey and sings in the wind and snow.&lt;br />;Bi Ant: that is, &quot;green ant&quot;. Ant, the foamy scum of wine, looks like an ant. Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;Ask Liu Shijiu&quot;: &quot;Green clams make new fermented wine, and a small red mud stove.&quot; &quot;&lt;br />;Dong Jun: God of Spring.&lt;br />;Baling: Emperor Wen of the Han Dynasty built and buried this place, so it was named Baling, located in the east of Chang&#39;an County. &quot;Baling breaks willows&quot;, which has been an allusion to seeing off guests since the Han and Tang Dynasties. &lt;br />;Violence: Violence.&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem is a poem about scenery. The first rhyme &quot;Nijie Feiqiong&quot; is adapted from myths and legends , a metaphor for the snow that is about to fall. The title of the poem is &quot;to urge the snow&quot;. The two sentences of &quot;Nijie&quot; use the white color of the two characters &quot;Qiong&quot; and &quot;Yu&quot; to describe snow, and &quot;Nijie&quot; and &quot;Luanjia&quot; are used to describe snow. Flying. Such a personification technique not only makes the colors simple and elegant, but also writes the snow in a beautiful and elegant mood. It creates a mythical artistic conception at the beginning of the chapter. &quot;The separation between the plain clouds and the weak water&quot; is transformed into the &quot;weak water separation&quot; It is an allusion to say that it is far away and difficult to reach. This sentence changes the pen and writes that the snow will not fall, which is the root of the word &quot;urge&quot;. The rhyme of &quot;Qian Haohe Chuan Shu&quot; has the word &quot;urge&quot; written on the front, and the poet further Expand your imagination, the idea here is unique and the wording is novel. &quot;Crane Script&quot; is an ancient calligraphy style specially used to write edicts for recruiting magi. In the ci, Bai Xue is compared to a magi, and it is conveyed in Crane Script, and in &quot;Crane Script&quot; Add the word &quot;Hao&quot; before &quot;&quot;, compare it with &quot;Snow&quot;, and change the &quot;Crane Book&quot; into a white crane. It has become a bird that can fly and pass messages. Here, inanimate objects are turned into animate objects, which seems It is more vivid and expressive. The ice in the jade pot in the poem is compared to the white snow. The word &quot;urge&quot; is written on the front of &quot;chuanshu&quot; and &quot;call out&quot;. &quot;Don&#39;t wait for the powder river to condense at dawn&quot; rhymes, &quot;Don&#39;t wait&quot; means sincerity. &quot;Yao Sheng&quot; &quot;Fei Huan Pei&quot; echoes the words &quot;Fei Qiong&quot; and &quot;Nong Yu&quot; at the beginning, still using fairies to compare snow. Imagine fairies flying into the world under the moonlit night, playing Sheng music like the sound of Huan Pei Yu ornaments. Here not only will Inanimate objects are compared to humans, and they are vivid and ethereal. The rhyme of &quot;the donkey is singing its shadow&quot; also uses allusions related to snow, giving snow its inherent elegance and white social essence. This rhyme refers to the fall of snow. The sentence &quot;Jian donkey&quot; is adapted from the story of Zheng Wei recorded in Sun Guangxian&#39;s &quot;Bei Meng Suoyan&quot;. Someone asked the Prime Minister Zheng Wei: &quot;Has the Prime Minister written any new poems recently?&quot; Said: &quot;The poem is on a donkey in the wind and snow in Baqiao. How can I get it here?&quot; &quot;Only when riding a donkey in the wind and snow can one have poetic thoughts, and when serving as an official in the court, there is a poetic feeling.&quot; The two sentences of &quot;tea smoke and stove are cold&quot; are used by Yuan An before he arrived. There was a heavy snowfall that closed the door, but the smoke was cold and the stove was cold at home. A story about lying down and defending oneself in poverty. Yang Tiefu commented on these two rhymes and said: &quot;It serves as a counter-challenge for the following text. &quot; (&quot;Explanation of Selected Notes on Mengchuang Ci&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the film, the second rhyme of &quot;Ge Li&quot; appeared. Yang Tiefu commented on this rhyme and said: &quot;It has changed to a lively state again.&quot; &quot; (&quot;Explanation of Selected Notes of Mengchuang Ci&quot;) The poet changed this lively state to contrast the tranquility and tranquility when the snow falls. The three rhymes of &quot;Putting the Embroidered Curtain Half Hook&quot; after the film all have the word &quot;urge&quot; written from the side. &quot;It is necessary to borrow Dongjun&quot; rhyme, with the word &quot;urge&quot; written on the front, it is necessary to borrow the spring breeze from the east to urge the snow. &quot;Spring breeze in Baling&quot; once again uses the phrase &quot;poems are on donkeys in the wind and snow in Baqiao&quot; by Zheng Xi. , connects snow with poetry, and paints snow with poetic color. &quot;Dawn of dawn first confuses dream of butterfly&quot; rhyme, which is adapted from Zhuangzi&#39;s dream of turning into a butterfly. When he woke up, he didn&#39;t know whether he was transformed by a butterfly or himself. The story was written in a confused dream. The wind was howling, the snow was flying, and the heavy cold air invaded the quilt tent. The snow has fallen, which completes the word &quot;urge&quot; in the title of the poem. Finally, it ends with &quot;I am still afraid of covering the pear blossoms in the deep courtyard.&quot; A rhyme is used as the postscript of the title, and the snow is changed into another artistic conception, creating a sad state of pear blossoms with rain and a beautiful woman crying. Yang Tiefu said: &quot;I also fell into a level of Dharma. ” (&quot;Explanation of Selected Notes on Mengchuang Ci&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This word is cleverly conceived, and the rhetoric is wonderful. For example, flying snow is compared to two fairies, &quot;Fei Qiong&quot; and &quot;Nong Yu&quot; arriving in a luan. , the whiteness of &quot;Qiong&quot; and &quot;Jade&quot; is more appropriate than snow, and it is compared with fairies. The image is vivid and full of ethereal and elegant beauty. When writing &quot;Jiu Xue&quot; on the front, the crane body used to write imperial edicts and the jade pot ice body of Aunt Wei are used In comparison, it is both solemn and beautiful. When it is written about waiting for snow, &quot;the embroidered curtain is half hooked, and the treasure platform is being built&quot;. The words are beautiful, and it has the charm of a beautiful lady waiting for the one she likes. It writes about the psychology of looking forward to the snow but being afraid of the heavy snow. , but said &quot;I am still afraid of covering up the pear blossoms in the courtyard, and making old friends shed tears&quot;, creating the beautiful image of &quot;the rain hits the pear blossoms and closes the door&quot; and &quot;a branch of pear blossoms brings rain in spring&quot;. The words are both dense and beautiful, just as Kuang Zhouyi said : “In the secret place of the dream window, there can be countless beautiful words, which are vivid and dancing, like thousands of flowers for spring. &quot;(&quot;Hui Feng Ci&quot;)&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; The specific time of creation of this poem is unknown. Wu Wenying&#39;s life had almost no expectations of making a contribution and a positive career. His pursuit of life is relatively narrow, and he has many dreamy works. The sentence &quot;Zhuang Shengxiao is obsessed with butterflies in his dream&quot; in Li Shangyin&#39;s &quot;Jin Se&quot; has a dream-like and illusive feeling of confusion in life. I liked this very much. So I used Lekuo in various ways in my lyrics many times. This song &quot;No Boredom·Driving Snow&quot; is his representative work. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the Author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; &lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/wuwenying.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Wu Wenying (about 1200~1260), character Junte, also known as Mengchuang, and later Jueweng, was born in Siming (today&#39;s Ningbo, Zhejiang). He was originally named Weng, and later heir to the Wu family. He was friendly with Jia Sidao. There is a collection of Mengchuang Ci, which is extant. There are more than 340 ci poems, divided into four volumes and one volume. His ci works are abundant in quantity, elegant in style, and contain many poems that respond to grief, grief, and mourning. They are called &quot;Li Shangyin in Ci&quot;. However, later generations have praised him very much. There is controversy.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>