<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[瞻卬 | 诗经·大雅·荡之什]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239161]]><description> &lt;h2>;Looking at the Haotian&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] The Book of Songs·Daya·Dangzhishi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;Looking at the Haotian, will you not benefit from me? The holes are filled with restlessness, so the punishment is so severe. The state is in ruins, and the soldiers and the people are in trouble. There are thieves and diseases, and there are barbarians everywhere. If the crime is not taken away, there will be chaos! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Men have land, but women have it. People have people, and women overthrow them. This should be innocent, but the woman will accept it. Bi Yi is guilty, and the woman replies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A wise husband makes a city, and a wise wife charms a city. Yi Jue is a wise woman, and she is an owl and an owl. The woman has a long tongue and is powerful! Bandits descend from heaven and are born from women. Bandit religions and bandit teachings were at the Weifu Temple. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The people in Jiu are worried about it, but they are afraid of it. How can it be said that Yihu is not extremely? Like Jia three times, a gentleman is knowledgeable. If a woman has no official business, she should stop weaving silkworms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why is the sky thorny? Why is God not rich? Sheer Jiedi, Weiyu Xuji. Not hanging is ominous, and the majesty is not the same. When people die, the country will die! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heaven’s bestowal on him is to maintain his superiority. People&#39;s clouds are dying, and their hearts are worried. Heaven&#39;s surrender is just a matter of a few. When people die, their hearts are filled with sadness! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the boiling spring, it is very deep. The heart is worried, would you rather stay from now on? Don’t put yourself first, don’t put yourself last. Anyone who despises Haotian can defeat Gong. There is no anger for the emperor, and he will save you later. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Looking up at the sky means deep things, but the sky is merciless to me. The world has not been peaceful for a long time, and great disasters have caused great harm to the world. There is no peace in the country, and the scholars and common people are harmed. Pests and diseases destroy crops year after year without end. If the law of crime is not restrained, the abyss of suffering will not be alleviated. &lt;br />;People have a good piece of land, but you take it for yourself. Others have strong labor force, but you take advantage of it. This man was originally innocent, but you turned against him and arrested him. That person should be a sinner, but you forgive and forgive. &lt;br />;A talented man will dominate, but a talented woman will destroy the country. It&#39;s a pity that this woman is so arrogant and has a bad reputation like an owl or an owl. They are good at telling lies with their sweet words, and they hide the root of disaster and evil. Disasters do not come from heaven, but from the side of women. It is not for others to teach me, just because I am close to the girl Hongzhuang. &lt;br />;Luo Zhi was accused of being framed, and his words were contradictory. Isn&#39;t she cruel? Who is so cruel and evil! Just like a profiteer making a fortune, a gentleman has clear insight. Women should not be involved in government affairs, and all silkworm and weaver girls should be put aside. &lt;br />;Why does heaven punish suffering? Why don’t gods protect us? The culprit and stubborn enemy didn&#39;t care at all, he was just jealous of me. People show no mercy when suffering disasters, and pretend to be ignorant when their discipline is corrupted. All the good ministers and wise men have fled, and the country is in crisis without help. &lt;br />;The sky is merciless and has cast down the net of law, and it is difficult to hide in the harsh and numerous ways. All the good ministers and wise men are in exile, and they taste the bitter fruits when they worry about the country. The sky is mercilessly raining down the law, and frequent crises are unstoppable. Kill all the good ministers and wise men, and feel sad when you are worried about the country. &lt;br />;The gushing spring boils and sprays water, and the gurgling spring has deep roots. When you are worried about the country, your heart is sad. Could it be that today your worries are increasing? Disasters will not befall you during your lifetime, and disasters will not follow you after your death. The Thousand Earth Emperor is unpredictable, controlling all living beings and determining the universe. Do not dishonor your ancestors and save your country for your descendants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;卬 (yǎng): means &quot;Yang&quot;. Haotian: the vast sky. &lt;br />;Hui: love. &lt;br />;Fill in: Pass through &quot;dust&quot;, long-lasting. &lt;br />;Li: Disaster. &lt;br />;Shimin: scholars and common people.瘵 (zhài): disease. &lt;br />;Police (máo): an insect that damages crops. Thief, disease: harm. &lt;br />;Eradicate: level. Period: ultimate, extreme. &lt;br />;罟 (gǔ): net. Crime: the legal net for criminal crimes. &lt;br />;禳 (chōu): recovery from illness. &lt;br />;Reverse: reverse. &lt;br />;Said: through &quot;taking off&quot;. &lt;br />;Philosophy: Wisdom. &lt;br />;Yi (yì): means &quot;噫&quot;, an interjection. &lt;br />;Owl (xiāo): Legend has it that it is an evil bird that eats its mother when it grows up.鸱(chī): A bird with a bad sound, that is, an owl. &lt;br />;Stairs: stairs. &lt;br />;Bandit: No. Teaching: teaching. &lt;br />;Temple: Close. eunuch: chamberlain. &lt;br />;鸫(jū): exhaustion.忮(zhì): Harm. Te: change. &lt;br />;议(zèn): to make slanderous remarks. Finally: end. Back: Violation, self-contradiction. &lt;br />;Extreme: ruthless. &lt;br />;Yi: auxiliary word.杝(tè): evil, wrong. &lt;br />;Jia (gǔ): businessman. Triple: Refers to three times the profit. &lt;br />;Gentleman: Refers to those who are in power. Knowledge: Pass &quot;job&quot;. &lt;br />;Official work: that is, meritorious work, which refers to the textile and sericulture work done by women. &lt;br />;Thorn: accuse, blame. &lt;br />;Fu: Blessed. &lt;br />;Introduction: Big. Di: Tong &quot;Ti&quot;, far. &lt;br />;Taboo: Resentment. &lt;br />;Condolence: Condolence and condolences. &lt;br />;Category: Good. &lt;br />;Cloud: particle. &lt;br />;宄(tiǎn) and 瘁(cuì): both words refer to &quot;disease&quot;. &lt;br />;罔 (wǎng): access to the &quot;net&quot;. &lt;br />;Excellent: Thick. &lt;br />;A few: near. &lt;br />;觱(bì) boiling: the appearance of spring water rising up. &lt;br />;Miǎo: Gao Yuan appearance. &lt;br />;Consolidation: solidification, refers to restraint and control. &lt;br />;忝(tiǎn): humiliation. &lt;br />;Formula: use. &lt;br />;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; There are seven chapters in the poem. The first chapter describes natural disasters and man-made disasters, the current situation is difficult and dangerous, the country is unstable, and the lives of people are in ruins. The &quot;heaven&quot; here refers to the heaven of nature, and also refers to the &quot;heaven&quot; of human society - the supreme ruler of mankind. Therefore, the &quot;disaster&quot; here includes both natural disasters and man-made disasters. And man-made disasters are even worse than natural disasters. Chapter two exposes the perverse tyranny through two &quot;reverse&quot; and two &quot;overturn&quot; accusations. Chapter 3 believes that the root cause of trouble is that women are favored, and the main means of harming others are slander and gossip. Chapter 4 proposes that an effective way to eliminate &quot;female troubles&quot; is to let &quot;women&quot; work as female workers in silkworm weaving and not participate in government affairs. The fifth chapter directly accuses King You of not guarding against the Rong and Di, but resenting the virtuous ministers, which resulted in the destruction of the country. In the sixth chapter, in the face of natural and man-made disasters, he expresses his sincere concern for the times and the country. In Chapter Seven, he hurt himself and was born in troubled times, and put forward a plan to remedy the situation to admonish the king. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The questions raised in &quot;Zhan Yan&quot; can not only be confirmed from historical books, but also supplement the omissions and deficiencies in historical records. The main historical fact that King You of Zhou favored Bao Si and destroyed the country with his desolate government is: Ever since King You received Bao Si, he pampered her endlessly, became extravagant and ignored the affairs of the state. One is to use the beacon tower to buy a thousand pieces of gold. The princes thought that the enemy was invading and came to rescue him, but they were deceived and returned angrily. After teasing him many times, he broke his trust with the princes and never came to King Qin again. The second is to reuse the sycophant Guo Shifu. This person is &quot;a sycophant, good at flattery, and a profit-loving person&quot; and &quot;all the people in the country are resentful&quot; (&quot;Historical Records·Zhou Benji&quot;). Third, he wanted to depose Empress Shen and Prince Yijiu, and make Bao Si the empress and Bao Si&#39;s son Bofu as the crown prince. This angered Empress Shen and colluded with the Western Yi and Quan Rong to attack the Zhou Dynasty, kill King You and destroy the Western Zhou Dynasty. The content reflected in &quot;Zhan Yen&quot; is more extensive, specific and profound than the historical records. The poem lists the evil deeds of King You of several weeks, including: making accusations and killing scholars; being harsh and oppressive, making the people miserable; occupying land and plundering slaves; and indulging sinners. , persecution of the innocent; corrupt political style, disordered discipline; jealousy of the virtuous and capable, traitors gain power; crimes are so dense that loyal ministers flee. It comprehensively and vividly presents a historical picture on the eve of the collapse of Western Zhou society in front of readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is unknown who the author of &quot;Zhan Xian&quot; is. He was either a bloody clan member of the Zhou Dynasty, an upright and powerful official in the court, or a persecuted remonstrator. No matter who he was, he deeply hated the social darkness, political corruption and perverse behavior under the rule of King You of Zhou Dynasty, so he ruthlessly exposed and severely criticized what King You had done. Feeling sorry and heartbroken. The poet is particularly saddened by the fact that &quot;when a person dies, a country dies.&quot; The &quot;death&quot; of a person may include death, killing, demotion, seclusion, or flight. Wise men and gentlemen are the pillars of the country, and the old and mature weeds are the vitality of the country. Now that the vitality has been damaged, the pillars will collapse, the people will perish, the country will be exhausted, and the gods will be angry. The poet&#39;s emotions are uncontrollable, like lava erupting from a volcano, stuck in the throat, and he is unhappy if he doesn&#39;t spit it out. In the fifth chapter, there are two sentences at the beginning: &quot;Why is the sky stabbed? Why is the god not rich?&quot; He is really crying out to the gods, beating his chest and feet, and feeling sad. Incessantly. Then three sentences &quot;Man&#39;s death in the clouds&quot; welled up from his heart, lamenting the indescribable meaning of regret and loss, and repeatedly stating &quot;Wei Qi is excellent&quot;, &quot;Wei Qi is few&quot;, &quot;Wei Qi is deep&quot;, sighing and worrying. , in &quot;My heart is worried&quot; and &quot;My heart is sad&quot;, the pain is fully expressed, and the stirring emotions are tragically expressed. The poem is in such loops and sad syllables, which makes people cry, and presents the sincere heart of the lonely minister and evil son in broad daylight. It makes people read it as if they hear his voice and see his person. He is a person who cares about the country and cares about the time. The image of a warm-hearted character appears on the page and is ready to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The number of sentences in each chapter of &quot;The Book of Songs&quot; is roughly the same. There are only a few chapters of varying lengths. &quot;Zhan Xian&quot; is an example. The poem has seven chapters in total, with the first, third and last chapters having ten lines, and the remaining four chapters having eight lines. This jagged chapter and sentence makes it easier for hearty narrative, lyricism and discussion. The structure of the poem is extremely majestic at the beginning, with a high-level view, sweeping everything in, and it is as vigorous as vomiting. The language in the article is very fresh and sharp, but it also has a straightforward meaning. The words in the poem are finished but the meaning is still unfinished. The rhetorical sentences are quite distinctive, or use contrasting and contrasting sentence patterns to express the accumulated anger in the chest, or to reflect on the feelings of deep contemplation. Or it is ingenious with vivid metaphors, rich connotations, and profound expressions. In terms of rhyme, each chapter is different. There is a rhyme used at the end of each sentence, such as Chapter 4, which may have the same rhyme or co-rhyme. This kind of rhyme used in sentences is a common rhyme example in the Book of Songs. The &quot;Bai Liang style&quot; of seven-character poems in the Han, Wei, Southern and Northern Dynasties inherited this tradition. There are also a few ancient seven-character poems in the Tang Dynasty that use rhyme in every sentence. There are two rhymes in one chapter of this poem, such as Chapter 5 and Chapter 6. As the poet&#39;s emotions change, the rhythm of the poem slows down or accelerates, rises or falls, and the rhyme also changes accordingly, either in flat tones, or oblique tones, or in conjunction with each other, which increases the beauty of the sound and style and makes the poem more vivid. . &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This is a poem that satirizes King You of Zhou for his chaos and ruin of the country. King You of Zhou was stupid and decadent, favored his concubines, corrupted discipline, appointed treacherous people, rejected the virtuous, and acted against the will of others, which led to the wrath of heaven and the resentment of people. The dogs and soldiers from the north took the opportunity to invade and killed King You of Zhou at the foot of Mount Li, thus leading to the demise of the Western Zhou Dynasty. Therefore, the poet wrote this poem &quot;Daya Zhanyi&quot; to satirize it. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寒食寄郑起侍郎 | 杨徽之]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239151]]><description> &lt;h2>;Cold food sent to the minister of Zheng Qi&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Yang Huizhi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;When I went out to the suburbs during the Qingming Festival, I saw the willows in the lonely mountain city. &lt;br />;Separated from the water by the light smoke is Xiuzhu Temple, passing by Shuyuluohua Village. &lt;br />;It’s hard to get drunk when the weather is cold and the wine is thin, and it’s easy to lose one’s soul when the ground is so different and the buildings are high. &lt;br />;Looking back at my hometown thousands of miles away, to whom do I address my thoughts of separation? &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;During the Qingming Festival, I walked out of the countryside alone, and the doorways of every house in the lonely mountain city were hidden by green willows. &lt;br />;Across the water, in the light mist, you can see the Buddhist temples lined with bamboos. It is drizzling along the way, and the villages passing by have fallen flowers. &lt;br />;The weather is cold and the meager wine cannot keep me drunk. When I climb a tall building, I can only see the huge difference between the sky and the earth. It makes me feel extremely sad when I miss my hometown and my friends. &lt;br />;Looking back at my hometown thousands of miles away, who can I tell it to when I am full of emotions of separation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Hanshi: Cold Food Festival. One hundred and five days after the winter solstice every year, fire is forbidden and cold food is eaten, which is called cold food. Zheng Qi: Yu Menglong. In the later Zhou Dynasty, he served as Youshiyi and Zhishiguan, and moved to the palace to serve as the censor. After entering the Song Dynasty, he was demoted in 963 (the first year of Qiande) and died without taking office again. &quot;Servant&quot; may be a mistake for &quot;Servant&quot;. &lt;br />;Qingming Festival: Two days after the Cold Food Festival is the Qingming Festival, so Cold Food and Qingming Festival are often celebrated together. Jiaoyuan: suburban wilderness. Ancient customs include outings to visit tombs during Cold Food Festival and Qingming Festival, and spring outings in the countryside. &lt;br />;Liu Yingmen: During the Qingming Cold Food Festival in the Song Dynasty, there was a custom of inserting willows on the door, which is recorded in Volume 7 of &quot;Tokyo Menghua Lu&quot; and Volume 2 of &quot;Mengliang Lu&quot;. &lt;br />;Xiuzhu Temple: a Buddhist temple with slender bamboos. &lt;br />;Luohua Village: A village of falling flowers. &lt;br />;Jiuban: The wine tastes light. &lt;br />;迥(jiǒng): far. Broken Soul: This is used to describe extreme sadness. &lt;br />;Gushan: hometown. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first sentence &quot;Qingming&quot; is suffixed with the word &quot;season&quot;, which includes cold food. It was a custom in the Song Dynasty to &quot;go out to the countryside&quot; for a spring outing at this time. For example, there is a sentence in Shao Yong&#39;s &quot;Spring Outing&quot;: &quot;Only cold food can be eaten during the festivals in the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second sentence &quot;Mountain City&quot; points out the poet. Travel location. &quot;Silent&quot; is a redundant word used to enhance the surrounding environment. Willow is a plant with seasonal climate characteristics. Not only did Han Xu of the Tang Dynasty have a famous saying that &quot;cold food makes the east wind protect the willows from slanting&quot;, but also people in the Song Dynasty used willows and other objects to decorate the top of the sedan chair and cover it with hanging willows every time they had cold food. Each household also made &quot;flying swallows made of jujube flour, strung with wicker sticks, and inserted at the root of the door&quot; (Volume 7 of &quot;Tokyo Menghua Lu&quot;). Therefore, &quot;Liu Yingmen&quot; is a unique scene of Hanshi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are two sentences and two scenes in the chin couplet: one far and one close, one hazy and one clear, just like the composition of a painter, with harmonious tones and well-proportioned brushstrokes. Also written about the cold food Qingming Festival, Liu Yong&#39;s &quot;Magnolia Slowness&quot; poem: &quot;The tung blossoms are blooming, and the rain is sparse, washing the Qingming Festival. The apricots are burning in the forest, the peach fields are embroidered, and the scenery is like a screen.&quot; And in Yang Huizhi&#39;s poem In the description of the painting, &quot;a bamboo temple is built across the water and there is light smoke, passing by Shuyuluohua Village&quot;. Such a scene with elegant colors and desolate scenery echoes the &quot;silent mountain city&quot; in the past, and forms a distinct contrast with the bustling and lively scene of the capital during the cold weather. In contrast, the twists and turns euphemistically express the poet&#39;s sorrow after being demoted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The neck couplet expresses emotions instantly. &quot;The weather is cold&quot; points out the climate characteristics of the Cold Food Festival, which is warm and then cold. &quot;The wine is thin&quot; implies the remoteness of the mountain city. From the Tang Dynasty to the Song Dynasty, there was a custom of sweeping graves with cold food. At this time, seeing this scene from a high place makes me miss home even more. In the poem, &quot;it&#39;s easy to lose one&#39;s soul&quot; comes from &quot;the place is far away&quot; and &quot;looking back to the old mountain thousands of miles away&quot;; and &quot;it&#39;s difficult to become drunk&quot; is also inseparable from this. These two sentences are similar to the lyrics in Fan Zhongyan&#39;s &quot;Royal Street Journey&quot;: &quot;My heart has been broken and I can&#39;t get drunk. Before the wine arrives, I will burst into tears.&quot; It is said that Song Taizong admired Yang Huizhi&#39;s poems very much and specially selected ten couplets to be written on the screen, including this couplet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The beauty of the last couplet lies in ending it with a question. The poet originally had a &quot;feeling of separation&quot; that was ready to burst out. Here it is expressed as &quot;To whom&quot;, in the &quot;exposed bones&quot;, it is still the sound of singing and sighing, which is in harmony with the tone of the whole poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When Xikun style was popular, the author could avoid carving gold and jade or piling up allusions. The forehead couplets are slightly changed in level and obliqueness. Although the neck couplets are perfectly aligned, they still have a slight meaning of &quot;flowing water pairing&quot; and still have the beauty of natural flow. The whole poem appears natural and fresh, both in content and artistic technique. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This poem was written from the beginning of the Qiande period of the Northern Song Dynasty (963-968) to the beginning of the Taiping and Xingguo period (976-984). Yang Huizhi was demoted to When I was a foreign official. Confessing the &quot;feelings of separation&quot; to his old friend Zheng Qi is the main theme of the whole poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yang Huizhi (921-1000) was an official in the Song Dynasty and a leader among the first generation of poets in the early Song Dynasty. His courtesy name was Zhongyou, a native of Pucheng, Jianzhou (now part of Fujian). In the second year of Xiande&#39;s reign in the later Zhou Dynasty, he was promoted to Jinshi Jia Ke, and he started as a school secretary, Jixian school manager, and was a retired official. Because of his outstanding literary talent, he was once ordered to participate in the editing of &quot;Wenyuan Yinghua&quot; and was responsible for the poetry section. During the reign of Emperor Zhenzong, he went to the Imperial Academy to study for a bachelor&#39;s degree. He was a pure and honest person, abiding by the rules, and respected the teachings. He was especially unfavorable to those who did not follow the Tao and worked hard. He later died of foot illness and was given the posthumous title of Wenzhuang. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:23:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>