<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[渡易水歌 | 佚名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310282]]><description> &lt;h2>;Song of Crossing the Yishui&lt;/h2>;[Pre-Qin] Anonymous&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;The wind is rustling and the Yishui is cold, and the strong men will never return once they are gone. (Return to the first work: Fufan)&lt;br />;Enter the tiger&#39;s den and enter the dragon&#39;s palace, look up to the sky and exhale and a white rainbow will appear. (This sentence is suspected to be a later addition) &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;The wind blows rustlingly, and the water changes The cold air is blowing, and the strong man is leaving here. I swear I will not return until I complete my mission! &lt;br />;Assassinating the King of Qin is as dangerous as going to the tiger&#39;s den or the dragon&#39;s palace, but our hero&#39;s heroic spirit can make a white rainbow even when he exhales to the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Xiao Xiao: refers to the sound of wind. Yishui: refers to the name of water, originating from Yixian County, Hebei Province, which was the southern boundary of Yan State at that time. &lt;br />;Xi: modal particle. &lt;br />;The strong man: here refers to Jing Ke. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The previous sentence describes the wind and cold water, exaggerating the desolate and solemn atmosphere. The next sentence expresses the desperate feelings, knowing that there is no way back, but resolutely going there and never looking back. The sound of &quot;wind rustling&quot; audibly exaggerates the tragedy of parting; &quot;Yishuihan&quot; is bone-piercing, describing the desolation of the environment from the sense of feeling; up and down, the world is extremely miserable, further highlighting Jing Ke&#39;s &quot;gentleman&quot; &quot;Die your confidant&quot;, the awe-inspiring and upright spirit of generously going to the national calamity. Although it has only fifteen words, it is &quot;sad, intense, full of character and emotion&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; &quot;The wind is rustling and the water is cold, and a strong man will never return once he is gone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jing Ke used this It got its name, and the two short poems will last forever. The difficulty in expressing majestic emotions in poetry lies in being convincing rather than being arrogant and exaggerated; it is in being able to express the more permanent and universal sentiments hidden behind the temporary feelings rather than in the momentary impulse. Perhaps tragic words are often used emotionally, and it is difficult for people to distinguish truth from falsehood when they are emotional, so the words not only deceive others, but also deceive themselves. Many works that are exciting at the moment are boring when you read them afterwards. It is precisely because of the performance that you deceive yourself. &quot;Song of Yishui&quot;, with its two gentle lines, has become an eternal masterpiece. When we read it, we must know Jing Ke&#39;s life experience. This is the universality of art, which transcends time and space and appeals to the eternal sentiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word &quot;xiaoxiao&quot; is commonly seen in poems. Ancient poem: &quot;The white poplars are full of sorrow and the wind is sad, and the rustling of the wind kills people.&quot; The three words &quot;wind and rustling&quot; naturally bring out the meaning of high autumn. The ancients said, &quot;When you climb a mountain and reach the water, you will see the general return home&quot;, and here it is said: &quot;A strong man will never return once he is gone.&quot; There seems to be a comparison between them, and it seems to be an explanation. It is inconvenient for us to say what it is, but we can I found some other verses. Here we first remember the vastness of &quot;the bright moon shining on the snow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The bright moon shines on the snow&quot;, which is clean and cold. The so-called &quot;Qionglou Yuyu, the height is not cold&quot;. &quot;Song of Yi Shui&quot; mentions the word &quot;cold&quot;, but Xie&#39;s poem does not mention it, but both are high because of the cold, and more emotional because of the high. Du Shi said, &quot;The wind is strong and the sky is high, and the apes are screaming in mourning.&quot; Naturally, we can&#39;t explain why the apes roar in mourning. However, don&#39;t we see that &quot;the new wind is strong and sad&quot;? The new wind is the north wind, so it is naturally very strong, but this word &quot;sorrow&quot; is the expressive part of this poem. So how can a strong man return once he is gone? When he is gone, it is written as a word of strength, but when he is gone, it is also a word of sorrow. Coincidences in the world must have a reason, not to mention that they are all famous sentences, not to mention that they are not related to each other. They are not related but have a deeper unity. This is the universality of art. Whenever the Qiuyuan is vast, the cold water is clear, and we are independent among the rustling wind, even if we are not strong men, we must have the mind of a strong man, so this poem exists without Jing Ke. Although it was spoken by Jing Ke, it belongs to everyone. &quot;Withered mulberry trees know the wind in the sky, and sea water knows the cold weather.&quot; This little understanding between us people, this little understanding between us people and nature, seems to be possible to say, but it seems impossible to say, but it is It brings our souls to a broader world. The vast wilderness is where life comes from. We have long forgotten it in our narrow life, but we have come to know it again in literature and art. Although our life is short, it has the meaning of eternal life here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhuan Zhu assassinated the King of Wu, but died and succeeded. Jing Ke stabbed the King of Qin, died but failed. However, we have forgotten Zhuan Zhu for a long time and are praising Jing Ke. Scholars cannot be judged on success or failure, and why we miss Jing Ke even more, isn’t it precisely because of this short poem? The poet created poetry, and at the same time he created himself. It belongs to Jing Ke and to all people. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 3&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This short song expresses the story of Jing Ke when he went to assassinate the King of Qin by exaggerating the external scenery with the rustling wind and the cold water. The tragic feelings and the firm will not to return until the mission is completed. Some people renovated the meaning to express the heroic spirit of revolutionaries who risked their lives to fight against the enemy. This poem was quoted in the movie &quot;The Five Heroes of Langya Mountain&quot; to inspire the revolutionary warriors to have the courage to fight against the enemy, and to exaggerate the generous and tragic atmosphere of fighting for the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This history has been compiled into a beautiful story, which is the book &quot;The Bright Moon in the Qin Dynasty - Jing Ke&#39;s Biography&quot;, in which the beautiful story of Jing Ke and Li Ji is written in vivid and beautiful language, which is worth reading. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation 4&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; There are only two sentences in this poem. At first glance, it is easy to understand and straightforward. However, if you taste it carefully, it has profound meaning. , upright, and quite artistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem imitates the &quot;Xing&quot; technique in &quot;The Book of Songs&quot;, which &quot;prefaces other things to trigger the words to be chanted&quot;. First, it uses the west wind to change the water, and then draws out the warrior&#39;s ambition and feelings, and it is coherent. , quite impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first sentence explains the time and place of the expedition. The rustling autumn wind, the cold and changing water, are all natural scenery with no emotion at all, but here Jing Ke expresses his heart&#39;s emotions on the scenery in front of him. His emotions are full of wind, and his meaning is overflowing in the water, giving it a strong emotional color. . The choice of the onomatopoeia &quot;xiaoxiao&quot; and the adjective &quot;han&quot; is very unique and exciting. The former appeals to hearing, and the latter appeals to touch, creating a solemn, melancholy, and tragic natural and social atmosphere, which lays the artistic foundation for the emergence of the theme of the next sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last sentence follows the first sentence. Clarify the purpose of this poem. Because the previous sentence has sufficient momentum, this sentence expresses the heart directly, singing the heroic and dignified feelings of a strong man who sacrifices his life for righteousness and regards death as if he is home. Jing Ke knew very well that using his own meager strength to fight against the King of Qin, who was in charge of thousands of troops and had been familiar with swordsmanship since childhood, would be like hitting an egg against a stone, and the hope of survival would be almost zero. There is a great enemy at hand, and the fate of the country is uncertain, which is tragic; when we are weak against a strong enemy, the outcome is unpredictable, which is sad; when we know that it is difficult to survive, we die generously, which is heroic! Jing Ke&#39;s heroic act of &quot;knowing that there are tigers in the mountains, but preferring to go to the tiger mountains&quot; could not have been accomplished without extraordinary courage and courage. Therefore, even though he stopped abruptly after singing the sentence &quot;A strong man has gone and never comes back&quot; without another word, it still made those who saw him off &quot;all their eyes were filled with anger and their fingers were stretched out&quot; (see &quot;Historical Records&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jing Ke got his name from this poem, and the two short lines of the poem will last forever. The difficulty in expressing majestic emotions in poetry lies in being convincing rather than being arrogant and exaggerated; it is in being able to express the more permanent and universal sentiments hidden behind the temporary feelings rather than in the momentary impulse. Perhaps tragic words are often used emotionally, and it is difficult for people to distinguish truth from falsehood when they are emotional, so the words not only deceive others, but also deceive themselves. Many works that are exciting at the moment are boring when you read them afterwards. It is precisely because of the performance that you deceive yourself. &quot;Song of Yishui&quot;, with its two gentle lines, has become an eternal masterpiece. When we read it, we must know Jing Ke&#39;s life experience. This is the universality of art, which transcends time and space and appeals to the eternal sentiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This unembellished and extremely simple lyric &quot;can describe the misery of heaven and earth, and the feeling of a strong man returning home even after death&quot; (&quot;Suihantang Poetry&quot;) precisely because of Jing Ke&#39;s Emotions are moved in the text and expressed in words, giving it the ability to feel the autumn wind, move the water, shake the world, weep ghosts and gods, be generous and passionate, and show a huge charm that is heart-stirring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The language of this poem is very plain and concise. It uses scenes to express emotions and blends scenes. By rendering the external scenery with the rustling wind and cold water, it expresses Jing Ke’s tragic feelings and unhappiness when he went to assassinate the King of Qin. A firm will to complete the mission and never give it back. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Also known as anonymous, it refers to a person whose identity is unknown or whose name has not yet been learned. Literary and musical works originating from ancient times or among the people and whose author is unknown will be named anonymously. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 04:23:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[题榴花 | 韩愈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=2310271]]><description> &lt;h2>;Inscribed on pomegranate flowers&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Han Yu&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;In May, the pomegranate flowers illuminate the eyes, and the seeds are beginning to appear among the branches. &lt;br />;It&#39;s a pity that there are no carriages and horses here, and the moss is upside down and the flowers are falling. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;The fiery pomegranate flowers in May are particularly vivid and can be seen between the branches and leaves. To the first small fruits. &lt;br />;It&#39;s a pity that no dignitaries came here to appreciate it, so the gorgeous pomegranate flowers had to be scattered on the moss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;br />;&lt;/strong>;Shining: still dazzling. Describes the brightness or luminosity of an object. &lt;br />;Occasionally: common. Zi: refers to pomegranate. &lt;br />;Pity: What a pity. &lt;br />;No carriages and horses: No dignitaries came to enjoy the scenery in carriages or horses. &lt;br />;Inverted: spinning and flipping, with multiple fingers and a confused mind. &lt;br />;绛(jiàng): bright red. &lt;br />;Jiangying: This refers to the pomegranate petals falling to the ground. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; The first two sentences of this poem point out the season and outline the lush and brilliant scene in May when the pomegranate flowers bloom; the last two sentences point out the location. , indicating that no one is visiting the pomegranate flowers so that the beautiful scenery is lonely and scattered, euphemistically expressing the poet&#39;s lonely mood. The whole poem describes the fresh and natural scenery, and embodies the philosophy of life in the description of the objective scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In May, pomegranate flowers illuminate your eyes, and you can always see the beginning of growth among the branches.&quot; Two sentences point out the season, and a few words outline the lush and brilliant scene of pomegranate flowers in May, especially The three words &quot;illuminate the eyes&quot; are vivid and expressive. The poet not only wrote about flowers, but also about the happy mood of people who look at them. The last two sentences indicate the location. This is a pomegranate that grows in a remote place. No one climbs or breaks its flower branches to damage it. The bright red pomegranate flowers fall on the moss in large numbers. The red and green contrast with each other. The picture is very beautiful, making people feel how cute it is. and regret. In fact, the poet loves it because no tourists come to admire it, and he loves the &quot;moss&quot; and &quot;red flowers&quot; all over the ground. If someone comes to admire it, it will be trampled under the ruts and horse hooves. It is better to let the flowers bloom and fall, and the fruits are ripe and rotten. Naturally, it euphemistically expresses the poet&#39;s lonely mood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first two sentences of this poem describe the scenery, and the last two sentences express feelings. The author does not describe the scenery directly, but uses people&#39;s feelings to highlight the gorgeousness of the pomegranate flowers. But no matter how beautiful the flowers bloom, they still fall silently. The poet laments that no one comes to appreciate the flowers, which is a metaphor for a friend who is full of talents, but is relegated to a remote place by the ruler and unable to display them. The word &quot;inverted&quot; is even more so. It effectively criticizes the rulers&#39; ignorance of talents and the resentment of poets and authors who have not been recognized for their talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The whole poem describes the scenery as fresh and natural, from which we can see the poet&#39;s rich interest and thoughtful and rich literary thoughts. However, the sudden changes in poetic meaning and description are all contained in sentences that seem to be light and heavy in reality, making the poetic meaning suddenly become deeper, and also showing the changing characteristics of &quot;hills and hills are uneven&quot; in writing. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Creative background&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; This poem was titled at Zhang Shiyi’s Hotel, and the specific time of creation is unknown. Zhang Shiyi is a good friend of the author. When the author wrote this poem, both Zhang Shiyi and he were demoted. The poet wrote this poem because of his feelings. In &quot;Poems of a Thousand Families&quot;, the author of this poem is Zhu Xi in the engravings of the past dynasties, which has been erroneously corrected by later generations. &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/hanyu.jpg&quot; width=50%>;&lt;/ center>;&lt;/div>;Han Yu (768-December 25, 824), also known as Tuizhi, was a native of Heyang, Henan (now Mengzhou City, Henan Province). He claimed to be his &quot;ancestral home in Changli County&quot; and was known as &quot;Han Changli&quot; in the world. &quot;Mr. Changli&quot;. A minister in the mid-Tang Dynasty, a writer, thinker, politician, and the son of Secretary Lang Han Zhongqing. In the twelfth year of Yuanhe (817), he served as prime minister Pei Du and marched to Sima to quell the &quot;Huaixi Rebellion&quot;. He bluntly remonstrated with the Buddha&#39;s bones and was demoted to be the governor of Chaozhou. With the ups and downs of the officialdom, he moved to the Ministry of Officials and became a minister, known as the &quot;Han Officials Department&quot;. In the fourth year of Changqing (824), Han Yu died of illness at the age of fifty-seven. He was given the posthumous title &quot;Wen&quot; by the Minister of Rites, so he was called &quot;Han Wen Gong&quot;. In the first year of Yuanfeng (1078), he was granted the title of Uncle of Changli County and worshiped in the Confucius Temple. As an advocate of the ancient prose movement in the Tang Dynasty, Han Yu ranked first among the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot; and was known as &quot;The Great Master of Articles&quot; and &quot;The Master of Literature for a Hundred Generations&quot;. Together with Liu Zongyuan, he is known as &quot;Han Liu&quot;, and together with Liu Zongyuan, Ouyang Xiu and Su Shi, he is known as &quot;the four great writers through the ages&quot;. He advocated writing theories such as &quot;the unity of literature and Taoism&quot;, &quot;the words are powerful and the words are appropriate&quot;, &quot;the things are more important than the statements&quot;, and &quot;the words are consistent with the words&quot;, which have guiding significance for future generations. He is the author of &quot;Collection of Han Changli&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 04:23:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>