<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily ancient poetry</title><description> RSS of the full text of daily ancient poems. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.gushiwen.org <item><title><![CDATA[江城子·江景 | 苏轼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239222]]><description> &lt;h2>;Jiangchengzi·Jiangjing&lt;/h2>;[Song Dynasty] Su Shi&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;&lt;p>;On the lake, he and Zhang Xian wrote the same poem, and sometimes they heard playing the zither&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was raining in Phoenix Mountain The sky is clear at first, the water and wind are clear, and the sunset is bright. A hibiscus bloomed gracefully. A pair of egrets flew from nowhere, admiring Pingting if you wanted to. &lt;br />;Suddenly I heard mourning kites being played on the river, expressing sorrow and emotion. Who can listen to them! The smoke gathers and the clouds gather, it is Xiang Ling as promised. I want to wait until the end of the song to ask for it, but no one can see it, and the peaks are green. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and annotations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Under the Phoenix Mountain, it is clear after the rain, the clouds are clear, the wind is clear, and the sunset glow Bright. A lotus flower, although it has bloomed, is still beautiful and pure. A pair of egrets flew by somewhere, and they also came to admire the beauty of the kite player. Suddenly I heard the sad tune on the river, full of sorrow, who could bear to listen to it. The mist is restrained by it, and the clouds are faded by it. This song is like the goddess of Xiangshui playing the harp to express her sorrow. When the song ends, she has drifted away, and only the green mountain peaks are still standing quietly. By the lake, it seems that the sad music is still rippling in the mountains and waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Lake: refers to the West Lake in Hangzhou. Zhang Xian: a famous poet in the Northern Song Dynasty. &lt;br />;Phoenix Mountain: south of West Lake in Hangzhou. &lt;br />;Fuyu: Lotus. &lt;br />;Pingting: Beautiful posture, this refers to a beautiful woman. &lt;br />;Jiang Shang: Yuan Wen of the Song Dynasty quoted it as &quot;Feast on the Banquet&quot; in &quot;Weng Wan Xian Commentary&quot;. &lt;br />;Zheng: stringed instrument, long wooden shape. Before the Han and Jin Dynasties, the zither had twelve strings, and later it was increased to thirteen, fifteen, sixteen and twenty-one strings. &lt;br />;Xiang Ling: The goddess of Xiangshui. According to legend, she was originally the concubine of Shun. &quot;Chu Ci·Nine Songs&quot; contains &quot;Mrs. Xiang&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This word was written by Su Shi from the fifth year to the seventh year of Xining (1072) when he was appointed as the Tong magistrate of Hangzhou and he was over eighty years old at that time. It was written by the famous Zhang Xian (990-1078) when he visited the West Lake with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The author interestingly sticks to the title &quot;hearing the zheng played&quot; and describes the beauty of the zheng player and the moving music from many aspects. In the poem, the zither player is placed in the clear lakes and mountains after the rain and the beautiful sunset, so that the characters and the scenery complement each other, and the music and the mountains and rivers complement each other. In the description of the characters, the author uses metaphors and foil techniques. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first three sentences describe the scenery of mountains and lakes, which are just background images of the characters. The two sentences &quot;a hibiscus&quot; follow immediately, which not only describe the lotus on the water surface, but also use the hibiscus out of the water as a metaphor for the beauty playing the kite, which has the artistic effect of pun. From a structural point of view, this scene is described on the surface, but in fact it turns to the description of the kite player. It can be said that it is seamless. According to &quot;Mozhuang Manlu&quot;, the kite player is in her thirties, &quot;elegant and graceful, and full of attitude.&quot; Here, the metaphor of &quot;a flower blooming over Shang Yingying&quot; is not only accurate, but also very interesting. Then the egret seemed to be admiring intentionally to highlight the beauty of the kite player. The two egrets in the poem actually refer to the situation of two guests staring blankly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next film focuses on music. It is written based on the overall melody of the music, so it is called &quot;Ai Zheng&quot;. It is written based on the emotions conveyed by the music, so it is said that &quot;bitter (very, extremely) contains emotions&quot;; it is said &quot;who can be sent to listen&quot;, which means that the music is sad, who Can bear to listen, is written from the perspective of the listener; here we further exaggerate the sadness of the music, saying that the ignorant nature is also moved by it: the mist is restrained by it, and the clouds are faded by it; finally, to sum up, this sadness The music is like the goddess of Xiangshui pouring out her sorrow. Xiang Ling is an allusion to Emperor E and Nvying. The lyrics are written here, pushing the sad and moving music to the highest peak step by step. It seems that such sad and moving music does not belong to the world, but can only come from the hands of gods like the goddess of Xiangshui. At the same time, the phrase &quot;according to the agreement is Xiang Ling&quot; is a metaphor for the beauty of the kite player being like Xiang Ling. At the end of the poem, the sentence &quot;according to the promise&quot; is waiting to be written about the person, but it adopts a hard-to-get approach. Not only does it not describe the person from the front, but it writes that the person playing the kite has drifted away, and only the green mountain peaks are still standing quietly. By the lake, it seems that the sad music is still rippling in the mountains and waters. The two lines &quot;when no one is there, one can count the green peaks&quot; are taken from the poem &quot;Provincial Examination of Xiangling Gusel&quot; written by Qian Qi, a poet from the Tang Dynasty. &quot;At the end of the song, when no one is there, one can count the green peaks on the river&quot;, it is so natural, appropriate and without revealing any trace. It not only has a moving image, but also implicitly inherits the sentence &quot;Yi Yue is Xiang Ling&quot; in structure, combining the upper and lower allusions. &quot;Several peaks are green&quot; echoes the beginning of the poem &quot;It begins to clear after rain in Phoenix Mountain&quot; describing the scene of rain passing through the green mountains, which can be said to be said forever. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/sushi.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Su Shi, (January 8, 1037 - August 24, 1101), also known as Zizhan and Hezhong, also known as Tieguan Taoist and Dongpo layman, known as Su Dongpo and Su Xian in the world. Han nationality, a native of Meishan, Meizhou (Meishan City, Sichuan Province), his ancestral home is Luancheng, Hebei Province, a famous writer, calligrapher, and painter in the Northern Song Dynasty, and a celebrity in water control in history. Su Shi was a literary leader in the mid-Northern Song Dynasty and made great achievements in poetry, lyrics, prose, calligraphy, and painting. His writing is bold and unbridled; his poems are broad in subject matter, fresh and vigorous, good at using exaggerated metaphors, and have a unique style. Together with Huang Tingjian, he is called &quot;Su Huang&quot;; His prose writings are grand and bold. Together with Ouyang Xiu, he is called &quot;Ou Su&quot; and is one of the &quot;Eight Great Masters of Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;. Su Shi was good at calligraphy and one of the &quot;Four Masters of the Song Dynasty&quot;; he was good at literati painting, especially ink bamboo, strange rocks, dead wood, etc. Together with Han Yu, Liu Zongyuan and Ouyang Xiu, they are known as the &quot;Four Great Masters of Eternal Writing&quot;. His works include &quot;Dongpo Seven Collections&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yi Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Dongpo Yuefu&quot;, &quot;Xiaoxiang Bamboo and Stone Picture Scroll&quot;, &quot;Old Trees and Strange Stones Picture Scroll&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:23:10 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长干曲四首·其一 | 崔颢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://feedx.net/read?r=shiwen&d=239221]]><description> &lt;h2>;One of Four Changqian Songs&lt;/h2>;[Tang Dynasty] Cui Hao&lt;div style=&quot;color: #5b4636;&quot;>;Where does the Jun family live? I live in Hengtang. &lt;br />;The boat stopped for a while to ask, maybe he is from the same hometown. &lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Translation and Notes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Translation&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Brother, where is your home? My family lives in Hengtang, Jiankang. &lt;br />;Stop the boat and let me ask you a question. Judging from our accents, I think we are from the same hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notes&lt;/strong>;&lt;br />;Changganxing: the name of Yuefu music. It is a folk song from the Changqianli area, which is south of today&#39;s Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;br />;Jun: An ancient honorific title for men. &lt;br />;Concubine: A modest word for an ancient woman to call herself. &lt;br />;Hengtang: now Jiangning District, Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;br />;Temporarily: for the time being, tentatively. &lt;br />;Excuse me: Please ask. &lt;br />;Or fear: maybe. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Appreciation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;p>; This lyric poem captures a dramatic moment in life, using the technique of line drawing and a few strokes to make the characters, The scene comes to life on the page. It does not use any color to highlight it, just like an ink stroke; it does not need any decoration to highlight it, it is a sketch; it does not rely on any scenery, just like a male and female duet; it cuts off the beginning and the end to highlight the main body, and it is very like a one-act play. The subject matter is ordinary, but the expression technique is extraordinary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A girl who lived in Hengtang heard the voice of a man in a neighboring boat while rafting, so she innocently asked: Are you from the same hometown as me? It is such a simple plot, using only five words &quot;I live in Hengtang&quot; to clarify the speaker&#39;s gender and residence through the heroine&#39;s words. The word &quot;stop boat&quot; is also used to indicate that it is a chance encounter on the water, and the word &quot;jun&quot; is used to indicate that the other person is a male. The narrative in front of the title has been completely omitted using this technique of killing two eggs with one stone. The poem goes straight to the point at the beginning, allowing the heroine to ask questions and appear on the page, and the reader hears her voice as if she sees the person, and there is no sense of being clueless. From the perspective of literary description skills, &quot;co-production of voices and forms&quot; has reached the artistic height of &quot;everything should be included, and there should be no end&quot;, which is both condensed and concentrated yet exquisite and clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In just two words, the poet only used his tone of voice to express the heroine&#39;s voice and smile vividly. He did not write &quot;Ping Ping curled up for more than thirteen years&quot; like Du Mu, nor did he point out &quot;fifteen years ago, weeping in the spring breeze, swinging on the back&quot; like Li Shangyin. He just asked the question and without waiting for the other party&#39;s reply, he eagerly reported that &quot;I live in Hengtang&quot;, which naturally reflected the age of the heroine from the naive and innocent tone. The hero didn&#39;t speak, but the reason why the little girl had the idea that she might be from the same hometown was because she heard the other person&#39;s words with a local accent. Here the poet omits the link of &quot;asking each other because of hearing the sound&quot;. This is a description outside of words, the so-called &quot;writing without writing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This poem also expresses the heroine’s situation and inner loneliness. Just from the fact that she was eager to &quot;stop the boat&quot; to ask questions when she heard the local accent, it can be seen that she left her hometown and stayed in the water, alone and without anyone to talk to. Therefore, I was overjoyed to hear the sounds of my hometown in a foreign land and regard it as my hometown. The poet not only reproduced the heroine&#39;s voice and smile on paper, but also deeply explored her personality and heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The language of the poem is simple and natural, like a folk song. But it has endless artistic appeal. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;About the author&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;center>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://song.gushiwen.cn/authorImg/cuihao.jpg&quot; width=50 %>;&lt;/center>;&lt;/div>;Cui Hao (hào) (704-754), a native of Bianzhou (now Kaifeng City, Henan Province), was a poet of the Tang Dynasty. In the 11th year of Kaiyuan of Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty (AD 723), he became a Jinshi and became the Prime Minister of Taipu Temple. He was appointed as Si Xun Yuan Wai Lang in Tianbaozhong. The most praised piece is his &quot;Yellow Crane Tower&quot;. It is said that Li Bai wrote for it, and once praised it, &quot;Cui Hao wrote a poem on top of the scenery before his eyes.&quot; &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot; contains forty-two poems. He has an upright nature and quick thinking. His works are passionate, bold and magnificent. He is the author of &quot;The Collection of Cui Hao&quot;. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 04:23:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>