<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>经济学家</title><description>经济学人全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.economist.com <item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s second term would be a protectionist nightmare | Finance & economics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2023/10/31/donald-trumps-second-term-would-be-a-protectionist-nightmare]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231014_FND001.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;S&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;后缀永远不如原始版本&lt;/small>;。当原作很糟糕时，我们更有理由害怕下一集。 《关税人第二部》也是如此。在白宫，唐纳德·特朗普提出了更多&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/united-states/2023/10/26/the-republican-party-no-longer- believes-america-is- the-essential-nation&quot;>;对美国进口产品征收的新关税&lt;/a>;比近一个世纪以来任何一位总统都要高。他的理念很简单：“我是关税人。当人们或国家进来掠夺我们国家的巨大财富时，我希望他们为此特权付出代价。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普先生的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist. com/finance-and-economics/2023/10/26/america-and-the-eu-demonstrate-protectionisms-ratchet-effect&quot;>;保护主义&lt;/a>;使美国变得更加贫穷，对出口商几乎没有帮助，并且仍然加剧了通货膨胀愤怒。如果他赢得共和党总统提名（一个可能的结果）并继续赢得选举（势均力敌），他发誓要加大力度。他正在考虑对所有进入美国的产品全面征收 10% 左右的关税。他的计划一举将美国平均关税提高了三倍以上。直接成本已经够糟糕的了，关税就像对消费者征税一样，损害了大多数生产者的利益。然而，他们也会撕裂&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/briefing/2023/10/24/the-overstretched-superpower&quot;>;美国与其盟友的关系&lt;/a>;，并威胁要破坏全球贸易体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;要了解其影响，请回顾一下。 2018 年 1 月 23 日，即特朗普宣誓就职一年后，他开始征收关税，打击洗衣机和太阳能电池板。几个月后，他开始追求铝和钢。几个月后，就是中国货了。到 2021 年，美国关税占该国进口总额的 3%，是特朗普上任时水平的两倍。智库彼得森国际经济研究所的查德·鲍恩 (Chad Bown) 计算，对中国进口商品的关税从 3% 上升至 19%。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemProp=&quot;image&quot; itemType =&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; data-slim=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;meta itemProp=&quot;url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/662/90/ media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png&quot;/>;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/662/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863。 png&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/218/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 200w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/ 300/327/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 300w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/400/436/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 400w，https： //www.economist.com/img/b/600/653/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 600w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/640/697/90/media -assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 640w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/800/871/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 800w，https://www.economist.com /img/b/1000/1089/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863.png 1000w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/1394/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC863。 png 1280w&quot;sizes=&quot;336px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p>;特朗普先生的首要目标是缩小贸易赤字。他认为关税会迫使其他国家屈服，导致它们调整政策以对美国有利。令人印象深刻的是，他宣称“贸易战是好的，而且很容易获胜。”但赤字非但没有缩小，反而扩大了。中国没有屈服，而是将美国的关税提高了两倍。许多盟友也进行了报复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后果是惨淡的。受关税保护的行业获得了好处，获得了更大的市场份额和更丰厚的利润。大多数其他人都遭受了痛苦。两党机构美国国际贸易委员会 (&lt;small>;usitc&lt;/small>;) 发现，受关税困扰的生产商的下游产业面临着更高的投入价格和更低的盈利能力。彼得森研究所估计，钢铁用户实际上为钢铁行业创造的每一个就业岗位额外支付了 65 万美元。研究表明，几乎所有成本都由美国人承担，而不是外国生产商。美国国际贸易委员会发现，对中国征收关税后，美国进口产品的价格几乎一对一上涨。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemProp= “图像”itemType =“https://schema.org/ImageObject”data-slim =“1”>; &lt;meta itemProp =“url”content =“https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/ 662/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png&quot;/>;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/662/90/media-assets/图片/20231104_EPC873.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/218/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 200w,https://www.economist.com/ img/b/300/327/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 300w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/400/436/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 400w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/600/653/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 600w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/640/697 /90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 640w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/800/871/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 800w，https://www .economist.com/img/b/1000/1089/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC873.png 1000w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/1394/90/media-assets/ image/20231104_EPC873.png 1280w&quot; Sizes=&quot;336px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p>;特朗普先生在某一方面无疑取得了成功。他帮助重塑了政治。智库芝加哥全球事务委员会最近的一项调查显示，66% 的美国人认为政府应该限制进口外国商品以保护国内就业，这一比例高于 2018 年的 60%。 2019 年乔·拜登批评关税是一项代价高昂的政策。掌权后，他只让他们退缩了一点。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/leaders/2023/08/10/joe-bidens-china-strategy-is-not-working&quot;>;对中国征收的一系列关税&lt;/a>;保持不变。无论取消关税有什么好处，白宫似乎都担心因对中国表现软弱而产生反弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，拜登先生制定了一项庞大的产业政策，并在超过 1 万美元的补贴的推动下电动汽车、海上风电、半导体等。这是比特朗普更加深思熟虑和深思熟虑的做法，但它看起来仍然可能无法带来制造业复兴，而且成本非常高，而且对美国工厂提供大量补贴，存在对其他国家的歧视。简而言之，这是相当特朗普主义的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemProp=&quot;image&quot; itemType=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; data-slim=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;meta itemProp= “url”内容=“https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/662/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png”/>;&lt;img加载=“lazy”src=“https： //www.economist.com/img/b/608/662/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/218/90 /media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 200w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/300/327/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 300w，https://www.economist .com/img/b/400/436/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 400w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/600/653/90/media-assets/image/ 20231104_EPC864.png 600w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/640/697/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 640w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/ 800/871/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 800w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/1000/1089/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 1000w，https： //www.economist.com/img/b/1280/1394/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC864.png 1280w&quot;sizes=&quot;336px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;事情还能变得更糟吗？如果特朗普赢得 2024 年总统选举，世界可能会发现答案是：“相当多”。 8 月，特朗普先生接受了电视频道福克斯商业频道的采访，采访对象是他的前经济顾问、长期担任媒体人物的拉里·库德洛 (Larry Kudlow)。特朗普先生提出了两个想法。首先，所有向美国销售产品的外国公司都将面临 10% 的关税。其次，如果任何国家对美国任何商品征收高关税，他都会以完全相同的关税进行反击。 “称之为报复，”特朗普先生说。 “互惠”，库德洛先生插话道，用了比较礼貌的标签。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些想法的血统可以追溯到特朗普先生担任总统期间制定政策的思想家，以及正在制定新的、更详细的计划的思想家。特朗普领导下的美国贸易代表罗伯特·莱特希泽(Robert Lighthizer)最近在一本书《没有自由的贸易》中阐述了他的愿景。他的想法之一是对所有进口商品征收普遍关税，以此作为杠杆来使美国的贸易流量达到平衡，从而使该国不再出现巨额赤字。莱特希泽不会将关税限制在 10%。相反，他写道，美国应该“年复一年地逐步提高税率，直到我们实现平衡”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;保守派团体联盟 Project 2025 在今年早些时候出版了一本书，其中列出了特朗普第二届政府期间几乎涉及政府的方方面面。在贸易章节中，特朗普的另一位经济顾问彼得·纳瓦罗对中国和印度等国家对美国商品征收的关税比美国对它们征收的关税还要高表示遗憾，他认为这导致了“对美国农民、牧场主的系统性剥削”。 、制造商和工人”。原则上，互惠可以通过两种方式实现——要么说服其他国家降低关税，要么美国提高自己的关税。纳瓦罗先生对自己的偏好毫无疑问。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h2>;行动，反应&lt;/h2>;&lt;p>;如果特朗普先生如愿，其他国家可能会通过对美国征收关税来回应。普遍关税的扩大将类似于对跨境交易征收巨额税，从而降低国际贸易的吸引力。与此同时，特朗普缩小贸易逆差的希望将与真正决定国家间贸易平衡的经济力量发生冲突。就美国而言，关键因素是该国的低储蓄率，由于消费者支出持续高企和政府赤字扩大，这种情况几乎肯定会持续下去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;特朗普先生指出了他的关税的一个表面优点：它们创造了收入。倡导团体负责任的联邦预算委员会估计，10%的关税在实施的第一个十年内可能会带来高达2.5万亿美元的额外收入，这可以用来减少美国的预算赤字。但这笔钱也可以通过其他方式带来。提高关税仅仅意味着选择它们作为一种高于其他税收的税收，例如更高的收入或遗产税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每种税收都有优点（例如，产生公共收入或阻止不良行为）和缺点（例如，损害增长或给个人带来成本）。关税的弊端很大。印第安纳大学的艾哈迈德·拉什卡里普尔 (Ahmad Lashkaripour) 估计，全球关税战将使美国&lt;小>;GDP&lt;/小>;缩水约 1%。大多数国家的跌幅将接近 3%。对较小的、依赖贸易的经济体的拖累将会更大。关税也是累退的，因为它们对低收入群体造成了两次伤害。他们通过提高消费品价格和收入增加对支出征税，因为许多人在建筑等行业工作，这些行业面临更高的材料成本。如果大部分关税费用转嫁给美国消费者，就像特朗普第一轮关税那样，那么 10% 的关税将使每个美国家庭每年损失约 2,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt; span itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemProp=&quot;image&quot; itemType=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; data-slim=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;meta itemProp=&quot;url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.economist.com /img/b/608/662/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png&quot;/>;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/662 /90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/218/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 200w,https:/ /www.economist.com/img/b/300/327/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 300w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/400/436/90/media-资产/image/20231104_EPC237.png 400w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/600/653/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 600w，https://www.economist.com/ img/b/640/697/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 640w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/800/871/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 800w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/1000/1089/90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 1000w，https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/1394 /90/media-assets/image/20231104_EPC237.png 1280w&quot;sizes=&quot;336px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p>;普遍关税造成的损失将超出其经济影响。第二次世界大战后建立的国际商务及其支持体系允许各国在世界贸易组织 (&lt;small>;wto&lt;/small>;) 中挑战彼此的政策。但自 2019 年以来，世贸组织在争端解决方面的作用一直被削弱，当时特朗普政府阻止了其上诉机构的任命，导致该机构无法做出具有约束力的裁决。结果是，反对特朗普关税的国家将缺乏合适的方式来应对。达特茅斯学院的道格拉斯·欧文表示：“即使在他的第一个任期内，这个体系也会以更加严重的方式崩溃。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登先生并不是一个模范的自由贸易者。他的产业政策建立在大量补贴的基础上，通过刺激对美国的投资，对其他国家不公平。然而，即使有些笨拙，他仍然致力于拼凑供应链和贸易网络，使美国及其盟友更加紧密地联系在一起。这是减少对中国依赖的尝试的一部分，但仍处于起步阶段。特朗普的关税将扭转拜登的进展。这将不再是美国和（有时不情愿的）朋友与中国的对抗，而是美国与世界的对抗。 “如果其他国家感到不安，特朗普会将其视为荣誉勋章。他会说，“看，我正在为你们而战，我们将坚持到底”，”欧文先生预测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普先生将缺乏实施普遍关税的绝对权力。宪法赋予国会监管商业的权力；总统只能在有特殊理由的情况下进行干预。特朗普此前援引了两项法规：贸​​易法第 232 条允许总统限制进口以保护国家安全（对钢铁和铝征收关税的可疑依据）； 301条款允许总统对具有歧视性贸易行为的国家征收关税（对中国采取行动的更合理依据）。但这两项都需要耗时的调查，这将违背特朗普及其顾问迅速采取行政行动的愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一种选择是援引特朗普先生在2020 年，命令将中国社交媒体巨头 TikTok 和微信从美国应用商店下架。在这种情况下，特朗普将宣布国家进入紧急状态，然后宣布征收普遍关税作为回应。美国贸易代表前总法律顾问詹妮弗·希尔曼 (Jennifer Hillman) 表示：“目前尚不清楚具体会宣布何种国家紧急状态。” “也许贸易逆差正在威胁美国的竞争力？或者贸易逆差的规模不可持续？”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;很少有经济学家会赞同这种想法。对进口的需求绝非弱点，而是来自美国的实力。该国在过去半个世纪的经济主导时期一直处于赤字状态。更重要的是，法律专家也会对声明持悲观态度。贸易法领域的资深人士艾伦·沃尔夫表示：“特朗普将把法律朝着从未打算适用的方向弯曲。” “会有法庭挑战，而且很可能会成功。”互惠关税可能看起来更整洁，但即使是试图征收针锋相对的关税也会变得混乱。纳瓦罗先生喜欢指出，美国对汽车的关税仅为 2.5%，而欧盟则征收 10%。他忽略的是，美国长期以来对皮卡车进口征收25%的关税，更不用说对一些进口木材和一些食品征收高额关税了。任何对关税的逐行检查都会发现大量美国关税高于其他国家的例子。 &lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;确实，这是&lt;small>;wto&lt;/small>;的指导原则各国可以就不同产品类别进行谈判，设定保护政治敏感行业的关税，只要它们总体上降低关税。让各国制定独特的关税制度是外交的核心部分。纯粹的互惠会陷入荒谬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治上，特朗普也会面临反对。尽管他拥护保护主义，但共和党内的许多人却不太坚定。以“2025计划”为例，该联盟为特朗普第二任期制定政策计划。除贸易问题外，其所有立场都很明确。其中关于贸易的章节分为两部分：纳瓦罗对关税的呼吁是针对智库竞争企业研究所的肯特·拉斯曼的自由贸易论点。拉斯曼提出了他所谓的“保守的贸易愿景”，呼吁削减关税以降低消费者价格，并制定更雄心勃勃的贸易协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普的国内对手将得到国外的支持。一位美国盟友的贸易官员表示，他的政府在特朗普新政府上任之初就做好了应对关税的准备，他和他的同事们已经在特朗普执政四年期间磨练出了一套限制损害的策略。他们将与享受贸易好处的共和党选区的公司和政界人士合作——从爱荷华州的玉米种植者到田纳西州的汽车工业——并试图说服特朗普先生排除例外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，法律挑战和游说将需要数月甚至更长的时间才能发挥作用。与此同时，全球贸易体系将陷入不确定性。其他政府将对美国征收报复性关税。拜登修复与美国盟友关系的努力将被撕裂。当企业试图评估风险时，它们很可能在投资上变得更加谨慎，这将拖累经济增长。拥有跨境业务的公司将面临缩减开支的压力。依赖贸易的小国将很容易受到伤害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普第一次入主白宫的教训之一是，他大笔一挥就能造成巨大损害，而这种损害是不容易逆转。他的大部分关税仍然在账本上。 &lt;small>;wto&lt;/small>;仍然处于绝育状态。他宣扬的美国优先精神曾经是一种边缘偏好，现在已成为政治主流的一股力量。特朗普连任总统对全球贸易的影响将是严重且持久的。 &lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;>;■&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 03:57:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Bibi Netanyahu is the wrong man in the wrong place | Middle East & Africa]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2023/10/31/bibi-netanyahu-is-the-wrong-man-in-the-wrong-place]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_MAP504.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;F&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;IVE DAYS&lt;/small>; 进入以色列&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. economics.com/middle-east-and-africa/2023/10/28/israels-new-plan-to-encircle-hamas&quot;>;对加沙的地面入侵&lt;/a>;，其装甲营和步兵营正在深化其在加沙的存在加沙地带的北部和中部地区，同时开始造成人员伤亡。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2023/10/30/why-urban-warfare-in-gaza-will-be-bloodier-than-in-iraq “平民死亡人数继续上升到可怕的水平，有报道称，加沙城北部贾巴利亚的几座建筑物遭到轰炸，造成数十名巴勒斯坦人死亡。”以色列声称在同一地点打死了 50 名武装分子，其中包括哈马斯 10 月 7 日袭击的指挥官之一易卜拉欣·比亚里 (Ibrahim Biari)。来自巴勒斯坦的视频似乎证实许多旁观者也死亡。 &lt;/p>;&lt;aside>;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/israel-hamas&quot;>;&lt;i>;阅读我们对以色列和哈马斯之间战争的所有报道&lt;/i>;&lt;/ a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;以色列境内 &lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.economist.com/briefing/2023/10/25/israels-prime-minister-and-its-army-are-damagingly-divided&quot;>;政治斗争正在因战争的进行而激烈进行、其后果以及谁做出决定。其核心人物是本雅明·内塔尼亚胡（Binyamin Netanyahu），他是以色列政坛二十多年来的主导人物，但现在他可能在错误的时间、错误的地点成为了错误的人选。人们普遍认为他已经失去了以色列公众的信任，并且正在努力有效地管理战时内阁。他也是提出两国解决方案的令人难以置信的候选人，美国隐含地要求美国以回报其对攻势的支持。 10 月 31 日，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯 (Antony Blinken) 向国会表示，他支持“复兴”的巴勒斯坦权力机构 (&lt;small>;PA&lt;/small>;) 在以色列撤离后在国际社会的帮助下管理加沙。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从舆论入手。许多公众认为内塔尼亚胡先生对导致哈马斯袭击的失败负有责任。尽管军队和情报负责人有罪，但他们仍然比他更受欢迎。根据最近的一项调查，一半的以色列人相信以色列国防军（&lt;small>;IDF&lt;/small>;）指挥官能够在战争中领导国家，只有五分之一的人同样信任总理和将军。只有极少数人更信任内塔尼亚胡先生。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这激怒了内塔尼亚胡先生，加剧了第二个问题，即以色列战时内阁内部的分歧。出席会议的官员描述了一种“痛苦”的气氛。内塔尼亚胡先生开始公开攻击他的将军：地面部队进入加沙的第二天，他在 X（以前的 Twitter）上指责军事情报部门和辛贝特安全机构负责人在 10 月 7 日袭击之前做出的评估：“哈马斯被吓倒并寻求妥协。”在战时内阁成员公开批评后，他删除了该帖子。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;分歧正在影响军事决策。他们解释了为什么&lt;小>;以色列国防军&lt;/小>;士兵在加沙地带附近的集结地待了两周，直到下达进入命令。一位高级官员表示：“军队遭受了严重打击，但现在已经站稳了脚跟。” “政府其他部门却不能这么说。”以色列宣称的目标仍然是摧毁哈马斯的军事能力并推翻其在加沙的政府。但如果这些目标实现了，将军们就需要为第二天的权力真空做好准备。谁能确保哈马斯不会卷土重来并承担起对饱受战争蹂躏地区超过200万平民的责任？安全负责人抱怨说，他们没有收到政府关于此事的指示。以色列动员了 360,000 名预备役军人，经济损失巨大，战争规划者需要知道其中一些人何时可以恢复平民生活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内讧也阻碍了针对以色列公民的救援计划。数以万计的家庭被迫离开加沙边境周围和北部的社区，真主党一直从黎巴嫩炮击以色列。地方议会领导人抱怨说，他们在安排临时住房方面没有得到政府的任何援助。协调救援的公务员工作组组长刚刚被任命。财政部长贝扎莱尔·斯莫特里奇（Bezalel Smotrich）是极右翼宗教犹太复国主义党的领导人，他试图将救援计划的资金转移到约旦河西岸的犹太人定居点和其他特殊利益集团。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内塔尼亚胡先生最大的弱点可能是第三个问题：他已成为对两国解决方案顽固敌意的象征，而以色列以某种形式对其做出的承诺作为任何“一天”的一部分都至关重要。之后”计划。这是为了维持美国的支持并维持与一些阿拉伯国家建立外交关系的亚伯拉罕协议。在缺乏明确的政府指示的情况下，以色列国防机构正在制定所有计划。它首选的解决方案是让巴勒斯坦权力机构最终返回加沙，该地区一直由巴勒斯坦领导层控制，直到 2007 年哈马斯政变为止。巴勒斯坦领导层明确表示，任何返回加沙的行为都需要以色列保证恢复停滞的外交进程，以实现加沙的和平。两国解决方案。尽管如此，内塔尼亚胡先生联盟中的一些极右翼成员坚决反对与&lt;small>;巴勒斯坦权力机构&lt;/small>;进行任何合作。 10 月 30 日，斯莫特里奇先生宣布，他将冻结以色列代表&lt;小>;巴勒斯坦权力机构&lt;/小>;征收的税收收入转移，因为他声称以色列高级官员支持哈马斯袭击。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内塔尼亚胡先生还能存活多久？在 10 月 7 日的袭击发生之前的好几个月里，针对政府及其非自由立法议程的广泛抗议活动已经发生。这些已被暂停，他的联盟也暂停了“与战争无关”的立法。来自内部的叛乱煽动尚不构成威胁，因为推翻内塔尼亚胡先生需要在议会中获得多数席位，以选出替代总理。在以色列支离破碎的政治体系中，目前没有其他候选人能够获得如此支持。战时内阁成员包括领导反对党第二大党的本尼·甘茨。与甘茨关系密切的人士表示，他“为了国家利益”而忍住了挫败感。目前，内塔尼亚胡先生仍在坚持。以色列有能力在加沙发动战争，甚至可能成功推翻哈马斯。但在以色列历史上最具考验的时刻之一，负责人对接下来发生的事情没有答案。 &lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;>;■&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:57:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why is Washington, DC so violent? | United States]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/united-states/2023/10/30/why-is-washington-dc-so-violent]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231028_USP002.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;T&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;尽管他拥有&lt;/small>;空手道黑带，但三个武装男孩10 月 2 日，来自德克萨斯州的国会议员亨利·奎利亚尔 (Henry Cuellar) 在他的海军造船厂公寓外受到戴着滑雪面罩的威胁，他迅速交出了丰田跨界车的钥匙。这是美国首都今年发生的第 754 起劫车事件，自 1 月份以来每天大约发生三起劫车事件。这并不是第一次针对国会议员的袭击。 2 月，明尼苏达州的安吉·克雷格 (Angie Craig) 在国会大厦附近的大楼电梯里英勇地击退了一名掐住她脖子的男子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年该地区的暴力犯罪增加了 40%。枪支泛滥已将数十起小纠纷演变成杀戮：四分之一个世纪以来，首次有超过 200 人在 10 月 1 日之前被谋杀。这与&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/united-states/2023/08/09/murder-rates-are-falling-in-a-majority-of-american-cities&quot;>;全国趋势&lt;/a>;。在其他地方，covid-19 带来的犯罪流行正在消退。智库刑事司法委员会发现，在 30 个公开谋杀案数量的城市中，截至 7 月，凶杀案比 2022 年上半年减少了 202 起，下降了 9.4%。在亚特兰大、洛杉矶、费城和罗切斯特，谋杀率下降了 20% 以上。那么，为什么自由世界的首都将迎来几十年来最糟糕的一年呢？&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;p>;因为哥伦比亚特区是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2021/03/19/why-is-washington-dc-not-a-state “联邦政府不是一个州&lt;/a>;，对其事务拥有非同寻常的发言权。三月份，国会推翻了区议会通过的华盛顿刑法修正案，其中包括取消了对劫车的强制性最低刑罚。这是三十年来国会第一次废除地方法律。参议院少数党领袖米奇·麦康奈尔(Mitch McConnell)警告说，该地区“软弱犯罪”的领导人需要“成人监督”。夏末，三名共和党国会议员提出了一项法案，要求解散市议会和市长办公室，并给予联邦立法者对该地区的自由支配权。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地方政府肯定对&lt;small>;DC&lt;/small>;的一些问题负有责任。华盛顿犯罪实验室是负责处理法医数据的地区机构，在多次试图掩盖自己所犯错误后，于 2021 年春季失去了认证。关闭后前九个月的数据显示，在犯罪现场收集的 &lt;small>;DNA&lt;/small>; 样本中，只有 7% 得到了分析。这使得一些案件无法起诉。两年半后，该实验室目前正在寻求重新认证。但即使恢复工作，华盛顿首席检察官马修·格雷夫斯预计，法院是否可以再次承认该实验室科学家为法医专家，将引发大量诉讼。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，让众议院管理该选区并不是什么神奇的解决办法（特别是考虑到众议院本身就有扰乱行为的倾向）。事实上，目前联邦政府的参与程度似乎正在阻碍华盛顿打击犯罪的能力。刑事司法研究表明，人们之所以不敢犯罪，并不是因为惩罚的严厉程度，而是因为惩罚是否确定和迅速。联邦政府对该地区的控制使两者都变得更加复杂。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;国会大厦犯罪&lt;/h2>;&lt;p>;在华盛顿，与任何其他美国城市不同，&lt;小>;美国&lt;/小>;律师负责起诉地方和联邦犯罪（并捍卫联邦政府）民事案件）。该办公室的人格分裂意味着必须对资源进行配给。例如，2021 年 1 月 6 日之后，前&lt;小>;美国&lt;/小>;律师将工作人员从当地案件中撤出，以帮助起诉袭击国会大厦的叛乱分子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，该办公室拒绝起诉 67%当地逮捕的人数（重罪案件的 53%），高于 2016 年的 31%。这一数字远高于其他城市：据《华盛顿邮报》报道，去年费城检察官仅撤销了 4% 的案件，库克县，其中包括芝加哥（14%）和底特律（33%）。 Such a high dismissal rate could well be discouraging police from making arrests. And though it could suggest triaging, where prosecutors prioritise slam-dunk cases, the office&#39;s win-rate did not budge as they slimmed down their docket. That sends a message: in America&#39;s capital, committing a crime may not have consequences. &lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Because there is no state apparatus, district judges who hear local cases are nominated by the president and approved by the Senate, just like federal judges. Since presidents are eager to fill circuit-court posts across the country to increase their political influence, Washington&#39;s judges get sidelined. As a result the district has 12 vacancies and 7 judges awaiting Senate confirmation. That is unusual: in Pennsylvania just two posts are unfilled, in neighbouring Maryland one. With nearly one-third of the bench empty, fewer cases go to trial. The backlog is not only an injustice to defendants waiting for their cases to be heard from jail, but also pulls the punch of a quick conviction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More independence from the feds would probably help the district get back on track. But local leaders will be trusted only when they prove they can reduce violence. In July the council passed an emergency safety bill that raised the charge for firing a gun from a misdemeanour to a felony and made it easier to lock up violent offenders before trial. After Mr Cuellar was attacked they voted to extend that bill for another 90 days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week the mayor introduced another one, to crack down on loitering, wearing dodgy masks and scheming to steal from stores. Congress ought to commend them for it. Instead House Republicans are doing what they do. Their latest appropriations bill includes a provision to allow out-of-state gun-owners to carry concealed weapons in the district. It is hard to imagine how that will help. &lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;>;■&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:27:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Steven Simon thinks that Israel may be able to avoid a regional escalation | By Invitation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/by-invitation/2023/10/31/steven-simon-thinks-that-israel-may-be-able-to-avoid-a-regional-escalation]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_BID002.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;O&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;N OCTOBER 7TH&lt;/small>; Hamas showed that it was true to itself by abandoning its periodic ceasefires and skirmishes with Israel and embracing Götterdämmerung. Perhaps it expected its murderous attacks to spark a regional conflict that would bring Israel to its knees, with Palestinians battered but triumphant. But this motivation seems unlikely, and we may never know. Regardless, America, Israel and key Arab states such as Egypt and Saudi Arabia must now plan for the day after, if only to avoid the prolonged immiseration of Gaza&#39;s population and a resumption of regional hostilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas&#39;s problem is that even a widened conflict including Iran, Hizbullah and a motley collection of smaller Iran-backed militias would not overcome the fundamental power disparity between Israel and its foes, let alone Palestinians. Moreover, both Iran and Hizbullah, its most powerful proxy, have reasons to avoid escalation. &lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hizbullah has refrained from engaging in a full-blown conflict with Israel on its northern border since the Hamas attack, though there have been exchanges of fire. Iran&#39;s leaders and senior commanders have reportedly concluded that there is not much they can do, apart from tacitly permitting their country&#39;s proxies to act as they see fit. These prevarications have given Israel time to mobilise an immense army, deploy a large part of it to the Lebanese border, evacuate local towns and buttress its air defences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;True, to dismiss the risk of escalation because it would not serve the alleged interests of Hizbullah or Iran could be just another example of the mirror-imaging&lt;!-- -->; and wishful thinking that plague policymakers of all stripes—and which contributed to the Israeli blunders that opened the door to Hamas on October 7th. Hamas may yet find fellowship in its self-immolation. Nonetheless, compared to Hamas, Iran and Hizbullah are conventional creatures and can therefore be deterred by the prospect of a punitive Israeli response. Hamas clearly can not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hence Israel&#39;s conclusion that Hamas must go. This has entailed the sudden reversal of entrenched policy. As Israel&#39;s prime minister, Binyamin Netanyahu, has explained, Hamas was an essential tool in Israel&#39;s effort to split the Palestinian national movement, weakening the more moderate, West Bank-based Palestinian Authority (PA). Hamas functioned, perversely, as the loyal opposition to Likud governments. Even Israel&#39;s ultra-right was on board; Bezalel Smotrich, the hardline finance minister, has described the PA as a burden but Hamas as an “asset”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scale and sadism of Hamas&#39;s rampage on October 7th has made a return to the old arrangement unthinkable for now. Although Hamas is not Islamic State, its participants in the atrocities were weaned on IS&#39;s gruesome videos, which had redefined the culture of jihad. Whatever the precise inspiration, the resulting performance of Wagnerian apocalypticism has now reached its culminating acts of fire and purification. If past were prologue, this process would be interrupted within weeks as the marginal costs exceeded the returns for both sides. This time, the past is merely the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s friends, especially America, have expressed concern about its war aims. The Biden administration must worry about regional escalation, and about its own reputation as Palestinian civilian casualties grow. It must also fear an all-out push by Israel that fails to eliminate Hamas but pulverises Gaza and ends in a comprehensive Israeli blockade, a traumatised population, a public-health crisis, warlord rule and a lost generation of Palestinian youth. The question of who rules Gaza if Hamas is toppled, or even crippled, is therefore urgent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are good reasons to doubt Israel&#39;s ability to dislodge Hamas as the power in Gaza. Its army is not battle-hardened, urban combat is more gruelling than open warfare—and Hamas will have prepared the battlefield to compound the challenge. Toppling Hamas could require a lengthy occupation of Gaza, raising the spectre of an insurgency amid the ruins. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the other hand, Israel&#39;s armed forces are powerful and highly motivated, the war has unified a citizenry riven by political differences just weeks ago, and there is something like a consensus over the need to remove Hamas. Toppling the group—not as a social movement, but as a government and army—is thus at least a plausible aim.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Victory, however, could prove pyrrhic—not least if there is no government to replace Hamas. Israel will need to hand responsibility for Gaza to a competent, temporary steward as soon as is practicable. Such a transitional government will have to be formed of a coalition of states and perceived as legitimate and effective, as well as being acceptable to Israel. It will need to be authorised and equipped by the UN to defend itself while administering Gaza&#39;s urgent needs, and it must be ready to enter the territory when the shooting stops. And as it restores order, it must also prepare the ground for reassertion of Palestinian rule through elections in both Gaza and the West Bank. Planning for this will require time and complex diplomacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PA, however, is run by a president elected in 2005 and legislature elected in 2006. It is corrupt and widely perceived as a tool of Israeli occupation. It is incapable of stemming Israel&#39;s building of settlements in the West Bank and their occupants&#39; attacks on Palestinians. Any expectations of a role for the PA in governing a post-conflict Gaza are unrealistic unless these conditions change. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Furthermore, Arab states&#39; participation in a transitional administration will hinge on the promise of Israeli concessions on the West Bank, including a halt to the building or expansion of settlements, curbing violence by settlers and the transfer of some land from mixed Palestinian and Israeli control to the PA. No long-term solution to the problem of Gaza is possible without this. It will require the application of a defibrillator to the peace process, as well as the resumption of Israeli-Saudi normalisation talks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the many obstacles to this approach, Israel&#39;s willingness to make concessions is the most formidable. How formidable will depend on what kind of government emerges in Jerusalem after the war. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bernard Avishai, the author of “The Tragedy of Zionism”, believes that “the combination of corruption, fecklessness and extremism of the hard-right government—and especially Netanyahu himself—will be expelled like a hairball from the cat.”&lt;!-- -->; A darker view is that the terrible costs of the conflict, global opposition to Israel&#39;s military campaign, tinged as it is in places with antisemitism, the awfulness of October 7th and intensified mistrust of Arabs will push Israelis to continue backing hard-right rule. If so, the dystopia won&#39;t just envelop the Gaza Strip.&lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;>;■&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;i>;Steven Simon is the professor of practice in Middle Eastern studies at the Jackson School of International Relations, University of Washington, senior research fellow at the Quincy Institute for Responsible Statecraft and the author of “Grand Delusion: The Rise and Fall of American Ambition in the Middle East” (2023).&lt;/i>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:27:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Senegal’s President Macky Sall on democracy in a coup-prone region | Podcasts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/31/senegals-president-macky-sall-on-democracy-in-a-coup-prone-region]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_PDP502.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;A&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;s country after&lt;/small>; country in the Sahel has fallen prey to coups, President Macky Sall&#39;s Senegal seemed an outpost of stability. Yet our correspondent finds him &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2023/10/26/senegals-president-asks-if-democracy-can-work-in-africas-coup-belt&quot; data-tegid=&quot;7dehifbd6377tecii99s80rqf1reqif9&quot;>;less than sanguine&lt;/a>; about democracy in the region. We sift through what little is known about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/1843/2023/10/20/hamass-deadly-phantom-the-man-behind-the-attacks&quot; data-tegid=&quot;vlnic6gdbvcn55t9m8k43hdn29u51lap&quot;>;“the Phantom”&lt;/a>;, the Hamas fighter behind the attacks in Israel (11:57). And eating &lt;i>;steak frites&lt;/i>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/europe/2023/10/26/the-french-debate-the-future-of-steak-frites&quot; data-tegid=&quot;1t02dgqeidj1op37d2rl24hp2ipfcsk6&quot;>;gets political&lt;/a>; in France (19:47). Runtime: 23 min&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;div>;&lt;figcaption>;Listen to this podcast&lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/div>;&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;audio-player&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; src=&quot;https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/theintelligencepodcast/e/6540cf36e72d5000124303ae/media.mp3?tk=eyJ1aWQiOiJ0b20iLCJ0ayI6ImZHeExMd3dDIiwiYWRzIjpmYWxzZSwic3BvbnMiOmZhbHNlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;amp;sig=4u2WHFPsahk_eVRYouJfW5rTGQj8afMWRL6D26dTFdM&quot; title=&quot;The Intelligence&quot; controlsList=&quot;nodownload&quot;>;&lt;p>;Your browser does not support the &amp;lt;audio&amp;gt; element.&lt;/p>;&lt;/audio>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Listen on: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-intelligence-from-the-economist/id1449631195&quot;>;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a>; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://open.spotify.com/show/12zKAMNyS2GNentUzxq9QN&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sign up for Economist Podcasts+ now and get 50% off your subscription with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://subscribenow.economist.com/podcasts-plus?purchaseRedirect=economist.com%2Faudio%2Fpodcasts%2Fonboarding%3Fpodcast%3Dthe-intelligence&quot;>;offer that ends today&lt;/a>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you&#39;re already a subscriber to &lt;i>;The Economist&lt;/i>;, you&#39;ll have full access to all our shows as part of your subscription.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For more information about how to access Economist Podcasts+, please visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://myaccount.economist.com/s/article/What-is-Economist-Podcasts&quot;>;FAQs page&lt;/a>; or watch our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48TlDbL-4vU&quot;>;video&lt;/a>; explaining how to link your account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Podcast transcripts are available upon request at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;01716e6562607275724164626e6f6e6c6872752f626e6c&quot;>;[email&amp;#160;protected]&lt;/a>;. We are committed to improving accessibility even further and are exploring new ways to expand our podcast transcript offering. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:57:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How strong is Taiwan’s silicon shield? | Podcasts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/31/how-strong-is-taiwans-silicon-shield]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_PDP503.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;N&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;o industry matters&lt;/small>; more to Taiwan than chipmaking. That&#39;s because semiconductors power everything—from mobile phones to electric cars—and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/special-report/2023/03/06/taiwans-dominance-of-the-chip-industry-makes-it-more-important&quot;>;Taiwan makes the most advanced ones in the world&lt;/a>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;div>;&lt;figcaption>;Listen to this podcast&lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/div>;&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;audio-player&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; src=&quot;https://sphinx.acast.com/p/open/s/633ebf6dfc7f5a0012acdc97/e/6541441a30d67500126a312c/media.mp3?tk=eyJ1aWQiOiJ0b20iLCJ0ayI6IlFQRW5LbjZqIiwiYWRzIjpmYWxzZSwic3BvbnMiOmZhbHNlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwcml2YXRlIn0=&amp;amp;sig=hp5Y8ut5p7hskz-Wc5uYTDlV8JaigdAZ6vXtcsMaXy8&quot; title=&quot;Drum Tower&quot; controlsList=&quot;nodownload&quot;>;&lt;p>;Your browser does not support the &amp;lt;audio&amp;gt; element.&lt;/p>;&lt;/audio>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s chips also give the world an economic reason &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/special-report/2023-03-11&quot;>;to protect the island from a Chinese invasion&lt;/a>;. But now America and China are competing to control the supply of these sophisticated chips. And that puts Taiwan in the middle of the two superpowers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the second episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/24/what-does-taiwan-want&quot;>;a four-part series on the future of Taiwan&lt;/a>;, David Rennie, &lt;i>;The Economist&lt;/i>;&#39;s Beijing bureau chief, and Alice Su, our senior China correspondent, ask whether semiconductors could save Taiwan from attack.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henry Hsieh, a former Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company engineer, and his wife, Lin Cai-wen, explain the part Taiwanese people played in China&#39;s economic growth. CC Chen, Taiwan&#39;s deputy minister of economic affairs, explains how the island&#39;s trade policy has changed as the threat from China has grown. Runtime: 53 min&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;i>;This is a subscriber-only episode. If you&#39;re already a subscriber to The Economist, you have full access to all our shows as part of your subscription. For more information about how to access Economist Podcasts+, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://myaccount.economist.com/s/article/What-is-Economist-Podcasts&quot;>;our FAQs page&lt;/a>; or watch&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48TlDbL-4vU&quot;>; our video&lt;/a>; explaining how to link your account.&lt;/i>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:57:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What is Hizbullah? | Films]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/films/2023/10/27/what-is-hizbullah]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231027_FLP001.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;F&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;or the past&lt;/small>; couple of weeks Hizbullah and Israel have been exchanging fire across the Israel-Lebanon border. In 2006 the militia group went to war with Israel in response to Israel&#39;s ground operation in Gaza. Now there&#39;s speculation that it might do so again. What is Hizbullah, and how did they become an important force?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;iframe height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xZ_BZ-knasU?enablejsapi=1&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 12:57:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to get the lying out of hiring | Business]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/business/2023/10/30/how-to-get-the-lying-out-of-hiring]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_WBD001.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;H&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;iring processes&lt;/small>; can be thought of as a battle between candour and dishonesty. You might imagine this is a simple fight between truth-seeking firms and self-promoting candidates, and to a certain extent it is. But companies themselves are prone to bend reality out of shape in ways that are self-defeating. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Start with the obvious culprits: job applicants. The point of a &lt;small>;CV&lt;/small>; or a LinkedIn profile is to massage reality into the most appealing shape possible. Everyone beyond a certain level of experience is a transformational leader personally responsible for generating millions in revenue; the world economy would be about 15 times bigger than it actually is if all such claims were true. The average Briton spends four and a half hours a day watching &lt;small>;TV&lt;/small>; and online video. But the average job candidate uses their spare time only for worthy purposes, like volunteering in soup kitchens or teaching orphans to code. &lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The cover letter is so open in its insincerity (“When I saw the advertisement for this job, I almost fainted with excitement”) that people are starting not to bother with it. At the interview stage one task facing the firm&#39;s recruiters is to winkle out the truth of what a person actually contributed to a project. Those hoary questions about a candidate&#39;s weaknesses and failures are there for a reason; no one will bring them up unprompted. Cognitive and behavioural tests are useful in part because they are harder for applicants to game. &lt;/p>;&lt;aside>;&lt;p>;In our new seven-part podcast series, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/02/introducing-boss-class-from-the-economist&quot;>;Boss Class&lt;/a>;, our Bartleby columnist searches for the secrets to being a better manager. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/23/2-out-of-office&quot;>;Episode two&lt;/a>; looks at hybrid working and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/30/3-testing-testing&quot;>;episode three&lt;/a>; explores how to get hiring right.&lt;/p>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;p>;But a tendency to stretch the truth infects companies as well as applicants. The typical firm will write a job description that invariably describes the work environment as fast-paced and innovative, and then lays out a set of improbable requirements for the “ideal candidate”, someone who almost by definition does not exist. Sometimes—as when ads demand more years of experience in a programming language than that program has existed for—these requirements include an ability to go back and alter the course of history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industrialised hiring processes can often reward mindless exaggeration. Services that scan your résumé when you are making an application mark you down if your &lt;small>;CV&lt;/small>; does not match the keywords that appear in the original job advertisement. The message is clear: to get through to the next stage, you have to contort yourself to meet corporate expectations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Substance can matter less to recruiters than form. One software engineer claims to have got a 90%-plus response rate with a spoof &lt;small>;CV&lt;/small>; which showed apparent spells at Microsoft and Instagram but also boasted, among other things, that she had increased team-bonding by organising the company potato-sack race and “spread Herpes &lt;small>;STD&lt;/small>; to 60% of intern team”. References are so prone to inaccuracy that many firms have a policy of not giving them, fearing legal action from defamed candidates or deceived employers.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Too few firms offer an accurate account of what a position actually involves. Tracey Franklin, the chief &lt;small>;HR&lt;/small>; officer for Moderna, a fast-growing drugmaker—and an interviewee in this week&#39;s episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/30/3-testing-testing&quot;>;Boss Class&lt;/a>;, our new podcast—is a fan of “realistic job previews” (&lt;small>;RJP&lt;/small>;s). These are meant to give prospective recruits a genuine sense of the negatives and positives of the job, as well as a clear idea of the company&#39;s corporate culture. One effective tactic is to lay out, in text or video, what a typical day in the role would look like. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such honesty can be its own reward. Longstanding research suggests that &lt;small>;RJP&lt;/small>;s lead to lower turnover and higher employee satisfaction. A paper in 2011 by David Earnest of Towson University and his co-authors concluded that favourable perceptions of the organisation&#39;s honesty are the best explanation for why. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incentives on both sides of the hiring process lean naturally towards glossing reality. If candidates were to give genuinely truthful answers (“I have a habit of making basic but calamitous errors”), many would rule themselves out of jobs. And if firms were to give a warts-and-all description of themselves, many would end up deterring good applicants. But a process designed to uncover the truth about job applicants would run a lot more smoothly if firms were also honest about themselves. &lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;>;■&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Read more from Bartleby, our columnist on management and work:&lt;/b>;&lt;br/>;&lt;i>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/business/2023/10/23/is-being-a-leader-really-sexier-than-being-a-manager&quot;>;Would you rather be a manager or a leader?&lt;/a>; (Oct 26th)&lt;/i>;&lt;br/>;&lt;i>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/business/2023/10/19/how-big-is-the-role-of-luck-in-career-success&quot; data-tegid=&quot;d3efu6u4qsm5m90unal3abbrigbmfpb0&quot;>;How big is the role of luck in career success?&lt;/a>; (Oct 19th)&lt;/i>;&lt;br/>;&lt;i>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/business/2023/10/12/trialling-the-two-day-workweek&quot; data-tegid=&quot;d9sk44t7q84flauajuu1tlu4gork0aie&quot;>;Trialling the two-day workweek&lt;/a>; (Oct 12th)&lt;/i>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;i>;Also: How the Bartleby column &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/column-names&quot;>;got its name&lt;/a>;&lt;/i>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 06:27:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A vision for the Palestinians after the war | Middle East & Africa]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2023/10/30/a-vision-for-the-palestinians-after-the-war]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_MAP502.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;H&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;e iS OFTEN&lt;/small>; mentioned as a possible future leader of the Palestinians. But in a lengthy discussion with &lt;i>;The Economist&lt;/i>; from his home in Abu Dhabi on October 27th Muhammad Dahlan, a former security chief for the Palestinian Authority (&lt;small>;PA&lt;/small>;) from Gaza, denied he wanted the role.在这次采访中，达赫兰先生自管理加沙的伊斯兰组织哈马斯于 10 月 7 日袭击以色列以来首次接受西方媒体采访，但他确实阐述了他对加沙战争后的愿景。 It was one of surprising hope, amid the horrors of the fighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;aside>;&lt;p>;Read more on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/israel-hamas&quot;>;war between Israel and Hamas.&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Born in an impoverished refugee camp in the south of the Gaza Strip, Mr Dahlan rose through the ranks of Yasser Arafat&#39;s Fatah movement, and spent much of the 1980s in Israeli prisons where he learned to speak fluent Hebrew. He was the Palestinian national security adviser when the &lt;small>;PA &lt;/small>;lost control of Gaza to Hamas in 2007. He has connections on all sides of the conflict. He has enemies in Fatah—notably among the inner circle of Mahmoud Abbas, the&lt;small>; PA&lt;/small>;&#39;s embattled and ageing president. 2016 年，巴勒斯坦法院缺席审判他犯有腐败罪。但他也有很多朋友。他在加沙南部的汗尤尼斯难民营长大，与哈马斯现任领导层的大部分成员一起长大，因此可以与这个伊斯兰组织进行对话。 He also speaks warmly of his relations with some senior Israeli figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mr Dahlan rubbishes the suggestion that once the war ends any one individual could be shipped in to run Gaza.相反，他建议实行两年过渡期，由加沙和西岸的技术官僚领导政府。他认为，这可能会使经过十多年内讧的巴勒斯坦领土重新统一。之后，他设想在巴勒斯坦国的基础上举行议会选举，当时边界尚未确定。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All Palestinian political factions should be allowed to participate, including Hamas (fears of a Hamas victory have been one of Israel&#39;s main reasons for blocking Palestinian elections in recent years).他认为，即使在这场战争之后，未经加沙同意也不可能对其进行治理：“哈马斯不会消失。” He believes that Arab states such as Egypt, Jordan, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates (&lt;small>;UAE&lt;/small>;) could support such a body. This Palestinian state should then be internationally recognised, including by Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div id=&quot;econ-2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;More immediately Mr Dahlan, who has recently returned from Egypt and has close ties with Abdel-Fattah al-Sisi, Egypt&#39;s president, pours scorn on the idea of allowing refugees into the Sinai peninsula as a way to relieve the crisis in Gaza. “谁将承担这一被阿拉伯人民指责帮助以色列取代巴勒斯坦人的历史责任？” he says, noting that the mass displacement of Palestinians into Egypt would create serious national-security issues for the government in Cairo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A parliamentary system as envisaged by Mr Dahlan would yield a prime minister to lead the Palestinians.这将意味着取消目前由阿巴斯先生担任的主席职务。达兰先生赞成这种转变。他坚称，任何一个人都能解决巴勒斯坦问题是一种“幻想”：“英雄时代已随阿拉法特一起逝去。”在回应有关他可能是以色列在战后管理加沙的传言时，他拒绝接受有关他将在战斗结束后收拾残局的建议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And yet he firmly sets out his credentials for leadership;他很了解加沙，并为巴勒斯坦事业奋斗了40年，但他也声称了解以色列人。近年来，他已成为阿布扎比强大统治者穆罕默德·本·扎耶德的亲密顾问。 He claims to have channelled around $50ma year from the &lt;small>;UAE&lt;/small>; into Gaza. He has also built a network of support in the West Bank&#39;s refugee camps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To many, the Palestinian national movement has never looked in worse shape than in the days since Hamas&#39;s attack, and Israel&#39;s retaliation. The long-standing divisions between the leaderships in the West Bank and in Gaza have only worsened, and international backers of the &lt;small>;PA&lt;/small>; have announced reviews of its funding. Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas and the &lt;small>;PA&lt;/small>; seems weaker than ever. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It would be easy to argue that the Palestinians are further away than ever from a state of their own.然而达兰先生却出人意料地充满希望。即使在战争期间，他也看到了巴勒斯坦事业的机会。他说，上个月对巴勒斯坦人来说发生了巨大的变化。 “三个月前，希望为零。三个月前谁提到巴勒斯坦事业？没有人……现在每个人都在谈论我们的痛苦。” &lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;>;■&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 06:27:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel’s ground offensive in Gaza points to a grinding encirclement | Podcasts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/30/israels-ground-offensive-in-gaza-points-to-a-grinding-encirclement]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231104_PDP501.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;T&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;he long-anticipated&lt;/small>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2023/10/28/israels-new-plan-to-encircle-hamas&quot; data-tegid=&quot;3dbp02udc2avnqkjrrch8bv0f8i01re6&quot;>;invasion&lt;/a>; is not the expected blitzkrieg; we ask how a longer, more cautious war will be fought. Kemal Ataturk is still wildly popular a century after he founded modern Turkey—so instead of undoing his legacy, President Recep Tayyip Erdogan is simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/europe/2023/10/26/instead-of-undoing-ataturks-legacy-recep-tayyip-erdogan-has-claimed-it&quot; data-tegid=&quot;euo6jlv2tktemiofejq7mcsj3t3rlee0&quot;>;claiming it&lt;/a>; (10:57). And an ode to Canada&#39;s “long dash”, a time-marking tradition that has now gone silent (21:15). Runtime: 28 min&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;div>;&lt;figcaption>;Listen to this podcast&lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/div>;&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;audio-player&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; src=&quot;https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/theintelligencepodcast/e/653f87518f6e5f0012628f5d/media.mp3?tk=eyJ1aWQiOiJ0b20iLCJ0ayI6ImZHeExMd3dDIiwiYWRzIjpmYWxzZSwic3BvbnMiOmZhbHNlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;amp;sig=K1Kr8IVnN1e-uqaxEd0U6CnnrNnDJgPiGLKDs_9n7P4&quot; title=&quot;The Intelligence&quot; controlsList=&quot;nodownload&quot;>;&lt;p>;Your browser does not support the &amp;lt;audio&amp;gt; element.&lt;/p>;&lt;/audio>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Listen on: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-intelligence-from-the-economist/id1449631195&quot;>;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a>; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://open.spotify.com/show/12zKAMNyS2GNentUzxq9QN&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://subscribenow.economist.com/podcasts-plus?purchaseRedirect=economist.com%2Faudio%2Fpodcasts%2Fonboarding%3Fpodcast%3Dthe-intelligence&quot;>;Economist Podcasts+&lt;/a>; now and get 50% off your subscription with our limited-time offer. You will not be charged until Economist Podcasts+ launches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you&#39;re already a subscriber to &lt;i>;The Economist&lt;/i>;, you&#39;ll have full access to all our shows as part of your subscription.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For more information about how to access Economist Podcasts+, please visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://myaccount.economist.com/s/article/What-is-Economist-Podcasts&quot;>;FAQs page&lt;/a>; or watch our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48TlDbL-4vU&quot;>;video that explains&lt;/a>; how to link your account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Podcast transcripts are available upon request at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;ed9d82898e8c9e999ead888e82838280849e99c38e8280&quot;>;[email&amp;#160;protected]&lt;/a>;. We are committed to improving accessibility even further and are exploring new ways to expand our podcast transcript offering.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:27:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3. Testing, testing | Podcasts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2023/10/30/3-testing-testing]]><description> &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.weserv.nl/?url=www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/media-assets/image/20231014_PDP511.jpg&quot;/>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;>;I&lt;/span>;&lt;small>;t is the most&lt;/small>; important decision a manager can make. How do you increase your chances of hiring the right people? Tracey Franklin, Moderna&#39;s human-resources chief, tells Andrew Palmer how the company scaled up at speed during the pandemic. Andrew learns what not to do when taking psychometric recruitment tests and a headhunter from Russell Reynolds reveals the secrets to a successful CEO search.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;figure>;&lt;div>;&lt;figcaption>;Listen to this podcast&lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/div>;&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;audio-player&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; src=&quot;https://sphinx.acast.com/p/open/s/64ee35bafc643000110d1607/e/653f94b08f6e5f0012681a0d/media.mp3?tk=eyJ1aWQiOiJ0b20iLCJ0ayI6IkxWSlA2Sk9kIiwiYWRzIjpmYWxzZSwic3BvbnMiOmZhbHNlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwcml2YXRlIn0=&amp;amp;sig=QQeMJ9WY6IyJYtT_9_HqRdC3VH4EYO3PdtFUsxM0TsM&quot; title=&quot;Boss Class&quot; controlsList=&quot;nodownload&quot;>;&lt;p>;Your browser does not support the &amp;lt;audio&amp;gt; element.&lt;/p>;&lt;/audio>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Listen on: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/boss-class-from-the-economist/id1705972518&quot;>;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a>; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://open.spotify.com/show/5U9AVLBdcqysaLO8vOxlpM&quot;>;Spotify.&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a subscriber-only episode. Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://economist.com/podcastsplus-bossclass&quot;>;free trial&lt;/a>; of Economist Podcasts+ or if you&#39;re already a subscriber to &lt;i>;The Economist&lt;/i>;, you have full access to all our shows as part of your subscription. For more information about how to access Economist Podcasts+, please visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://myaccount.economist.com/s/article/What-is-Economist-Podcasts&quot;>;FAQs page&lt;/a>; or watch our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.comhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48TlDbL-4vU&quot;>;video&lt;/a>; explaining how to link your account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Podcast transcripts are available upon request at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;a4d4cbc0c7c5d7d0d7e4c1c7cbcacbc9cdd7d08ac7cbc9&quot;>;[email&amp;#160;protected]&lt;/a>;. We are committed to improving accessibility even further and are exploring new ways to expand our podcast transcript offering.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:27:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>