<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[Lib Dems seize on Braverman’s unpopularity to win over ‘blue wall’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/nov/13/lib-dems-seize-on-bravermans-unpopularity-to-win-over-blue-wall]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T06:00:25Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0341d146bfee3943c93fc352a6250e77f50a3edf/0_15_4432_2659 /master/4432.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=88f92dcd92e2adfbf004dc713dadffa0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;内政大臣 Suella Braverman 于 10 月 3 日在曼彻斯特举行的保守党年度会议上。&lt;/div>;&lt; p>;自由民主党表示，Suella Braverman 最近发表的一系列有争议的言论令“蓝墙”席位中的大量保守党选民感到沮丧，一名候选人称她为“我们最好的招募工具之一”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;特别是，自由民主党活动人士表示，布雷弗曼对无家可归的描述&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/nov/06/rishi-sunak-suella-braverman-lifestyle-choice-homeless-声称“作为一种“生活方式的选择”&lt;/a>;受到了更多中间派保守党选民的强烈反对，其中许多人在上门聊天时提出了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而自由民主党一直坚决拒绝公开表态蓝墙（一个宽松的术语，主要涵盖伦敦附近的通勤带地区）中的许多传统保守党支持者感到沮丧，这引发了人们的猜测，这个数字可能远高于 30 个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自由民主党活动人士称，这种效应始于鲍里斯·约翰逊和利兹·特拉斯，布雷弗曼再次助长了这种效应，可能会在谴责政府在选举中惨败方面发挥重要作用 — — 保守党议员对此表示赞同将争夺温彻斯特保守党超边缘席位的丹尼·钱伯斯 (Danny Chambers) 表示，对布雷弗曼的情绪如此强烈，以至于一些住所靠近她的新席位的选民边界变化很高兴得知她不会成为他们的议员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱伯斯表示，最近对两个选区边缘的一个村庄的拉票之旅让他认为布雷弗曼是“我们最好的招聘工具之一”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多人都认为布雷弗曼会成为他们的下一任议员，但当他们得知事实并非如此时，他们欣喜若狂，”他说。 “有一个人甚至大声叫他的妻子下来和我们说话，让我再告诉她一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这些都是正宗的保守党村庄，他们真的很高兴见到我们。这主要是因为布雷弗曼。他们只是觉得她完全令人厌恶。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是将无家可归者或寻求庇护者武器化，作为文化战争的一部分。这是人们不喜欢的共同点——语气、侵略性、肮脏。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布雷弗曼在移民等领域的强硬路线似乎并没有阻止选民从他也是保守党改革英国的右翼，他说：“即使有些人支持她在卢旺达问题上的立场，他们也不相信她会解决这个问题。他们甚至没有在同意他们的人中支持他们的选票。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自由民主党官员，他们一直在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.html&quot; 中严格优先考虑目标席位。 com/politics/2023/sep/26/not-so-cuddly-lib-dems-laser-focused-on-target-list-of-seats&quot;>;纪律严明的竞选活动&lt;/a>;，布雷弗曼和李·安德森说，保守党&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/feb/07/lee-anderson-tory-deputy-chair-one-man-controversy-machine&quot;>;好斗的副主席&lt;/a >;，是蓝墙席位中被提及最多的两个名字。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自由民主党对蓝墙席位中摇摆选民的研究表明，他们往往是慈善机构的定期捐助者，无家可归者组织是最常见的受益者之一，部分解释了对布雷弗曼评论的负面反应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马克斯·威尔金森 (Max Wilkinson) 将在下次选举中试图推翻切尔滕纳姆司法部长亚历克斯·查克 (Alex Chalk) 的 2,500 多数票，他表示，“令人不快和不友善” ” 布雷弗曼所表现出的影响力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有一个人告诉我，他投票支持脱欧，而且他一生都投票给保守党，但现在他会投票给任何能够摆脱他们的人， ”威尔金森说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他直接说他对苏埃拉·布雷弗曼 (Suella Braverman) 很不以为然，尤其是在无家可归问题上，但也对游行感到不满。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查克来自自由派边缘保守党，而且显然不喜欢他在内政部的同事。威尔金森说，即便如此，也不一定对他有利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“粉笔显然他对此感到非常尴尬，我确信他不会同意正在使用的那种言辞，”他说。 “但我认为人们对他没有更公开地谴责此事感到有点失望。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 14:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[High silver levels in some period pants could pose health risk, study says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/nov/13/high-silver-levels-some-period-pants-could-pose-health-risk-study]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T05:00:23Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/788f7a447e26cc3c81a943ec5cf5ab0e51a58e49/666_711_5861_3517 /master/5861.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=327a6d2193e4eb6f4651346a9f999e7e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;一位年轻女子双手放在肚子上的特写&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;出售一些古裤一项调查发现，商业街零售商生产的产品含有高含量的银，可能会对消费者的健康和环境产生影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;银被用作抗菌剂，通常添加到经期裤中，以消除用户对银的担忧。气味和卫生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，科学家们越来越多地警告潜在的健康影响。美国食品和药物管理局发现纳米银可以杀死乳酸菌，这是阴道中有助于抵抗感染的健康细菌。这可能会使经期裤使用者面临更多有害细菌的风险，从而可能导致细菌感染和妊娠并发症的风险增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which? 家居产品和服务主管娜塔莉·希钦斯 (Natalie Hitchins) 表示：“消费者应谨慎购买含银的经期裤，因为专家担心其对健康的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“哪个？认为品牌还应该明确说明哪些产品含有银，以便购物者可以就自己购买的商品和可能的风险做出明智的决定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;消费者权益组织与意大利消费者组织 Altroconsumo 合作，进行独立测试受欢迎的品牌，并检查它们是否含有任何令人担忧的化学物质。他们担心一些产品含有大量的银，而包装上并不总是明确说明这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bodyform 的 Intima 和 Marks &amp;amp; 的裤子。尤其是 Spencer 的银含量明显高于其他品牌，分别为 126.7 毫克/公斤和 57.8 毫克/公斤。其他品牌的含量分别为 8.3 毫克/公斤、7.4 毫克/公斤和 0.9 毫克/公斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bodyform 和 Modibodi 的所有者 Essity 表示，银铜沸石用于“防止穿着裤子时产生异味”。长达 12 小时”。该公司补充说，其所有“可洗内衣均经过 Oeko-Tex Standard 100 认证，这意味着每一个成分都经过了有害物质测试”，并且“内衣已被指定为对人体健康无害”。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;标记和标记斯宾塞拒绝发表评论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哪一个？表示认为没有必要使用银，并且 Altroconsumo 之前的测试表明，以这种方式处理的纺织品不具有承诺的抗菌性能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲化学品管理局表示银处理，例如纳米银和银沸石，对水生生物有毒并具有长期影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;测试哪些？检测结果显示，银含量超过0.1毫克/公斤，而Primark、Repeat、Wuka、Lovable和Sloggi裤子中均未发现银含量。 Sloggi 的网站称其确实使用了银基抗菌剂，而 Primark 则表示其使用了含有氯化银的 Micro-Fresh。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Primark 发言人表示：“经期裤的性质意味着有可能穿着过程中会产生气味（就像细菌会导致袜子和鞋子在穿着过程中产生气味一样），而我们的抗菌表面处理可最大限度地减少此类气味。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sloggi 没有回复“哪个？”在发布时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国对于古裤中可以添加多少银没有法律限制。制造商不必在其包装或网站上声明银的存在。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Woman who suffered complications from vaginal mesh implant awarded at least £1m]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/nov/13/woman-suffered-complications-vaginal-mesh-implant-awarded-1m]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T05:00:26Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/316ab5f405ed7792a1fef3271bd7725f8fe188e1/0_305_6120_3671 /master/6120.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=f6e684a7b6d82e4feaa2e33b53b6a953&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Yvette Greenway-Mansfield&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一名因阴道网状植入物而遭受创伤性并发症的妇女已被NHS 获得了至少 100 万英镑的创纪录和解金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;59 岁的 Yvette Greenway-Mansfield 于 2009 年在考文垂大学医院接受了网状植入，但随后出现了严重的并发症。她对医院信托基金提出的医疗过失索赔发现，手术过早进行且没有必要，而且她的同意书在格林威-曼斯菲尔德签署后经过修改，加入了额外的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格林威-曼斯菲尔德表示，获得赔偿是一种“巨大的解脱”，但她补充说，许多其他遭受类似损害的妇女只得到很少或根本没有得到赔偿，并批评政府的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bmj.com/content/ 379/bmj.o3011&quot;>;未能为受害者建立经济赔偿机构&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不是唯一一个。有成千上万的我，”她说。 “应该有一大笔钱来为这些女性提供损害赔偿，并制定一个护理计划，作为对网状受损人群的自动反应。这归根结底是对妇女和妇女健康问题的看法。我们都已经受够了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格林威-曼斯菲尔德 (Greenway-Mansfield) 最初于 2009 年去看了全科医生，当时她出现下腹部不适和排尿频率增加，导致对喝水感到焦虑。她的症状归因于子宫脱垂，一位妇科医生顾问建议进行阴道子宫切除术，并插入经阴道胶带 (TVT) 网状植入物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初，手术似乎很成功，但在 2017 年，在去新西兰出差时，她开始感到疼痛和出血。 “当我回到英国后，有人认为网状物可能已经开始侵蚀阴道壁，”格林威-曼斯菲尔德说。 “听到这个信息我很震惊，因为我不知道会发生这样的并发症。”&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;7d452c0ef89a6d573ce0f2d34d8f1f101cf69b92&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co. uk/7d452c0ef89a6d573ce0f2d34d8f1f101cf69b92/0_591_6346_3808/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yvette Greenway&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;Yvette Greenway-Mansfield：“如果我没有保留该文档，我可以站在法庭上，受到拷问，被证明是骗子。”&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;摄影：Andrew Fox/The Guardian&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;她疼痛变得更加严重，但她被告知没有明显的医疗解决方案。 2020 年 2 月，在私人转诊至 Spire Bristol 医院后，网片被移除，但她现在患有尿失禁和大便失禁以及慢性疼痛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;声明发现 Greenway-Mansfield 的表格同意手术她签字后就被更改了。医院的版本包括膀胱镜检查和额外的风险，包括失败、胶带腐蚀、疼痛、膀胱过度活动症和深静脉血栓形成。这些内容并不在格林威-曼斯菲尔德的原件复本上，她保留了原件。 “我简直不敢相信我所看到的，”格林威-曼斯菲尔德说。 “我觉得自己完全被证明是正确的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果我没有保留这些文件，我可能会站在法庭上，受到盘问，被证明是一个骗子，”她说。 “对于必须经历这些的女性来说，这让我心碎。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;手术也被认为是在探索其他选择（例如物理治疗和膀胱训练）之前进行的。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.limesolicitors.co.uk/people/neil-clayton/&quot;>;Neil Clayton&lt;/a>;，代表 Greenway-Mansfield 的 Lime Solicitors 临床过失合伙人表示：“考文垂和沃里克郡 NHS 信托大学医院有义务确保获得格林威-曼斯菲尔德夫人对任何外科手术的完全知情同意，并告知她由此可能出现的风险。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “妇科医生在用尽所有行为和医疗选择之前过早地进行了手术。而且，她在错误的情况下进行了错误的手术，不必要地进行了手术。尤其令人震惊的是，格林威-曼斯菲尔德夫人签署了一份同意书，该同意书后来被修改，其中包括了她从未意识到的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“没有多少钱可以完全补偿格林威-曼斯菲尔德夫人所遭受的痛苦。考文垂和沃里克郡 NHS 信托大学医院的发言人表示： “我们直接向 Greenway-Mansfield 女士表示最诚挚的歉意，并认识到她的生活受到 2009 年这一手术的影响。自 2019 年以来，英国已暂停提供使用阴道网片治疗压力性尿失禁或盆腔器官脱垂的手术，并于 2022 年创建了专科中心。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们希望和解协议将使 Greenway-Mansfield 夫人能够满足她持续的护理需求，并为她和她的家人的未来提供安全保障。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hungarian plan to target foreign influence fuels NGO and media fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/13/hungary-plan-target-foreign-influence-ngo-media-fears-sovereignty]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T05:00:25Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4ccc64acc3058a1fd048335805a4b6f825128772/0_20_3024_1814 /master/3024.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=71d7f5c0ad49087cd2ce9142cd7a09dc&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Viktor Orbán&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;匈牙利权利倡导者对新立法表示担忧，他们认为新立法可能会增加更多内容独立媒体和民间社会团体面临压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预计匈牙利执政党青民盟将于周二提交的法案草案将提议设立一个新办公室，负责调查威胁匈牙利“主权”的活动.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;政府几乎没有透露其计划的细节。但青民盟领导层表示，新立法可能适用于政党的外国资助，也可能适用于其指责在华盛顿和/或布鲁塞尔影响下运作的媒体机构和民间社会组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;匈牙利总理维克多·欧尔班十多年来一直在巩固权力并将其政党的影响力扩大到公共生活的各个方面，长期以来一直宣扬外国实体正在干涉匈牙利政治以及他的批评者正在反对的观点。国家利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，匈牙利颇具争议地批准了一项反非政府组织法，政府认为该法旨在确保接受国外捐赠的团体的透明度。欧盟法院后来&lt;a href=&quot;https://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2020-06/cp200073en.pdf&quot;>;裁定&lt;/a>;该法律侵犯了匈牙利人的权利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管遭受法律挫折和国际批评，总理仍继续辩称他的国内批评者受到外部势力的控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/07/hungary-national-museum-director-fired-lgbt-homomaleity-laws&quot;>;匈牙利解雇博物馆馆长因未在 LGBTQ+ 展览中执行 18 岁以下禁令&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“他们公开表示希望匈牙利更换政府。他们使用一切政治腐败手段来资助匈牙利反对派。”Orbán &lt;a href=&quot;https://miniszterelnok.hu/en/speech-by-prime-minister-viktor-orban-at-the-32nd-balvanyos -summer-free-university-and-student-camp/&quot;>;在去年夏天的一次演讲中宣布&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 9 月份的一次党内会议上，总理特别&lt;a href=&quot;https ://magyarnemzet.hu/belfold/2023/09/orban-viktor-nem-engedhetjuk-hogy-magyarorszag-sorsarol-kulfoldon-dontsenek#google_vignette&quot;>;抱怨&lt;/a>;来自国外的资金，援引民间社会团体和媒体的话说“由布鲁塞尔或通过&lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/business/george-soros&quot;>;索罗斯网络&lt;/a>;提供资金”。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;现在，随着匈牙利在明年的欧洲议会和市政选举之前进入竞选模式，匈牙利记者和监督团体担心政府可能会在竞选活动中采取进一步措施来压制批评声音。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Telex 是匈牙利仅存的少数独立媒体之一，其领导层最近发布了一份公开的&lt;a href=&quot;https://telex.hu/velemeny/2023/10/25/telex-szabad-sajto-fuggetlenseg-tamogatas-szuverenitas&quot; >;警告&lt;/a>;“在保护主权的幌子下”，欧尔班政府“向批评媒体宣战”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;权利倡导者表示，新立法是长期进程的一部分，欧尔班正在努力巩固自己的控制权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“主权保护机构的理念绝对符合趋势，”匈牙利公民自由联盟战略主管斯特凡尼亚·卡普罗恩茨 (Stefánia Kapronczay) 表示。 “政党接受外国资金已经被禁止，这背后有充分的理由，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们有充分理由担心，这项即将出台的立法将符合政府寻求限制的一系列行动。参与公共生活和新闻自由运作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，她说，人们担心该法案可能会进一步推动政府的说法，即任何形式的外国资金都会违背匈牙利的国家利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;匈牙利政府没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然专家强调，在全文发布之前不可能评估新立法的影响，但已经有&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是针对独立非政府组织和独立媒体的无数法律威胁，”专门研究媒体法和政策的匈牙利教授 Gábor Polyák 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/26/orban-is-lonelier-than-ever-on-the-european-stage-but -hes-still-got-cards-to-play&quot;>;欧尔班在欧洲舞台上比以往任何时候都更加孤独 - 但他仍然有牌可打&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;但目前还不清楚”，他说，“另一头无牙狮子是否会诞生”，或者青民盟是否会采取“普京主义”的做法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果对外援助确实面临强大的法律威胁，那基本上就意味着终结对于独立媒体和民间社会来说，”波利亚克指出。 “可以肯定的是，记者和平民都存在着焦灼的期望。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些批评者表示，主权运动在一定程度上是为了分散选民的注意力，而该办公室本身如果成立，将不会有什么好处。匈牙利青民盟成员马顿·汤波斯 (Márton Tompos) 表示：“通常，青民盟想要转移人们对真正问题的注意力，比如通货膨胀、我们的教育、医疗保健和社会服务系统的状况。” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果政府真的想开始打击危及匈牙利主权的问题，”他补充道，“他们应该从与莫斯科和北京的协议开始。”&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US announces fresh strikes on Iran-linked sites in Syria]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/13/us-announces-fresh-strikes-on-iran-linked-sites-in-syria]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T04:28:10Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/34a615f5eb9b817b3ad8559b7f76fae67efc4a17/0_130_3888_2333 /master/3888.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=b10d56b70b91799611f8388268f4b487&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;美国空军F-15战斗机&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美国对两架伊朗进行了打击美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀 (Lloyd Austin) 表示，周日，叙利亚境内的链接网站针对美国军队遭受的袭击做出了回应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是不到三周内的第三次 &lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/27/what-prompted-us-air-strikes-syria-what-happens-next&quot;>;美国军方已瞄准叙利亚境内&lt;/a>;据称与伊朗有关，华盛顿指责伊朗支持武装组织，导致其在中东的部队遭受袭击激增。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国军队今天对伊朗伊斯兰革命卫队使用的叙利亚东部设施进行了精确打击奥斯汀在一份声明中表示，“伊朗革命卫队（IRGC）和伊朗附属团体对驻伊拉克和叙利亚的美国人员持续遭受的袭击做出了回应。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“袭击是针对附近的一个训练设施和一个安全屋进行的。分别是 Albu Kamal 和 Mayadeen 城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/ 27/what-prompted-us-air-strikes-syria-what-happens-next&quot;>;美国为何对叙利亚发动空袭以及接下来会发生什么？&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“总统的首要任务莫过于美国人员的安全，他指示今天的行动是为了明确美国将保卫自己、其人员和利益。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/09/us-strikes-iran-weapons-storage-facility-syria-iirgc-pentagon-conflict&quot;>;美国瞄准了与德黑兰有关的武器储存地点&lt;/ a>; 周三在叙利亚发动袭击，并于 10 月 26 日袭击了叙利亚的两处设施，据称这些设施被伊朗及其附属组织使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;华盛顿评估称，此前的袭击均未造成人员伤亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国表示，此次袭击旨在阻止以色列与哈马斯战争后对驻伊拉克和叙利亚美军的袭击激增。美国表示，自10月17日以来，该地区已发生超过45起针对其军队的袭击事件，造成数十名美军人员受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据五角大楼称，约有56名美军人员在袭击中受伤。五角大楼表示，他们的伤势从脑外伤到轻伤不等，而且所有人都已返回岗位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大约有 2,500 名美军驻扎在伊拉克，大约有 900 名美军驻扎在叙利亚，以防止疫情死灰复燃。伊斯兰国组织。圣战分子曾在两国占据大片领土，但在持续数年的冲突中，被当地地面部队在国际空袭的支持下击退。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加沙冲突也给美国在伊拉克和叙利亚以外的地区带来了影响。 ，伊朗支持的也门胡塞叛军周三表示，他们击落了一架美国无人机，该无人机“在也门领海进行敌对监视和间谍活动，作为美国对以色列军事支持的一部分”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;美国高级官员 — — 在 10 月 7 日袭击事件后，美国紧急向以色列提供了军事支持，并支持了驻该地区的美军 — — 已证实他们的一架无人机被击落。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;法国通讯社-新闻社和美联社&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 12:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tim Scott suspends presidential bid as Trump leads Republican pack]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/13/tim-scott-suspends-presidential-bid]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T03:14:24Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/e171bd25c520d49435d0619a48b3a0afd9603fbb/0_0_4319_2592 /master/4319.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=9d1571a0cb9ae080e24ea3c827c02466&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;参议员蒂姆·斯科特于 10 月 28 日在内华达州拉斯维加斯举行的共和党犹太联盟 2023 年度领导峰会上发表讲话。&lt; /div>;&lt;p>;南卡罗来纳州参议员蒂姆·斯科特已暂停总统竞选活动，他承认，由于唐纳德·特朗普在初选民意调查中保持显着领先优势，他看不到任何获得共和党提名的途径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斯科特告诉我们福克斯新闻周日晚间接受采访时表示，他已暂停竞选活动。他的退出可能会为其他试图将领跑者唐纳德·特朗普从榜首位置上赶下来的候选人提供一定的推动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我认为选民是地球上最杰出的人，他们非常清楚他们他告诉我：‘现在不行，蒂姆。’”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个消息是在斯科特发起入主白宫竞选后不到六个月发布的，他承诺对美国的未来提出更乐观的愿景，预计一个准备带领共和党进入新时代的“快乐战士”的形象。斯科特是参议院中唯一的黑人共和党人，他用自己作为单亲母亲的孩子的个人故事来论证美国的伟大，指责乔·拜登和其他民主党人“攻击对我有帮助的每一级”爬”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在我们生活的土地上，一个在小公寓单亲家庭中长大的贫困孩子绝对有可能有一天在人民家里服务，甚至可能在白人家中服务。”众议院，”斯科特在宣布时说道。 &lt;/a>; 他五月份的竞选。 “这是上帝创造的绿色地球上最伟大的国家。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是这种积极的信息未能影响共和党初选选民，斯科特努力赢得党内基础的支持，尽管 91前总统面临重罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近几个月，斯科特在竞选审判中探讨了更为阴暗的言论，显然是为了增强他日益渺茫的获得提名的希望。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/27/republican-candidates-second-debate-polls-california-reagan-library&quot;>;第二次共和党初选辩论&lt;/ a>; 9月下旬，斯科特暗示，对于美国黑人来说，奴隶制比林登·约翰逊总统的反贫困计划“伟大社会”更容易忍受，该计划导致了医疗保险和医疗补助等社会福利计划的创建。该评论&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A6Xwf7Qx3hk&quot;>;赢得了福克斯新闻评论员和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charlotteobserver.com/的赞扬&lt;/a>;意见/文章279896804.html&quot;>;激起了斯科特批评者的愤怒&lt;/a>;，他们指责斯科特淡化奴隶制的暴行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件发生几周后，斯科特痛斥拜登对袭击事件的反应10 月 7 日，哈马斯发动袭击，造成 1,400 多名以色列人死亡。斯科特猛烈抨击拜登的外交政策议程，指责总统无意中引发了暴力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当哈马斯实施这些袭击时，乔·拜登的手上沾满了鲜血，”斯科特说。 “他的弱点引发了攻击。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斯科特后来 &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/scott-foreign-policy-national-security-ap-georgetown-b13c5c1b93fd113b6070e5dcd0dc9225#:~ :text=Tim%20Scott%20of%20South%20Carolina,7%20attack.&quot;>;赞扬&lt;/a>;以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡在应对哈马斯袭击时的“克制”。在斯科特发表评论时，据报道以色列对加沙的空袭已经造成大量巴勒斯坦人死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管斯科特转向更严厉的言辞，但他在全国初选民意调查中的支持率仍然处于低位。数字，使他没有获得提名的途径。斯科特十月份宣布，他将把竞选资源转移到爱荷华州，瞄准第一个投票州，为重振竞选活动做最后的努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这一策略未能提升斯科特的民调数字，并且随着特朗普巩固了他在竞选中明显领先者的地位，他现已正式暂停竞选活动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Netanyahu sets out uncompromising postwar vision as Israel pounds Gaza]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/12/main-gaza-hospital-totally-surrounded-director-says-as-netanyahu-rejects-ceasefire-calls]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T13:37:38Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c9aca0a4975657995e903a6cd41b1fc682a24be0/0_54_1024_614 /master/1024.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=f4b86a1d4449fe5a8f71e79aa0b2fe6e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;以色列国防军发布的照片​​显示以色列军队在加沙地带北部进行地面行动。&lt;/div>;&lt; p>;在总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡发誓要“全力”推动以色列进入加沙地带，并制定了毫不妥协的战后解决方案之后，以色列对加沙的猛烈空袭仍在继续。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;轰炸周日的袭击集中在加沙城的 al-Shifa 医院周围，这是该地区最大的此类设施，哈马斯和以色列地面部队之间最激烈的战斗大部分都在那里进行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该医院“完全瘫痪”其负责人穆罕默德·阿布·萨尔米亚 (Mohammad Abu Salmiya) 在周六晚间的一份声明中表示：“被包围，附近正在进行轰炸。”最近几天的激烈冲突已导致数千名伤病员和流离失所者被困在阿尔及尔地区。希法没有电力供应，供应也日益减少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医务人员和救援人员警告说，除非战斗暂停，否则患者将会死亡。随着以色列“镇压”哈马斯的行动进入第六周，还有数千人被困在加沙北部的其他卫生设施中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管来自坚定盟友的压力越来越大，但内塔尼亚胡迄今为止拒绝了国际社会的呼吁停火。 “针对[哈马斯]的战争正在全力推进，它的目标只有一个：取胜。除了胜利，别无选择。”他在周六晚间的电视评论中说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;内塔尼亚胡还明确表示，他希望以色列在发生任何冲突后保留总体安全控制权，“能够随时介入”为了杀死恐怖分子”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不会有哈马斯。不会有任何文职当局教育他们的孩子仇恨以色列、杀害以色列人、摧毁以色列国。那里不可能有一个机构向凶手家属支付报酬。那里需要有其他东西，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些评论似乎排除了巴勒斯坦权力机构在冲突后发挥任何作用，这是美国和许多欧洲大国青睐的解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列表示，在加沙北部医院避难的医生、患者和数千名撤离人员必须离开，以便能够对付哈马斯枪手，据称这些枪手已在他们的下方和周围设立了指挥中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;哈马斯否认以这种方式使用医院。医务人员表示，如果患者被转移，可能会死亡，巴勒斯坦官员表示，以色列的大火对其他人离开造成危险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列认为，哈马斯总部位于希法下方，医院和哈马斯声称， denied.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/12/relatives-count-cost- gaza-airstrikes-israeli-missiles-apartment-blocks-survivors&quot;>;&#39;Families want to die together&#39;: relatives count the cost of Gaza airstrikes&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“The medical team cannot work and the bodies, in their dozens, cannot be managed or buried,” said Abu Salmiya. Two newborns had already died on Saturday after the hospital&#39;s fuel ran out and dozens more were at risk, officials said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli military described fierce close-quarter fighting in the area but denied any “siege” of al-Shifa. Israeli forces had observed “temporary tactical pauses” and opened “humanitarian corridors” to allow those trapped by the fighting to flee to relatively safer zones to the south, they said.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;a52c139e6d620ae094ee0eb26d5a787aadf011f2&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/a52c139e6d620ae094ee0eb26d5a787aadf011f2/90_0_2661_1598/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screen grab from a video shows smoke rising after Israeli airstrikes on the Indonesian hospital in the Jabalia neighbourhood of Gaza City on Sunday.&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;A screengrab from a video shows smoke rising after Israeli airstrikes on the Indonesian hospital in the Jabaliya neighbourhood of Gaza City.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Anadolu Agency/Anadolu/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;An Israeli military statement on Sunday said soldiers had “opened and secured a passage which enables the civilian population to evacuate, on foot and by ambulances, from the Shifa, Rantisi and Nasser hospitals”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The World Health Organization expressed “grave concern” for the safety of everyone trapped in al-Shifa by the fighting and said it had lost communications with its contacts there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As horrifying reports of the hospital facing repeated attacks continue to emerge, we assume our contacts joined tens of thousands of displaced people and are fleeing the area,” the organisation said on X, formerly Twitter, late on Saturday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are reports that some people who fled the hospital have been shot at, wounded and even killed.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 11,000 Palestinians have now been killed during the Israeli air and ground offensive, and many more wounded, according to the Hamas-run health authorities in Gaza. The dead include more than 4,500 children and more than 3,000 women,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Officials from the health ministry said 13 Palestinians were killed in an Israeli strike on a house in Khan Younis, in southern Gaza, on Sunday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A correspondent for Al Jazeera TV network reported that one of the family members who survived the attack said “the ground was shaking underneath their feet before the explosion took place and destroyed the building”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The claims have not been independently verified. Khan Younis is in the south of the Gaza Strip, and is inside the area to which Israel&#39;s military has been directing Palestinians to evacuate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The military wing of Hamas&#39;s ally Islamic Jihad, the al-Quds Brigades, said they were “engaged in violent clashes in the vicinity of al-Shifa medical complex” as well as several other locations in the northern part of Gaza, while a Hamas health official claimed that an Israeli airstrike destroyed the cardiac ward of the hospital. Witnesses confirmed a blast at the hospital, which the Guardian was unable to independently verify.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel has cut most supplies of electricity, fuel, water and food to Gaza, causing acute suffering to the population of 2.3 million. Many are now crammed into private homes, makeshift shelters in schools and other accommodation in deteriorating conditions. Many lack clean water, appropriate treatment for chronic medical conditions and food. In some shelters, hundreds share a single toilet, with poor hygienic conditions leading to the outbreak of infectious diseases.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Commentators in Israel said Israel was winning the military campaign but losing the battle for global public opinion. Netanyahu has said any ceasefire must be conditional on the prior release of all the 240 or more hostages taken by Hamas and other groups during the attacks the militant organisation launched into Israel last month which killed 1,200. Most victims were civilians, killed in their homes or at a dance party.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-67356581&quot;>;French president, Emmanuel Macron&lt;/a>;, urged Israel on Friday to “stop this bombing” in Gaza and said: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/nov/11/as-a-former-palestinian-negotiator-i-know-bidens-two-state-solution-is-sheer-delusion&quot;>;There is no other solution&lt;/a>; than first a humanitarian pause, going to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/nov/10/labour-mps-urged-not-to-back-snp-middle-east-ceasefire-motion&quot;>;ceasefire&lt;/a>;, which will allow [us] to protect … all civilians having nothing to do with terrorists.” On Friday, Antony Blinken, the US secretary of state, said “far too many Palestinians have been killed” in Gaza.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;beae3ecf4808d86fa3180cb192da5bca389b48d3&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/beae3ecf4808d86fa3180cb192da5bca389b48d3/0_340_8192_4918/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Palestinian man sits on the debris of buildings destroyed in the Israeli bombardment of Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip on Friday.&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;A Palestinian man sits on the debris of buildings destroyed in the Israeli bombardment of Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip on Friday.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Said Khatib/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;There is domestic pressure too on Netanyahu, who announced the deaths of five more Israeli soldiers in Gaza. The Israeli military said 46 had been killed since its ground operations there began.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Though there remains overwhelming support for the war among Israelis, the issue of how to obtain the release of the hostages held by Hamas in Gaza is more divisive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thousands joined a rally outside the Tel Aviv Museum Square, which has been informally renamed “Hostages Square”, to support families of the hostages late Saturday, while Israel&#39;s three major TV news channels, without citing named sources, said there had been some progress toward a deal to win their release.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/11/israel-new-leader-benjamin-netanyahu&quot;>;What would Israel look like under a new leader – and who would benefit?&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;Netanyahu said he would not discuss details of any possible deal, which according to N12 News would involve 50 to 100 women, children and elderly being released in stages during a three- to five-day pause in fighting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the reports, Israel would release women and minor Palestinian prisoners and consider letting fuel in to Gaza, while reserving the right to resume fighting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There will be no ceasefire without the return of our hostages,” Netanyahu told Israelis on Saturday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Reuters and Agence France-Presse contributed to this report&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shots fired at another Jewish school in Montreal amid tensions over Israel-Hamas war]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/13/shots-fired-at-another-jewish-school-in-montreal-amid-tensions-over-israel-hamas-war]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T01:52:14Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6a5bc9f3aa37cd76ff93dec3ca6a9cebeb363cfc/0_0_3000_1973/master/3000.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=c46d6bea87dfbfc563c00d58d04718a0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Police search an area near the Yeshiva Gedolah Jewish school after shots were fired at the school in Montreal, Canada&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A Jewish school in Montreal was hit by gunfire, according to local media, marking the Canadian city&#39;s third such attack in less than a week amid heightened tensions over the conflict in Gaza between Israel and Hamas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one was injured when the facade of Yeshiva Gedola of Montreal was struck early on Sunday. Bullet marks and shells were found after residents heard gunfire, CBC News in Canada reported.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/09/canada-elnaz-hajtamiri-abducted-police-charge-suspect-boyfriend&quot;>;Canada: murder charge for ex-boyfriend of woman abducted by fake police&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;Police on Thursday said they were investigating overnight shootings at two Jewish schools in the Côte-des-Neiges neighbourhood after staff reported finding bullet holes in the front doors.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;df261b7528b5216152a879151f18d0e56ea7a92f&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/df261b7528b5216152a879151f18d0e56ea7a92f/281_135_2719_1766/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A police officer exits the Yeshiva Gedolah Jewish school&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;650&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;A police officer exits the Yeshiva Gedolah Jewish school.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Canadian Press/Shutterstock&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;It was unclear if the incidents at Jewish schools in the city&#39;s west end were related.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Wednesday, a violent altercation at Concordia University in Montreal between people aligned with opposing sides of the Gaza conflict resulted in injuries and an arrest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Administrators said that the university, like others, has witnessed “a concerning rise in acts of intimidation and intolerant behaviour” that had left students in fear.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Canadian prime minister, Justin Trudeau, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/09/justin-trudeau-montreal-canada-jewish-schools&quot;>;condemned the violence&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I know emotions are high, and people are scared. But attacking each other is not who we are as Canadians,” Trudeau said on Thursday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If anywhere in the world is going to start building the kinds of understandings that we&#39;re going to need to see peaceful resolution in the Middle East … it starts in a place like Canada.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel-Gaza war has sharply divided Canada, with a growing number of people calling for a ceasefire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Toronto, police said that in the three weeks after the initial Hamas attack on 7 October, hate crimes against Jews and Muslims were more than double the entire number in 2022.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[England stop and search pilot scheme does not cut violence, thinktank finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/nov/13/england-stop-and-search-does-not-cut-violence-thinktank]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13T00:01:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2165f6db29371ac195a60ea363680791d048bdae/0_0_2464_1478/master/2464.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=24dc8083ba7d2a2b3bf6f358493de398&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Police carrying out stop and search&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A pilot scheme that allows police to stop and search people without having any grounds for suspicion does not work to reduce serious violence and disproportionately targets people of colour, a report has concluded.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first comprehensive review of evidence on stop and search and serious violence reduction orders (SVROs), the racial equality thinktank Runnymede Trust found that there was no statistically significant link between existing police stop and search powers and violence prevention or reduction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study also showed that people from ethnic minority backgrounds, and particularly Black people, were more likely to be stopped and searched, and experience negative mental and physical health outcomes as a result.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SVROs are court orders that allow officers to search people who have been convicted of an offence that involved a “bladed article or offensive weapon”, even if there are no immediate grounds for thinking they are carrying one at that time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This order, introduced as a pilot under the Police Crime Sentencing and Courts Act 2022, can last for between six months and two years, though it can be extended.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a criminal offence for someone with an SVRO to obstruct officers conducting a search or to deny having the order if asked. The orders are being piloted in Thames Valley, West Midlands, Merseyside and Sussex.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Runnymede Trust said the court orders were “part of a broader expansion of police powers and the rolling-back of safeguards and avenues for police accountability”, citing the poor outcomes relating to stop-and-search powers used without reasonable suspicion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Section 60 search powers, under which police officers can stop and search a person without reasonable suspicion, are particularly ineffective, the thinktank said, with an overall arrest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/police-powers-and-procedures-stop-and-search-and-arrests-england-and-wales-year-ending-31-march-2021&quot;>;rate of 0.5% for offensive weapons between 2001 and 2021&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dr Tim Head, an author of the report and a criminology lecturer at the University of Essex, said: “One of the most striking things about the government&#39;s introduction of serious violence reduction order powers is that next to no evidence has been cited to support their rollout.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However you frame it, the vast majority of rigorous evidence on SVROs points towards a single conclusion: high-discretion police stop interventions like this do not &#39;work&#39;, even on their own terms. Instead, they produce harm, anxiety and misery among the communities they purport to &#39;protect&#39;.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SVROs were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/law/2019/nov/19/johnson-reveals-plans-to-extend-police-stop-and-search-powers&quot;>;proposed in 2019 by Boris Johnson in an attempt to tackle knife crime&lt;/a>;. The idea was first set out by the rightwing Centre for Social Justice thinktank and supported by the former Conservative leader and ex-work and pensions secretary, Iain Duncan Smith.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/stop-and-search-section-60-relaxation-equality-impact-assessment/stop-and-search-section-60-relaxation-equality-impact-assessment-accessible#in-light-of-the-overall-policy-objective-are-there-any-ways-to-avoid-or-mitigate-any-of-the-negative-impacts-that-you-have-identified-above&quot;>;report by the Home Office last year showed that people from Black, Asian and other minority ethnic backgrounds were likely to be targeted&lt;/a>; under relaxed stop and search rules, despite not having committed crimes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 12 months to June 2020, Black people were 3.7 times more likely to be stopped than white people. This figure rose to 6.9 times for stops relating to weapons, points and blades and section 60.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report also highlights that the stop and search orders are detrimental to the mental and physical health of those targeted, and called for the SVRO pilot to be scrapped and replaced by a community-led, evidence-based approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Deal to resettle climate-hit Tuvalu residents shows world ‘what’s at stake’, European officials say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/nov/13/australia-tuvalu-pacific-islands-climate-emissions-europe]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T20:53:13Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ad4cce9240a1eef2d2659487e8274b7619c82be2/86_0_3322_1993/master/3322.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=f796d1addfaf1d9427f0600bc12a187c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Tuvalu&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Australia&#39;s residency offer to citizens from the low-lying Pacific country of Tuvalu must spur the world to dramatically cut emissions, two senior European officials have declared.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Germany&#39;s climate envoy, Jennifer Morgan, said the deal “puts a very clear pointer on what&#39;s at stake” as the negotiators prepare for next month&#39;s UN climate summit, adding that “all countries have to scale up their ambition for 2030”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The message was echoed by a senior European Union official, Koen Doens, who said the climate crisis was putting Pacific island countries under increasing stress and more urgent action was “absolutely essential”.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/10/tuvalu-residency-and-security-treaty-what-is-it-and-why-is-australia-doing-it&quot;>;Tuvalu residency and security treaty: what is it and why is Australia doing it?&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The comments follow the Australian government&#39;s announcement that it would offer up to 280 people from Tuvalu access to residency, work and study rights each year, as part of a new treaty that also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/10/tuvalu-residency-and-security-treaty-what-is-it-and-why-is-australia-doing-it&quot;>;binds the two countries closely together on security&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deal is driven by recognition that Tuvalu – a country of nine low-lying islands about halfway between Australia and Hawaii – is particularly vulnerable to rising sea levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed&quot;>;Sign up for Guardian Australia&#39;s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;But Australia has also promised to fund coastal adaptation projects – including land reclamation work around the capital, Funafuti – to help as many as possible of Tuvalu&#39;s 11,200 citizens “stay in their homes with safety and dignity”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking to the Guardian on the sidelines of a Pacific summit in Cook Islands, where the deal was announced, Morgan said the news was “attracting attention” in Germany.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What I&#39;ve heard back from friends – not climate people – in Germany is that they&#39;re very sad about the fact that a country like Tuvalu has to be thinking about where their people may have to go,” Morgan said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She called for “even more focus on driving down emissions to avoid that, so that people can stay in their homes”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Morgan said the world must not abandon the goal of limiting global heating to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels, saying this was “a matter of life and death for many people here in this region”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doens, the European Commission&#39;s director general for international partnerships, said the Australia-Tuvalu treaty was “a very impactful agreement”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We all know what is happening to some of the islands in the Pacific. We know what is happening to Tuvalu,” he told the Guardian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The stress on the people living on the islands is increasing.”&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/10/australia-to-offer-residency-to-tuvalu-residents-displaced-by-climate-change&quot;>;Australia to offer residency to Tuvalu citizens displaced by climate change&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;Doens also called for “a more ambitious climate mitigation agenda than what we are seeing from the global community”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The US ambassador to the UN, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, who also visited Cook Islands, told reporters the climate crisis was having “a disproportionate impact on Pacific island nations”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Asked whether the Australia-Tuvalu agreement was a sign of things to come, she said: “We have seen these displacements take place already, not just here in the Pacific but across the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We see environmental migration, if you just look at the situation in the Sahel, where you see people moving across the Mediterranean. So the Australian announcement, I think, is a positive response to that movement.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The comments came after the Pacific Islands Forum (Pif) – whose 18 members include Australia and New Zealand – wrapped up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/11/climate-crisis-and-china-us-rivalry-five-top-takeaways-from-the-pacifics-most-important-summit&quot;>;its most important annual political summit&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite many Pacific island leaders wishing to explicitly call for a phase-out of fossil fuels, the final communique include caveats that were seen to be heavily influenced by Australia.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cook Islands prime minister and summit host, Mark Brown, confirmed that leaders “aspired” to phasing out fossil fuels while acknowledging the pathway was “not immediate nor one size fits all”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The summit also rebuffed calls by a group of former Pacific leaders to make Australia&#39;s bid to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/nov/05/australia-will-bid-for-2026-climate-summit-but-still-has-work-to-do-on-emissions-credentials-at-cop27&quot;>;co-host the 2026 Cop UN climate summit&lt;/a>; conditional on it stopping new coal and gas developments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Pif secretary general, Henry Puna, said the regional grouping had already agreed to promote the joint bid, “keeping in mind that Australia has already committed to making this the Pacific Cop”.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/11/climate-crisis-and-china-us-rivalry-five-top-takeaways-from-the-pacifics-most-important-summit&quot;>;Climate crisis and China-US rivalry: five top takeaways from the Pacific&#39;s most important summit&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;But he said advancing the bid had to be “done by consensus”. That was likely a reference to the “western European and other states” – a UN grouping that will be decisive in who hosts the 2026 conference. Germany is in that group.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Morgan reiterated Germany&#39;s support, saying her country was “quite positive about the approach of having the Pacific islands going hand in hand with Australia on that bid”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We would expect, of course, that the Pacific islands&#39; priorities and goals would play a big role in how that Cop is carried out,” Morgan added. “And being here just reinforces that even more.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shiva Gounden, the Greenpeace Pacific adviser, said the Australian government should prove its seriousness by no longer approving new fossil fuel projects – “something Pacific leaders and civil society have been crying out for in very clear terms”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Pacific Islands Climate Action Network&#39;s regional coordinator, Lavetanalagi Seru, described the Australia-Tuvalu pact as “a mere Band-Aid solution that in no way adequately addresses the fossil-fuelled climate crisis”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Climate Council senior researcher Wesley Morgan said Australia&#39;s “first responsibility must be to get emissions down as fast as possible” to minimise the risk of people being forced from their homes.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelenskiy warns Ukrainians to prepare for Russian attacks on infrastructure]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/12/zelenskiy-warns-ukrainians-to-prepare-for-russian-attacks-on-infrastructure]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T22:35:07Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/fca50b0aefa53ec8926777399c56df6eaf943371/0_150_4500_2700/master/4500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=e4f5e8316459f618104bd10075217e39&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Volodymyr Zelenskiy&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Volodymyr Zelenskiy has warned Ukrainians to prepare for new waves of Russian attacks on infrastructure as winter approaches, saying that troops were anticipating an onslaught in the eastern theatre of the war.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His comments came on Sunday as a military spokesperson said Russian attacks on the shattered eastern town of Avdiivka had eased in the past day, but were likely to intensify.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And Ukrainian military intelligence said an explosion killed at least three Russian servicemen in the Russian-occupied southern town of Melitopol, which it described as an “act of revenge” by resistance groups.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zelenskiy issued his warning during his nightly video address a day after Russian forces carried out their first missile attack on the capital, Kyiv, in seven weeks.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/11/as-its-counteroffensive-stalls-ukraine-signals-readiness-for-a-long-war&quot;>;As its counteroffensive stalls, Ukraine signals readiness for a long war&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“We are almost halfway through November and must be prepared for the fact that the enemy may increase the number of drone or missile strikes on our infrastructure,” Zelenskiy said. “Russia is preparing for &lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/world/ukraine&quot;>;Ukraine&lt;/a>;. And here, in Ukraine, all attention should be focused on defence, on responding to terrorists, on everything that Ukraine can do to get through the winter and improve our soldiers&#39; capabilities.“&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last winter, about 10 months into the invasion, Russia made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/oct/31/russia-assault-on-ukraine-power-grid-is-strategy-of-nihilism&quot;>;waves of attacks on power stations and other plants linked to the energy network&lt;/a>;, prompting rolling blackouts in widely disparate regions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The energy minister, German Galushchenko, said on Saturday that Ukraine would have enough energy resources to get through the winter, but added: “The question is how much future attacks can affect supplies.“&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ukrainian officials on Wednesday said Russia had struck Ukrainian infrastructure 60 times in recent weeks, an indication that a renewed campaign may already be under way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his remarks, Zelenskiy hailed the “heroic” efforts of troops defending Avdiivka, under pressure from attempted Russian advances since mid-October. Pictures have emerged showing buildings in the town reduced to hollow shells.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Military spokesperson Oleksandr Shtupun said the number of infantry attacks in the past 24 hours was at half of the levels earlier in the week, but air strikes were on the rise.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The enemy suffered significant losses the day before yesterday and has to regroup,” Shtupun told national television.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The head of Ukraine&#39;s ground forces, Gen Oleksandr Syrskyi, said on Telegram that Moscow&#39;s forces were “more active in the Bakhmut sector and trying to recover lost positions“.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhmut, north of the city of Donetsk, was captured by Russian forces in May after months of heavy combat, but Ukrainian troops have since retaken nearby villages.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Russian accounts of the fighting on Sunday said its forces had repelled five Ukrainian attacks near Bakhmut. Reuters could not verify accounts from either side.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Melitopol, a hub for Russian occupation forces, the blast killed three men during a meeting at a post office used as a military headquarters, Ukraine&#39;s military intelligence directorate said. The dead were officers of Russia&#39;s National Guard or FSB intelligence service, the directorate said in a statement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was no comment from Russian officials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s military has been increasingly active in attacking Russian-held areas, but does not always acknowledge the strikes.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 06:52:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>