<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[Ten people airlifted to safety after torrential rain in Scotland causes flooding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/oct/07/train-services-suspended-in-parts-of-scotland-with-heavy-rain-forecast]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T15:42:52Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0008ac3dadd82244f0d1a68bac8bb96b605fa986/0_186_5235_3141 /master/5235.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=26fe40a9823fe921ce6c3f8a485fa56c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;一名男子站立，水深没过膝盖。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;十人被空运至安全地点苏格兰各地的强降雨导致洪水和山体滑坡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个地区的天气警报仍然存在，旅行受到广泛干扰。英国气象局警告说，极端天气可能会对生命造成威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国海岸警卫队表示，在 A83 和 A83 公路发生山体滑坡后，多辆车辆被困，苏格兰警察局使用了一架直升机执行行动。阿盖尔比特西部地区的 A815。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方表示，没有人员伤亡报告，但两条道路仍然封闭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包括 M9 高速公路在内的许多其他道路都被封锁。周六早上遭受洪水袭击，许多火车服务已暂停。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国气象局发布黄色降雨预警，覆盖苏格兰大部分地区，预计低洼地区降雨量为 50-75 毫米，降雨量接近 100 毫米在地势较高的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;f290e74ae410f89dc1a783867851370f1a2589ed&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/f290e74ae410f89dc1a783867851370f1a2589ed/0_0_4975_2985 /1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;车辆移动穿过苏格兰敦巴顿被洪水淹没的道路。” width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;车辆驶过苏格兰敦巴顿被洪水淹没的道路。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;摄影：Jeff J Mitchell/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;周六凌晨 3 点至周日早上 6 点，苏格兰中部、泰赛德和法夫将发布单独的黄色警报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国气象局表示，该地区可能会迎来 150-180 毫米的降雨量。截至下午 4 点，苏格兰环境保护局 (Sepa) 已发布了 53 条本地化的&lt;a href=&quot;https://floodline.sepa.org.uk/floodupdates/&quot; >;苏格兰中部和北部地区发出洪水警告&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Avanti West Coast 建议苏格兰和普雷斯顿之间的乘客不要出行，并确认普雷斯顿以北不会有任何服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;曼彻斯特、利物浦、普雷斯顿至卡莱尔以及格拉斯哥和爱丁堡之间的 Transpenine Express 服务也受到影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些火车站，包括西邓巴顿郡的 Bowling 车站，轨道完全淹没在水中。苏格兰铁路网表示，附近的达尔缪尔双隧道的水泵“完全被淹没”，铁轨上的水“已达到火车窗户的高度”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏格兰国家铁路运营商 ScotRail 还宣布了一系列取消服务，影响到周日早上的服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从周六凌晨 1 点开始，在奥本、马莱格和威廉堡运营的西高地线将暂停。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;海伦斯堡中心/巴洛赫 (Helensburgh Central)/巴洛赫 (Balloch) 至达尔缪尔 (Dalmuir) 的服务也将停止，但达尔缪尔 (Dalmuir) 和格拉斯哥 (Glasgow) 之间的服务将继续运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;珀斯 (Perth) 和因弗内斯 (Inverness) 之间的高地干线 (Highland Main Line) 路线的服务也将停止。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;ScotRail 表示，作为安全预防措施，大多数其他路线已实施临时限速。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏格兰网络铁路公司还表示，为了公共安全，将实施限速&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 X（以前称为 Twitter）上，一位发言人表示：“由于极端降雨，部分地区发布了黄色和琥珀色警报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“180 毫米（一个月的量）可能会短短 36 小时内就会出现大面积洪水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在此期间，我们将关闭 3 条线路，并限制所有其他线路的速度，以确保每个人的安全。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sepa 的洪水值班经理，文森特·菲茨西蒙斯 (Vincent Fitzsimmons) 表示，他想“非常明确地表明，这对苏格兰来说不是正常的秋日”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们预计受影响地区将出现大范围的河流和地表水洪水。这对生命构成威胁，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这将对公路和铁路产生广泛的影响。存在发生更严重的社区规模财产洪水的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“许多地区将遭遇持续超过 24 小时的大雨，周日才会放晴。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏格兰交通部长菲奥娜 (Fiona)希斯洛普说：“人们在出发前计划好旅程非常重要。驾车者应确保路线畅通，遵循苏格兰警方的旅行建议并按照条件驾驶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果您计划乘坐火车、渡轮或飞机旅行，请咨询您的运营商看看这些情况是否对您的服务产生任何影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏格兰政府弹性室官员于周五下午开会，收集并评估来自英国气象局、国家环境保护局、苏格兰交通部、苏格兰警察局和苏格兰司法部长兼复原力部长安吉拉·康斯坦斯 (Angela Constance) 表示：“苏格兰政府和合作伙伴将继续密切关注局势，部长们正在不断更新。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，英国南部的天气预计将更加温和，英格兰东南部的气温预计将在周六高达 24 摄氏度，并保持在相同水平周日高。中部地区和威尔士也将是晴朗的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国气象局发言人奥利·克莱登 (Oli Claydon) 表示：“对于该国南半部的几乎所有人来说，天气都将是干燥的，并且气温异常温暖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当我们进入英格兰最北端并进入苏格兰时，差异就开始了，苏格兰各地有一些持续的大雨，尤其是在苏格兰西部。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;克莱登说，苏格兰的降雨将在周日向北移动，预计部分地区会出现干燥和更多云天气。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 23:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Iranian intellectual calls on opposition to unite as he is again sent to prison]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/07/iranian-intellectual-calls-on-opposition-to-unite-as-he-is-again-sent-to-prison]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T13:48:26Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a4dea2e050e5f429620d008b018d002063a93939/0_293_1806_1083 /master/1806.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=1787c9e1b530850d572cfc1651f62416&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Majid Tavakoli。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;伊朗最重要的公共知识分子和伊朗政权的批评者之一被带走周六戴着手铐入狱，开始服五年徒刑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/01/prominent-iranian-liberal -majid-tavokoli-set-to-be-sed-back-to-prison&quot;>;Majid Tavakoli&lt;/a>; 有一个三岁的孩子，被判犯有散布反国家宣传罪。他被送往监狱的时间被推迟了三周，但安全官员于周六将他带走，就在另一名伊朗人权活动家被监禁的第二天，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023 /oct/06/jailed-iranian-activist-narges-mohammadi-wins-2023-nobel-peace-prize&quot;>;Narges Mohammadi，&lt;/a>;被授予诺贝尔和平奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的照片社交媒体上流传着戴着手铐与妻子玛丽亚姆告别的消息。她在 X（以前称为 Twitter）上写了一首短诗，称这一天让她与自己的心分离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在明确自己没有进一步上诉的权利后，塔瓦科利同意接受《纽约时报》的采访。 《卫报》，他在其中承认目前不可能在国内组织政治反对派。他说：“回到监狱的前景让我变得脆弱和虚弱，因为我的家人充满了爱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他回忆说，在之前的监狱服刑期间，他不被允许做出任何事情。四年后的一个电话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说他已经入狱七年，其中包括一年单独监禁。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2023/sep/14/mahsa-amini-and-a-year-of-brutality-and-courage-in-iran- in-illustrations&quot;>;马赫萨·阿米尼和伊朗一年的残酷和勇气——插图&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;他批评反对派抗议活动缺乏计划，抗议活动是在阿米尼死后开始的。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2022/oct/31/mapping-irans-unrest-how-mahsa-aminis-death-led-to-nationwide-protests&quot; >;库尔德妇女马赫萨·阿米尼被警方拘留。&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说：“带来政治变革不是伊朗境内人民的任务，而是伊朗境外政治力量的任务。伊朗的政治气氛被政府通过监禁和清除知识分子和政治力量来严重操纵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我敦促伊朗以外的人开始坦诚地分析为什么广泛反对该政权的人接连失败。”他指责“缺乏变革的思想和动力”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“许多在这些领域工作过的人认为伊朗的核心问题是现代化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“未能实现现代化伊朗的现代化使我们无法像其他国家一样走上发展道路并达到我们想要的状态。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为伊朗社会作为一个整体已经接受了现代化，但这在政治领域并没有发生或政治体系的形成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，伊朗不同的反对派需要在对该国问题进行自我批评分析的基础上找到共同点，否则很难达成解决方案。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 22:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Off-duty US air force officer saves fallen climber on Yosemite’s Half Dome]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/oct/07/air-force-officer-rescues-climber-yosemite-half-dome]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T12:00:11Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ffd8149fb74438fbf55f460ca4ec1a84ed74113b/0_166_643_386 /master/643.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=690be010040f1bc42c35b27bb984eb8c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;优胜美地国家公园半圆顶 8,842 英尺高的山峰。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据 &lt;a href=&quot;https&quot; 报道，上个劳动节周末，美国空军值班飞行教官冒着强风、冰雹和湿滑的条件，营救了一名从约塞米蒂国家公园滑坡上跌落约 80 英尺（24.4 米）的登山者。 ://www.travis.af.mil/News/Article/3540503/everyday-heros-remarkable-rescue/&quot;>;军事部门&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约书亚·哈夫曼的英勇行动不仅为他赢得了荣誉空军同事们给予了英雄般的赞扬，但他们也阻止了另一场徒步旅行悲剧的发生，因为在过去的几个月里，多名徒步旅行者在一系列危险的情况下丧生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈夫曼，一名上尉正在尝试登顶优胜美地&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps?sca_esv=571342877&amp;amp;output=search&amp;amp;q=half+dome+yosemite&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;entry=mc&amp;sa =X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwj_98bYi-KBAxW5nGoFHayCAGUQ0pQJegUIrwEQAQ&quot;>;2023 年 9 月 2 日的半圆顶&lt;/a>;，当时他帮助解决的紧急情况展开了。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;ab1bfad8e7690e2439cbd5c3bd0597c867136eb3&quot;>; &lt;img src=“https” ://media.guim.co.uk/ab1bfad8e7690e2439cbd5c3bd0597c867136eb3/0_56_7267_4361/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023 年 9 月 23 日，约书亚·哈夫曼上尉站在特拉维斯空军基地的训练人体模型前。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;2023 年 9 月 23 日，约书亚·哈夫曼上尉站在特拉维斯空军基地的训练人体模型前。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：高级飞行员劳伦·雅各比/第 60 空中机动联队公共事务&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;半穹顶海拔 8,842 英尺（2.7 公里）。当哈夫曼在最后 400 英尺（122 米）时，他注意到一名登山者在沉闷、寒冷的环境中摔倒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈夫曼看着登山者从大约 80 英尺的高度坠落，落在一个仅约 6 英尺的壁架上（1.8 米）x 1.5 英尺（0.4 米）。这个空间是唯一将登山者与另一次至少 500 英尺（152 米）坠落的物体隔开的空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加利福尼亚州特拉维斯空军基地的飞行教官立即试图接近坠落的登山者，尽管部分坠落的登山者已经坠落。半圆顶的这一部分需要徒步旅行者通过困难的花岗岩表面。哈夫曼冒险越过永久性的电缆屏障，这些屏障是为了给登山者提供更多的安全性和杠杆作用，希望能够接近这位陷入困境的登山者，他带着急救箱成功做到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“其他登山者担心哈夫曼告诉特拉维斯基地的官员，该基地距离半圆顶约四个小时车程。 “所以我离开了电缆区域，爬上了壁架。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈夫曼很快就明白了为什么倒下的徒步旅行者会尖叫：他的腿被折断了。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id =&quot;5d44336263d5ee52c9ba3dbd98c6f2cc7e1e37ce&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/5d44336263d5ee52c9ba3dbd98c6f2cc7e1e37ce/0_64_1536_1920/800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;登山者等待 e 2023 年 9 月 2 日在优胜美地国家公园进行疏散。” width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;2023 年 9 月 2 日，登山者在优胜美地国家公园等待撤离。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：高级飞行员 Lauren Jacoby/第 60 空中机动联队公共事务部&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;“你可以看到他的腿根本没有自然定向，”哈夫曼说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈夫曼在走向伤者的路上收集了木棍。登山者。他将它们制成临时夹板，然后用它们将徒步旅行者固定在小腿骨折处的上方和下方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈夫曼还用绷带包裹了徒步旅行者受伤的脚踝，并用自己的夹克盖住了他，保护了他哈夫曼从那里安排了一个电话到公园管理员的站。空军官员说，他清楚地传达了他和受伤登山者在​​公园里的位置，帮助紧急救援人员找到了他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名专门从事搜救行动的公园护林员很快就到达了。护林员和哈夫曼帮助受伤的徒步旅行者从电缆梯上下来，然后另一名紧急救援人员带着完整的医疗包到达，其中包括更高质量的夹板。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，天气好转，更多的登山者到达帮助临时搭建一个帐篷。滑轮系统帮助受伤的徒步旅行者完成下降。直升机机组人员最终抵达，将徒步旅行者带离该地区并前往他当时需要的紧急护理处。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;25512dbf37362e8818e7f6eb822718c2f7100fbc&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media .guim.co.uk/25512dbf37362e8818e7f6eb822718c2f7100fbc/0_154_2048_1229/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023 年 9 月 2 日，登山者和优胜美地公园护林员挥舞直升机进行医疗后送。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;2023 年 9 月 2 日，登山者和优胜美地公园护林员示意一架直升机进行医疗后送。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：高级飞行员 Lauren Jacoby/第 60 空中机动联队公共事务&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;哈夫曼将他对生死攸关的情况做出有效反应的能力归功于他之前的攀爬经验以及他在某种类型的训练中的表现。急救称为战术战斗伤员护理。他说，他也很高兴自己保持了警惕，因为在他尝试登顶半圆顶的过程中，后期情况恶化得多么严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我知道一旦我登顶，人们就会遇到麻烦。哈夫曼说：“因为天气又冷又风大，人们绝望地想要下山。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并非每次此类旅行的千钧一发都会有美好的结果。 9 月 23 日，一名 61 岁的妇女沿着北卡罗来纳州蓝岭公园大道徒步&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/25/north-carolina-blue -ridge-parkway-glassmine-falls-fatal-fall&quot;>;从瀑布观景台坠落约 150 英尺&lt;/a>;后死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8 月，一名妇女在 &lt; 徒步旅行时从山上摔下来身亡a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/aug/12/woman-dead-falls-off-mountain-grand-teton-wyoming&quot;>;怀俄明州大提顿国家公园&lt;/a>; 。 7 月，一名搬运工在攀登世界第二高峰乔戈里峰时坠落身亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6 月，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023 /jun/26/man-and-teen-stepson-die-hiking-extreme-heat-big-bend-texas&quot;>;一名十几岁的男孩在 119 华氏度（48.3 度）的危险高温下徒步旅行时生病后死亡&lt;/a>; C) 在参观德克萨斯州西南部的大弯国家公园期间。然后男孩的继父在绝望地寻求帮助时撞车后被杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;八月的另一名十几岁男孩&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023 /aug/16/grand-canyon-teenager-fall-off-cliff&quot;>;从大峡谷的悬崖上 100 英尺处坠落&lt;/a>;幸存。这名少年在接受医院治疗后接受了伤势治疗，他在接受采访时表示，他意识到自己“离死亡只有几英寸的距离”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 20:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden accused of betrayal of Khashoggi over push to deepen Saudi ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/07/biden-saudi-arabia-mohammed-bin-salman-jamal-khashoggi]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T12:00:11Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6cd25191bfa0bdf984922aee109c72c5b9a2f10b/0_50_3369_2021 /master/3369.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=e37290ec55992f5d941d2b987bbee761&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;去年夏天拜登与王储在吉达。分析人士表示，“现实政治”促使华盛顿加深与沙特的关系。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;乔·拜登面临着背叛选举前承诺的指控，即因贾迈勒·卡舒吉被谋杀而重新评估与沙特阿拉伯的关系，以支持他寻求与沙特和解，旨在击退中国对美国在中东的主导地位的挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人权活动人士和一些民主党人在卡舒吉死于手中五周年之际提出了这一指控沙特政权特工的行为，正值华盛顿和利雅得之间拟议的新防御条约受到越来越多的批评，该条约可能导致沙特阿拉伯正式承认以色列。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/oct/02/ Five-years-after-killing-a-journalist-in-cold-blood-saudi-arabia-is-stronger-than -ever&quot;>;冷血杀害一名记者五年后，沙特阿拉伯比以往任何时候都更强大 |穆罕默德·巴齐&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;拜登上任之初打算淡化美国在中东的传统角色，这一政策与卡舒吉谋杀案引发强烈抗议后与沙特阿拉伯保持一定距离的政策一致.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但总统此后态度大转变，在访问该地区时表示，美国将“仍然是一个积极、参与的合作伙伴”，并补充道：“我们不会走开并留下一个真空将由中国、俄罗斯或伊朗填补。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分析人士称，去年 2 月俄罗斯入侵乌克兰引发国际制裁后，拜登政府与沙特阿拉伯的关系最初冷淡，开始升温。迫使西方国家寻求俄罗斯能源供应的紧急替代方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拜登去年7月访问了沙特首都利雅得，并与王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼举行了会谈。两人被拍到击拳致意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总统后来表示，他告诉王储，他个人对卡舒吉的谋杀负有责任，并补充说穆罕默德亲王否认有罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;政府后来裁定，王储享有国家元首豁免权，不受美国法院对卡舒吉谋杀案的任何裁决的影响，卡舒吉死前一直流亡在美国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vali约翰·霍普金斯大学国际事务和中东研究教授纳斯尔表示，有关政府放弃卡舒吉立场的指控是合理的。但他表示，去年三月中国促成沙特阿拉伯和伊朗恢复长期断绝的外交关系后，“现实政治”推动华盛顿深化关系，这被视为北京的一次重大地缘战略政变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “美国希望离间中国和沙特阿拉伯，”纳斯尔说。 “中国在海湾地区的参与不断增加一直是华盛顿的担忧，当中国能够解决沙特和伊朗之间的棘手问题时，它告诉华盛顿，中国对该地区的参与不仅仅是商业性的。”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;现在，沙特阿拉伯首相兼事实上的统治者穆罕默德亲王正在讨价还价，以达成一项协议 — — 其中可能包括安全保障和美国开发核能计划的技术 — — 以换取与以色列建立全面外交关系，拜登政府的一个珍贵目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙特领导人还敦促以色列对巴勒斯坦人做出让步，这对以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡领导的极右翼联合政府来说是一个潜在的绊脚石，该政府已承诺在被占领的约旦河西岸，在巴勒斯坦人声称是未来国家一部分的土地上建造更多定居点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙特持不同政见者、《华盛顿邮报》专栏作家卡舒吉在遭到国家袭击后遭到酷刑，然后被勒死2018 年 10 月 2 日，他进入沙特阿拉伯驻伊斯坦布尔领事馆，前往该领事馆领取即将结婚的文件。据报道，他的尸体被肢解，据报道是用骨锯，然后被处理掉的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央情报局随后的调查得出的结论是，这起谋杀案是按照穆罕默德亲王的命令实施的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;活动人士说最新的外交姿态玷污了卡舒吉的记忆，并违反了拜登的竞选承诺，即他的死“不会白费”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这不仅是对贾迈勒·卡舒吉的背叛，也是对数百万沙特阿拉伯人民的背叛。穆罕默德亲王不仅毁掉了拜登总统向美国人民做出的结束对这个独裁、反社会政府的支持的承诺，”卡舒吉被谋杀前几个月创建的民主组织黎明组织执行董事莎拉·利·惠特森 (Sarah Leigh Whitson) 表示。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在他更进一步，向美国承诺前所未有的安全保障，这将使美国军人有义务维护这个独裁者的统治。这是连特朗普政府都没有做到的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是美国必须不惜一切代价维持在中东的霸权和主导地位的一个可悲的反映，它的优先顺序被错位了，这是可悲的，因为我们现在生活在一个多极世界。”&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;1155b6078ebf00eac62e75130650d159ebfcb91f&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/1155b6078ebf00eac62e75130650d159ebfcb91f/0_0_347 8_2087/1000.jpg &quot; alt=&quot;贾迈勒·卡舒吉 (Jamal Khashoggi)，五年前在沙特驻伊斯坦布尔领事馆被谋杀。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;五年前在伊斯坦布尔的沙特领事馆被谋杀的 Jamal Khashoggi。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：Emrah Gürel/美联社&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;2020 年 10 月，在卡舒吉被谋杀两周年之际，拜登承诺他的政府将“重新评估我们与沙特王国的关系……并确保美国不会在卡舒吉被谋杀的门口检查其价值观”。出售武器或购买石油”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国对民主价值观和人权的承诺将是一个优先事项，即使与我们最亲密的安全伙伴也是如此，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在这些同样的价值观在 20 名民主党参议员签署一封信给拜登，表达了对拟议防御条约的担忧后，拜登所在政党的成员援引了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“需要提供大量证据来证明与沙特阿拉伯这个独裁政权经常损害美国在该地区的利益，其人权记录令人深感担忧，并奉行侵略性和鲁莽的外交政策议程，它符合美国的利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信中还要求以色列不要吞并约旦河西岸的任何部分，并停止在该领土上建设定居点，以实现拜登所宣称的“保留两国解决巴以冲突的选择”的目标。&lt;/纳斯尔表示：“美国的赌注比一位领导人的人权记录要大得多，因为它试图与中国玩一场更大的战略博弈，同时试图解决阿拉伯人和以色列之间的重大冲突。美国不会让这些问题服从其对贾迈勒·卡舒吉的立场。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战略与国际研究中心中东项目主任乔恩·奥尔特曼表示，还有其他因素促使美国采取行动，包括他说，内部改革带来了妇女权利和地位方面的进步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“沙特阿拉伯是一个拥有巨大可动用财富的国家。如果你考虑反恐的话，这是一个拥有强大情报能力的国家，”他说。 “这对全球能源市场很重要。它在许多其他方面都是一种资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你可以在中东制定一项试图压制沙特阿拉伯的美国政策，但如果你不能做到这一点，一切都会变得更加困难，也不会成功。沙特阿拉伯的支持。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在谈到卡舒吉被谋杀一事时，他说卡舒吉是他的朋友，奥尔特曼补充道：“我认为沙特阿拉伯不能纯粹通过这个棱镜来定义。犯罪。它需要更全面的观点，这不仅会让你对沙特阿拉伯感到厌恶，而且会做出更复杂和混乱的评估。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一份电子邮件声明中，白宫国家安全委员会发言人表示： “我们已经明确表示，并将继续这样做，残杀贾迈勒·卡舒吉是一项应受谴责的罪行。”发言人补充说，美国已与沙特阿拉伯建立了“战略伙伴关系”，以获取更多信息。 80 多年来，它被认为是“地区安全的基石，[并]造福于美国人民的利益”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们将继续推进我们的共同利益和共同愿景，一个更加安全、稳定和繁荣的地区，与世界互联互通。”声明补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们打算将人权保留在我们的双边议程上。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 20:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nobel peace prize winner joins calls for UN to criminalise gender apartheid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/law/2023/oct/07/nobel-peace-prize-winner-joins-calls-for-un-to-criminalise-gender-apartheid]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T11:59:48Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/bb5afd86def9f0a358339d5358383e991d08f7df/542_25_1921_1153 /master/1921.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=eb8b9371158d7acf9f9001270d22051a&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Narges Mohammadi&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;新任诺贝尔和平奖得主、被监禁的伊朗人权活动家&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/06/jailed-iranian-activist-narges-mohammadi-wins-2023-nobel-peace-prize&quot;>;纳尔吉斯·穆罕默德&lt;/a>;，与女性活动家和法律学者一起呼吁联合国扩大危害人类罪的计划定义，将性别种族隔离编入法典。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合国将于下周就危害人类罪条约草案进行辩论，她正在加入呼吁，通过在文件中纳入性别种族隔离来解决“问责真空”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其他倡导者包括前民主党总统候选人希拉里·克林顿、南非法官理查德·戈德斯通、作家格洛丽亚·斯泰纳姆、前联合国人权事务高级专员纳维·皮莱以及三位诺贝尔奖获得者希林·伊巴迪、马拉拉·优素福扎伊和纳迪亚·穆拉德。它还由前国际刑事法院首席检察官 Fatou Bensouda 博士签署。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-atom-id=&quot;156c786a-97ff-4ebf-9497-f311baae0189&quot; data-atom-type=&quot;media&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div style=&quot;font-size:0&quot;>; __YOUTUBE_MEDIA_PLACEHOLDER_156c786a-97ff-4ebf-9497-f311baae0189__ &lt;iframe id=&quot;gu-video-youtube-156c786a-97ff-4ebf-9497-f311baae0189&quot; src=&quot;https: //www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IFJbGwIRUIU?modestbranding=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;embed_config=%7B%22disableAds%22%3Atrue%2C%22nonPersonalizedAd%22%3Atrue%2C %22restrictedDataProcessor%22%3Atrue%2C%22adsConfig%22%3A%7B%22adTagParameters%22%3A%7B%22cmpGdpr%22%3A1%7D%7D%7D&quot;frameborder=&quot;0&quot;allowfullscreen>;&lt;/iframe>; &lt;/ div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;在致联合国的联名信中，作者也得到了许多阿富汗女性人权活动家的支持，他们说：“未能将性别种族隔离制度编入法典，导致问责真空长期存在，导致许多受害者这一呼吁专门针对塔利班压迫妇女等极端案件，但在一些伊斯兰国家可能会引起争议，因为这些国家的一些人对妇女的角色有不同的看法其统治者，不是征服，而是保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合国已经争论了 12 个月，如何就起诉和预防危害人类罪的公约或条约达成共识，这一过程预计将于 2024 年 10 月达到顶峰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;危害人类罪与战争罪不同，可以发生在和平时期，也可以由国家和非国家行为者实施。目前还没有国际商定的针对危害人类罪的普遍多边条约，更不用说防止危害人类罪了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者写道：“性别种族隔离犯罪的敌意和意图都是独一无二的。它与包括性别迫害在内的其他国际犯罪不同，因为它的反乌托邦野心是维持系统性压迫和统治的制度化政权，在这种政权中，下层阶级为了统治群体的利益和生存而被征服，被非人化，并被切断资源并需要获得克服他们精心设计的压迫的机会。塔利班对阿富汗妇女和女孩不断加深和制度化的压迫就是一个很好的例子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们认为，只要在条约草案中纳入 1998 年《罗马规约》中所规定的“种族隔离”定义即可。在国际刑事法院，联合国“不必要地受到 25 年来基于种族的种族隔离的阐述”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们补充道：“它没有考虑到基于性别的种族隔离，长期以来，得到了包括联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯在内的国际社会的认可。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“因此，追究肇事者（无论是国家还是个人）对整个事件负责的能力存在差距。性别种族隔离受害者所遭受的独特且往往是跨代的伤害。”通过其委员会，性别种族隔离的肇事者“寻求维持一种治理形式，旨在他们补充道：“系统地压迫和统治社会的一小部分人，以便占主导地位的群体可以与他们生活在一起，并从他们的征服中受益。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在阿富汗，塔利班系统地剥夺了女性生活的自主权和代理权。和期货。 The Taliban&#39;s system of governance has removed women and girls from public life – from parliament, offices, salons, universities and schools, parks and playgrounds, and protests – and sequestered them to the smallest possible concentric circle: a dot of existence behind their (or rather, their closest male relation&#39;s) front door.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 20:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Poll predicts landslide Labour election victory with 12 cabinet ministers losing their seats]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/oct/07/poll-predicts-landslide-labour-election-victory-with-12-cabinet-ministers-losing-their-seats]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T11:04:32Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0538bc7f0fa7bc75abe6327692757f1a3a515974/51_0_5421_3253/master/5421.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=4ac96ecfa4f935d3d39916d9a3c58e05&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Keir Starmer with MP Michael Shanks after victory in the Rutherglen and Hamilton West by-election&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Labour is currently on course to win a landslide victory on the scale of 1997, according to dramatic new modelling that points to the Conservatives losing every red wall seat secured at the last election.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tories could also lose more than 20 constituencies in its southern blue wall strongholds and achieve a record-low number of seats, according to a constituency-by-constituency model seen by the &lt;em>;Observer&lt;/em>;. Deputy prime minister Oliver Dowden, defence secretary Grant Shapps and leadership contender Penny Mordaunt are among those facing for defeat. Some 12 cabinet ministers face being unseated unless Rishi Sunak can close Labour&#39;s poll lead.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the model&#39;s central projection, which takes into account the new boundaries that the next election will be fought on, Labour would win 420 seats – equating to a landslide 190-seat majority. The Tories would take just 149 seats and the Lib Dems 23. The results mirror the 1997 landslide, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/oct/05/it-was-electrifying-the-inside-story-of-labours-1997-election-landslide&quot; title=&quot;&quot;>;Tony Blair&#39;s party secured a majority of 179 with 418 seats&lt;/a>;. The new analysis also suggests that the cost of living and the state of the NHS continue to be the clear priorities for voters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The huge study, commissioned by the 38 Degrees campaign group, has been carried out by the Survation polling company using a mega poll made up of more than 11,000 voters. A modelling technique called multilevel regression and post-stratification (MRP) has then been applied to reach constituency-level findings. Pollsters using the method successfully detected the swings ahead of the 2017 election.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While a 190-seat Labour majority is its average estimate, the modelling – based on polling carried out shortly before the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/oct/04/our-panels-verdict-on-rishi-sunaks-speech-to-the-tory-party-conference&quot; title=&quot;&quot;>;Tory conference last week&lt;/a>; – suggests Labour could have between 402 and 437 seats. The Tories could have between 132 and 169 seats. The results suggest a Labour majority between 154 and 224 seats.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every one of the 44 red wall seats that the Tories won at the last election would return to the Labour party, the analysis found. A further 22 so-called blue wall seats – defined as those held by the Tories in 2019, have a majority of Remain voters and a higher than average number of graduates – are also lost by the Conservatives.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Voters will want real guarantees of action to bring the dual cost of living and NHS crises under control for all of us&lt;/p>; &lt;footer>; &lt;cite>;Matthew McGregor, 38 Degrees&lt;/cite>; &lt;/footer>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The findings will be controversial among both parties members. Many Labour insiders are expecting the polls to close over the coming months as the election approaches. Senior figures in Sunak&#39;s team also believe they can target Labour leader Keir Starmer, whom they don&#39;t believe has been embraced by the public.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite Sunak&#39;s attempts to switch focus to his plans to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2023/oct/04/hs2-rishi-sunak-manchester-tory-conference-conservative-rail-latest-updates?page=with:block-651d2c068f0880e74add4d3a&amp;amp;amp;filterKeyEvents=false&quot; title=&quot;&quot;>;ban smoking, overhaul A-levels and ditch the northern leg of HS2&lt;/a>;, the analysis suggests that voters remain overwhelmingly focused on the cost of living and the state of the NHS.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In every single constituency, these two issues were most important to voters. Across the country, a third said they are “getting by, but making cutbacks” and 8% described themselves as “financially desperate”. More than two fifths (42%) said they had struggled to get a GP appointment in the past six months.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a major blow for Sunak, Labour has some significant leads in red wall seats. In Blyth Valley, the first red wall seat to be declared for the Tories in 2019, large Labour majorities are predicted. In Blyth and Ashington, Labour are ahead 49% to 22%. In Hartlepool, whose predecessor seat was won by the Conservatives for the first time in a 2021 byelection, Labour have a 38-point lead. In both constituencies, a quarter of voters said they were “worried about their financial future”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bassetlaw, whose predecessor seat saw the country&#39;s largest swing from Labour to the Tories in 2019, is predicted to return to Labour. The model suggests a 23-point lead with 12% of residents reporting they are “financially desperate”. Meanwhile, North Dorset – whose predecessor seat last elected a non-Conservative MP in 1945 – is predicted to fall to the Liberal Democrats. At 64% the NHS was a top issue for the highest proportion of this constituency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matthew McGregor, chief executive of 38 Degrees, said the findings suggested voters were “crying out for change” and warned Labour against being overly cautious. “With the spotlight this week on the Labour party&#39;s conference pledges, it&#39;s clear what voters will be looking for: real guarantees of action to help those most in need and bring the dual cost of living and NHS crises under control for all of us,” he said. “If they can&#39;t deliver that, there&#39;s no promise these polling results will hold.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“These are the issues which will dominate at the next election. Parties who are unconvincing, out of touch or distracted on these issues will rightly suffer at the polls.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results make it even less likely that Sunak and his team will opt for a spring election. Figures close to the PM are said to be opposed to a May vote, despite many MPs believing it may be in the party&#39;s interests to go for an earlier vote. Meanwhile many figures in the Labour party accept that a lack of clarity over Starmer&#39;s vision for power remains a vulnerability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Damian Lyons Lowe, chief executive of Survation, said: “Red wall seats, which were crucial to the Conservative&#39;s Brexit coalition, are all predicted to return to Labour. Furthermore, it is in seats with the highest proportion of Leave voters that the swing back to Labour is largest. Even traditional Conservative strongholds in the south-east and south-west are under threat from the Liberal Democrats and Labour.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Survation polled 11,793 people between 11-25 September&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 19:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Western Afghanistan hit by series of powerful earthquakes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/07/western-afghanistan-hit-by-series-of-powerful-earthquakes]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T11:21:00Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/81b50664b70df40df72bd5b1648de5d83c975519/0_72_2151_1291/master/2151.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=0b2e40e86895cbd84af51f86ada5b307&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Residents gather outside in Herat after the earthquakes&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A magnitude 6.3 earthquake has hit western Afghanistan, the United States Geological Survey said, followed by four large aftershocks with epicentres close to the region&#39;s largest city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least five powerful earthquakes struck Herat, resident Abdul Shakor Samadi said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The epicentre was 24.8 miles (40km) north-west of the city and was followed by an aftershock with a 5.5 magnitude, the USGS reported.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A map posted on the USGS website indicates seven earthquakes in the region, including a magnitude 5.9 earthquake 21.7 miles north-northwest of Herat, a 6.3 magnitude earthquake 20.5 miles north-north-east of Zindah Jan and another 6.3 magnitude earthquake 18 miles north-north-east of Zindah Jan, which is about 26 miles west of Herat city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“All people are out of their homes,” Samadi said. “Houses, offices and shops are all empty and there are fears of more earthquakes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Me and my family were inside our home, I felt the quake.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was no immediate comment from Taliban government officials on possible casualties or damage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Telephone connections were down, causing difficulties in obtaining precise details from the impacted areas. Social media videos showed hundreds of people in the streets outside their homes and offices in Herat city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heart province borders Iran. The quake was felt in the nearby provinces of Farah and Badghis, according to local media reports.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, a powerful earthquake struck a rugged, mountainous region of eastern Afghanistan, flattening stone and mud-brick homes. The quake was Afghanistan&#39;s deadliest in two decades, killing at least 1,000 people and injuring about 1,500.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The country is frequently hit by earthquakes, especially in the Hindu Kush mountain range, which lies near the junction of the Eurasian and Indian tectonic plates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afghanistan is already in the grip of a grinding humanitarian crisis, with the widespread withdrawal of foreign aid since the Taliban returned to power in 2021.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 19:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 1,000 birds died from colliding with one Chicago building in one day]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/07/chicago-mccormick-place-building-bird-deaths-windows]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T09:00:08Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/db899c4710731bb3388a091a7ae830e34f9de546/0_0_3954_2636/master/3954.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=861607236da3b8b93dcd40ee9e4b016d&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Several rows of dead birds.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At least 1,000 birds died from colliding into a single building in Chicago on Thursday, 5 October, as they migrated south to their wintering grounds. Volunteers are still recovering bird carcasses within 1.5 miles of McCormick Place, the largest convention center in North America, which is largely covered with glass.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/07/nyc-migrating-birds-night-lights-architecture&quot;>;New York&#39;s plan to save birds from crashing into buildings: lights out&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“It&#39;s the tip of an iceberg but it&#39;s it&#39;s a huge, huge amount of birds we found both dead and injured,” said Annette Prince, director of Chicago Bird Collision Monitors, adding that this was the highest number of bird strikes that the group recorded from the grounds of one building in a single day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From late Wednesday, 4 October, through early Thursday, 5 October, a peak estimate of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dashboard.birdcast.info/region/US-IL-031?night=2023-10-04&quot;>;1.5 million&lt;/a>; birds were in the air over Cook county, home to the Chicago metropolitan area. Carcasses of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Tennessee_Warbler/id#&quot;>;Tennessee warblers&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Hermit_Thrush/id#&quot;>;hermit thrush&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/American_Woodcock/id&quot;>;American woodcocks&lt;/a>; and other varieties of songbirds were recovered.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Not every bird that hits the window is going to leave behind a body,” said Brendon Samuels, who researches bird window collisions at the University of Western Ontario.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He noted that the true extent of affected birds will unravel over a couple of days as people continue to pick up birds around downtown Chicago.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In fact, we often see birds collide with glass and they continue flying some distance away, seriously injured in ways that ultimately they won&#39;t survive past a few hours,” Samuels added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Birds &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/07/nyc-migrating-birds-night-lights-architecture&quot;>;dying&lt;/a>; in large numbers in a small geographic area tends to occur during peak migration periods in spring and fall. Weather conditions like opposing wind, rain and fog can make it difficult for birds to orientate themselves, in addition to light pollution from cities that can draw them in and trap them among deadly structures.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Anywhere you&#39;ve got glass, you&#39;re gonna have birds hitting the windows,” said Bryan Lenz at the American Bird Conservancy. Annually, up to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcbirds.org/blog/truth-about-birds-and-glass-collisions/&quot;>;billion&lt;/a>; birds die due to collisions, and in the case of Chicago, the dead and injured birds were most likely flying from Canada en route to South and Central America.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everywhere birds visit, they perform essential ecosystem services that have economic value and are necessary for the functioning of ecosystems. Following major wildfires like those in Canada, birds that return to burned areas can disperse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0006320712004247#:~:text=Remnant%20trees%20or%20artificial%20perches,shrubs%20in%20post%2Dfire%20areas.&quot;>;seeds&lt;/a>; and aid forest landscape regeneration. Global increases in temperatures contribute to the increase in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.usda.gov/ccrc/topics/insect-disturbance-and-climate-change#:~:text=forest%20insect%20species.-,In%20some%20cases%2C%20larger%20and%20more%20frequent%20insect%20outbreaks%20may,to%20forest%20insect%20population%20growth.&quot;>;insect populations&lt;/a>;, and birds that feed on them can help curb the issues that pose a threat for humans and food systems.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of all cities in the US, Chicago&#39;s light pollution poses the greatest risk for migrating birds. Turning off building lights is one way to reduce fatalities. A 2021 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/doi/full/10.1073/pnas.2101666118&quot;>;study&lt;/a>; done in McCormick Place, the same site of Thursday&#39;s bird deaths, found that shutting off half the lights in large buildings can reduce collisions by six to 11 times. McCormick Place is a participant of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mccormickplace.com/birds/&quot;>;Lights Out Chicago&lt;/a>; program, which has buildings voluntarily switch off or dim lights at night unless someone is inside.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is important to understand that there is an event going on at Lakeside Center [part of McCormick Place] this week, so, therefore, the lights have been on when occupied. Once the space is unoccupied, the lights have been turned off,” said a representative from McCormick Place.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It&#39;s a known hazard, and yet we still can&#39;t see action being taken about it,” says Prince.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having window glass with visual markers like dots or patterns can break up the appearance of reflection and let birds recognize whether there is a safe passage for them to fly through.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Chicago approved a bird-friendly design ordinance but it is yet to take effect. In 2021, the Illinois governor, JB Pritzker, signed the Bird Safe Buildings Act, which “requires bird-friendly design to be incorporated into the construction and renovation of state-owned buildings” in the state, per &lt;a href=&quot;https://gl.audubon.org/news/new-law-will-protect-illinois-birds-deadly-building-collisions&quot;>;Audobon.org&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have a lot of existing buildings that are killing birds, not just new construction,” said Samuels, adding that investments in retrofits, creating tax credits for such environmental initiatives and making windows more bird-friendly can be an economical way to solve this. “We already have solutions, we just need to put those into policy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 17:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia-Ukraine war live: buildup of trains on Russia-North Korea border reported; Moscow strikes Odesa grain infrastructure]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2023/oct/07/russia-ukraine-war-latest-updates-putin-zelenskiy]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T08:45:57Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/1845cca91292fdf5540637e24185a1b178b07f4f/0_279_2961_1778/master/2961.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=db23541b1f2b9e583563904ebd616973&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;A residential building hit in a Russian missile attack in Kharkiv, Ukraine.&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 16:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel declares state of war after Hamas launches ‘5,000 rockets and attacks with ground troops’ – live]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2023/oct/07/hamas-launches-attack-on-israel-with-5000-rockets-live]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T06:49:38Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/69dbc664eb65da448b3b48a3c51be0bc6737ab90/0_58_2835_1701 /master/2835.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=c2a0ec7510473336584a9927a45e8937&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;巴勒斯坦人发射的火箭的视图 &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 14:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hamas launches surprise attack on Israel as Palestinian gunmen reported in south]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/07/hamas-launches-surprise-attack-on-israel-as-palestinian-gunmen-reported-in-south]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T05:40:58Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/3445b56532cec36104edc99501c304485ef153e0/0_210_5500_3300 /master/5500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=e6b1764946ac688da09d3b3d4cd2b824&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;以色列阿什凯伦加沙发射火箭袭击的后果。哈马斯表示已向以色列发射了 5,000 枚火箭弹。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦枪手已渗透到以色列南部地区，周六从加沙地带发射了火箭弹，伊斯兰运动哈马斯声称这是一次突然袭击。&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>;哈马斯高级军事指挥官穆罕默德·代夫在哈马斯媒体广播中宣布行动开始，呼吁各地巴勒斯坦人进行战斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是巴勒斯坦人民最伟大战斗的一天。结束地球上最后的占领，”他说，并补充说已经发射了 5,000 枚火箭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据紧急服务部门称，当救护人员部署在加沙地带周围地区并拉响警报时，一名以色列妇女被杀响彻以色列各地，包括耶路撒冷。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;141d5e22c1ed97ba6711a4656e2d84adeed57221&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/141d5e22c1ed97ba6711a4656e2d84adeed57221/0_59_6146_368 8/1000.jpg&quot; alt= “2023 年 10 月 7 日，火箭从加沙城向以色列发射。” width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;2023 年 10 月 7 日从加沙城向以色列发射火箭。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;摄影：Mahmud Hams/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span >; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;以色列媒体报道称，枪手在以色列南部的斯德洛特镇向路人开枪，社交媒体上流传的视频似乎显示了城市街道上的冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;军方在一份声明中表示，“一些恐怖分子已从加沙地带渗透到以色列领土”，并补充说加沙地带周边地区的居民已被告知留在家中。&lt;/p>; &lt;旁白>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/04/gaza-strip-protesters-received-bullet-wounds-to -ankles-medics-report&quot;>;医务人员报告称，加沙地带抗议者脚踝受弹伤&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“以色列国防军将保护以色列平民，哈马斯恐怖组织将付出代价它说：“它的行动付出了沉重的代价”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它还表示正在对加沙地带发动自己的袭击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡的办公室表示，他将与高级安全官员会面在接下来的几个小时内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在加沙，可以听到发射的轰鸣声，居民报告说，在南部城镇汗尤尼斯附近，与以色列的隔离围栏沿线发生了武装冲突，并表示他们看到武装战士的大量行动.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列救护车服务部门表示，已向以色列南部加沙附近地区派遣救护队。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 13:52:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>