<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[Large-scale warfare occurred in Europe ‘1,000 years earlier than previously thought’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/science/2023/nov/02/large-scale-warfare-occurred-in-europe-1000-years-earlier-than-previously-thought]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T20:01:30Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/61a9c30aec3b53a4fb7d651979432b412a2d927a/0_26_1711_1026 /master/1711.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=65d7f742344d1cc0d4e63a3474beb2f0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;西班牙北部里奥哈阿拉韦萨地区浅洞穴中的集体墓地中的骨骼遗骸&lt;/div>;&lt; p>;研究人员认为，欧洲最早的战争时期可能发生在之前被认为是该地区第一次大规模冲突的 1000 多年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对 300 多组数据的重新分析西班牙发现的大量骨骼遗骸（放射性碳可追溯到 5,400 至 5,000 年前）表明冲突早在该地区形成强国之前就已发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受损骨骼的数量和男性比例过高发表在《科学报告》上的一项研究的作者表示，表明这些伤口是由一段冲突时期造成的，可能持续至少几个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该研究重新检查了来自一群人的 338 具遗骸。西班牙北部里奥哈阿拉韦萨地区一个浅洞穴中的墓地。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;77357929b5aedf5cb4ce81a3c05aab0aa4949c1c&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/77357929b5aedf5cb4ce81a3c05aab0aa4949c 1c/ 0_0_835_1042/801.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;研究中记录的多个头骨中未愈合的颅骨损伤&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;研究中记录的未愈合的颅骨损伤。&lt;/span >; &lt;span>;照片：科学报告&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;研究人员发现，当时的受伤率要高得多，23.1% 的人有骨骼损伤的证据，10.1% 的人有骨骼损伤的证据&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者还发现，74.1%的未愈合损伤和70.0%的已愈合损伤发生在青少年或成年男性，显着高于女性个体，且差异不显着。在其他欧洲新石器时代大规模死亡遗址中也曾出现过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该遗址还发现了 52 个燧石箭头，其中 36 个因击中目标而受到轻微损坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上一页研究表明，冲突由持续几天的短期袭击组成，涉及最多 20 至 30 人的小团体，并且人们认为早期社会缺乏支持更长期、更大规模冲突的后勤能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;欧洲最早的此类冲突此前被认为发生在青铜器时代，距今约4000年至2800年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体受伤率，男性受伤率较高，治愈率相对较高伤害，表明冲突持续了几个月，而之前观察到的箭头损坏使作者得出结论，墓地的许多人都遭受过暴力，可能是战争伤亡。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;作者表示，冲突的原因尚不清楚，但他们推测，这可能是由于新石器时代晚期（公元前 3000 年至公元前 1600 年）该地区不同文化群体之间的紧张关系造成的。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rats may have power of imagination, research reveals]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/science/2023/nov/02/rats-may-have-power-imagination-research]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T18:43:51Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/8e76ab2ca8429dbb2740f997fb2487a5a5a3eced/0_874_4370_2622 /master/4370.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=367a50977fe7036437800651254ff0cd&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;一只棕色的老鼠&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;无论是梦想着一个白色的圣诞节，还是只是在思考如何最好地过一个白色的圣诞节重新布置家具，人类能够想象出无数不在我们面前的情况。现在看来，老鼠也许能够做类似的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员发现，老鼠可以仅用自己的思想在之前探索过的空间中导航，这表明啮齿动物具有某种想象力。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;该研究的第一作者、来自霍华德休斯医学研究所珍妮莉亚研究园的 Chongxi Lai 表示，这项研究首次表明动物可以随意灵活地激活大脑对远处地点的表征。他们目前所处的位置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是特定类型想象力的基本组成部分，它使我们能够在特定场景内将自己投射到过去或未来，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adh5206&quot;>;在《科学》杂志上撰文&lt;/a>;，研究人员指出，大脑的一个区域称为海马体包含一种心理模型或地图，描绘了以前探索过的环境。当一个人在这样的环境中穿过特定位置时，特定的神经元会在大脑中放电。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，人类可以随意想象通过他们以前访问过的地方的路线 - 例如，走廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了探索老鼠是否能做到同样的事情，并找出可能的机制，研究人员采用了脑机接口，通过手术将电极植入老鼠的大脑中。然后将老鼠放在 360 度沉浸式虚拟现实 (VR) 竞技场中的跑步机球上，并在屏幕上显示要跑向的目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着老鼠的移动，跑步机球也会随之移动。反过来，动物在 VR 环境中的明显位置会在屏幕上更新，就像老鼠在真实环境中奔跑时会发生的情况一样。当老鼠到达目标时，它们会收到奖励，目标也会在 VR 环境中移动。然后重复这个过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个初始阶段，团队记录了动物海马体内的活动。然后，他们使用计算机系统将这种神经活动转移到 VR 环境中的特定位置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，研究人员将跑步机与 VR 系统解耦。这意味着老鼠无法通过在跑步机上跑步达到目标。相反，他们只能利用大脑活动在 VR 环境中导航。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过在任务期间实时分析老鼠海马体的活动，团队能够每 100 毫秒更新一次屏幕根据动物大脑中发生的情况，确定动物在 VR 环境中的当前位置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结果表明，老鼠确实可以仅通过大脑活动导航到目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在随后的实验中，研究小组给老鼠布置了一项“绝地任务”，其中动物本身静止不动，但必须仅利用它们的大脑活动将屏幕上的物体引导到 VR 环境中的特定目标。老鼠再一次做到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍华德休斯医学研究所这项研究的另一位作者蒂姆·哈里斯教授表示，人们认为人类的想象力和记忆力与大脑的活动有关。海马体与现实生活中的情况相似。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为此，可以公平地说，老鼠确实会想象，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; &lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 02:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Aerosmith singer Steven Tyler accused in new lawsuit of sexual assault]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/nov/02/steven-tyler-sexual-assault-allegation-lawsuit]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T18:29:01Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/48611a41b65cddb8e4c969134b97253cf557b20c/148_2_3352_2011 /master/3352.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=b6ce5e8a7ba350c35c30465e01b27413&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;史蒂文·泰勒 (Steven Tyler) 于 2019 年在洛杉矶参加一次活动。《滚石》报道了诉讼的详细信息。&lt;/div >;&lt;p>;史密斯飞船歌手史蒂文·泰勒 (Steven Tyler) 面临新的性侵犯指控，周四在纽约提起诉讼，声称他在 1970 年代的一次遭遇中猥亵了一名 17 岁女孩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-news/steven-tyler- Sex-assault-second-woman-lawsuit-1234868124/&quot;>;《滚石》周四报道了详细信息&lt;/a >;，其中称，前儿童模特珍妮·贝利诺 (Jeanne Bellino) 据称在被这位现年 75 岁的音乐家强行抚摸和亲吻后，遭受了“永久性的情绪困扰”和其他状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泰勒，其乐队目前正在美国各地进行告别和平巡演，已经面临一项诉讼。该诉讼去年在加利福尼亚州提起，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2022/dec/30/aerosmith-steven-tyler-lawsuit- Sex-battery-assault&quot;>;指控性殴打和在同一十年的三年时间里，他因与当时 16 岁的朱莉娅·霍尔科姆·米斯利 (Julia Holcomb Misley) 的关系而袭击了一名未成年人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贝利诺 (Bellino) 是一名在曼哈顿参加时装秀的青少年。据滚石杂志报道，1975 年夏天，一位朋友安排她在附近的一家酒店与 Aerosmith 见面。诉讼称，泰勒在他们在一起的唯一一天里对她进行了两次性侵犯，一次是在电话亭里，她说，他把她推了进去，然后摸索并摩擦了她；后来在酒店，她声称泰勒强行吻了她并再次用身体抵住她。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该出版物称，泰勒的一名律师和乐队的代表没有立即回复置评请求，泰勒在被指控的袭击发生时年龄约为 27 岁。 《卫报》已分别联系了泰勒的经纪公司和公关代表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《滚石》报道，贝利诺的诉讼寻求未具体说明的损害赔偿，并以“性别动机的暴力”作为诉讼理由。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管所指控的事件发生在半个多世纪前，但诉讼称贝利诺“已经并将继续遭受精神和身体的巨大痛苦，严重和永久性的情绪困扰，情绪困扰的身体表现，尴尬，羞辱，身体，个人与”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;声明还声称，她“因这起事件而住院并接受了药物治疗”，现在仍在服用药物“以应对性侵犯，并遭受了与性侵犯相关的长期身体伤害”。贝利诺说，所谓的电话亭袭击事件发生在乐队和几名随行人员离开曼哈顿沃里克酒店沿着第六大道散步时。她说，在走路时，她问泰勒一个关于一首令他沮丧的歌词的问题，他强迫她进入售货亭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在俘虏她的同时，泰勒将舌头伸进她的喉咙，然后把据《滚石》报道，诉讼称，他的双手放在她的身体、胸部、臀部和生殖器上，移动并脱掉衣服，并将她按在电话亭的墙上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“泰勒殴打并抚摸原告，他假装与原告发生性关系，假装与原告发生性关系。其他人站在电话亭外大笑，路人围观并目睹，随行人员中没有人介入。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诉讼进一步指出：“泰勒的阴茎是勃起的，当他用它摩擦时，她很明显她说他没有穿内裤，穿着薄裤。”她说，她抬起膝盖，拉扯泰勒的头发，释放了自己，然后“震惊和恐惧”地从电话亭跑了出去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贝利诺说，她依靠朋友的交通，并陪同乐队返回所谓的第二次袭击发生的酒店。她说泰勒在酒吧区附近强行亲吻和摩擦她，然后消失在他的房间里，并表示他会打电话给她。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当电话打来时，她声称，她非常害怕“无法说话，瘫痪了”，然后跑向出口，被看到她痛苦的门童“扔”进出租车。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文章没有说明为什么贝利诺没有挺身而出这些指控已经持续了近 50 年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该案与加州诉讼中的指控相似，米斯利在该诉讼中表示，她&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/tv- and-radio/2021/sep/13/look-away-review-horrifying-stories-of-abuse-at-the-hands-of-male-rock-stars&quot;>;在泰勒 16 岁时成为她的情人&lt;/a>; ，说他利用自己作为著名明星的影响力在几个月内“培养、操纵、利用和性侵犯”她。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的影响力扩大到说服米斯利的父母允许他成为她的合法伴侣据称，他可以带她跨越州界而不必担心被捕。泰勒否认米斯利的攻击和殴打指控，但否认他与她发生性关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该案件是根据一项州法律提起的，该法律暂时延长了成年人对性虐待采取法律行动的时效期限。童年时期遭受苦难。&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;以下组织可为任何受强奸或性虐待问题影响的人提供信息和支持。在美国，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rainn.org/&quot;>;Rainn&lt;/a>; 通过 800-656-4673 提供支持。在英国，&lt;a href=&quot;https://rapecrisis.org.uk/&quot;>;Rape Crisis&lt;/a>; 提供支持电话：0808 500 2222。在澳大利亚，可以通过 &lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.1800respect.org.au/&quot;>;1800Respect&lt;/a>; (1800 737 732)。其他国际帮助热线可在 &lt;a href=&quot;http://ibiblio.org/rcip/internl.html&quot;>;ibiblio.org/rcip/internl.html&lt;/a>; 找到。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt; /li>; &lt;/ul>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 02:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Storm Ciarán: Seven people killed and dozens injured in Europe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/02/storm-ciaran-people-killed-injured-storm-ciaran-batters-europe-wind-rain]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T16:55:58Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7afcfb48cb46910ecbc6212cf5e9cdd8b26c8aa8/0_10_4872_2923 /master/4872.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=3d54c409be91035da88e4e6f93dc6a63&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;2023 年 11 月 2 日，海浪袭击法国西部波尔斯波德的 Phare du Four（四号灯塔）塞兰袭击了该地区。 &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;席伦风暴席卷欧洲西北部，带来倾盆大雨和时速高达 200 公里/小时（124 英里/小时）的大风，造成至少 7 人死亡、数十人受伤，房屋受损，学校被迫关闭，航空公司和航空公司被迫关闭。当局周四表示，法国北部埃纳省的一名卡车司机被倒下的树砸死，超过 120 万人失去了电力供应，其中大约一半的人失去了电力供应。布列塔尼的人口。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;勒阿弗尔一名 70 岁的男子在一场事故中从阳台坠落身亡，警方称这起事故与席伦风暴破纪录的大风有关；而在西班牙，一名妇女在事故中丧生。马德里市中心一棵树倒下压在她身上，造成三人受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比利时根特市中心有两人被掉落的树枝击中身亡。其中一名受害者年龄5岁，另一名受害者是一名64岁的德国妇女，正在比利时旅游。当局称，港口城市安特卫普的一座高墙在创纪录的大风中倒塌，造成三分之一人受重伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在荷兰南部省份文莱 (Venray)，一人被树压死。林堡省当地媒体称。全国各地至少有 10 人因飞扬的碎片受伤，其中至少三人伤势严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian .com/uk-news/2023/nov/02/storm-ciaran-schools-close-travel-disrupted-uk-amber-warning&quot;>;风暴夏兰：风雨袭击英国，学校关闭，出行中断&lt;/a>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;德国消防部门周四还表示，一名来自巴伐利亚的 46 岁妇女与丈夫和两个孩子一起家庭度假，在外出时被倒下的树砸死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当巨浪冲击法国港口和海岸线时，包括七名消防员在内的 15 人因倒下的树木受伤，主要发生在布列塔尼，菲尼斯特雷当局敦促人们留在当地在家躲避时速 207 公里/小时（129 英里/小时）的大风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;地方当局关闭了公园、森林和海滨，取消了当地火车，并关闭了菲尼斯特雷的所有道路。超过 1,300 人被重新安置，主要是从营地转移，布雷斯特的几所房屋在起重机倒塌后被疏散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周四上午，法国大陆几乎所有海岸线都收到了恶劣天气警报。在北部加莱海峡地区，当局为希望乘小船前往英国的移民开设了健身房和庇护所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国交通部长克莱门特·博纳 (Clément Beaune) 敦促人们避免驾车并谨慎行事穿越有天气警告的地区时。博纳对法国信息广播电台说：“我们看到在这种情况下道路可能会致命。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两周前的风暴“巴贝特”之后，风暴“塞兰”是由一股强大的急流驱动的，该急流从大西洋，带来暴雨和创纪录的大风，已经在北爱尔兰和英国部分地区造成严重洪水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;铁路和轮渡服务，包括连接荷兰、比利时、法国、德国和英国的欧洲之星英国经历了取消和延误，荷兰国家航空公司 KLM 取消了所有往返荷兰的航班。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第八届荷兰全国逆风自行车锦标赛在 8.5 公里（5.3 公里）的赛道上举行-mile) 当西南大风超过七级时，Oosterscheldekering 风暴潮屏障被匆忙组织起来，但后来因为风力太强而取消。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;荷兰天气预报员 Roosmarijn Knol 表示，风暴发生的时间已经确定特别是对倒下的树木数量产生重大影响。 “由于秋天温暖，雨水较多，树木仍然有叶子，地面像海绵一样潮湿，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这意味着特别是弱树有很好的机会跌倒。这与 11 月底的秋季风暴有很大不同，当时所有的树叶都已经落下。”Knol 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;远至西班牙南部都感受到了风暴的影响。葡萄牙多个地区处于红色警戒状态，倒下的树木导致停电，火车服务中断。西班牙当局警告北大西洋沿岸海浪高达 9 米，西班牙机场运营商表示 42 个航班被取消。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 02:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Suspect in 1996 murder of Tupac Shakur pleads not guilty]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/nov/02/tupac-shakur-murder-las-vegas-nevada]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T18:03:12Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/90dfed78f7ec8af8caff0d1ed2eb1db7fbe454d0/0_814_2744_1646 /master/2744.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=b9171de99baa7df60e507028f7ed6715&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;年轻黑人的黑白特写，大眉毛和修剪胡须，右手手指上有大戒指，他将下巴靠在上面。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>; 周四，一名前南加州街头帮派头目对策划 1996 年在拉斯维加斯杀害图帕克·沙库尔 (Tupac Shakur) 的驾车枪击事件表示无罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜安·基思·“凯夫·D”·戴维斯 (Duane Keith “Keffe D” Davis) 是开枪的车内唯一还活着的人，也是该案中唯一被指控犯罪的人，他戴着手铐站在克拉克县地方法官蒂拉·琼斯 (Tierra Jones) 面前.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周四，特别公设辩护律师罗伯特·阿罗约和查尔斯·卡诺代表戴维斯出庭。周三，戴维斯未能聘请辩护律师罗斯·古德曼。两周前，古德曼曾表示，检察官缺乏 27 年前谋杀案的证人和关键证据，包括枪支或车辆。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/nov/01/tupac-shakur-las-vegas-murder&quot;>;被指控杀害 Tupac Shakur 的男子失去了律师代理权&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt; /aside>; &lt;p>;在周四提出认罪之前，戴维斯穿着深蓝色监狱服，回答了一系列简短的问题，告诉法官他已经上过“大学一年”，没有受到任何毒品的影响、药物或酒精，并且他知道自己被指控谋杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;7c1fed1350e2c3cab9bf2342eef055077c12588c&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/7c1fed1350e2c3cab9bf2342eef055077c12588c /0_156_6329_3799/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;年长的黑人男子，秃头，全套椒盐装备，坐在一张黑色椅子上，旁边是桌子后面的两张空椅子。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;60 岁的 Duane &#39;Keffe D&#39; Davis 于 2023 年 10 月 19 日因谋杀指控在拉斯维加斯法庭出庭。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：John Locher/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;戴维斯，60 岁，来自加利福尼亚州康普顿。 9 月 29 日，他在内华达州亨德森郊区的一处住宅外被捕，拉斯维加斯警方于 7 月 17 日向该处发出搜查令，重新引起人们对嘻哈音乐最持久的谜团之一的关注。戴维斯仍被监禁，不得保释，没有在起诉他的大陪审团面前作证，并拒绝出狱接受美联社采访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;起诉书称戴维斯获得了一把枪并将其提供给后面的某人在拉斯维加斯大道附近的一个十字路口，一辆凯迪拉克汽车的座位上发生了汽车对汽车的交火，沙库尔和说唱音乐大亨马里昂·“苏格”·奈特(Marion “Suge” Knight)受了致命伤。一周后沙库尔去世。他当时 25 岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knight 现年 58 岁，因 2015 年谋杀一名康普顿商人而被判 28 年徒刑，目前在加利福尼亚州监狱服刑。他尚未回复通过律师寻求评论的信息。戴维斯被捕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察官声称，沙库尔在拉斯维加斯被杀是东海岸血帮帮派成员与包括戴维斯在内的西海岸克里普斯帮派成员之间争夺音乐流派主导地位的结果被称为“黑帮说唱”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大陪审团被告知，1996 年 9 月 7 日在拉斯维加斯发生的枪击事件是对几个小时前在拉斯维加斯大道赌场发生的斗殴事件的报复，涉及沙库尔和戴维斯的侄子奥兰多“宝贝巷”安德森。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;70f92dcd5aa332ae95b2a193cbd072cd16c29b44&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/70f92dcd5aa332ae95b2a193cbd072cd16c29b44/0_10_7100_4258/ 1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;夜间照片黑色轿车的右侧，车门和乘客车窗上都有弹孔。” width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;1996 年 9 月在拉斯维加斯，说唱歌手 Tupac Shakur 被枪杀的汽车。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：拉斯维加斯大都会警察局/美联社&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;检察官告诉大陪审团，戴维斯在多次采访和 2019 年的回忆录中将自己卷入了这起谋杀案，该回忆录描述了他在康普顿领导克里普斯教派的生活。戴维斯表示，他获得了一把 .40 口径手枪，并将其交给了坐在凯迪拉克后座上的戴维斯团伙成员安德森，但他没有透露安德森就是枪手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;安德森当时 22 岁的他否认参与杀害沙库尔，并于两年后在家乡康普顿的一次枪击事件中死亡。凯迪拉克车的另一名后座乘客和司机也死了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;戴维斯在书中写道，他在 2010 年向当局透露了他所知道的沙库尔和帮派竞争对手 Notorious BIG 被杀的情况，该组织的法律他的名字叫克里斯托弗·华莱士 (Christopher Wallace)，为了保护自己和 48 名 Southside Compton Crips 帮派同伙免遭起诉和被判处无期徒刑的可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;华莱士，又名 Biggie Smalls，在洛杉矶被枪杀1997 年 3 月，即 Shakur 去世六个月后。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shakur 在很大程度上被认为是有史以来最有影响力和多才多艺的说唱歌手之一。他拥有五张排名第一的专辑，获得六项格莱美奖提名，于 2017 年入选摇滚名人堂，并于今年在好莱坞星光大道上获得了一颗追随明星。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 02:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mpox circulated for five years before global explosion in 2022, research says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/02/mpox-monkeypox-circulated-global-explosion-in-2022]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T18:00:02Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4b600c9f574c9591cf03a73440cf6bcac90c9045/0_1_5392_3235 /master/5392.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=9d4e7885c93abf760aa8d5d794628f4f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;2022 年在加利福尼亚州洛杉矶的临时疫苗接种诊所制备的 Mpox 疫苗。&lt;/div>;&lt;研究人员表示，这种以前被称为猴痘的疾病在 2022 年以前所未有的爆发方式在世界各地传播，在病例激增引发全球公共卫生紧急事件之前，该疾病已在人类中传播了五年多。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;发现人与人之间长期存在的隐性传播，促使人们呼吁加强对 MPXV 病毒的全球监测，以消除这种疾病，该疾病已更名为 &lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/列出/标签/世界/猴痘“去年，mpox&lt;/a>;来自人类，并防止其再次出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“任何新的或新生的疫情都有可能蔓延到全球，”博士说爱丁堡大学的进化生物学家艾娜·奥图尔（Áine O&#39;Toole）研究了病毒的进化。 “即使在病例数很少的情况下，我们也需要集中精力检测疫情，并找到一种方法，在它在人群中蔓延之前将其消灭。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mpox 首次被发现于 20 世纪 50 年代，当时 Mpox 爆发了。疾病袭击了实验室里进行研究的猴子。 1970 年，刚果民主共和国 (DRC) 记录了第一例人类病例。未来 50 年的散发病例主要发生在刚果民主共和国和尼日利亚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020 年之前，大多数人类 MPOX 感染被归咎于与该疾病流行国家中携带该病毒的啮齿动物的接触。在极少数情况下，人们会传播感染，受影响的人通常是住在同一屋檐下的家庭成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，全球性mpox疫情却有所不同。奥图尔和她的同事在《科学》杂志上撰文，描述了 2022 年从患者身上收集的病毒如何传播到更远的地方突变比预期更多。 mpox 病毒预计每三年就会出现一次突变，但与 2018 年在尼日利亚收集的病毒相比，2022 年患者身上的 mpox 出现了多达 42 个突变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仔细观察发现，大多数突变是由人类免疫系统的冲突引起的，特别是一种名为 apobec3 的抗病毒酶。这一发现意味着人类免疫系统正在推动病毒的进化，标志着病毒已转向在人类中持续传播。根据突变率，科学家估计 mpox 至少从 2016 年起就在人类中传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全球 mpox 爆发是由一种名为 B.1 的谱系驱动的，自 2016 年以来，MPOX 病例一直在下降。公共卫生建议和疫苗接种计划主要针对男男性行为者，他们占病例的绝大多数。但研究人员指出，英国、美国、葡萄牙、印度和泰国等国家继续报告该病毒的其他谱系，几乎所有谱系都可以追溯到尼日利亚，这表明引发2022年疫情爆发的人类流行病仍在继续“有增无减”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瑞士热带和公共卫生研究所首席研究员艾玛·霍德克罗夫特博士（Emma Hodcroft）没有参与这项研究，她表示，早在 2022 年之前，病毒就在人类中传播，这可能奠定了基础该病毒能够在全球范围内爆发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“了解[该病毒]已经并且仍然在人类中以持续的方式传播，这改变了我们应如何采取预防和根除策略，并且霍德克罗夫特告诉《卫报》，“这提醒我们，未被发现的病毒行为变化可能会导致病毒毒力或传播能力发生变化，从而构成更大的威胁。” “为了真正让这些病毒在全球范围内受到关注，我们需要不断要求更公平的培训、资金和设备分配。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 02:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Buffy Sainte-Marie Indigenous roots controversy rocks Canada First Nations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/02/buffy-sainte-marie-documentary-controversy-indigenous-canada]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T15:31:18Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/bd261717a2d9d4b7bb58909fafaa4b65ff2b8fdf/0_18_5176_3105 /master/5176.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=ffb491a9795b0ab5e384a28ff4192f80&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Buffy Sainte-Marie 于 2018 年 3 月 24 日在不列颠哥伦比亚省温哥华庆祝她的 Juno 获得年度土著专辑奖。 &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一部纪录片中指控美国流行民谣歌手 Buffy Sainte-Marie &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/27/buffy-sainte-marie- Native-ancestry-canada-documentary&quot;>;曲解了她的原住民根源&lt;/a>;，这让她声称出生在加拿大的原住民社区感到不安，突显了这位艺术家的复杂遗产，她数十年的职业生涯都是通过倡导土著文化来定义的原住民权利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sainte-Marie 将自己描述为“克里族歌手兼作曲家”，长期以来，她的身份一直追溯到萨斯喀彻温省的 Piapot 原住民保护区，她声称自己 1941 年出生在那里。Sainte-Marie 说她在婴儿时期就被从亲生母亲身边带走，由美国的一个白人家庭抚养长大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但上周，加拿大广播公司&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc. ca/player/play/2277416003540&quot;>;发布了一部纪录片&lt;/a>;，对这种叙述和她拥有土著根源的说法提出质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其报告让社区难以置信，并威胁要玷污圣玛丽的声誉她被誉为文化偶像，在职业生涯中不知疲倦地为社会正义运动而奋斗，赢得了奥斯卡奖、无数行业荣誉和加拿大大学的四个荣誉博士学位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Delia Opekokew，Sainte-Marie 的前律师，克里人对这些说法提出了异议，并最近签署了一份宣誓书，得出的结论是圣玛丽可能出生在萨斯喀彻温省的一所私人住宅中，不久后就被放弃给访问该地区的一个美国家庭收养。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“作为 20 世纪 60 年代的一名原住民女性，我试图自豪地行走，但我们面临着如此多的种族主义和性别歧视。所以我一直低着头。但当我第一次听到巴菲唱歌时，我的心就爆发出喜悦。我哭了，”她说。 “她唱的歌真是太深情了。这体现了对原住民尊严的尊重。它给了我尊严。于是我抬起了头。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了支持她的研究，奥佩科科是安大略省和萨斯喀彻温省第一位获得律师资格的土著妇女，二十多年前用克里语和英语进行了多次采访，包括与埃米尔和克拉拉·皮亚波特夫妇交谈，这对夫妇根据克里族传统法律将圣玛丽成年后收养到他们的家庭中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还与国家印第安兄弟会的前全国首领诺埃尔·斯塔布兰克特进行了交谈，后来该兄弟会成为原住民大会。 She says Starblanket&#39;s account is corroborated by others she has spoken with.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She criticized what she called the CBC&#39;s “voyeuristic journalism” that she said had failed to include the importance of oral history and Cree traditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The CBC did not speak to me as the witness to the oral history. I spoke to the elders and oral history is just as important as written records. And for the purposes of Indigenous history, it&#39;s often more important. They lacked that sense of respect for our way of keeping our history,” she said. “And I just feel awful about that. I feel awful for Buffy and all those in the community that support her.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a written statement in response, Sainte-Marie said she had “always struggled to answer questions about who I am” and had in the past instructed her lawyer to discover information about her background. She said her “growing-up mother” had told her many things “including that I was adopted and that I was native but there was no documentation as was common for Indigenous children born in the 1940s.”. She added: “I may not know where I was born, but I know who I am.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The allegations broadcast by the CBC, including a birth certificate for Sainte-Marie issued by the state of Massachusetts, as well &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=pfbid0zePRTqQLvyeZLxBqaEs2QTxMiZZZzDTL2BHKvZw1xs4PPqopLYkdzMyVaxH2Eiucl&amp;amp;id=704571716&amp;amp;mibextid=2JQ9oc&quot;>;as posts on social media&lt;/a>; by Sainte-Marie&#39;s son, have unleashed a torrent of vitriol.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“How much ugliness this has brought upon my aunt and our family is shameful,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ntawnis?__cft__[0]=AZVirSIsX_ECmR80pG4LK0SZi4whpRNS3rokVUkUw2OhDwcPdiVthWsGYBgyIJ_5iecDQCNsJ1j9nDXjDzQ0UWTsh5He_LFAE_IrasXm7thAkdt-ZmO3TU5KjZIAJ6IYxxpQQ0LWMTJ8nMBvNNAOLuli&amp;amp;__tn__=-UC%2CP-R&quot;>;Ntawnis Piapot&lt;/a>;, whose grandparents adopted Sainte-Marie under Cree traditions, wrote on Facebook. She says the report has caused “pain and suffering” among her relatives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opekokew, who was taken from her family to attend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/sep/06/canada-residential-schools-indigenous-children-cultural-genocide-map&quot;>;residential school&lt;/a>;, says the broadcaster should have better considered the immense harms the reporting would have on those also taken from their families and survivors of sexual abuse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You don&#39;t do that kind of stories without preparing the possible possibility that you might be triggering many people. And it triggered thousands of people, including myself.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The CBC, which previously outlined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/editorsblog/editor-blog-indigenous-identity-1.7009049&quot;>;its criteria&lt;/a>; for reporting “pretendian” stories, said it reached out to members of the Piapot family, but received no response. The CBC also says it reached out to the acting chief of Piapot First Nation to arrange a visit to the community, but the chief declined. The broadcaster added it “does not dispute the Piapot family adopted Buffy Sainte-Marie as an adult, nor does it dispute the validity of that traditional adoption”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the weekend, the Indigenous Women&#39;s Collective &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IndigenousWome4/status/1718779275455717808&quot;>;said in a statement&lt;/a>; that after weighing the claims against Sainte-Marie, it concluded the singer had engaged in a “great deception” that allowed her to benefit from a “very deliberate and false narrative that misled thousands of Indigenous youth, adults, and most tragically, Indigenous survivors of colonial harm”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The group singled out Sainte-Marie&#39;s previous statements that she was a survivor of the Sixties Scoop – a notorious period in Canadian history in which Indigenous children were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2017/feb/14/canada-sixities-scoop-ruling-first-nations-children&quot;>;forcibly taken&lt;/a>; from their homes and sent to live with white families. While the CBC documentary notes the Scoop began a decade after Sainte-Marie was born, adoptions into white families still took place.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Indigenous Women&#39;s Collective also called for Sainte-Marie to be stripped of her 2018 Indigenous Album of the Year award at the Junos, a prestigious Canadian music award show.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But others say that Sainte-Marie&#39;s history and career highlight the complexity and tangled nature of identity. Kim Wheeler, a Manitoba-based writer who recently worked as a producer on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nac-cna.ca/en/event/30072&quot;>;musical celebration&lt;/a>; of Sainte-Marie, says the Juno category Indigenous artist of the year largely exists because of the singer&#39;s trailblazing career.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Buffy inspired so many of the performers at that show. She was their north star. They said without her, they might not have pursued careers in music. Buffy showed them that if she could succeed, so could they,” she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wheeler, who is of Anishinaabe and Mohawk descent, says Sainte-Marie&#39;s appearances on Sesame Street were powerful to see as a child. “Just watching her on the show, we knew we could be more than what society told us we were.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Throughout her career, Sainte-Marie fought to to ensure Indigenous peoples were included in casting decisions and given opportunities they had long been denied, says Wheeler. She questions the broadcaster&#39;s decision to move ahead with the documentary, given the fracturing and polarizing effects it has had on Indigenous communities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It&#39;s going take a while for people to decide for themselves whether they&#39;re going to discount her entire legacy or if they&#39;re going to continue to uphold her as a hero,” said Wheeler. “People are talking about the stages of grief. They&#39;re angry. They&#39;re hurt. They&#39;re in denial. Are we all going to come to acceptance?我不知道。 It&#39;s so complicated.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HBO boss apologises for using fake Twitter accounts to troll TV critics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2023/nov/02/hbo-boss-fake-twitter-show-critic-negative-review]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T14:47:54Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/713343e1d9a605a5eb75259f6612b78aac9e8c11/0_166_4320_2592/master/4320.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=2ba8e27d040a65f56d62b47c235e1567&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Casey Bloys.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The HBO CEO and chairman, Casey Bloys, has apologised for tasking employees with creating fake Twitter accounts to attack TV critics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bloys was responding to a bombshell &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/hbo-casey-bloys-secret-twitter-trolls-tv-critics-leaked-texts-lawsuit-the-idol-1234867722/&quot;>;Rolling Stone report&lt;/a>; that referenced alleged text messages between himself and Kathleen McCaffrey, HBO&#39;s senior vice-president of drama programming. In six conversations, the pair discussed a “secret army” that could respond to TV critics who gave HBO shows a negative review.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During a presentation for HBO and Max&#39;s upcoming programming, Bloys addressed the allegations. “For those of you who know me, you know that I am a programming executive very, very passionate about the shows that we decide to do.” he said, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2023/tv/news/hbo-casey-bloys-explains-fake-twitter-accounts-troll-critics-1235775997/&quot;>;Variety&lt;/a>;. “And the people who do them and the people who work on them. I want the shows to be great. I want people to love them. I want you all to love them. It&#39;s very important to me what you all think of the shows. When you think about that, and then think of 2020 and 2021, I&#39;m working from home and doing an unhealthy amount of scrolling through Twitter. And I come up with a very, very dumb idea to vent my frustration.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He admited that six tweets over an 18-month period was “not very effective” but apologised to anyone who had been involved. “Obviously, nobody wants to be part of a story that they have nothing to do with,” he said. But also, as many of you know, I have progressed over the past couple of years to using DMs. So now, when I take issue with something in a review, or take issue with something I see, many of you are gracious enough to engage with me in a back and forth and I think that is a probably a much healthier way to go about this.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original Rolling Stone story detailed a 2022 incident involving Vulture TV critic Kathryn VanArendonk when she subtweeted a comment about Perry Mason: “Dear prestige TV. Please find some way to communicate male trauma besides showing me a flashback to the hero&#39;s memories of trench warfare.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bloys was furious and had reportedly drafted a response over text for a former employee, Sully Temori, to tweet: “A somewhat elitist take.对于男性（现在是女性）来说，还有比战争更痛苦的事情吗？ Sorry if that seems too convenient for you.” The decision was ultimately made not to send it but the idea was crafted to use this method in the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Temori is filing a wrongful termination lawsuit against HBO. He claimed he was harassed and faced discrimination after a mental health diagnosis. In a statement, HBO said it “intends to vigorously defend against Mr Temori&#39;s allegations”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Text messages also reference Joss Whedon&#39;s fantasy series The Nevers and a middling review by the Rolling Stone critic Alan Sepinwall. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KellySh33889356&quot;>;A fake account&lt;/a>;, a “vegan Texan mom” called Kelly, sent a reply to him and also to a negative tweet about the show from James Poniewozik, the New York Times TV critic. McCaffrey allegedly texted about the critics: “I fucking hate these people, yes.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sepinwall was also attacked for his thoughts on Mare of Easttown. At the time, McCaffrey wrote: “His highness needs another one.” When asked for comment, Sepinwall said: “I&#39;m surprised HBO would even bother with this.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bloys also instructed fake comments to be posted in the reply section of Deadline stories. Temori&#39;s lawyer called the culture at HBO “very petty”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Temori&#39;s lawsuit also names Abel “the Weeknd” Tesfaye and two producers for The Idol, for which he also worked as a script coordinator. He claims similar harassment and discriminatory behaviour also happened there.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Students walk out of Hillary Clinton’s class to protest Columbia ‘shaming’ pro-Palestinian demonstrators]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/02/hillary-clinton-columbia-walkout-palestine]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T13:55:43Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d49f7e24454c30d24f6f221caf83d1e78cf8bf25/0_262_3936_2362/master/3936.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=8b76dee2e1b53319ce98d04641bfac14&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Hillary Clinton on 25 October 2023 in Washington DC. &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Dozens of students walked out of a class taught by Hillary Clinton in New York on Wednesday in protest at their university&#39;s role in the “shaming” of pro-Palestinian demonstrators.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 30 students were involved in the protest at Columbia University, where the former secretary of state and previous senator for the state was delivering a foreign policy lecture as part of her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/jan/05/hillary-clinton-columbia-university-global-affairs-professor&quot;>;global affairs class&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The walkout was in support of students who signed a declaration blaming Israel for the 7 October Hamas attacks, and whose photographs were displayed on video screens on a truck parked near the university&#39;s campus last week above the words “Columbia&#39;s biggest antisemites”, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/01/world/middleeast/columbia-protest-hillary-clinton-class.html&quot;>;New York Times reported&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The photographs, according to the protestors, were lifted from a “secure and private” student portal at Columbia&#39;s school of international and public affairs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Times reported that the walkout was planned and peaceful, with those leaving almost halfway through Clinton&#39;s two-hour lecture, attended by about 300 students, joining several dozen other demonstrators in the lobby of the school.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were demanding “immediate legal support for affected students” and “a commitment to student safety, well being and privacy”, according to the Times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Clinton, and the school&#39;s dean Keren Yarhi-Milo, who co-teaches the class, reportedly left by a side door and bypassed the protest following the lecture.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Democratic former presidential candidate has taken a strong pro-Israel stance since the conflict erupted last month, last week denouncing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hBMQtDcHUwU&quot;>;those calling for a ceasefire as not understanding Hamas&lt;/a>; during a discussion at Rice University&#39;s Baker Institute.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Columbia is among the universities that have become a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/13/us-campuses-in-uproar-as-israel-palestine-conflict-exposes-divide&quot;>;flashpoint for protests&lt;/a>; over the war, with students on both sides angrily denouncing the other for the escalating violence and growing number of deaths.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A rally at the campus last month called by National Students for Justice in Palestine was part of a “day of resistance” at Israel&#39;s military response to the attacks by Hamas, and also attracted a sizeable group of pro-Israel protestors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pro-Palestinian students whose faces were shown on screens near the campus last week had signed a declaration in support of Hamas. The statement said in part: “The weight of responsibility for the war and casualties undeniably lies with the Israeli extremist government”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Officials at Columbia had no comment on the walkout, the Times reported. The newspaper noted that the university last week unveiled a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sipa.columbia.edu/news/announcing-sipa-task-force-doxing-and-student-safety&quot;>;new task force&lt;/a>; to counter student doxxing – the intentional &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2023/02/07/world/what-is-doxxing-explainer-as-equals-intl-cmd/index.html&quot;>;publication online of a person&#39;s private information&lt;/a>;, usually with malicious intent – and to enhance student safety.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Clinton, 76, Barack Obama&#39;s first-term secretary of state from 2009-2013, began teaching her class, called Inside the Situation Room, at the start of the academic year in September. Some expressed frustration at the logistical impact of her presence, complaining that about 500 students in one of Columbia&#39;s most popular computer science classes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.columbiaspectator.com/news/2023/09/12/classroom-changes-for-clinton-course-push-out-major-undergraduate-lectures/&quot;>;were evicted&lt;/a>; “to put up a nice stage for [Clinton&#39;s] high-profile lecture series”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yarhi-Milo interrupted one of Clinton&#39;s first lectures to allow students with cell phone cameras to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/07/nyregion/hillary-clinton-columbia-university.html&quot;>;take photographs of their celebrity teacher.&lt;/a>; “This is like the paparazzi,” Clinton said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Announcing her appointment in February, then Columbia president Lee Bollinger said Clinton&#39;s class would explore “fundamental questions” about how to advance the renewal of democracy and foster more engagement with women and youth across the US and the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Now and Then: listen to the ‘final’ Beatles song]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/nov/02/now-and-then-listen-to-the-final-beatles-song-john-lennon-paul-mccartney-ringo-george-harrison]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T14:04:58Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/076212cc2a42fc723e537723dbfe8dd34d8fa397/0_464_1656_993/master/1656.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=214b744b3bebc9426b8a96f9c743f485&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;The Beatles in 1967.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Beatles have released what is being described as their final new song together, entitled Now and Then.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It completes a series of Lennon-penned songs handed in demo form to Paul McCartney in 1994 by Yoko Ono, with “For Paul” written on the cassette. McCartney and the remaining Beatles created two new songs from the recordings, Free As a Bird and Real Love – each was a Top 5 hit in the UK, with Free As a Bird reaching No 2 in December 1995 and Real Love at No 4 in March 1996.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-canonical-url=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AW55J2zE3N4&quot;>; &lt;iframe height=&quot;480&quot; width=&quot;854&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AW55J2zE3N4?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen>;&lt;/iframe>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;But the band struggled to complete a song from the demo of Now and Then, and abandoned their attempt. Now, enabled by AI technology that has better isolated John Lennon&#39;s vocal from the demo, the song has finally been completed. McCartney and Ringo Starr recorded new parts for it, while the late George Harrison features via guitar parts kept from that shelved 1995 session.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A making-of film was released on Wednesday, which doesn&#39;t feature the song itself. Referring to Lennon, Starr says in the film: “It was the closest we&#39;ll ever come to having him back in the room.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;McCartney explained the difficulties the band faced in 1995: “On John&#39;s demo tape, the piano was a little hard to hear. And in those days, of course, we didn&#39;t have the technology to do the separation … we kind of ran out of steam a bit, and time. Now and Then just languished in a cupboard.”&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/nov/02/the-beatles-now-and-then-review&quot;>;The Beatles: Now and Then review – &#39;final&#39; song is a poignant act of closure&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;He said he had some doubts about making full songs out of Lennon&#39;s demos, out of respect for the late songwriter&#39;s unfinished work: “Is it something we shouldn&#39;t do? Every time I thought like that I thought, wait a minute, let&#39;s say I had a chance to ask John: &#39;Hey John, would you like us to finish this last song of yours?&#39; I&#39;m telling you, I know the answer would have been: &#39;Yeah!&#39;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peter Jackson directed the music video for Now and Then – launching at 2pm GMT on Friday – having directed the eight-hour Get Back documentary, which also utilised the same AI technology to show how the band pieced together songs for their final two albums, Abbey Road and Let It Be.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liam Gallagher appeared to have had an early listen to Now and Then, writing on X on Thursday morning: “Absolutely incredible biblical celestial heartbreaking and heartwarming all at the same time.” When asked by a fan if he was worried he wouldn&#39;t like the song, Gallagher replied: “The Beatles could shit in my handbag and I&#39;d still hide my polo mints in there.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Italian police search for Briton after partner found stabbed to death]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/02/italian-police-search-for-british-man-after-partner-found-stabbed-to-death]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02T13:33:13Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4e409443e7dce0071187989947ad1b82c890e29c/0_547_3648_2189/master/3648.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=ba36602cf907bd9d1ec09693bcc4371f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Abruzzo town of Casoli&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Police in Italy are searching for a British national suspected of killing his partner, whose body was found with stab wounds at her home in the Abruzzo region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has been identified as Michael Dennis Whitbread, 74, originally from Torquay. A police source confirmed that a search for Whitbread was launched after the body of Michele Faiers, 66, also British, was found in her home near the town of Casoli on Wednesday morning. She had several stab wounds to her abdomen, and is believed to have died four or five days earlier.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faiers was found by a friend who went to check on her after failing to reach her by phone for several days. The friend was able to enter the property as a key had been left in the door, and was reported to have had found Faiers&#39; body in bed. The local news website ChietiToday reported that neighbours heard the friend&#39;s screams and called the police.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whitbread is believed to have driven out of the town in a white Jeep Compass.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports in Italian media, Whitbread and Faiers had been living near Casoli for about three years. They were reported to have been a “very reserved” couple who enjoyed going for long walks with their dogs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are very sorry about what has happened,” Massimo Tiberini, the mayor of Casoli, told the Italian news agency La Presse. “We are concerned … the police are continuing with their investigations.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:52:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>