<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[Top officials called Johnson’s No 10 ‘mad’ and ‘poisonous’, Covid inquiry hears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/nov/07/top-officials-call-boris-johnson-no-10-mad-and-poisonous-covid-inquiry-hears]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T17:48:58Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/8398c9cbaaba4102b4bc951cc5f5c47cf49a2a0d/59_6_3801_2281 /master/3801.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=b691f76dac2e39dcdc25f7887bc37204&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;英国内阁大臣兼公务员系统负责人西蒙·凯斯&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;两位最资深的民事据对新冠病毒的调查得知，英国的仆人们交换了信息，称鲍里斯·约翰逊(Boris Johnson)唐宁街内部的人“有毒”、“疯狂”，不适合管理国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我从来没有见过一群人时任内阁办公室主任的西蒙·凯斯 (Simon Case) 于 2020 年 7 月写信给内阁秘书马克·塞德威尔 (Mark Sedwill)。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯斯接替了塞德威尔的第二职务。几个月后，他仍然担任内阁大臣，还回忆道，他告诉约翰逊，许多高级官员不想在唐宁街工作，“因为他的业务声誉不佳”。疫情期间约翰逊的幕僚长爱德华·乌德尼-利斯特 (Edward Udny-Lister) 在取证期间进行的调查进一步突显了在此期间 10 号大楼内看似有毒的气氛。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/nov/07/westminster-is-rife-with-entitlement-syndrome-during-covid-it-cost-lives&quot;>;威斯敏斯特充满了“权利综合症”。新冠疫情期间，它夺去了生命|贾斯汀·格林宁&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;李斯特在自己的证词中证实，约翰逊曾一度在电视上谈到注射新冠病毒，以表明它无害，后来在大流行期间表示”几个月。这些人太疯狂了。 （还没有）对我有毒，但他们只是疯狂地弄巧成拙。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sedwill 回答道：“到目前为止你还好，因为你已经经历了好消息阶段。等到莱斯特城增多（由于新冠病例激增，当地实施了限制），毛皮就会飞起来。小心点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sedwill 补充道：“正如我向 Eddie [Lister] 指出的那样，如果人们背部中弹，就很难要求人们在枪声中游行。”&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>;凯斯随后告诉塞德威尔，约翰逊曾问他谁将接替汤姆·辛纳 (Tom Shinner)，另一名在新冠疫情 10 号部门内工作的高级官员，他补充道：“我非常直接地告诉他，我问过的很多顶级人士由于他的行动声誉不佳，他拒绝来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次交流并没有明确说明两人指的是谁，或者他们是否仅指官员和工作人员，或者政治家。&lt; /p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/nov/06/boris-johnson- Called-treasury -pro-death-squad-during-pandemic-inquiry-told&quot;>;Covid 调查告诉鲍里斯·约翰逊称财政部为“支持死亡小队”&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;被问及这些消息是否“公平地反映”了当时唐宁街内部的情况，李斯特表示同意，但似乎说这很大程度上要归功于约翰逊当时的首席顾问多米尼克·卡明斯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他不是一个李斯特谈到卡明斯时说，他是个容易相处的人，这很紧张，他说约翰逊应该采取行动。 “性格冲突一直在发生，而且有一种氛围。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及他自己与卡明斯的工作时，李斯特说：“我们一起工作。我们的桌子面对面。我不能说有任何密切的关系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他的证据中，李斯特还证实了卡明斯首先描述的两件轶事，即李斯特所说的约翰逊在会议上发表的“不幸”评论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在危机刚开始的一个不确定时刻，李斯特在证人证词中表示，约翰逊在一次会议上提议在电视上注射新冠病毒，“以向公众证明它不会构成威胁”。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;“我完全接受这是一个不应该发表的评论，但它是在一时冲动下做出的，”当被问及此事时，李斯特说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他的证人证词中的其他地方李斯特证实，2020 年 9 月感染率快速上升的情况下，当提议实行所谓的“断路器”短暂封锁时，约翰逊在一次会议上表示，他宁愿“让尸体堆积如山”。李斯特说，这是“一个不幸的措辞”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 01:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[German chancellor Olaf Scholz agrees ‘historic’ stricter migration policy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/07/german-chancellor-olaf-scholz-agrees-historic-stricter-migration-policy]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T17:24:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7dfc4da7bb895d297634bccca7be585de14119ee/0_207_6212_3727 /master/6212.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=7c8962e77eb9bd2a60b8ed330ebb4f59&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨 (Olaf Scholz) 参加了在柏林举行的关于庇护程序的马拉松式会谈。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;由于非政府组织批评意大利在 &lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis 建立中心的计划，德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨 (Olaf Scholz) 和国家领导人已同意采取更严格的措施来应对大量抵达德国的移民。 .com/international/lists/tag/world/albania&quot;>;阿尔巴尼亚&lt;/a>;容纳寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在柏林进行了一场持续到周二凌晨的马拉松式会谈后，肖尔茨表示这些措施将有助于加快庇护程序，限制移民的社会福利，并为当地社区提供更多联邦资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;睡眼惺忪的肖尔茨表示，这些决定对该国来说是一个“历史性时刻” ，尽管联合政府的绿党成员表示，削减社会福利等同于让寻求庇护者生活在贫困之中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这只会加剧社会紧张局势，让融入变得更加困难，”绿党移民问题专家朱利安·帕尔克 (Julian Pahlke) 向《时代周报》表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;移民问题再次成为德国领导人面临的爆炸性政治挑战，政府感受到了来自内部和反对派的压力，要求遏制移民问题。抵达人数主要来自叙利亚、阿富汗和土耳其。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;官方统计数据显示，今年 1 月至 9 月，庇护申请量比去年同期增加了约 73%，达到 25 万多人.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这与自 2022 年俄罗斯入侵以来抵达的超过 100 万乌克兰人不同，他们不需要申请庇护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入这场充满争议的辩论肖尔茨称这项改革是“向呼吸系统的过渡”，并表示新措施意味着“随着人数的增加，钱会更多，随着人数的下降，钱会更少”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此举发生在数小时内。意大利总理周一公布了一项单独的移民协议，该协议将在阿尔巴尼亚为数千名通过海路抵达的人建立接待中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周二，乔治亚·梅洛尼 (Giorgia Meloni) 在接受《信使报》采访时表示这些计划可以成为“欧盟与非欧盟国家之间合作的典范”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但国际救援委员会称罗马与地拉那的协议是对欧盟团结的“进一步打击”。其欧洲倡导高级总监将其描述为“非人性化”，并表示“每个人都有申请庇护的基本权利——无论他们来自哪里，或如何抵达。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“最新决定无国界医生组织表示，这项协议“超越了一步”。此前欧盟国家与土耳其、利比亚和突尼斯达成的协议。 “其目的不再只是阻止人们离开，而是积极防止人们逃离以及海上获救的人安全快速地进入欧洲领土，从而绕过国际法和欧洲公约规定的保护和救援义务。” ”在一份声明中说。“拒绝进入意大利领土、对庇护申请进行域外管理、实施加速边境程序以及在第三国拘留人员，这是对意大利的新攻击。获得庇护的权利。这些举措重复了遏制和威慑政策，这些政策已被证明从长期来看是无效的，但却能够增加成千上万人的痛苦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发言人乔治亚·利纳迪(Giorgia Linardi)&lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>;救援非政府组织 Sea&lt;strong>;-&lt;/strong>; 表示，该协议代表“意大利政府对国际和欧盟庇护法的一次新的正面攻击，利用国际承认的愿望和第三国的脆弱性来逃避其制裁”。庇护责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些计划引起了欧盟高层人士的恐慌。内部人士表示，欧盟委员会仅“一小时收到”该协议的通知，该协议可能会在阿尔巴尼亚处理多达 36,000 名移民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位官员称这是 Meloni 的“令人讨厌”的举动，在移民法最终谈判前夕，旨在为意大利、希腊和其他面临非正常移民大幅增加的边境国家提供解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梅洛尼的协议最初将使移民中心容纳约 3,000 人，但最终每年处理多达 36,000 名移民。她表示，为了减少通过海路抵达意大利的移民数量，该计划是必要的。与去年同期相比，意大利的移民数量增加了约 65%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的计划被拿来与意大利政府有争议的努力进行比较。英国政府向卢旺达派遣数千名寻求庇护者，但由于法律障碍而受阻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧盟委员会发言人表示，正在向意大利寻求详细信息，但警告称，必须确保任何“安排都得到充分落实”尊重欧盟和国际法”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在柏林，肖尔茨表示，他的政府仍在考虑欧盟以外的庇护程序是否可行，但尚未准备好就长期以来高度重视的问题做出决定。这是一个有争议的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;帕尔克表示，关于是否允许在欧盟之外进行庇护程序的讨论“在法律上和实际上都是不可能的，因此是一个伪解决方案”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 01:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beleaguered DeSantis falls further behind Trump in Florida, poll shows]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/07/ron-desantis-trump-florida-poll]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T16:32:04Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b604ba201225979f980bb38a2bc784fceaac0e6e/0_292_4093_2456 /master/4093.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=a4f0221e7bb28f2f137ddf35f428a4f3&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;佛罗里达州州长 Ron DeSantis 周一晚上在爱荷华州得梅因发表演讲。&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;一项新的民意调查显示，佛罗里达州极右翼州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯 (Ron DeSantis) 在本州进一步落后于唐纳德·特朗普 (Donald Trump)，而就在这位四面楚歌的共和党总统提名候选人在迈阿密进行辩论的前一天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北佛罗里达大学 (UNF) 的研究&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unfporl.org/uploads/1/4/4/5/144559024/unf_porl_fall23_repprim_statewide.pdf&quot;>;于周二发布&lt;/a>;显示德桑蒂斯在佛罗里达州共和党选民中落后特朗普 39 个百分点 (60-21)，前南卡罗来纳州州长妮基·哈利 (Nikki Haley) 以 6% 的支持率位列第三。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/07/iowa-governor-kim-reynolds-endorses-ron-desantis&quot;>;爱荷华州州长打破中立，支持罗恩·德桑蒂斯总统&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fau.edu/artsandletters/fau-polcom-lab/pdfs/mainstreet-florida-july-2023。 pdf&quot;>;佛罗里达大西洋大学 7 月民意调查&lt;/a>;显示，在类似的假设初选中，特朗普以 50-30 领先德桑蒂斯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一场直接的正面对决中，特朗普占据优势根据 UNF 的新研究，以 59 比 29 的优势，其中 12% 的人没有做出选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“尽管民调中支持率达到历史最高水平，但德桑蒂斯州长在他的家乡失去动力并不是好兆头UNF 政治学教授兼舆论研究实验室主任迈克尔·宾德 (Michael Binder) 表示：“即使你在正面交锋中击败了其余的竞争对手， ，特朗普领先德桑蒂斯 20 个百分点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;佛罗里达州的民意调查反映了德桑蒂斯的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/21/ron-desantis-第五-新罕布什尔州-特朗普-拉马斯瓦米-黑利-克里斯蒂&quot;>;由于他努力维持曾经健康的竞选活动，他在全国范围内的受欢迎程度急剧下降。但一年前他以 20% 的优势再次当选州长的他所在州的支持率下滑将尤其令人恼火。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特朗普将于周三在海厄利亚举办一场竞争对手的集会。晚上，距迈阿密市中心辩论舞台仅几英里的地方，抓住了德桑蒂斯的绊脚石，在竞选信息中称他为“一只从天上掉下来的受伤的鸟”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海莉也在一次&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/04/nikki-haley-republican-presidential-primary-trump&quot;>;最近她自己的受欢迎程度飙升&lt;/a>;到了一个不太可能的水平在几个早期初选州中成为特朗普的领先替代者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们将看看他是否能在这些州竞选，”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2023 /11/02/haley-desantis-2024-00124962&quot;>;她谈到&lt;/a>;德桑蒂斯穿着牛仔靴参加竞选活动，据报道，其中含有增高隐形高跟鞋，而他在乌克兰和加沙冲突方面的外交政策受到了更严重的攻击和中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;德桑蒂斯确实获得了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/07/iowa-governor-kim-reynolds-endorses -ron-desantis&quot;>;周一晚上得到爱荷华州州长金·雷诺兹&lt;/a>;的支持，但一直难以在佛罗里达州找到有影响力的共和党支持。他的前任州长、现任该州初级参议员里克·斯科特(Rick Scott)上周站出来支持特朗普，随后是&lt;a href=&quot;https://themessenger.com/news/trump-scores-more-florida-lawmaker-endorsements -包括-desantis-defectors-exclusive&quot;>;五名佛罗里达州议员叛逃&lt;/a>;，之前曾在德桑蒂斯阵营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“削弱德桑蒂斯在佛罗里达州的地位是特朗普竞选活动的明确目标，”亚历克斯·科南特共和党策略师周末告诉美联社。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他的整个信息都建立在他是一位出色的州长的理念之上。当佛罗里达州的共和党官员选择特朗普而不是德桑蒂斯时，这确实削弱了德桑蒂斯的核心主张。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Portuguese PM António Costa resigns amid corruption inquiry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/07/portuguese-pm-antonio-costa-resigns-amid-corruption-inquiry]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T15:49:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/1bf9b78bb3474dfb5150bdf72523b9d5304a4870/0_258_4630_2778 /master/4630.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=23ed531aa7d93301dd8dffffbc4b60f9&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;安东尼奥·科斯塔在 2022 年 1 月的选举后连续第三次担任总理。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;葡萄牙社会党总理安东尼奥·科斯塔在审查涉及锂和“绿色”氢交易涉嫌腐败的检察官宣布他正在接受调查并且警方搜查了数十个地址后数小时辞职，其中包括他的官邸以及环境和基础设施部。周二下午，在与葡萄牙总统马塞洛·雷贝洛·德索萨举行两次紧急会议后，科斯塔表示他已提交辞呈，并补充说他“良心清白”，“完全相信正义”及其运作方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“总理的职责与对我诚信的任何怀疑是不相容的，”他在新闻发布会上说。 “在这种情况下，我已向共和国总统提出辞呈。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科斯塔在他的政党获得选举后连续第三次担任总理。 www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jan/31/portugal-general-election-pm-antonio-costa-wins-surprise-outright-majority&quot;>;令人惊讶的绝对多数&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jan/29/splits-in-left-are-set-to-boost-far-right-tv-pundit-in-portugals-snap-election&quot;>;快照一般在 2022 年 1 月举行的选举&lt;/a>;中，他表示，尽管他“完全愿意投入全部精力来履行职责，直到本届立法机关结束”，但他还是辞职了。他还表示，他不会参加任何即将举行的选举。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在葡萄牙媒体报道至少有五人被拘留，其中包括科斯塔的幕僚长维托·埃斯卡里亚和科斯塔的朋友之后，他宣布了这一消息。商业顾问迪奥戈·拉塞尔达·马查多 (Diogo Lacerda Machado)。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察官办公室随后透露，科斯塔本人正在接受调查，并补充说，在调查期间接受讯问的嫌疑人引用了总理的“姓名和权力”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷贝洛·德索萨证实，他已接受科斯塔的辞职，并将于本周晚些时候与党领导人会面，召开国务委员会。随后预计他将解散议会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年 1 月，检察官表示，他们正在调查与锂和氢项目相关的腐败指控，但没有透露任何嫌疑人的名字。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对涉嫌“滥用资金、政治人物主动和被动腐败以及兜售影响力”的调查涉及该国北部的锂矿特许权。它还正在调查 Start Campus 公司在里斯本以南约 100 公里（62 英里）的小镇锡尼什 (Sines) 建造的制氢项目和数据中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在周二发布的一份声明中，检察官表示警察和刑事调查和行动部门的工作人员搜查了 42 个场所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它证实，“为了识别和扣押文件和其他相关证据”而搜查的地址包括“警察使用的空间”。总理办公室负责人”、两个部委和锡尼什市议会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察官表示，以潜逃风险和非法活动可能继续的可能性为由，已对科斯塔的幕僚长、国家安全局发出了逮捕令。锡尼什市长和 Start Campus 的两名高管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察官还表示，作为调查的一部分，葡萄牙基础设施部长若昂·加兰巴 (João Galamba) 以及葡萄牙机构执行委员会主席已被起诉&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5 月，APA 批准了一个锂矿开采项目，锂是制造电池的重要金属。第二个项目于 9 月初获得批准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年早些时候，Rebelo de Sousa 告诉政府在单独的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/portugals-government-hot-water-tap-airline-scandal-deepens-2023-04-21/&quot;>;国有航空公司 TAP 的丑闻&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着搜查和逮捕的消息传出，反对派政客呼吁他辞职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保守派 CDS-人民党敦促科斯塔下台，称“鉴于当前局势和破产的严重性”极右翼切加党领袖安德烈·文图拉也表示，科斯塔必须辞职，以结束“怀疑浪潮”。并允许葡萄牙自我更新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但科斯塔在共产党和左翼集团中的前盟友呼吁在得出任何结论之前调查事实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“民主要求没有任何权力凌驾于法律之上，”左翼集团议员佩德罗·菲利佩·苏亚雷斯说道。 “找出需要查明的内容，调查需要调查的内容。司法必须迅速、迅速和透明。”&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;路透社和法新社为本报告做出了贡献&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ ul>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Greener electric car batteries among Prince William’s £1m Earthshot winners]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/nov/07/greener-electric-car-batteries-among-prince-william-1m-earthshot-winners]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T15:14:23Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f53a78cc36cafe1484c458f6c85e223a7273e8a1/0_150_3145_1888 /master/3145.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=da7c33afc2c12bb45da47f62a4a14bf5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;威廉王子与部分 2023 年 Earthshot 奖获得者于 11 月 7 日星期二在新加坡举行的颁奖典礼上&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;开发出一种更清洁、更可持续的方法来制造电动汽车电池的科学家是今年威尔士亲王奖 100 万英镑的获奖者之一 &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthshotprize.org/&quot;>;Earthshot &lt;/a>;奖项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该奖项于周二在新加坡举行的盛大仪式上宣布，旨在奖励应对气候和生物多样性紧急情况的创新解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在活动中发表讲话，以在 20 世纪 60 年代美国前总统约翰·F·肯尼迪 (John F Kennedy) 提出的登月挑战中，王子表示，即使气候危机的影响变得“过于明显，不容忽视”，“希望仍然存在”。王子穿着亚历山大·麦昆 (Alexander McQueen) 的西装外套，这件外套已经成为他衣橱的一部分了 10 年。他曾在 2021 年首届 Earthshot 颁奖典礼上佩戴过它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“去年是发生巨大变化、面临更大挑战的一年，”他说。 “这一年让很多人感到挫败，他们的希望越来越渺茫。然而，正如我们今晚所看到的，希望确实存在。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王子说，未来几代人将“回顾这十年，我们在全球范围内为我们的星球采取集体行动......那一刻” ，以及我们星球的未来。我相信我们会找到这样做的勇气。我们会找到勇气，因为我们将坚持最强大的动力——乐观和希望。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五个获奖项目，每个项目都获得了 100 万英镑的奖金，它们是：&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;•&lt;/span>; GRST 的项目，旨在以更清洁、更可持续的方式制造和回收锂离子电池。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;•&lt;/span>; 野生救援海洋计划的倡议，旨在将各国政府、科学家和活动人士共同打击非法捕捞并加强海洋保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;•&lt;/span>; S4S Technologies 计划开发太阳能干燥机和加工设备，帮助小农户保护海洋农作物并将废物转化为有价值的产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;•&lt;/span>;Boomitra 的项目与非洲、南美洲和亚洲一些最贫困地区的 150,000 名农民合作，旨在减少排放并促进通过经过验证的碳信用市场激励土地恢复来获取利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;•&lt;/span>; Accion Andina，该项目将安第斯山脉当地和原住民社区的数万人团结起来，保护和恢复原生森林和生态系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;获奖者由王子和 Earthshot 奖委员会选出，该委员会由克里斯蒂娜·菲格雷斯 (Christiana Figueres) 担任主席，她是 2015 年在巴黎签署的气候协议的缔造者之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;组织者表示，所有五名获奖者以及其他 10 名决赛入围者都将获得 Earthshot 奖奖学金的指导、资源和技术支持，这是一项为期一年的计划，旨在加速他们的项目发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;地球奋斗奖理事会成员大卫·阿滕伯勒爵士在颁奖典礼上通过视频露面，告诉观众“我们可以在我们的星球上既美好又负责任地生活”。他补充道：“今晚，我们向那些引领更美好未来的人们致敬。”&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;PA Media 对本报告做出了贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ ul>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Euclid telescope sends back first images from ‘dark universe’ mission]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/science/2023/nov/07/euclid-telescope-first-images-dark-universe-mission]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T14:25:01Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ea62ad5abcbffa2d30d1b2cec3d5aefddbcda6b7/0_299_5354_3212 /master/5354.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=5edd41dc7105ce779392eb565525287e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜拍摄的马头星云图像。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;欧几里得太空望远镜有在一项承诺揭开“黑暗宇宙”面纱的任务中传回了第一批图像。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲航天局 (Esa) 耗资 10 亿欧元（8.5 亿英镑）的任务重点关注暗物质和暗能量，它们共同构成了宇宙的 95%，但它们的本质几乎完全是神秘的。第一批图像以令人眼花缭乱的细节展示了英仙座星系团和马头星云，并在单个快照中捕获了大约 100,000 个星系，展示了该望远镜在广阔的空间中进行锐利观测的无与伦比的能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终这台望远镜可以探测到 100 亿光年以外的星系，旨在绘制有史以来最大的宇宙 3D 地图。这将使天文学家能够推断暗物质的大尺度分布，并揭示暗能量在早期宇宙中的影响。暗物质遍布宇宙，充当将星系粘合在一起的宇宙胶水，而暗能量是一种神秘力量的名称，这种力量被认为会加速宇宙的膨胀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卡罗尔·蒙代尔教授，该任务表示，欧洲航天局的科学主任，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2023/jul/01/euclid-telescope-lifts-off-in-search-of-the-secrets -of-dark-universe&quot;>;于 7 月推出&lt;/a>;，将把科学知识的前沿推向“超越爱因斯坦”的未知领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;c32ccd78934a12b7998f977d72a52a348c4c11c2&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/c32ccd78934a12b7998f977d72a52a348c4c11c2/0_0_6600_4400/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;属于英仙座星团的星系&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;属于英仙座星团的星系。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：Esa/Euclid/Euclid Consortium/NAS/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;“作为人类，我们”我们已经成功地弄清楚了宇宙 5% 的部分是如何运作的，而且我们还发现了另外 95% 的部分仍然是我们未知的，”她说。 “我们无法前往宇宙边缘进行调查，但我们可以将这些图像带回地球并在计算机上进行研​​究 - 只需花费 14 亿欧元。我认为这很神奇。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接下来的六年里，欧几里得将利用红外光和可见光在 36% 的夜空中观测到大约 80 亿个星系。在某些情况下，来自这些遥远天体的光在通往地球的旅程中会靠近暗物质。当这种情况发生时，它的引力场会弯曲光的路径，使星系在最终图像中显得扭曲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“背景圆形星系可能会变成香蕉形状，”马克·克罗珀教授说伦敦大学学院的教授，他领导了欧几里得光学相机的设计。通过分析扭曲的模式，天文学家可以推断出夜空和宇宙历史上暗物质的分布图。 “你这样做就像在烤面包架上烤面包一样，”克罗珀说。 “首先，你要观察附近星系的扭曲情况，并找出第一片吐司中的暗物质。然后你会进一步回到下一个切片——在宇宙中越来越远，并回到过去。 guim.co.uk/e5d89e06c07d369910ab32807379e8c06e0f027c/0_0_3020_3020/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;螺旋星系 IC 342。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;螺旋星系 IC 342。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：Esa/Euclid/Euclid Consortium/NAS/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt; /figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;该任务最初可能不会回答暗物质是什么，但至少应该揭示它的位置及其行为方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员还将观察星系的运动，以了解暗物质的性质。建立一幅关于引力和暗能量的精确图像，引力和暗能量导致星系聚集在一起，暗能量推动空间加速膨胀。这将使科学家第一次看到暗能量在早期宇宙中是如何发挥作用的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒙代尔说：“暗物质将星系聚集在一起，并使它们比单独的可见物质旋转得更快可以解释；暗能量正在推动宇宙加速膨胀。欧几里得将首次允许宇宙学家一起研究这些相互竞争的黑暗之谜。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲航天局欧几里得项目科学家雷内·劳雷伊斯 (René Laureijs) 补充道：“我们以前从未见过这样的天文图像，包含如此多的细节。它们比我们所希望的更加美丽和锐利，向我们展示了附近宇宙中众所周知的区域中许多以前未曾见过的特征。现在我们已经准备好观测数十亿个星系，并研究它们在宇宙时间内的演化。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 22:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Minister robbed and bodyguards’ guns stolen in South Africa]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/07/south-africa-minister-sindisiwe-chikunga-robbed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T13:38:56Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/3f380ddc539b2dde7a449302957dd390fddd8eb3/0_257_3500_2099 /master/3500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=cc39c18e2fcd7bf2265c23c90fbdbe35&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;约翰内斯堡警察&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;南非政府部长被抢劫，她的保镖也被抢劫警方表示，枪支被盗，该国当局称这是“前所未有的事件”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袭击发生在周一，当时交通部长辛迪西韦·奇孔加 (Sindisiwe Chikunga) 正在约翰内斯堡以南的高速公路上行驶。警方表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;交通部表示，“部长的汽车轮胎被尖刺刺破，导致汽车停下来，犯罪分子可以抢劫车内人员的贵重物品。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;它补充说，部长和她的警卫从这场磨难中“毫发无伤，安全”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方发言人 Athlenda Mathe 表示，劫匪带走了个人物品和两名南非警察局 (SAPS) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在这起史无前例的事件发生后，我们开始了搜捕行动，并将责任人绳之以法。”马特说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南非长期以来一直以暴力犯罪和暴力犯罪而闻名。经常被描述为世界上战区以外最危险的国家之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年 4 月至 6 月，在这个拥有 6200 万人口的国家，警方每天记录了 500 多起抢劫案和近 70 起谋杀案，据官方统计。当局被指控未能确保犯罪受害者的安全和伸张正义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“SAPS 致力于执行其保护国家和整个社区行政人员的职责，”Mathe 说。 “VIP 保护是 SAPS 的关键优先领域之一，多年来一直表现出色。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 21:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thousands of lone child asylum seekers left in limbo by Home Office, data shows]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/nov/07/thousands-of-lone-child-asylum-seekers-left-in-limbo-by-home-office-data-shows]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T12:52:26Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/59f8d0862d23926a7e43f988e26b663f0a14753d/508_479_2992_1797 /master/2992.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=d63060a764f954cf7c512678fc34d73c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;谢菲尔德的四名年轻难民，将视线移开镜头，以免露出他们的脸&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;官方数据显示，数千名独生子女寻求庇护者被内政部搁置，没有对其保护申请做出决定，其中数十人等待了五年以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;内政部数据显示，超过过去三年，超过 7,500 名独自前往英国的儿童等待了一年多的时间，才得到是否接受庇护申请的初步决定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;律师、政界人士和人权活动人士谴责了这种做法。苏格兰民族党公布的数据显示，57 名儿童等待初步决定已经五年多了– 他们生活的很大一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/sep/ 22/fear-of-x-ray-age-tests-may-force-uk-child-asylum-seekers-to-flee&quot;>;担心英国的 X 光年龄测试“可能迫使儿童寻求庇护者逃离”&lt; /a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The number of delays was much higher in 2022 than in the previous two years, with four times as many children waiting more than a year for asylum, with 1,083 delayed cases in 2020 and 4,103 in 2021.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There has been a sevenfold increase in those waiting five years or more for an initial asylum decision, with just five in 2020 and 35 in 2022. In some cases, there may be delays because of disputes over a child&#39;s age, later resolved in the child&#39;s favour.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kate Forbes, a Scottish National party MSP and former Scottish finance secretary, condemned the delays in making initial decisions on children&#39;s asylum claims.&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;“These figures show the UK asylum system in crisis, with waits soaring and innocent children stuck in the middle of the UK government&#39;s mess,” she said. “Every number represents a young and potentially vulnerable individual stuck waiting months if they are lucky, but more likely over a year, for a decision on their asylum to be made.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Instead of creating a functioning asylum system, the Tory UK government&#39;s hostile environment model has left thousands of children stuck in limbo. This is completely unacceptable.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Greater Manchester Immigration Aid Unit, which has expertise in lone children&#39;s asylum claims in England, said it had more than 300 children on its waiting list.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The unit blames a combination of the Home Office&#39;s huge asylum backlog and the crisis in legal aid funding in the immigration legal sector, which has led to long waiting times for children to access legal advice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local councils in north-west England have provided some emergency funding for the centre to help children access legal advice more quickly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amanda Shah, a senior policy officer at GMIAU, said: “We regularly hear from young people who are confused, upset and angry that they are waiting months and months for the Home Office to make a decision on their asylum claim.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“No asylum decision means young people don&#39;t have the safety and security they desperately need to get on with their lives in their new communities.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The joint committee on human rights, a parliamentary body made up of MPs and peers, is holding an evidence session on Wednesday on whether the government is failing to protect the human rights of unaccompanied child asylum seekers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The UK is legally obliged to respect the “best interests” principle that requires all decision makers to make the best interest of the child a primary consideration in their cases, as well as uphold the child&#39;s rights as set out in the Human Rights Act.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Home Office has been approached for a response.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 21:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elections from Virginia to New Jersey could offer early referendum on Biden]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/07/elections-virginia-new-jersey-ohio-abortion-biden]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T10:00:04Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/971a123aefe956c68f0e29eb99cb172ef45c7637/0_72_4014_2408/master/4014.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=b425d547577042cccc2b5ea71163c6a5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Nick Ignacio, independent candidate for Spotsylvania county clerk of court, stands by campaign signs at an early voting location in Fredericksburg, Virginia, last month.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Millions of Americans go to the polls on Tuesday to vote in elections and ballot measures that could offer an interim verdict on Joe Biden&#39;s presidency a year out from his bid to retain the White House.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Voters will choose governors in Kentucky and Mississippi, decide legislative control in New Jersey and Virginia and determine whether the Ohio state constitution should protect abortion rights.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/nov/03/virginia-election-mail-in-ballots-democrats&quot;>;Virginia white voters&#39; mail-in ballots face fewer challenges, Democrats say&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;All 40 seats in Virginia&#39;s senate and all 100 seats in the state&#39;s house of delegates &lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/us-news/series/virginia-votes&quot;>;are in play&lt;/a>;. Democrats are aiming to hold or widen their 22-18 advantage in the senate and win a majority in the House, where Republicans currently have a 52-48 edge.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Voters&#39; decisions could be affected by events on the national political stage, ranging from Biden&#39;s low approval ratings to the recent chaos in the House of Representatives as Republicans struggled for three weeks to elect a speaker.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“People say, oh, it doesn&#39;t matter because it&#39;s national but people don&#39;t make those distinctions,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://centerforpolitics.org/staff/larry-j-sabato/&quot;>;Larry Sabato&lt;/a>;, director of the Center for Politics at the University of Virginia in Charlottesville. “国家是州，州是地方。他们正在衡量各方的价值，一一比较。 I don&#39;t know if there&#39;s any way we can measure it but surely this Republican dysfunction in the US House is having some effect.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Virginia is the only state in the south that has not imposed further limits on abortion since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/may/10/divided-america-roe-v-wade-supreme-court-cold-civil-war&quot;>;supreme court overturned&lt;/a>; the landmark Roe v Wade ruling last year. But Republicans have pledged to pass a 15-week abortion ban – supported by the Republican governor, Glenn Youngkin – if they gain control of the legislature.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Youngkin, who upset Democrats in 2021 by making “parents&#39; rights” his signature issue, is not on the ballot this time but the elections will be watched closely for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/30/hes-pretty-smooth-glenn-youngkin-of-virginia-may-be-a-challenger-for-trump&quot;>;clues to his future political prospects&lt;/a>;. Republican donors opposed to Donald Trump could yet try to persuade Youngkin to make a last-minute entry into the 2024 presidential primary.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Republicans are also pursuing control of either legislative chamber in solidly Democratic New Jersey, where all seats in the general assembly and senate are up for grabs. Republicans have made headway since 2021, when they flipped seven seats, and are pushing issues ranging from the economy to parental rights in K-12 education.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, in conservative Kentucky, the Democratic governor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/dec/12/kentucky-ex-felons-vote-democratic-governor-andy-beshear&quot;>;Andy Beshear&lt;/a>;, is running for re-election against the Republican state attorney general, Daniel Cameron. Beshear&#39;s campaign is touting his record of bringing jobs to Kentucky, backing public schools, expanding healthcare access and setting strict policies to curb the spread of the coronavirus.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;11a965f7cb1fc5a81af8030a80565e2cfa3653bf&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/11a965f7cb1fc5a81af8030a80565e2cfa3653bf/0_68_2048_1229/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pro-choice canvasser Summer McLain, 27, and her mother Lorie McLain, 61, look at a map of a neighborhood before canvassing ahead of the election in Columbus, Ohio, on Sunday.&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;Pro-choice canvasser Summer McLain, 27, and her mother Lorie McLain, 61, canvass ahead of the election in Columbus, Ohio, on Sunday.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Megan Jelinger/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;Cameron, who is African American, has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/meetthepressblog/kentuckys-daniel-cameron-touts-trump-backing-home-stretch-governors-ra-rcna121081&quot;>;touting his endorsement&lt;/a>; by Trump. He is focusing on public safety, learning loss from school closures during the pandemic and culture war issues championed by Republicans nationally, such as opposing gender-affirming care for transgender children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Mississippi, the Republican governor, Tate Reeves, is running for re-election against the Democrat &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/29/brandon-presley-elvis-presley-mississippi-governor-tate-reeves&quot;>;Brandon Presley&lt;/a>;, a former small-town mayor who is the second cousin of singer Elvis Presley. While Reeves is leading in the polls in the deeply conservative southern state, Presley has raised more money over the course of the campaign.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In political ads, Reeves has accused Presley of being backed by out-of-state liberals and opposing bans on gender-affirming care for transgender youth like the one Reeves signed into law in February. Presley has said he does not support gender-affirming care for minors, or transgender girls playing girls&#39; sports, and is running on the promise of tax cuts and expanding Medicaid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A debate between the candidates last week proved &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/mississippi-governor-election-debate-reeves-presley-f157476d126399736bdb856d1c4cff85&quot;>;an ill-tempered affair&lt;/a>; with Reeves and Presley trading insults and talking over one another.&lt;br>;&lt;br>; A ballot question in Ohio asks voters whether to enshrine abortion rights in the state constitution, a move that would render moot a six-week limit signed into law by the Republican governor, Mike DeWine.该法律目前处于搁置状态，等待州最高法院的诉讼。 The vote is being closely watched as Democrats across the country hope to add to their string of abortion-related ballot measure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/aug/03/democrats-abortion-rights-victory-kansas&quot;>;wins in 2022&lt;/a>;.&lt;br>;&lt;br>; Ohio voters will also answer a ballot question about whether the state should legalise marijuana for recreational use. If approved, the statute would legalise, regulate and tax marijuana for adults over 21, expanding on the currently legal medicinal use of cannabis.&lt;br>;&lt;br>; Cities across the country will elect mayors on Tuesday. In Philadelphia, Democrat &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inquirer.com/politics/election/david-oh-cherelle-parker-mayor-election-20231101.html&quot;>;Cherelle Parker and Republican David Oh&lt;/a>;, both former city council members, are competing for an open seat as Democrat Jim Kenney reaches the limit of his mayoral term. In Houston, a crowded field of candidates led by the US congresswoman Sheila Jackson Lee and state senator John Whitmire, both Democrats, are competing to succeed the term-limited mayor, Sylvester Turner, also a Democrat.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bad night for Democrats might been seen as a grim reflection on Biden, who approval rating &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.gallup.com/poll/513305/democrats-ratings-biden-slip-overall-approval.aspx&quot;>;stood at just 37%&lt;/a>; in a Gallup opinion poll last week. Surveys suggest he is running neck and neck with Trump in a hypothetical rematch.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Suella Braverman fails to get ban on charities giving tents to homeless included in king’s speech – UK politics live]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2023/nov/07/kings-speech-rishi-sunak-conservatives-charles-keir-starmer-labour]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T10:00:49Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a83def86bf351ef2ad62b0cd31b0a99bb71e6579/0_0_4060_2437/master/4060.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=1b386eb68c2f1fd9af52e02e0af09594&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;A pedestrian walks past a tent used as shelter by a homeless person.&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Eighteen Afghanistan men’s footballers to boycott World Cup qualifier]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/football/2023/nov/07/eighteen-afghanistan-men-boycott-world-cup-qualifier]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T10:00:05Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/13b7c12f225589bc43ad52d7d09fc7c64449075f/0_198_5091_3055/master/5091.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=78765863f76990a38acd05f7dde747f4&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Afghanistan&#39;s Farshad Noor (left) and Qatar&#39;s Ahmed Alaaeldin compete for the ball&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Most of the Afghanistan men&#39;s team are boycotting their World Cup qualifier against Qatar next week in protest against what they describe as substandard treatment by the country&#39;s football federation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A letter, which has been seen by the Guardian, signed by three overseas-based players who were captains of the squad that defeated Mongolia in the first round of qualifying last month was sent to Fifa and the Asian Football Confederation (AFC) this week outlining their complaints. They include allegations of serious corruption by the Afghanistan Football Federation (AFF).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The last straw came at the last camp when a big group of us decided that we&#39;d had enough – 18 players got together and said: &#39;If we&#39;re going to move forward, we have to put a stop to this,&#39;” said Noor Husin, who plays for National League side Southend United.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/football/2023/jun/20/uk-parliament-calls-on-fifa-to-support-exiled-afghanistan-womens-team&quot;>;UK parliament calls on Fifa to support exiled Afghanistan women&#39;s team&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“We really want change.我们想帮助国内球员，因为他们从国际足联得到的钱没有得到正确的使用。我们的航班可能最差，而且我们不得不住在不合格的酒店。 We&#39;ve come together as a group because we want football in Afghanistan to move forward and we believe that it&#39;s not going to move forward with the people that are in charge at the moment.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The captain, Farshad Noor, and his predecessor, Faysal Shayesteh, are the other players to have signed the letter, which demands Fifa investigates allegations that senior officials in the AFF have been misappropriating funds that are supposed to be invested in developing football in the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Every year our federation gets financial support from Fifa and from the AFC,” said Shayesteh, who plays for the Indian side Sreenidi Deccan. “We want to show a positive Afghanistan to the world so we are asking Fifa to stop supporting our federation financially because the money is going into the pockets of a gang who is ruling football in the country.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The AFF&#39;s general secretary Behram Siddiqui has denied the allegations and said “such behaviour falls under the jurisdiction of Fifa&#39;s compliance team.如果这些资金来自赞助，则联合会的审计必须披露此信息。 The previous General Secretary (Fazil Mohammad Shahab) finalised the 2021 audit report and submitted it to Fifa.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Since the regime transition in August 2021, there has been no movement of funds from Fifa or any external sources to the football federation&#39;s bank account. Therefore, any previous actions concerning this issue are not within my knowledge.”&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-atom-id=&quot;eab35d41-dbe9-4aec-9209-ae22c3b80688&quot; data-atom-type=&quot;guide&quot;>; &lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;eab35d41-dbe9-4aec-9209-ae22c3b80688&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;guide&quot;>; &lt;summary>; &lt;span>;Quick guide&lt;/span>; &lt;h4>;How do I sign up for sport breaking news alerts?&lt;/h4>;&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>; &lt;span>; &lt;svg width=&quot;18px&quot; height=&quot;18px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 18 18&quot;>; &lt;path d=&quot;M8.2 0h1.6l.4 7.8 7.8.4v1.6l-7.8.4-.4 7.8H8.2l-.4-7.8L0 9.8V8.2l7.8-.4.4-7.8z&quot; />; &lt;/svg>; Show&lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;svg width=&quot;32px&quot; height=&quot;32px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot;>; &lt;rect x=&quot;5&quot; y=&quot;15&quot; width=&quot;22&quot; height=&quot;3&quot;>;&lt;/rect>; &lt;/svg>; Hide&lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/summary>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Download the Guardian app from the iOS App Store on iPhone or the Google Play store on Android by searching for &#39;The Guardian&#39;.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;If you already have the Guardian app, make sure you&#39;re on the most recent version.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;In the Guardian app, tap the Menu button at the bottom right, then go to Settings (the gear icon), then Notifications.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Turn on sport notifications.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;footer>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Was this helpful? &lt;/div>;&lt;button value=&quot;like&quot; aria-label=&quot;Yes&quot;>; &lt;svg width=&quot;40px&quot; height=&quot;40px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 40 40&quot;>; &lt;path fill=&quot;#FFF&quot; d=&quot;M33.78 22.437l-4.228 13.98L27.93 37.5 5.062 34.14V15.503l7.8-1.517L24.354 2.5h1.624L28.9 5.426l-4.548 8.67h.107l10.477 1.31&quot; />; &lt;/svg>;&lt;/button>; &lt;button value=&quot;dislike&quot; aria-label=&quot;No&quot;>; &lt;svg width=&quot;40px&quot; height=&quot;40px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 40 40&quot;>; &lt;path fill=&quot;#FFF&quot; d=&quot;M33.78 22.437l-4.228 13.98L27.93 37.5 5.062 34.14V15.503l7.8-1.517L24.354 2.5h1.624L28.9 5.426l-4.548 8.67h.107l10.477 1.31&quot; />; &lt;/svg>;&lt;/button>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div hidden aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;>; Thank you for your feedback. &lt;/div>; &lt;/footer>; &lt;/details>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;The players have also alleged that members of the AFF&#39;s executive committee distributed half of the $30,000 bonus meant for the squad after making it through to the next round of World Cup among themselves. Siddiqui disputed this and said the players had been given $20,000, with the remaining $10,000 used “to cover our national team&#39;s expenses during training camp, as we have not had any money in our bank account for the past 10 months”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He added that the money was “used to pay for the domestic flights of the national team players from various provinces, as Fifa does not cover domestic flights for all players who have to join the national team”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shayesteh and his teammates have also claimed that members of the AFF leadership have been misappropriating money from airfare tickets of players for traveling to play matches. In documents seen by the Guardian, the AFF claimed back almost $65,000 from Fifa for a trip to the Central Asian Football Association Nations Cup in Kyrgyzstan in June that was initially expected to cost about $45,000.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;66f7dd2387d6248a561179d8af209f8672659c44&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/66f7dd2387d6248a561179d8af209f8672659c44/0_0_2142_1515/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Noor Husin&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;707&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;Noor Husin says at the last camp &#39;a big group of us decided that we&#39;d had enough&#39;.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;Siddiqui has denied the allegations and said the increase in costs was due to their original quotation from the travel agency having expired, meaning they were forced to buy the flights hours before they were due to leave. “一些球员抱怨没有提供商务舱航班，而商务舱航班通常由职业球队使用，”他说。 “However, the federation is unable to charter or pay for business class flights from its funds.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The players&#39; letter also accuses the AFF president inflated bills covered by Fifa for hotel rooms – an allegation that was also denied by Siddiqui. “事实是，所有酒店都会将发票连同银行账户详细信息一起发送给国际足联。 Once approved by Fifa&#39;s compliance team, the money is directly transferred to the hotel&#39;s account, which can take a considerable amount of time.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that former Bradford and Wrexham defender Ashley Westwood has been approached to take over from Abdullah Al Mutairi, who was sacked after refusing to sign the match sheet before the qualifier against Mongolia. Westwood has yet to sign a contract due to apparent concerns about the dispute.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A squad of largely local-based players has been selected for the qualifier against Qatar, which is due to take place in Saudi Arabia after the AFF signed a deal for the country to host all of its home matches.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have been playing our home games in Tajikistan and that is the country where we have an advantage if you look at our results – even against Qatar we only lost 1-0 and we missed a penalty – because the weather is a big advantage,” said Shayesteh. “But now they have sold our home games to Saudi where the weather is hot so it&#39;s not to our advantage.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Fifa spokesperson said: “Fifa was informed of these allegations very recently and is currently looking into the matter.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:22:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>