<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[Ukrainian PoWs being sent to fight their own army, Russian news claims]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/ukrainian-pows-being-sent-to-fight-their-own-army-russian-news-claims]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T21:59:53Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a90aabd5eb70c91fdc136012bf40b1ffa7278364/0_79_6720_4032 /master/6720.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=409b13a74c7950e6c737254340f740bf&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;夏季的一天，一名士兵在奥列尼克看守监狱&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯正在将乌克兰囚犯据俄罗斯国家通讯社俄新社报道，乌克兰人前往祖国前线，在战争中站在莫斯科一边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄新社周二发布的视频显示，乌克兰人手持步枪宣誓效忠俄罗斯身着军装，在以中世纪贵族波格丹·赫梅利尼茨基命名的营中作战。波格丹·赫梅利尼茨基因在 15 世纪将乌克兰部分地区置于莫斯科的控制之下而被视为俄罗斯的民族英雄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该通讯社称，该营上个月开始服役。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/ Russia- ukraine-war-at-a-glance-what-we-know-on-day-623&quot;>;俄罗斯-乌克兰战争一览：我们在 623 天所知道的&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;美联社无法立即证实该通讯社发布的报道或视频的真实性，也无法确认战俘是否是被迫采取行动的。乌克兰军方和人权官员以及俄罗斯国防部均未立即回应美联社的置评请求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专家表示，此类行为明显违反了有关治疗的日内瓦公约战俘，这禁止他们参加战斗或在不健康或危险的条件下工作——无论是否受到胁迫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“俄罗斯当局可能声称他们是在自愿的基础上招募他们的，但很难想象他们会在自愿的基础上招募他们。人权观察组织乌克兰问题高级研究员尤利娅·戈尔布诺娃 (Yulia Gorbunova) 表示：“考虑到强制拘留的情况，战俘的决定可以真正自愿地做出。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尼克·雷诺兹 (Nick Reynolds)伦敦皇家联合军种研究所补充说，“整个情况都存在胁迫的可能性”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，战俘没有“大量的代理权”，而且华盛顿战争研究所表示，此前有报道称乌克兰战俘被要求“自愿”加入该营。他们被关押在奥列尼夫卡监狱，该监狱于 7 月被炸毁。 2022 年&lt;/a>;。俄罗斯称乌克兰用火箭摧毁了该国东部的监狱，但基辅将爆炸归咎于莫斯科，以掩盖其所谓的虐待和杀害战俘的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /www.theguardian.com/world/2022/sep/20/ Russia-recruits-inmates-ukraine-war-wagner-prigozhin&quot;>;俄罗斯还利用自己监狱的囚犯&lt;/a>;在乌克兰作战，以换取如果他们幸存，将减刑。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/apr/22/alcohol -and-prostitutes-wagner-convicts-pardoned-by-putin-return-to-terrorise-home-towns&quot;>;谋杀、“酒精和妓女”：被普京赦免的瓦格纳罪犯返回恐怖家乡&lt;/a>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;ISW 的卡罗琳娜·赫德 (Karolina Hird) 表示，它还试图通过“在被占领的乌克兰开展征兵活动”来增强其力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过动员乌克兰战俘、部署俄罗斯囚犯和征兵入伍赫德表示，对于生活在被占领地区的乌克兰人来说，俄罗斯正在增加其作战力量，“而不必冒进行总动员带来社会影响的风险”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年早些时候，俄罗斯媒体报道称，约有 70 名乌克兰战俘加入了部队&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄新社报道称，乌克兰人将作为乌克兰东部另一个部队的一部分行动，该部队的网站称其拥有约 7,000 名战士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考虑到该部队的位置赫德表示，她预计乌克兰战俘将被部署到顿涅茨克和扎波罗热地区的前线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷诺兹表示，这些战斗机并不是作为俄罗斯常规军事部队的一部分部署的，而是众多战俘之一。不遵循“法向力结构”的不规则队形。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 06:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cruise recalls all self-driving cars after grisly accident and California ban]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/nov/08/cruise-recall-self-driving-cars-gm]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T18:17:31Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/26ce3afad784fd52b5617e7cc798a881a00f4d94/0_111_3913_2348 /master/3913.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=bc29e80c9075b791bcd89a3843230b91&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;在旧金山公司总部外巡航自动驾驶汽车。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;通用汽车的 &lt; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/24/driverless-car-self-driven-california-cruise-gm&quot;>;邮轮自动驾驶车辆&lt;/a>;单位正在召回所有10 月初，其中一辆汽车将一名行人拖到旧金山街道一侧，随后加州监管机构发出禁令，该公司的 950 辆汽车需要更新软件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该公司在美国安全监管机构发布的文件中表示周三，通过更新软件，如果将来发生类似事件，Cruise 车辆将保持静止状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 月 2 日的事故促使 Cruise 在加州监管机构发现其汽车构成危险后在全国范围内暂停了无人驾驶业务为了公共安全。该州机动车辆部门吊销了 Cruise 的执照，该公司在旧金山各处运送乘客，但没有人类司机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在事故中，另一辆载有人员的车辆撞到了一名行人，导致行人摔倒Cruise 自动驾驶车辆的路径。游轮最初停下来，但仍然撞到了人。但随后它向右行驶以避开交通，将人向前拉了约 20 英尺（六米）。行人被困在 Cruise 车辆的一个轮胎下，受重伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cruise 在美国国家公路交通安全管理局发布的文件中表示，它已经更新了由美国国家公路交通安全管理局监管的测试车辆的软件。人类安全驾驶员。该公司表示，无人驾驶车队将在恢复运营之前安装新软件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通用汽车部门在周三的一份声明中表示，尽管它确定发生类似的事故并有可能造成严重后果，但它还是进行了此次召回。如果没有更新，每 10m 到 100m 英里就可能再次发生严重伤害。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们努力不断改进，让此类事件变得更加罕见，”声明称。 “随着我们的软件不断改进，我们很可能会提出更多召回，以通知 NHTSA 和公众更新，以增强我们车队的安全性。”克鲁斯表示，在检查其系统后，它已经决定增加一名首席安全官，聘请一家律师事务所来审查其对 10 月份事故的反应，任命一家第三方工程公司来查找技术原因，并在全公司范围内采用“支柱”来关注安全性和透明度。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Cruise 的问题可能会减慢全自动驾驶汽车的部署速度，这些汽车在没有人类驾驶员的情况下载客。它还可能会加强联邦对这些车辆的监管，这些车辆在全国更多城市载客。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NHTSA 于 10 月 16 日对四份有关 Cruise 车辆可能未对行人保持适当警惕的报告展开调查。该机构的文件提到了两人受伤，其中包括 10 月 2 日的坠机事故。该机构表示，这些投诉涉及自动驾驶的车辆以及“侵犯道路上或进入道路的行人，包括车辆预定行驶路径附近的人行横道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在向 NHTSA 提交的文件中， Cruise 表示，其自动驾驶系统的设计目的是在某些情况下靠边停车，以尽量减少碰撞后的安全风险和干扰，并根据碰撞的特征做出反应。但在某些情况下，例如行人位于车辆路径上的地面上，靠边停车并不是理想的反应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巡航系统“错误地将碰撞定性为横向碰撞，并命令自动驾驶汽车尝试尝试该公司表示，“为了避开交通拥堵，将个人向前拉，而不是保持静止。”虽然机动车辆管理局没有详细说明吊销 Cruise 驾照的具体原因，但该机构指责Cruise 歪曲了有关其车辆自动驾驶技术的安全信息。此次撤销是在一系列事件发生后发生的，这些事件加剧了人们对 Cruise 机器人出租车造成的危险和不便的担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;DMV 和其他机构指责 Cruise 最初没有分享事故的所有视频片段，但机器人出租车运营商推动回来 - 表示已向州和联邦官员披露了完整的视频。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通用汽车公司对 Cruise 有着雄心勃勃的目标。这家底特律汽车制造商预计，到 2025 年，Cruise 的年收入将达到 10 亿美元，比去年的 1.06 亿美元收入大幅增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通用汽车最近暂停了 Origin 的生产，这是一款专为 Cruise 设计的全自动货车运载多名乘客。一旦 Cruise 恢复自动驾驶乘车服务，该公司预计将恢复底特律地区工厂的生产。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Uyghur film-maker claims he was tortured by authorities in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/nov/08/uyghur-film-maker-ikram-nurmehmet-claims-he-was-tortured-by-authorities-in-china]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T20:05:21Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/62bf0bcf1678b4ae4359ddd37d94b23f1e296a11/0_378_1751_1750 /master/1751.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=5c493470aa76768ef1698eda3f1dce42&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Ikram Nurmehmet&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一名维吾尔族电影制片人声称他受到酷刑并被迫给予新疆省拘留期间作出虚假供述。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;32岁的伊克拉姆·努尔买提于10月27日在乌鲁木齐市中级法院出庭受审，被指控组织“恐怖”活动和参加“东突分裂”组织，与他关系密切的消息人士告诉《卫报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国当局指责东突厥斯坦伊斯兰运动，该运动&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/23/world/asia /afghanistan-uyghurs-china-taliban.html&quot;>;曾在新疆主张独立&lt;/a>;，因为 20 世纪 90 年代末发生了一系列恐怖袭击，并将类似组织视为分裂主义威胁。努尔买买提否认了这些指控，也没有宣布任何判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;努尔买买提因在作品中描绘维吾尔族主角而闻名，他还花了六年时间在土耳其学习电影制作，他的支持者称这使他成为国家审查的目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据报道，努尔梅迈特在审判期间表示，“我被关在暗室里 20 天，并受到肉体折磨”，并补充说，他在拘留期间被迫做出虚假供述。 “我在土耳其期间从未参加过任何恐怖组织或任何政治活动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nurmehmet 的妻子、母亲和父亲参加了审判，自从他出生以来，他们就没有见过他&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/oct/24/trial-of-uyghur-film-maker-to-begin-in-china-this-week&quot;>;在家中被捕&lt;/a>; 于北京，并于 5 月飞往新疆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据与努尔买买提关系密切的消息人士透露，他选择法律顾问的决定被拒绝，目前由国家指定的律师代理。律师告诉家人，预计将被判处“八年以上监禁”，并且可能在“一周或几年后”的任何时间宣布判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我一直感觉他可以突然释放。这一直在我的脑海里，”一位与他关系密切的消息人士告诉《卫报》。 “这就是为什么当我听说他（可能面临）至少八年监禁时感到非常失望。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人权观察亚洲分部副主任王玛雅 (Maya Wang) 称使用酷刑是“例行公事” ”在被告面临政治指控的案件中，尤其是在新疆。她说，虽然中国法律有一项排除条款，规定任何通过刑讯逼供取得的口供都应在审判中排除，但该规则“实际上在实践中不起作用”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据中国法律，“恐怖主义”一词中国人权捍卫者组织的研究和宣传协调员倪威廉表示，“恐怖分子”的定义很广泛，可以涵盖从制作政治敏感电影到会见任何海外维吾尔族或人权活动人士（他们都被中国政府视为恐怖分子）的任何事情。 。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nee 补充说，在国家想要控制结果的政治敏感案件中，当局经常会剥夺家庭指定自己法律顾问的权利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;努尔梅迈特的支持者正在努力关于向联合国任意拘留问题工作组提交请愿书，要求提供更多信息并继续为他辩护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去一年，工作组就&lt;a href=&quot;https ://thediplomat.com/2023/08/a-un-body-sheds-light-on-the-fate-of-disappeared-uyghurs/&quot;>;三起涉及维吾尔人的案件&lt;/a>;，均被视为维吾尔人权项目研究和宣传副主任彼得·欧文表示，维吾尔知识分子和文化精英遭受的迫害可能比报道的更为广泛建议的案例。他说，就努尔梅迈特的案件而言，很难知道他是因为在土耳其留学还是因为他作为文化人物的身份而成为目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有很多被判刑的人都去了土耳其。在某些方面，这位电影制片人通过他的作品所做的事情——维吾尔人的人性化以及[促进]维吾尔人和中国人民之间的沟通——我认为政府对这类事情感到怀疑和担忧。”&lt;/p>; &lt; 2014年，据报道维吾尔分裂分子策划了多起恐怖袭击事件后，中国政府在新疆发起了严厉打击恐怖主义行动。估计有 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hrw.org/news/2022/09/14/china-xinjian-official-figures-reveal-higher-prisoner-count&quot;>;50 万&lt;/a>; 人据信，他们是在 2017 年升级的镇压期间被监禁的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据统计，有 300 多名知识分子及其文化精英成员在 2016 年至 2021 年间失踪后，目前受到某种形式的法外拘留。维吾尔人权项目的&lt;a href=&quot;https://uhrp.org/intellectuals/&quot;>;数据库&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Economists warn electing far-right Milei would spell ‘devastation’ for Argentina]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/argentina-election-javier-milei-economists-warning]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T19:28:54Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f4772ba01a503abab71594a620ccf6dfde43afb2/0_224_4287_2573 /master/4287.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=016aca69d1a0f029cb8d0c6170814494&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;哈维尔·米雷在车里挥手&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;激进右翼经济学家哈维尔·米雷当选总统&lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/world/argentina&quot;>;阿根廷&lt;/a>;可能会给南美洲造成进一步的经济“破坏”和社会混乱100 多位顶尖经济学家组成的团体发出警告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿根廷 11 月 19 日大选之前发表的一封公开信中，经济学家表示，他们理解阿根廷民众“对经济稳定的根深蒂固的渴望”。考虑到阿根廷频繁发生的金融危机和反复出现的高通胀，目前十分之四的公民生活在贫困之中，年通货膨胀率接近 140%——米雷发誓要通过击败竞争对手来解决这一危机，阿根廷财政部长塞尔吉奥·马萨，并&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/22/argentina-javier-milei-presidential-election&quot;>;采取戏剧性措施，例如废除中央银行银行和经济美元化。&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“然而，虽然表面上简单的解决方案可能很有吸引力，但它们可能在短期内对现实世界造成更多破坏，同时严重压缩政策空间这封信警告说，“从长远来看，”这封信的签署人包括法国的托马斯·皮凯蒂、印度的贾亚蒂·戈什、塞尔维亚裔美国人布兰科·米兰诺维奇和哥伦比亚前财政部长何塞·安东尼奥·奥坎波等有影响力的经济学家。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/22/argentina-javier-milei-presidential-election&quot;>;“糟糕而危险”：阿根廷的特朗普有望成为总统&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;这封信称，米莱的提议虽然被提出为“彻底背离传统经济思维”，但实际上“植根于自由放任的经济学”，并且“充满风险，对阿根廷经济和阿根廷人民可能非常有害。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在竞选过程中，自称无政府资本主义者的米雷挥舞着一把电锯来象征他的愿望削减补贴并大幅减少国家在社会项目上的支出。他还多次声称“税收是盗窃”，并称他们资助的“社会正义”计划是“失常”。他说：“国家是魔鬼发明的，上帝的制度是自由市场。”但经济学家在信中警告说，“政府支出的大幅削减将加剧本已很高的贫困水平”和不平等，并可能导致社会紧张和冲突显着加剧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“哈维尔·米莱的美元化和财政紧缩提议忽视了现代经济的复杂性，忽视了历史危机的教训，并为强调已经存在的问题打开了大门。他们写道：“严重的不平等”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马萨诸塞大学阿默斯特分校的发展经济学家戈什表示，她和这封信的另外两位合著者皮凯蒂和米拉诺维奇担心米莱的政策“将严重损害社会”。阿根廷，对整个大陆来说非常不幸”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这不仅是极右立场可能造成的社会混乱，而且是公共收入和公共收入下降所带来的经济混乱。戈什补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“阿根廷人将在一场面临非常艰难选择的选举中投票。但诋毁公共部门的自由主义解决方案只会增加痛苦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;距离阿根廷近代历史上最重要的选举之一还有不到两周的时间，这次选举看起来势均力敌。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;在上个月的第一轮比赛之前，米雷被广泛认为是领跑者，尽管他 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/23/argentina-javier-milei-presidential -election&quot;>;出人意料地以 29.9% 的得票率击败马萨的 36.6% 获得第二名&lt;/a>;。然而，从那时起，这位古怪的经济学家得到了两位著名保守派人士的支持：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/25/argentina-presidential-election-patricia-bullrich-endorse -javier-milei&quot;>;第三名候选人帕特里夏·布尔里奇&lt;/a>;和前总统毛里西奥·马克里。燃料短缺也削弱了马萨的竞选活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布宜诺斯艾利斯咨询公司 Cefeidas Group 的董事总经理胡安·克鲁斯·迪亚斯 (Juan Cruz Díaz) 表示，当两位候选人进入最后的直选阶段时，需要在选举中推动选举。不同的方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;米莱需要将辩论的重点放在对手庇隆主义运动的经济失败上，该运动在过去 20 年中掌权了 16 年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马萨同时需要集中精力米雷反复无常的性格说服选民不要支持像他的对手这样“奢侈、愤怒、疯狂”的散漫大炮。迪亚斯说：“他会尽力表现出他情绪不稳定、暴力、好斗、极端两极分化和分裂的形象。”考虑到阿根廷的经济困境，他不确定这样的努力是否足够。 “如果你问我，米莱有优势。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只要提到 20 世纪英国哲学家和经济学家约翰·梅纳德·凯恩斯，米莱就会爆发出无法控制的愤怒，他不太可能对此印象深刻。通过公开信。米莱认为凯恩斯是一位马克思主义者，凯恩斯挑战了自由市场可以提供充分就业和经济增长的观点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西班牙报纸 El País 的一个新播客采访了米莱的一位前邻居，他试图“闲聊，”凯恩斯在电梯里提到。 “但你就是个共产主义废物，”据说米莱一直对着那个女人喊到了十楼。米莱过去也攻击过皮凯蒂，称他为“混蛋”和“伪装成知识分子的罪犯”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 03:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Industrial robot crushes man to death in South Korean distribution centre]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/nov/08/south-korean-man-killed-by-industrial-robot-in-distribution-centre]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T18:58:43Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ebadf4c27c4983323d9e17c0ddf81e24bcf5dcdc/0_70_6720_4032 /master/6720.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=404b0bc42604ab0e279ace956fd4eaf8&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;机器人手臂将箱子放在传送带上。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;南部的一个机器人将一名男子压死据韩联社周三报道，该男子是一名 40 多岁的机器人公司员工，当时他正在检查机器人的传感器操作。在庆尚南道的农产品配送中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工业机器人正在举起装满青椒的盒子并将其放在托盘上，但似乎发生了故障，并识别出该男子是一个盒子，韩联社援引警方消息报道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据韩联社报道，机械臂将这名男子的上半身压在传送带上，压碎了他的脸部和胸部。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他被转移到了医院。报道称，送往医院后不治身亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3月份，一名50多岁的韩国男子在一家汽车零部件制造厂工作时被机器人困住，身受重伤。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 03:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Seventeen men arrested in Sicily and US in joint anti-mafia operation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/us-sicily-mafia-arrests-gambino-family]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T18:33:55Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/140dba7886994088458382ce4ad8037a66321965/0_350_5247_3148 /master/5247.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=754d82706aaf4e067c749328446b7b62&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;宪兵警察和军人阻止进入黑手党老大马泰奥·梅西纳·德纳罗 (Matteo Messina Denaro) 用作藏身之处的房屋， 1 月 19 日在西西里岛坎波贝洛迪马扎拉。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;联邦调查局和意大利警方联合开展反黑手党行动，在西西里岛和美国逮捕了 17 名男子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;逮捕行动来之后&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansa.it/sito/notizie/cronaca/2023/11/08/blitz-contro-famiglie-mafiose-17-fermi-tra-palermo-e-new- york_627a27f5-52d3-45d7-8dad-25c6a8a7448e.html#:~:text=Sono%20in%20corso%20una%20serie,incendi%20aggravati%20dal%20metodo%20mafioso。&quot;>;针对以下成员的两年调查&lt;/a>;纽约臭名昭著的甘比诺犯罪家族及其一些驻扎在巴勒莫省的西西里同伙。西西里岛有 7 名男子被捕，纽约有 10 名男子被捕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴勒莫检察官表示，调查揭示了纽约和西西里黑帮之间“现有关系的牢固性”以及“美国对该组织的兴趣”。甘比诺家族是纽约五个历史悠久的意大利裔美国黑手党家族之一。此前针对家庭成员的指控包括谋杀、高利贷和非法毒品分销。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察官发现的证据表明，美国黑手党正在接受西西里“表兄弟”的培训和指导，以雇用更温和、更少暴力的人方法。这种做法包括向勒索受害者索要较少的金额，这样受害者就不太可能向当局寻求帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据调查人员称，西西里黑手党家族还帮助美国人针对纽约餐馆老板的亲属居住在西西里岛，强迫他们支付&lt;em>;pizzo&lt;/em>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/mar/09/internationalcrime.italy&quot;>;或黑手党保护费&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这次行动再次证明了西西里部落与美国黑手党家族之间的关系网络是多么危险和相互关联，”反黑手党委员会主席基亚拉·科洛西莫 (Chiara Colosimo) 说。 “我一直认为，像黑手党这样的全球现象需要全球性的应对措施，今天的调查证实了这一点。”&lt;br>;&lt;br>; 调查人员强调，贩毒仍然是大洋彼岸犯罪家族之间的共同商业联系.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最早处理纽约和西西里黑手党家族之间毒品交易的法官之一是传奇的反黑手党法官乔瓦尼·法尔科内 (Giovanni Falcone)。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10979 年至 1984 年期间，与美国调查人员一起，法尔科内发现了如何&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1987/03/03/nyregion/17-found-guilty-in-pizza-trial-of-a-drug-ring.html&quot;>;意大利美式比萨饼店和餐馆被用来掩盖从西西里岛进口海洛因&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西西里黑手党家族通过土耳其毒贩从瑞士购买了大量吗啡。然后吗啡将通过海运或陆运到西西里岛，暴徒在巴勒莫省建立了隐藏的实验室来提炼毒品。提炼后的产品随后被送往北欧和美国。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019 /may/23/us-mafia-explosives-expert-helped-sicilian-mob-kill-judge&quot;>;美国黑手党爆炸物专家“帮助西西里暴徒杀死法官”&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;据当时的调查人员称，美国消耗的海洛因中有30%是由西西里黑手党管理的。 &lt;br>;&lt;br>; 在那次行动之后，乔瓦尼·法尔科内成为那些年西西里和美国黑手党的头号敌人。 1992 年，他被暗杀，当时在高速公路下放置的 300 公斤 TNT 在道路上炸出了一个 15 米深的弹坑，导致他、妻子和三名保镖丧生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/may/23/us-mafia-explosives-expert-helped-sicilian-mob-kill-judge&quot;>;一名前黑手党杀手&lt;/a>;后来声称甘比诺家族在暗杀前派出了一名炸弹专家前往西西里岛训练科萨·诺斯特拉 (Cosa Nostra) 暴徒。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 02:52:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Two with suspected Hezbollah links held in Brazil over alleged terror plot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/brazil-hezbollah-terror-plot]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T18:19:46Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6658aa50cac2b62c33b62ec1871598c289b992a0/0_70_1920_1152 /master/1920.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=2e92826801f1db2c1e459da7eeeeabb3&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;三辆巴西警车&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;巴西联邦警察逮捕了两名涉嫌与黎巴嫩人有联系的男子据报道，武装组织真主党密谋对巴西的犹太社区发动恐怖袭击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;逮捕行动是在周三警方的行动&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.br/pf /pt-br/assuntos/noticias/2023/11/policia-federal-deflagra-operacao-para-prevenir-atos-terroristas-no-pais&quot;>;呼吁&lt;/a>;采取行动“中断恐怖主义行为的准备工作，获取有关可能招募巴西人实施极端主义行为的证据”。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world /2023/nov/03/hezbollah-leader-threatens-escalation-in-fighting-with-israel&quot;>;真主党领导人威胁与以色列的战斗升级&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;媒体报道称一名男子从黎巴嫩飞抵巴西最大的国际机场圣保罗瓜鲁柳斯后被捕。巴西有线电视网络 CNN &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnnbrasil.com.br/nacional/brasileiros-ligados-ao 表示：“联邦警察相信他带来的信息是为了向他的搭档传递有关实施袭击的信息” -hezbollah-preparavam-ataques-no-brasil-diz-pf/&quot;>;报道&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;里约热内卢《O Globo》报纸称，调查人员认为“该组织计划对属于巴西政府的建筑物发动袭击”犹太社区，包括犹太教堂”，但没有提及具体目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴西是拉丁美洲第二大犹太社区的所在地，还有一座据说是美洲第一座建于 17 世纪的犹太教堂。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;多份报告称，被捕男子与总部位于黎巴嫩的伊斯兰民兵组织真主党有联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方表示，他们已在三个地区执行搜查令：圣保罗、米纳斯吉拉斯州和巴西首都巴西利亚周围的联邦区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“招募人员及其招募人员将面临创建或属于恐怖组织以及为恐怖主义行为做准备的指控，最高可能判处 15 刑期。” - 入狱一年半，”警方在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真主党是以色列 1982 年入侵黎巴嫩后由激进的什叶派神职人员创立的，如今它既是一个强大的政治运动，也是一个拥有全球足迹，包括南美洲。美国认为该组织被称为“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/19/what-is-hezbollah-and-how-will-it-influence- the-israel-hamas-war&quot;>;大规模伤亡自杀式袭击的先驱&lt;/a>;”——一个外国恐怖组织，而英国则将其视为被禁止的国际恐怖组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去的恐怖行为归因于真主党包括 1983 年对美国和法国军队以及美国驻黎巴嫩大使馆的自杀式袭击，造成 300 多名士兵和平民死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真主党还因 1992 年 3 月轰炸以色列驻阿根廷首都大使馆而受到指责，布宜诺斯艾利斯。这次袭击造成 29 人死亡，袭击者是一名名叫穆罕默德·努尔丁 (Muhammad Nur al-Din) 的自杀式炸弹袭击者，他是黎巴嫩公民，最初移民到巴西。据报道，这起爆炸事件计划在阿根廷、巴西和巴拉圭三国边境地区进行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两年后，阿根廷犹太社区遭受了更严重的打击，有 86 人在&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.theguardian.com/world/2015/may/19/iran-argentina-jewish-centre-amia-bombing&quot;>;1994 年 AMIA 犹太社区中心爆炸案&lt;/a>;。 《纽约时报》&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/22/world/middleeast/argentina-mossad-hezbollah-bombings.html&quot;>;称&lt;/a>;这次袭击是“第二次世界大战以来最致命的反犹太罪行”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据去年同一份报纸的报道，以色列特勤局摩萨德随后进行的调查得出的结论是，阿根廷的两次袭击是由一名武装人员实施的。 secret Hezbollah unit in retaliation for Israeli operations against the group, including the 1992 assassination of its leader Abbas Musawi. The explosives that were used for the Buenos Aires attacks were reportedly smuggled into the South American country on flights from Europe concealed in shampoo bottles and boxes of chocolate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Latin America is home to several large Jewish communities, the biggest of which is in &lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/world/argentina&quot;>;Argentina&lt;/a>;, home to an estimated 180,000 Jews. About 100,000 Jews live in Brazil, the majority in Rio and São Paulo, and 40,000 in Mexico.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 02:52:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Olympic Games organisers sticking to Tahiti surfing site amid coral reef fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2023/nov/08/olympic-games-organisers-sticking-to-tahiti-surfing-site-despite-coral-reef-fears]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T17:33:41Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6f756cd57116d7b5847d4e304112d7c69542a26e/0_9_6000_3600/master/6000.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=8c3f5491f669fd4f0dd4d57f1ae280b1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;The existing wooden surf tower in Teahupo&#39;o&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Paris 2024 organisers are sticking to their choice of Tahiti&#39;s Teahupo&#39;o site for the Olympics surfing competition despite local opposition amid a dispute over the construction of an aluminium tower that residents say would damage the coral reef.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The idyllic lagoon-side village has long hosted some of the best contests on the professional World Surf League&#39;s (WSL) championship tour, using a modest wooden tower for judges on the reef that is dismantled after every event.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/oct/08/can-paris-clean-seine-for-next-year-2024-olympics&quot;>;Can Paris clean up the Seine in time for next year&#39;s Olympics?&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;Paris 2024, which has highlighted its ambition to minimise the Games&#39; environmental impacts, plans to spend nearly $5m to build a much larger tower with toilets, air-conditioning and space for 40 people that it says is needed to meet safety standards.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An online petition calling for the scrapping of plans for the 14-metre aluminium scaffolding and 800m service channel through the reef had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/faatura-ia-teahupo-o&quot;>;gathered more than 150,000 signatures&lt;/a>; by Wednesday. French Polynesia president Moetai Brotherson on Wednesday said the surfing events for the Summer Games could be moved to the Taharuu, on Tahiti&#39;s West coast.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“That would have enabled us to avoid the problems we have today. At the time, it wasn&#39;t possible. In view of the issues at stake and the protests today, perhaps we can revise this option,” Brotherson was quoted as saying by French media at the Pacific Islands Forum (PIF).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paris 2024 said it wished to find a solution through dialogue. “As our president, Tony Estanguet, recently pointed out, our priority today is to find a solution that will enable us to organise the surfing events of the Olympic Games in Tahiti, at the Teahupo&#39;o site, in the best possible conditions,” Paris 2024 organisers said in a statement to Reuters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Tahiti was chosen because of the Teahupo&#39;o site and its legendary wave, one of the most beautiful in the world. Discussions and studies will continue over the coming weeks to find a solution for organising the events on the Teahupo&#39;o site.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-atom-id=&quot;eab35d41-dbe9-4aec-9209-ae22c3b80688&quot; data-atom-type=&quot;guide&quot;>; &lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;eab35d41-dbe9-4aec-9209-ae22c3b80688&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;guide&quot;>; &lt;summary>; &lt;span>;Quick guide&lt;/span>; &lt;h4>;How do I sign up for sport breaking news alerts?&lt;/h4>;&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>; &lt;span>; &lt;svg width=&quot;18px&quot; height=&quot;18px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 18 18&quot;>; &lt;path d=&quot;M8.2 0h1.6l.4 7.8 7.8.4v1.6l-7.8.4-.4 7.8H8.2l-.4-7.8L0 9.8V8.2l7.8-.4.4-7.8z&quot; />; &lt;/svg>; Show&lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;svg width=&quot;32px&quot; height=&quot;32px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot;>; &lt;rect x=&quot;5&quot; y=&quot;15&quot; width=&quot;22&quot; height=&quot;3&quot;>;&lt;/rect>; &lt;/svg>; Hide&lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/summary>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Download the Guardian app from the iOS App Store on iPhone or the Google Play store on Android by searching for &#39;The Guardian&#39;.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;If you already have the Guardian app, make sure you&#39;re on the most recent version.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;In the Guardian app, tap the Menu button at the bottom right, then go to Settings (the gear icon), then Notifications.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Turn on sport notifications.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;footer>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Was this helpful? &lt;/div>;&lt;button value=&quot;like&quot; aria-label=&quot;Yes&quot;>; &lt;svg width=&quot;40px&quot; height=&quot;40px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 40 40&quot;>; &lt;path fill=&quot;#FFF&quot; d= “M33.78 22.437l-4.228 13.98L27.93 37.5 5.062 34.14V15.503l7.8-1.517L24.354 2.5h1.624L28.9 5.426l-4.548 8.67h.107l10.477 1. 31&quot; />; &lt;/svg>;&lt; /button>; &lt;button value=&quot;不喜欢&quot; aria-label=&quot;否&quot;>; &lt;svg width=&quot;40px&quot; height=&quot;40px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 40 40&quot;>; &lt;path fill=&quot;#FFF&quot; d=&quot; M33.78 22.437l-4.228 13.98L27.93 37.5 5.062 34.14V15.503l7.8-1.517L24.354 2.5h1.624L28.9 5.426l-4.548 8.67h.107l10.477 1.3 1&quot; />; &lt;/svg>;&lt;/按钮>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div hide aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;>; 感谢您的反馈。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/footer>; &lt;/details>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;“Along with all the stakeholders, and the Polynesian government in particular, Paris 2024 will continue to listen to all possible solutions to further improve the project. Dialogue and work will continue with environmental associations and local residents.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The International Surfing Association (ISA), which is in charge of the surfing competition at the Olympics, was not immediately available for comment. The Paris 2024 Olympics will be held from 26 July to 11 August.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 01:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[European Commission backs talks on Ukraine and Moldova EU membership]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/european-commission-endorses-membership-talks-with-ukraine-and-moldova]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T17:02:34Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/03987795bbb147327b82990a3264d3357376d643/0_501_8208_4925/master/8208.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=db74caa1e309d3d3a672cb63c0418c8a&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Ursula von der Leyen holds a press conference&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2023/nov/08/eu-ukraine-moldova-kosovo-turkey-member-states-russia-europe-live&quot;>;has recommended&lt;/a>; that formal EU membership negotiations should begin with Ukraine and Moldova in a move its president, Ursula von der Leyen, described as a response to “the call of history”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a 1,200-page report on future enlargement of the 27-member bloc, the EU said talks should formally be launched once Kyiv satisfied remaining conditions related to stepping up the fight against corruption, adopting a law on lobbying in line with EU standards and strengthening national minority safeguards.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report also recommended opening accession talks with Bosnia, but only if it met conditions in certain areas, and giving candidate status to Georgia, a step that would set it on the path for eventual accession.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writing on Telegram in response, Volodymyr Zelenskiy, the Ukrainian president, welcomed the long-awaited decision, which marks an important milestone on Kyiv&#39;s road to integration and a geopolitical gambit for the west, as the country has been fighting against Russia&#39;s invasion since February 2022.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Today, the history of Ukraine and the whole of Europe has made the right step,” Zelensky said on Telegram. “Our country should be in the European Union,” he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ukrainian foreign minister, Dmytro Kuleba, said the hope of a “European future for our children” had helped to get his country through “the most difficult time any European nation has faced in modern history”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our fight and sacrifices are not in vain. Our transformation is recognised. Our dreams and hopes are coming true,” Kuleba wrote on X, formerly Twitter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commission&#39;s decision, which has to be ratified by prime ministers at a summit in December, could eventually lead to the biggest expansion of the bloc since 2004, when 10 countries joined the EU, including Poland, the Czech Republic, the Baltic states and Hungary.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Von der Leyen, said: “Completing our union is the call of history. It is the natural horizon.” Membership of the EU was a “powerful lever” that would boost economies and stability of the bloc, she added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said: “The neighbourhood, our neighbourhood, has to choose where they want to go. And the western Balkans, Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine chose very clearly where they want to go.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She added: “If you look into the report and you see the list of reforms, it shows determination, the steadfastness and the political will of the population” of those countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/our-farewell-to-russia-ukraine-poised-to-take-step-closer-to-eu-membership&quot;>;&#39;Our farewell to Russia&#39;: Ukraine poised to take step closer to EU membership&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The progress report focused on reforms needed in 10 countries that have asked to join the EU, including the six Balkan states and Georgia.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Commission is also recommending a €6bn “accession fund” be set up to give incentive for reforms in the countries in the waiting room, with payments twice a year. If they stall on reforms, they will not benefit from the funds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recommendation to open negotiations with Ukraine and Moldova was “unconditional”, but both countries have been asked to complete reforms already under way before talks begin in earnest. The commission believes they can do this by March.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ukraine, for example, is being asked to complete implementation on anti-corruption by enacting some laws already laid and making changes to the asset declaration systems now in place for public servants.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It also wants the body overseeing the asset declaration list to be given additional powers to revisit the list if new evidence emerges of a conflict of interest among politicians.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moldova has been described as the “frontrunner” in terms of the speed of reforms required for full alignment with the EU, with officials describing its “great progress” so far.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is being asked to complete reforms in three areas, including the staffing of anti-corruption offices and regulations in relation to cash payments in the public system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I&#39;m very confident that Moldova will move on because [its] track record is impressive under very difficult circumstances,” said von der Leyen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Asked why there were conditions set on negotiations opening with Bosnia, von der Leyen denied Brussels was in effect resisting accession. “We open the door very wide. We invite Bosnia and Herzegovina to go through the door,” she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 01:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[More than half of black people surveyed in Germany report racism]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/08/more-than-half-of-black-people-surveyed-in-germany-report-racism]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T16:37:33Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/111030157063a8d83efb3e8b26e40f5a7c9d0ad6/0_389_6720_4032/master/6720.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=45bd23914f7557f8a0cbd4ea2e7ee248&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;A Black Lives Matter vigil at Alexanderplatz square&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;More than half of Black people living in Germany have experienced racism, with nearly 20% saying they have been subject to repeated threats or harassment, a first-time survey of more than 21,000 people across the country has revealed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The findings, published this week by the German Centre for Integration and Migration Research (DeZIM), also suggested that about 13% of Muslims and 12% of Asians experienced threats or harassment at least several times a year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This most often affects populations groups that are racially marked and whose affiliation to Germany is repeatedly the subject of public debate: Black, Asian and Muslim people,” Naika Foroutan, the centre&#39;s director, said in a statement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incidents spanned the public sphere, taking place anywhere from public transport to sports clubs and banks, said Cihan Sinanoglu, who heads the office that carried out the survey, known as the National Discrimination and Racism Monitor.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sinanoglu said the findings challenged a deep-rooted “self-perception” in German society that “racism was something that ended in 1945” or “something on the extremes, used as a synonym for rightwing extremism, or something that happens in the US, UK or France but not in Germany”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These arguments are thought have been supported by the historical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/jun/16/france-and-germany-urged-to-rethink-reluctance-to-gather-ethnicity-data&quot;>;reluctance of Germany&lt;/a>; to collect demographic data on ethnicity. In 2020, after the killing of nine people in an apparently&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/feb/19/shooting-germany-hanau-dead-several-people-shisha-near-frankfurt&quot;>; racially motivated&lt;/a>; shooting attack in the German town of Hanau and amid the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/george-floyd-murder-change-across-world-blm&quot;>;global debate&lt;/a>; on systemic racial discrimination set off by the killing of George Floyd in the US, the German government suggested a national monitor to track discrimination and racism as part of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euractiv.com/section/non-discrimination/news/german-cabinet-committee-agrees-to-e1-billion-package-to-combat-racism/&quot;>;dozens of recommendations&lt;/a>; to combat racism.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even for those who were aware that racism exists in Germany, the survey&#39;s findings were surprising, said Sinanoglu. “It&#39;s not just the numbers, it&#39;s the reality that Black communities are facing. It&#39;s shocking.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall it found 54% of Black people in Germany had experienced racism at least once.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sinanoglu pointed to the finding that 41% of Black men and 39% of Muslim men reported being discriminated against by police. “These are major institutions that are built to protect people.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The findings echo a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/25/pervasive-and-relentless-racism-on-the-rise-in-europe-survey-finds&quot;>;recently published EU survey &lt;/a>;that found racism to be “pervasive and relentless” and on the rise across Europe, with nearly half of Black people in member states surveyed reporting incidents that ranged from the verbal abuse of their children to being blocked by landlords from renting homes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Germany, the plan is to carry out the survey annually, each time including questions on different sectors such as housing and labour.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time around, the survey homed in on the respondents&#39; experience of the healthcare system. More than a third of Black and Muslim women, as well as 29% of Asian women surveyed, said they had been treated unfairly on occasion or had felt their health concerns had not been taken seriously.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For white women, the figure was 26%. “Which tells us that there is a dynamic of racism and sexism,” said Sinanoglu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interviews delved into the details of the discrimination in play. Black women said they were treated as though they were hypersexualised, with healthcare providers regularly offering them HIV/STI testing, while Muslim women said they were likely to be provided sexuality-related health services, said Sinanoglu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result was at times a sort of healthcare avoidance, with about 13% of Black, Asian and Muslim women saying that concerns about discrimination had led them to delay or avoid treatment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consequences risk being far-reaching, as they pile on top of the health impacts caused by racism, said Sinanoglu. “Our data shows that experiences of discrimination and racism are also very clearly linked to anxiety disorders or depressive symptoms.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s a glimpse of how racism and discrimination often snowball, accruing power as a series of small aggressions add up, he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“All these small, subtle details have a big impact,” he said. “It&#39;s a cumulative thing, racism isn&#39;t one big thing happening all the time. It&#39;s these small details.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Half of Australia left without internet or phone as Optus crashes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/nov/08/half-of-australia-left-without-internet-or-phone-as-optus-crashes]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T15:23:46Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2eecae75458e6e031c2c311b710f6396325cd96b/0_300_5000_3000/master/5000.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=e52d76d90f58d3a371d4c4461bbe81b3&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Optus is Australia&#39;s second largest telecoms provider.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nearly half the Australian population were left without internet or phone service on Wednesday, when the country&#39;s second largest telecommunications provider crashed and cut off 10 million people from Sydney to Perth and all points in between.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those affected woke up on Wednesday morning to find they could not log on or make a call, train systems fell down, and businesses could not complete sales because their tap and pay machines were offline.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were left in limbo for hours as Optus, their provider, struggled to find out what had gone wrong.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company suggested that customers should think about “finding a family member or neighbour with an alternative device”, not always easy to do in a country where many people live in remote areas where the next house can be a long drive away.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The increasing frustration and anger of customers showed as people began to queue outside the shops of rival providers in the hope of buying a new sim card, or lingered outside libraries in the hope of catching some free wifi.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Optus&#39;s chief executive, Kelly Bayer Rosmarin, eventually called into a Sydney radio station by WhatsApp – presumably using non-Optus wifi – to apologise for the outage and reassure people everything was being done to restore services. The outage lasted until the evening.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the failure leading to widespread disruption of health, transport and other key government services, the federal communications minister, Michelle Rowland, was moved to intervene and, with some understatement, said that customers were experiencing “a high level of anxiety and frustration”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All Melbourne metropolitan train services were stopped from about 4.30am because of a communications fault across the train network, reportedly due to the outage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Metro Trains services started to resume just before 6am but major delays continued throughout the morning peak as services were restored.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Call centres running state government services in New South Wales, which include health, leisure and road and driving services, were affected, along with Victoria&#39;s virtual emergency department. In the Northern Territory, hospital phone lines were cut off by the outage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The South Australian premier, Peter Malinauskas, said his government would reconsider its contracts with Optus, and the National Retail Association director Rob Godwin said the outage was costing his members “thousands of dollars” in lost sales.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Optus urged customers – especially small businesses – to keep receipts if they wanted to seek compensation, but consumer advocates were not sure whether people would be able to claim much back.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind some of the customer anxiety was the feeling that the outage was a repeat of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2022/oct/01/optus-data-hack-australians-scramble-to-change-passports-and-driver-licences-after-telco-data-debacle&quot;>;damaging hack&lt;/a>; Optus suffered last year, which resulted in the exposure of the personal information of 10 million customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Minds turned to a possible repeat cyber-attack, although Bayer Rosmarin said it was “highly unlikely” the outage was caused by a hack, and that an outage of this sort was a “very, very rare occurrence”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Services began to be restored by Wednesday afternoon and the network was fully up and running again by 6pm, but the exact cause of the outage was still not fully established.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One expert suggested it could have been caused by the same issue that brought down Facebook two years ago. Cloudflare, which tracks a range of activity on the internet, noticed a spike in border gateway protocol (BGP) announcements from Optus coinciding with the time the network went offline.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;BGP effectively acts as a roadmap for the internet, and the announcements tell the rest of the internet the easiest way to a particular location.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matt Tett, the managing director of the network analysis company Enex TestLab, said that while he was not certain of the cause, Optus appeared to have had some failure in routing at 4am that caused an exponential increase in BGP announcements.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why it brought down not just internet but also landline and mobile services, Tett said, was because networks were now IP-based and when the internet protocol network had an issue, “absolutely, it will take down all their systems”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facebook, WhatsApp and Instagram went &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/04/facebook-instagram-and-whatsapp-hit-by-outage&quot;>;offline for five hours in 2021&lt;/a>; due to an issue with BGP.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 23:52:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>