<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[King Charles asked for ‘unequivocal apology’ by Kenya’s rights commission]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/oct/31/king-charles-asked-for-unequivocal-apology-by-kenya-human-rights-commission]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T12:00:03Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a29d490716b3861907f2e4c1f062f1f76971b31b/0_0_4500_3000 /master/4500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=85c3f8576683e281dce3afcef759658a&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;在查尔斯国王访问肯尼亚之前的示威活动中，一名前自由战士举着横幅。&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khrc.or.ke/&quot;>;肯尼亚人权委员会&lt;/a>;呼吁查尔斯国王为殖民时期的虐待行为提供“明确的公开道歉”本周访问该国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们呼吁国王代表英国政府发表无条件和明确的公开道歉（而不是非常谨慎、自我保护和保护性的声明）肯尼亚人权委员会表示：“我们对肯尼亚公民遭受的残酷和不人道待遇表示遗憾。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 1952 年至 1960 年间的“紧急状态”期间，即肯尼亚争取独立斗争最激烈的时期，英国士兵强迫大约 1.5数百万肯尼亚人被怀疑参与了毛毛反殖民起义，被关进集中营，在那里他们遭受酷刑、强奸和非人化待遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预计国王将“承认更多&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/oct/11/king-charles-to-acknowledge-painful-past-on-state-visit-to-kenya&quot;>;痛苦的方面10 月 31 日至 11 月 3 日，他在对这个东非国家进行为期四天的访问期间，回顾了英国和肯尼亚的共同历史&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Royal.uk/Kenya-announcement&quot;>;本月白金汉宫发表声明&lt;/a>;表示，国王将“在访问期间花时间加深对肯尼亚人民[在紧急情况下]所遭受的错误的理解”。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;人权委员会表示，“没有迹象表明”国王打算对肯尼亚的殖民暴行进行“全面且无条件的道歉”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对被拘留者的虐待被描述为“令人痛苦地&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/jun/06/mau-mau-sinning-quietly&quot;>;让人想起纳粹德国或共产主义俄罗斯的情况&lt;/a>;”，英国殖民地司法部长埃里克·格里菲斯·琼斯 (Eric Griffith-Jones) 1957 年致英国总督的信。格里菲斯·琼斯后来起草了允许殴打的立法，但条件是保密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国达成了一项协议： &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/uk-compensate-kenya-mau-mau-torture&quot;>;2013 年与 5,228 名肯尼亚人达成了 2000 万英镑的庭外和解&lt; /a>; 参与针对紧急情况下侵权行为的集体诉讼。英国政府经过 11 年的竞选活动后，支付了这笔款项，并发表了“遗憾声明”。 the-mau-mau-claims/#:~:text=The%20Kenyan%20claimants,Kenya%20during%20the%20Kenya%20Emergency.&quot;>;针对英国的法律诉讼&lt;/a>;，最初由五名肯尼亚老人提起。&lt; /p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/oct/29/king-charles-britain-already-admitted -torture-in-kenya-no-need-for-you-to-choke-on-an-apology&quot;>;查尔斯国王，英国已经承认在肯尼亚使用酷刑，你没必要因为道歉而哽咽 |卡罗琳·埃尔金斯&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;该案件除其他事项外还表明，英国人&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk/2012/apr/ 18/britain-destroyed-records-colonial-crimes&quot;>;销毁或隐藏&lt;/a>;殖民当局的官方记录&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2016/aug/18/历史学家表示，揭露真相-英国-帝国-卡罗琳-埃尔金斯-莫-莫&quot;>;残酷的镇压&lt;/a>;，而在发现过程中发现的文件，使英国政府处于“尴尬[和]可耻”的境地。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;过去十年中有关殖民暴行程度的调查结果已曝光，并且 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/sep/11/david -olusoga-on-the-queen-the-commonwealth-and-the-monarchys-future&quot;>;类似的计算&lt;/a>;席卷了英联邦，要求承认和赔偿这些历史错误的呼声越来越高。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;查尔斯在作为国王首次访问英联邦成员国期间的做法将表明他计划如何应对类似的要求承认殖民暴行并道歉的呼声。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 20:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Calls in Spain to stop selling ‘sexy nurse’ Halloween costumes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/31/calls-in-spain-to-stop-selling-sexy-nurse-halloween-costumes]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T11:39:02Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0dc761fabcea5d32bfb3a6e506e766e172ff08d6/231_227_4879_2927 /master/4879.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=845ee17cf5dcfd289f8e525ad4b961c5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;化装护士帽&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;西班牙总护理委员会呼吁零售商停止销售“ ”性感护士”万圣节服装，抱怨这些服装损害了公众对这一职业的看法，并延续了女性“性感、琐碎和轻浮”的形象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该委员会代表西班牙各地 330,000 名男女护士，说服装在现代平等社会中没有地位。它还批评“僵尸”和“杀手”护士服装，称它们也没有给护士带来什么好处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当人们准备庆祝万圣节和万圣节时，总护理委员会对服装泛滥感到遗憾就该职业而言，具有冒犯性和侮辱性的含义，”它在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以非常短而性感的护士服装为例，它们与真正的制服毫无相似之处。还有浸满鲜血的服装、杀手服装和活死人服装，所有这些现在都是这种庆祝活动的典型特征，这种庆祝活动在我们国家已经根深蒂固，尤其是在儿童和年轻人中。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该委员会再次呼吁商店和在线零售商停止销售将死亡和谋杀与专业人士“矛盾地联系在一起”的服装，这些专业人士的工作是帮助治愈和照顾人们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“女性和女性男护士不喜欢忍受一年一度的‘性感护士’、‘杀手’或‘僵尸’护士服装浪潮，因为这让他们感到困惑和冒犯，”该委员会主席弗洛伦蒂诺·佩雷斯·拉亚(Florentino Pérez Raya)说。 “[这些服装]损害了这个职业的公众形象，这个职业的奉献精神不仅需要顶级的学术和大学资格，而且还被认为是医疗保健质量的堡垒。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该委员会表示，家长和在解决有害的护理形象方面，其他人可以发挥重要作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们不仅仅是批评万圣节，”其副总裁 Raquel Rodríguez Llanos 说。 “这也是派对、单身派对、私人派对和嘉年华。我们呼吁所有的母亲和父亲不要让自己的儿子和女儿穿着冒犯该职业的服装，因为这样这些做法就会变得常态化并延续到成年。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加拿大的护士发布了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oiiq.org/non-al-erotising-de-la-profession-infirmiere-cmq&quot;>;去年也有类似的请求&lt;/a>;，称这些服装“将魁北克护士协会 (OIIQ) 主席 Luc Mathieu 表示，“这个职业已经发展，但刻板印象依然存在。” “护士从事科学职业，他们的专业知识必须得到更好的了解和重视。现在是改变观念的时候了。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France is Europe’s biggest supporter of ‘carbon bomb’ projects, data shows]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/oct/31/france-carbon-bomb-projects-banks-fossil-fuels-climate]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T11:16:19Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7679c510e91cb525edaa5bb60fc8329b4049d44f/0_137_6000_3600 /master/6000.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=9b022b37ac61458c4da040a0d5a579e4&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;气候活动人士在 6 月的抗议活动中将巴黎埃菲尔铁塔改造成风力涡轮机。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据《卫报》透露，法国是欧洲“碳炸弹”开采项目的最大支持者，这些项目拥有足够的化石燃料，每个项目可抽取超过十亿吨的 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从世界2015 年，各国领导人齐聚法国首都签署《巴黎协定》——他们承诺努力阻止地球升温比工业化前水平高 1.5 摄氏度——法国银行已为计划或运营碳弹的公司提供了总计 1,540 亿美元的融资。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;碳弹是全球425个最大的化石燃料开采项目。专家表示，在它们的下面，有足够的煤炭、石油和天然气来燃烧人类的碳预算，将升温控制在 1.5 摄氏度之内四倍以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/oct/31/banks-pumped-more-than-150bn-in-to-companies-running-carbon-bomb-projects-in-2022&quot;>;银行在 2022 年向运行“碳炸弹”项目的公司注入了超过 1500 亿美元&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“化石燃料公司和银行实施了愤世嫉俗的战略，”Valerie Masson-Delmotte 表示，CEA Paris-Saclay 的气候科学家，政府间气候变化专门委员会最新报告的物理科学部分的联合主席。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管目标是到 2050 年实现碳中和，但她说，他们“现在就采取行动增加化石燃料的使用，从而增加排放——故意忽视将累积 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 排放与全球变暖水平相关的最有力的科学发现之一”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;法国非政府组织 Data for Good 和 Éclaircies 以及《卫报》和《世界报》等欧洲媒体的研究发现，法国银行投入了更多资金法国巴黎银行、BPCE 集团、法国农业信贷银行和法国兴业银行这四家法国银行共同投资了运营这些项目的公司，仅次于中国和美国。研究发现，到 2022 年，计划或运营碳弹的公司将获得 178 亿美元的投资。从2016年开始的六年时间里，获奖者范围从美国的石油和天然气公司到巴西、沙特阿拉伯和中国等国家的国有能源公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;碳弹项目的原始数据库来自&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0301421522001756?via%3Dihub&quot;>;研究论文&lt;/a>;，该论文统计了 425 个潜在生命周期排放量更大的煤矿、油田和气田超过 1 十亿吨 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国研究人员随后将其与全球能源监测 (Global Energy Monitor) 的运营商数据以及气候混乱银行 (Banking on Climate Chaos) 的金融家数据进行匹配，该报告涵盖了非政府组织的报告60 家最大的银行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于某些项目，该信息与用于识别公司和银行的数据不匹配。其他一些已经过时或运行状态不明确。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导这项研究的 Data for Good 联合总裁 Lou Welgryn 表示：“可供参考的公开且可靠的数据非常少。确定全球化石项目、其总储量、相关温室气体排放以及相关参与者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在某些情况下，这种不透明性导致我们低估与公司相关的项目数量或资金流动研究显示，法国能源公司 TotalEnergies 参与了全球至少两打碳弹项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media- id=&quot;34a9eb4fb3ce9d1aaa984ef84c884d143e14f2b5&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/34a9eb4fb3ce9d1aaa984ef84c884d143e14f2b5/0_186_5568_3341/1000.jpg&quot; alt =&quot;TotalEnergies 徽标&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption >; &lt;span>;据一份报告称，自 2015 年以来，TotalEnergies 涉嫌获取了 80 多个勘探项目的许可证。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;摄影：Christophe Archambault/AFP/Getty&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt; /figure>; &lt;p>;单独的&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.greenpeace.fr/site/uploads/2023/10/Rapport-Greenpeace-_-Bombes-Climatiques-_-Oct-23-1.pdf &quot;>;绿色和平组织上周的报告&lt;/a>;统计了 TotalEnergies 参与的 33 枚碳弹，计算方法采用了一种不太保守的方法来计算上游排放量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该报告还发现 TotalEnergies 参与了收购自 2015 年以来，为 84 个项目颁发了新的勘探许可证。其中 11 个是在 2021 年之后，当时国际能源署 (IEA) 警告称，所有新的石油和天然气勘探都不符合其净零排放情景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Edina法国绿色和平组织的化石燃料活动人士 Ifticene 表示，TotalEnergies 的定位是通过满足化石燃料的需求来为公众提供服务。 “但正是通过开发新的石油和天然气项目，化石燃料行业人为地创造了这种需求，这样他们就可以获得巨额利润，并使我们对化石燃料的依赖继续持续数十年。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位发言人TotalEnergies表示：“IEA预测从现在到2028年石油和天然气产量将增长。在此背景下，我们继续投资新的石油项目，以满足仍在增长的全球需求，特别是发展中国家的需求。”而且，考虑到我们当前油田的自然衰退（每年 4%），我们将继续保证我们的客户以负担得起的成本获得能源。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发言人还指出了 TotalEnergies 的计划到 2030 年将其可再生能源产能增加五倍，并补充说，该公司将在 2023 年在可再生能源和低碳能源上投资近 50 亿欧元——这是该公司对低碳能源的投资首次超过对新化石燃料项目的投资。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发言人补充道：“因此，TotalEnergies 正在以具体方式实现其雄心，同时继续满足全球人口不断增长的能源需求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国巴黎银行发言人表示，公司已经停止向名单上的一些公司提供贷款，并补充说其中一个基础数据库包含人为夸大其数字的错误。&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;3107f5c65602e8d2d2e47e9dc80f9e2c75fa363b&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https:// /media.guim.co.uk/3107f5c65602e8d2d2e47e9dc80f9e2c75fa363b/0_137_5268_3161/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;法国巴黎银行董事兼首席执行官 Jean-Laurent Bonnafé 在巴黎举行的集团股东大会上致辞。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;法国巴黎银行董事兼首席执行官 Jean-Laurent Bonnafé 在巴黎举行的集团股东大会上致辞。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;摄影：Éric Piermont/法新社/盖蒂&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;发言人表示，法国巴黎银行今年更新了政策，不再为新油田和气田提供融资，无论采用何种融资方式，其目的是到 2030 年，将其基于能源的融资进一步转向低碳来源的 80%。“法国巴黎银行已采取积极主动的方法，减少对高排放行业的融资。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国农业信贷银行的发言人也提出异议报告中的数字，称其中包括重复计算，并且清单中的大多数项目已经运营多年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们表示：“我们已承诺不再资助任何项目新的煤矿开采项目或开发此类项目的公司。我们还承诺不会为任何新的石油勘探生产项目提供资金。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该发言人证实，该承诺仅指项目融资，而非企业融资，但表示该公司致力于减少信贷从 2020-25 年起，上游石油敞口将减少 25%，符合 IEA 的净零情景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;BPCE 集团发言人表示，该公司支持包括大型能源公司在内的所有客户的能源转型和脱碳战略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这种伙伴关系方法至关重要，而且比突然停止向客户提供融资更有利。 BPCE 集团相信，这些参与者凭借其技术和财务能力，拥有必要的手段，通过开发可再生能源和低碳能源来加速能源转型。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国兴业银行发言人表示，该公司已九月份制定了“我们行业中一些最雄心勃勃的目标”。其中包括到 2030 年，与 2019 年水平相比，将石油和天然气生产风险减少 80%，从 2024 年起终止对 2021 年之后做出最终投资决定的新油田和气田的支持，以及停止向任何私人提供金融产品和服务。该公司几乎所有收入都来自上游石油和天然气活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大型能源公司通常有足够的资金来资助自己的勘探项目。但活动人士表示，银行仍然可以通过拒绝为其运营商提供资金来拆除碳炸弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“凭借规模，世界上最大的银行可以提供更好的利率，”可持续发展专家 Joe Thwaites 表示。自然资源保护委员会的金融活动家。 “如果主要金融家拒绝为化石燃料提供资金，这并不是说开采公司无法找到其他来源，但他们可能必须支付溢价。这相当于如果你无法去商业街银行，你就被迫去找高利贷者。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;银行经常辩称，如果他们不为化石燃料项目提供资金，就会有人否则会的，他补充道。 “这就是毒贩的辩护。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Top Trump allies facing charges lose lawyers after failing to pay legal bills]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/31/top-trump-allies-facing-charges-lose-lawyers-after-failing-to-pay-legal-bills]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T11:00:19Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/996e063201845e1b6f873859ab400593d8cc03b2/0_0_5760_3456 /master/5760.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=65142dea5cab556060b2e5c25bb8da9c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;史蒂夫·班农于 2023 年 2 月 28 日出现在纽约曼哈顿最高法院。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;三人组唐纳德·特朗普的一些高级盟友花费了巨额法律费用来为自己辩护，免受刑事指控、定罪或诽谤诉讼，但他们因未能支付六位数和七位数的账单而失去了重要律师，这表明他们面临着巨大的法律问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前特朗普顾问史蒂夫·班农 (Steve Bannon)、前特朗普律师鲁迪·朱利安尼 (Rudy Giuliani) 和 MyPillow 首席执行官迈克·林德尔 (Mike Lindell) 提出的巨额法律诉讼凸显了困扰他们的刑事和民事指控的规模。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/30/trump-14th-amendment-colorado-Trial-jan-6 ”科罗拉多州法院听取了阻止“叛乱分子”特朗普参加 2024 年投票的论据&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;欢迎来到困扰这位美国前总统的三位高级忠诚者不断升级的法律和财务问题，他们推动了各种关于他在 2020 年选举中输给乔·拜登的虚假说法，为特朗普的选举谎言提供了掩护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法律困境的清单很长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班农定于 11 月向法院提起上诉他去年被定罪，因拒绝调查 1 月 6 日叛乱的众议院小组传票而妨碍国会而被判处四个月监禁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班农明年 5 月还将在纽约面临与以下问题有关的审判：朱利安尼被指控犯有国家欺诈、共谋和洗钱罪，并在墨西哥修建隔离墙项目中向捐助者诈骗，该项目被称为“我们建造隔离墙”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，朱利安尼在 8 月被指控犯有 13 项刑事罪行佐治亚州富尔顿县地区检察官法尼·威利斯 (Fani Willis) 指控特朗普和其他 17 人参与阴谋，以阻止特朗普 2020 年在佐治亚州落败。十月份，朱利安尼面临的压力不断升级，当时以不同方式与朱利安尼共事的另外三名前特朗普律师同意认罪&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;并与检察官合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，林德尔正在与价值 20 亿美元的诽谤作斗争。他声称电子投票机公司提起的诉讼帮助操纵了 2020 年针对特朗普的诉讼，这让他损失了欠明尼阿波利斯一家律师事务所数百万美元的法律费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 月，该律师事务所正式向法院提出请求允许它在这些案件中退出代表林德尔，理由是它欠了数百万美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在另一个法律方面，班农和朱利安尼的一位顶级律师已经抛弃了他们，并对所欠款项提出了巨额索赔。罗伯特·科斯特洛和他的代表朱利安尼和班农的公司已分别向两人提出索赔，索赔金额为 140 万美元和 48 万美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法院已对班农做出了赔偿 48 万美元的判决，其中他在律师哈伦·普罗塔斯的帮助下进行战斗。目前尚不清楚朱利安尼何时以及向科斯特洛及其公司支付多少钱。但一位熟悉朱利安尼七位数债务的法律消息人士将未付账单归咎于特朗普，而不是朱利安尼，声称特朗普今年早些时候在佛罗里达州与科斯特洛和朱利安尼会面时表示，他将“处理”朱利安尼的法律账单。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;除了逾期未付的法律费用外，朱利安尼和班农现在还陷入了其他高风险的法律斗争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在佐治亚州，吉利安尼的法律处境似乎变得更加危险：律师珍娜·埃利斯 (Jenna Ellis)朱利安尼在佐治亚州和其他地方就特朗普落败提出虚假指控，肯尼思·切塞布罗和西德尼·鲍威尔以不同的方式与朱利安尼合作，他们于 10 月认罪，并同意与威利斯办公室合作。起诉书是“嘲讽”，但前检察官表示，在其他特朗普律师达成认罪协议后，他面临着新的压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“正如预期的那样，佐治亚州的多米诺骨牌已经开始倒下，三项认罪协议司法部欺诈部门前代理负责人保罗·佩尔蒂埃 (Paul Pelletier) 告诉卫报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“鲁迪也可能想辩护和合作。以减少他的暴露，但没有一个头脑清醒的检察官会利用他作为合作证人。根本没有办法消除他古怪行为所留下的根深蒂固的影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其他前检察官一致认为朱利安尼作为证人的资格受到玷污。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“鲁迪承受着巨大的压力，但是前检察官保罗·罗森茨威格 (Paul Rosenzweig) 告诉《卫报》：“他不太可能改变立场，因为这是理性的做法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仍有一些司法部资深人士表示，朱利安尼可能会尝试达成协议。&lt;/p>; &lt; “朱利安尼一定担心鲍威尔和埃利斯会出庭指控他，从而增加定罪的可能性，”密歇根州东部前美国律师芭芭拉·麦奎德 (Barbara McQuade) 告诉《卫报》。 “承认不当行为可能不是朱利安尼的基因，但如果法尼·威利斯愿意认罪，现在是时候向他寻求达成协议了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据报道，朱利安尼尚未获得认罪协议到目前为止，朱利安尼的发言人已经拒绝了接受的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在佐治亚州，朱利安尼的另一次打击是，朱利安尼在八月份因对两名佐治亚州选举工作人员发表诽谤性言论而被判负有责任，后来被勒令支付他们的法律费用此外，投票技术公司 Smartmatic 8 月份在法庭文件中对朱利安尼进行了攻击，指控他“编造一个又一个借口”，以避免在价值 27 亿美元的诽谤案中交出文件。对他、福克斯新闻和其他散布有关 2020 年选举结果谎言的人提起诉讼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管朱利安尼面临的问题越来越多，但他仍然保留了一些长期盟友。 WABC 电台的亿万富翁约翰·卡西马蒂迪斯 (John Catsimatidis) 告诉《卫报》，朱利安尼“在我们这里赚了很多钱。”朱利安尼在 WABC 电台每天都有广播节目。他每月领取工资。”卡西马提迪斯补充道：“我祈祷他被判无罪。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然班农的法律问题有所不同，但它们同样激烈，甚至更严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位好斗的特朗普盟友，以他的极右翼战争室播客去年被定罪，并因无视与调查 1 月 6 日叛乱和特朗普角色的众议院小组合作的传票妨碍国会而被判处四个月监禁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班农已对定罪提出上诉，法庭听证会定于 11 月举行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管卡尔·尼科尔斯法官准许班农对其定罪提出上诉，为可能的逆转或重新审判敞开了大门，但前检察官并不认为“我认为班农&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;的定罪可能会被推翻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我认为班农的定罪是有非常坚实的基础的，”麦克奎德告诉《卫报》。 “当国会传唤他时，他甚至没有出庭。如果他认为自己拥有作证特权的善意基础，那么主张这一特权的方法就是出席并回答所有其他问题，并在逐个问题的基础上主张特权。他甚至没有做到这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“此外，由于他在相关时间段内不是行政部门的雇员，因此他所声称的行政特权是站不住脚的，甚至是不存在的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其他前检察官对班农的上诉能否成功表示怀疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“尽管尼科尔斯法官表示班农的上诉是认真的，但事实并非如此。班农几乎没有机会推翻他的判决。罗森茨威格告诉《卫报》，他显然有罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，班农将于明年 5 月接受纽约州审判，罪名是他欺骗非营利组织“我们建墙”项目的捐助者，该项目已经导致班农的同事三人提出认罪或定罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班农的审判将在曼哈顿同一家法院进行，该法院裁定他欠科斯特洛律师事务所 48 万美元。他的律师预计是普罗塔斯，他正在对法院针对班农的收费决定提出上诉，他称这一决定“明显错误”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班农对欺骗捐赠者的指控表示无罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 就在特朗普于 2021 年初卸任之前，他赦免了班农，班农因在“我们建造隔离墙”中扮演的角色而被指控类似的联邦欺诈指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管他的法律威胁越来越大，班农仍然是一个激进的人和忙碌的特朗普盟友。 10 月，他利用自己的战争室播客接待了特朗普最右翼的 Maga 盟友，例如佛罗里达州众议员马特·盖茨 (Matt Gaetz)，他在驱逐前众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡 (Kevin McCarthy) 的过程中发挥了关键作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些前共和党人国会议员将班农视为一支破坏性的、支持特朗普的政治力量。 “班农一直给我的印象是共和党联盟虚无主义派别的领导人，”前共和党国会议员查理·登特告诉《卫报》。 “他对议长竞选的干预显然是一个问题，并提高了特朗普对众议院的兴趣。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他就像特朗普：所有的不满，一直。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; &lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US labor movement faces big obstacles despite surge in strikes and union wins]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/31/union-labor-win-strike-obstacles]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T10:00:38Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2ee7e2fdb22ad5cc8a4ebe984287cd1f90357bd6/0_192_4928_2956 /master/4928.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=0290f6de13b691c95cf19b53459a2a21&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;FILES-US-AUTOMOBILE-STRIKE-FORD(FILES) 美国汽车工人联合会 (UAW) 纠察队成员9 月 26 日，密歇根州韦恩市的密歇根零部件装配厂。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美国劳工运动最近取得了一些重大的工会合同，罢工激增，历史性的工会选举在激进的反工会中获胜。公司和总统政府&lt;a href=&quot;https://aflcio.org/statements/icymi-president-biden-im-most-pro-union-president-american-history-and-i-make-no&quot; >;标榜自己是“历史上最支持工会”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上周，美国汽车工人联合会与福特达成了一项历史性的临时协议，其中包括 25% 的工资增长，随后不久又达成了协议与 Stellantis 和通用汽车公司达成协议。 UAW 已&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/UAW/status/1718800736174080378&quot;>;呼吁&lt;/a>;其他工会将其合同到期时间定在 5 月 1 日，以便在下一份 UAW 合同的同时向雇主集体施压三巨头的合同将于 2028 年 5 月 1 日到期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其他工会也赢得了&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamster.org/2023/08/teamsters-ratify-historic-ups-contract /&quot;>;今年，UPS 和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/oct/07/screenwriters-won-a-historic- 等大型雇主取得了历史性的&lt;/a>;合同收益victory-against-ai-the-rest-of-us-should-follow&quot;>;电视和电影编剧的好莱坞工作室&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但美国劳工仍然面临重大障碍和挑战在几十年来工会衰落、财富不平等加剧和违反劳动法的背景下，将流行文化的转变转化为收益。雇主违反劳动法而不受惩罚，并试图推迟和破坏工会组织活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工会化工人们一直在策划近期围绕企业贪婪、利润过高和高管薪酬飙升的新合同罢工浪潮，利用劳动力市场紧张和公众日益支持美国劳工运动的转变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至 2023 年停工现象大量涌入，雇主因停工而遭受了至少 23 年来最大的劳动时间损失&lt;a href=&quot;https://poweratwork.us/why-so-many-strikes&quot;>;&lt;/a href=&quot;https://poweratwork.us/why-so-many-strikes&quot;>; a>;，根据美国劳工统计局的数据，2023 年 1 月至 9 月的劳动时间约为 1100 万小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;康奈尔大学劳工行动追踪器&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ILRLaborAction/status /1716443493294350503/photo/1&quot;>;2023 年 9 月记录了&lt;/a>; 69 起罢工，涉及 214,300 名工人。大约 11,000 名好莱坞电视和电影编剧在五个月的罢工后最近达成了一项历史性协议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“虽然业务蓬勃发展，制片厂每年获得近 300 亿美元的利润，但编剧的薪酬却下降了，” Laura Blum-Smith，WGA West 研究和公共政策总监，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/apr/17/writers-strike-hollywood-wga-vote -latest&quot;>; 四月份告诉《卫报》&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;代表超过 150,000 名演员的美国演员工会 (Screen Actors Guild) 一直在&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/ culture/2023/oct/24/actors-strike-when-will-it-end-negotiations#:~:text=美国演员工会，（迪士尼、派拉蒙、索尼，&quot;>;自 7 月起罢工&lt;/a>; 2023 年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《傲骨之战》明星克里斯汀·巴伦斯基 (Christine Baranski) 在一次演讲中说道-speech-1235544919/&quot;>;7月份的三轮车集会&lt;/a>;：“如果这个行业能够产生数百万、数亿美元的收入，作为对顶层人士的补偿，它就有能力分享财富。”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;10 月 4 日至 7 日，超过 75,000 名医护人员举行了为期三天的罢工，这是美国历史上最大规模的医疗罢工，罢工后不久就赢得了新合同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“ making millions of dollars aren&#39;t thinking about anyone else but their own profit and their own increasing wages and not thinking about the rest of us,” Jeffrey Melara, a Kaiser Permanente worker in California, t&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/oct/03/kaiser-permanente-healthcare-strike-hospital-union-california-washington-dc&quot;>;old&lt;/a>; The Guardian in the days ahead of the strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it is the strike that hit the US car industry that has created the most headlines and impact.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Big 3 automakers, Ford, General Motors and Stellantis, made $250bn in profits from 2013 to 2022, an increase in 92% while average auto worker wages&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/blog/uaw-automakers-negotiations/&quot;>; dropped&lt;/a>; 19.3% during the same period. Their three CEOS have&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-10-13/detroit-carmakers-paid-1-billion-to-ceos-as-auto-wages-slumped&quot;>; received&lt;/a>; around $1bn in compensation since 2010.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Andy Davis, an assembler at Allison Transmission in Indianapolis, Indiana, and UAW Local 933 second vice-president, said the recent strikes and broad fight by autoworkers is a push to restore the upward mobility and security that has dissipated as a worker in a highly profitable industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“America sees our UAW jobs as icons of success and stability for the average and ordinary,” said Davis. “That&#39;s exactly what we&#39;re trying to get back to.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Labor Relations Board, union petitions&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/unions-and-well-being/&quot;>; increased&lt;/a>; 3% in fiscal year 2023 compared to 2022, with 2022 seeing a 53% increase in union election petitions from the previous year. During the same period, the NLRB&#39;s field offices saw a 10% increase in unfair labor practice charges, from a 19% increase in 2022.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The NLRB has&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nlrb.gov/news-outreach/news-story/unfair-labor-practices-charge-filings-up-10-union-petitions-up-3-in-fiscal&quot;>; noted&lt;/a>; the agency remains severely understaffed and underfunded amid rises in caseloads, with field office staff being cut by 50% in the past two decades.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, labor law reform efforts to improve worker protections to organize unions such as the PRO Act have stalled in Congress, with little to no support from the Republican party despite public support for unions bridging across partisan lines.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;US union membership declined to&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/union2.nr0.htm&quot;>; 10.1%&lt;/a>; in 2022 from 10.3% in 2021, the lowest on record according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics. Although the number of workers belonging to unions increased by 273,000 workers to 14.3 million in 2022, the total number of workers in the US workforce grew by 5.3 million, resulting in the drop in union density.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While national headlines suggest there is a wave of union wins across the US, wide variations persist in unionization rates based on workforces and geography.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some 33% of public sector workers are union members, compared to 6% of private sector workers. Hawaii has the highest union density in the US, with&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/union2.t05.htm&quot;>; 21.9%&lt;/a>; of the workforce affiliated as members of unions, compared to the lowest union density in South Carolina at 1.7%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These wide variations in union density by state have significant economic impacts. A December 2021&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/unions-and-well-being/&quot;>; report&lt;/a>; by the Economic Policy Institute found on average the 17 states with the highest union densities have higher state minimum wages, higher median annual incomes, higher unemployment insurance recipiency rates, lower uninsured populations, and are more likely to have state laws such as paid sick leave and paid family and medical leave.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Union membership in the US soared in the 1930s among industrial unrest and the Great Depression, spurring union density rates of&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/unions-help-reduce-disparities-and-strengthen-our-democracy/&quot;>; over 30%&lt;/a>; in the wake of second world war, but gradually began decreasing in the 1960s only to sharply decline in the 1980s and the following decades.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The labor movement&#39;s rise in the US incited well-funded anti-union efforts, propped up by a multi-million dollar anti-union consultant industry and corporations that are currently fighting union campaigns despite numerous violations and rulings against them at the National Labor Relations Board. They include Amazon, Starbucks, REI, Trader Joe&#39;s, Apple and Chipotle – massive employers who have vigorously fought off union drives and efforts for workers to secure a first union contract.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Management and employers have captured the labor law terrain and this has been true for quite a while, so that they are extremely effective at blocking unionization efforts and diminishing the power of already organized workers,” said Ruth Milkman, chair of the Labor Studies Department at CUNY School of Labor and Urban Studies. “Until there&#39;s some kind of overhauling of US labor law, it&#39;s hard to see how that long-term decline is going to get turned around. Because what we&#39;re seeing in the new organizing is blockages at every turn.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Milkman explained that previous upswings in unionization in the US have historically come in large waves, but that the increases in strikes, union organizing among young workers especially, and increases in public support for the labor movement have yet to occur on a big enough scale to reverse the long trend of union density decline in the US.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the desire among workers for unionization is there as numerous polls have&lt;a href=&quot;https://aflcio.org/press/releases/afl-cios-shuler-state-unions-strong-record-public-support-unprecedented-activism-and&quot;>; reported&lt;/a>; record favorability, especially among young people, for labor unions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/working-people-want-a-voice/&quot;>;Polling&lt;/a>; has shown that an increasing number of workers would join a union if they could – far higher rates of favorability than the low proportions of workers in the US who are currently unionized.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The new organizing is happening, the attitudes, pro-union views, led by a new generation that was often dismissed as apolitical,” added Milkman. “This whole political generation that has only come to being in the last decade or so, they&#39;re very eager to do this and they are running up against a brick wall in a lot of cases, but I don&#39;t think they&#39;re going to stop.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ken Jacobs, chair of the University of California Berkeley Center for Labor Research, cited some of the positive rulings to come out of the NLRB under the Biden administration aimed at improving workers&#39; protections to organize under the National Labor Relations Act amid not only at increases in union election petitions, but&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.bloomberglaw.com/bloomberg-law-analysis/analysis-unions-on-a-roll-are-reeling-in-the-workers&quot;>; win rates&lt;/a>; for unions as well.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The win rate has to be turned into gaining collective bargaining agreements” said Jacobs. “There won&#39;t be a change in labor law unless large numbers of workers are in motion demanding unions, and that won&#39;t happen without a large investment in organizing.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2018/apr/28/resistance-now-arizona-colorado-teachers-strikes&quot;>; Red for Ed&lt;/a>; teachers&#39; strike wave in 2018 and 2019 to the uptick in worker organizing both in and out of unionization efforts through the Covid-19 pandemic, Jacobs noted workers being able to raise public awareness and see a ground swelling of support have helped inspire this cultural shift to viewing unions favorably.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I think we have seen a big cultural shift around unions,” concluded Jacobs. “I don&#39;t think we have in any time in history seen examples that have an important effect on the balance of power between workers and capital happen without very significant pressure from below with massive engagement of workers.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 18:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Police open fire after alleged threats by woman on Paris train]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/31/police-open-fire-after-alleged-threats-by-woman-on-paris-train]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T10:16:08Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/46f5419aa0ea370da67ff493148653b0ef56db74/0_290_6048_3630/master/6048.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=728720f2490589a84fe06c8d5a625456&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Two police on patrol in front of a high school in Paris&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Paris police have opened fire on a woman who allegedly made threatening remarks on a train, the latest security incident in a country that has been on heightened anti-terror alert since &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/france-school-stabbing-arras-878f42a5df4a873ca7bd80a173cc9097&quot;>;a fatal stabbing at a school&lt;/a>; earlier this month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking after the incident, police said they had no immediate information on the woman&#39;s condition. Officers opened fire after she failed to respond to their warnings, they added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police action came after a train passenger phoned the emergency services on Tuesday morning and reported that a woman, who was wearing a face covering, was making threats. It was unclear what threats she was making.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Metro and suburban train station that serves the François-Mitterrand national library in eastern Paris was evacuated, police said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;More details soon …&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 18:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Suspected gunman takes hostages in Japan post office]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/31/suspected-gunman-takes-hostages-japan-post-office]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T09:12:32Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/dbc997819f9027e00be5b1246c41fb85da3f7d1f/0_161_3952_2370/master/3952.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=e476a6b61a19c0cd2590d560e595c23b&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Aerial photo shows police outside the post office in Warabi, north of Tokyo.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A suspected gunman has taken an unknown number of people hostage in a post office in Japan after an apparent shooting in a nearby hospital.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The city&#39;s authorities said: “At approximately 2.15pm today (0515 GMT), a person has taken hostages and holed up at a post office in Chuo 5-chome area of Warabi city ... The perpetrator is possessing what appears to be a gun.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Citizens near the scene are urged to follow police instructions and evacuate in accordance with police instructions.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yomiuri daily newspaper reported on Tuesday that about 10 post office staff may be in the building.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It said there was speculation the man may be carrying paraffin, without citing sources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Police urged 300 people in the nearby area to evacuate, broadcaster TBS said. A number of police cars were surrounding the post office.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident came as officers investigated a suspected shooting in the nearby town of Toda, on the outskirts of Tokyo, earlier in the day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two people were slightly wounded but it was unclear how they were hurt. It was also unclear if the two incidents were related.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Images on television showed the man in the post office, wearing a baseball cap and a white shirt under a dark coat, with what looked like a gun attached to a cord around his neck.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Violent crime is rare in Japan, in part because of strict regulations on gun ownership. The country has one of the lowest murder rates in the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in recent years violent crime, including gun attacks, has been making headlines, most notably the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jul/08/shinzo-abe-japans-former-prime-minister-dies-after-being-shot&quot;>;assassination of the former prime minister Shinzo Abe&lt;/a>; in July last year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Abe&#39;s accused assassin, Tetsuya Yamagami, reportedly targeted the politician over his links to the Unification church.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April, a man was arrested for allegedly hurling an explosive towards the prime minister, Fumio Kishida, as he campaigned in the city of Wakayama. Kishida was unharmed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following month a man holed up in a building after allegedly killing four people, including two police officers and an elderly woman, in a gun and knife attack.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Masanori Aoki, 31, was taken into custody at his house outside a farm near the city of Nakano, in the Nagano region, police said at the time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two women and two police officers were killed in the attack.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 17:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[BP profits lower than expected amid gas trading slump]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/oct/31/bp-profits-gas-bernard-looney]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T07:23:52Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/e5a831c9cb3218b6527c08101543aee9ed3655ff/0_440_5935_3560/master/5935.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=2a5320efbd9889345c4dd47f9d71a332&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;BP logo at a petrol and diesel filling station in north London&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;BP has reported weaker than expected profits of $3.3bn (£2.7bn) for the third quarter of this year after a slump in its gas trading business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/business/bp&quot;>;company&lt;/a>; said its profits halved in the three months to September compared with bumper profits of $8.2bn in the equivalent months last year when oil and gas prices soared after Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result was also well below analysts&#39; expectations of $4.01bn for the quarter.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/oct/30/world-bank-warns-oil-price-could-soar-to-record-150-a-barrel&quot;>;World Bank warns oil price could soar to record $150 a barrel&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The lower than expected profits mark BP&#39;s first set of financial results since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/12/bp-boss-bernard-looney-to-resign-after-failing-to-reveal-ties-with-colleagues&quot;>;the shock exit of its chief executive&lt;/a>; last month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bernard Looney stepped down after three years at the helm after failing to disclose full details of relationships with colleagues. He was also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/sep/14/bp-must-not-backtrack-climate-action-after-ceo-exit-campaigners-bernard-looney&quot;>;under pressure&lt;/a>; from shareholders over his plan to cut oil production by the end of the decade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The BP&#39;s chair, Helge Lund, started the hunt for a new boss, which could lead to the company&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/14/new-bp-boss-to-replace-bernard-looney-could-be-external-hire-says-chairman&quot;>;first external chief executive hire for decades&lt;/a>;. The role is now being filled by the BP chief financial officer, Murray Auchincloss, on an interim basis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Auchincloss said it had been a “solid quarter” for the company because of its “strong underlying operational performance”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He added: “As we laid out at our investor update in Denver, we remain committed to executing our strategy, expect to grow earnings through this decade, and on track to deliver strong returns for our shareholders.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia-Ukraine war live: Biden officials to make case for Ukraine funding; Russia bulks up forces around Bakhmut, says Kyiv]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2023/oct/31/russia-ukraine-war-live-biden-officials-to-make-case-for-ukraine-funding-russia-bulks-up-forces-around-bakhmut-says-kyiv]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T07:38:36Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/3cdf2356a722549767574b5048c4576be107ce92/0_0_8055_5370/master/8055.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=773fd5a233338161423dedd7eed2d385&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;A local resident is seen on a bicycle on 30 October 2023 in Avdiivka, Ukraine. An operation to evacuate the remaining local residents from the city is apparently underway. Approximately 1,400 people remain, according to the national police.&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Eurozone economy: French growth slows to 0.1% – business live]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2023/oct/31/eurozone-economy-french-growth-slows-italy-portugal-inflation-bp-profits-business-live]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T07:09:40Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7bcc06d3bd413555127fde914a0cf968abf02768/0_249_5438_3263/master/5438.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=c109a67aa0541d4352d68426a43f3b0b&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;The centre of Paris, France, where growth has slowed from 0.6% to just 0.1%&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader defends elections after largest pro-democracy party shut out]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/31/hong-kong-leader-defends-elections-after-largest-pro-democracy-party-shut-out]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31T06:58:49Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c69cf82ad451a1b23988ad146d884c9aef7ee045/0_0_3712_2474/master/3712.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=e505d720ccd0411b1bba54f3cf57335d&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee speaks at a reception following a flag raising ceremony at the Golden Bauhinia Square in Hong Kong on 1 October, 2023.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s leader has defended the rules for upcoming local elections as open and fair, even though an electoral overhaul means the city&#39;s remaining pro-democracy activists won&#39;t be part of the race.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The city&#39;s largest pro-democracy party, the Democratic party, will be absent in December&#39;s district council election for the first time since its establishment in 1994.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Party chair Lo Kin-hei said he and other members could not secure enough nominations under the new rules authorities introduced, which are designed to ensure that “patriots administer Hong Kong.” Other smaller groups from the camp had the same problem.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/aug/14/hong-kong-pro-democracy-advocates-have-part-of-convictions-quashed-jimmy-lai-martin-lee-margaret-ng-&quot;>;Hong Kong pro-democracy advocates have part of convictions quashed&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;To enter the race, candidates have to secure endorsements from at least nine members of local committees that are packed with pro-government figures. Some pro-government politicians, including lawmaker Michael Tien, also said it was challenging for their groups to secure nominations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jul/29/us-bars-hong-kong-leader-john-lee-from-san-francisco-apec-summit&quot;>;Chief Executive John Lee&lt;/a>; said at a weekly news briefing on Tuesday that candidates have to respect the decisions of the people from which they sought nomination.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is up to you to ensure that you can convince the person you want to convince,” he said.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;5391f8212c2a20a9254881ba7bee189b186a10b3&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/5391f8212c2a20a9254881ba7bee189b186a10b3/0_0_4815_3210/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This photo taken on 26 October 2023 shows candidate Kwok Wai-shing putting up a banner of himself before canvassing for votes to compete for a seat in the Sham Shui Po East constituency in the coming district council poll in Hong Kong.&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;This photo taken on 26 October 2023 shows candidate Kwok Wai-shing putting up a banner of himself before canvassing for votes to compete for a seat in the Sham Shui Po East constituency in the coming district council poll in Hong Kong.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Peter Parks/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;The district councils were the last major political representative bodies chosen by the public. Under the electoral overhaul, most directly elected seats in the municipal-level organisation have been eliminated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of participation from pro-democracy parties reflects the dwindling space for the movement in the city, after a government crackdown on dissidents following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/oct/04/hong-kong-leader-threatens-harsher-crackdown-under-emergency-law&quot;>;anti-government protests in 2019&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Elections for the district council seats typically draw little international attention as the councillors mainly handled municipal matters, such as organising construction projects and ensuring that public facilities are in order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the councils took on importance after the city&#39;s pro-democracy camp won a landslide victory in the last poll at the height of the 2019 protests&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:22:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>