<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[Women urged to come forward with Russell Brand concerns as charity cuts ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/sep/17/amnesty-international-urges-women-to-come-forward-with-russell-brand-concerns]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T13:12:52Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c9c9a70767922f9c2e43583517b8ab0563c747e8/0_307_4500_2700 /master/4500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=9057299b1ae26832a387e5d225d96ca4&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;2006 年的拉塞尔·布兰德。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国际特赦组织敦促女性挺身而出，如果她们有任何疑问在公布强奸、性侵犯和精神虐待指控后，人们对拉塞尔·布兰德 (Russell Brand) 在 2006 年和 2012 年参加该慈善机构的两次单口喜剧活动期间的行为表示担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;支持弱势女性从毒瘾中康复的慈善机构表示，它将切断与布兰德的联系。特雷维妇女和儿童慈善机构表示，它已经终止了与布兰德及其慈善基金“保持自由基金会”的合作关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周六，《星期日泰晤士报》发表指控称布兰德&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /www.thetimes.co.uk/article/russell-brand-rape- Sex-assault-abuse-allegations-investigation-v5hxdlmb6&quot;>;在对有关布兰德行为的指控进行了长达数年的调查后，对四名女性进行了性侵犯&lt;/a>;与 Channel 4 的 Dispatches 合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些指控发生在 2006 年至 2013 年之间，当时布兰德的名气最盛，当时这位喜剧演员为 BBC 广播 2 台和第 4 频道工作，并主演好莱坞电影。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;这位 48 岁的人最近将自己重塑为健康大师，正在进行全国单口喜剧巡演。未来几天，他将在温莎、伍尔弗汉普顿和普利茅斯演出，网上呼吁这些场馆取消演出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家制作公司据称在布兰德为他们工作期间收到了针对布兰德的投诉，已还对布兰德在主持节目时的严重不当行为指控发起了“紧急”内部调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名研究人员声称，有报道称，布兰德在 2004 年和 2005 年参与《老大哥》衍生节目时的行为令人担忧”配合广播合作伙伴和外部机构索取信息的任何请求”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们还鼓励任何认为自己在制作这些作品时受到布兰德行为影响的人与我们私下联系，”它补充道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际特赦组织在一份声明中表示，它发现这些指控“令人震惊和痛苦”，并且与这位喜剧演员没有任何关系。布兰德于 2012 年和 2006 年参加了该慈善机构的秘密警察舞会活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该慈善机构表示，虽然在活动发生时“没有人对他的行为提出投诉或担忧”，但“非常了解女性在提出性侵犯投诉时面临的障碍，并鼓励任何女性让我们知道她们当时经历的任何令人担忧的事情”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Trevi，这是总部位于英格兰西南部的公司表示，对这一消息“深感悲痛和不安”，并终止了与布兰德及其慈善机构的合作。品牌的“保持自由”基金会资助慈善机构，“通过从成瘾、心理健康问题中恢复过来，以及帮助他们的非营利组织”来支持人们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宣布决定切断与 Instagram 帐户的联系，特雷维说：“拉塞尔在听说我们多年来帮助一些令人难以置信的母亲戒毒后，于 2022 年认识了我们的慈善机构。他希望支持我们的事业并通过他的“保持自由”基金会筹集资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今天的媒体披露很难处理，但我们的首要任务仍然是现在和将来所有妇女和女孩的安全和福祉。将来。我们已经结束了与拉塞尔·布兰德和保持自由基金会的合作关系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它补充道：“作为一个慈善机构，其价值观将女性的声音置于我们工作的核心，我们始终优先支持受暴力影响的女性周六公布的指控包括，布兰德在一名女学生 16 岁、他 31 岁时与一名女学生发生了关系。据报道，她说他在一段涉嫌情感虐待和控制的三个月关系中，她称她为“孩子”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《星期日泰晤士报》报道，另一名妇女声称 2012 年布兰德在洛杉矶的家中强奸了她，声明称，她当天在强奸危机中心接受了治疗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在声明发表之前，布兰德在网上发布的视频声明中声称，他面临着“一连串极其恶劣和侵略性的攻击” ”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他继续说道：“这些指控与我在主流工作时、当我一直在报纸上、当我在电影中时有关，正如我所写的那样在我的书里，我非常非常性交。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在，在性交的那段时间里，我的关系绝对是两厢情愿的。那时我总是对此保持透明，几乎太透明了，现在我也对此保持透明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“看到透明度转移到犯罪行为上，我绝对否认，这让我怀疑是否存在这种情况另一个议程正在发挥作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;已联系品牌征求意见。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 22:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Libya floods: warlord using disaster response to exert control, say observers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/17/ibya-floods-derna-warlord-khalifa-haftar-libyan-national-army]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T14:19:47Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/040eb8c728040bbbb8910058848b1459c98de60b/0_11_3543_2126 /master/3543.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=00a80bd78cef3ecb10b72d253b743d6a&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;2023 年 9 月 17 日，搜救行动小组在利比亚德尔纳继续开展工作。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在利比亚沿海城市德尔纳，当搜救队继续寻找被困在房屋泥浆和瓦砾下的尸体时，观察人士称，军阀哈利法·哈夫塔尔和他的儿子们正在使用&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian .com/world/2023/sep/16/Second-Humanarian-crisis-feared-in-wake-of-libya-floods-as-hopes-of-finding-survivors-fade&quot;>;灾难响应&lt;/a>;一种施加控制的方式，而不是确保重要的人道主义救济到达平民手中。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/global- development/2023/sep/16/libyan-reporters-floods-journalists-storm&quot;>;“城镇被夷为平地”：利比亚记者讲述洪水造成的“可怕、痛苦”&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt; p>;据利比亚红新月会称，上周的一场强风暴导致两座水坝决堤，造成至少 11,300 人死亡、10,000 多人失踪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此引发的洪水完全摧毁了德尔纳的近 900 座建筑物据位于西北部城市的黎波里的该国民族团结政府称。报告补充说，超过 200 座建筑物部分受损，近 400 座建筑物完全淹没在泥浆中，这意味着德尔纳四分之一的建筑物受到洪水影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;绝望的救援工作仍在继续，试图找到任何剩余的幸存者&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/14/libya-floods-appeals-for-body-bags-disease-fears-northeastern-flooding&quot;>;尸体继续被冲上海岸线&lt;/a>;。现场的急救人员经常在利比亚国民军武装分子的包围下工作，利比亚国民军是一个忠于哈夫塔尔的庞大军事联盟，观察人士称，他们正在努力严格控制抵达这座遭受危机的城市的重要援助。&lt;/p >; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;5d307f5b86ca61f66cab3e07d8aa450abf2f8ca3&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/5d307f5b86ca61f66cab3e07d8aa450abf2f8ca3/0_0_4376_2626/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;德尔纳废墟的鸟瞰图，利比亚，2023 年 9 月 17 日。” width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;2023 年 9 月 17 日利比亚德尔纳遭受破坏的鸟瞰图。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：Halil Fidan/Anadolu Agency/Getty Images&lt; /span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;受洪水影响最严重的德尔纳市中心的公共通道已被关闭，该城市已被正式宣布为灾区。德尔纳的公民在没有电力、安全饮用水或食物的情况下艰难生存。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com /world/2023/sep/15/libya-floods-derna-relatives-mourn&quot;>;“洪水在我眼前带走了我的儿子”：痛苦的利比亚人哀悼失去的亲人&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/上周晚些时候，位于东部的利比亚议会主席奥萨马·哈马德表示，当局正在考虑封锁整个城市，因为担心水传播疾病的传播，该城市曾经居住着 10 万人。&lt;/大西洋理事会利比亚问题分析师埃马德丁·巴迪表示：“从本质上讲，军事存在正在制造瓶颈，而不是有利于提供救援。” “救援工作的主要推动力不是由军方领导层推动的，军方领导层在逃避责任和指责受害者的同时表现出控制欲，从而获得既得利益，而是由志愿者、医疗队、红新月会、童子军和外国搜救组织推动。自 2014 年以来，哈夫塔尔带头单方面控制利比亚东部大部分地区的军事行动，周五访问了德尔纳。他赞扬了急救人员以及 LNA 成员的行动，LNA 是一个由年老的前中央情报局人员和美国公民监督的民兵联盟，批评者指责他们在他控制下的地区运行，就像军事独裁者一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;巴迪说：“在公共关系方面，他们利用现有的宣传渠道来表现出控制力，同时成为管理危机救援的主要界面和城市的守护者。” “但是，这又在各处造成了瓶颈。哈夫塔尔的来访是这个问题的一个缩影，一切都因为公关噱头而被冻结了一个小时。”&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;d216f25ee042fed201761264bdd58381d33deb67&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim. co.uk/d216f25ee042fed201761264bdd58381d33deb67/0_23_3000_1800/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;哈利法·哈夫塔尔（右）在班加西会见埃及武装部队参谋长奥萨马·阿斯卡中将。&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;哈利法·哈夫塔尔（右）于 2023 年 9 月 12 日在班加西会见了埃及武装部队参谋长奥萨马·阿斯卡中将。阿斯卡率领军队抵达据埃及国防部称，代表团和紧急救灾援助。 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;照片：埃及国防部/法新社/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;哈夫塔尔的儿子们，每个人都控制着自己广泛的金融利益网络，有时还有军事利益利比亚东部地区的紧急救援队通过寻求进一步对救灾工作进行控制来应对德尔纳的人道主义危机。德尔纳发生灾难的同一天，哈利法·哈夫塔尔的长子埃尔塞迪克 (Elseddik) 宣布有兴趣在拖延已久的选举中竞选利比亚总统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观察人士称，32 岁的萨达姆·哈夫塔尔经常被看到尽管他的兄弟们做出了努力，但作为可能的继承人，他很快利用自己作为利比亚救灾委员会主席的角色，使自己的国际地位合法化，同时严格控制援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萨达姆·哈夫塔尔领导塔里克·本·扎耶德旅，隶属于 LNA 的民兵组织，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2022/12/libya-hold-commanders-of-tariq-ben-zeyad-武装团体对恐怖目录负责/&quot;>;最近被国际特赦组织指控“造成一系列恐怖事件，包括非法杀戮、酷刑和其他虐待、强迫失踪、强奸和其他性暴力和强迫流离失所——无需担心后果”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;利比亚问题专家、皇家联合军种研究所副研究员贾勒尔·哈查维 (Jalel Harchaoui) 指出，萨达姆·哈夫塔尔试图展现对国际援助队伍的控制力。抵达德尔纳，以及这如何减缓了危机时期至关重要的灾难响应：“一切都集中在哈夫塔尔家族手中。我希望我能告诉你，利比亚东部还有其他权力中心，但没有这样的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在过去十年的大部分时间里，利比亚一直保持着激烈的局势 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www .theguardian.com/world/2023/jul/04/fears-for-libyan-oil-product-amid-military-action-threats&quot;>;东部和西部派别之间存在着各自的军事利益，在北约部队进行军事干预以支持反对前独裁者穆阿迈尔·卡扎菲的起义之后。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Harchaoui 表示，哈夫塔尔家族对应对工作的控制，特别是萨达姆·哈夫塔尔的突出作用，使任何国内或国际组织都没有希望。对德尔纳事件的国际调查可以充分审查他们作为负责官员以及任何其他责任人的角色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;利比亚总检察长 al-Sediq al-Sour 承诺 &lt;a href =&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/16/Second-Humanarian-crisis-feared-in-wake-of-libya-floods-as-hopes-of-finding-survivors-fade&quot; >;调查德尔纳两座水坝的倒塌&lt;/a>;，并分配数百万美元的资金用于维护这些建于 20 世纪 70 年代的建筑。在承诺调查德尔纳地方当局和前任政府的同时，苏尔还会见了萨达姆·哈夫塔尔。当地电视台报道称，德尔纳市长周六已被停职，等待调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“萨达姆将自己定位为老大。你需要亲自接触受害者和这座城市，而要做到这一点，他们取决于他的善意，”哈沙维说。 “事情慢慢地走向一个结论，那就是只能责怪中层官员。很大一部分结论从一开始就被排除了，这不是一个公开的调查。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 22:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Halliburton equipment worth $7.1m exported to Russia in past year, customs records show]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/17/russia-trade-halliburton-equipment-export-us-oil]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T13:37:02Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/fee69d5dcd361df7736781821a8c8409fbc4a0d7/0_129_1280_768 /master/1280.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=691ad635c1f20ea4b207cdd297b8132b&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;乌克兰士兵在黑海石油平台上举着乌克兰国旗&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美国石油海关记录显示，自宣布结束俄罗斯业务以来，哈里伯顿制造的价值超过 710 万美元（570 万英镑）的设备已出口到俄罗斯，天然气跨国公司在与俄罗斯的贸易方面面临新的问题。 p>; &lt;p>;去年九月，全球最大的石油和天然气勘探产品和服务提供商之一哈里伯顿将其俄罗斯办事处出售给当地管理层，原因是所有美国公司在入侵乌克兰后面临停止贸易的压力。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;《卫报》看到的俄罗斯海关记录显示，尽管哈里伯顿在 9 月 8 日采取了出售行动，但在出售后的六周内，哈里伯顿子公司向其之前在俄罗斯的业务出口了价值 5,729,600 美元的设备。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;这些设备主要是从美国和新加坡运来的，尽管记录显示其源自英国、比利时和法国等一系列国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;子公司的大部分出口已结束10 月 6 日，但最后一次从哈里伯顿公司（记录中记录为 Halliburton MFG）向俄罗斯发货的是密封元件，价格为 2,939.40 美元，于 2022 年 10 月 24 日从马来西亚发往一家名为萨哈林能源公司（Sakhalin Energy）的公司，该公司正在开发萨哈林岛俄罗斯东部-2石油天然气项目。其投资者包括俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司。壳牌在入侵乌克兰后从该财团撤资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;短暂暂停后，2022 年 12 月恢复从与这家美国跨国公司无关的两家公司向俄罗斯进口哈里伯顿设备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些产品从土耳其进口，使哈里伯顿设备自该公司关闭以来向俄罗斯出口的总价值至少达到 7,163,317 美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自去年 9 月以来对俄罗斯的出口总额中，98%供应给哈里伯顿新独立的前业务部门 BurService，其客户包括俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司 (Gazprom)、俄罗斯石油公司 (Rosneft)、TNK-BP 和卢克石油公司 (Lukoil)。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据海关记录，向俄罗斯出口的哈里伯顿设备的类型包括泵、钻井扳手和水泥添加剂的生产至少持续到今年六月底。最近的记录尚未公布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰对西方许多大型工业企业在从俄罗斯经济中抽身而表现出的冷漠感到愤怒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查结果说明跨国公司在解除贸易关系和通过第三方控制其产品分销方面遇到的困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些全球最大的美国油气田​​服务公司已经面临对其行为的质疑。克里姆林宫严重依赖石油和天然气部门的收入来资助其军队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本月早些时候，美国参议院外交关系委员会主席鲍勃·梅嫩德斯 (Bob Menendez) 致信哈里伯顿及其竞争对手 SLB梅南德斯在给这三家公司首席执行官的信中表示，他在去年 2 月入侵乌克兰后继续与俄罗斯进行不同程度的贸易。美联社报道称 2022 年销售仍在继续，对此他感到“极度不安”。他指责管理层寻求“盈利”，而不是与乌克兰站在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贝克休斯在 2022 年出售了其油田服务业务。入侵九个月后的俄罗斯。据报道，SLB 在俄罗斯有 9,000 名员工，直到今年 7 月才宣布将停止向俄罗斯出口技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有任何迹象表明这些公司违反了美国或俄罗斯的制裁制度。其西方合作伙伴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，哈里伯顿在俄罗斯业务的出售日期直到当天晚些时候才确定，这可能是因为其子公司在不久前和不久后发往该国的货物。 9 月 8 日后。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈里伯顿发言人表示：“哈里伯顿是第一家完全遵守制裁规定退出俄罗斯的大型油田服务公司。我们在那里开展业务已经一年多了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“哈里伯顿在不到六个月的时间内缩减了俄罗斯业务并完成了俄罗斯业务的出售，同时优先考虑安全并获得必要的政府批准，包括运送到俄罗斯。哈里伯顿不再在俄罗斯开展业务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由美国前副总统迪克·切尼领导的哈里伯顿公布，截至 2023 年 6 月 30 日的 12 个月毛利润为 40.52 亿美元，同比增长 63.19%尽管在出售俄罗斯业务时注销了 3 亿美元，但仍同比增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基辅智库 StateWatch 首席执行官格利布·卡涅夫斯基 (Glib Kanevskyi) 表示，西方政府需要采取更多措施来说服他们的国家&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他补充说，应鼓励哈里伯顿等公司在如何确保其产品不被流入市场方面保持透明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卡内夫斯基说：“当我们谈论哈里伯顿案时，我们需要明白，如果美国或其他国家试图惩罚涉及该案的某些公司，那么它就不会有效。该计划将哈里伯顿设备运送到俄罗斯。我认为它不会有效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果国际社会愿意合作并让企业参与进来，那么它会有所帮助。这并不容易。今天各国能做的就是与本国企业对话。如果我们谈论哈里伯顿，它是世界上一个重要的参与者，美国政府可以与它进行对话，看看它如何更好地控制其分销过程。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 21:52:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Majority of Scottish voters support assisted dying bill, poll reports]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/sep/17/majority-of-scottish-voters-support-assisted-dying-bill-poll-reports]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T12:24:39Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0dfa59abce2530ffdd7b1307e4ef30d4f967fa1e/0_72_2534_1521 /master/2534.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=11aadf8eb6b2a40bd62bdbde33c3993c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;利亚姆·麦克阿瑟签署了一张承诺卡 - 声明中写着“我相信垂死的人应该选择如何死去” – 去年在荷里路德外面的台阶上支持他的安乐死法案。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;根据活动人士发布的一项民意调查，绝大多数苏格兰选民支持允许绝症患者结束自己生命的提议苏格兰议会将于今年晚些时候公布一项使苏格兰协助死亡合法化的新法案，这是其支持者首次尝试颁布该措施在英国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;YouGov 对运动组织“死亡尊严”的民意调查发现，77% 的苏格兰人支持这项措施，12% 的受访者反对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查结果还建议有宗教信仰的人的态度已经转变，支持合法化，尽管这与大多数宗教教义相冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年早些时候，该国最大的信仰团体苏格兰教会的大会，暂停了其历史上对安乐死的反对。它投票探讨了对该问题的“神学观点和伦理观点的范围”，然后再决定其立场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;民意调查发现苏格兰教会成员、英国圣公会成员大多数支持该法案的措施以及——另一个可能与宗教教义发生重大分歧的——罗马天主教徒，尽管民意调查中的样本很小。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;354 名受访者中的大多数人患有一些或“很多”危及生命的健康或疾病残疾问题也支持该法案，少数人表示他们“可能”或“肯定”会考虑前往瑞士的安乐死诊所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正在提出该法案的苏格兰自由民主党议员利亚姆·麦克阿瑟 (Liam McArthur) ，这些调查结果说，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/28/two-thirds-of-britons-support-legalising-assistance-dying-poll-shows&quot;>;与最近的其他民意调查相呼应&lt;/a>;，证明这些措施得到了广泛支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们知道，优秀的姑息治疗对于大多数临终者来说是正确的道路，但也有一些人面临着惨痛的死亡，在极大的痛苦中死去，”他说。 “受到严密保护和富有同情心的协助死亡法律不仅为垂死者提供了他们所需要的东西，而且还保护了所有其他群体。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的法案得到了来自各方的 36 名 MSP 的支持——是提出议案所需人数的两倍这是一项私人议员法案，但预计会遭到残疾人权利和信仰团体的强烈反对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;反对者认为，国家批准自杀在道德上是错误的，甚至一度限制了安乐死的权利在法律上，减少资格限制的压力将不可避免地增加。他们表示，这将使脆弱、虚弱和贫穷的人面临更大的压力，选择协助自杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本月早些时候，苏格兰首席部长胡姆扎·优素福 (Humza Yousaf) 和卫生部长迈克尔·马西森 (Michael Matheson) 表示，他们反对苏格兰工党领袖阿纳斯·萨瓦尔 (Anas Sarwar) 也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尤素夫和萨瓦尔都是穆斯林；马西森是天主教徒。伊斯兰教与犹太教和主流基督教一样，禁止自杀。 YouGov 调查的少数穆斯林、浸信会和福音派选民反对安乐死。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;麦克阿瑟的法案将是在荷里路德引入安乐死立法的第四次尝试，荷里路德控制着苏格兰的法律。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2015/may/27/scottish-parliament-rejects-assistance-suicide-law&quot;>;MSP 尚未充分考虑&lt;/a>;。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;为了减轻人们对这些措施过于广泛的担忧，麦克阿瑟的法案将比苏格兰之前的提案更具限制性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它只对那些签署了证书的人开放两名医生声称他们已病入膏肓，在手术时精神状态良好，并且没有压力。医生可以就申请人的心理能力寻求专家意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;申请人必须自行服用终止生命的药物，包括使用技术辅助工具来触发注射。他们必须居住在苏格兰，并在医生处注册至少一年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国医学会和皇家内科医师学会最近结束了对辅助死亡的历史性反对，转而采取中立立场，现在越来越多的医生支持这项措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尤萨夫告诉《每日纪事报》，在格拉斯哥会见残疾人权利活动人士后，他的反对态度变得更加强硬。 “他们非常强烈地反对安乐死，因为他们认为，正如他们所描述的那样，他们将成为楔子的薄弱一端，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;米罗格里菲斯是利兹大学残疾研究研究员，也是反对安乐死运动组织“更好的方式”的发言人，他说帮助人们结束自己的生命将创造“国家在保护生命方面发挥的作用的一个非常危险的先例”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在正常情况下，警察、社会服务和国民医疗服务体系会努力阻止人们结束自己的生命。他说，自己的生活，但在这里却得到了便利。其他辅助死亡合法国家的经验教训是，“一旦立法通过，就会产生扩大立法范围的压力”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;&lt;span>;•&lt;/span>;在英国和爱尔兰，可以通过免费电话 116 123 或发送电子邮件至 jo@samaritans.org 或 jo@samaritans.ie 联系 Samaritans。在美国，您可以拨打国家自杀预防生命线 988 或发短信，在 988lifeline.org 上聊天，或发短信 HOME 至 741741 与危机顾问联系。在澳大利亚，危机支持服务生命线是 13 11 14。其他国际帮助热线可以在 befrienders.org 找到&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 20:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden adviser calls for spending ‘race to the top’ on green tech]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/17/biden-adviser-calls-for-spending-race-to-the-top-on-green-tech-heather-boushey]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T11:39:23Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7a680b64c040bf3aae0364757f17f2f722f63813/0_267_4862_2917 /master/4862.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=f7e0c4e1787818f904b38295e977b432&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Heather Boushey，白宫经济顾问委员会成员。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;世界各国政府总统高级顾问表示，必须大幅增加对绿色技术的公共投资，以应对全球变暖并推动可持续经济增长&lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/us- news/joebiden&quot;>;乔·拜登&lt;/a>;说过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白宫经济顾问委员会成员希瑟·布希表示，包括英国在内的国家需要加大绿色投资以重启经济增长，提高能源安全，并防范未来的通胀冲击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在接受《卫报》采访时表示，拜登政府将数十亿美元公共资金投入基础设施和可再生能源的决定是“蜂拥而至”私人投资——帮助世界上最大的经济体处于更有利的地位，避免衰退。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们正在与我们的朋友和盟友合作，激励他们也这样做——因为我们都需要使这些投资，”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这种公共支出激励了全国各地数十亿美元的投资——私人资金，投资于半导体和清洁能源。事实上，很多公共资金还没有花出去，私营部门正在涌入。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的评论是在访问包括英国在内的欧洲国家时发表的，其中包括与&lt;a href= “x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/politics/edmiliband&quot;>;Ed Miliband&lt;/a>;，影子网零秘书 - 强调&lt;a href=&quot;x- gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international/lists/tag/politics/labour&quot;>;工党&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;x-gu://list/mobile.guardianapis.com/international /lists/tag/us-news/democrats&quot;>;民主党&lt;/a>;即将迎来明年两党的关键选举。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白宫正在投资 3690 亿美元（2890 亿英镑）清洁能源和低碳能源-通过拜登具有里程碑意义的《减少通货膨胀法案》(IRA) 实现碳技术&lt;/a>;，旨在解决全球变暖问题，为绿色经济增长奠定基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“问题是英国、欧洲以及其他国家如何崛起并应对挑战， ”布希说。 “我们认为这是一场力争上游的竞赛——激励每个人都这样做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工党承诺，如果当选，每年将借贷投资 280 亿英镑，投资于绿色就业和工业。 ，但是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/jun/09/labour-government-would-have-to-delay-28bn-green-fund-rachel-reeves-says&quot;>;今年夏天，&lt;/a>; 放弃了承诺，表示将在 2027 年“增加”到这一数字，以证明财政可信度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Boushey 表示，虽然重要的是要表明投资是“付出了代价”，绿色支出是有充分理由的，因为它可以为未来更具弹性的经济增长铺平道路——有助于支撑公共财政&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“总统并没有在任期内增加赤字。任期。他实际上降低了赤字，因为我们很快就让经济重回正轨。因此，税收收入开始增加，经济增长又回来了。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了回击政府增加支出以实现净零排放的批评者，布希警告说，如果不采取“大胆行动”，国家可能会落后。 in a global race to decarbonise. “It&#39;s an enormous economic opportunity. And if we don&#39;t do it, we&#39;ll end up importing these products from abroad.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A key architect of “Bidenomics” as one of the president&#39;s closest advisers, the economist said investing public money was helping to create jobs, while building US domestic capacity to produce clean, reliable energy. Doing so could protect against future inflation shocks by limiting exposure to volatile fossil fuel prices and fragile international supply chains.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As we&#39;ve seen with the war in Ukraine, access to energy is everything. If you don&#39;t have energy you can&#39;t power your factories, you can&#39;t keep your homes warm, you can&#39;t keep the lights running,” she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Building the green energy economy will be able to deliver lower prices over time and less volatile.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/15/tata-steel-seals-500m-uk-support-package-but-big-job-losses-feared&quot;>;Last Friday, the UK government agreed a £500m support package for Tata Steel &lt;/a>;to help its Port Talbot steelworks switch to greener forms of steelmaking using electricity rather than coal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the chancellor, Jeremy Hunt, insisted Britain was not about to adopt Biden&#39;s economic approach.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are very clear – we won&#39;t pursue the Inflation Reduction Act subsidy bowl approach to economic policy,” Hunt told the Financial Times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Critics have warned that Biden&#39;s agenda amounted to a new protectionism that could unsettle relations with America&#39;s allies, while breeding inefficiencies and adding to living costs. However, Boushey said the scale of the challenge to decarbonise in countries around the world meant there was “plenty of work to go around”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are so far from capacity that the idea there is not going to be enough production to go around, is not where we need to start this conversation.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Figures from the International Energy Agency and the OECD suggested up to $6.9tn of annual global investments may be needed to meet the Paris agreement&#39;s emissions reduction target. The IEA estimated about 70% would probably need to come from the private sector.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Boushey&#39;s comments coincided with growing concerns about a possible US recession a year out from the next presidential election, driven by persistent inflation and higher interest rates from the US Federal Reserve. Despite an uptick in inflation in August, the US central bank is widely expected to keep rates unchanged at its next meeting on Wednesday after 11 previous increases.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Boushey dismissed concerns over a recession, while arguing the longer-term path for inflation was “moving in the right direction” despite last month&#39;s rise. Asked whether a recession could be avoided ahead of the election, she said: “I don&#39;t have a crystal ball, but the US economy is strong and resilient.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 19:52:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden to meet Benjamin Netanyahu at UN in awkward rapprochement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/17/joe-biden-benjamin-netanyahu-talks-un-general-assembly-israel-us]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T11:48:20Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/5894394258f5097706c0b0ea275b2a9ddb3dadf4/0_447_3200_1919/master/3200.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=03fee543f5add222887d05d769ab65c6&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Joe Biden (right) and Benjamin Netanyahu&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nine months after returning to office, Israel&#39;s prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, is finally getting his long sought-after meeting with Joe Biden - but an awkward rapprochement at the UN general assembly is unlikely to improve the strained relationship between the two leaders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The US president is scheduled to meet Netanyahu in New York on Wednesday, the White House said on Friday. The US national security adviser, Jake Sullivan, said the two leaders would “discuss a range of bilateral and regional issues focused on the shared democratic values between the United States and Israel and a vision for a more stable and prosperous and integrated region, as well as to compare notes on effectively countering and deterring Iran”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sullivan&#39;s reference to shared democratic values was a reference to deep unease in Biden&#39;s White House about the judicial overhaul being pushed by Netanyahu&#39;s hardline coalition partners, which it sees as an assault on the judiciary&#39;s independence. The proposals have been greeted by the largest protest movement in Israeli history, including unprecedented declarations from thousands of military reservists that they wish to be released from service.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That has been the primary factor in Biden&#39;s refusal to meet Netanyahu so far during the Israeli prime minister&#39;s current term, and the principal reason there will not be the meeting in the White House that Netanyahu sought.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Biden&#39;s administration has also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jun/19/us-deeply-troubled-as-israel-plans-to-approve-thousands-of-homes-in-west-bank&quot;>;expressed frustration with accelerating Israeli settlement growth&lt;/a>; in the occupied West Bank, which the international community considers a major obstacle to peace with the Palestinians and a two-state solution to the decades-old conflict.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement came amid calls from Israeli artists and intellectuals, including well-known &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/israel-netanyahu-protests-supreme-court-2598dfc6c2c824fd78e50c9a53d71c48&quot;>;writer David Grossman&lt;/a>; and painter Tamar Getter, for the US president to shun a sit down with Netanyahu altogether.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From the outset of establishing his extreme right-wing government, Netanyahu&#39;s coalition has worked tirelessly to weaken the supreme court, neutralise the media and destroy the few checks and balances safeguarding the health of our nation,” an open letter published last week and signed by 3,500 Israeli academics and public figures read.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Netanyahu incites citizens against each other, threatens the country&#39;s security and economy, and turns his face away from the historical conflict that tears Israel apart – the forceful domination of the Palestinian people.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli leader announced earlier this month that he would visit the US, Israel&#39;s staunchest ally, which donates billions in military aid to the country each year. Initially, however, no meetings with US officials were announced - an anomaly for visiting Israeli prime ministers. Netanyahu, who grew up between Jerusalem and the US city of Philadelphia, frequently boasts of his close connection to the US to bolster his platform both at home and abroad.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Biden said earlier this year that he had no intention of sitting down with Netanyahu “in the near term”, before his office said in July &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/jul/17/benjamin-netanyahu-joe-biden-israel-white-house-visit&quot;>;that a meeting had been agreed&lt;/a>;. Netanyahu&#39;s office was quick to announce that he had been invited to meet the president in the US, but the Biden administration pointedly declined to call it an invitation and did not specify where the leaders would meet.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The snub was emphasised when Biden welcomed Israel&#39;s figurehead president, Isaac Herzog, to the White House in July.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Axios news site, the issue of a Netanyahu invitation split Biden&#39;s advisers, ultimately leading to a compromise of the meeting on the sidelines of the UN general assembly on Wednesday. A meeting in the White House, it was argued, would signal approval and reward for Israeli government policy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Biden&#39;s team also did not want to import Israeli politics and have a crowd of demonstrators outside the White House during a meeting, which would also have led to complaints from the progressive end of the Democratic party.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A White House invitation has not been ruled out before the end of the year, because the Biden administration is keen to use the prize as leverage, waiting to see what happens to the legislation on the judiciary, now being challenged in Israel&#39;s supreme court.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also an incentive for Netanyahu&#39;s cooperation in a deal that would normalise relations with Saudi Arabia. Such an agreement would be a political coup for the Israeli prime minister, but Washington and Riyadh are seeking to persuade him to accept elements of the deal intended to benefit Palestinians, possibly including the transfer of West Bank territory to direct Palestinian rule.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/01/pro-israel-lobby-groups-netanyahu-government&quot;>;US pro-Israel groups in bitter feud over Netanyahu&#39;s far-right government&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;There is no personal bond between Biden and Netanyahu, who have known each other for decades, although the US leader often describes himself as a “true friend of Israel”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Biden is well aware of the Israeli&#39;s previous interventions in US politics in favour of Donald Trump, and has called the current Israeli cabinet one of the most extreme he has seen in his long political lifetime.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is also is cognisant of the fact though that freezing out an Israeli leader entirely is bad electoral politics in the US, and that the two countries have to be seen to be sticking together in the face of the steady progress of Iran&#39;s nuclear programme.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his week-long visit, Netanyahu will also meet leaders of the US Jewish community.在抵达纽约之前，他预计还将访问旧金山，在那里他将与包括埃隆·马斯克在内的科技行业领袖会面。 The pair are scheduled to discuss antisemitism on X, the platform formerly known as Twitter.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 19:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Global inflation fears as oil price rises towards $100 a barrel]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/17/global-inflation-fears-as-oil-price-rises-towards-100-a-barrel]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T11:02:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7d7cf0d1f17d8fc5ed8f0ef17c27ddea486b0397/0_147_4500_2700/master/4500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=2273cd2296b44bfe9f22801922add999&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;a B petrol station displays petrol prices at 157.9pa litre&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Oil prices are on track to reach $100 a barrel this month for the first time in 2023 after surging by almost 30% since June, after Russian and Saudi Arabian production cuts and rising demand from China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brent crude, the oil price benchmark, rose to a 10-month high last week of almost $94 a barrel, up from $72 a barrel at its lowest point in June – heading for its biggest quarterly increase since Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lighter US crude, West Texas Intermediate, has climbed from $67 a barrel to $90 a barrel over the same period. Both benchmarks were up by about 4% on the week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Petrol and diesel prices in the UK have begun to rise modestly, adding 10p to the cost of a litre since June. The motoring organisation RAC said the average price of unleaded fuel was £1.52 per litre on Friday, up from £1.43 in June.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the US, where tax makes up a smaller proportion of the price at the pumps, gasoline has jumped by more than 10% to $3.90 (£3.15) per gallon (3.8 litres).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An increase in demand for flights in the US, Europe, and more recently China have spurred an even larger increase in jet fuel prices tracked by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/e/energy-information-admin.asp&quot;>;Energy Information Administration (EIA)&lt;/a>;. Prices averaged $3.07 a gallon at the end of August, up by 50% from a recent low of $2.05 in early May.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier this month, Saudi Arabia extended 1.3m barrels per day (bpd) of combined cuts to the end of the year, accelerating a drawdown in global inventories.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Supply cuts by Russia to boost prices have also supported efforts by other Opec countries to push prices towards $100 a barrel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The International Energy Agency (IEA) warned last week that the ongoing supply cuts made by these two Opec+ leaders would create a “significant supply shortfall”, which poses a considerable threat to ongoing price volatility.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report was released just a day after Opec announced that the market is facing a deficit of more than 3m bpd in the upcoming quarter, potentially resulting in the most substantial supply shortage in more than a decade.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saudia Arabia and its partners in Opec are also concerned that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/sep/12/beginning-of-the-end-of-fossil-fuel-era-approaching-says-iea&quot;>;the IEA has predicted that demand for oil will peak before 2030&lt;/a>;, a data which some analysts believe could be brought forward to 2026 by the rapid switch to renewables already under way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stephen Innes, managing partner at SPI asset management, said: “Oil&#39;s wicked ripper is showing few signs of abating just yet.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rising cost of fuel and demand from the Chinese economy, which ranks as the world&#39;s biggest oil importer, are expected to cloud the outlook for central banks and their mission to bring down inflation rates that are still well above the 2% target level.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A drop in oil prices played a large role in the fall of inflation in the first half of this year, but are now expected to act as a brake in the second half and into 2024.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Central Bank implemented a 10th consecutive increase in interest rates last week and implied it was likely to stop there. On Friday, however, policymakers said further hike was not &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/ecbs-kazaks-keeps-door-open-rate-hikes-if-needed-2023-09-15/&quot;>;off the table&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;US central bank interest rates were widely expected to have hit a peak after a drop last month in core inflation, which strips out volatile elements such as fuel and food. Yet, the Federal Reserve has signalled that the door remains open for a possible final increase in November.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Betting on oil is becoming a favourite trade on Wall Street. No one is doubting the Opec+ (oil output) decision at the end of last month will keep the oil market very tight in the fourth quarter,” said OANDA analyst Edward Moya.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 19:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russell Brand: entertainment industry has questions to answer, says Cleverly]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/sep/17/russell-brand-entertainment-industry-has-question-to-answer-says-james-cleverly]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T10:46:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d294b6ad1ba00d1852eaf1a7e725ef7e75912292/654_305_2559_1536/master/2559.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=8b0d5f777c0289f674e83468c137334e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Russell Brand performed a comedy set in London on Saturday night.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The foreign secretary has said the entertainment industry has questions to answer following revelations that the comedian Russell Brand has been accused of rape, sexual assault and emotional abuse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;James Cleverly became the most senior British politician to talk about the issue after the allegations about Brand&#39;s behaviour were published on Saturday night.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told the BBC&#39;s Laura Kuenssberg: “We have to be particularly careful when we listen to the voices of the people who are relatively powerless. Because we, I think, collectively have missed opportunities to do the right thing and intervene much, much earlier.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Asked whether he thought there were questions for the entertainment industry more broadly to answer, he added: “Sadly I think there are.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Separately, Cleverly told Sky News&#39; Sir Trevor Phillips: “In the film industry, in the entertainment industry … in the area that I work in, in terms of politics, where you have very, very significant power differentials, long working hours – in those environments, I think institutionally, we need to be particularly vigilant.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cleverly was speaking the morning after the allegations were published after a multi-year investigation by the Times, the Sunday Times and Channel 4&#39;s Dispatches.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sunday Times revealed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/russell-brand-rape-sexual-assault-abuse-allegations-investigation-v5hxdlmb6&quot;>;its coverage&lt;/a>; that Brand had been accused by multiple women of aggressive and abusive sexual behaviour between 2006 and 2013.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One woman said she entered a relationship with the comedian and presenter when she was 16 and he was 31. During that relationship, she said, Brand called her “the child”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another woman said Brand raped her in his home in Los Angeles in 2012, after which she visited a rape crisis centre. The Sunday Times published texts to her – from a phone number which multiple sources verified as belonging to Brand – in which he said: “I&#39;m sorry. That was crazy and selfish.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A third woman says she was assaulted in the same house the following year after having worked with Brand on a project.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several sources told the Sunday Times that the BBC had failed to act despite multiple complaints about Brand&#39;s behaviour, including one incident in which he is alleged to have urinated into a bottle in a Radio 2 Studio.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The BBC said: “The BBC has, over successive years, evolved its approach to how it manages talent and indeed how it deals with complaints or issues raised.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brand has denied the allegations. In a video he posted online on Friday night, he said: “During that time of promiscuity, the relationships I had were absolutely always consensual. I was always transparent about that then, almost too transparent, and I am being transparent about it now as well.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite the allegations, Brand performed a show in London on Saturday night, telling the audience: “There&#39;s some things I cannot talk about and hopefully you appreciate that. I&#39;m gonna give you everything I&#39;ve got.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 18:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AOC to headline major New York climate march ahead of UN summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/17/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-new-york-climate-march-un-summit]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T10:00:56Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2ba1649edda4d9455562aec374b661c0ff29313f/0_520_7798_4679/master/7798.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=5881464e326d903027988f77d2ecc382&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Climate activists demonstrate in front of the headquarters of BlackRock, in New York.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A climate protest and rally headlined by Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez on Sunday are expected to bring thousands of activists to the streets of New York.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the banner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.endfossilfuels.us/&quot;>;March to End Fossil Fuels&lt;/a>;, protesters will push the Biden administration to take bold steps to phase out fossil fuels. The demonstration will fall days before the United Nations Climate Ambition Summit, which the UN secretary general, António Guterres, has described as a “no nonsense” conference meant to highlight new climate commitments.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/14/climate-activists-protests-fossil-fuels-united-nations&quot;>;Climate activists kick off rallies against fossil fuel in week of action in New York&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The protesters will demand an end to the approval of new oil and gas projects, a phasing out of fossil fuel drilling on public lands, the declaration of a federal climate emergency and support for workers as polluting industries are phased out – demands that have been endorsed by more than 500 organizations including the NAACP, the Sierra Club and the Sunrise Movement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.endfossilfuels.us/letter-to-president-biden&quot;>;celebrities&lt;/a>; such as Jeremy Strong, Edward Norton, Jane Fonda and Mark Ruffalo, and more than 400 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foodandwaterwatch.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/March-to-End-Fossil-Fuels-Scientist-Letter-to-Biden_Format.pdf&quot;>;scientists&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a recent Guardian &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/03/aoc-interview-2024-election-climate-democrat&quot;>;interview&lt;/a>;, the Democratic congresswoman spoke about how the climate crisis “does not really care about the political complexities that we very much have to grapple with in our work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We can celebrate all of these policies that result in reductions but we also can&#39;t erase them with increased oil and gas production.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sunday&#39;s march was organized in large part by youth-led climate groups, including Greta Thunberg&#39;s Fridays for Future movement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are marching to make it clear to President Biden that he is betraying the very youth who helped get him into office in the first place,” Bree Campbell, a 17-year-old organizer with New York City&#39;s Fridays for Our Future chapter, said. “We are marching to make him see us – and to make him act on his promises. We are marching because everyone deserves a clean, healthy, and just future, and ending the era of fossil fuels will help ensure that.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill McKibben, veteran climate campaigner and co-founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://thirdact.org/&quot;>;Third Act&lt;/a>;, a climate group aimed at older activists, said the event will also convene elders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It&#39;s true that some of us will be dead before the climate damage reaches its peak – but we can imagine that future and so we want to help head it off while we can,” he said, noting that some activists who will attend “have been marching since the first Earth Day in 1970”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New York congressman Jamaal Bowman and former Ireland President Mary Robinson are expected to give remarks before Sunday&#39;s protest, while Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and Unicef goodwill ambassador Vanessa Nakate will headline the rally that will follow.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Organizers expect the event will be the largest climate march in the US in five years. It will cap off a week of more than 650 global climate actions that took place this week in countries including Bolivia, Pakistan, Ethiopia and Austria.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Washington, DC on Friday, progressive lawmakers and activists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/14/climate-activists-protests-fossil-fuels-united-nations&quot;>;rallied outside the Capitol&lt;/a>;. And In New York, scores of activists protested outside of the headquarters for asset manager BlackRock and Citibank on Wednesday and Thursday respectively, to call attention to both firms&#39; investments in fossil fuels; dozens were arrested.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Quezon City in the Philippines, activists lay in front of the department of environment and natural resources in protest and held signs demanding fossil fuels – from coal to natural gas – be phased out. Outside the Indonesian energy and mineral resources ministry in Jakarta, protesters held signs calling for end to dirty fuels and greenwashing as police officers looked on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sweden, climate activists gathered in front of Parliament, just next to the Royal Palace where Sweden&#39;s King Carl XVI Gustaf was celebrating his 50th anniversary on the throne. Their chants about “climate justice” could be heard in the palace courtyard as the king watched the changing of the guard during the golden jubilee celebrations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And in Democratic Republic of the Congo, dozens joined a protest march through the city of Goma, shouting slogans and waving banners and placards calling for an end to corporate control of fossil fuels. The Congolese government caused an uproar among environmentalists last year by putting 30 oil and gas blocks up for auction, including 13 blocks crisscrossing through protected areas and national parks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Additional climate protests will be held throughout the following week, including at New York City&#39;s Zuccotti Park on Monday morning.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 18:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fourteen people killed in plane crash in Brazil’s Amazonas state]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/17/plane-crash-brazil-barcelos-amazonas-state]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T09:23:46Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/fd2f9b95bffea370cdf7ec8afa0d5b037468559f/1041_761_3293_1977/master/3293.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=6ac6343dcd6b96c59ed30f7a379f4d1d&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;People gather at the scene of the crash in Barcelos province, Amazonas state&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Fourteen people on a small jet died when the plane crashed in Brazil&#39;s northern Amazonas state on Saturday, the regional governor said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The crash took place in Barcelos province, about 250 miles (400km) from the state capital, Manaus.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I deeply regret the death of the 12 passengers and two crew members who were victims of the plane crash in Barcelos on Saturday,” the Amazonas governor, Wilson Lima, said on X.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our teams have been working from the outset to provide the necessary support. My sympathy and prayers go out to their families and friends.“&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Manaus Aerotáxi airline issued a statement confirming there had been an accident and that it was investigating, but it offered no details about deaths or injuries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We count on respect for the privacy of those involved at this difficult time and will be available to provide all necessary information and updates as the investigation progresses,” the statement said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Brazilian air force said in a statement that investigators from the Accident Investigation and Prevention Centre (CENIPA) had been called in to begin an investigation into the cause of the crash of the aircraft, an Embraer Bandeirante with the registration PT-SOG.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with O Globo newspaper, Lima said the bodies had already been removed from the aircraft and that the victims were Brazilian tourists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also said the most likely cause of the accident was an error in the approach to landing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 17:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Kim Jong-un returns home after Russia trip underscoring ties with Putin]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/17/kim-jong-un-returns-north-korea-russia-trip-putin-weapon-transfer-deals]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17T09:20:50Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6463f188793c220a562f5f1a98abf9d5f3716501/0_122_3000_1800/master/3000.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=af4c3b0f86733b63772c5aca4353d534&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Kim Jong Un (second from left) and Vladimir Putin (right) visitng the Vostochny Cosmodrome in Russia&#39;s Amur region. &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The North Korean leader, Kim Jong-un, was on his way home from Russia on Sunday, ending a six-day trip that triggered global concerns about weapons transfer deals between the two countries locked in separate standoffs with the west.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kim began his journey back onboard his armoured train from the Primorye region in Russia&#39;s far east, after a farewell ceremony at the train station, Russia&#39;s state news agency RIA said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering Russia on Tuesday in his first overseas trip in more than four years, Kim met Vladimir Putin and visited key military and technology sites. Earlier on Sunday, he toured a university and watching a show at a Russian aquarium before his departure.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Russia&#39;s state media released videos of Kim talking to Russian officials through translators as he walked through the campus of the Far Eastern Federal University in Russky Island.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kim was later seen at the island&#39;s Primorsky Aquarium, Russia&#39;s largest, where he watched performances featuring beluga whales, bottlenose dolphins, fur seals and Misha the walrus, which he seemed to particularly enjoy, according to Russian media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kim&#39;s trip, which included a summit with Putin on Wednesday, has underscored how Russia and North Korea&#39;s interests are aligning in the face of separate, intensifying confrontations with the west. US and South Korean officials have said North Korea could provide badly needed munitions for Moscow&#39;s war in Ukraine in exchange for sophisticated Russian weapons technology that would advance Kim&#39;s nuclear ambitions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A day after visiting an aircraft plant in Komsomolsk-on-Amur that produces Russia&#39;s most powerful fighter jets, Kim travelled to an airport near Vladivostok on Saturday where the defence minister, Sergei Shoigu, and other senior military officials gave him a close-up look at Russia&#39;s strategic bombers and other warplanes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All the Russian warplanes shown to Kim were among the types that have seen active use in the war in Ukraine, including the Tu-160, Tu-95 and Tu-22 bombers that have regularly launched cruise missiles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During Kim&#39;s visit, Shoigu and Lt Gen Sergei Kobylash, the commander of Russia&#39;s long-range bomber force, confirmed for the first time that the Tu-160 had recently received new cruise missiles with a range of more than 4,000 miles (6,500km).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shoigu, who had met Kim during a rare visit to North Korea in July, also showed him another of Russia&#39;s latest missiles, the hypersonic Kinzhal, carried by the MiG-31 fighter jet, that took part in its first combat role in Ukraine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kim and Shoigu later travelled to Vladivostok on Saturday, where they inspected the Admiral Shaposhnikov frigate. Russia&#39;s navy commander, Adm Nikolai Yevmenov, briefed Kim on the ship&#39;s capabilities and weapons, which include long-range Kalibr cruise missiles that Russian warships have regularly fired at targets in Ukraine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;North Korea&#39;s state media reported that Kim had been accompanied on Saturday&#39;s visits by his top military officials, including his defence minister and the top commanders of his air force and navy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a lunch, Kim and Shoigu talked about the regional security environment and exchanged views on “practical issues arising in further strengthening the strategic and tactical coordination, cooperation and mutual exchange between the armed forces of the two countries,” according to the North&#39;s official Korean Central news agency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In their July meeting, Kim gave Shoigu a similar inspection of North Korean weapons systems before inviting him to a parade in the capital, Pyongyang, where he rolled out his most powerful intercontinental ballistic missiles designed to target the US.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kim&#39;s visits to military and technology sites this week possibly hint at what he wants from Russia, perhaps in exchange for supplying munitions to refill Putin&#39;s declining reserves as his invasion of Ukraine becomes a drawn-out war of attrition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kim&#39;s meeting with Putin was held at Russia&#39;s main spaceport, a location that pointed to his desire for Russian assistance in his efforts to acquire space-based reconnaissance assets and missile technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts have said potential military cooperation between the countries could include efforts to modernise North Korea&#39;s outdated air force, which relies on warplanes sent from the Soviet Union in the 1980s.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 17:52:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>