<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>守护者</title><description>卫报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://theguardian.com <item><title><![CDATA[X/Twitter scraps feature letting users report misleading information]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/27/xtwitter-scraps-function-letting-users-report-misleading-information]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T03:34:29Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b472045c3d4852a1206dcd7fbec3914c599a944c/0_0_8256_4954 /master/8256.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=6a7b6d1eddab53d42023bea6497295ab&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;X 和 Twitter 徽标&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;X（以前称为 Twitter）公司已删除了该功能就在澳大利亚议会就原住民声音进行公投的几周前，人们可以举报包含误导性信息的推文。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自 2021 年以来，美国、澳大利亚和韩国等国家的 X 用户已经能够标记他们认为包含误导性信息的推文，以供公司员工审查——与公司报告滥用或仇恨言论的其他流程分开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该功能已在美国、澳大利亚推出自 2021 年 8 月以来，该工具已扩展到巴西、菲律宾和西班牙，并于 2022 年初扩展到巴西、菲律宾和西班牙，当时该公司的管理层注意到了这种工具在选举期间的重要性。然而，根据数字平台评论团体 Reset Australia 的说法，该工具在过去一两周内已从这些市场中删除。&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed&quot;>;注册澳大利亚卫报的免费上午和下午电子邮件通讯，获取每日新闻摘要&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt; /ul>; &lt;p>;在周三发表的一封公开信中，Reset Australia 表示，距离议会就原住民声音进行公投仅几周后，Reset Australia 就被取消了，并且“对澳大利亚来说正处于灾难性的时刻”，这“非常令人担忧”。如果该工具被故意删除，“选举的完整性”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们联系 X 征求意见，并在自动回复中说：“现在很忙。请稍后再回来查看。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该网站的所有者埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 将反对审查平台上的内容作为他接管 Twitter 的一个关键原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;澳大利亚选举委员会之间的通讯委员会和 X &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/sep/21/aec-twitter-x-struggles-posts-violence-disinformation-removal&quot;>;由澳大利亚卫报获得&lt; /a>; 上周透露，委员会内部对 X 未能采取行动删除煽动针对其工作人员的暴力行为和宣扬有关选举过程的虚假信息的帖子感到沮丧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AEC 专员汤姆·罗杰斯 (Tom Rogers) 表示 &lt;a href=&quot; https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/sep/21/aec-twitter-x-struggles-posts-violence-disinformation-removal&quot;>;在社交媒体平台上对员工发出隐晦的威胁&lt;/a>;无论它们在哪个平台上，都很难删除。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AEC 的一位发言人表示，该委员会有自己的途径将内容提交给 X。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有一个途径AEC 仍然可以将内容提交给 X，我们也利用它，”该发言人表示。 “但是，我们对向社交媒体平台举报的事项有很高的门槛，并且对此很现实。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/sep/21/aec-twitter-x-struggles-posts-violence-disinformation-removal&quot;>;AEC 努力让 Twitter 删除“煽动暴力”和传播“虚假信息”的帖子” 在声音之前&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“AEC 明白，AEC 在平台上的响应速度总是比在平台上更快、更有效地反击有关选举过程的不正确说法。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发言人表示，在过去的一年中，社交媒体平台的响应能力发生了转变，而不仅仅是 X。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有些问题与什么有关我们会考虑煽动暴力或隐晦的威胁，我们认为应该采取行动。这种情况有时会发生，但情况并非总是如此。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 5 月份向数字平台游说团体 Digi 提交的一份关于遵守自愿行业错误信息和虚假信息代码的报告中，Twitter 指出了其社区注释功能– 用户可以事实上检查一条推文，如果有足够多的用户批准它，它就会作为附加上下文添加到推文中 – 作为平台如何打击错误信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们知道误导性信息很复杂，不断发展，有时隐藏在问题或意见后面，”该公司表示。 “为了确保人们在 Twitter 上更好地了解情况，我们推出了社区注释，这是我们提供背景信息和呈现可信信息的方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“随着社区注释在平台上、Twitter 内部以及公共场合的快速发展，该产品为我们公司和使用我们服务的人们带来了深刻的转变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一个优先发展领域，植根于 Twitter、平台和内容审核实验、政策、和产品。它还以正在进行的研究、评估和咨询为基础。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一变化是在联邦政府面临反对派压力&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news /2023/jul/18/labor-social-media-regulation-laws-free-speech-coalition&quot;>;废除一项法案草案&lt;/a>;，该法案将授予澳大利亚通信和媒体管理局 (Acma) 执行该守则的权力平台。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 12:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Revealed: Europe’s role in the making of Russia killer drones]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/27/revealed-europes-role-in-the-making-of-russia-killer-drones]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T04:00:48Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b6122af4319a7e5afc33acb34bf8ac7371152de0/0_406_6016_3610 /master/6016.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=d79476e5e15eb31fe2f1d3178c5a397d&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Shahed-136 无人机&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;最近对乌克兰城市的袭击中使用的伊朗神风特攻队无人机是基辅向其西方盟友发送的一份秘密文件显示，该产品充满了欧洲部件，其中呼吁使用远程导弹攻击俄罗斯、伊朗和叙利亚的生产基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一份长达 47 页的文件中乌克兰政府8月份向七国集团政府提交的一份报告称，在过去三个月里，使用含有西方技术的无人机对城市进行了600多次袭击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报告称， 《卫报》获得的信息显示，Shahed-131 无人机中发现了 52 个西方公司制造的电气元件，Shahed-136 型号中发现了 57 个电气元件，该型号的飞行距离为 2,000 公里（1,240 英里），巡航速度为 180 公里/小时（111 英里/小时）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包括一家英国跨国公司的波兰子公司在内的五家欧洲公司被指定为已确定组件的原始制造商。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“制造商中有总部位于制裁联盟国家的公司：美国、瑞士、荷兰、德国、加拿大、日本和波兰，”它声称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据该报告，伊朗已经通过在叙利亚的一家工厂实现了生产多元化。新罗西斯克港，但无人机的生产正在转移到俄罗斯，转移到阿拉布加的鞑靼中部地区，尽管德黑兰继续供应零部件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它表示，伊朗政府正试图“脱离向俄罗斯提供零部件的关系”乌克兰的西方盟友提出的行动建议（他们可能会犹豫）包括“对生产设施进行导弹袭击”。这些无人机位于伊朗、叙利亚以及俄罗斯联邦的潜在生产基地”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该文件继续说道：“如果合作伙伴提供，乌克兰国防军可能会执行上述任务。必要的破坏手段。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有迹象表明其零部件已被确认的西方公司有任何不当行为。报告称：“伊朗无人机生产已经适应并主要使用现有的商业组件，但其供应控制不佳或根本不受控制。”&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-interactive=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co .uk/embed/iframe-wrapper/0.1/boot.js&quot; data-canonical-url=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/uploader/embed/2022/10/drone-zip/giv-6562n93d2p4i016H/ &quot; data-alt=&quot;伊朗 Shahed-136 无人机图&quot;>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/uploader/embed/2022/10/drone-zip/giv-6562n93d2p4i016H/&quot;>;交互式&lt;/a>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;乌克兰报告称，海关信息显示，“几乎所有对伊朗的进口都来自土耳其、印度、哈萨克斯坦、乌兹别克斯坦、越南和哥斯达黎加”。&lt;/p>; &lt;欧洲议会国防与安全小组委员会成员、欧洲议会议员巴特·格鲁特修斯表示，欧盟情报部门之间协调不足，无法应对西方组件的滥用问题。 “我认为许多欧洲情报机构甚至没有考虑制裁，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰政府文件——“弹幕死亡：关于 Shahed-136/131 无人机的报告”——是在乌克兰政府的协助下起草的乌克兰中央军备和军事装备研究所及其情报部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自哈尔科夫首次使用“沙赫德”无人机以来，它提供了对俄罗斯不断变化的无人机战术和生产计划的最新分析。 2022 年 9 月 13 日，在库皮安斯克市。它声称：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;从 11 月 17 日到 12 月 7 日持续的袭击暂停“可能是由于为温暖气候设计的无人机适应了乌克兰的冬季”，而这“可能表明俄罗斯和伊朗在 Shahed-136/131 的生产和现代化方面进行了更多合作”。&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;从伊朗向俄罗斯交付 Shahed-136/131 无人机需要花费里海对面的地方。 “这些无人机从德黑兰被运送到伊朗阿米拉巴德港口，再从那里运往俄罗斯港口城市马哈奇卡拉。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;电子元件上的标记近几个月在乌克兰使用的无人机已被摧毁，“可能是使用激光”，俄罗斯军队已开始使用这些无人机的名称 Geranium-1 和 Geranium-2，这“可能是双方协议的一部分”伊朗和俄罗斯掩盖了伊朗的角色”。&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;7月初，一架标记为“Y002”的新Shahed-136型号在乌克兰被击落，该型号“可能是在俄罗斯的新生产设施”。据说该样本具有不同的机翼造型，这“也可能表明是在新地点生产的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯和伊朗“已经在为Shahed-136，它应该能提供更好的速度和航程”。&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;据美国国防部称，在被击落的无人机型号中发现了多种西方公司生产的组件向由法国、美国、英国、德国、日本、意大利和加拿大以及欧盟组成的七国集团报告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由德国 Ti Automotive Gmbh 公司在波兰制造的燃油泵，其中据英国跨国公司 TI Fluid Systems 的母公司称，在 Shahed-136 中发现了该器件，以及瑞士公司意法半导体制造的带有内置闪存的微控制器和带有抑制剂的超低压降稳压器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 Shahed-136 中还发现了缓冲网络驱动器和晶体管的集成电路，由德国英飞凌科技公司的子公司国际整流器公司制造。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;TI Fluid Systems 没有回应置评请求。他们的设备可以从欧洲各地的零售商处免费购买，该公司此前曾表示不会向伊朗销售。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意法半导体的一位发言人表示：“我们与全球超过 20 万客户和数千个合作伙伴合作。世界。我们不会授权或纵容在其预期用途之外使用我们的产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们拥有全面的全球贸易合规计划，通过该计划，我们遵守所有国际贸易规则和法规。我们有一个内部出口管制合规计划，其中包含确保遵守各种出口管制法规的培训和程序。作为该计划的一部分，我们为销售渠道提供指南，以确保供应链中的每一方都了解其遵守适用法律和法规的责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英飞凌发言人表示，该公司不销售组件&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示：“总的来说，遵守适用法律对英飞凌来说至关重要，我们已经制定了强有力的政策和流程来遵守与这些法律。我们指示包括经销商在内的客户仅按照适用规则进行连续销售。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“事实证明，在产品的整个生命周期中控制销售是很困难的。尽管如此，我们仍然采取了广泛的措施，以确保遵守对俄罗斯的制裁，不仅要遵守制裁的文字，还要遵守制裁的精神。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 Shahed-131 模型中，乌克兰专家确定了荷兰恩智浦半导体公司生产的 14 通道、可定制集成电源管理电路和微处理器以及国际整流器公司生产的功率晶体管和集成电路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个 32 位微控制器、一个 32-还发现了意法半导体制造的位处理器、内置闪存的微控制器和带有抑制剂的超低压降调节器，以及瑞士公司 U-blox 制造的 GPS 跟踪器芯片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A U-blox 发言人表示：“U-blox 强烈谴责俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。 2022 年 2 月俄罗斯入侵乌克兰后，U-blox 立即停止了对俄罗斯、白俄罗斯以及俄罗斯军队在乌克兰占领的领土的所有销售，无论其用途如何。最近，U-blox 还决定不向欧亚经济联盟（与俄罗斯的自由贸易区）成员出售产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href= “https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/27/the-ukrainian-experts-dismandling-bombs-for-clues-to-putins-arms-supply&quot;>;乌克兰专家拆除炸弹寻找线索普京的武器供应&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“自 2002 年以来，U-blox 制定了严格的公司政策，其产品不得用于武器或武器系统 - 包括用于目标的系统恩智浦半导体的一位发言人表示，该公司正在寻求新的方法来避免其技术被滥用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说：“我们不会容忍在以下情况下使用我们的产品：俄罗斯或伊朗武器，或我们的产品未设计或授权的任何其他应用。我们继续遵守业务所在国家/地区的出口管制和制裁法律，并且我们不支持在俄罗斯、白俄罗斯和其他禁运国家/地区（包括伊朗）开展的任何业务。我们的团队正在就这个问题与世界各地的监管机构保持联系，同时探索其他措施来帮助消除非法芯片转移。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 12:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pacific divided on Biden’s charm offensive with calls for more ‘results on the ground’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/27/pacific-divided-on-bidens-charm-offensive-with-calls-for-more-results-on-the-ground]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T01:40:39Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6183a8f1c15e11c1f57a9ca9ca3a5afa5cef16b7/0_60_5012_3006 /master/5012.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=a764c71b2161f9d336aaf9728d27569c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;美国总统乔·拜登与基里巴斯总统塔内蒂·马毛聊天，库克群岛总理马克·布朗站在他们旁边。&lt; /div>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登最近吸引太平洋国家的举措受到了该地区领导人和分析人士的广泛欢迎，而一些人则呼吁采取更多措施支持其经济，并寻求“实地成果”而不是承诺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拜登&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/25/biden-pacific-islands-aid-china&quot;>;接待了一群太平洋领导人继一年前举行过类似会议后，本周在华盛顿举行了一次峰会，此举被广泛视为旨在阻止中国在该地区日益增长的影响力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前部长卡利奥帕特·塔沃拉 (Kaliopate Tavola)斐济和该国前驻布鲁塞尔大使表示，美国“正在努力赶上其他国家”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国选择缺席太平洋地区数十年，在长期缺席之后，它将卷土重来。 。但它的回归显然是出于对抗中国的需要。”塔沃拉说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国总统承诺与国会合作，为该地区旨在减轻气候影响的项目提供 2 亿美元资金变革，刺激经济增长，打击非法捕鱼并改善公共卫生，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2023/09/25/fact-sheet-enhancing-the -us-pacific-islands-partnership/&quot;>;根据一份声明。&lt;/a>;美国还表示将与另外两个太平洋岛国库克群岛和纽埃建立外交关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/25/biden-pacific-islands-aid-china&quot;>;拜登承诺更多向太平洋岛屿提供援助，以对抗中国日益增长的影响力&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;“美国致力于确保印太地区自由、开放、繁荣和安全，”拜登&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国列出了一系列“加强”太平洋参与的重点领域，包括贸易关系和经济发展以及应对气候变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“许诺了很多。 [我们]需要看到实地成果，”塔沃拉在谈到加强“民间”关系的承诺时说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;关注安全&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;确保安全在华盛顿和北京争夺该地区影响力之际，该地区的问题是谈判的另一个内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5 月，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023 /may/22/us-png-defence-security-agreement-papua-new-guinea-china-india-modi-pacific-militarization-concerns&quot;>;巴布亚新几内亚与美国签署防务和海上合作协议&lt;/a >;。巴布亚新几内亚是人口最多的太平洋岛国，其位于澳大利亚北部的位置使其具有重要的战略意义。美国协议是在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/20/the-deal-that-shocked-the-world-inside-the-china-solomons-security- pact&quot;>;中国于 2022 年与所罗门群岛签署了安全协议&lt;/a>;。所罗门群岛总理马纳西·索加瓦雷 (Manasseh Sogavare) 目前与北京密切合作，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/ sep/24/biden-pacific-summit-suffers-setback-as-solomon-islands-pm-skips-meeting&quot;>;没有参加本周的白宫会谈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;塔沃拉说“两个世界大国之间的地缘政治紧张局势使太平洋成为该地区岛国的不安全空间”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴布亚新几内亚总理詹姆斯·马拉佩呼吁美国在安全协议之外支持这个太平洋国家。马拉佩表示，回顾 2022 年第一次峰会，巴布亚新几内亚与美国“关系大为改善”，参加了最新的白宫会谈，“但这主要是从安全角度出发，我们必须在所有其他方面加强这一点”马拉佩在一份声明中表示：“我们关系的全部力量还必须体现在商业、贸易和经济等其他发展领域。”&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot; 5099c09e246f37bc3a757937061f0a4b0faf14c1&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/5099c09e246f37bc3a757937061f0a4b0faf14c1/0_48_4777_2867/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;萨摩亚总理菲亚梅·纳奥米·马塔阿法（右）和巴布亚新几内亚总理詹姆斯马拉佩周一出席美国-太平洋岛屿峰会。” width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;周一，萨摩亚总理 Fiame Naomi Mata&#39;afa（右）和巴布亚新几内亚总理 James Marape 在美国-太平洋岛屿峰会上。&lt;/span >; &lt;span>;照片：Evan Vucci/美联社&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;帕劳总统小苏兰吉尔·惠普斯 (Surangel Whipps Jr) 形容这次峰会“非同寻常”，赞扬拜登在将太平洋领导人聚集在一起解决问题方面发挥的领导作用共同面临的挑战称其为“前所未有的”。惠普斯在其办公室的一份声明中表示，这些挑战包括在新冠疫情之后重建太平洋经济体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示这次峰会是一次“重要的家庭聚会”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;库克群岛总理马克布朗还对美国与他​​的国家关系的提升表示欢迎，并表示美国与太平洋岛屿的伙伴关系可能成为帮助该地区实现其愿望的重要工具。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;对资金的担忧&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;一些太平洋地区也对资金能否到位表示担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那里有一些非常有价值的举措……有些早就应该采取了，”莫尔兹比港国家事务研究所执行主任保罗·巴克 (Paul Barker) ”，说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴克表示，该清单包括新的和正在进行的参与领域，同时警告说，它仍然“取决于国会的批准。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太平洋岛屿项目主任梅格·基恩博士澳大利亚洛伊研究所表示，尽管自去年峰会以来美国在该地区开设了新的大使馆和美国国际开发署办事处，但国会尚未批准 2022 年做出的大部分资金承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;塔沃拉表示，美国对该地区的管理和资金分配体系“不利于及时批准为太平洋地区提供足够的资金。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国的许多承诺可能会因官僚主义而被拖延和掩盖， ”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;丽贝卡·库库 (Rebecca Kuku) 是《国民报》的记者，驻巴布亚新几内亚莫尔兹比港&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/li>; &lt; /ul>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;路透社为本报告做出了贡献&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 09:52:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Senate finds breakthrough on funding as government shutdown looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/26/government-shutdown-2023-update-mccarthy]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T01:04:45Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d8cfb39018491067da164fb61edf385001d30b1b/0_200_6000_3600 /master/6000.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=5cc90c744fbaa2171539dda20a9b6406&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;美国国会大厦&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;参议院周二采取了重大举措，将政府拨款延长到年底之后本月，距离避免政府关门仅剩几天时间，政府关门可能迫使数百万联邦雇员停薪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参议院以 77 票对 19 票的投票结果提出了一项空壳法案，该法案将成为&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.appropriations.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/230926_cr_legislative_text.PDF&quot;>;权宜之计&lt;/a>;，为政府提供截至 11 月 17 日的资金，同时拨出约 60 亿美元用于乌克兰的战争努力和另外 60 亿美元用于救灾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参议院可能会在未来几天内最终批准该法案，但该提案在共和党控制的众议院获得通过的可能性很大，极右翼成员已经谴责了该法案努力向乌克兰提供额外资金。持续存在的分歧增加了国会无法在 10 月 1 日最后期限之前通过一项短期拨款法案（称为持续决议）以避免政府关门的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参议院多数党领袖、民主党人查克·舒默 (Chuck Schumer) 称赞该法案的制定是两党共同的成就，将为立法者赢得更多时间来做出长期资金决策，他敦促众议院共和党人在谈判中采取类似的方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们周末我们一起努力、勤奋地工作，我认为，我们取得了一个结果，这表明两党合作可以战胜极端主义，”舒默在投票前说道。 “这是通向合作和远离极端主义的桥梁，这将使我们能够继续努力为联邦政府提供充分资金，并使家庭免受政府关闭的痛苦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白宫新闻秘书卡琳·让-皮埃尔回应了这一信息，并在一份声明中表示：“参议院的两党持续决议将使政府保持开放，为救灾支付首付款，这是对乌克兰支持的重要表现。众议院共和党人应该与参议院一起完成他们的工作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，即使参议院在一项持续决议上取得了进展，众议院仍将注意力集中在一套单独的拨款法案上，该法案将解决长期问题政府资金需求，但不会特别有助于避免本周晚些时候的关闭。&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us -news/2023/sep/22/us-government-shutdown-kevin-mccarthy-spending-bill&quot;>;白宫计划在国会山混乱后关闭政府&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;这四项法案包括极右翼众议院议员要求的进一步削减资金，他们拒绝支持防止政府关门的权宜之计支出法案。由于众议院共和党占据微弱多数，议长凯文·麦卡锡(Kevin McCarthy)&lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>;只能在他的会议上失去少数选票，而极右翼成员则利用这一动态来推动政策让步。周二晚上，众议院共和党人以 216 比 212 的程序性投票成功推进了这四项拨款法案。这次投票标志着麦卡锡的胜利，议长誓言众议院共和党人也将很快采取行动，通过推进一项持续解决方案并附加边境安全措施来防止关闭。然而，麦卡锡会议的几位极右翼成员继续拒绝支持任何持续解决方案的想法，进一步增加了政府关门的可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管众议院共和党人成功推进了这四项法案，但他们的支出计划没有机会成为法律。该提案将在参议院被否决，占多数的民主党已全面拒绝进一步削减资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着国会僵局的持续，白宫指责共和党在参议院玩弄政治。美国人民的代价。在&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1706677624230002758&quot;>;分享给 X&lt;/a>;（以前称为 Twitter）的视频中，乔·拜登周二警告称，停摆可能会迫使美国军人因为他们仍在值班，所以没有工资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我准备尽自己的一份力量，但众议院的共和党人拒绝了。他们拒绝对抗党内的极端分子。因此，现在美国的每个人都可能被迫付出代价，”拜登说。 “为政府提供资金是国会最基本的职责之一。现在是众议院的共和党人开始做他们的工作的时候了——做美国选举他们做的工作。所以让我们完成它吧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但共和党人同时面临着来自党内领袖唐纳德·特朗普的压力，要求他们在预算谈判中坚持到底——即使这意味着面临政府关门的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周日，特朗普在其社交媒体平台 Truth Social 上分享的一篇帖子中写道：“除非你得到一切，否则就将其关闭！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;麦卡锡可能会尝试在民主党的支持下通过一项持续决议，但这样的选择将立即遭到极右翼共和党人的强烈反对，他们威胁说，如果议长选择这种两党合作的策略，他们将把他赶下台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位熟悉较为温和的众议院共和党人想法的消息人士认为，只有两党一致的提案才能最终在参众两院获得通过，批评极右翼议员寻求“烧毁这个地方”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这些人都不是认真的人，”消息人士称。 “他们认为拜登想要的任何东西都是坏的，但差距如此之小，他们的选票很重要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;马丁·彭杰利 (Martin Pengelly) 贡献了&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;报道&lt;/em>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 09:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hollywood writers agree to end five-month strike after new studio deal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/sep/26/hollywood-writers-strike-ends-studio-deal]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T00:50:30Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f0f4fd50262ae2ac450ec327b95e0b380b2969c1/0_200_4995_2997 /master/4995.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=9deeb5025a92c32cd95e5349c011dc69&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;一位留着长发、身穿粉白格子连衣裙的女子单脚跳跃，玩起粉色小提琴，另一个人在她身后的山上与好莱坞标志合影。&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;好莱坞编剧将于周三正式结束为期五个月的罢工，工会领导人批准了与运动联盟达成的协议电影和电视制片人，并将新合同的完整细节发送给工会成员以供批准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国作家协会 (WGA) 在周二晚间的一份声明中表示，其成员可以重返工作岗位今晚午夜，同时对与好莱坞电影公司签订的为期三年的新合同进行批准投票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工会领导人“一致投票决定从太平洋时间/3 上午 12:01 起解除限制令并结束罢工”美国作家协会 (WGA) 和工作室、流媒体服务和制作公司联盟的谈判代表 &lt;a href= “https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/sep/25/hollywood-writers-strike-end-wga-deal-details-negotiations&quot;>;在五个马拉松日之后于周日达成了临时协议&lt;/a>; &lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关：&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/sep/25/is-hollywood-writers -strike-over-deal-explained&quot;>;好莱坞编剧的罢工结束了吗？临时协议的解释&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;周日，WGA 称赞这项为期三年的协议是“特殊的——为会员各个领域的作家带来了有意义的收益和保护”。该协议将给予编剧&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;流媒体平台节目的剩余付款、防止使用人工智能的保护以及电视节目编剧室的最低人员配备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Themove 带来了戏剧性的效果罢工结束后，好莱坞的篇章结束了——这是该行业历史上最长的罢工之一——导致制作停顿，引发了冲击&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/jul/29 /los-angeles-actors-writers-strike-businesses-affected&quot;>;横跨洛杉矶&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2023/aug/13/already-vulnerable -uk-film-and-tv-workers-feel-the-pinch-from-us-strike&quot;>;超越&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5 月，WGA 以压倒性多数投票授权其 11,500 名会员由于与主要电影公司的谈判陷入僵局，这是 15 年来的首次罢工。作家们辩称，在在线流媒体时代，他们的工资更低，工作也更不稳定。工会还要求对电影公司使用人工智能的行为提供额外保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;编剧们在从洛杉矶到纽约的主要电影公司外的纠察线上花了数月时间，其中包括亚马逊、Netflix、派拉蒙和华纳兄弟。 after the writers began their strike, the Hollywood actors&#39; union Sag-Aftra undertook similar action in what amounted to a historic “double strike”, the first such action in over six decades.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The writers&#39; strike, which lasted 146 days, was just five days shy of becoming the longest strike in the guild&#39;s history.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The agreement with the WGA came after negotiators renewed talks following a months-long impasse. Four top industry executives – Bob Iger, the Disney CEO; David Zaslav, the Warner Bros Discovery CEO; Ted Sarandos, the Netflix co-CEO; and Donna Langley, the NBCUniversal Studio group chair took part in this week&#39;s negotiations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Late-night and daytime television are expected to return to the air quickly. But most TV and film production cannot yet resume as the actors&#39; strike is still under way, and the strikes have already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2023/jul/14/the-hollywood-actors-strike-everything-you-need-to-know&quot;>;affected the production&lt;/a>; and release schedules for the coming months.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The WGA has encouraged members to continue to support actors and to join with Sag-Aftra on its picket line. The deal could provide a path forward to resolve the actors&#39; strike, as the WGA agreement addresses concerns similar to those highlighted by Sag, including streaming residuals and AI.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;More details soon …&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 09:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US government accuses Amazon of using its power to inflate prices]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/26/amazon-ftc-price-inflation-lawsuit]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T23:32:06Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c2e27797e1ffe40fd217475aaf96adf494eb24a7/0_132_8640_5185/master/8640.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=4f82b764e6667d9dc03c753da7e3ecb5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;amazon sign on the side of a building&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and 17 state attorneys general have sued Amazon, alleging the e-commerce behemoth uses its position in the marketplace to inflate prices on other platforms, overcharge sellers and stifle competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lawsuit, filed in US district court for the western district of Washington on Tuesday, is the result of a years-long investigation into Amazon&#39;s businesses and one of the most significant legal challenges brought against the company in its nearly 30-year history.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/sep/25/amazon-invest-openai-rival-anthropic-microsoft-chat-gpt&quot;>;Amazon to invest up to $4bn in OpenAI rival Anthropic&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The FTC and states are asking the court to issue a permanent injunction that they say would prohibit Amazon from engaging in its unlawful conduct and loosen its “monopolistic control to restore competition”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The complaint sets forth detailed allegations noting how Amazon is now exploiting its monopoly power to enrich itself while raising prices and degrading service for the tens of millions of American families who shop on its platform and the hundreds of thousands of businesses that rely on Amazon to reach them,” the FTC chairperson, Lina Khan, said in a statement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lawsuit is one of the biggest legal challenges the company has faced since its inception in 1994.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it did not come as a surprise. The suit comes after years of complaints that Amazon and other tech giants abused their dominance of search, social media and online retailing to become gatekeepers on the most profitable aspects of the internet. And the US government in recent years has signaled an increasing willingness to challenge the companies&#39; hegemony.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Observers had wondered whether the FTC would seek a forced breakup of the retail giant, which is also dominant in cloud computing and has a growing presence in other sectors like groceries and healthcare. In a briefing with reporters, Khan dodged questions of whether that will happen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“At this stage, the focus is more on liability,” she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amazon said that the FTC lawsuit was wrongheaded and would hurt consumers by leading to higher prices and slower deliveries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The practices the FTC is challenging have helped to spur competition and innovation across the retail industry, and have produced greater selection, lower prices, and faster delivery speeds for Amazon customers and greater opportunity for the many businesses that sell in Amazon&#39;s store,” said David Zapolsky, Amazon&#39;s general counsel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2023/09/ftc-sues-amazon-illegally-maintaining-monopoly-power&quot;>;lawsuit&lt;/a>;, the FTC does not argue Amazon is a monopoly because of its size but because it uses its position as both an online seller and online marketplace to deny meaningful competition. Amazon, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/ftc_gov/pdf/1910129AmazoneCommerceComplaintPublic.pdf&quot;>;124-page complaint&lt;/a>; argues, is stifling competition by imposing anti-discounting measures that prohibit merchants who sell products on Amazon from offering lower prices elsewhere.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the complaint, the FTC accuses Amazon of tactics such as “anti-discounting” measures that penalize sellers offering their products for cheaper in other online marketplaces. The filing also notes that Amazon controls a vast distribution network and alleges the company forces third-party sellers to pay high fees for its fulfillment services with little other option but to comply.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Amazon has hiked so steeply the fees it charges sellers that it now reportedly takes close to half of every dollar from the typical seller that uses Amazon&#39;s fulfillment service,” the complaint states.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complaint also accuses Amazon of requiring merchants to use the company&#39;s delivery and fulfillment system in order to qualify for Prime.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The also charges that Amazon prioritize&lt;strong>;s&lt;/strong>; the company&#39;s in-house line of products over others, even if those other products are of better quality, and serve&lt;strong>;s&lt;/strong>; an increasing number of paid and junk ads.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The injunction the FTC and states are seeking would force the company to stop these practices, the agency and states say, a change that could significantly alter the ways customers interact with Amazon&#39;s platform and the types of products that surface when they are shopping.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Worth more than $1tn today, Amazon controls 82% of the online retail market, according to the complaint, making it a virtual necessity for merchants to sell their products on the platform in order to reach most online customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This market power enables Amazon to set the price floor on almost every online retail item offered by sellers, extract a 50% cut from each sale, and punish sellers who try to sell elsewhere at lower prices,” Matt Stoller, the director of research at the non-profit advocacy group the American Economics Leadership Project, said in a statement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There&#39;s no such thing as &#39;free shipping&#39; just as there&#39;s no such thing as a free lunch. Amazon is just hiding from consumers how much they have to pay,” he added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The FTC action against Amazon has been long awaited. During the Trump administration, which ended in 2021, the justice department and FTC opened investigations into Google, Facebook, Apple and Amazon.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The justice department has sued Google twice - once under Trump regarding its search business and a second time under Joe Biden over its advertising technology. The FTC sued Facebook during the Trump administration and Biden&#39;s FTC has pressed forward with the lawsuit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;News of imminent action against Amazon had been circulating for months, after a meeting between regulators and top Amazon executives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-to-meet-with-ftc-officials-ahead-of-expected-antitrust-complaint-fbb0927f&quot;>;in August&lt;/a>; failed to assuage the government&#39;s antitrust concerns.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Khan, the FTC chairwoman, has for years been clear she considered Amazon among the worst anti-trust violators. In fact, Amazon in 2021 demanded Khan recuse herself from any antitrust investigations into the e-commerce firm because of her previous criticisms of its business practices. These critiques were most notably lodged in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yalelawjournal.org/pdf/e.710.Khan.805_zuvfyyeh.pdf&quot;>;law school paper she wrote in 2017&lt;/a>;, in which she argued that Amazon was engaged in anti-competitive behavior despite the low prices found on the platform.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Khan was also on the staff of the House committee that wrote a report issued in 2020 that advocated reining in four tech giants: Amazon, Apple, Google and Facebook.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after she became chair of the FTC, in 2021, she sued the company, accusing it of using “manipulative, coercive” methods to trick people into recurring subscriptions – a claim Amazon has denied.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Feminist approach’ to cancer could save lives of 800,000 women a year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/sep/26/feminist-approach-cancer-save-lives-800000-women]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T22:30:40Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/593f2a98aa8df4597cfab24499285a3e8c6e7c5b/22_0_5655_3394/master/5655.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=a55dade22bc1f547473f716d71e8b6f1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;A woman having a mammography scan&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Health experts are calling for a “feminist approach” to cancer to eliminate inequalities, as research reveals 800,000 women worldwide are dying needlessly every year because they are denied optimal care.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cancer is one of the biggest killers of women and ranks in their top three causes of premature deaths in almost every country on every continent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But gender inequality and discrimination are reducing women&#39;s opportunities to avoid cancer risks and impeding their ability to get a timely diagnosis and quality care, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/commission/womenpowerandcancer&quot;>;a report published in the Lancet&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The largest report of its kind, which studied women and cancer in 185 countries, found unequal power dynamics across society globally were having “resounding negative impacts” on how women experience cancer prevention and treatment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was particular focus on “women&#39;s cancers” – including breast and cervical – despite lung and colorectal cancer being among the top three causes of deaths from the disease, researchers said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gender inequalities are also hindering women&#39;s professional advancement as leaders in cancer research, practice and policymaking, which in turn perpetuates the lack of women-centred cancer prevention and care, the report adds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commission brought together a multidisciplinary and diverse team from around the globe. It included experts in gender studies, human rights, law, economics, social sciences, cancer epidemiology, prevention, and treatment, as well as patient advocates, to analyse how women around the world experience cancer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is calling for a new feminist agenda for cancer care to eliminate gender inequality.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The impact of a patriarchal society on women&#39;s experiences of cancer has gone largely unrecognised,” said Dr Ophira Ginsburg, a senior adviser for clinical research at the National Cancer Institute&#39;s Centre for Global Health and a co-chair of the commission.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Globally, women&#39;s health is often focused on reproductive and maternal health, aligned with narrow anti-feminist definitions of women&#39;s value and roles in society, while cancer remains wholly underrepresented.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our commission highlights that gender inequalities significantly impact women&#39;s experiences with cancer. To address this, we need cancer to be seen as a priority issue in women&#39;s health, and call for the immediate introduction of a feminist approach to cancer.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/commission/womenpowerandcancer&quot;>;A second study published in the Lancet Global Health&lt;/a>; suggests 1.5m premature cancer deaths in women under 70 in 2020 could have been prevented with the elimination of exposures to key risk factors or via early detection and diagnosis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research analysed premature deaths from cancer among women aged 30 to 69 and found a further 800,000 lives could be saved each year if all women had access to optimal cancer care.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 1.3 million women of all ages died in 2020 due to four of the major risk factors for cancer: tobacco, alcohol, obesity, and infections. But the burden of cancer in women caused by these four risk factors is “widely underrecognised”, the report says.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, a study from 2019 found only 19% of women attending breast cancer screening in the UK were aware that alcohol is a major risk factor for breast cancer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Discussions about cancer in women often focus on &#39;women&#39;s cancers&#39;, such as breast and cervical cancer,” said Dr Isabelle Soerjomataram, a co-chair of the commission. “But about 300,000 women under 70 die each year from lung cancer, and 160,000 from colorectal cancer: two of the top three causes of cancer death among women, globally.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Furthermore, for the last few decades in many high-income countries, deaths from lung cancer in women have been higher than deaths from breast cancer. The tobacco and alcohol industry target marketing of their products specifically at women, we believe it&#39;s time for governments to counteract these actions with gender-specific policies that increase awareness and reduce exposure to these risk factors.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Greater scrutiny of the causes and risk factors for cancer in women is also needed as they are less well understood compared with cancer risk factors for men.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Of the 3 million adults diagnosed with cancer under the age of 50 in 2020, two out of three were women,” said Dr Verna Vanderpuye, a co-chair of the commission.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Cancer is a leading cause of mortality in women and many die in their prime of life, leaving behind an estimated 1 million children in 2020 alone. There are important factors specific to women which contribute to this substantial global burden – by addressing these through a feminist approach we believe this will reduce the impact of cancer for all.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To counter the negative impact of gender inequality and transform the ways women interact with the cancer health system, the commission argues for sex and gender to be included in all cancer-related policies and guidelines.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It also calls for strategies targeted at increasing women&#39;s awareness of cancer risk factors and symptoms, along with increasing equitable access to early detection, diagnosis and treatment of cancer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writing in a linked comment, Dr Monica Bertagnolli, the director of the National Cancer Institute, who was not involved in the commission, said the recommendations must be acted on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Achieving gender equality in the context of cancer research and care will require broad implementation of the recommendations in the Lancet Commission on women, power, and cancer, including the overarching priority action that sex and gender be included in all cancer-related policies and guidelines so that they are responsive to the needs and aspirations of women in all of their diversities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is something that we can and should all support. Improved outcomes for women translate into benefits for households, communities, societies, and the world.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nagorno-Karabakh: almost a quarter of the region’s population flees into Armenia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/27/nagorno-karabakh-azerbaijan-conflict-quarter-region-population-flee-into-armenia]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T23:59:27Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4f839ed0f44d1a339645f0ca767406f4f472d891/0_253_4336_2602/master/4336.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=f7034deed9b5ea376e95e0f7260ce329&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Ethnic Armenians from Nagorno-Karabakh ride a truck on their way out of the region. &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Almost a quarter of Nagorno-Karabakh&#39;s population have fled into Armenia since Azerbaijan launched an attack on the breakaway region last week, according to Armenia&#39;s government.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some 28,000 people – about 23% of the region&#39;s population – scrambled to flee as soon as Azerbaijan lifted a 10-month blockade on the region&#39;s only road to Armenia.这次封锁导致食品、药品和燃料严重短缺。 While Azerbaijan has pledged to respect the rights of Armenians, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/24/fear-rises-food-runs-short-karabakh-azerbaijan&quot;>;many residents feared reprisals&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The updated figures came as the death toll from an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/26/nagorno-karabakh-blast-fuel-depot-armenia-azerbaijan&quot;>;explosion at a fuel depot in Nagorno-Karabakh&lt;/a>; rose to 68, with a further 105 people missing and nearly 300 injured, the office of Karabakh&#39;s ombudsman said.&lt;/p>; &lt;aside>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Related: &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/25/nagorno-karabakh-families-anguish-forced-to-flee-homes-azerbaijan&quot;>;&#39;I will never go back&#39;: death stalks the exodus from Nagorno-Karabakh&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/aside>; &lt;p>;The explosion took place as people lined up to fill their cars at a gas station outside Stepanakert, the region&#39;s capital, late Monday. The cause of the blast remains unclear, but Nagorno-Karabakh presidential aide David Babayan said initial information suggested that it resulted from negligence, adding that sabotage was unlikely.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Armenian authorities also said that they brought 125 bodies over to Armenia from Nagorno-Karabakh for identification. The country&#39;s Health Ministry clarified that all of those were killed in the fighting last week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Azerbaijani presidential aide Hikmet Hajiyev said on X, formerly Twitter, that hospitals in Azerbaijan were ready to treat victims, but did not say if any had been taken there.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;f33fafd6e0152be0a74cc64729de249aa63319dd&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/f33fafd6e0152be0a74cc64729de249aa63319dd/0_0_5000_3218/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A satellite image shows a long traffic jam of vehicles along the Lachin corridor as ethnic Armenians flee from the Nagorno-Karabakh region.&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;644&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;A satellite image shows a long traffic jam of vehicles along the Lachin corridor as ethnic Armenians flee from the Nagorno-Karabakh region.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Maxar Technologies/Reuters&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;Azerbaijan also said Tuesday that 30 metric tons of gasoline and 34 metric tons of diesel fuel were being sent into the region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;US secretary of state Antony Blinken urged Azerbaijan&#39;s president, Ilham Aliyev, to refrain from further hostilities in the region, to provide assurances to its residents and to allow access to an international observer mission.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;US national security council spokesperson Adrienne Watson said the US would provide additional assistance to help local communities “provide shelter and essential supplies – such as hygiene kits, blankets, and clothing – to address the needs of those affected or displaced by violence in Nagorno-Karabakh.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Azerbaijani military &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/19/azerbaijan-launches-anti-terrorist-campaign-in-disputed-nagorno-karabakh-region&quot;>;routed Armenian forces in a 24-hour blitz last week&lt;/a>;, forcing the separatist authorities to agree to lay down weapons and start talks on Nagorno-Karabakh&#39;s “reintegration” into Azerbaijan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fuel has been in short supply in Stepanakert for months, and the depot explosion further added to the shortages, compounding anxiety among many residents about whether they would be able to drive the 35 kilometres to the border.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Tuesday, cars bearing large loads on their roofs crowded the streets of Stepanakert, and residents stood or lay along sidewalks next to heaps of luggage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nagorno-Karabakh authorities asked residents to hold off on leaving in order to keep the road clear for emergency services and said buses would be provided for those who want to leave.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I think we&#39;re going to see the vast majority of people in Karabakh leaving for Armenia,” said Thomas de Waal, a senior fellow at the Carnegie Europe thinktank. “他们被告知要融入阿塞拜疆这个他们从未参与过的国家，他们中的大多数人甚至不会说阿塞拜疆语言，并被告知要解散当地机构。 That&#39;s an offer that most people in Karabakh will not accept.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nagorno-Karabakh was an autonomous region within Azerbaijan under the Soviet Union. The region came under the control of ethnic Armenian forces, backed by the Armenian military, after a six-year separatist war that ended in 1994.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another war in 2020, Azerbaijan took parts of Nagorno-Karabakh and completely reclaimed surrounding territory that it lost earlier.根据2020年结束战斗的停战协议，俄罗斯向该地区部署了约2000人的维和部队。 Russia&#39;s influence in the region has waned amid its war in Ukraine, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/25/nagorno-karabakh-refugees-pour-into-armenia-after-military-offensive-azerbaijan&quot;>;emboldening Azerbaijan and its main ally, Turkey&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;The Associated Press and Reuters contributed to this report&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[More than 100 people killed after fire breaks out at Iraq wedding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/27/iraq-wedding-fire-hamdaniya-nineveh-provice-at-least-100-people-killed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T23:56:09Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ae5a6b8fb213ea9003a8770866051b9f83691573/0_232_3500_2100/master/3500.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=0549f65a82ae461d3fd9febf1bb2b22b&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Soldiers and emergency responders gather around ambulances carrying wounded people after a fire at a wedding in Iraq.&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;More than 100 people have been killed and 150 people injured in a fire at a wedding celebration in the district of Hamdaniya in Iraq&#39;s Nineveh province, Iraqi state media have reported.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nineveh Deputy Governor Hasan al-Allaq told Reuters that 113 people had been confirmed dead, with state media putting the death toll at least 100, with 150 injured.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fire ripped through a large events hall in the north-eastern region after fireworks were lit during the celebration, state media said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Video from a Reuters correspondent at the site showed firefighters clambering over the charred wreckage of the building in search of survivors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Preliminary information indicated that the building was made of highly flammable construction materials, contributing to its rapid collapse, state media said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ambulances and medical crews were dispatched to the site by federal Iraqi authorities and authorities in Iraq&#39;s semi-autonomous Kurdistan region, according to official statements.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eyewitnesses at the site said the building caught fire at about 10:45pm local time and that hundreds of people were in attendance at the time of the incident.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;This is a breaking news story, please check back for updates&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:22:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump committed fraud as he built his real estate empire, New York judge rules]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/26/trump-liable-fraud-new-york]]><description>&lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T20:53:13Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/96cea14fce46fe4f060762c60b3dd13b3fb06d67/0_302_5268_3161/master/5268.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=03833535edf99bae0666ff095e2b89b9&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;Trump at microphone outside&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A New York judge has ruled that Donald Trump committed fraud for years while building the real estate empire that catapulted him to fame and the White House.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judge Arthur Engoron, ruling Tuesday in a civil lawsuit brought by Letitia James, New York&#39;s attorney general, found that the former US president and his company deceived banks, insurers and others by massively overvaluing his assets and exaggerating his net worth on paperwork.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision, which comes days before the start of a non-jury trial, is the strongest repudiation yet of Trump&#39;s carefully coiffed image as a wealthy and shrewd real estate mogul turned political powerhouse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;James sued Trump in September 2022, accusing him and the Trump Organization of lying for a decade about asset values and his net worth to get better terms on bank loans and insurance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has said Trump inflated his net worth by as much as $2.23bn, and by one measure as much as $3.6bn, on annual financial statements given to banks and insurers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attorney general has said assets whose values were inflated include Trump&#39;s Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida, his penthouse apartment in Manhattan&#39;s Trump Tower, and various office buildings and golf courses.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;More details soon…&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 05:22:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Key details behind Nord Stream pipeline blasts revealed by scientists]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/sep/26/nord-stream-pipeline-blasts-key-details-revealed-by-scientists]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T20:24:45Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/090cd2c05def3235285e69c201f3c03fbdf44add/0_0_6095_3658/master/6095.jpg?w=600&amp;fit=bounds&amp;sig-ignores-params=true&amp;s=6cdc1ec9ecec1fc59229cfe7575d5c76&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;One of four gas leaks at one of the damaged Nord Stream gas pipelines in the Baltic Sea, seen through the window of a Danish aircraft in September 2022&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Scientists investigating the attack on the Nord Stream pipelines have revealed key new details of explosions linked to the event, which remains unsolved on its first anniversary.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers in Norway shared with the Guardian seismic evidence of the four explosions, becoming the first national body to publicly confirm the second two detonations, as well as revealing a detailed timeline of events.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recently discovered additional explosions took place in an area north-east of the Danish Baltic island of Bornholm about seven seconds and 16 seconds after the two previously known detonations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using information from seismic stations in northern Europe and Germany, including the Swedish National Seismic Network and Danish stations on Bornholm, seismologists deployed advanced analysis techniques to observe and pinpoint the blasts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seismologists at Norsar, Norway&#39;s national data centre for the comprehensive nuclear test ban treaty (CTBT), told the Guardian they had so far found a total of four explosions – one south-east of Bornholm and three north-east of the island.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two clear seismic events, named Event S and Event N, were identified on 26 September 2022, soon after the attack. The first, on Nord Stream 2, occurred at 02:03:24 (UTC+2), and the second, on Nord Stream 1, at 19:03:50 (UTC+2).&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;bfe9aac01c098fad6456654f1ffe4c9c34887cf0&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/bfe9aac01c098fad6456654f1ffe4c9c34887cf0/0_0_2800_1680/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The gas leak at the Nord Stream 2 gas pipeline off the Danish Baltic island of Bornholm, south of Dueodde&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;The gas leak at the Nord Stream 2 pipeline off the Danish Baltic island of Bornholm, south of Dueodde.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Danish Defence/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;Norsar said there could potentially be further explosions buried in the data.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The explosions made holes in both Nord Stream 1 pipelines and one of the Nord Stream 2 pipelines. By November last year, Swedish investigators had confirmed that the breaches were caused by man-made explosives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investigations are continuing, but officials quoted in the US and German press have said the evidence points towards a Ukrainian-backed group, or a pro-Ukrainian group operating without the knowledge of the leadership in Kyiv.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;German investigators have focused on a 51ft rental yacht called the Andromeda, which was hired by a mysterious crew of five men and one woman, at least some of whom were travelling on false passports.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/investigating-the-attack-on-nord-stream-all-the-clues-point-toward-kyiv-a-124838c7-992a-4d0e-9894-942d4a665778&quot;>;Der Spiegel, which recreated the Andromeda&#39;s journey&lt;/a>;, quoted investigators as saying the evidence all pointed at Kyiv&#39;s involvement. There is debate, however, over whether a small crew of divers operating from a pleasure yacht would have been capable of carrying out the difficult, deep and slow dives necessary to place the explosives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A leaked US defence document, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2023/06/06/nord-stream-pipeline-explosion-ukraine-russia/&quot;>;reported by the Washington Post&lt;/a>;, showed the CIA had been tipped off by an allied European agency in June 2022, three months before the attack, that six members of Ukraine&#39;s special operations forces were going to rent a boat and use a submersible vehicle to dive to the seabed using oxygen and helium for breathing, in order to sabotage the pipeline. But the leaked US document said the planned operation had been put on hold.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other reports in the Scandinavian media have pointed to a cluster of Russian ships, with their identifying transponders turned off, in the vicinity of the blast sites in the days before the explosions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Nord Stream pipelines are operated by two companies, Nord Stream AG and Nord Stream 2 AG, both majority-owned by the Russian state energy company Gazprom. Nord Stream 1 and 2 are both twin pipelines, and together they bring up to 110bn cubic metres of gas annually from Russia to Germany.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nord Stream 1 went into operation in 2012. Nord Stream 2 was completed in September 2021 but has never transported any gas. From the outset it was mired in controversy in the face of adamant opposition from German allies, in particular the US and Poland, who both believed the Germans were making themselves and much of the rest of Europe hostage to Russian energy supplies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The US made clear that bilateral relations would be badly affected if Nord Stream 2 went into operation. Once the full-scale invasion of Ukraine began, all talk of opening the pipeline was shelved.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;a41926892d999cb5fd1e5bf45d92a778708083d4&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/a41926892d999cb5fd1e5bf45d92a778708083d4/0_364_5472_3283/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ben Dando&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;Ben Dando, head of the department of test ban treaty verification at Norsar, an independent research foundation specialising in seismology and seismic monitoring.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Fredrik Naumann/Felix Features&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;The newly discovered events, named NB and NC, took place about seven seconds and 16 seconds after the event previously known as Event N, which they now refer to as NA.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investigations by Denmark, Sweden and Germany are understood to be planned for publication in a joint study with Norsar. Authorities for all three countries declined to comment on the investigations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the UN security council heard investigators had found traces of undersea explosives in samples from a yacht, but that they were unable to reliably establish the identity or motives of those involved or whether it was the work of a specific country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using information from a number of seismic stations in northern Europe and Germany, including the Swedish National Seismic Network and the Danish stations on Bornholm, seismologists used advanced analysis techniques to observe the additional two explosions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to their calculations, the second and third explosions (NA and NB) were 220 metres apart from each other (with the third west of the second) and the fourth was several kilometres south-west of the second.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;4d583b0a766e0ac01e49f4933a6f285e2e7c1072&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/4d583b0a766e0ac01e49f4933a6f285e2e7c1072/0_124_3500_2100/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pipes at the landfall facilities of the Nord Stream 1 gas pipeline in Lubmin, Germany, in 2022&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;Pipes at the landfall facilities of the Nord Stream 1 gas pipeline in Lubmin, Germany, in 2022.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Hannibal Hanschke/Reuters&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;Andreas Köhler, a senior seismologist at Norsar, said the distance between NA and NB “fit very well with the distance between both pipelines of Nord Stream 1 at the westernmost gas plume location northeast of Bornholm.” Nord Stream 1 and Nord Stream 2 both have two pipelines each.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The location of the final explosion, however, is less clear because there are less station observations. “This best fits an explosion on the Nord Stream 1 pipeline, but we cannot exclude a location at Nord Stream 2,” said Kohler.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysis of the source mechanism from the signals showed they were generated by explosive devices.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based in Kjeller, near Oslo, Norsar monitors events across the world including nuclear testing in North Korea, the impact of CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; storage on the Norwegian continental shelf and conflict zones such as Ukraine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes 10 minutes for shock waves to reach them after a nuclear test in North Korea, with location accuracy of 150-200 metres, leading to the claim that it is “10 minutes from Kjeller to North Korea”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The war in Ukraine has marked a significant breakthrough for Norsar in terms of the potential use of seismology in conflict monitoring. “The technology that is used to find explosions the other side of the globe can also find explosions closer to home,” said its chief executive, Anne Strømmen Lycke.&lt;/p>; &lt;figure data-media-id=&quot;e6ece08416c38910f822d4cd79ddf8a8c112e3fa&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/e6ece08416c38910f822d4cd79ddf8a8c112e3fa/0_272_5029_3018/1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anne Strømmen Lycke, the CEO of Norsar&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;>; &lt;figcaption>; &lt;span>;Anne Strømmen Lycke, the CEO of Norsar.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Photograph: Fredrik Naumann/Felix Features&lt;/span>; &lt;/figcaption>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;It started monitoring Ukraine for the Civil Radiation Authority due to concerns of radioactive landfall over Norway after the 1986 Chernobyl disaster. It monitors bombing around the power plant on a continuing basis and has been able to contribute evidence to the UN truth commission.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June, its scientists were able to confirm the time and location of reports of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jun/09/seismic-data-adds-evidence-ukraine-kakhovka-dam-blown-up&quot;>;two explosions at the Kakhovka dam&lt;/a>; using data from seismic stations in Romania and Ukraine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It&#39;s amazing, the accuracy of the observation and the use of it. The UN truth commission for Ukraine has contacted us to ask us to verify some events, among them the Kakhovka dam, so they are interested in having these cold data as basis for their considerations.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Norsar is also investigating whether its technology could be used in the future to monitor ceasefires.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We know that we could see, based on frequency content and signal difference, between different helicopter types and likely also different weaponry types,” Strømmen Lycke said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“And that could be something to verify and then you could actually monitor and trace after unravelling who did what. I suppose that is why the UN truth commission is interested in these things.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:52:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>