<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[How Digital Technologies Could Boost Tiny Retailers in Developing Countries]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/how-digital-technologies-could-boost-tiny-retailers-in-developing-countries]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_03_1479691508.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;master1305/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span >;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;微型零售商对于发展中国家的经济和消费品公司至关重要。但他们的全部潜力尚未得到充分发挥。数字技术的采用可能有助于改变这一现状。但要做到这一点，必须克服障碍。三种策略可以解决这些问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-digital-technologies-could-boost -tiny-retailers-in-development-countries?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-digital-technologies-could-boost-tiny-retailers- in-development-countries?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;通常为当地社区不到 100 个家庭提供服务的独立经营的微型零售商占据了发展中国家零售业务的大部分。例如，在拉丁美洲，这些“纳米商店”约占 40% 到 70% &lt;/a>; 的消费品 (CPG) 公司销售额，使其成为销量最大的渠道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，这个巨大市场的大部分潜力尚未实现，因为这些小型零售商未能采用可以提高其绩效和盈利能力的数字技术。在本文中，我们提供了三种实用策略，帮助他们利用数字技术的优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;1.使技术解决方案变得用户友好。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;可以提高微型零售商绩效标准的数字技术包括提供更高效的库存管理和支付交易以及企业资源规划 (ERP) 的移动应用程序增强记录保存和订单管理的系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，采用此类解决方案的一个障碍是，它们对于 Nanostore 所有者来说不够用户友好。研究表明，发展中国家的店主缺乏对现成管理系统使用的仪表板和数据的了解。一项由&lt;a href=&quot;https://liftlab.mit.edu/&quot;>;麻省理工学院低收入企业转型 (LIFT) 实验室&lt;/a>;（我们中的一位 Josué 负责人）进行的一项研究，研究了墨西哥的 4,000 家纳米商店2022 年秋季发现，在拥有销售点 (POS) 管理系统的 25% 左右的店主中，约 55% 更喜欢使用纸张或电子表格来跟踪和管理库存，而不是 POS 技术。在&lt;a href=&quot;https://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/152063&quot;>;对拉丁美洲研讨会的研究&lt;/a>;中，我们发现拒绝 POS 的一个可能原因是对这些知识的理解不够充分。系统及其功能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以通过使管理解决方案更易于访问来解决该问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center &quot; title=&quot;运营新时代&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率并增强弹性。&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;为了帮助实现这一目标，LIFT 实验室正在开发两项实验来分析微型零售商如何店主在为微型公司使用任何 POS/ERP 系统时做出补货决策及其行为。我们的研究着眼于系统的界面和显示。一项在线实验针对 400 名参与者。第二项研究将验证第一项研究的结果，并在墨西哥大约 500 个纳米商店中进行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目的是利用研究结果来确定如何提高技术解决方案的可及性。此外，我们正在研究如何使用嵌入在应用程序中的聊天机器人来提供清晰简洁的技术解释，从而解决阻碍微型零售商使用上述 POS/ERP 系统的知识差距。&lt;/p>; &lt; h2>;&lt;强>;2。消除财务障碍。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;电子商务彻底改变了全球零售业，但并未改变微型零售市场。错过这一波数字化转型浪潮的主要原因之一是 Nanostore 在采用电子商务平台时面临着严峻的财务障碍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanostore 在传统的实体业务中已经面临着这样的障碍。当像沃尔玛这样的大型商店下订单时，货物会首先交付，然后付款的时间要晚得多——有时会晚 60 到 120 天。这种延长的付款期极大地影响了现金转换周期（即企业销售产品并收回库存投资资金所需的天数）。大型零售商使用有利的付款条件来转移现金或投资以赚取利息并增加商店的销售额，然后再偿还供应商。这种模式的好处不可低估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此形成鲜明对比的是，根据 &lt;a href=&quot;https://dspace.mit.edu 的报告，nanostore 并没有获得大型零售商享有的至少 60 天的期限。 /handle/1721.1/130977?show=full&quot;>;我们在巴西、哥伦比亚和墨西哥进行的研究&lt;/a>;。他们必须提前向供应商付款，通常是在收到货物前两天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在电子商务市场中，Uber Eats 和 Rappi 等平台的付款要求加剧了这些处罚。访问此类平台会延长现金转换周期（即企业销售产品并收回库存投资资金所需的天数），尽管从长远来看利润可能会更高。大多数平台要求 Nanostore 支付额外的佣金并接受数字支付，这使得接收客户付款的时间增加了长达 30 天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大型消费品 (CPG) 供应商和电子商务平台可以采取第一步来消除这些障碍，审查 Nanostore 付款条款并找到减轻其惩罚的方法。例如，他们可以将付款期限延长至两周，而不是坚持预付款。我们相信，这样的变化将迫使纳米商店利用现金可用性的增加来探索数字市场，提高技术采用率，并下更多的产品订单，这将使供应商受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;3.利用它们的普遍性。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;任何电子商务商业模式的一个至关重要的组成部分是高效、及时的最后一英里交付。微型零售商在这方面享有优势：其门店无处不在。面临的挑战是如何利用这一优势，帮助微型零售商发展可行的电子商务业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全球估计有 5000 万家 nanstore。这些网点遍布发展中国家的当地社区，为在线购买提供现成的订单履行网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;LIFT 实验室正在探索利用杂货零售业务中纳米商店网络的可达性的商业模式。例如，本地商店电子商务履行概念的灵感来自于众包Uber模式。这个想法是创建一个移动应用程序，将消费者与纳米商店联系起来。当消费者通过应用程序订购时，系统会将订单分配给最近的 Nanostore，并设置价格和交货时间。考虑到可用的纳米商店数量，很可能可以找到靠近客户的商店。如果选定的 Nanostore 接受订单，则负责交付商品，通常是步行或骑自行车。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在早期开发工作之后，包括在 Nanostore 研讨会上获得有关概念的反馈，我们正在构建一个提供所需功能和用户界面的应用程序模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;让所有人受益&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这三种策略并不代表解决以下问题的灵丹妙药：阻碍新兴经济体的微型零售商获得数字化转型的好处。然而，它们表明这些障碍是可以克服的，数字化带来的盈利能力的提高和市场增长的回报可惠及整个微型零售商生态系统，包括大型消费品供应商。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/p>;分区>; &lt;/分区>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10 Pitfalls That Destroy Organizational Trust]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/10-pitfalls-that-destroy-organizational-trust]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_03_147917751.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;broken3/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span >;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;在他们的新书《快速行动并解决问题》中，Frances Frei 和 Anne Morriss 概述了帮助领导者解决问题的五项策略最困难的问题并迅速做出改变。他们的第二个战略是建立“或重建&amp;#8212;信任您的利益相关者。这意味着他们需要相信三件事：你关心他们（同理心），你有能力满足他们的需求（逻辑），并且你可以按照你所说的去做（真实性）。大多数组织至少在其中一个信任支柱上不稳定，通常出现以下情况之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href= &quot;/2023/10/10-pitfalls-that-destroy-organizational-trust?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/10-pitfalls-that-destroy -organizational-trust?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Facebook 将“快速行动，打破常规”作为非正式的公司座右铭。但领导力专家弗朗西斯·弗雷和安妮·莫里斯认为，这种信念存在严重缺陷，它阻碍了领导者打造一家伟大的公司。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;最好的领导者能够快速行动并解决问题——他们解决难题，同时使组织变得更强大。在他们的新书中&lt;/em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/move-fast-and-fix-things-the-trusted-leader-s-guide-to-solving-hard -problems/10546&quot;>;快速行动并解决问题&lt;/a>;&lt;em>;（哈佛商业评论出版社），Frei 和 Morriss 概述了帮助领导者解决最棘手问题并快速做出改变的五项策略：&lt;/em>;&lt;/p >; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;确定您真正的问题。 （请参阅&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/10-signs-your-company-is-pressive-to-change&quot;>;您的公司抵制变革的10个迹象&lt;/a>;）&lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;与利益相关者建立或重建信任。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;创造包容性的条件，让您的整个团队蓬勃发展。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;讲述一个关于您需要做出的改变的引人入胜的故事。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;带着紧迫感执行你的计划。&lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;本月，我们将发布一份与每个策略相对应的一系列摘录。在这段摘录中，弗雷和莫里斯解释说，就像个人信任一样，组织信任也依赖于真实性、同理心和逻辑的存在。但大多数组织至少在其中一个信任支柱上摇摆不定&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;。哪些因素阻碍了您组织的进步？ &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;。 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;为了信任您作为一个组织，您的利益相关者需要相信三件事：您关心他们（同理心），您有能力满足他们的需求（逻辑），并且您可以期望做你所说的事情（真实性）。就像人们失去信任一样，正在失去信任或未能建立尽可能多的信任的组织往往会在这三个维度之一上变得不稳定或摇摆不定。下面列出了我们在工作中最常见的一些信任问题，以及它们所揭示的&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/begin-with-trust&quot;>;哪些方面变得不稳定&lt;/a>;。&lt; /p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;1. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;厌恶做出选择&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这一点可以以各种方式呈现，从管理共识到努力做好组织所做的一切。温柔的提醒：虽然对冲你的赌注可能感觉更安全，但迎合最能描述为“每个人”的选民对于公司来说往往是一条风险更大的道路。你拒绝选择会增加你疲惫不堪的平庸的可能性。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：逻辑。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;2.依赖英勇的员工&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;许多商业模式都是为我们希望拥有的员工设计的，而不是为我们实际拥有的员工设计的——那些不完美的、在工作之外生活的员工。如果您的运营依赖于人们不断超越，那么请准备好更加努力地工作来找到这些神奇的生物，并以巨额报酬奖励他们。很少有组织能够真正胜任这项任务。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：逻辑。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;3.闪亮物体综合症&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;人类的大脑天生就会关注新的事物，即使旧的事物更重要。在追求新机会时缺乏意图（也称为缺乏&lt;em>;纪律&lt;/em>;）会让您的商业模式面临风险。新产品和新市场的出色冒险往往是通过模糊的投资回报率方程来证明的，这些方程夸大了收益并淡化了风险，包括从更紧急的优先事项中分心的成本。可能伴随着其他类型的神奇思维。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：逻辑。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;4.不敬业的中层管理人员&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们所说的组织“黑暗中层”的管理者往往是唯一知道公司现实与其雄心之间真正差距的人。他们知道要付出多少努力才能获胜，了解旅途中的真正危险，并且通常会在途中失去最多（而获得最少）。然而，中层管理人员并没有在重大变革的时刻发挥自己的力量，而是经常被专注于激励一线人员和获得高层支持的领导团队所忽视。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：同理心&lt;/em>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;5. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;与他人时间的随意关系&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;您是否将员工的时间视为您最具战略性的资产？这是我们最喜欢的领导力反思提示之一，您会听到我们一次又一次地重复它。太多的组织乐于将员工的时间浪费在各种事情上，从笨重的人力资源软件到强迫每个人进入办公室沉迷于怀旧的工作习惯。机会成本是不可估量的。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：同理心&lt;/em>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;6. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;坦然接受附带损害&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这是“快速行动，打破常规”的“打破常规”部分，它可以融入组织的文化中。它通常表现为对无意伤害的麻木不仁，并通过“我们尽力而为”的故事情节来证明其合理性。在涉及业务某些部分时永远不会容忍这种态度的组织（“我们尽最大努力保护我们的财务数据！”）通常希望因&lt;em>;尽力不伤害&lt;/em>;其用户和员工而获得参与奖杯。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：同理心。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;7. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“周日恐怖”的发生率很高&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;如果你的同事中有很大一部分人一想到要上班就感到一种迫在眉睫的恐惧感，那么有些事情就发生了。公司与员工的关系即使没有破裂，也会变得紧张。有时，应该归咎于不熟练（或更糟糕）的经理，但是当人们大规模经历这种预期焦虑时，就会出现需要解决的组织级别问题。 （剧透：你得到的只是你的员工能够贡献的一小部分。）信任摇摆：同理心。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;8 。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;在董事会中取悦他人&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这种模式植根于我们人类的冲动，告诉人们我们认为他们想听的话，特别是当人们所说的可以产生实质性影响时我们的组织和/或职业未来。我们这里讨论的不是欺诈或歪曲事实，而是一种温和隐瞒、捏造和构建现实的习惯。这方面的信任度往往比我们想象的要高，因为董事会往往对管理很敏感，并且通常由部分事实的优秀探测器组成。要知道他们真正想从您这里得到的是帮助公司解决问题所需的信息。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：真实性。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;9. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;错位容忍度&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;您的营销团队是否正在写出您的产品团队无法兑现的支票？业务中任何地方缺乏一致性都是一个问题，但要密切关注组织级别的脱节。我们经常看到的是战略和文化之间的差距——例如，创新战略叠加在由线条内的颜色定义的文化之上。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：真实性。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;10。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;精英管理的错觉&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;好吧，事情是这样的：你告诉自己你是一个精英管理的人，但你不断雇用、提拔和留住人才相同类型的人。如果你组织的高层人员与你的其他员工、你服务的客户或你所在社区的人口分布几乎没有相似之处，那么我们向你保证，你不是一个精英领导者。 &lt;em>;信任摇摆：真实性。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;此摘录经过轻微编辑。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 22:25:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Data-Driven Decisions Help Restaurants Stay Competitive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/how-data-driven-decisions-help-restaurants-stay-competitive]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_03_200566491-001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria- label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;德怀特·埃施利曼/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot; >; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;如今，数据对于餐厅如何创造价值变得越来越重要，无论是在需求方面（消费者如何选择就餐地点、预订、下订单和支付账单）和供应方（详细的准备和食物资源管理记录，使餐厅能够优化库存并减少浪费）。为了保持竞争力，餐厅需要改变商业决策的方式；他们需要将重点从粮食成本转向收入管理，并利用扩大规模的机会。根据他们的研究，作者提出了六种策略来指导战略和运营决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/ 10/how-data-driven-decisions-help-restaurants-stay-competitive?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-data-driven-decisions -help-restaurants-stay-competitive?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;今天的餐厅看起来与二十年前没有太大不同——前面有桌子和椅子，后面有一个厨房。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乍一看，您不会知道这个巨大的行业（几乎&lt;a href=&quot;https://restaurant.org/research-and-media/research/research -reports/state-of-the-industry/&quot;>;2022 年，仅美国的年收入就达到 9370 亿美元&lt;/a>;）正处于令人兴奋的、数据驱动的转型之中，以适应不断变化的客户期望和加剧的竞争事实上，IT 正在成为餐厅如何创造价值的一个日益重要的部分，从消费者如何选择就餐地点、预订、下订单以及如何创造价值。他们的账单是如何保留夜晚的记忆并与朋友分享。客户在旅程中的几乎每一步都会生成数据，从他们的渠道偏好和预订模式到代客泊车、销售点 (POS) 记录和反馈系统。在供应方面，详细的准备和食品资源管理记录使餐厅能够优化库存并减少浪费。总体而言，用于管理客户体验和盈利能力的有用数据量成倍增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种丰富的数据自助餐为餐厅经理提供了各种新颖的机会和商业模式，例如“幽灵厨房”（只提供送货服务的工业厨房空间）和客户数据挖掘。一家连锁餐厅的首席运营官告诉我们：“我们利用数据来取悦顾客——利用数据提供个性化菜单，并通过更好的劳动力和菜单管理来减少高峰时段的等待时间。”赶上数字化浪潮以提高客户便利性和管理运营，利用所捕获数据的潜力的机会是无限的。忽视这些机会可能会很危险。为了保持竞争力，餐厅需要改变商业决策的方式；他们需要将重点从粮食成本转向收入管理，并利用扩大规模的机会。他们怎样才能做到这一点？根据&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/poms.13809&quot;>;我们对餐厅如何利用智能技术和数据分析的研究&lt;/a>;，我们提供了六种指导战略和运营决策的战略：&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;1.利用公开的“情报”来确定在哪里开设新餐厅。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;位置是预测餐厅成败的首要因素。星巴克等大型连锁店已经使用商业智能平台，根据消费者人口统计数据、竞争对手、人口密度、收入水平、汽车交通模式、信用卡交易历史等来评估潜在的商店选址。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，餐厅可以更进一步，将来自社交媒体平台和菜单搜索请求的数据（例如，使用文本挖掘、情感分析和其他学习技术）添加到混合中，使他们能够提取消费者偏好，预测竞争对手的进入/退出，并做出决定他们下一个成功的餐厅地点。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;2.预订顾客中“精挑细选”。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;餐馆的收入管理远不如酒店和航空公司等其他服务行业发达。餐厅通常只接受预订，直到可用座位满为止。有时，他们会通过等待时间较长或不允许在线预订等方式积极阻止大型团体就餐，因为较大团体的用餐时间往往较长，而人均消费较低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，餐厅可以使用以下数据：预订平台和 POS 以获得更详细的客户洞察，并&lt;a href=&quot;https://ecommons.cornell.edu/server/api/core/bitstreams/b6ff2ca4-92b6-497b-b2ad-9a8c2651b95b/content&quot;>;更好选择他们想要在热门时段接受哪些客户&lt;/a>;。例如，他们可以选择最忠诚的客户、最具消费潜力的客户或最有可能对餐厅声誉产生积极影响的客户。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;3.智能管理顾客队列。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;所有接受直接顾客的餐厅在最繁忙的时间都会面临队列。排队可以作为餐厅质量的信号，但也会引起顾客不满。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代 POS 和队列管理系统提供有关队列长度和等待时间的汇总且更细粒度的数据，这些数据与销售情况相结合劳动力数据可以提供有关等待时间对客户和员工行为影响的独特见解。预测分析现在可以确定潜在的临界点，在该临界点上，队列的潜在积极影响将变为消极影响，并为产能和劳动力决策提供信息。基于规范分析的差异化定价可用于减少预订价格最高的客户的等待时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;4.忘记循环 (RR) 座位规则&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;餐厅里的顾客传统上是由主人根据简单的规则就座的，例如 RR 规则，其中各方被分配到区域，每个区域由一组服务员提供服务，按循环顺序提供服务，无优先级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;餐厅现在可以使用历史数据来估计顾客和员工特征对速度、支出和顾客满意度的影响，并随后设计有针对性的座位政策基于实时信息。例如，当工作量较高时，主人可以优先考虑较小的聚会规模，并将其分配给具有较高速度技能的服务员，以提高吞吐量。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/poms.13155&quot;>;对美国主要大都市的一家大型休闲连锁餐厅的分析&lt;/a>;显示，与基于服务员工作量和速度的 RR 规则可以将总销售额提高 9%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者，当顾客等待时间较长时，经理可以指派更有经验和交叉销售技能的服务员，以提高销售额和顾客满意度排队等待入座。这种做法可以创造个性化体验，同时最大限度地提高效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;5.创建动态和个性化的菜单。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;数字订购——无论是通过网站、应用程序、平板电脑还是简单的二维码——无处不在。通过数字订购，餐厅可以捕获更丰富的销售数据，例如客户级别的订单商品时间戳、菜单导航模式和实时客户行为（例如，购物篮中已有的商品）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，数字菜单为基于客户动态微细分的个性化推荐提供了巨大的潜力，类似于在线零售。例如，餐厅可以将客户数据与实时运营信息（例如，准备中的菜品）相结合，提供个性化推荐，从而提高客户满意度和厨房效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于高级数据分析和机器学习通过算法，餐厅还可以动态更新菜单以增加销量，同时减少食物浪费。例如，餐厅可以根据食材供应情况、厨房工作量和外部情况（例如天气和活动）更新其菜单包并提供折扣。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;6.有效平衡多个订单渠道&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;随着在线配送平台的日益普及，当今的餐厅需要在多种客户流之间进行平衡，例如堂食、外卖和送货上门。为了成功做到这一点，餐馆老板需要确定来自不同渠道的订单如何相互作用以及如何影响产能利用率和瓶颈（例如，厨房与座位区）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，餐馆需要能够估计在线订单以及就餐等待时间、客户体验和收入的定价。将过去的需求和服务数据与模拟模型和网络排队分析相结合，餐馆老板可以决定何时接受/拒绝客户的在线订单，以获得最大的盈利能力。根据接受的订单数量，餐馆老板还可以估算工作量，以进一步优化人员配置水平，对于连锁店，可以根据实时配送能力将送货上门订单分配到特定地点。&lt;/p>; &lt; h2>;&lt;strong>;今天的特别活动是......您&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;除了对餐厅运营决策有用之外，餐厅顾客数据和分析也正在成为其他行业的宝贵资产。正如餐馆老板发现外部数据对他们有价值一样，其他行业也正在从他们选择的餐馆中了解客户。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，这对餐馆来说应该是个好消息，但天下没有免费的午餐：如果预订、排队、餐桌分配、点餐、使用、人员配置、库存和支付管理都已经外包给外部平台，餐厅的杠杆作用可能很小。 “餐厅必须考虑数据所有权，”一位在餐厅应用领域工作的高管建议道。 “餐厅并不关心他们的数据、数据存储在哪里、谁拥有数据以及谁进行分析。”这位高管继续说道，如果他们不小心，他们可能会放弃很多价值，特别是对于“如果聚合大量数据，就能够提供分析即服务”的 POS 提供商。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;餐厅生意一直很艰难，但原因正在不断变化。明天的餐馆老板最大的担忧可能不是库存和位置等传统的不确定性，而是他们自己的数据定价是否太便宜，如何充分利用他们拥有的数据，以及他们应该问哪些问题有关其客户的数据。数字时代的最佳实践，例如“挑选”预订、管理虚拟队列以及平衡客户渠道，都与更广泛的服务行业（例如酒店和娱乐）相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 - ->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Employer-Educator Partnership That Can Fill U.S. Jobs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/the-employer-educator-partnership-that-can-fill-u-s-jobs]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_03_1213571139.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;菲利克斯·切萨雷/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt; span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;中等技能工人 &amp;#8212;那些受过四年以下大学教育但高中以上文凭的人——占美国25岁以上工人的60%以上。这些工人是保持美国经济引擎运转的生命力，但是，随着他们越来越多地进入劳动力市场，他们发现自己失业了，尽管公司有越来越多的职位需要填补。作者报告说，大部分问题源于雇主和社区学院之间的合作不足，社区学院代表雇主的利益。最大的潜在人才来源。作者为改善雇主与教育者的合作提供了切实可行的建议，他们鼓励企业带头这样做，因为他们了解工作的新要求并控制着劳动力市场上最有价值的货币——劳动力。工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/the-employer-educator-partnership-that-c​​an-fill -us-jobs?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/the-employer-educator-partnership-that-can-fill-us-jobs?language= pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;For going on a decade and a half, much has been made of the chronic shortage of workers. Month after month, US employers post millions of jobs while millions of Americans are actively seeking them — and yet those positions remain unfilled. The situation appears only to be getting worse: Workers entering the workforce find that they are unemployable; educators worry that their students lack the technical and foundational skills (problem-solving, communications) that employers seek; and companies struggle to deliver goods and services to customers in the absence of workforce-ready talent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This vicious cycle remains especially true of middle-skills workers: those with less than a four-year college education but more than a high school diploma. Workers who don&#39;t have a four-year college degree or higher constitute more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/data/tables/2021/demo/educational-attainment/cps-detailed-tables.html&quot;>;62% of US workers over the age of 25&lt;/a>;. They work in critical occupations across virtually every industry and are the life force that keeps America&#39;s economic engine humming.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So why is fixing the middle-skills gap so hard?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, in-depth and for the first time, we investigated this problem from the employer perspective. As part of our research, we partnered with the American Association of Community Colleges and surveyed presidents, deans, or provosts at 347 community colleges across the country. In parallel, we surveyed 800 business leaders. These surveys made clear to us that one factor has played a powerful role worsening the middle-skills gap: inadequate collaboration between employers and educators. In this article we&#39;ll sum up our findings, which we published last year in a report titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbs.edu/managing-the-future-of-work/Documents/research/The%20Partnership%20Imperative%2012.12.2022.pdf&quot;>;“The Partnership Imperative,”&lt;/a>; and we&#39;ll offer some suggestions for doing better.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;What&#39;s Gone Wrong&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In our research, we identified three main problems that are contributing to the middle-skills gap:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The struggle to produce workforce-ready graduates.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Eighty-four percent of the business leaders we interviewed told us that they hired from community colleges, but many seemed to feel that community colleges were not producing graduates with the right kinds of skills for today&#39;s needs. Only 26% strongly agreed, and 36% agreed, that their local community college was producing work-ready employees. The challenge of closing the middle-skills gap in America is thus not just a problem of matching supply and demand. It&#39;s also an issue of quality and the work-readiness of the students coming out of the community-college system.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Will your company adapt or be left behind?&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The Future of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Will your company adapt or be left behind? &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;Faculty at community colleges are generally under-resourced and over-burdened, and they lack direct access to employers&#39; workplaces or relationships with their opposite numbers from the private sector. Not only that, their institutions can&#39;t afford to buy the latest technology and software licenses that power employers&#39; processes. Students without access to such resources are simply not ready to become productive in the workplaces that their course of study is intended to equip them for. Just as important, the dialogue between employers and educators as to how to improve the system&#39;s performance is insufficiently frequent or candid.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;An inadequate playbook for collaboration.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;For several decades now, the pace of change in technology has outstripped the ability of educators to institute effective curricular change on their own — a trend that holds true across occupations and industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To synchronize this change so that it meets rapidly evolving needs in the workplace, employers and community colleges need work in tandem. The community-college leaders we surveyed recognized this: 98% told us that they&#39;ll need to partner with employers if they want to create programs that yield work-ready graduates. Business leaders, on the other hand, were significantly more ambivalent: Only 59% deemed such partnerships very important, and 30% considered them only somewhat important. Perhaps not surprisingly, given those numbers, only 16% of community-college leaders described themselves as very satisfied with how employers collaborated with them, and only 28% of employers described themselves as very satisfied with collaboration efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One reason for tepid collaboration is that there is no playbook for such partnerships. While much ink has been spilt on framing this problem, in our research we have found that no clear understanding exists of what such a partnership would actually look like. Everyone accepts that when it comes to talent, educators and employers need to work together to better synchronize the quality and quantity of middle skills talent — but they have developed no shared action plan for making it happen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In most cases, this means that community colleges and local employers have drifted to low-levels of equilibrium in their partnerships, settling for superficial, weak relationships, with no accountability and little impact. Most community colleges, for example, pride themselves on their business advisory groups — but many of their business partners are small businesses or retired business leaders, and the advisory services are ad-hoc and transactional.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Partnerships trapped in low expectations.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Our survey revealed that neither educators nor employers are investing the time and effort necessary to make a partnership work and improve continuously. Most community-college leaders felt that they were doing what they could to improve the situation, but they also expressed doubts about whether what they were doing was actually producing better outcomes — most notably, in the form of more work-ready students. Employers, for their part, admitted to doing far less to foster partnerships with local educators and to applying less effort in doing so.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our research across the country, we found only a handful of cases where students were graduating in decent numbers from programs to start jobs in their field of study that paid household-sustaining wages with local employers. When we studied these cases, we found an underlying pattern. Unerringly, one or more local employers were deeply engaged across a plethora of actions: influencing the curriculum, providing apprenticeships, tracking data, synchronizing the hiring calendar with the teaching calendar, training faculty members, and constantly providing access to the latest technology. Whether it was Siemens&#39; partnership with Piedmont Community College, in North Carolina; or Disney&#39;s collaboration with Valencia College, in Orlando, Florida; or the truck manufacturer PACCAR&#39;s association with East Mississippi Community College&#39;s Golden Triangle campus, the programs that offered a glimmer of hope for closing the skills gap relied on the sustained commitment of business leaders, often in senior positions, to work directly with community colleges to drive results.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s worth restating this point: All of the successful partnerships we have studied were initiated and led by employers. It stands to reason that this would be the case. Employers know the emerging requirements of work and, more important, control the most valuable currency in the labor market — jobs. During the past two decades, for example, as the nature of work has evolved so rapidly, community colleges simply haven&#39;t been able to update their curriculums at a fast enough pace to give their students the skills needed by cutting-edge companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;A Playbook for Partnership&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We can do better. America&#39;s business leaders need to recognize that just as they use best practices to manage suppliers, develop new products, and allocate resources, they now need to develop a specific, data-driven approach for partnering with community colleges, their largest potential source of talent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We know quite well what the actions are that have the most impact in closing the middle-skills gap. For educators, these include prioritizing job-placement rates over graduation rates as an outcome metric, committing to hiring targets for graduates, and creating customized programs that meet employers&#39; emerging needs. For employers, these include supporting efforts to offer English language courses to students who speak other languages, donating or leasing equipment or license software to community colleges, and committing to guaranteed work-based learning opportunities or job offers for graduates of approved programs. Unfortunately, neither group is investing time or effort in these actions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last year, in “The Partnership Imperative,” we put forth a set of more than 40 best practices that employers and educators can use to develop a close collaboration. As part of that effort, we identified three main goals and laid out strategies for achieving each.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1) Partner with each other to offer training and education that is aligned with industry needs.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strategies&lt;/strong>;: Co-create and regularly update college curriculums so that they reflect relevant technical and foundational skills based on industry needs. Co-design programs that fit with students&#39; lives and industry hiring cycles. Incorporate classroom experiences that simulate real-world settings and scenarios.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;2) Establish relationships with each other that result in the recruitment and hiring of students and graduates.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strategies&lt;/strong>;: Dedicate staff time to managing employer-college relationships. Create processes for hiring community-college students and graduates. Develop commitments for hiring and recruitment.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;3) Make supply-and-demand decisions that are informed by the latest data and trends.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strategies: &lt;/strong>;Collect and share data on the local supply of talent. Collect and share data on the local demand for talent. Build mechanisms to jointly monitor and improve the supply-and-demand for talent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these goals and strategies and practices sound simple and rooted in common sense, that&#39;s because they are. Solving America&#39;s chronic skills gap doesn&#39;t have to be as hard, expensive, or complicated as it seems to be. It will just require a mutually supportive and focused emphasis on collaboration — an effort that in many ways is led by business. Companies that rely on middle-skills workers have the most at stake in resolving the shortage of workforce-ready workers, and by investing in improving the performance of community colleges, they can strengthen their talent supply chain and ensure their ongoing competitiveness. In doing so, they can ensure better outcomes not only for themselves but also community colleges and all aspiring workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bottom line is this: We know how to fix the broken employer-educator ecosystem. It&#39;s now time to get serious about doing it.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Supporting Decarbonization Efforts in Every Link of Your Supply Chain - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SCHNEIDER ELECTRIC]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/10/supporting-decarbonization-efforts-in-every-link-of-your-supply-chain]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-0&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/SC_HBR-1024x907.jpg&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;Every day, more organizations are joining the global effort to mitigate climate change by implementing ambitious sustainability initiatives and practices.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many are embracing the framework established by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghgprotocol.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Greenhouse Gas (GHG) Protocol&lt;/a>;, a set of global standards that outlines three scopes to measure, manage, and reduce carbon emissions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While many organizations tend to focus primarily on Scope 1, upgrading their internal infrastructure and processes, and Scope 2, reducing the output from the energy they purchase and consume, some struggle to meet Scope 3, reducing emissions across their supply chain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many barriers have prevented businesses from decarbonizing, including a lack of awareness, a dearth of pragmatic tools, and limited access to resources and tools to design and execute their own effective decarbonization programs,” said Steve Wilhite, president of Schneider Electric Sustainability Business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zeigo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Zeigo&lt;/a>;, Schneider Electric&#39;s decarbonization software suite, empowers users on their path to decarbonization. The software can help guide small organizations through the process of setting goals that are credible, reliable, and appropriate for their size and maturity. These organizations can use the software to build a customized roadmap and connect to an open marketplace of solution providers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Larger companies are also finding their own paths to sustainable supply chains. Organizations in sectors including energy, manufacturing, and retail are devising innovative technology-driven solutions to address supply chain carbon emissions, including working with industry partners on programs that make it easier for suppliers to access alternative energy sources. This approach includes providing these partners with ready-made, easy-to-use software tools to reduce their carbon output and share progress with stakeholders and customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Supporting the Transition to Renewable Energy Across the Value Chain&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;With stakeholders that include raw material suppliers, drug manufacturers, wholesale distributors, pharmacies, and health care providers—all subject to high levels of regulation—the pharmaceutical supply chain is incredibly complex.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To simplify decarbonization efforts among their suppliers, major pharmaceutical corporations, including AstraZeneca, Novartis, and GSK, created &lt;a href=&quot;https://perspectives.se.com/supply-chain-decarbonization/energize-program-announces-first-year-progress-including-formation-of-ppa-buyers-cohort-for-climate-action&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Energize&lt;/a>;, an initiative Schneider Electric manages, to help suppliers overcome financial and operational barriers to decarbonization by aggregating purchases of renewable energy. This Power Purchase Agreement strategy streamlines the energy-buying process and enables smaller suppliers to take advantage of economies of scale. These programs help organizations initiate further access to renewable energy and create additional value from this shared aggregation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Energize provides suppliers with access to Zeigo Hub, a user-friendly platform with built-in workflows and processes to help suppliers procure, track, and measure their renewable energy supplies and emissions. In addition, the program delivers critical training and education on relevant sustainable practices. More than 350 pharmaceutical supplier companies have joined the program, translating into 22.1 terawatt hours of electricity demand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Reducing Emissions Across the Energy Industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Across multiple industries, the emergence of digital products has helped drive the renewable energy transition. But the semiconductor manufacturing sector requires more resource-intensive processes than most, and its growing carbon footprint ironically offsets the key role semiconductors play in enabling clean-energy technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intel and Applied Materials, in partnership with Schneider Electric, recently created &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.se.com/ww/en/about-us/newsroom/news/press-releases/schneider-electric-partners-with-intel-and-applied-materials-to-help-decarbonize-the-semiconductor-value-chain-with-new-catalyze-program-64ae3205a5de19549d01ca0c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Catalyze&lt;/a>;, the first program of its kind for the semiconductor industry, to help suppliers in the sector source clean power and engage in other decarbonization initiatives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar supply-chain cohorts were born out of other Schneider initiatives, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.zeigo.com/energize&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Energize&lt;/a>; program, in the pharmaceutical value chain. Using a digital application, suppliers can easily learn about options to reduce emissions, choose the approach most appropriate for their company&#39;s size and maturity, and create step-by-step plans to achieve their goals. The platform also provides clear real-time visibility into individual and collective progress toward goals and can analyze real-time data to help users estimate the amount and rate of future emissions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other energy companies are taking significant steps to cut emissions in their supply chain. With its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.se.com/ww/en/about-us/sustainability/zero-carbon-project.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Zero Carbon Project&lt;/a>;, Schneider Electric provides both Zeigo Hub and Zeigo Activate from the software suite to help suppliers measure their carbon emissions and use the information to identify and implement the most effective strategies to reduce them.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;As the company&#39;s top suppliers account for 70% of its upstream carbon emissions, the program will help Schneider Electric achieve its ambitious goal of cutting overall emissions in half by 2025.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Supply Chain Decarbonization Solutions Are Here&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The distributed and fragmented nature of supply chains poses significant barriers to efficient decarbonization projects. But with new models providing a path toward achieving decarbonization across the global value chain, digital technologies are critical for providing suppliers with the tools and resources to establish and maintain their own carbon emissions initiatives, as well as collecting and analyzing data that can keep them on track toward achieving their decarbonization goals.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climate change is accelerating, so efforts to decarbonize the supply chain must accelerate as well. By applying these innovative strategies and solutions, businesses across a range of industries can support a healthier environment now and in the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;See how &lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N1433633.130212HARVARDBUSINESSON/B29804068.376432375;dc_trk_aid=567361859;dc_trk_cid=199225123;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc_tdv=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Zeigo by Schneider Electric&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>; can help your organization promote decarbonization across your supply chain.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 03:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Create Smart Business Buying Efficiencies With Integrations - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM AMAZON BUSINESS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/10/create-smart-business-buying-efficiencies-with-integrations]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;figure>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-365237&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/AB-LIfestyle.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;For decades, many businesses ordered office supplies through paper catalogs or at brick-and-mortar stores. As more and more business processes have gone digital, so has business buying.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Procurement is a critical business function at every organization, helping to ensure spend stays in line with budgets and business priorities, ensuring the organization purchases the right products and services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Corralling spend coming from multiple vendors can bring challenges, like hindering visibility into and control over spending. Multistep workflows, manual reporting, and redundant or disparate systems can cause processing delays and costly inefficiencies. All of which can impede an organization&#39;s ability to operate and compete effectively.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;E-procurement system integrations automate procurement decisions and can provide seamless workflows to speed up and streamline recurring processes. They can reduce or eliminate the back-and-forth of many legacy procurement practices that required employees to manually submit items for approval, search for and order each item (or wait for someone else to order it), and then eventually fill out an expense report to get reimbursed—a long and often frustrating experience for both employees and procurement teams.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Connecting e-procurement systems to a centralized source of supply within a familiar consumer-friendly interface simplifies comparison-shopping and decision-making, leading to more time and cost savings. Greater transparency into transactions, data across teams, and more accurate reporting can also support insights that strengthen business strategy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I often hear from procurement teams about how closely they work with finance and IT leaders on shared strategy and their need to streamline data,” said Satya Mishra, Amazon Business Director of Product Management. “Integrations can be the throughline that brings your colleagues together to talk about who&#39;s ultimately owning spend activity beyond budget lines to meet your enterprise goals.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Procurement for a Growing and Distributed Workforce&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;At msg group, a Germany-based company that provides systems integrations consulting, leaders saw a need to refine their internal purchasing processes as their workforce became more geographically distributed. Routing employees&#39; office supply needs through the procurement team became cumbersome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By integrating its e-procurement system with Amazon Business, msg systems automated purchasing workflows and spend policies. Employees can browse and purchase products, and msg&#39;s procurement team gained greater visibility into transactions before processing, enabling them to better monitor spending and budgets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tapping integrations, specifically Amazon Business&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.amazon.com/en/find-solutions/punchout?ref=b2b_cm_3p_o_t_us_HBR_Q4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Punchout&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.amazon.com/en/find-solutions/integrated-search?ref=b2b_cm_3p_o_t_us_HBR_Q4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Integrated Search&lt;/a>;, cut the average purchasing time at msg group in half, helping to lower process costs. In addition, teams spend less time comparing products and can cut costs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Choose your own purchasing journey&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;E-procurement integrations can allow leaders to customize the flow of their buyers between systems to create their preferred buying journey. If business buyers are accustomed to going to a retail website before a procurement tool, they can build a connected experience that creates that sequence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Township High School District 214 in Illinois chose to initiate its buying experience on the Amazon Business store for its business buyers with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.amazon.com/en/find-solutions/punch-in?ref=b2b_cm_3p_o_t_us_HBR_Q4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Punch-in integration&lt;/a>;. After starting their integrated buying journeys in the Amazon Business store, users can punch into their e-procurement system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school reduced the steps for purchasing and provided a streamlined buying experience. In addition, the integration helps the district maintain rigorous compliance policies for public school systems.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Integrations also allow procurement teams to maintain control over purchasing by guiding employees to preferred products and brands and setting spend limits. Beyond budget considerations, these guardrails can also help organizations support supplier diversity and sustainability goals.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level up &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;security for your buyers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Integrations can facilitate procurement at organizations of any size in any industry. For some, one out-of-the-box integration may be sufficient and can even be self-serviced. Others may prefer to build a custom integrating buying journey based on specific business needs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.amazon.com/en/find-solutions/manage-purchasing/single-sign-on-sso?ref=b2b_cm_3p_o_t_us_HBR_Q4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;Single Sign-on&lt;/a>; (SSO) integrations, IT teams can centrally enable and disable buyer access and maintain a secure and often one-click login experience to the Amazon Business store, just like other common SSO-integrated business tools. This can ease onboarding of staff, removing the manual process of inviting users to create logins as well as automatically blocking access if a team member leaves an organization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SSO can be stacked on more integrations, creating a connected experience with the systems that matter most to your stakeholders&#39; operations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Unify your tools and teams&lt;br>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;br>; In today&#39;s fast-moving business environment, breaking down silos among teams and tools is key to quickly gathering insights. Business buying is very much a part of digital transformation. Upgrading e-procurement processes with integrations can help your organization increase efficiency, lower costs, and gain a competitive edge.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Contact Amazon Business to &lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://business.amazon.com/en/contact-us?ref=b2b_cm_3p_o_t_us_HBR_Q4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;build your integrated smart business buying journey&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:55:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Operations in an Era of Radical Uncertainty]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/operations-in-an-era-of-radical-uncertainty]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_03_4006218.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Yaroslav Danylchenko/Stocksy&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Operations have always been foundational to competitive advantage, but the nature of this relationship is shifting: Historically, the strategic goal of operations was to achieve scale in order to create a sustainable efficiency advantage. In recent years, winners have focused more on ensuring their operations and strategies were adaptive to changing and unforeseen circumstances, with resilience driving outperformance. In the era of radical uncertainty we are now entering, the next frontier of operations will be to enable optionality, which entails an even closer integration with strategy.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/operations-in-an-era-of-radical-uncertainty?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/operations-in-an-era-of-radical-uncertainty?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Operations have always been, and remain, crucial to achieving a competitive advantage. Tim Cook, who has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2021/08/25/tim-cooks-decade-at-apple-makes-him-the-most-successful-successor-ceo-ever&quot;>;created more shareholder value&lt;/a>; than any other CEO at any other company, is an operations specialist. Indeed, he believes that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2023/04/07/apple-ceo-tim-cook-steve-jobs-expected-innovation-from-everyone.html&quot;>;being innovative in operations&lt;/a>; was crucial to Apple&#39;s success even when the visionary, Steve Jobs was at the company&#39;s helm.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the nature of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2023/why-ambidexterity-in-business-needs-to-evolve&quot;>;competitive advantage shifts over time&lt;/a>; — and so does the role operations plays in it. Historically, the main strategic value of operations was to create scale in order to gain a self-reinforcing &lt;em>;efficiency&lt;/em>; advantage by riding the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2013/growth-business-unit-strategy-experience-curve-bcg-classics-revisited&quot;>;experience curve&lt;/a>;. With the digital revolution, static, physical scale lost its edge: By building or leveraging digital platforms and ecosystems that connected suppliers and consumers, even small start-ups were able to attain dominant positions and high margins.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Resilience: Today&#39;s Operational Advantage&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The new source of advantage became &lt;em>;flexibility, &lt;/em>;the ability to adjust business models in tune with shifting technologies and competitive conditions. Flexibility comes in different modes: It can mean being able to rapidly scale up solutions as new opportunities present themselves. It may mean being resilient to unanticipated shocks. Resilience proved to be &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/make-resilience-your-companys-strategic-advantage&quot;>;a key source of advantage&lt;/a>; during the Covid pandemic, as evidenced by significant divergences in performance between firms. Some never regained their pre-shock performance levels, others were able to recover, but have since lost their temporary edge, and few emerged as structural winners, able to thrive sustainably in the post-shock environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364565&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/W230907_REEVES_COVID_WINNERS_360.png&quot; >; &quot; title=&quot;Many Pandemic-Era High-Performing Firms Have Lost Their Advantage.&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; height=&quot;779&quot;>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbr.org/data-visuals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;See more HBR charts in Data &amp;amp; Visuals &lt;i>;&lt;/i>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Covid not only underlined the value of resilience but revealed the work to be done both within operations teams and across the broader organization to turn it from an intuitive set of approaches applied during a crisis to make it a perennial, systematic, and repeatable capability. In the multi-crisis world we find ourselves in after the pandemic, honing and systematizing resilience capabilities will be crucial. To do this, leaders must:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;1. Adopt the right mindset.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Efficiency continues to dominate the financial management mindset — particularly as investors&#39; demand for short-term profitability has risen alongside interest rates. Investments in resilience may appear to be inefficient and have limited immediate payoffs, causing managers to undervalue them.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The New Age of Operations&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Improving efficiency and increasing resilience. &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2020/how-to-become-an-all-weather-resilient-company&quot;>;empirical analysis&lt;/a>; shows that resilience drives shareholder value: Over a 25-year timeframe, 30% of companies&#39; total shareholder returns (TSRs) were accrued during times of crisis — even though these times accounted for only 11% of the period investigated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By positioning companies to leverage crises as competitive opportunities — rather than as shocks to be temporarily defended against — resilience can drive long-term outperformance. Leaders need to think of resilience as a strategic capability that can be built by honing the ability to experiment, as well as select and scale up emerging models, and harnessing the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/we-need-imagination-now-more-than-ever&quot;>;power of imagination&lt;/a>; to proactively reinvent the firm and reshape its environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;2. Take a holistic approach.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/make-resilience-your-companys-strategic-advantage&quot;>;Building resilience&lt;/a>; includes taking actions at the operations level, for example, by creating early warning systems or setting up multiple, redundant manufacturing facilities or supply channels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But resilience also needs to be thought of beyond operations — it&#39;s a property of whole systems, not parts of systems — and firms need to take a broader approach. Measures also need to be taken beyond the company: By aligning their goals and activities with the broader business ecosystem and society, firms strengthen relationships with stakeholders that can be relied on in a crisis.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;3. Institutionalize learnings from crises.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;While many leaders are eager to move on once a crisis has passed, they should instead take time to institutionalize what they have learned.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this, we propose a &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/03/has-your-organization-acted-on-what-its-learned-in-the-pandemic?ab=hero-main-text&quot;>;three-step approach&lt;/a>;, which entails evaluating your performance (against your peers and over time); extracting the lessons (eg, which capabilities were missing, which decisions were right or wrong); and implementing necessary enhancements (eg, writing a crisis playbook, creating more flexible collaborative structures). As one CEO put it “we cannot rely on the initiative and surge capacity of a handful of individuals to create a sustainable capability of resilience.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;4. Adopt resilience measurements.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The benefits of resilience are difficult to measure with traditional business metrics, which causes leaders to make decisions that overweight short-run efficiency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To re-orient towards long-term value-creation, firms need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2020/benefits-of-corporate-vitality&quot;>;introduce new metrics&lt;/a>; that measure and incentivize flexibility and responsiveness. This includes strategic measures, which can be quantified retroactively, such as recovery rates (how quickly did the company return to pre-crisis performance levels, relative to competitors) or the share of an industry&#39;s or economy&#39;s post-shock upswing a firm captured.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as crucial are operational measures, which can help companies assess their readiness for the next shock: For example, analyzing the flexibility of capital or capacity (how much of it can be reallocated, and how quickly) or the agility of operational mobilization (eg, how quickly can back-up systems or facilities be spun up).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By systematizing and institutionalizing resilience, firms will be positioned to withstand specific, low-probability, high-impact events, and to thrive in changed circumstances by leveraging the flexibility to jump to &lt;em>;new&lt;/em>; experience curves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this is not the final frontier for operations.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Optionality: The Next Frontier of Operational Advantage &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We are now entering an era of radical uncertainty, with multiple crises unfolding simultaneously across different scales and timeframes. As a result, firms must be prepared to adapt to a very broad range of plausible future states of the world – and they must be able to do so efficiently, given recently elevated costs of capital. In other words, they must flexibly combine both efficiency and flexibility considerations to thrive in this new era.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To succeed in this context, operations must enable and create &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/radical-optionality&quot;>;radical optionality&lt;/a>;: The ability to efficiently build a &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/why-conflicting-ideas-can-make-your-strategy-stronger&quot;>;portfolio of options&lt;/a>; — each of which could be the basis for future competitive advantage — and retune and reweight them as the future manifests itself.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can firms conquer this next frontier of operations?&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;1. Expand customer interactions and insights.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;To create new options more efficiently, firms need better approaches to harnessing customer information. Each customer interaction is unique, and operations must be set up in a way that the information from it is captured and analyzed, and lessons learned are fed back into the company&#39;s exploration process. An example of this are digital tools leveraged to record, analyze, parse, and encode customer calls.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies can learn not just from their customers&#39; actions (ie, what they buy), but also from their search activity (ie, what (else) they want to buy). Datadog, a provider of a cloud-based monitoring and analytics platform, uses this approach successfully: Following an open-source model, the firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datadoghq.com/blog/community/interview-brett-langdon-node-dogapi/&quot;>;welcomes code contributions from its user community&lt;/a>;, which inform Datadog of the kinds of problems their customers need to address, inspiring its development efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;2. Monetize customer search.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Customers don&#39;t just consume — they also explore. By interacting with their customers&#39; search processes, companies can also shape their journey, exposing more of their offerings to clients. Most e-commerce platforms do this via recommendations – think of “wear it with” or “other buyers liked” tabs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another powerful approach is monetizing the customers&#39; exploration journey itself: For example, Spotify realized that the value proposition of a music streaming service would not only be the ability to instantly access songs users already know they want to listen to, but also the ability to discover new artists and albums they might enjoy. Its &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.atspotify.com/2015/11/what-made-discover-weekly-one-of-our-most-successful-feature-launches-to-date/&quot;>;“Discover Weekly”&lt;/a>; feature, a personalized playlist, uses data collected from millions of users exploring Spotify&#39;s catalogue to predict which songs an individual might find appealing. For Spotify, this creates a unique and monetizable competitive advantage that is more difficult to imitate than the breadth of its music catalogue or the reliability and sound quality of its app.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;3. Individualize offerings.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;By leveraging information from customers&#39; actions and search processes, firms can better cater to specific customers&#39; individual needs. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-04-12/indochino-hacked-suiting-now-can-it-do-the-same-for-retail&quot;>;Indochino&lt;/a>; updated the business of made-to-measure suits for the digital age. An online store allows users to design suits and shirts, choosing cut and fabrics that will be fitted to their measurements. With this model, users are offered a broad selection of products, but Indochino does not have to invest upfront into designs that will not sell — meaning that it can expand optionality in an efficient manner.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking customization a step further, companies like Roblox give their platform users the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/10/technology/roblox-stock-price.html&quot;>;tools to build the products&lt;/a>; they desire themselves. Instead of guessing which experiences will be most engaging, the platform focuses on maximizing ease of development for users, so they can realize their dream creation, as well as inspire (and be inspired by) the creations of others. This virtuous circle has helped Roblox reach enormous scale: In 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/16/how-roblox-kids-video-game-platform-became-worth-almost-30-billion.html&quot;>;more than half of US children below age of 16&lt;/a>; had played on the platform, which now boasts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1192573/daily-active-users-global-roblox/&quot;>;more than 65 million daily active users&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;4. Integrate search and execution.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Finally, firms must integrate their internal processes of search and execution in order to improve the flow of knowledge across the organization, as well enhance the speed with which new offerings are brought to market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This entails, on the one hand, feeding learnings from daily operations into the R&amp;amp;D process. An example of the power of a tight feedback loop is &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/the-slack-origin-story/&quot;>;Slack&lt;/a>;, which was originally a side project of developers working on a video game who were looking to improve communication within their team. As both users and creators of the tool, they could quickly see which features worked best and what could make the software even better. When their game failed to take off, the company realized that in Slack they had built something valuable that could help other teams be more productive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, it means embedding components of search into execution — for example, by leveraging A/B-testing to improve the design of webpages (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://netflixtechblog.com/its-all-a-bout-testing-the-netflix-experimentation-platform-4e1ca458c15&quot;>;Netflix&lt;/a>; or &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/building-a-culture-of-experimentation&quot;>;Booking.com&lt;/a>;) or by rolling out new solutions to users early to obtain feedback. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2023/05/19/a-short-history-of-chatgpt-how-we-got-to-where-we-are-today/?sh=5c3ce4e6674f&quot;>;Consider the successful launch of ChatGPT&lt;/a>;, which was made available for free not only to spark interest, but also to improve the technology based on user interactions.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;As companies navigate our era of radical uncertainty, operations will remain crucial to competitive advantage, but in a new way – by creating strategic optionality, efficiently. This means moving from a model of &lt;em>;thinking then doing &lt;/em>;to one of &lt;em>;thinking while doing&lt;/em>;: Strategizing and operationalizing will become even more intertwined, with successful strategies being continuously tuned based on operational data and new operational capabilities emerging regularly to support the strategic intent.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[4 Ways to Make Work More Meaningful]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/4-ways-to-make-work-more-meaningful]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_03_1410099860-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;master1305/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Curiosity is not just a medium by which we achieve professional success, it&amp;#8217;s also imperative to unlocking purpose and meaning at work. Curiosity about ourselves, our work, and our colleagues is the key to unlocking the significance behind our work. Adopting the mindset of curiosity with the intention of discovering purpose is made possible through four simple practices: &lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;crafting your work, making work a craft, connecting work to service, and investing in positive relationships. With these essentials in mind, we&amp;#8217;re prompted to ask the right questions and come into each work day more intentionally, carefully, and mindfully.&amp;#160;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/4-ways-to-make-work-more-meaningful?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/4-ways-to-make-work-more-meaningful?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Curiosity is critical to professional success. A curious mind will spot and solve problems&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;, while being unafraid to try something new. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;It will seek out the insights of others, and open itself to&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; expanded&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; thinking. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;A &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;curious&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; person&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; will never succumb to apathy, instead pushing consistently for growth, innovation, and improvement. Anyone seeking to build a successful career must embrace curiosity.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;>;But curiosity isn&#39;t just essential to professional advancement — it&#39;s central to crafting purpose and meaning at work. We all want to feel that our work is meaningful, and we all have an opportunity to make it so. But i&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;t takes curiosity — about ourselves, our work, and the people we work with — to unlock deeper purpose each day.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;In &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;my book, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;the &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/hbr-guide-to-crafting-your-purpose/10401&quot;>;&lt;i>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;HBR Guide to Crafting Your Purpose&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;, I outline four essential ways in which any person can better pursue professional purpose: craft your work, make work a craft, connect work to service, and invest in positive relationships. Engaging in these four simple practices makes any job more meaningful. But each of us must embrace curiosity to fully mine these practices for meaning. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;b>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Craft Your Work&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;One of the best ways to enhance the meaning you get from work is &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;through &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/what-job-crafting-looks-like&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;job crafting&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; — &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;the art of making small changes to your work life to turn the job you have into the job you want. The idea is that by making small changes to your work, you can tailor it to your unique passions, personality, and interests in a way that maximizes its meaning to you and others. My favorite example is &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/curtis-jenkins-lake-highlands-elementary-bus-driver-beloved-by-community-2019-05-24/&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Curtis Jenkins&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;, a Dallas bus driver who managed to revolutionize his position to create what reporters called a “yellow bus utopia” while changing hundreds of lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Curiosity is &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;a necessary pre-condition for job crafting. It starts with&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; a&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; self&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;-evaluation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; Ask yourself questions such as&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;w&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;hat am I good at (really)? What do I love to do? What makes me happy on the job? A thoughtful self-understanding explored deeply and with an open-mind can provide the foundation upon which job-crafting is built.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Then, apply this self-awareness to the job: &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;2&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What elements of my job could I tweak to be more meaningful for me and more impactful for others?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;2&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;2&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Can what I currently do be done differently?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;2&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;3&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Is my job, as structured, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;solving&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; the most important problems — for the organization and those we serve — in the best ways? &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;To get started on this practice, make a list of the core people you serve in your work, then list the outcomes of your job that help to serve them well. Then reflect on your current tasks and see if there are ways in which you could serve those people as well or better by doing your work differently. You may find ways in which to craft your work that are both better for them and more meaningful for you.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;b>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Make Work a Craft&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;The second way to make work more meaningful is to make it a craft. For much of history, people would often practice professions inter-generationally.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; Trades like f&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;arming, carpentry, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;and &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;cobblery might pass generation to generation in a family. And often a person would painstakingly perfect the craft over a lifetime. This quest for perfection and constant improvement created the most memorable achievements in history — from the murals of the Sistine Chapel to &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_Genome_Project&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;breakthroughs in genetics&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; and the &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/how-steve-jobs-love-of-simplicity-fueled-a-design-revolution-23868877/&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;elegant simplicity of the original Mac&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;This &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;commitment to &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;craftsmanship offers a sense of purpose in and of itself. As I explain in my book, we all gain meaning from work well done&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;.&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;There&#39;s intrinsic motivation and purpose in knowing that we&#39;ve put our best efforts into something, that we&#39;ve honed a craft in a way that challenges us.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;But how can we find opportunities for craft in our modern jobs? After all, building financial models or leading a team in a factory can feel a bit distant from &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Michelangelo&#39;s historic&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; masterworks or the genius of &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Steve &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Jobs. But craft is not about historical &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;impact&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;. It&#39;s about self-improvement and a quest to push the limits of our own performance — to take on new challenges and achieve something hard and unique. When I was an analyst at McKinsey, this looked like building beautiful Excel models with elegant formulas that could last clients years. I did this whether the partners &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;noticed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; or not because I took pride in challenging and improving myself. In your job, it&#39;s something else. Curiosity can unlock it. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Ask yourself:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;3&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What are the core elements of your job that require excellence?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;3&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;2&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What skills do you need to perform that job well?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;3&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;3&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What are one or two areas you can focus on now to make a craft, and how can you improve day-by-day until you do those things better than anyone else and to the best of your ability?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;To begin, pick one area of your work you&#39;d like to try to hone and perfect. Make this something you enjoy that is important to your job. Then assess the 5-10 ways you could make it better and begin working to improve them and challenge yourself. Keep notes each day or save old versions sequentially so you can see your improvement over time.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;b>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Connect Work to Service&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;There&#39;s almost nothing in life that improves our sense of well-being and purpose like service to others. &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/intentional-insights/201607/is-serving-others-the-key-meaning-and-purpose&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Numerous studies&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; have shown that acts of service have an immediate impact on happiness and fulfillment. And in my own life, I&#39;ve rarely felt as purposeful as when building a &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.habitat.org/&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Habitat for Humanity home&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; with colleagues, serving in a soup kitchen, or reading to kids at a local school.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Service doesn&#39;t have to be confined to volunteer work in a community, however. As I&#39;ve &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/feeling-demotivated-consider-how-your-job-helps-others&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;outlined in a previous article&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;, there are at least six opportunities to serve others in any job: clients or customers, colleagues, capital, community, partners, and people we love. Knowing this and seeking opportunities for service in each of these areas can bring meaning to work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;But identifying the people we serve and ways to serve them requires deep-seeded curiosity. Consider these questions:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;4&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Who are my clients?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;4&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What do they need?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;4&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What are the key obstacles to their well-being that I&#39;m helping to overcome in my work, and how can I do it better?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;4&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Which colleagues need my help the most?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;4&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;How can I effectively offer that with no expectation of return?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;4&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Which two or three people could I best serve today?&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;These questions, founded in curiosity, are at the heart of service to others. Pick two of the six areas you like above — colleagues and customers for example. Think of 2-3 individuals in each of those two groups you could serve better and spend the next month trying to really understand them, and ways to use your work to serve them well. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;b>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Invest in Positive Relationships&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;In social science literature, perhaps nothing is as central to happiness as meaningful positive relationships with others. Such relationships are essential to Martin Seligman&#39;s &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://positivepsychology.com/perma-model/&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;PERMA framework&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; for flourishing and the findings of the Harvard Grant Study that “&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/05/thanks-mom/309287/&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Happiness is love&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;.” And those findings are echoed in the works of many others.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Relationships aren&#39;t confined to our personal lives. Each workday we spend &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/charts/american-time-use/emp-by-ftpt-job-edu-h.htm&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;more than 8 hours&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; with work colleagues, whether remotely or in person. And trying to navigate work in the absence of meaningful relationships is a recipe for disappointment. Positive relationships at work can help us to flourish, can make others happy, and can create extraordinary corporate cultures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;At work, as at home, relationships rest on &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/mindful-anger/202003/the-secret-happy-relationship-is-empathy&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;empathy&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; and curiosity. We can&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;&#39;t&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; have a relationship of mutual care and respect with someone if we don&#39;t display a genuine curiosity for that person. Ask:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;5&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;1&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Who are they?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;5&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;2&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What matters to them?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;5&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;3&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What are their anxieties and fears, passions&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; and purpose?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;5&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;4&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;On any given day, how are they feeling?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-leveltext=&quot;&quot; data-font=&quot;Symbol&quot; data-listid=&quot;5&quot; data-list-defn-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}&quot; aria-setsize=&quot;-1&quot; data-aria-posinset=&quot;4&quot; data-aria-level=&quot;1&quot;>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;What are they interested in intellectually?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Constantly approaching others with curiosity will naturally build your own empathy and show those people you care — creating meaningful relationships in the process. When you are interacting with work colleagues over the next month or two, consciously make a game of trying to know them better. Ask more questions than you answer. And carve out time for conversations and interactions with your colleagues that don&#39;t just accomplish your work tasks but (in a professional way) enhance the relationship you have with them. Improving your work relationships will make you and those around you happier, and it will probably make you more &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;productive as&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>; well.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;>;Curiosity is undoubtedly essential to professional success, but it&#39;s also at the heart of purpose. Living with greater curiosity at work can help us to craft jobs and professional environments that help us and others flourish.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:6,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:6}&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Does Your Hybrid Strategy Need to Change?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/does-your-hybrid-strategy-need-to-change]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_02_BeatriceCaciotti.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Beatrice Caciotti&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Companies continue to struggle to design and implement a post-Covid return-to-office strategy that works for employees. To find the most workable alternative, they should focus on four factors: the needs of the work, the needs of the people, how work gets done, and the new managerial muscle required to manage a hybrid workforce.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/does-your-hybrid-strategy-need-to-change?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/does-your-hybrid-strategy-need-to-change?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;This fall, companies are once again pushing workers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/zoom-other-remote-work-champions-call-employees-back-to-the-office-e5a78c2d&quot;>;return&lt;/a>; to the office, continuing the debate over how many days employees should work together in person.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This debate continues to miss the point.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One-size-fits-all mandates can succeed only if work is a universal task executed by a homogenous workforce. Of course, we know neither is true. Instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2023/08/29/business/amazon-jobs-return-to-office/index.html&quot;>;threatening&lt;/a>; employees, CEOs should empower and enable their managers — especially those on the front line — to gain a deep and nuanced understanding of the work their teams do, the working style of their team members, and how that work best gets done. They must also consider the impact of generative AI, which will change all of these factors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our research, experience working with company leaders, and surveys of workers around the world show how considering these factors can lead to better outcomes for everyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Companies Are at a Crossroads&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We can empathize with CEOs. Leaders must justify office rents despite record-low occupancy levels and build a culture of collaboration in a place with empty halls. They are grappling with &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/09/when-quiet-quitting-is-worse-than-the-real-thing&quot;>;quiet quitting&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/lifestyle/careers/youve-heard-of-quiet-quitting-now-companies-are-quiet-cutting-ba2c326d&quot;>;quiet cutting&lt;/a>;, pressure from city governments to restore the vibrance of business districts, and the impact of generative AI.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the answer to these pressures is not return-to-office mandates that essentially use face time as a performance management tool — think badge-swipe monitoring, which has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2023/06/13/google-rto-crackdown-gets-backlash-check-my-work-not-my-badge.html&quot;>;elicited notable backlash&lt;/a>;. Monitoring the time employees spend online doesn&#39;t work, either. A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/intl/en-gb/blog/news/state-of-work-2023&quot;>;survey of 18,149 desk workers and executives conducted by Slack&lt;/a>; revealed that 32% of employees&#39; time is spent on performative work, and 63% try to keep their status active online even if they&#39;re not working at that moment.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Will your company adapt or be left behind?&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The Future of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Will your company adapt or be left behind? &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;The inclination to associate physical presence or time active online with productivity is a symptom of a broader issue, as many of today&#39;s leaders struggle to embrace ways of working that are radically different from how they grew up. They proved themselves in a culture where commuting to the office to work from 9 to 5 was the norm, and where anyone who tried to work flexibly was marginalized — such as those on the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com/advice/mommy-track-what-to-do&quot;>;mommy track&lt;/a>;.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most successful organizations will recognize that there is too much complexity to set rigid, top-down mandates, and that the managers who are at the rock face of the work, the team, and the customers are best positioned to make such decisions when they are empowered with the right skills and tools.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CEOs and executive teams who focus on the following four actions can make work &lt;em>;work better &lt;/em>;for everyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Recognize the Needs of the Work&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When we asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2023/flexible-working-models&quot;>;more than 1,500 office-based workers&lt;/a>; when they wanted to be in person, we learned that they want to come to the office to do tasks and activities they consider best done there. For instance, participants were eight times more likely to prefer being in-person for affiliation and development, compared with doing work that requires focus or tackling administrative tasks, which are better done remotely.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But where employees feel most effective doing certain types of work is only one side of the coin. We also explored how much time they spend doing these tasks. We found that individual contributors spend 37% of their time on work they believe is done most effectively in person; for managers and executives, this jumps to 49%. But this is on average across organizations. It is important for leaders to spend time investigating what those preferences look like based on the nature of work and people across their organization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It becomes even more critical to recognize which types of work are best done in different settings in the age of generative AI. When doing focus work, our survey data suggests that 65% of employees want to be remote — but some of this work can be greatly enhanced with the use of generative AI. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2023/how-people-create-and-destroy-value-with-gen-ai&quot;>;field experiment that our BCG colleagues conducted&lt;/a>; with the support of a group of academics from HBS, MIT, Wharton, and the University of Warwick found that for tasks that involve creative ideation, GenAI generates output that should be considered as a final draft (versus a first draft that humans need to take time to edit). This means that for some employees, the mix of work that they do may start to shift, as they hand over some of the focus work they would have preferred to do remotely and pick up other tasks beyond the frontier of generative AI&#39;s competence. As a result, their work models may also need to shift, depending on what these new tasks are.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Recognize the Needs of the People&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In our survey, roughly 90% of employees who identify as female, caregivers, LGBTQ+, or as having a disability consider flexible work options an important factor when deciding whether to stay in or leave their job. That is 30% higher than employees who did not identify with these categories. In other words: If you care about diversity, equity, and inclusion, you need to get your working model right.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We saw a particularly wide gap when it comes to gender: Female employees are 1.5 times more likely than their male counterparts to prioritize flexibility. And this is not just a working-mom phenomenon. We found only a marginal difference (3%) among women when comparing caregivers with non-caregivers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our biological cognitive differences also indicate preferences toward certain work environments. In some situations, groups of people doing the same job may have similar cognitive profiles. For example, a team of software engineers is more likely to be “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01098/full&quot;>;analytical/tough-minded&lt;/a>;” and therefore might work best when allowed to maintain focus and prefer to have routines in how they do their day-to-day work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But teams with high cognitive diversity will need more options to maintain optimum performance and happiness. We found outliers in our survey, for example — those who prefer to do interactive work remotely, and administrative or focus work in person. Some of their preferences are likely linked to cognitive characteristics such as introversion/extraversion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leaders struggling with how to think about getting the best out of employees with different cognitive profiles would do well to remember that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/deborahlovich/2022/03/02/its-past-time-to-treat-all-employees-like-customers/?sh=4e65e14126ff&quot;>;your people are just as diverse as your customers&lt;/a>;. Just as successful companies obsess about their customers and the decisions they make, it may be even more important for them to obsess about their employees. By doing so, they can reveal the root of the emotional and functional needs involved in making decisions about their careers — and create work environments that fulfill these needs.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Rethink How Work Gets Done&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;“Place” is just another tool for getting work done. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2023/stop-tracking-employee-attendance-start-trusting-people&quot;>;As HBS professor Tsedal Neeley has observed&lt;/a>;, “I talk about using the office as a tool, the same way we use various technologies as tools to communicate and engage. If you see the office as a tool, you determine what specific uses it has for collaborations that require people to be physically present together.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yet 62% of our survey respondents told us that they do not have a say in their work model policy. Instead, it is dictated either by company-wide guidelines or by their manager. Of all participants, 39% reported that their company decides where they work. In these companies, 24% of employees were unhappy with their work location policy; this figure decreases to 14% if the manager decides, and to 6% if the team decides. The closer to the executors of the work the policy gets set, the more satisfied employees are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2023/05/05/cisco-ceo-chuck-robbins-rebranding-office-collaboration-center-slashing-private-workspaces-coax-employees-back/?utm_source=email&amp;amp;utm_medium=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=chro-daily&amp;amp;utm_content=2023081413pm&amp;amp;tpcc=NL_Marketing&quot;>;Cisco&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.dropbox.com/topics/work-culture/the-shifting-dimensions-of-work#:~:text=At%20Dropbox%2C%20we&#39;ve%20decided,a%20daily%20basis%20post%2DCOVID.&quot;>;Dropbox&lt;/a>; are redesigning their office space to make it more amenable to collaboration. Such moves are consistent with their respective work model policies, which enable employees to do focus work remotely and encourage employees to come together for key events such as all-hands meetings. As Cisco&#39;s CEO Chuck Robbins put it, in today&#39;s world you have to offer a compelling “return on commute” to get your employees bought into coming into the office.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Redesigned work models also need to consider the ways in which we communicate. For example, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.verizon.com/about/news/verizon-study-focus-meeting-accomplish-more&quot;>;worked with Verizon&lt;/a>; to improve the way they run meetings, such as scheduling 25- or 50-minute meetings with a 5- or 10-minute lagged start time to give people breathing room. We also identified meetings that could be replaced by asynchronous modes of work (such as email, chat, shared documents, or offline review) and clarified what “required” and “optional” meant. In our experiments, 90% of participants reported overall meeting effectiveness had improved and 78% felt they wasted less time sitting in meetings where their live participation wasn&#39;t required.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leaders will also need to monitor the impact of new technologies that they introduce. The generative AI experiment mentioned above also revealed that overreliance on generative AI can lead to a loss of collective diversity of ideas. As leaders seek to benefit from the value creation opportunities of generative AI, they&#39;ll need to consider where and how people collaborate most effectively to ensure they retain their creativity and innovativeness.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Invest in Building a New Managerial Muscle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The orchestration of these factors needs to come from managers — those at the front line, working with the teams. They are closest to the needs of the work, the people, and how that work gets done.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this orchestration requires two new managerial muscles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is one that was not needed before Covid, when work was done in the office by default, nor during Covid, when remote work was predominant for many office-based professionals. Managers now need to facilitate discussions with and align their teams on where, when, and how work gets done. They need to hold weekly retrospectives on what worked, what didn&#39;t, and what to change in how they work the next week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second muscle is one that managers arguably needed before Covid, since working with distributed teams isn&#39;t new. Managers need to build their ability to create connection and culture as well as develop, inspire, mentor, and coach across distributed and hybrid teams. They must also meet employees&#39; emotional as well as functional needs. A&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2022/all-about-generative-leadership-and-its-benefits&quot;>;recent BCG survey&lt;/a>; on employee expectations about leadership at work conducted across nine countries revealed that the top four qualities characterizing great leaders are recognition, people coaching and development, empathetic listening, and care.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Building these new managerial skills requires work, but the rewards are worth it: better performance, engagement, and retention, to name but a few. And just like any muscle, it needs investment of time and practice to strengthen. However, every organization can take positive steps starting from within: Identify your best managers — the ones who are already doing some of these things. Determine the specific habits and behaviors that set them apart, then follow a “best teach the rest” approach to help others learn how to develop similar capabilities. This is beyond simple training; it is about teaching, coaching, role modeling, and rewarding new ways of working every day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short: Instead of setting top-down mandates and expecting frontline managers to enforce them, leaders ought to focus on empowering those managers to co-create ways of working with their teams that are best suited to the needs of the people and the work they do, as well as the digital and GenAI tools at their disposal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While it may be easier to follow the crowd and issue blanket return-to-office policies, the potential upside of implementing thoughtful changes based on the four categories above is not only worth it — it will soon become an imperative for businesses that want to create and sustain work and talent advantages into the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Better Ways to Support a Colleague with Breast Cancer]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/better-ways-to-support-a-colleague-with-breast-cancer]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_02_558367763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff/Willie B. Thomas/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Chances are, you&amp;#8217;ll work with a person who is diagnosed with breast cancer at some point in your career. Do you know how to best support them during one of the most challenging times of their lives? In this article, five women who have undergone treatment describe ways their colleagues did &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400&quot;>;&amp;#8212; and didn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8212; lift them up through their words and actions, both at the time of their diagnosis and beyond.&amp;#160;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/better-ways-to-support-a-colleague-with-breast-cancer?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/better-ways-to-support-a-colleague-with-breast-cancer?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;A breast cancer diagnosis is devastating and all too common. An estimated &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancer.org/facts-statistics?gclid=Cj0KCQjwuZGnBhD1ARIsACxbAVh7H6Um54-BFgIP2czF2c5kDOJyT8RyDPVyD1mvvxFixCP3b13TZ-IaAnjHEALw_wcB&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;one in eight women in the US will receive this diagnosis in their lifetime&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;, and those affected by the disease have every part of their lives touched: family, romantic relationships, friendships, their relationship with themselves, and, yes, their work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;For people in the workforce that experience this life-altering diagnosis, most choose to tell their teams — 77% of those navigating cancer tell their manager and 63% disclose to their coworkers, according to a&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancerandcareers.org/newsfeed/research/posts/2022/10/2022-the-harris-poll-cancer-an&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; 2022 Cancer and Careers Harris Poll.&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; For those that opt to share, navigating these conversations can be difficult. “It&#39;s a hard topic,” says Christy Lyons, CEO and principal at &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;4 Point Consulting&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;, an&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; on-demand HR and talent advisory firm&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;, who focuses much of her thinking on mental health at work. And while there is much to say about managing the task-related &lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/what-to-do-when-your-employee-is-diagnosed-with-cancer&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;logistics of having someone with cancer on your team&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;, there aren&#39;t many resources out there that address the&lt;/span>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/working-with-cancer-pledge-to-provide-employee-support-1849994094&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;psychological burden&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; — specifically, how we can help alleviate the mental anguish those with cancer are going through.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Cancer is difficult to discuss from &lt;/span>;&lt;em>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;any&lt;/span>;&lt;/em>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; point of view, of course, but a workplace, with its sometimes-blurry distinctions between what is “work related” and what isn&#39;t, can present especially challenging scenarios. To better understand these scenarios, we spoke with five women who have talked about their breast cancer diagnoses at work, and they&#39;ve experienced the gamut of how colleagues react. While it&#39;s a small sample size, we believe that, together, their stories show that there are better and worse ways to support a colleague through this experience, and they offer some helpful strategies to be there for someone who is facing this diagnosis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;What Not to Say&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Breast cancer patients are often deluged by well-meaning but unhelpful platitudes, especially with people they may know only casually at work. According to the Harris Poll, 21% of working adults with cancer encountered “insensitive or offensive comments regarding their cancer diagnosis.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Sabrina Elizondo, an executive producer at a mixed media production company, experienced this when, at one point in her chemo cycle, she was feeling better and posted some photos of herself at a music festival doing cartwheels. At work the following Monday, her boss commented: “&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;If you have the energy to do cartwheels, I feel like you have the energy to take on more work.” The observation felt like a gut-punch, flipping Elizondo&#39;s momentary gratitude for the ability to have a bit of fun into a dehumanization. &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;“Her indifference made me feel so much less seen and cared for as a human,” Elizondo explains.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Jamie Parcon, an accountant, points out that even comments that seem like they are coming from a place of support may have unintended painful reverberations. “I felt like one in five responses were that they knew someone else who had breast cancer,” says Parcon. Lyons says she thinks this is most people&#39;s gut reaction. “We want to relate it to our own stories,” she says. “Everybody has been touched by cancer.” But while this may seem innocuous to say, “it didn&#39;t make me feel better to know other people had to suffer,” Parcon explains.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Other knee-jerk responses like “You&#39;ll get through this!” are tempting, but they can also alienate the person wading through this treacherous experience — especially if that&#39;s &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;all &lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;you say, and it isn&#39;t followed up with meaningful support. “I got platitudes and then silence,” says Anais Masiello, an entertainment attorney. “Supportive words were easy to come by, but I was made very aware of how burdensome [my reduced capacity at work] had become, which made me feel isolated.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Vagaries like “You&#39;ll beat this” can often be unwelcome, too. Plus, promising or hinting at a full recovery isn&#39;t appropriate when you don&#39;t know all the details. “A genuine, helpful text message spoke volumes compared to a &#39;You&#39;ve got this!&#39;” says Casey Liening, a spokesperson for a municipal police department. There&#39;s also an implicit, and often unappreciated, sentiment at work here: that cancer patients are “warriors” who will vanquish the foe in their bodies. This, of course, is not how cancer treatment works, and this sentiment can actually have the opposite effect, especially when things feel particularly challenging: “It made me feel like I was weak, not strong enough,” says Elizondo.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Another pitfall to avoid: Steer clear of doling out unsolicited advice. “It&#39;s not asked for or needed,” says Liening. “When I first learned my treatment wouldn&#39;t consist of surgery, chemo, or radiation, I must have told someone at work. That started a rumor that I was choosing not to undergo any type of treatment,” she says. Colleagues sharing their thoughts on that was &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;very&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; unwelcome. Telling someone how to feel, what to do, or making assumptions about their health amid this potentially life-threatening experience is both unwanted and, in no uncertain terms, unhelpful.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;And while it&#39;s understandable to be concerned about your colleague&#39;s workload and how that might affect yours, those thoughts need to be relegated to second place. Their well-being and health must come first and foremost, not their ability to get things done. “For my coworkers who feel stress, well, I have that stress [too], &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;plus&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; chemo, chemo brain, menopausal brain, and all the worries and financial strain that come along with metastatic cancer,” says Elizondo. “I&#39;m amazed I do as well as I do, but sometimes I want to remind my bosses that I&#39;m dealing with &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;this&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; on top of everything, so they cut me a little slack. But I also don&#39;t want a pity card or a &#39;special&#39; narrative. It&#39;s a double-edged sword.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Better Ways to Support a Colleague with Breast Cancer&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;The most important thing? “Follow their lead,” says Lyons. Some people will want to open up, some won&#39;t. For some, their work life may offer a haven from the realities of living with cancer, and they may not want to talk about cancer and all that it entails — if so, honor that. (The Harris Poll found that 40% of respondents said they kept working in order to feel “as normal as possible.”)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;That said, we asked the women we spoke with to share examples from times that they actually &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;felt&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; supported at work to help guide your actions. Parcon recounts a card sent to her by a colleague. “Inside, it says &#39;I&#39;m sorry this is happening to you.&#39;” It&#39;s simple, yes, but “those words were a breath of fresh air,” she says. “It was finally empathy instead of sympathy that I was getting from everyone else.” Masiello similarly appreciated when the words felt specific, rather than generic. Genuine words of care, Masiello says, look like “Your strength is inspirational, I just wish you didn&#39;t have to be this strong,” or notes she received the mornings of her treatments that said “One more down!” “All of those small actions mean so much,” she says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Far from pedantic platitudes, that attentiveness towards your colleague&#39;s exact situation demonstrates understanding and communicates care. “One thing a coworker said to me that I&#39;ll never forget is &#39;Stage 4 is not a death sentence,&#39;” says Liening. “This one meant just a little bit more because sometimes it does feel like exactly that. Subtle reminders to stay positive were always enlightening.” While the line between these sentiments and more generic responses might not be crystalline to those who haven&#39;t experienced cancer themselves, they are orders of magnitude different. In Liening&#39;s example, the commenter both knew and remembered specific information about her diagnosis, and walked the fine line between support and toxic positivity: no effusive promises, just thoughtfulness hedged in truth and personal experience. It is worth stating, however, that not everyone &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;wants&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; positivity. Sometimes, just being the person to reiterate “This sucks” is heartening.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Parcon also liked when colleagues checked in, as it allowed her not to have to volunteer updates. Masiello&#39;s coworkers sprung into action, another concrete way to help: “Having coworkers who simply took care of things without me having to worry about it was the most helpful thing. They didn&#39;t want me to have to worry about the work on my plate around treatment or surgery days. I had coworkers fill me in on any calls or meetings I missed so I didn&#39;t feel out of the loop,” she says. “I was encouraged to take as much time as I needed, and knew that I&#39;d always have someone to help out in my absence. Coworkers stepped in preemptively, took care of things on my behalf, and checked in to see how I was doing with genuine care,” Masiello says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Lyons says this goes a long way towards creating a supportive culture — the more proactive you can be, the less burden on the person with cancer. After all, how often is “Let me know if I can do anything” met with silence? When it comes to workload and work-related tasks just &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;do&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; something, don&#39;t ask. Jessica Sidener, a library executive, said one of the most unexpectedly thoughtful things her colleagues did was assisting her with prioritizing tasks. “My colleagues kindly and clearly let me know when I was doing too much and helped me prioritize the to-dos, obligations, and responsibilities, especially when I felt too overwhelmed to navigate them on my own,” she explains. “For those tasks that did have a sense of urgency, they figured out how they could step in.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;The feeling of community can also offer solace. “The overall attitude among my colleagues was &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;we&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; will get through this versus &lt;/span>;&lt;i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;you&lt;/span>;&lt;/i>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>; will get through this,” says Sidener. Liening felt this sense of solidarity, too, when her coworkers created a fundraiser for her, and said “No one fights alone.” “That has served as the most amazing reminder of how big my support system is,” she says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;It&#39;s important to remember that the fears your colleague might be wrestling with don&#39;t necessarily have a timeframe, and therefore support shouldn&#39;t either. While your colleague may wrap up treatment, announce a remission, and seemingly recover, “there&#39;s challenges that come in the aftermath,” says Lyons. People who&#39;ve navigated cancer and are now technically “on the other side of it” will confront fears of recurrence, face years-long daily medications and their side effects as well as follow-up appointments with oncologists, may contend with a body full of scars, and potentially experience debilitating exhaustion.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Breast cancer, oftentimes, isn&#39;t quick or simple. It doesn&#39;t get tied up with a bow. People deal with after-effects for years to come. The compassion that comes from continued check-ins — “How are you feeling?” or “What is survivorship like for you?” — can be invaluable. &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;&lt;br>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;&lt;br>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Lastly, it&#39;s worth noting that following this advice isn&#39;t guaranteed protection against taking a misstep or making a comment that your colleague with cancer will find hurtful. And you may not always know when or even if one of your thoughts, comments, or actions has been received this way. But that isn&#39;t a reason to stop showing up, or to avoid your coworker — the disappearing act can be the most painful of all. Humility, a willingness to be corrected, and a continued effort to make your colleague feel cared for are your greatest assets — use them. “It really does help to be able to be open, and have [that openness] met with love,” says Masiello. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Whole Foods CEO Jason Buechel on the Challenges and Opportunities of Following a Visionary Leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/whole-foods-ceo-jason-buechel-on-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-following-a-visionary-leader]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;div js-target=&quot;video-player-page&quot; data-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;6338086375112&amp;quot;}&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;Loading... &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;In the final episode of the season, HBR editor Adi Ignatius interviews Jason Buechel, the CEO of Whole Foods. Buechel discusses the challenges of succeeding a larger-than-life executive, the role of Whole Foods as a subsidiary of Amazon, and how the company is addressing changes in the business environment, such as climate change and hybrid work. Buechel emphasizes the importance of understanding the voice of team members during a leadership transition and being authentic as a leader. He also highlights Whole Foods&amp;#8217; focus on growth opportunities for employees and its commitment to sustainability. Buechel believes that AI will fundamentally change the retail and grocery shopping experience in the next decade. The episode concludes with Buechel sharing his favorite products from Whole Foods.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/whole-foods-ceo-jason-buechel-on-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-following-a-visionary-leader?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/whole-foods-ceo-jason-buechel-on-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-following-a-visionary-leader?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Jason Buechel, the CEO of Whole Foods, faced a unique challenge when he took over from cofounder John Mackey, who had been the company&#39;s CEO for 42 years. Buechel, who became CEO in 2022, had the opportunity to work closely with Mackey for nine years and had an 11-month transition period to prepare for the role. However, stepping into the shoes of a larger-than-life executive like Mackey was not only a personal challenge but a significant adjustment for Whole Foods employees, from the C-suite to the hundreds of local stores.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buechel recognized the importance of connecting with the team members, addressing their concerns, and assuring them that the company&#39;s culture, quality standards, and core values would remain intact under his leadership. He emphasized the need for authenticity and being true to oneself while also supporting the company&#39;s vision and direction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this episode of our video series “The New World of Work”, HBR editor in chief Adi Ignatius sat down with Buechel to discuss:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;How authenticity is crucial in leadership and sustainability efforts, as companies need to ensure their actions align with their core values and mission&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;How focusing on the happiness, growth, and development of employees not only leads to higher employee retention but improves customers&#39; experience&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;While CEO roles can vary depending on the company, for Buechel the focus is primarily on internal leadership and supporting the vision and growth of the organization&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;“&lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;The New World of Work&lt;/a>;” explores how top-tier executives see the future and how their companies are trying to set themselves up for success. Each week, Ignatius talks to a top leader on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/harvard-business-review/&quot;>;LinkedIn Live&lt;/a>; — previous interviews included &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/10/microsofts-satya-nadella-on-flexible-work-the-metaverse-and-the-power-of-empathy&quot;>;Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11/indra-nooyi-former-ceo-of-pepsico-on-nurturing-talent-in-turbulent-times&quot;>;former PepsiCo CEO Indra Nooyi&lt;/a>;. He also shares an inside look at these conversations —and solicits questions for future discussions — in a newsletter just for HBR subscribers. If you&#39;re a subscriber, you can sign up &lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences?movetile=newworldofwork&quot;>;here&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New World of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Previous episodes&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The New World of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Previous episodes &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jason, welcome. Let&#39;s start with your transition to CEO. It&#39;s always interesting how a founder CEO transitions to the next generation of leadership. Talk about that challenge and what you&#39;ve tried to bring to that role.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the fortunes I had was working with John [Mackey] over the course of nine years and had about an 11-month timeframe to do our transition. It was a great opportunity for me to be able to jump into the role. I had a lot of great support from John where he really wanted me to help take on some of those responsibilities over the course of the 11 months. I was prepared when my day was to step formally into the role.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stepping into shoes like that is also a really difficult process for our team members. John was our CEO for 42 years, and ultimately that&#39;s what they knew. For me, it was really important to connect with our team members, make sure that we could provide a vision and that they understood the elements of Whole Foods Market, our culture, our core values, our higher purpose. They were going to remain intact, and my job was to help take those responsibilities and support us being able to keep Whole Foods and the important elements intact.&lt;/p>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;newsletter&quot; name=&quot;The New World of Work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;follow-subscribe data-name=&quot;hbpnewworldofwork&quot; data-activity=&quot;newsletter&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div style=&quot;color: #000000&quot;>; &lt;svg>; &lt;use xlink:href=&quot;/resources/css/images/hbr-icons.svg#the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;&lt;/use>; &lt;/svg>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Subscribe to our Weekly Newsletter &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; The New World of Work &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Candid conversations on talent, tech, and the future of business. A special email series for subscribers. &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; js-target=&quot;subscribe-for-newsletter-tout&quot; data-method=&quot;subscribe&quot;>;Sign Up&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/sign-in&quot; js-target=&quot;sign-in-this&quot;>;Sign Up&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe&quot;>; Sign Up&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Thanks for signing up, &lt;span js-target=&quot;newsletter-success-firstname&quot;>;&lt;/span>;! &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; You can view our &lt;a href=&quot;/email-newsletters&quot;>;other newsletters&lt;/a>; or opt out at any time by managing your &lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences&quot;>;email preferences&lt;/a>;. &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/follow-subscribe>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At HBR, we love to give people practical takeaways. You&#39;re not the first and you won&#39;t be the last to succeed an iconic CEO who&#39;s been in place for many years. What&#39;s your advice to people who are in your role and coming in? What have you learned from the process that you&#39;d like to share?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s important to understand the voice of the team members. What are they looking for in that transition and what&#39;s important for them? For me, I took an opportunity over those 11 months to do something we call the Whole Conversations Tour, which gave me some great insights for what was on the mind of our team members.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some cases, they had fears with John&#39;s retirement of whether there are going to be major changes to our culture or our quality standards? What are things going to look like going forward? For our stakeholders, whether it was suppliers or customers, community partners, I think it&#39;s important to understand the voice of all of those stakeholders as you&#39;re making the transition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the other part I would give advice on is making sure that you&#39;re not just trying to be that leader. For me, John and I, we lead in very different ways and that&#39;s why we were so complementary in working together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s also about being authentic to yourself and at the same time making sure that you&#39;re supporting the company and where it needs to go.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Your path to CEO is not typical. Maybe no one&#39;s is, but yours in particular isn&#39;t. Talk about your past and your life and career and how it ended up in this role?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ve had the opportunity to work in retail since 2000. My first set of experiences really came through consulting. I worked for Accenture and had an opportunity to work with a lot of leading retailers and grocers, both here in the US and around the world. It was that passion I had in working within the retail space.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That career allowed me to connect with several executives at Whole Foods Market, our former Co-CEO, Walter Robb and CFO, Glenda Flanagan. As they were looking to hire a new CIO or CTO, they had reached out to me. I had provided some names of some clients that I thought would be good folks to go for the job, and they reached back out and said, “Why aren&#39;t you putting your name on? We&#39;d really love for you to consider joining Whole Foods.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I came to Austin, spent two days here, and just really had an amazing appreciation for the fact that the higher purpose and core values weren&#39;t just words on a wall. They were being lived out day-to-day. That was the awakening that this is the right place for me to go work and spend the rest of my career.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I joined Whole Foods, I was responsible for technology as well as our digital businesses. Helping stand up both our delivery and pickup businesses, which we hadn&#39;t yet launched. During that timeframe, I also helped looked at ways for us to establish some organizations and support practices we didn&#39;t have before like our first operations support team.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I spent more time at Whole Foods, I picked up additional responsibilities in areas like team-member services (what other companies would call HR), and eventually stepped into the chief operating officer role in January of 2019. And going through that role really helped prepare me in taking the next step up to the CEO position.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was thinking about your past even before that. When I first got in contact with your staff, they said “He&#39;s a cheese guy. You have to understand that.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Absolutely. I&#39;ve had a long connection to food, been gardening since I was seven. My dad actually was a cheese maker. Both of my parents grew up on dairy farms. I was in rural Wisconsin and just have an interesting connection to our food systems and couldn&#39;t be happier to have the opportunity today to be in a role where I can help influence and support our food systems for future generations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What does it mean for Whole Foods to report up to a giant, Amazon.com?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We are very privileged in a number of ways. First and foremost, one of the things we&#39;ve been really excited about over the last six years is we&#39;re really focused on the long-term of Whole Foods Market and being able to have the support of Amazon providing us with capabilities that allow us to serve our customer in the most amazing ways possible. Whether it&#39;s through technology or other services, being able to help create great customer experiences is one of the things that Amazon has been helpful with.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, we&#39;re helping redefine what grocery is going to look like in this space. Having a parent company that has resources and expertise that we can plug into and utilize to support Whole Foods is really important.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also appreciate the same things where we&#39;re able to be Whole Foods and maintain our culture. I mentioned earlier we still have the same higher purpose and core values. While we&#39;re part of Amazon, it&#39;s really a complementary relationship where we bring the very best of what we can offer and we&#39;re able to plug in and leverage the very best within Amazon.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think we have emotional connections to the brands that we like. What do you say to people who love the Whole Foods brand and its brand promise, but don&#39;t feel the same emotion toward Amazon?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some cases it&#39;s helping those customers understand some of the benefits that they can use, that Amazon can support them as well. Whether it&#39;s providing a quicker checkout in one of our stores using Amazon One, or ultimately some of the support and work, where we&#39;re collaboratively looking at ways by which we&#39;re going to help meet our environmental and sustainability commitments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s something a lot of our customers care about and something we&#39;re able to leverage as Whole Foods and supporting our core value around the environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you see as Whole Foods&#39; biggest challenges? Is it simply to grow as quickly as possible, to add new stores? Or do you think about it in some other way?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s really figuring out how we expand our reach and impact. One of the ways we&#39;ll do that obviously is adding new stores, but it&#39;s also finding new ways that we can serve customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the things we launched earlier this year is the ability to have items directly shipped to our customer&#39;s homes through Amazon. We currently have over 800 products available within our exclusive brands, our 365 brand as an example. That&#39;s something we can serve more customers in new ways.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re also really focused on ways we can help support our higher purpose in nourishing people on the planet. It&#39;s not just growth for growth&#39;s sake, but how do we help be the force for change?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the things I&#39;m really passionate about is regenerative agriculture. This is an opportunity that&#39;s ultimately going to allow us to take the products that we know and love today and make sure that we can continue to produce those for future generations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For people who aren&#39;t familiar with the idea of regenerative products or agriculture, what does that that mean?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an area where I think a lot of consumers don&#39;t understand that our current topsoil continues to lose the nutrients that it needs to produce the products that we know and love. Regenerative is about not only helping bring those nutrients back into the soil, but help in a sustainable way. To make sure that we can continue to support our soil and the broader biological environments not only to continue to produce the products that we know and love today, but ultimately create an ecosystem where it&#39;s not as disruptive as what we&#39;re seeing today. How do we make sure that we can partner with our suppliers so they can support these practices and be an advocate for them?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the things I&#39;m really proud of is that we&#39;ve already launched three regenerative products under our own exclusive brands to help take that leadership position. One of my personal favorites is our green lentils under our Whole Foods Market brand, a great product. And it&#39;s one of the very first certified regenerative products from a private label perspective on the market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Your strategy, if I understand it, seems essentially still to be primarily a brick and mortar one. Do you feel the need to become more of an e-tailer going forward?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reality is we are an e-tailer today. Whether you are having products delivered to your house, you&#39;re picking them up in one of our stores, you&#39;re getting some of our exclusive brand products like our 365 products shipped directly to your home: we&#39;re already playing in that space. I continue to see that we&#39;ll have opportunities both in the physical experience as well as online.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A lot of our customers like to shop through multiple different channels. In some cases they&#39;d like to have center of store picked for them and ready for them to pick it up when they shop the store, and then look at our perimeter, whether it&#39;s picking out their own meat or seafood or interacting with our team members. As an example, at our cheese case, a certified cheese professional can help choose exactly the right cheeses as you&#39;re putting together your cheeseboard and charcuterie plates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So fast-forward, not way into the future, but a year or two or three. How do you think the in-store experience will change for Whole Foods customers?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re going to continue to find ways to help simplify and make things easier for our customers. One of the things our customers find value in is our ability to help save them time. In some cases, as I mentioned earlier, delivery and pickup help support that. We want to be able to find ways that customers can find products in the store faster. How can we better provide the expertise across all the different areas within our stores so customers can make sure we&#39;re supporting the amazing events and dinners they&#39;re helping prepare for their family and loved ones, and ultimately, checking out faster in our stores?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a lot of things we&#39;re making investments on where technology will support things, and investments into our team-member experience, to make sure that our team members can best serve our customers and help save them time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to go to an audience question. This is from Holly who&#39;s in Boston. Do you have any recommendations for how companies can best develop an internal leader to be the next CEO, including maybe external development programs?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the things I&#39;m really, really proud of is the investment we put into our team member experience and focus around internal growth and development. We had over 11,000 promotions over the last 12 months, which I&#39;m so proud of.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, when I look at my executive team, two of my direct reports actually started in our stores part-time. Our head of operations, Bill Jordan, as an example, joined through Mrs. Gooch&#39;s [Natural Food Markets], which was one of our acquisitions. He&#39;s worked across almost every part of our stores, multiple regions, and now leads operations reporting directly to me for all of Whole Foods Market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re making big investments into career development programs. We do this for our major leadership positions within the organization. Just yesterday, I was actually doing the keynote graduation ceremony for our store team leader career development program which is focused on a six-month period, helping make sure our team members are ready to take that next step up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For our most senior leadership positions, we&#39;ve helped cross-pollinate and have leaders work across multiple different parts of the company. That was something I was privileged to be part of, being able to lead multiple different functions before stepping into this role.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the other things that&#39;s really unique for us is both for our executive team and something we call WFLN, which is the Whole Foods Market Leadership Network, built of our 19 most senior leaders. We collectively work together across all different facets. Folks are helping participate in work in parts of the company they may not lead. For us, it&#39;s really making sure we&#39;re working together as a team and helping make sure we&#39;re bringing some of those experiences and expertise across our entire leadership team.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m also really proud of the fact that 50% of the group I just mentioned grew up in our stores, and so that expertise of knowing Whole Foods and being able to build a career in a functional area is something we&#39;re really proud of.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let&#39;s shift gears a little bit. This is another audience question, from Punjab, Pakistan, and it&#39;s about hybrid work. How do you manage the fact that your frontline workers need to be there full-time in the stores, versus white collar workers who are able to work hybrid? How do you balance that?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;ve done a return to office where our store support team members are required to be in the office three days a week, but ultimately many of them also have to spend time in our stores or in our facilities, helping connect with team members.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the things that&#39;s been an important part of our vision is something I call store-centricity, in making sure that every single one of our store support team members has a connection to our stores. We ultimately have included it in something we call our job-dialogue process, which is part of our performance management process, on setting the expectation, and ultimately having team members talk about the things they&#39;ve done over the course of the last 12 months to connect with our stores, and what those experiences have taught them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;ve also built some programs around our senior leadership and other leaders that we have within our store support group, and actually pairing them with stores and partnering up with our store team leaders, and finding ways that we can better support our stores, and ultimately making sure that we can bring those experiences where our store support team members really understand everything that&#39;s happening day-to-day in a store, what it takes to lead a store, and how do we help improve our team member and customer experiences in the work that we do.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To build on that, you used the phrase before, the theater of retail. I love that term. When you think about Whole Foods, the Whole Foods experience, what is your theater of retail?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For so many of our customers, they&#39;re coming to Whole Foods as an oasis, to get out of the hectic day-to-day life, you know? One of my favorite examples of that is our Manhattan West store, located in Hudson Yards in Manhattan, and you get off the busy street and you walk in the store, and it&#39;s just an immediate sense of Zen. For me, we want to be able to create this oasis for customers, bring the theater of retail.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We want our customers to have sensory overloads in the experiences they have, as they&#39;re walking into produce, the smells that they&#39;re having, the beautiful merchandising that they&#39;re seeing, the demos of products that we&#39;re doing in the store. We can be at our very best when we&#39;re helping bring this theater to life for our customers, because it&#39;s one of the reasons they&#39;re coming to our stores.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have a question from Reno, Nevada in the US. How does Whole Foods think about the phenomenon of food deserts. You aren&#39;t everywhere. You&#39;re in markets that can sustain it. How do you think about the food desert issue, at least in the US, and whether there&#39;s anything you can do to alleviate that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is one of the areas we&#39;ve actually made investments in and have tried to find ways to support those who might be underserved or don&#39;t have access to some of the highest quality products we sell at Whole Foods Market. We have an entire foundation that we call &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholecitiesfoundation.org/about/&quot;>;Whole Cities&lt;/a>;, which has been dedicated to some of these efforts, in not only having us establish stores, but ultimately investing in communities through a lot of different programs that can help bring access to food in these underserved communities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here&#39;s a question from London in the UK. Having followed a very dynamic, well-profiled CEO, how do you think about the role of the CEO? Does it need to be a very public-facing role, or not necessarily?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It really depends upon the company. You know, are you public or private? In our case, we are a subsidiary, and for me, the most important role that I have is internal from that perspective. Obviously, having responsibilities external allows us to support our stakeholders as well, so when I look at the time that I spend, it&#39;s probably 80% on the internal side of things, and in the 20% I&#39;m spending external, it&#39;s really trying to help connect with and support our stakeholders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I give a great example on this with our suppliers. How do we help bring a voice into other organizations, folks within government, around some of the work that we need to do to help support our farmers and our suppliers and ranchers?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s figuring out that right balance, but the responsibility I personally have is serving as our internal leader, and making sure that our team members understand the vision that we have as an organization. I&#39;m spending time directly in our stores, connecting with our team members, making sure that they understand where we are going, and making sure we can get feedback. My job is to be a servant leader in serving our stores. One of the things I really have tried to do is set the tone across the entire organization of us being store-centric.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we launched our new vision, growing with purpose, in January, one of the commitments we made is that every single one of our stores is being visited by a member of our executive team. There&#39;s eight of us, so for our 535+ stores, we&#39;re spending a lot of time on this road show this year, connecting with our team members, making sure they understand where we&#39;re going and getting their feedback of what they&#39;re seeing. It&#39;s helping us improve and elevate many of the priorities and initiatives we&#39;re doing across the organization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think we&#39;ve been through a show this year without talking about generative AI. We have a question from Tampa, Florida, which is just how do you think about AI and how it can, or maybe already is, changing the grocery shopping experience?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s going to fundamentally change retail and grocery over the course of the next 10 years. To go into one of your earlier questions, this is one of the great things about being a subsidiary of Amazon as well, and being able to leverage capabilities on this side.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I think about how we work, things are going to change. You know, the role of a merchant, which is very much at the center of retail in how you select product, decisions that you&#39;re going to be making around assortment, and pricing, and merchandising. We&#39;re going to have additional insights and toolsets that AI is going to really influence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think about all of the different, amazing things that this is going to provide for customers as well, whether it&#39;s helping build out a shopping list, to helping select products that you&#39;re going to bring together for an amazing meal or experience that you&#39;re preparing for, to helping provide discovery. I think there&#39;s going to be so many different applications in how this is going to make things easier, better, and more impactful for our customers, and at the same time, allowing us to raise the bar on how we look at things like assortment and all of the key things that we do in bringing the experiences to our customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You&#39;ve talked a couple times about sustainability, and I know that&#39;s a big priority for you. How does a company go from wanting generally to do the right thing in terms of climate change, in terms of sustainability, to really making it fundamental?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First and foremost, it&#39;s important to be authentic. For us, within our core values, the environment has always played a role. The work that we&#39;ve done in supporting the organic movement is an example, which has been the leading climate-friendly agricultural practice over the last several decades. It&#39;s always been part and parcel around how we can make sure that this is authentically connected to the work we&#39;re doing. For us it&#39;s easy, because it ties to our higher purpose of nourishing people on the planet.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes down to doing things just for the sake of hitting metrics and goals, when you&#39;re not thinking about how this ties to why you&#39;re doing it, I think you have to take a step back and really understand, “How does this actually connect to the company&#39;s vision, and the mission, and the goals that we&#39;re trying to do?” If it&#39;s not authentically there, understand the changes that you need to make within the organization to make sure that it is. That would be my top piece of advice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here&#39;s a question from Ontario, Canada, about retention: what strategies has the company implemented to retain employees?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the top things is providing growth opportunities for our team members. I mentioned a little bit earlier we had 11,000 promotions over the last 12 months. One of the things that&#39;s important about doing that is providing ways by which we can help support our team members&#39; growth and happiness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One area I&#39;m excited about is an apprentice program. We currently have three live, a Butcher Apprentice program, a Certified Cheese Professional, and a Bakery Decorator Apprentice. We&#39;re going to be rolling this out so each one of our departments and teams has an apprentice program going forward. This allows team members to develop skills and trades they can use at Whole Foods Market and elsewhere in their life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s not only great for the team member, but it&#39;s great for our customers: our customers are actually coming to Whole Foods Market for the great expertise and experience we can provide. By having things like this in place, it makes sure that our team members are supported in taking those next steps for growth within the company.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I mentioned a little bit earlier the career development programs we do. We do this throughout our entire organization, so we&#39;ve got programs from multiple levels within our store, around store leadership as an example. Team members not only see their current next-step opportunities, but they see the growth and support they&#39;re going to have at future levels as well.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One other area that I&#39;m proud of is something called Cultivate. It&#39;s a mentoring program that we have in place, and this is very unique to Whole Foods Market. Most other retailers might offer this type of program for their store team leader or store leadership. We open up all this for our team members so they have opportunities to connect with other folks to get supporting, coaching, mentoring experiences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have a great example of connecting the two where we have a team member, Marie in Hawaii, who&#39;s connected with a mentor who&#39;s in Boston, and the experience that she&#39;s able to have virtually in a wonderful way to learn things that allow her not only to grow, but bring new experiences into her store. Examples like that have team members not only connected to Whole Foods, but knowing that they&#39;re supported for an entire career they can have with us.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re almost out of time, but I want to ask the cliche question you probably get all the time. When I interviewed Howard Schultz when he was CEO of Starbucks, I had to ask, what does he order when he walks up to the barista. So when you shop Whole Foods, what&#39;s in your basket? What are some of your favorites?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Well, every shop is a little bit different depending upon what I&#39;m preparing for. When I&#39;m going through produce, I&#39;m always picking up bananas, blueberries, avocado. At our seafood counter, I&#39;m looking at whatever&#39;s coming fresh. I love our salmon. It&#39;s one of my favorite products. In meat, it&#39;s the ribeye. In cheese, I&#39;m looking to see what artisan cheeses we have in place. Current favorites right now are Uplands and Jasper Hill as far as producers. The Harbison is actually one of my personal favorites. In our prepared foods, I hit the salad bar almost daily for lunch. And in center store, I&#39;m always trying to check out whatever store I&#39;m in, what are the local products? Local is a really important part of Whole Foods Market, so I love discovering new local favorites in whatever store I&#39;m at.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I assume your certified cheese professional gets a little nervous when you walk up and ask what they&#39;ve got?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not at all, because they know that I&#39;m excited about a great conversation we&#39;re going to have on some of their favorites. And usually it involves tasting a few samples as well, so always a great experience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All right, well Jason, I want to thank you for being on the show. It&#39;s really great to hear your thoughts, and thank you for being here.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;JASON BUECHEL:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks for having me.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 02:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>