<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[Keeping Procurement and Supply Chain Strategy Rooted in Real Time and in the Real World - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/keeping-procurement-and-supply-chain-strategy-rooted-in-real-time-and-in-the-real-world]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img 咏叹调-scribedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364594&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/07/shutterstock_1779391529.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;作者：Etosha Thurman&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通货膨胀、经济不稳定、材料和劳动力短缺、气候变化——几乎任何你能想象到的干扰都是一个压力点，使采购和供应链管理变得更加复杂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当他们努力应对持续的干扰时，采购领导者还必须管理不断变化的战略，以控制支出、满足利益相关者的需求并降低风险暴露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据过去几年我们在全球经济中的经历，预测风险从未如此难以预测。气候变化和网络攻击增加了停电风险。无法衡量和跟踪您的供应链或在价值观和流程上与供应商保持一致会带来声誉风险。如果没有对市场进行自动实时监控，您的成本风险就会很高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采购范围已经远远超出了通过具有成本效益的解决方案满足组织需求的范围。并非所有供应商都是平等的，价格不应成为采购决策中的唯一标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了满足您的采购优先级，采购领导者必须建立广泛的供应链关系并做出包含以下因素的采购决策：材料和劳动力、供应商多样性和可持续性等因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;不断变化的采购格局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt; script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;p>;如果您的组织正在尝试使用传统的供应链管理基础设施来管理寻源和采购，而这些基础设施将您的数据锁定在孤岛和手动更新的电子表格中，那么您就无法跟上不断变化的实时变化出现在现实世界中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在比以往任何时候都更需要您对公司所有团队的采购和支出数据有一个统一、透明的实时视图，以跟上变化的步伐。掌控供应链生态系统中的许多移动部件需要强大的基于云的采购技术，该技术可以帮助您的组织提高数据透明度、减少支出、最大限度地降低风险并改善供应商协作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;人工智能 (AI) 和自动化对于从供应链数据中收集实时见解至关重要，可以帮助您提高效率。将人工智能和自动化应用于流程和工作流程管理的成长型组织发现，他们可以加快采购周期、提高生产力、更好地量化支出和节省、明确定义和观察供应商参数以及处理发票，所用时间仅为过去的一小部分。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;​改进采购流程可以为您的组织和供应商提供请购、审批工作流程以及发票和付款处理的无缝体验。采用人工智能和自动化技术的流程和工作流程管理还可以帮助您加快采购周期、提高生产力，并捕获和报告节省的成本。​更重要的是，它可以使采购和采购团队能够做出最佳的支出决策。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2020/12/daf1af4d-c27d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html&quot;>;波士顿大学&lt;/a>;正在使用与老化、低效的采购到付款平台以及基于电子邮件、传真和纸质的流程相比，数字化采购有助于做出更明智的支出决策。 BU 升级为&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/products/spend-management/procure-to-pay.html?campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517074&amp;amp;source=ppc-1na-google_ads -search-71700000111875678-58700008460611821-ism_ism-xxx&amp;amp;dfa=1&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw0IGnBhDUARISAMwFDLnwiBK6p1EXScf2cLhUS-​​cB22YFVNiezalphsnbiH3CNwduKeORQtAaAvwr EALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&quot;>;云解决方案&lt;/a>;，用于与其企业资源集成的采购、合同管理、发票和采购规划 (ERP) 软件，自动化其手动流程，并支持与供应商就数千个采购订单和发票进行更密切的协作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;管理业务流程生命周期&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;日益复杂的全球供应链生态系统要求组织管理整个业务流程生命周期的支出，从供应商寻源和管理到采购和付款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您的组织依赖于时间敏感的交易，那么实时供应商管理数据可以为您提供基于透明度、可见性和弹性的见解。人工智能的力量可以帮助您增强数据驱动的采购决策以及安全性和风险缓解。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>; if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;您可以&#39;不要改进你无法衡量的东西。如果您看不到合同或绩效指标，如何才能变得更好？使用一个由人工智能驱动、易于部署的集成采购平台，清晰透明地呈现所有团队的指标，可以为您的组织提供更加简化的用户体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总部位于蒙特利尔的 &lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.sap.com/uk/about/customer-stories/cirque-du-soleil.html&quot;>;太阳马戏团&lt;/a>;依靠全球 1,900 家供应商通过定制设备和数千种服装提供复杂的表演。 Cirque 在敏捷的云平台上标准化其核心业务功能后，极大地改善了其供应链管理，使采购变得透明和无缝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“最终用户选择首选供应商，订购他们需要的产品，然后太阳剧团娱乐集团采购高级总监 Stéphanie LeRoy 表示：“我们很高兴能按时收到。” “它比我们以前的系统快五倍，并且具有积极的财务影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采购的成功取决于能够分析实时数据、快速响应不断变化的市场状况并降低风险。基于人工智能和自动化的云采购基础设施对于降低风险和成本、提高效率以及增强整个供应链的敏捷性至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.363364705;dc_trk_aid=554534923;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd =;dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;强>; &lt;em>;了解更多信息。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Etosha Thurman 是 SAP 智能支出和业务网络的首席营销和解决方案官。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Video Quick Take: SAP&rsquo;s Etosha Thurman on Mitigating Risk and Building Resilience in Supply Chain and Procurement - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/video-quick-take-saps-etosha-thurman-on-mitigating-risk-and-building-resilience-in-supply-chain-and-procurement]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div data-props=&quot;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;6337165321112&quot;}&quot; js- target=&quot;video-player-page&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;加载中.. . &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，HBR&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢迎观看 HBR 视频快速观看。我是托德·普鲁赞 (Todd Pruzan)，《哈佛商业评论》研究和特别项目的高级编辑。今天我们采访了 Etosha Thurman，他是 SAP Intelligence Spend and Business Network 的首席营销和解决方案官。她和我们一起讨论供应链和采购的风险管理和弹性。 Etosha，非常感谢您今天与我们在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢谢您邀请我，Todd。我很高兴来到这里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text /javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p >;Etosha，企业如何更好地预测风险？他们如何衡量弹性？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过过去三年全球经济的经历，风险，而不仅仅是风险采购是许多高级管理人员（包括首席财务官和首席运营官）最关心的问题。我们都在努力找出如何降低风险的方法。我们如何预测可能的风险并尽力减轻风险？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在采购领域，当我们考虑风险时，我们会考虑几个组成部分。首先是我们如何理解供应链中的风险？我是否面临供应中断的风险，我们许多人在过去几年都经历过这种情况？然后是供应商风险，无论是供应商的质量还是使用供应商的潜在声誉风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，还有成本风险。因此，当你问企业如何更好地预测风险时，我的第一个答案是监控风险。考虑供应链风险，特别是供应风险，它能够具有可见性和透明度，能够根据您的需求、他们的能力以及您在该能力中的位置与供应商进行协作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并且有解决方案可以帮助促进这种类型的透明度和协作，包括我们在 SAP 的那些。然后，当你想到供应商、供应商风险时，我的意思是，这可能是企业在供应链方面管理风险的首要方法之一，通过测量、跟踪和与供应商合作来了解他们的风险。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;那么，无论是跟踪供应商绩效并制定工作基准，该供应商是否向我们提供优质产品或提供优质服务？它符合我们预期的时间准则吗？因此拥有供应商绩效管理流程和解决方案非常重要。当然，还有风险监控，您可以在其中提出问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对供应商进行风险评估。最重要的是，拥有可以监控供应商提供的数据之外的数据的技术，以便您深入了解总体风险。例如，SAP Ariba 风险管理解决方案具有监控功能，可以监听媒体、监听外部数据源，并通知您供应商的风险是否有可能增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt; div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;假设供应商正处于即将到来的海啸路径上。该解决方案会提醒您该供应商发生的风险因素。因此，公司可以采取很多措施来主动发现或监控风险。当然，一旦您意识到，您就可以采取主动措施来解决已识别的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是各种规模的公司都面临的问题。但我很高兴地说，有一些解决方案可以提供帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很高兴知道这一点。是的，听起来有很多不同的因素。 Etosha，采购和供应链领导者如何指导更广泛的企业降低风险？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先要做的事情之一思想就是将风险意识融入到采购过程中。举个例子，假设您有一位最终用户想要一项新服务。我需要一家新公司来提供任何服务，以便我能够满足最终客户的需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从采购角度解决风险的首要方法之一是在采购过程中进行采购并具有信息风险意识。采购流程。因此，当您组织采购活动寻找能够提供所需服务的公司时，您可以在采购活动中进行风险评估，以了解哪些选择中风险最小，并做出决定然后，一旦您选择了供应商并将其纳入您的供应商社区，并且您企业中的实际最终用户希望与这些供应商开展业务，就会向他们提供相同的风险信息。并非所有供应商都是生来平等的。价格并不总是唯一的关键决策标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，在最终用户想要购买笔记本电脑的地方利用技术。您有三个首选供应商与之签约。在做出购买决策时，您可以与他们分享风险评估——每个供应商的风险分析或评分，以帮助降低风险。如果我在一周内需要这台笔记本电脑，并且我可以从风险评分中看到，由于交货或质量问题，该供应商可能对我们来说是黄色的，也许我不会选择该供应商。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后，当然，另一种方法是确保公司的价值观和风险政策作为公司内部供应商管理方法的一部分进行沟通和共享。因此，当我们邀请供应商时，我们会与他们一起进行风险评估，询问他们与我们的价值观和政策相关的问题，并让他们回答这些问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这会围绕我们如何进行对话。想要表现良好并设定期望，这也可以减轻公司内部的风险。所以这些只是一些方法。当然，我不是在这里谈论企业范围的风险。但公司在法律和财务方面也做出了这些努力，特别是在采购方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;供应商管理、供应商绩效跟踪以及将风险意识引入采购和购买流程都是采购可以帮助减少或减少风险的方法。减轻公司内部的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好的。那么，Etosha，考虑到采购中的所有这些考虑因素，采购团队目前关注的最高组织风险优先事项是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;这是一个很好的问题，托德。如果我考虑一些最重要的风险优先事项，我首先想到的是确保我清楚自己的支出情况。首先，我们的钱去哪儿了？我们与哪些公司合作？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个是评估和了解这些供应商的风险评分。根据我的价值观、我公司的政策，与该供应商开展业务的风险有多大？因此，如果我考虑最重要的风险优先事项，那就是可见性。一旦我知道我与哪些公司合作，我就能了解供应商的风险状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企业（尤其是采购部门）最感兴趣且持续增长的一个问题是网络安全。我们的供应链是否存在网络攻击的风险？在过去几年中，我们听说过一些备受瞩目的案例，其中存在影响供应链的网络攻击。所以这是一个正在增长的领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后我认为我之前谈到的一直存在的一个实际上围绕风险评估的实际上是供应商管理。它是了解供应商、分享期望以及拥有允许供应商管理透明和协作的流程和技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以这些是一些风险领域。我想我还要补充一点。这就是对未知事物的预测风险分析，这确实很难。它正在推动利用品类管理等工具为行业的关键品类和关键材料设定基线，然后能够分析多种因素的风险，无论是财务风险、产能风险还是供应商集中度风险、地缘政治风险——它们都在发挥作用，并成为我们客户和整个市场当今的关注点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;托德·普鲁赞 (Todd Pruzan)，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是每个人都必须考虑的一系列令人惊奇的事情。 Etosha，非常感谢您今天的精彩对话以及您的见解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢谢您邀请我，Todd。我很高兴与您共度这一刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.375512081;dc_trk_aid=566751456 ;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;了解详情。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;&lt;em>;Etosha Thurman 是 SAP 智能支出和业务网络的首席营销和解决方案官&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body >; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Steps that Move Corporate Purpose From Words to Action - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM BRANDPIE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/5-steps-that-move-corporate-purpose-from-words-to-action]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img 咏叹调-scribedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364693&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/BP_HBR_Hero_1200x675.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;作者：MaryLee Sachs&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实现商业目的的好处是毋庸置疑的——那些成功实现商业目的的人比那些没有目的的竞争对手享受到更多好处。近十分之九的首席执行官表示他们的企业有一个目标。但是有多少企业利用目标来做出有意义的改变并推动可持续增长？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你的企业是这样吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;将目标付诸实践&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，所有组织都在全球地缘政治变化的背景下开展工作，其中包括气候危机、猖獗的通货膨胀和生成人工智能的稳步发展。如果您的公司现在没有定义自己的立场和未来的方向，那么以后这样做就会困难得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brandpie 的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brandpie.com/ thinking/ceo- Purpose-report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;第五届年度全球首席执行官目标报告&lt;/a>;带来了好消息。我们看到越来越多的组织将宗旨作为战略业务工具——我们调查的 1,000 名各行业首席执行官中，有 63% 表示他们将宗旨纳入高层决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，要实现宗旨，还有很多工作要做发挥其潜力。目前还没有领导者使用目的来指导他们的所有决策。为什么不？超过一半的首席执行官提出的响亮答案和持久挑战是如何将目标付诸工作的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type= &quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;如果您的组织难以将目标置于其业务战略的中心，这五个步骤可以帮助您从声明转向行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.确保你的目标是可行的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我们回顾一下。对于调查中近一半的领导者来说，定义目标陈述是一个挑战。您的目标以有意义的方式将您的业务与世界的需求联系起来。它应该激励、挑战并帮助您建立长期价值。您的目标还应该对所有内部和外部利益相关者相关且有意义。他们需要与之联系。对于以书面意向声明开始生命的事物来说，有很多要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这是在定义目的时要考虑的第一个问题：它是否可行？矛盾的是，目的陈述不应该是可以实现的。 （把它留给你的组织野心。）设定一个常青的目标，你总是努力改进的目标。最简单的目的陈述往往是最有力和持久的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.让领导力与您的目标保持一致&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要拥有与整个员工产生共鸣的强大目标，您必须自上而下地工作。如果要有效地嵌入目标，为组织注入活力，并成为每个决策的指南针，执行领导团队就需要接受目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着员工越来越多地在孤岛中远程和虚拟地工作，它变得越来越重要。让组织中的每个人都了解您的目标更加困难，更不用说将其用作行动的起点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有 26% 的调查受访者表示，目标有助于他们与高层领导保持一致。这标志着错失了一个机会；我们亲眼目睹了目标在行政领导层所具有的强大激励作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync() ) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.在内部实现目标驱动。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然薪资和福利对员工来说始终很重要，但&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey. com/capability/people-and-organizational-performance/our-insights/help-your-employees-find- Purpose-or-watch-them-leave&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;人们现在也希望为有明确目标的组织工作&lt;/a>;，他们可以做出有意义的贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有目标源于形成一个单一的想法，将你所做的事情牢牢地置于业务的核心。但这个想法必须既具有启发性，又具有可操作性，并且植根于企业业务和运营方式的日常现实。传达的信息是，整个企业的每个人都可以共同努力实现其目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，将目标和文化融入员工体验中。从中汲取经验来创建您的员工价值主张。将其应用到员工的日常工作流程中。将其嵌入到您的文化计划中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4.向外部利益相关者传达您的目标&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;组织的目标越明确，就越容易与关键的外部影响者（而不仅仅是其客户和客户）进行有意义的对话。除了激励员工之外，目标还必须成为做出更大战略决策的透镜。目标远非一次性项目，而是一个长期、持续的过程，它存在于组织的文化、品牌、活动、计划和抱负中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.倡导变革&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到目前为止，企业在帮助世界实现有意义的变革方面的作用不仅被接受，而且被期待。商业是创新的强大引擎，并且具有独特的优势来实现大规模变革。然而，调查中只有 28% 的首席执行官表示，他们利用目标来“倡导重要话题的积极变革”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种情况需要改变。负责任的领导者利用目标来赋予团队权力并创造可以发生变革的文化。他们带领合作伙伴、供应商和股东踏上构建共享价值的旅程，并在此过程中成为未来的市场领导者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是时候将目标从言语付诸行动了。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;需要帮助将您的目标从言语转化为行动吗？ Brandpie&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;哈哈&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;s&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;帮助企业通过以下方式推动进步超过15年的目标。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hello@brandpie.com?subject=HBR%20article:%20I&#39;d%20like%20to%20learn%20more%20about%20 Purpose-driven%20business&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;联系我们了解更多信息&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryleesachs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;玛丽李·萨克斯&lt;/em>;&lt;/强>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;是首席执行官U&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;S&lt;/em>;&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;在目标驱动转型咨询公司&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Brandpie&lt;/em>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10 Signs Your Company Is Resistant to Change]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/10-signs-your-company-is-resistant-to-change]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_26_654602221.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Jorg Greuel/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt; span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;在他们的新书《快速行动并解决问题》中，Frances Frei 和 Anne Morriss 概述了帮助领导者解决问题的五种策略他们最棘手的问题并迅速做出改变。第一步是确定您需要解决的真正问题。通常，每个人都不清楚这一点。因为人们已经开发出许多有效的方法来容忍问题而不是解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023 /09/10-signs-your-company-is-resist-to-change?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/10-signs-your- company-is-resist-to-change?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Facebook 将“快速行动，打破常规”作为非正式的公司座右铭。但领导力专家弗朗西斯·弗雷和安妮·莫里斯认为，这种信念存在严重缺陷，它阻碍了领导者打造一家伟大的公司。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;最好的领导者能够快速行动并解决问题——他们解决难题，同时使组织变得更强大。在他们的新书中&lt;/em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/move-fast-and-fix-things-the-trusted-leader-s-guide-to-solving-hard -problems/10546&quot;>;快速行动并解决问题&lt;/a>;（&lt;em>;哈佛商业评论出版社），Frei 和 Morriss 概述了帮助领导者解决最棘手问题并快速做出改变的五项策略：&lt;/em>;&lt;/p >; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;确定您真正的问题。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;与利益相关者建立或重建信任。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;创造包容性的条件，让您的整个团队蓬勃发展。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;讲述一个关于您需要做出的改变的引人入胜的故事。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;带着紧迫感执行您的计划。&lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;在接下来的五周内，我们将发布与每个策略相对应的一系列摘录。第一段摘录解释了为什么每个人都不清楚需要解决的真正问题 - 因为人们已经开发出许多有效的方法来容忍问题而不是解决它。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;。 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;并非每个组织都渴望解决其问题。在没有明显的绩效危机的情况下，领导者往往会紧抓现状而低估其风险。这种对变革的抵制可以以多种形式出现，其中一些难以解读。这里有 10 个迹象，表明你的公司可能试图让你放慢脚步，无论你在层级结构中处于何种位置。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;1.一个特别工作组正在被指派来解决这个问题。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;一个由改革者组成的小而勇敢的团队是一回事，但另一个是。事实上，我们经常建议加快行动。事实证明，大多数特遣部队并不符合这一特点。你怎么知道？如果您被要求依赖缺乏地位、合法性或决策权的结构或流程，或者拥有上述任何一项的人的赞助，那么它不太可能帮助您有所作为。&lt;/p>; &lt; h2>;&lt;强>;2。我们感谢您付出的时间和努力。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;如果您怀疑自己被纵容或被解雇，那么您可能就是这样。顺便说一句，这与不同意不同，无论诊断结果如何，这都是完全可以接受的反应。作为变革者，你的义务是为你的想法提供有说服力的案例。您同事的义务是真诚地与他们交往，而不是不加批判地同意您的观点。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;3. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;人们怀疑组织是否（真的）有问题。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;做好准备，你的一些同事会反驳你认为公司有问题的前提。顾名思义，残酷的事实是难以面对的。对于表明缺乏充分包容等文化问题的数据尤其如此。坚强点。流畅地讲述您今天收集到的证明问题确实存在的证据，以及有关组织为此付出的代价的共鸣故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;4. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;你被要求回应身份不明的批评者的严重关切。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这些交流通常以一些变化开始，“作为你的朋友，我认为你应该知道人们在说什么。”这通常是一种让你受到控制的策略，而不是向你提供有用的信息。不要上当并对谣言和道听途说做出反应。鼓励你的批评者说出自己的想法，这样你就可以直接解决他们的担忧，这很可能是有道理的。协作发生在白天。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;5. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“法律问题”的幽灵正在被唤起。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;解决这一问题的方法是直接与法律团队合作，该团队通常由人组成他们比那些使用他们名字的批评者更有创造力、更灵活、更注重解决方案。律师很少像非律师所说的那样无法容忍风险、令人扫兴，所以尽早与他们合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;6. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;您的同事指出了所有需要解决的&lt;em>;其他&lt;/em>;问题。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;此回复假设存在某种可测量的限制公司吸收积极变革的能力——而你正危险地接近这条线。人们往往会低估公司适应更好现实的能力（以及持续无所作为的真正成本）。您提出的问题需要快速响应，这反映了挫败感、平庸，以及某些组织中现状的真正痛苦。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;7. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;你不断听说未来的状态，变革的条件将会好得多。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这可能是我们看到的最常见的抵制表达：幻想在未来的某个时刻改变事情会更容易。根据我们的经验，这种情况几乎从来不会发生，而且通常情况恰恰相反。你现在拥有的清晰度和动力是巨大的资产，但它们也是易逝的。在大多数情况下，“现在的紧迫性”会赢得胜利，尤其是当你周围的人的成功和福祉处于危险之中时。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;8.行动的时间表越来越长。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这是另一种常见的拖延策略，是针对第 6 项和第 7 项中表达的担忧提出的解决方案。您的诊断在概念层面上得到了接受，但提议的变革的时间表漫长而模糊。 Treat this development as an existential threat. When it comes to solving mission-critical problems, the right time to take action is now.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;9. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Your colleagues think they can wait you out.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Management thought leader Earl Sasser calls this “kidney stone management” — the assumption that this, too, shall pass. Make it clear that you&#39;re not going anywhere, preferably with a smile. If you&#39;re not the boss, then show up in her office with a cup of coffee, just the way she likes it, every morning until you get her to engage. That move, by the way, has never failed us.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;10. You keep hearing, “We&#39;ve already tried that.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The company may have already wrestled with some version of the problem you&#39;ve surfaced, with little to show for it beyond a legacy of frustration and cynicism. If so, do your homework and learn what you can from whatever went wrong. Regardless, context changes, including the very material context of your willingness to lead on these issues. &lt;em>;You &lt;/em>;haven&#39;t tried before, which is going to make all the difference.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;This excerpt has been lightly edited. It&#39;s an updated version of a list that was originally shared in Frei and Morris&#39;s previous book &lt;/em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/unleashed-the-unapologetic-leader-s-guide-to-empowering-everyone-around-you/10245&quot;>;&lt;em>;Unleashed: The Unapologetic Leader&#39;s Guide to Empowering Everyone Around You&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;em>; (Harvard Business Review Press, 2020).&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Simple Solution for Simplifying Work Processes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-one-health-system-got-rid-of-bureaucratic-busywork]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_26_93191840.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Epoxydude/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Technological progress and new digital products have perennially been relied upon for improving operations. But the truth is, tech can often make bureaucracy worse. Electronic Health Records (EHRs) were hailed as a cure to the inefficiency of paper-based systems. But studies now reveal that doctors spend half of their time managing EHRs and desk work, shortchanging patients and fueling burnout. Dr. Melinda Ashton at Hawaii Pacific Health (HPH) proposed a simple and radical solution: Get Rid of Stupid Stuff (GROSS). She and HPH staff designed a simple form for reporting tasks that were poorly designed, unnecessary, or just made no sense. Simple fixes get implemented directly, more involved improvements get reviewed by the relevant groups for feasibility. With focused leadership and follow-through, GROSS has led to saving thousands of hours across the HPH system and to other health systems adopting the practice.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-one-health-system-got-rid-of-bureaucratic-busywork?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-one-health-system-got-rid-of-bureaucratic-busywork?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Across every industry, digital technologies have proved to be powerful tools for streamlining processes and automating workflows. In healthcare, the introduction of Electronic Health Records (EHRs) was hailed as a groundbreaking cure to the inefficiency of paper-based systems. But as many healthcare providers have now learned, digitizing a pointless or poorly designed process can make it even harder for employees to get their work done. The numbers are stark: a study in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acpjournals.org/doi/10.7326/m16-0961&quot;>;Annals of Internal Medicine&lt;/a>; revealed that doctors in outpatient settings spend just 27% of their day in face-to-face patient care, while half of their time is consumed by EHRs and desk work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This imbalance is a triple threat. It shortchanges patients, who are deprived of valuable time with their healthcare providers. It fuels burnout among nurses and doctors, who identify an excess of bureaucracy as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medscape.com/slideshow/2023-lifestyle-burnout-6016058?faf=1#6&quot;>;the primary cause&lt;/a>;. And it&#39;s expensive — the US healthcare system spends a staggering $1 trillion per year, or a quarter of total expenditures, on administration.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While some are hopeful that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90890543/how-ai-can-be-used-to-cut-a-1-trillion-healthcare-problem&quot;>;generative AI will help cut through the paperwork,&lt;/a>; these predictions remain speculative. In the meantime, there&#39;s a proven remedy for reducing the administrative burden. This solution doesn&#39;t hinge on fancy algorithms but on a commitment to rooting out bureaucratic inefficiencies and simplifying work processes. Take the case of Hawaii Pacific Health (HPH), a non-profit system employing 7,000 staff across four hospitals in the Aloha state.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The New Age of Operations&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Improving efficiency and increasing resilience. &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;The story starts in 2017 with Dr. Melinda Ashton, a pediatrician serving as HPH&#39;s Chief Quality Officer. In her role, Ashton had become increasingly concerned with the deluge of administrative tasks that were eroding the time medical staff could spend directly caring for patients. Across HPH there was a growing chorus of complaints about needless busywork and ponderous systems. Physicians and nurses were particularly frustrated by the hours they spent each day mechanically clicking through the maze of on-screen prompts that popped up whenever they needed to update a patient&#39;s care records.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The spark for change came when a group of nurses decided to calculate the time they and their peers spent documenting the simple fact that they had completed their hourly rounds. The team estimated that this perfunctory task consumed 1,700 nursing hours per month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This revelation — the perfect symbol of the unnecessary friction that was vexing clinicians — pushed Ashton over the edge. With a blend of boldness and pragmatism, she proposed a radical idea to her C-suite colleagues: rally all of HPH&#39;s medical staff in a campaign to “Get Rid of Stupid Stuff.” The blunt name raised eyebrows among execs, and some suggested blander terms like “administrative simplification,” but Ashton stood her ground. It was crucial to acknowledge the problem honestly and be clear about the intent to solve it.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;“Get Rid of Stupid Stuff” Suggestions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Get Rid of Stupid Stuff (GROSS) launched in October 2017. Clinicians were encouraged to identify anything in the EHR that was poorly designed, unnecessary, or just plain nonsensical. The submission form was simple and easily accessible on HPH&#39;s internet.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364148&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/W230905_HAMEL_GROSS_SUGGESTIONS_360.png&quot; >; First, identify your role, Such as a physician, nurse, pharmacist, medical assistant.Working at, blank.&lt;br />; Here you can Identify your location, for example, clinic, hospital unit, Epic login department.I would like to, blank.&lt;br />; State your goal.So that, blank.&lt;br />; Describe the benefit of the change.Finally, there are spaces to include your name and contact information.Source: Melinda Ashton, MD, “Getting Rid of Stupid Stuff,” American Medical Association, 20 19&lt;br />; &quot; title=&quot;Getting Rid of “Stupid Stuff” (GROSS) Suggestions.&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; height=&quot;951&quot;>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbr.org/data-visuals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;See more HBR charts in Data &amp;amp; Visuals &lt;i>;&lt;/i>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;To create buzz, Ashton toured each of HPS&#39;s four hospitals. She shared vivid examples of administrative absurdity and invited her colleagues to join the campaign.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the early nominations were for tasks that simply made no sense. A nurse in adolescent oncology pointed out that for over a decade she&#39;d been dutifully documenting “cord care” for her patients. The absurdity? Adolescents don&#39;t have umbilical cords. A neonatal nurse flagged another equally goofy task: Having to check three boxes every time she changed a baby&#39;s diapers, indicating whether or not her tiny patient was incontinent of urine, stool, or both.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other nominations targeted processes that were necessary but needed a serious efficiency upgrade. For instance, patients being discharged from the emergency department had to digitally sign an after-visit summary which was then printed out, scanned, and uploaded back into the system.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;From Idea to Action&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In the first year of the initiative, HPH staff submitted nearly 200 suggestions. These were reviewed by two nursing leaders in Ashton&#39;s department, both of whom had extensive experience in IT and quality improvement. The GROSS core team developed a simple but effective triage mechanism.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364149&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/W230905_HAMEL_GROSS_DECISION_TREE_360.png&quot; >; &quot; title=&quot;Getting Rid of “Stupid Stuff” (GROSS) Decision Tree.&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; height=&quot;799&quot;>; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbr.org/data-visuals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;See more HBR charts in Data &amp;amp; Visuals &lt;i>;&lt;/i>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Simple fixes, like removing the “cord” prompt for patients who weren&#39;t newborns, were handled directly by the GROSS team. Ideas requiring further review and elaboration were handled by pre-existing quality and EHR working groups. These teams, representing different hospital areas, reviewed and prioritized the nominations. When a “stupid stuff” idea got the green light, the working group would invite the individual behind the original nomination to help with the redesign.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some cases, finding a fix also meant liaising with clinical groups that had different perspectives on the merits of a specific practice. Emergency Department physicians, for example, preferred to fill out simple one-time prescriptions for antibiotics, while hospitalists, keen to prevent dosing delays, would typically opt for a recurring prescription, which took more time to enter. It was up to the working groups to identify these conflicts and design the best solution.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A small fraction of submissions — roughly one in every eight — ran into major regulatory or technological hurdles and were judged to be “not possible at this time.” When this happened, the GROSS team would write a response explaining why the fix wasn&#39;t feasible. The goal was always to acknowledge every nomination and be transparent when the barriers to a redesign seemed insurmountable.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;A Broader Impact&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The second year of GROSS would yield another 300 nominations. Out of all the actionable ideas, about 10% involved patently stupid activities that could be terminated immediately; 15% flagged gaps in clinical communication and support for necessary workflows; and the remaining 75% identified redesign opportunities to improve efficiency and effectiveness. In addition to saving thousands of hours across HPH, the GROSS initiative also had an effect on the organization&#39;s culture — principally by empowering frontline team members to challenge the systems and processes that make their work unnecessarily difficult and inefficient. As Ashton put it in an article for the &lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp1809698&quot;>;New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/a>;:&lt;/em>; “… there is stupid stuff all around us, and although many of the nominations we receive aren&#39;t for big changes, the small wins that come from acknowledging and improving our daily work do matter.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other hospital systems including the Cleveland Clinic and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8294464/&quot;>;Mount Sinai Health System,&lt;/a>; have taken take note of Dr. Ashton&#39;s work implemented their own versions of “Getting Rid of Stupid Stuff.” Seeing the potential to scale this approach across health care system, the American Medical Association (AMA) launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://edhub.ama-assn.org/steps-forward/module/2757858&quot;>;GROSS module&lt;/a>; as part &lt;em>;STEPS Forward&lt;/em>;, its signature practice improvement program.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Frontline Initiative and Intelligence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Dr. Ashton&#39;s individual leadership and initiative were key in Hawaii Pacific&#39;s success. She didn&#39;t mince words — she called out the “stupid stuff” for what it was. But the real magic of the effort was tapping into the power of the organization&#39;s collective intelligence. Those at head office, no matter how well-intentioned, aren&#39;t on the front lines and can&#39;t, therefore, calibrate the true costs of bureaucratic folly. It&#39;s the nurses, doctors, and others in the trenches, who see where the system falls short.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yet, ideas alone aren&#39;t enough. Dr. Ashton and team succeeded because they were disciplined and deliberate in the follow-through. GROSS wasn&#39;t just an electronic suggestion box — it was a system that filtered, prioritized, and executed promising ideas, working across departments and disciplines. The initiative produced meaningful results — results that improve the lives of clinicians and patients in ways&amp;nbsp; significant enough to justify the hard work of rooting out excess bureaucracy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the face of entrenched norms and processes, it&#39;s easy to succumb to a sense of helplessness, to accept the status quo as an immovable reality; it&#39;s also easy to believe that technology will solve every problem. Yet, the story of Hawaii Pacific Healthcare&#39;s GROSS initiative offers a compelling counter-narrative. It&#39;s a tale that reminds us that with simple, smart process improvements, we can, indeed, challenge and reshape the operational systems that bind us.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Strategic Benefits of Randomized Decision-Making]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/the-strategic-benefits-of-randomized-decision-making]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_26_1161120429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;MirageC/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;In highly ambiguous and challenging contexts, a random approach to decision-making confers a number of advantages. Operations managers have been using randomized decision-making since World War II (randomized search was used to locate enemy submarines in the open ocean), but it has not yet been seriously applied to strategic decision-making, which remains focused on hypothesis formulation and testing. &amp;#160;In this article the authors explain the strategic benefits of randomized decision making &amp;#8212; early advantage, faster learning, less predictability, and reduced biases &amp;#8212; and offer advice on how to incorporate randomness in the strategy-making process.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/the-strategic-benefits-of-randomized-decision-making?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/the-strategic-benefits-of-randomized-decision-making?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The Naskapi, a nomadic people indigenous to Quebec and Labrador, hunted most of their food. You might expect, then, that much analyzing and strategizing went into the crucial decision of where to hunt: The Naskapi might have recorded how many moose or caribou they hunted to ensure they did not overexploit their hunting grounds; they might have made systematic plans to regularly explore new regions to discover new herds; or they might have tried to predict the likelihood of finding particular herds in different landscapes, like valleys, hills, or along rivers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Instead, the tribe, along with many other ancient peoples, relied on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anthrosource.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1525/aa.1957.59.1.02a00060&quot;>;divination&lt;/a>;. In the case of the Naskapi, this consisted of heating up the shoulder blade of a dead animal to the point where it cracked. They started their hunt in the direction to which the crack pointed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This ritual will strike most people as superstitious and arbitrary, effectively making their strategic decision random. But that was precisely the point. The randomness of the process enabled the Naskapi to tackle the complex problem of choosing where to hunt quickly, without bias and without becoming predictable to their prey. As a result they avoided spending too much time and effort in the search for the ideal hunting ground and survived in the hostile, sub-arctic for hundreds of years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This seemingly implausible link between the Naskapis&#39; divination practices and their ability to thrive in a harsh environment can be extended into a business context. We&#39;ll look at how people are currently leveraging randomization to make operational decisions and discuss how applying this approach to strategy might enable businesses to thrive much as the Naskapi did. We&#39;ll conclude by offering tips on how companies can introduce randomness into their strategic decision-making process.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Randomization Today&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Randomized decision making has proved successful in modern times as well — most notably in operations management. During the Second World War, the Allied powers faced tough challenges like figuring out where to find enemy submarines in vast open waters, based on &lt;span>;the positions of &lt;/span>;last sightings. The problem was big because of the very large number of possible paths the vessels might take and because there were not enough ships or planes in one&#39;s own fleet to conduct a systematic, exhaustive search before an enemy submarine struck again. In these situations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/b100809&quot;>;research&lt;/a>; showed that quickly choosing, at random, a few places to search and then expanding the radius using random changes in direction beats systematic searches in which every step was pre-planned in advance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around the same time, researchers working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://permalink.lanl.gov/object/tr?what=info:lanl-repo/lareport/LA-UR-86-2600-05&quot;>;Manhattan Project&lt;/a>; invented Monte Carlo simulation, a method that relies on random sampling to estimate the outcome of a complex system or process, in which the environmental conditions themselves exhibit randomness. The scientists used this method to predict the performance of different bomb designs and shielding materials. Monte Carlo simulation continues to be used widely for making decisions under uncertain conditions, notably in finance and logistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, randomization is often employed to enhance the efficiency and accuracy of machine learning techniques. For example, the initial parameters of a neural network are often chosen at random to avoid the network getting trapped in a particular configuration. Broadening the search space increases the chance of finding superior configurations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More prosaically, package-delivery companies already leverage stochastic optimization techniques to identify robust routes across a range of different scenarios (eg, with factors such as shipping volume, time windows, vehicle availability, and road closures varying from day to day). There is also some evidence that designers of large-scale products and social systems develop an intuition for &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/smj.757&quot;>;when to choose randomly and when to optimize&lt;/a>;, based on an estimate of the problem&#39;s complexity.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;What About Strategy?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In contrast to operations management, strategy-making has remained a stubbornly &lt;a href=&quot;/2012/09/your-strategy-needs-a-strategy&quot;>;deterministic practice&lt;/a>;, which generally tries to, first, fully understand a problem and then deploy analysis to create a plan for tackling it. The Big Data revolution has encouraged this approach, leading us to believe that everything can be known and analyzed to create reliable strategies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this belief ignores the fact the very same piece of data can be used to argue for different, even opposing, courses of action. For example, Kodak&#39;s response to observing a rising demand for digital photography was to double down on the traditional film business to ensure it would not cannibalize its sales. Meanwhile, competitors, such as Sony and Canon, reacted to the same information by investing heavily in R&amp;amp;D to improve digital camera technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confidence in big data solutions also blinds people to the computational challenges. Organizational activities are often tightly coupled and interact densely — both with one another and with forces operating beyond the firm&#39;s boundaries. As a result, a very large number of causal paths, factors, and networks come together to determine any outcome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even apparently “simple” problems at the foundation of making strategy work, such as whom do you choose to spearhead a problem-solving process are, in fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbs.edu/ris/Publication%20Files/19-072_1da6ef3d-ac69-47d7-aec3-3f7616c0e3f9.pdf&quot;>;large&lt;/a>;. That is in part because there are many different kinds of authority different people can have — such as initiating a decision, awarding rewards, or sharing information — and, accordingly, many ways of assigning different levels of authority.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, given the pace of change and volatility of today&#39;s world, it is becoming infeasible to collect and analyze all information necessary for a deterministic approach to problem-solving in real time — doubly so as behavioral patterns of consumers and competitors keep changing in response to any moves made. The idea that you can always find algorithms that will reliably predict the outcomes of strategic decisions in the real complex world of business or politics will belong &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foundation_series&quot;>;in the realm of science fiction&lt;/a>; for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, strategy can no longer be about determining the single best course of action. Rather, the goal of strategy must shift from making plans to building a &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/why-conflicting-ideas-can-make-your-strategy-stronger&quot;>;portfolio of options,&lt;/a>; each of which could form the basis for future success. Building this optionality, however, is inefficient in the traditional strategy-making approach, as the search for multiple possible solutions can be prohibitively costly and time consuming. &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/radical-optionality&quot;>;Given these factors&lt;/a>;, perhaps it&#39;s time for strategists to take a leaf out of the Naskapi playbook and embrace their intelligent randomization in the face of complex problems in large, unknown, and changing landscapes. Let&#39;s turn to look at what benefits that might deliver.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Early Advantage&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Consider the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/how-twitter-was-founded-2011-4&quot;>;Odeo&lt;/a>;, which had built an online podcasting platform that, in 2005, found itself facing insurmountable odds when Apple announced it would ship its own competing platform as part of iTunes with every one of its iPods. Company leaders at Odeo recognized that a radical shift was required and started holding daylong “brainstorming” sessions — a collective random search for new directions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One idea that originated in these sessions was an online platform for sharing your status with friends and followers that, before its recent name change, was known as Twitter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Given the situation Odeo found itself in, there was limited time for developing a strategic roadmap, let alone for conducting any meaningful amount of market research or competitor analysis in what was already a crowded space, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/datablog/2014/feb/04/facebook-in-numbers-statistics&quot;>;Facebook&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/chart/26176/estimated-number-of-myspace-users-at-key-milestones/&quot;>;MySpace&lt;/a>; each attracting tens of millions of active monthly users at the time. Instead, Twitter was launched as a minimum viable product (MVP), creating an option for Odeo to survive and, by continually iterating on the platform, thrive. (Ironically, Odeo&#39;s investors did not realize Twitter&#39;s potential and allowed the firm&#39;s management to buy back its stock for approximately $5 million — around 0.01% of what Elon Musk paid for the platform in 2022.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A key lesson of the Twitter example is that, for many problems, solutions are only meaningful if they are implemented quickly enough for them to matter — the same benefit that the Naskapai ritual conferred. &amp;nbsp;Had the Naskapi comprehensively analyzed their way to a solution, the herds they were looking for would probably have moved on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Twitter, many of the best-known entrepreneurial ventures have benefited from the early-mover advantage that randomized decision-making and quick action bring. The first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/pictures/54f4e70eda47a54de8244f8b/the-original-35mm-hero/&quot;>;GoPro&lt;/a>; consisted of a just wristband and plastic casing housing a cheap off-the-shelf digital camera. Building customer relationships and iterating on this first design enabled the company to stand its ground when several heavyweights, like Sony, Nikon, and Garmin, later entered the market for action cameras.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Randomization works for incumbents just as well — arguably &lt;span>;even more readily&lt;/span>;, because they have more resources to leverage. As the online shopping market began to move down different paths simultaneously (towards a search-based model like Google Shopping, a multi-shop model like Tmall, and a general store model like Amazon), Alibaba &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/the-self-tuning-enterprise&quot;>;did not wait&lt;/a>; until it could reliably predict the winning model. Rather, it split its business and developed solutions for all three future scenarios, emerging more powerful than ever as it turned out that all of the new market segments were here to stay.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Faster Learning&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Getting started sooner also means you learn faster. For example, launching an MVP early generates information by sparking competitor and customer reactions, which inform your next move. For the Naskapi, following the divined direction in their hunts meant that, just by chance, they would regularly make new discoveries, such as water sources, places for temporary settlements, or potential hunting grounds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a more contemporary example, consider large language models like ChatGPT, which work by predicting the probable next word based on the previous ones. Programmers can control the degree of accuracy of this process through a setting called “temperature” — the higher it is, the less likely the algorithm is to select the word that is predicted to have the best fit with what came before. Increasing the temperature reduces accuracy but boosts creative surprise, which may be desired by the user and also has the benefit of creating more variation in output and, in turn, user reactions, which allows the model to improve over time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, businesses know about the value of experimentation. Physical retail stores have experimented with shelf placements for decades. In the digital context, firms routinely A/B test to optimize website designs, product recommendations, or pricing models.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the scale and speed of testing and experimentation have generally been undervalued, partly because the tests are often designed to prove or disprove a precise hypothesis, which itself has been predicated on a largely stable environment. As a result, strategists learn less than they could if they would if they had turned up the temperature and conducted less precise, more varied, and more frequent testing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/random-testing-in-software-testing/&quot;>;Random testing&lt;/a>; is often used to supplement to hypothesis-driven testing in software development, for example.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Less Predictability&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Employing a random strategy — selecting between all available moves with equal probability — is the only optimal strategy in a (repeated) game of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.cornell.edu/info2040/2014/09/12/applying-nash-equilibrium-to-rock-paper-and-scissors/&quot;>;rock, paper, scissors&lt;/a>;, because it is the only strategy that does not allow some dominant counter-strategy to emerge. In a more complex context, for example in chess, there are several famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/29/crosswords/chess/a-knight-sacrifice-by-topalov-sends-anand-into-a-tailspin.html&quot;>;examples&lt;/a>; of seemingly random (or at least counterintuitive) moves being made by a player that served to introduce complexity and stress into a game in which they faced a superior opponent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This benefit has long been recognized by some financial institutions, which employ randomness to obfuscate their trading strategies. By leveraging “scentless algorithms,” which introduce random delays and variations in the timing and size of orders, institutions can avoid signaling their intentions, which could be exploited by other market participants to register gains on the back of more competent traders&#39; analyses. A simpler example is “&lt;a href=&quot;https://uxknowledgebase.com/fake-door-testing-48af0616185a&quot;>;fake door testing&lt;/a>;” where random product or promotional configurations are presented to consumers on line to learn by eliciting a reaction, while at the same time giving few clues to competitors.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Reduced &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Biases&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Managers often tend to &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/11/dont-let-your-company-get-trapped-by-success&quot;>;replicate past successful approaches&lt;/a>;, while being less receptive to new ideas or external signals. This can lead to decline as the environment shifts around them. Well-known examples abound: Blockbuster and Nokia deferred to the “tried and true” with disastrous consequences when demand and competitive conditions changed radically.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Embracing randomness can provide a solution to this problem. In nature, evolution — random mutations, combined with natural selection pressures — ensure continued adaptation of a species to a changing environment. Learning from biological phenomena, designers of evolutionary algorithms quickly generate random bits and pieces of a solution to a big problem, which are then assembled into trial solutions that get evaluated against an objective or fitness function.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the political context, humans have been leveraging randomization for millennia. In ancient Athens, for example, a lottery system was used to select magistrates, to ensure that the rich and powerful did not buy their way into power. In the business context, organizations could easily adopt randomizing behavior to cut through the maze of political maneuvering and negotiations that accompany budget allocations to one or more competing alternatives, each with its own champion and leveraging private data. Because of the impartiality of randomizing over possible options, no one need feel unfairly excluded.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not all biases against change are the product of prior success. In highly negative contexts, humans fall prey to learned helplessness, in which repeated experiences condition a person to believe that they have no power to change their circumstances, and, therefore, they do not even try to take decisions. Adopting a randomized process to decision-making in such situations may counter this bias to inaction.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;How to Introduce Randomness into Strategy-Making&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Our standard mental image of randomness is a coin toss or a dice roll. But for real-life problems, using these techniques would require knowing, enumerating, and evaluating all of your options first — which is almost the same analyzing your way to an optimal strategy. Still, there are various tactics strategists can leverage to incorporate randomness into their toolboxes and identify a probably good-enough solution in good time for it to matter.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Vary the starting point.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Like machine-learning algorithms, use a random prompt to vary the starting point of your search. For example, to help musicians unlock their creativity, Brian Eno and Peter Schmidt have created a deck of cards with instructions that encourage lateral thinking, such as “change instrument roles,” “emphasize the flaws,” or “put in earplugs.” Introducing an element of chance into the creative process helps overcome creative blocks and ensures artists do not fall back on familiar habits and patterns.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Vary the pacing.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Vary the tempo or rhythm of the search (length of feedback loops). Too often, teams and groups are trapped by a “metronome” of quarterly reports, monthly reviews, and weekly meetings. But, to randomize intelligently, you may have to operate on time scales of days or even hours.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Vary the locus.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Do you search for a solution close to where you are now or far away? Random jumps can help unfreeze your strategic decision making by taking you to parts of the search space you had not previously considered. For example, research has shown that in the open ocean, where prey is scarce, fish use a search pattern that incorporates occasional, but extremely long “step” lengths between search areas, following a mathematical pattern known as Lévy flights.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Vary the heuristics.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Do you search top down or bottom up? Depth first or breadth first? Not all big problems will yield to the same search strategy. Some work better than others, and there is no “one best way” to solve any problem whatsoever.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Vary the searcher.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Make different people responsible for the search or for different aspects of it. Since different people have different built-in biases, prejudices, and go-to methods, randomizing across different problem solvers will also help you randomize across possible solutions.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;In the past, companies aspired to be “know-it-all” organizations that could understand and control their environments to such an extent that they were able to clearly plot an optimal path through it. Some companies, upon recognizing that know it all was no longer possible, pivoted towards a “learn-it-all” mindset, constantly &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/the-self-tuning-enterprise&quot;>;fine-tuning&lt;/a>; their approach as new information emerged.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While this continues to be powerful, we believe it can be further extended to create a “search-it-all” approach, in which an emphasis is placed on actively probing the environment to generate the valuable information that enables developing optionality quickly and efficiently. And quick, random choices help you accomplish just that. Which brings us back to the Naskapi, whose superstitious ritual looks increasingly like smart decision-making in the face of complex, ambiguous challenges.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Good Judgment Is a Competitive Advantage in the Age of AI]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/good-judgment-is-a-competitive-advantage-in-the-age-of-ai]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_ChenWu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Chen Wu&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;With generative AI, the technology game has changed &amp;#8212; suddenly everyone is a potential programmer. But as we travel these technological leaps forward, there&amp;#8217;s still a fundamental, longstanding capability every organization will need to realize AI&amp;#8217;s true potential: judgment. That idea of judgment in the age of AI was a central tenet of the work of the authors&amp;#8217; late colleague, visionary friend, and longtime HBR contributor Alessandro Di Fiore. Alessandro believed in putting humans at the center and considered technology to be a way to help people augment their creativity, autonomy, and critical thinking. He argued that judgment will be the real competitive advantage for organizations as AI systems rise to new common operating standard.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/good-judgment-is-a-competitive-advantage-in-the-age-of-ai?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/good-judgment-is-a-competitive-advantage-in-the-age-of-ai?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;It wasn&#39;t that long ago that AI was considered the domain of elite experts or data scientists. Companies spoke effusively about its potential to transform business, but only a fraction of their employees had access to it. With generative AI, the game has changed — suddenly everyone is a potential programmer thanks to tools like OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT, Google&#39;s Bard, or Anthropic&#39;s Claude 2. But as we travel these technological leaps forward, there&#39;s still a fundamental, longstanding capability every organization will need to realize AI&#39;s true potential: judgment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2HRqRUWWj58&quot;>;judgment in the age of AI&lt;/a>; was a central tenet of the work of our late colleague and visionary friend Alessandro Di Fiore. Alessandro believed in putting humans at the center and considered technology to be a way to help people augment their creativity, autonomy, and critical thinking. As &lt;a href=&quot;/search?term=alessandro%20di%20fiore&quot;>;a frequent contributor to HBR&lt;/a>; (and the former chairman of &lt;em>;Harvard Business Review Italia&lt;/em>;) he often reflected on how innovation, leadership, and AI went hand in hand. And in &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/08/why-ai-will-shift-decision-making-from-the-c-suite-to-the-frontline&quot;>;this 2018 article&lt;/a>;, he argued that as AI gets more accessible to all employees, judgment would become as crucial as any technical skill.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessandro argued that judgment will be the real competitive advantage for organizations as AI systems rise to new common operating standards. But reinforcing skills alone won&#39;t develop better judgment. Companies will need to radically rethink how they view and deploy judgment in order to adapt to the pace of change. Significantly, Alessandro saw three critical facets of judgment as crucial to this moment:&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Access&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This speaks to the idea of who has the authority or permission to exercise judgment.&amp;nbsp; As an early advocate of &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/the-democratization-of-judgment/ROT357&quot;>;democratization of judgment&lt;/a>;, Alessandro knew that making good decisions was not something confined to the C-suite. As knowledge, data and technologies are more widely distributed, judgment must also be more widely distributed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies need to understand how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capgemini.com/insights/research-library/generative-ai-in-organizations/&quot;>;leverage and scale&lt;/a>; generative AI, and trying to prohibit that access will ultimately be a futile effort. Making sure your workers have access to all the ways they can unlock the value in these tools is part of the transformation, of course doing so in a secure and controlled manner. This requires trust and communication. But leaders should consider that an increasing number of new use cases and practices are bound to emerge bottom up rather than stirred top down.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Exercise&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;of Judgment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This speaks to the act or process of deciding or forming an opinion. Alessandro considered judgment as a continuous process rather than a single moment:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Judgment is not only exercised in the moment of making a decision assessing data and information. Judgment is broader than that and it starts with asking the right questions, framing the right problem, evaluating the broader context. Judgment is co-creative, it&#39;s a journey.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;This concept of judgment is even more true today. The rise of generative AI expands judgment beyond discrete decisions — it&#39;s now a collaborative human-machine process.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With AI chatbots, the significance of contextual interactions is evident. Judgment emerges through integrated human-AI dialogue, not separated spheres. Our recent ChatGPT experiment on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbritalia.it/userUpload/ebook_Generative_AI_inglese.pdf&quot;>;how generative AI can enhance 10 popular management practices&lt;/a>; is a case in point. In a meaningful dialogue with ChatGPT, we had to exercise our judgment ability before, during, and after the prompting, inputting the right context, crafting the best chain of prompts, and carefully interpreting recommendations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experiment confirmed Alessandro&#39;s intuition: the ideal outcomes arise at the intersection of human and machine intelligence. Sound judgment&#39;s future is this symbiotic co-creation process. Such a shift mandates a comprehensive people transformation and reskilling, arming workers with the judgment prowess essential for the AI era.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Control&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This speaks to the systems or processes in place to oversee or check decisions. The traditional methods of control are quickly growing out of date. Strict top-down oversight can stifle agility in this new paradigm. Yet totally unconstrained autonomy poses its own risks if ethical AI development and deployment principles are not ingrained across organizations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The solution consists of two parts: first, building trust and responsibility in the system with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capgemini.com/about-us/who-we-are/our-values/our-ethical-culture/our-code-of-ethics-for-ai/&quot;>;code of ethics&lt;/a>; for a fair, safe and sustainable usage and to prevent AI models from producing inaccurate information or generating responses that contradict your company&#39;s values; second, providing training to users on how to set the right context for human-AI decision-making. That second part involves explaining appropriate boundaries for prompts and framing inquiries responsibly. Rather than micro-approving choices, leadership should focus on empowering workers with these skills at all levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this vision, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imd.org/ibyimd/team-building/control-systems-seven-ways-to-set-your-employees-free/&quot;>;control transforms&lt;/a>; from bureaucratic gatekeeping to fostering collective responsibility. As Alessandro wrote, “Leaders have in first person a duty to set the right context and conditions to empower employees make more autonomous decisions with the help of data and technologies. Giving freedom is good. But helping them exercise their freedom is more crucial.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessandro&#39;s vision underscores the need for sound judgment as AI reshapes society. His legacy remains a constant source of inspiration as we work towards a future where humans and technologies collaborate seamlessly, fostering innovation and progress.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the future remains ours to shape through vision, ethics, and responsible innovation.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using Technology to Improve Supply-Chain Resilience]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/using-technology-to-improve-supply-chain-resilience]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_GuillemCasasus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Guillem Casasus&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;The Covid-19 pandemic brought many global supply chains to a halt. And as we emerged from the pandemic, many companies overcorrected by adopting &amp;#8220;just-in-case inventory management.&amp;#8221; What&amp;#8217;s more, when consumer confidence varies widely from month-to-month and demand remains volatile, it is difficult for businesses to plan. In the apparel sector, for example, buyers must place peak-season orders six months in advance. With high volatility, demand forecasts in June can be completely different than actual demand in December. This raises the overall risk of either missing the season by not having enough, or facing enormous markdowns in January. To move forward, supply chain managers need more flexible, dynamic connections between trading partners to replace their current point-to-point, static connections that are unable to adapt to sudden, unexpected supply chain disruptions. What they need is a more modern, more responsive supply chain platform. This article discusses how today&amp;#8217;s supply chain technology can help businesses build more resilience into their supply chains moving forward.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/using-technology-to-improve-supply-chain-resilience?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/using-technology-to-improve-supply-chain-resilience?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The Covid-19 pandemic shook global supply chains to their core, and they have not yet fully recovered. What&#39;s more, many managers who had previously followed “lean” principles, including “just-in-time inventory management,” have overcorrected by adopting “just-in-case inventory management.” This tendency to simply overcorrect (and overstock) with an ad-hoc and ill-defined “just-in-case” inventory strategy has resulted in soaring global inventories in the retail, wholesale, and manufacturing industries at a time when the Business Confidence Index and Consumer Confidence Index &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.oecd.org/leadind/consumer-confidence-index-cci.htm#indicator-chart&quot;>;both show unusual volatility&lt;/a>;. When consumer confidence varies widely from month-to-month, it is difficult for businesses to plan. In the apparel sector, for example, buyers must place peak-season orders six months in advance. With high volatility, demand forecasts in June can be completely different than actual demand in December. This raises the overall risk of either missing the season by not having enough, or facing enormous markdowns in January.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The New Age of Operations&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Improving efficiency and increasing resilience. &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;To move forward, supply chain managers need more flexible, dynamic connections between trading partners to replace their current point-to-point, static connections that are unable to adapt to sudden, unexpected supply chain disruptions. What they need is a more modern, more responsive supply chain platform.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Building Supply Chain Resilience with a Modern Technology Platform&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Supply chain management technology platforms can build resilience on a number of levels, by allowing businesses to:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Establish unified commerce via increased supply chain visibility.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;One of the most significant challenges facing retailers today is the orchestration of a seamless consumer experience across multiple channels, such as online, in store, and hybrid models that combine the two. Many grocers have developed innovative technologies that allow customers to place orders online, that notify the customer when the order is ready, and that then detect when the customer is nearby, creating a seamless customer experience. Network-wide inventory visibility is essential for enabling unified commerce. With network-wide inventory visibility, companies can avoid stockouts and overstock situations, reducing carrying costs and enhancing customer satisfaction. By utilizing advanced tracking technologies such as RFID, IoT sensors, and data analytics, businesses can gain insights into inventory levels, location, and movement in real-time, allowing them to make better data-driven decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Collaborate on Sales &amp;amp; Operations Planning.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Successful sales and operations planning (S&amp;amp;OP) requires leadership participation from a broad range of functions, including finance, sales, marketing, production, and fulfillment. Fortunately, this becomes easier as modern collaboration platforms replace outdated tools to provide a single source of truth data, intuitive modeling, and performance dashboards. When executed properly, S&amp;amp;OP provides companies with the ability to anticipate future demand and respond proactively to changes in the market. This approach also aids in risk management and contingency planning, allowing businesses to mitigate the impact of supply chain disruptions or economic fluctuations.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Implement a SaaS System.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Software as a Service (SaaS) has had a profound impact on global technology implementation by revolutionizing how software is delivered, accessed, and utilized by businesses and individuals worldwide. For supply chain executives, SaaS extends reach and visibility by allowing every stage (eg, raw materials, production, finishing, warehousing, and distribution) to share information, actions, and insights.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Create flexible and open cloud architecture.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Increasing complexity and constant restructuring require supply chain technologies to integrate easily and adjust quickly, meaning that composable architecture is particularly well-suited for modern supply chains. Like a LEGO™ set, composable architecture allows for complex systems to be built by combining smaller, modular components that can be easily assembled, interconnected, and reused. Administrators can add new hardware resources to the pool, and the composable infrastructure can automatically incorporate these resources into the available pool. New Balance is a great example of this in practice. The sportswear company created a single library of content that feeds all of its systems — wearables, mobile, kiosk, and beyond. Instead of rebuilding the New Balance commerce experience from the ground up for every system, the use of common composable architecture suitable for every situation was far more effective.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Technology Is the Driving Force Behind Supply Chain Excellence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;While following this approach is critical to building a resilient supply chain that can endure unforeseen disruptions, the latest technology can also be leveraged to build stronger supply chain systems that position the entire organization for success. Instead of relying on technology to simply survive, forward-looking executives will use it to help their businesses thrive. The tactics adopted here will vary by organization, but here are a several broad approaches that can create stronger supply chains:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Leverage AI/ML to support supply chain management.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The emergence of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) has sparked a transformative era for supply chain management. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/operations/our-insights/ai-driven-operations-forecasting-in-data-light-environments&quot;>;According to McKinsey&lt;/a>;, effective use of AI in inventory control can achieve up to a 20% reduction in inventory carrying costs and a 50% decrease in stockouts. By leveraging advanced algorithms and data analytics, AI/ML technologies enhance the accuracy of demand forecasting, enabling companies to anticipate market trends, fluctuations, and customer preferences with unprecedented precision. This predictive capability facilitates efficient inventory management, reducing excess stock, and minimizing stockouts, thus optimizing working capital. In addition, AI/ML-driven algorithms optimize logistics, streamlining transportation networks and reducing costs.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Take collaboration even further. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;One of the most visible and lasting impacts of the pandemic was how it forced employees at every rung of the business to learn new collaboration skills. Daily meeting participants on Zoom &lt;a href=&quot;https://investors.zoom.us/static-files/a17fd391-13ae-429b-8cb3-bfd95b61b007&quot;>;rose from 10 million to 300 million&lt;/a>; in just four months. And the reality is that while collaboration within an organization has often proven to be challenging, it&#39;s even more imperative for supply chain managers to collaborate outside of their organization with customers, suppliers, and partners. These managers, in particular, will need to rely on the implementation of proper tools such as permission-based private networks to provide a safe, easy, and trusted environment to share supply chain data.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Invest in comprehensive cyber security.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Since 2019, cyberattacks against supply chains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1367208/us-annual-number-of-entities-impacted-supply-chain-attacks/&quot;>;have doubled&lt;/a>;. Just last year, attacks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1367208/us-annual-number-of-entities-impacted-supply-chain-attacks/&quot;>;increased by more than 200%&lt;/a>;. In many of these cases, security vulnerabilities in the supply chain were exposed by third-party operators, such as vendors and contractors. Fortunately, modern platforms are becoming the most effective defense for fighting cyberattacks. While managers might not be able to predict and protect against every risk, a modern technology platform is vital to keeping the organization one step ahead of threats.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Establish greater supply chain visibility.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Traditionally, visibility across the supply chain has been limited to “one-up” and “one-down,” meaning that managers can generally only “see” what their tier one suppliers and immediate customers are doing. However, in a multi-echelon supply chain, operators won&#39;t feel the impact of disruptions that occur three or four tiers back until it&#39;s too late to adjust. Today, modern IT platforms enable trading partners to gather in a safe, permission-based exchange where they can share information, improving visibility and building resilience across the entire supply chain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pandemic illustrated that we need to do more than simply invest in building effective supply chains — we need to place an equal priority on maintaining them. Regardless of how much expertise went into the creation of an efficient and resilient supply chain — we must recognize that in our ever-changing world the supply chain is never a finished product. By keeping our supply chains in a constant beta state and investing in the technology and insights needed to continually elevate them, a global supply crunch can be avoided. The task of building a supply chain that responds to real-time inputs and evolves to meet shifting demands will never be truly finished, but that&#39;s no reason not to start.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Evaluate a Job Candidate&rsquo;s Critical Thinking Skills in an Interview]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-to-evaluate-a-job-candidates-critical-thinking-skills-in-an-interview]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_152401239.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;混合图像 - Peathegee Inc/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close &quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;培养批判性思维的最古老且仍然最有效的策略是苏格拉底方法，该方法由苏格拉底 (Socrates) 于 2,400 多年前开发，苏格拉底是一位伟大的哲学家。西方哲学的奠基人。苏格拉底式方法使用发人深省的问答探究来促进学习。它的重点是产生更多的问题而不是答案，其中答案不是停止点而是进一步分析的开始。招聘经理可以应用此模型在现代组织中与候选人建立不同的对话。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot; /2023/09/how-to-evaluate-a-job-candidates-ritic-thinking-skills-in-an-interview?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/ 2023/09/how-to-evaluate-a-job-candidates-critical-thinking-skills-in-an-interview?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;招聘是其中之一它是最具挑战性的能力之一，但却是最具战略性和影响力的管理职能之一。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/capability/operations/our-insights/operations-blog/ Winning-the-war-for-talent-in-product-development&quot;>;麦肯锡研究&lt;/a >; 量化显示，优秀人才的生产力高达八倍，这表明人才质量与业务绩效之间的关系非常显着。在困难时期寻求增长或仅仅生存的组织必须成功招募一流人才、思想领袖和主题专家。这通常是在时间有限的情况下完成的，因为您必须快速填补关键职位。本质上，您是在几次非常短暂的约会后承诺建立长期关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在让我们考虑一下招聘人才的典型流程。我们用来评估人才的主要工具是一系列工作面试。典型的面试过程是问答形式，向候选人询问一些常见问题：&lt;em>;请告诉我们您的背景。你为什么想为我们工作？分享您在工作中遇到的挑战以及您是如何应对的。你最自豪的是什么？你产生了什么影响？为什么你是这项工作的最佳人选？你最大的成就是什么？你的弱点是什么？&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管人们对面试本身的价值表示赞成和反对，但典型的问答工作面试流程未能评估最重要的因素之一，如果不是最重要的技能，您应该从您雇用的人身上寻找最重要的技能——批判性思维。批判性思维是从各种来源寻找信息，评估其可信度，并确定其相关性和准确性。批判性思维通常被归类为高阶技能，它不是单一技能，而是一系列技能的集合，涉及推理、构建合理的论点以及识别情况的缺陷、偏见、逻辑或不一致之处。批判性思维与创造性思维不同。创造性思维是产生新的、创新想法的能力。批判性思维要求考生仔细、逻辑性地分析事实并形成判断。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;批判性思维从根本上来说是一个提问的过程&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;一个关键见解&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.amazon.com/Decisions-Over-Decimals-Intuition-Information/dp/111989848X&quot;>;根据我们的研究&lt;/a>;，基于对数千名高管的调查和教学，房间里最聪明的人并不是那个人与答案，但提出问题的人。他们好奇、投入、无所畏惧，&amp;nbsp;好奇心强，准备探索一个可能还没有答案的新领域。根据问题的性质，他们展示了观察、分析、推理、询问、解释和解释。批判性思考者很好奇。与生俱来的好奇心已被证明与以下八个特征相关：热心的学习者、问题解决者、积极的倾听者、自我驱动、高生产力、成长心态、卓越的成就以及强大的利益相关者管理能力。这八个特质读起来就像是你想加入团队的人员的资格愿望清单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;咨询公司和技术公司通过使用基于场景或行为的问题来推动标准的面试问题。 em>;：在亚特兰大修剪草坪需要多少钱？为什么公用孔是圆形的？你会如何为盲人设计一个酒架？如果您获得 500 万美元来解决一个全球性问题，您会解决什么问题以及如何解决？&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些是评估候选人提出问题的能力的一个很好的进步，但在回答时这些问题将分析应聘者解决问题的能力、处理歧义的能力和创造性思维，但不会表明他们是否好奇、积极主动或对您的公司、产品、文化或八个特质中的任何一个充满热情前面提到过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，您如何识别具有这种多才多艺且引人注目的批判性思维和好奇心组合的个人呢？大胆地&lt;em>;翻转面试过程。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;培养批判性思维的最古老且仍然最有效的策略是苏格拉底方法，由苏格拉底在 2,400 多年前开发，苏格拉底是一位伟大的哲学家。西方哲学的奠基人。苏格拉底式方法使用发人深省的问答探究来促进学习。它的重点是产生更多的问题而不是答案，其中答案不是停止点而是进一步分析的开始。招聘经理可以应用此模型在现代组织中与候选人建立不同的对话。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;翻转面试&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;让候选人面试你。翻转面试是揭示候选人内在优势、首选工作方式以及他们的想法的另一种方法。面试将展示候选人的思维和决策过程，并表明候选人是否表现出领导特质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;翻转面试不仅仅是让候选人问您开放式问题，例如，&lt;em>;什么是公司文化？&lt;/em>;或&lt;em>;在该公司工作感觉如何？&lt;/em>;面试官带着业务场景、对相关信息的理解进行讨论，并邀请受访者进行指导通过一系列问题进行发现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受访者可能会使用四种类型的问题，这些问题的复杂性和参与度不断增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;事实问题： &lt;/strong>;基于事实或意识提供简单答案的问题。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;趋同性问题：&lt;/strong>;具有有限答案的封闭式问题。通常，这些问题只有一个正确答案。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;发散性问题：&lt;/strong>;鼓励多种答案的开放式问题。这些问题是更详细地分析情况、问题或复杂性并激发创造性思维的一种手段。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;评估性问题：&lt;/strong>;需要更深层次思考的问题。问题可以是开放式的，也可以是封闭式的。评估性问题引发多层次、不同角度的分析，从而得出新综合的信息或结论。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h2>;进行翻转面试：四步流程&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;使用以下框架可以最大限度地提高与新员工对话的价值：&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1.框架&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;简要描述一个场景。预先说明您是该场景的信息来源，并要求受访者在接下来的 8 到 12 分钟内简单地说“您将如何开始这个发现？”当他们不可避免地陷入困境时，用决策树的一个分支来提示他们，进一步打开发现。邀请他们提问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;面试官评估&lt;/strong>;：在框架步骤中，您评估他们如何框架问题。他们是只看问题的表面还是探究问题的本质？他们提出的问题的质量应该决定他们需要的信息、所需的努力，并揭示要做出的重要决定。第一步更多的是发现问题而不是解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;2.链接&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;一旦他们定义了问题，请他们提出有关背景的问题。 “考虑到他们如何构建场景，他们还想知道哪些其他信息来做出推荐？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;面试官评估：&lt;/strong>;您希望了解他们的问题是否会引导他们将场景置于上下文中。语境为王。为了真正将情况置于背景中，他们的问题应该使他们能够通过以下方式进行三角测量：1）绝对值，2）随着时间的推移，3）相对于整个市场正在发生的事情，客户或竞争对手的行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3.解读&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;根据原始场景，结合所学知识，询问“需要做出的基本决策是什么？”或“他们对情况的理解发生了怎样的转变？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;采访者评价：&lt;/strong>;他们能够开始阐述叙述吗？您正在评估他们的叙述是摘要还是综合：摘要 = 数据陈述；综合就是数据+判断。批判性思考者将展示他们如何并行使用和综合不同的信息，以更深入地理解所需的场景或决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;4.继续&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在最后一步中，询问“您接下来会立即采取哪些步骤？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;面试官评估：&lt;/strong>;如果他们开始提问对于需要说服的关键利益相关者、影子影响者、倡导者或摇摆选民，候选人正在进行批判性思考。他们是否寻求了解逆风和顺风以使他们能够前进？请注意，这并不是要解决问题或评估他们是否提出建议，而只是他们如何解决问题和做出决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使用翻转面试，您可以评估候选人的逻辑和对工作的热情。根据他们的问题扮演角色。这些问题是多余的还是必然的？这些问题是通用的还是具体的？他们是否不仅提出事实性或趋同性的问题，而且还提出分歧性和评价性的问题？候选人是否会从不同角度进行转向、深入研究并重新审视某个主题？这些问题是否基于问题及其环境的背景？当他们向您提问时，您可以通过实时、旋转和探究的方式调整他们的问题来确定他们是否在积极倾听。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熟练的提问者会创建合作对话，通过以下方式引发新的学习：一系列问题。他们与对方互动。他们的问题应该引发推论和联系，并提出不明显的观点。这种探索心态鼓励尝试和迭代；意想不到的学习可能源自讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;微软改变面试流程&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;虽然没有被贴上“翻转面试”的标签，但一名候选人在 1998 年申请了微软的职位，结果发现自己陷入了一场面试。 。面试时，招聘人员要求他“卖给我一个烤面包机”。候选人停了下来。候选人毫不犹豫地问了几个问题：“家里有多少人？” “家里有小孩子吗？” “家里使用烤面包机的年龄范围是多少？” “他们住在狭小的空间里，比如公寓还是大房子？” “他们早餐吃得很多，还是他们的主餐是晚餐？” “他们多久出去吃饭一次？”在三分钟的时间里，这是一系列有关人口统计、心理统计和物理空间的问题。招聘人员要求应聘者停下来，并询问这与向她推销烤面包机有什么关系。候选人回答说：“一切。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发现并理解“烤面包机环境”的背景非常重要，以确保我向您推销您需要的东西。如果我将烤面包机的特性和功能与您的需求相匹配，销售的成功率就会提高，您将成为满意的客户。您需要烤面包机、弹出式 2 片烤面包机、4 片、宽片烤面包机、传送带烤面包机、商用烤面包机还是对流烤箱？也许帕尼尼压榨机最能满足您的需求。这项练习与烤面包机无关，招聘人员想了解候选人如何处理歧义。他是一个批判性的思想家吗？他是立即投入推销，还是暂停、转向并学习？如果您想知道，候选人得到了这份工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;建立好奇的文化&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;伟大的领导者建立伟大的文化。伟大的文化建立在好奇心之上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建立一支具有平衡好奇心的团队是致胜之路。具有不同背景的团队通过将不同的知识集引入到问题的解决中，可以进一步放大好奇心文化的影响，这些知识可以相互促进。从面试过程开始，从一开始就嵌入这种关键能力，将使您能够快速建立一种创造性思想家的文化。在翻转面试中取得成功的人都是持续学习者。他们将抓住这个机会——无论是作为个人还是作为一个充满活力的团队——并抓住这个机会。他们会表现出与生俱来的好奇心，并不断问“为什么？”或“那又怎样？”重要的是，“现在怎么办？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提出问题是我们的本能。十八个月。心理学家认为，这个年龄是孩子开始寻求信息的年龄。大约 36 个月大时，这种刚刚萌芽的好奇心转化为口头问题。这些问题看似无数且随机，似乎不加区别地从一个主题跳到下一个主题。为什么会下雨？月亮是由什么构成的？鸟儿是怎样飞翔的？狗去哪儿了？我们什么时候可以去公园？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，当孩子开始上小学时，这种通过提问来学习的永不满足的好奇心常常会发生转变。慢慢地，教育的重点从提出问题转向寻求答案。当孩子们知道答案时，他们会被要求举手，从而形成了一种新的习惯。这种心态——期望提供答案而不是提出更多问题——只会随着年轻人继续他们的教育旅程而加深。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当我们开始工作时，我们就被灌输了这样的观念：我们需要得到答案。在工作环境中，提问的价值经常被错误地忽视。答案受到拥护；预期解决方案；隐含地不鼓励提出更多问题。是的，结果很重要，但是通过更明智的资源分配或更具创造性的策略，这些结果是否可以更显着并以更低的风险实现？我们常常忽视这样一个事实：表现最好的人是那些提出问题并激发批判性思维的人，这些问题可以暴露策略中的弱点或揭示替代路径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到年轻、好奇的自我的道路是短的。事实上，这取决于问自己一个连接我们的职业和个人生活的问题：我们如何成长？这个问题是每个项目、每个请求、每次会议、甚至我们选择工作和生活的地方的基础。很少有人像这样直接问这个问题，但这个根本问题的答案是什么塑造了我们的职业和生活。我们在质疑中成长。了解这一点可以创建一个框架，帮助确定如何提高个人满意度或公司的市场份额、扩大我们的客户群、帮助提高产品使用率或推动更新。如果你寻求成长，你需要激发批判性思维。为此，你需要强有力的问题。这是翻转面试模型的基础。虽然我们从小就喜欢提问，但很少有人教导我们如何有效地培养提问技巧。在商业中，我们常常忽视提问的重要性。我们没有意识到提问是工作中不可或缺的技能。我们没有投入足够的时间和精力来培训自己和他人成为有效的调查员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在翻转面试中成功的候选人将表现出批判性思维的心态。这与了解分析工具和方法不同。批判性思维哲学是几乎每个领导者都寻求的技能，但许多团队都缺乏。分析性思考包括明确基本问题的目的，而不是在数据森林中徘徊，不是从统计角度好奇，而是质疑最初的表面价值，能够通过综合将各个点连接起来，并最终能够分辨出来一个基于更深层次的事实、判断和背景的知情故事，而不仅仅是重申最初的事实。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;。 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;公司的蓬勃发展需要反应能力、洞察力和独创性。您寻求敏捷的思想家，他们可以成为增长冠军、说真话的人、客户管理者和洞察创造者。能够概念化问题、构建情境并提出更深思熟虑的问题的候选人将胜过那些依赖教科书答案的候选人。雇用能够提出深思熟虑的问题的人才是建立成功团队的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，一旦你成功招募了出色的人才，你必须创造一个环境，让员工有动力集体工作，同时感到自己受到重视和认可。好奇和好奇。 An entire organization with a growth mindset that embraces questions and curiosity can reframe challenges as opportunities and move more freely to adjust to business conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What It Means to Be a Moral Leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;div js-target=&quot;video-player-page&quot; data-props=&quot;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;6337577423112&quot;}&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div >; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;加载中... &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption= &quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Dov Seidman 让人们认真思考，不仅思考他们做了什么，还思考他们如何做。他非常专注于“如何”做到这一点。他创建了 HOW 社会研究所，鼓励领导人走上道德领导之路。他甚至写了一本名为《如何：为什么我们做任何事意味着一切》的书。在我们每周直播系列节目“工作的新世界”的这一集中，塞德曼提供了关于当今良好的道德领导力的见解和灵感——在一个永远混乱的时代。他的中心思想是旧的领导方式不再有效。他向观众发起挑战，请他们选出一位近年来取得成功的指挥与控制型市长、大公司首席执行官或职业教练。他说得有道理。我们对领导者的要求的期望是：也许有一个明显的例子，那就是国家政治人物——现在包括同理心、脆弱性、正直和道德。 &lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader ?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader?language=pt&quot;>;阅读葡萄牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;还记得领导人何时可以通过说“商业就是商业”来回避在敏感的政治或社会问题上采取立场吗？ HOW 社会研究所创始人兼主席多夫·塞德曼 (Dov Seidman) 表示，这种冷漠的中立态度已经不再有效。 “我认为商业的本质就是社会，”他说。 “这是社区，以及我们如何应对遇到的一切，以及我们的深思熟虑和原则性。”坚持正义的领导者是员工、客户和其他利益相关者的新期望。更不用说感恩节餐桌上的亲戚了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着人工智能的发展并挑战人类对智力的垄断，道德判断和同理心等纯粹的人类技能对于领导者来说变得更加重要。塞德曼说，虽然机器可以被教导做正确的事情，但只有人才能带领他人做正确的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于我们视频系列“工作新世界”的这一集，《哈佛商业评论》主编Adi Ignatius 与 Seidman 进行了座谈，Seidman 也是《How: Why How We》一书的作者做任何事情都意味着一切&lt;/a>;&lt;/em>;，讨论：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;如何让你的原则指导你作为领导者&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;暂停的重要性为了反思、重新联系、重新思考和重新构想你的使命&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;随着人工智能原始智能的增长，哪些人类特征和能力的价值将会增长&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;“&lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;工作新世界&lt;/a>;”探讨了高层管理人员如何看待未来以及他们的公司如何努力为成功做好准备。每周，Ignatius 都会在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/harvard-business-review/&quot;>;LinkedIn Live&lt;/a>; 上与一位高层领导交谈 - 之前的采访包括 &lt;a href=&quot; /2021/10/microsofts-satya-nadella-on-flexible-work-the-metaverse-and-the-power-of-empathy&quot;>;微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11 /indra-nooyi-前百事可乐首席执行官谈动荡时期的人才培养&quot;>;前百事可乐首席执行官英德拉·努伊&lt;/a>;。他还在专门为《哈佛商业评论》订阅者提供的时事通讯中分享了对这些对话的内部看法，并为未来的讨论征求问题。如果您是订阅者，可以在&lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences?movetile=newworldofwork&quot;>;此处&lt;/a>;注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;工作新世界&quot; dek=&quot;前几集&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of -work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合&lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;工作新世界&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 前几集 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt; p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dov，欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢谢，阿迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您对领导力的道德方面思考了很多。在这个感觉像是永久颠覆的时代，优秀的领导力是什么样的？&lt;/p>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;newsletter&quot; name=&quot;The New World of Work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;follow-subscribe data -name=&quot;hbpnewworldofwork&quot; data-activity=&quot;newsletter&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div style=&quot;color: #000000&quot;>; &lt;svg>; &lt;use xlink:href=&quot;/resources/css/images/hbr- icon.svg#the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;&lt;/use>; &lt;/svg>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 订阅我们的每周通讯 &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;工作世界 &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; 关于人才、技术和商业未来的坦诚对话。为订阅者准备的特别电子邮件系列。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; js-target=&quot;subscribe-for-newsletter-tout&quot; data-method=&quot;subscribe&quot;>;注册&lt;/a>; &lt;/ div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/sign-in&quot; js-target=&quot;sign-in-this&quot;>;注册&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe&quot;>;签名向上&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 感谢您注册，&lt;span js-target=&quot;newsletter-success-firstname&quot;>; &lt;/span>;！ &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; 您可以查看我们的&lt;a href=&quot;/email-newsletters&quot;>;其他新闻通讯&lt;/a>;或通过管理您的&lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences&quot;>;随时选择退出电子邮件首选项&lt;/a>;。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/follow-subscribe>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;优秀领导者要做的第一件事他们会退后一步，试图理解他们所领导的世界。领导力与头条新闻无关。我们都可以阅读这些内容，推文到推文，帖子到帖子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是关于趋势线的，世界将走向何方？哪些熟悉和陌生的力量正在重塑它？我们用什么框架来判断未来？我们将使用什么剧本来吸引人们踏上通往未来的旅程？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我还喜欢说，平静的大海从来不会造就伟大的水手，而外面的大海并不平静。 。因此，如果你想成为一名伟大的领导者，在波涛汹涌的大海上航行就是其中的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导力始终很重要，它始终具有重要意义。我们将通过一些例子来说明领导力可能比以前更重要，因为它会产生回响。但我们正处于一个一切都被扰乱的时代，包括领导力和权威本身。负责一个组织、一个团队或其他人的意义已经与过去不同了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想构建我认为最伟大的 21 世纪领导力挑战，然后我们可以讨论什么样的领导层应对它。我想你和你的观众都会同意，如果没有正式的授权，你就无法管理一家公司、一个团队、一个国家。人们需要负责。我无法想象一支没有主教练的足球队，一所没有校长的学校，一家没有首席执行官的公司，或者一个没有总统或总理的国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我们都知道，组织当具有道德权威的个人占据这些正式权威的职位时，人类和社会才能真正发挥作用。在不太透明、更不透明的世界里，我们经常将两者混为一谈：“他一定是一个伟人，否则他是怎么达到那么高的地位的？”或者，“除非他是一位出色的领导者，否则董事会不会把他放在那里。”但现在我们看到，正式权力可以被夺取，你可以在选举中赢得它，其他人可以将其授予你，“我特此任命你为副总统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但道德权威确实是取决于你是谁、你体现的价值观、你如何领导、你如何做出决定以及你如何与他人相处。在这个颠覆的时代，我们面临的挑战是，正式权威已被破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;硅谷企业家，即使拥有 20 比 1 的超级多数股权，也无法保住自己的工作，如果他们没有以开明的方式领导，甚至更糟糕的是，存在一些不当行为。我们看到社会各个领域的正式权威被推翻和破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;挑战在于我们如何培养和发展以道德权威领导的道德领袖文化？这是第一步。我们如何确保他们是发号施令、担任正式权力职位的人？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想补充一点，就领导力而言，这场流行病的遗产是，它已经揭示并阐明了道德领导的重要性。不仅仅是最高层，学校校长、星巴克的咖啡师、组织、部门和社会各个层面的商店经理：领导力都很重要。因为特别是在危机时期，当人们自然地感到不确定和害怕时，他们会求助于任何对他们有一定权威的人。他们对他们的期望是真理，一些智慧，一些无私，真正把对方放在第一位。他们期待道德领导力，阿迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个很好的框架。你使用了“道德”这个词。在我们的世界里，为《哈佛商业评论》撰稿的人通常倾向于使用“良好的领导力”之类的术语。优秀的领导者除了拥有你需要的商业头脑之外，还具有同理心，他们很脆弱，但你使用“道德”这个词。你这是什么意思？为什么这是你的中心框架？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我所说的并不是说教、成为道德，或者成为如何应对道德困境的专家，或者如何在社会、政治、环境、宗教问题上采取立场的专家，即使它可能包括这些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道德领导实际上是关于如何。你如何领导、如何决策，是成本效益分析吗？还是有原则指导？你是否愿意做不方便、勇敢和困难的事情，因为这是原则或价值观对你的要求？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这实际上是关于你如何与他人相处和对话。是单向还是双向？这就是您结束会议的方式。你会说：“我们聊得很愉快吗？是谁的电话？哦，这是一个营销决定。谁有营销预算？”这是用权力来界定它，“这是谁的电话？”不如问：“什么是正确的选择？我们认为什么是公平的呼吁？什么是尊重并忠于我们价值观的召唤？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想了解一整套剧本，但现在我只想说，这不是道德说教。这实际上是关于如何做的。你如何运用权力，你如何做出决定，你如何行事，以及你在自己的价值观方面所体现的真正含义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许我们可以将这些纳入《哈佛商业评论》观众都在苦苦挣扎的问题中。阿迪，你在《哈佛商业评论》上写了很多关于我们在工作场所取得成功需要更多的行为和品质的文章。如果我能让你处于困境的话，你为什么不说出一些名字呢？为了赢得今天的胜利，我们希望我们的同事和队友有哪些行为？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好吧，相信。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;多夫·赛德曼：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信任。好吧，我要把这些写下来。信任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我之前谈到过诸如同理心、脆弱性、承诺之类的事情。我们不是在谈论个人贡献者，而是在谈论团队和公司，因此是共同的承诺和团队意识。请随意添加，这些只是一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些并不是可有可无的，这就是你所拥有的弄清楚今天很重要吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;您刚才没有提到的一些事情是效率、生产力和速度。你在呼唤人类品质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为道德领袖非常清楚改变行为和提升行为之间的区别。因为领导力是关于如何做的。 How we get people to do things, how we generate energy in them, how we enlist them in journeys and missions worthy of their dedication and loyalty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I were to put a product on sale, I could get you to buy now and not later, or more not less. If we create a great political attack ad I could get you to vote left not right, or right not left. We know how to use carrots and sticks to shift or nudge behavior. If you give me enough carrots and sticks, I could get you to work faster, maybe have fewer sick days, work 10 hours and not eight.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the behaviors that you asked for, Adi, no amount of carrots and sticks can get you because this is human beings acting and behaving in their most elevated way. Can you imagine saying to somebody, go in a room and don&#39;t come out or you&#39;ll be fired if you can&#39;t come out with empathy and the ability to engender trust in the other, or you find more courage in being vulnerable. There are no amount of carrots that can coerce people into these behaviors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let&#39;s try bonuses, and no amount of sticks. Let&#39;s try carrots. If you tripled everybody&#39;s salaries, Adi, would you get more empathy? Would you get more trust?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You would not. Probably not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We might get the opposite. We find ourselves in a discontinuous moment in leadership where what we want in and out of people, no amount of carrots and sticks can get us.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m not against sticks. There should be fireable offenses. But should the fear of being fired animate 2% or 98% of how things happen around this place? I&#39;m really for carrots too. I think we should pay our colleagues as much as possible and hopefully more than our competitors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what moral leaders understand is that certain behaviors cannot be coerced. They cannot be motivated, they can only be inspired. Moral leaders are inspirational leaders because trust, empathy, vulnerability, collaborating, honesty, courage, all these human elevated qualities that we aspire to see in those around us must and can only be inspired.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More leaders understand the difference. We&#39;re seeing this play out in return to the office. More leaders know that if you were my subordinate, Adi, I could insist never lie to me, always tell me the truth, but I could never insist, always be loyal to me. Moral leaders know that certain things they can insist on and other things they have to inspire. And we&#39;re actually seeing this play out with who&#39;s insisting that people come back to the office and who&#39;s trying to inspire it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leadership paradigms do shift. And in the past it was command control, “I am the boss.” “I say, you do.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re in an era now where we want the empathetic leader and the vulnerable leader. It&#39;s possible there&#39;ll be another turn of the wheel before long and there&#39;s another leadership paradigm.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is there science, or are there metrics to show that this approach to leadership not only is right in some 30,000-foot moralistic definition, but also in terms of outcome and performance for an institution?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let&#39;s get into the science and metrics, but before we do that, here&#39;s what&#39;s not going to change. There&#39;s only two types of behaviors. There&#39;s what you can and can&#39;t do, and what you should and should not do. I believe that Supreme Court Justice Potter Stewart said there&#39;s a difference between doing that which you have a right to do and that which is right to do.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We used to specify to people, here&#39;s what you can and can&#39;t do. And then we asked them to pursue goals and strategies mindful of what they can and can&#39;t do as fast and as ambitiously, and they had to outcompete on that basis. In that world, the few, a military general would say, take that hill. A CEO would say, “This is our strategy, these are our goals.” And in that world, everybody&#39;s job is to do the next thing right.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the way the world is working today, we want more and more people to not just do the next thing right, but to do the next right thing. I don&#39;t think that shift is ever going back from asking people to do the next thing right, to inspiring them to do the next right thing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Computers could be programmed to do the next thing right. Only a human being can do the next right thing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think we are now in a normative environment, normative as in norms, what you should and should not do. And moral leaders get out of bed to foster normative cultures where people are “should-minded” and that is here to stay.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason there&#39;s such an obsession with culture is corporate culture was invented, all culture was invented, to transmit norms from one generation to another. Norms as in what we ought to do and should do. You don&#39;t need culture if you&#39;re just going to specify the rules and the policies and the procedures, but you need to be deliberate and intentional about scaling values, values-based cultures, if you&#39;re going to be normative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think this is a fad. I think the world has been reshaped in ways to put us in a normative environment. We&#39;re seeing that in society, in community, and in companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think that&#39;s true. I think there&#39;s also a counterargument though, and maybe this is just high level political counter, but I feel like historians will look back at this era and define it perhaps as one of renewed autocracy, a move away from some of the ideals that you&#39;re talking about. Does that strike you as accurate?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I said that leadership is about trendlines. Let&#39;s step back. Can you name an autocratic mayor succeeding in terms of how his or her city is being led? Can you think of an autocratic CEO running a Fortune 500 company? Can you think of a championship won in basketball, baseball, soccer, world cup soccer, name the sport in the last 10 years, run by command and control screaming, that top-down coach?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Autocracy is asserting itself or reasserting itself in national politics where a dictator still has his hands on the levers of the military and ability to engage in propaganda, etc. There&#39;s an epic battle between Putin&#39;s autocracy and Zelenskyy&#39;s moral leadership. But if you step back, I&#39;m seeing some wonderful trends towards moral leadership in so many other more local sectors and dimensions of our lives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason I brought up sports is sports is about winning. It&#39;s about becoming a champion and it&#39;s incredible who&#39;s winning in sports. I mean, Steve Kerr with the Golden State Warriors had great talent, but so did his competitors. He had such a bad back one year that he missed 43 games. He wasn&#39;t even there to do the coaching and they did it through a trust-based culture.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jill Ellis, when she was winning champions as coach of the American women in soccer, she knew the names of the dogs and cats of every one of her players. That&#39;s just a symbol of how personal her coaching began.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You had &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/01/us-soccers-gregg-berhalter-on-rebuilding-trust-in-the-wake-of-controversy&quot;>;Gregg Berhalter on your show&lt;/a>;, and the US men&#39;s team has been incredibly successful in the last World Cup, and aiming to eclipse that in the next one. But if you listen to how the players talked about what they built there, it was an identity forged in unity. Even though they were a very young team, they tried to outcompete by out-behaving the competition through qualities of boldness and resilience, etc. I have more examples, but I am pretty positive about some large trends here.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I asked if this is the era of autocracy, part of it is it seems that leadership, at a certain level, political leadership at least, no longer feels shame. I&#39;m old enough that I remembered Richard Nixon and Nixon was accused, was impeached, and clearly he felt shame, and at that point he decided to step down.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m not sure today&#39;s political leaders feel shame. And if they don&#39;t feel that, then you open the door for untruths, rival truths, just no sense of responsibility, of morality. I worry about that. I worry that that has been a successful model for some political leaders and that it could inspire others to try to follow that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think that&#39;s a very serious worry. When you mentioned President Nixon, when he said, “I&#39;m not a crook,” he didn&#39;t want us to think that he&#39;s a crook, and whether he was a crook or not, he was celebrating the norm, “Let&#39;s not be crooks.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe we are now living in an era of impunity where some people in power are not just misbehaving, they&#39;re doing it with impunity. And impunity takes out and erodes the norm. Not only are we getting the harm that people in high places are causing through their conduct or nefarious conduct, but you do it with impunity, say, “My words are perfect, I&#39;d do it again.” Or they make the rest of us feel that we are somehow losers for wanting to live up to high standards and norms of conduct. You erode the norms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But that&#39;s an argument for why we need moral leaders, because moral leaders safeguard norms and they help create organizations and communities that are really there to be in fidelity to high norms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kanye West, right before his divorce with Adidas, said horrific things and hateful things online. Whether he meant it or not, we could debate, but he said them. But then he said one more thing: There&#39;s nothing Adidas can do to me. That&#39;s a statement of impunity. Adidas took a several billion [dollar] hit at the end of the day by fighting against that, by severing that relationship.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re seeing this battle of not just misconduct, but misconduct with impunity and those standing up to it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I think of the moral leader, in some ways I think about somebody who leads by example, who just sort of does the right thing and you realize this person is trustworthy, is upright, is inspiring.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s a new world now for leadership. We&#39;ve talked about this in previous shows where there is this inescapable imperative for leaders, for CEOs to respond to social and even political issues that lap up against their company, or sometimes are separate from it but employees and customers demand to know where the leader stands.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the way, if there isn&#39;t an overt statement, employees and customers will assume and fill the sentence for you. You might as well take a stand. This is tricky territory.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is there a framework for how a leader manages this new world of perpetual social issues that they&#39;re asked to somehow declare on?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m going to date maybe you. In the movie &lt;em>;The Graduate&lt;/em>;, [a character says to] the Dustin Hoffman character, “The future is plastics.” You just used the word Adi, which is the future is frameworks. All human judgment is framework-dependent. The prevailing framework in business is cost-benefit analysis. Now we need to create and scale new frameworks that are normative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world is so interdependent where the hopes, dreams, plight of one person are showing up viscerally and visually on tiny screens in our hands. I mentioned Kanye West. After his divorce with Adidas, he showed up in the lobby of Sketchers, and before Sketchers knew it, they were involved in a social maelstrom of how to respond to his appearance there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One thing I know for sure that the world has been reshaped in ways to fuse it. Social, environmental, political, human issues, what just happened with the Supreme Court with abortion or how to respond to the invasion of Ukraine: these issues that were once deemed tangential to the business agenda are now inescapably part of it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Neutrality is over. There is an expectation to have a point of view, especially from employees and consumers and other stakeholders. We need a framework for that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pfizer has a great framework. Sally Susman has spoken about it publicly. Does it align with our purpose, given our values, what should our point of view be? How does it impact our constituents? What would be the price of our silence?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tom Wilson has done a great job at Allstate with his framework. There&#39;s a threshold question: “Is what&#39;s going on legal? But even if so, given our values, what should our point of view be? Then if not, let&#39;s continue to challenge these ideas.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think taking a stand is now something where you don&#39;t just get to say, “Hey, I just run a business. The business of business is business.” I think the business of business is society, it&#39;s community, and how we relate to whatever comes our way, and how thoughtfully and principled we are is now the new expectation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanksgiving dinner is coming in a few months and employees are going to sit there and run into their cousins that they haven&#39;t seen in a long time. At the end of the day, a CEO has to ask herself this question, “Are my colleagues going to be proud of Thanksgiving dinner to brag to their cousins about how their company handled this issue and that issue and this issue and that issue that is now part of their business agenda?” We have to pass that Thanksgiving dinner test.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I love that. I also love the future is in frameworks. I want to go to an audience question now, and this is from Srinivas in India. In an era now where artificial intelligence may be better at making decisions based on data than humans are, can we say that the time has come for conscience-based management or leadership?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five hundred years ago we had the scientific revolution, and that was a true revolution. Uber putting yellow taxi cabs in or out of business, LinkedIn maybe making it harder for recruiters, those are disruptions. True revolutions happen about every 500 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the technological revolution and the revolution that&#39;s being accelerated through AI is an every-500-year revolution. 500 years ago, we looked around and we wanted to be in charge of our surroundings and we said, “We&#39;re the smartest.” Descartes said, “I think, therefore I am.” It was 500 years of revenge of the nerds, and we called it the era of enlightenment and reason. We pretty much organized our affairs by being the smartest. It&#39;s incredible what we achieved: modern capitalism, we proliferated individual rights, biodiversity. It&#39;s incredible what was achieved in the last 500 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s interesting about AI is it is challenging our monopoly on intelligence. We&#39;re no longer the smartest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s the one thing a machine will never have? A heart. I actually think the technological revolution is putting into stark relief and focus the imperative to scale that which comes from the heart. There&#39;s an adage of moral leadership that only that which comes from the heart enters the heart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an economic standpoint in the industrial age, we hired hands and we hired strong hands. Then we went into the knowledge or information economy and we hired heads and we favored knowledge and expertise and specialization. I think we&#39;re going into a more human age where the qualities that emanate from the heart, like the ones you mentioned, empathy and the ability to do the right thing in our capacity for ethics and morality and conscience is now something we&#39;re going to have to scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What worries me, Adi, is that when social networks were first launched, we had some utopian thinking, anything that connects the world is going to be great. We will have richer human experiences. Individuals will be empowered. In the first innings we saw pictures of dogs and cats and our acquaintances became close friends again.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But then we started to see that technology is a force for good and bad. Good things can happen and harmful things can happen, including democratic elections being hacked. We saw that we are not just organically divided, but the profit motive has been &amp;nbsp;behind division and people are now pitted against each other and we&#39;re being actively divided through technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those in charge back then often said, “We&#39;re just technology. We&#39;re just a platform.” They proclaimed their moral neutrality. I think, Adi, more important than anything now, we cannot afford with ChatGPT and generative AI to say, “It&#39;s just technology.” We know that good and harmful things are going to happen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people are talking about the possible end of humanity. The need for Spider-Man ethics, that with great power comes responsibility, has never been more important. I think those who are purveying these new technologies have unprecedented power, and they&#39;re going to need to scale conscience and Spider-Man ethics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;ve been talking mostly about morality and leadership at the highest level, that good leaders have it and people who are selecting good leaders should look for that. This is a question from Shabana from Islamabad in Pakistan. What role do you think leadership development can play in ensuring that individuals throughout an organization embody the same moral values?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s a great question. Moral leadership, there&#39;s an opportunity to build capacities, not skills, but qualities and capacities. And I think organizations can do that. There are some practices we need to scale of moral leadership and I&#39;m happy to mention a few.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to start with the most counterintuitive practice and piece of advice. I think everybody on this gathering would agree that the world&#39;s accelerating, it&#39;s always on. We&#39;re being digitally assaulted. We all experience FOMO, fear of missing out. Fair enough, Adi?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far so good.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The faster the world gets, and the more that comes at us, the more we need to pause. The hallmark of moral leadership is the pause. [Ralph Waldo] Emerson said that, “In each pause, I hear the call,” because only when we pause can we even ask ourselves important questions that a moral leader would ask. “How would I feel like if I were treated this way?” “What&#39;s the consequences of doing it this way or that way?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I like to talk about the four Rs, because in the pause, we can reflect on the challenge, the situation of the world in which we&#39;re operating. We can reconnect with our deeper sense of purpose and our values and conscience. We can rethink some of our assumptions of how we&#39;re operating, how we&#39;re making money, how we&#39;re making decisions. And only then can we reimagine a better solution, or a better path, or a better future. The hallmark of moral leadership is the pause.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral leaders also eschew philosophical mistakes. People think, “Oh, moral leaders must be about empowerment.” Well, that&#39;s true spiritually, but often empowerment, you know what happens? This is how a nonmoral leader might sound, “I push decisions to the front lines. I delegate authority.” And they think they&#39;re leading, and then five years later, everybody has all these rights, “I can spend $1,000 without asking my boss for permission.” “I can get on an airplane to a trade association meeting and spend money without asking for permission.” And you&#39;ve built a culture where everybody knows what rights they have. They&#39;re empowered in that way. But you haven&#39;t built a gym where they know the ethos. “What is the way here?”, where they know what is right.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;[Airbnb CEO] Brian Chesky recently came out against this form of empowerment, and said that he wants to be an orchestrator. Moral leaders don&#39;t just get out of the way and delegate. They show up, and they sit at the back of the room sometimes. They don&#39;t provide the answer. They ask the right questions. So there really are opportunities to be incisive and rigorous about what it is and what it&#39;s not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You&#39;ve identified the hallmarks of moral leadership. I&#39;m curious, as you look out at US companies, global companies, are many of them or most of them run by people you would consider moral leaders?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two things: I think what matters is not to look for beacons. I&#39;ve never seen a unicorn, but I&#39;ve seen a horse. I&#39;ve seen a horn. I&#39;ve seen white. I look for who&#39;s engendering trust by extending it. Who&#39;s creating such a high-trust environment where people feel that they can lean and take risks in order to innovate?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most innovation programs fail because trust is so low that people won&#39;t take the risk in order to innovate. I look not for perfection, and I think what matters most, Adi, is not who&#39;s a beacon and an icon of moral leadership, but who is authentically and deliberately on the journey. Who&#39;s taking risk in that regard? Who&#39;s being courageous in that regard? It&#39;s not about perfection in that way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And maybe I should end with the following: linearity is over in this world. We&#39;re in an up-and-down world, and the leaders who frame the future as a journey really elevate others, because nothing elevates a human beings more than being on a journey of progress, where we go up and down, but we stick together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Increasingly, I&#39;m seeing people have the confidence and the courage to frame that path ahead as a journey, develop an ethos for being on a journey together. I really think that nothing elevates somebody else more than framing the path ahead as a journey and creating an ethos where together, we can journey together, because to journey is to do something human.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s fantastic. Your words are inspiring.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can I say one last thing? Did you ever hear in business, “Hope is not a strategy?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through budgeting, planning, and control, we&#39;re going to superimpose the future, and that&#39;s kind of, “Hope is not a strategy.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Well, I&#39;m also here to say that without hope, there is no strategy. Moral leaders purvey hope, and they inspire hope in others by really helping them see possibility, helping them embrace the commonality in the other, so that we can do things together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral leaders really fight against the non-adage that hope is not a strategy, because they know that without hope, there is no strategy, and they&#39;re prepared to paint a picture of a distant future, but with rigor to go that way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to apologize for not answering your question before about metrics. I&#39;m just going to say the following. Metrics are moral choices. When we measure something, we&#39;re saying it matters. When we don&#39;t measure something, we say it doesn&#39;t matter. Moral leaders pause, and they pick the right metrics that move them on the journey, because they know that metrics don&#39;t come from on high. In and of themselves, they reflect our values.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dov Seidman, thank you for being on “The New World of Work”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adi, great to be with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Web3 Could Change the Business Model of Creative Work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_skizzomat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Skizzomat&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Web3 &amp;#8212; the read-write-own web &amp;#8212; could offer a new model for creative work. By offering new tools to earn and own assets, build wealth, and wrestle back control from powerful platforms and intermediaries, it has the potential to simplify how creators fund their ventures and new ways to earn a living, not just on the first sale of a work of art but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/nfts/earnings&quot;>;perpetuity&lt;/a>; thanks to programmatic royalty streams paid via smart contracts, self-executing code that can move and store money. If Web1 and Web2 democratized access to information and made it easier to collaborate online, Web3 equips creators with a new toolkit to build real wealth from their work, on a globally level playing field.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;For most of the industrial age, technology has acted as a tailwind for creators, powering an age of mass culture that supported a professional class of working artists. However, more recently, the rise of &lt;em>;digital &lt;/em>;technology — specifically, the internet and AI — has become a source of economic dislocation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web1, the so-called “read web,” was a digital printing press that democratized access to information, but it also commoditized art and music and undermined creators&#39; rights as their IP got laundered in the web&#39;s swirling washing machine of content.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web2, the “read-write web,” made it easier to publish content, share ideas and access a broader audience (ie, “write” to the internet) but it also confined creators to tightly run platforms they did not trust or control and where they lacked transparency into the economic impact of their work. Either that or risk the wilderness of the web where their creations could be copied without recourse. Digital artists had no easy way to monetize their creations and could not benefit when works were resold.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platforms that control content distribution have grown richer and more powerful, with precious little of that windfall trickling down to creators. Consider the strikes of the Writers Guild of America (WGA) and the Screen Actors Guild–American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG–AFTRA). Streaming has already shortened television seasons, shrunk writers&#39; rooms, and eroded artists&#39; traditional residual revenues; and generative AI and 3D modeling give companies more tools for further minimizing their use of writers and actors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/05/what-is-web3&quot;>;Web3&lt;/a>; — the read-write-own web — offers new tools to earn and own assets, build wealth, and wrestle back control from powerful platforms and intermediaries. Web3 could simplify how creators fund their ventures by crowdsourcing new titles directly from their fans. It could offer new ways to earn a living, not just on the first sale of a work of art but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/nfts/earnings&quot;>;perpetuity&lt;/a>; thanks to programmatic royalty streams paid via smart contracts, self-executing code that can move and store money. In other words, it might offer a new model for creative work.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;AI: Risk or Opportunity?&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Now, new technologies — namely, generative AI — pose new challenges for composers, screenwriters, visual artists, and other creative workers. It is too early to say whether AI will be all bad for all of them; it may expanding the ranks of professional artists or grow the market for culture and creating opportunities for humans to co-create or collaborate with AI on an equal footing. But it could also starkly devalue the work of copywriters, composers, and artists, and relegate these workers to supporting roles, such as polishing scripts or adding some depth of feeling to digitally rendered art. Cezanne said, “A work of art which did not begin in emotion is not art,” but plenty of studio executives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/disney-creates-task-force-explore-ai-cut-costs-sources-2023-08-08/&quot;>;see AI as a way to cut costs&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By analyzing hundreds of thousands of scripts against their viewership patterns over time, AI will get better at mimicking the stickiest and most bingeworthy of screenwriters&#39; styles, characters, and plots, not just to extend the arcs of existing stories but to synthesize all-new series and recommend the optimal cast or mix of character types. Ditto on the virtual replication of actors, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/indiana-jones-and-the-dial-of-destiny-de-aging-tech/&quot;>;tools like FaceSwap already in use&lt;/a>; to de-age stars like Harrison Ford for his latest portrayal of Indiana Jones. But such big names likely consent to such innovations on their own terms. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/money/2023/8/22/23840473/writers-strike-actors-wga-sag-workers-economy-impact&quot;>;As &lt;em>;Vox&lt;/em>; put it&lt;/a>;, “If people don&#39;t lock down control of their digital twins, then nothing else matters.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oscar winning director Stephen Soderbergh &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/steven-soderbergh-streaming-data-transparency-1235551409/&quot;>;told the &lt;em>;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; that, more than AI or visual effects, what keeps him up at night is the opacity of streaming data: He speculates that the studios are doing really well and don&#39;t want to share the wealth, or else really poorly and don&#39;t want their stocks to tank.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Artists hoped that the internet would help to disintermediate gatekeepers and middlemen, and change power dynamics in creative industries, but instead it added new intermediaries like streamers and platforms that distanced artists from their fans and obfuscated their economic impact. We need something different.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Culture Needs a New Business Model&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If technology is upending the longstanding business model of creative industries, it&#39;s also offering opportunities to establish a new one that can work better for creative workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web3 technologies can simplify how creators track the usage of their IP and to monetize it, ensuring they get paid promptly and fairly for their work. For instance, Web3 technologies could allow artists to grow and perhaps even thrive along with AI, rather than suffer at its expense. For example, smart contracts can create avenues for artists to be compensated when their work is used to train AI like a large language model.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web3 adds an &lt;em>;economic layer&lt;/em>; and a &lt;em>;rights layer&lt;/em>; to the Internet stack, where users can not only track the provenance of information and intellectual property but also protect, manage, and monetize these digital assets themselves with transparency peer to peer. These innovations can also change how creative ventures are funded, removing industry gatekeepers and amplifying underrepresented voices. In the Philippines, independent game studios are selling NFTs of in-game assets to gamers directly to fund new titles, disintermediating big studios and traditional financial backers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Jules Urbach, CEO of cloud graphics company OTOY, Web3 is fit for this purpose. OTOY&#39;s flagship product, OctaneRender, is what&#39;s known as an “unbiased, spatially correct graphics processing unit (GPU) render engine,” which is the industry&#39;s way of describing powerful software that can render more lifelike images and video than what came before. Marvel Studios used OctaneRender in the opening of &lt;em>;Ant-Man and the Wasp&lt;/em>;, according to Urbach.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using the cloud, OTOY is able to harness dozens — and sometimes hundreds — of GPUs at a time in its network to break down projects into smaller parts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By breaking up tasks, OTOY helps democratize the compute-intensive process of rendering, allowing artists to render in a couple of minutes what used to take hours on expensive hardware setups. Most important, anything created in the render network creates a hash on a blockchain, for the verifiable provenance essential to managing artists&#39; IP rights and moving digital goods from platform to platform. With such capabilities, artist guilds could create a set of smart contract templates for their members to use in managing such life-like renderings of themselves — their digital twins — and collect privatized data on industry usage that would give them bargaining power in future negotiations. The contracts could represent the artist guilds&#39; negotiated terms, plus whatever the individual artists or their agents have negotiated.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;From Hollywood to Everywhere&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This technology also offers artists ways to flip the traditional top-down model where studios and streamers try to control everything from IP to distribution. Hollywood screenwriter Jessie Nickson-Lopez has brought some of modern TV&#39;s most indelible characters to life. As a founding member of the writing team on &lt;em>;Stranger Things&lt;/em>;, she developed the story line for the character Eleven. Recently, as cofounder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mv3.io/&quot;>;Web3 startup MV3&lt;/a>;, she launched a collection of 6,500 non-fungible tokens (NFTs) of different characters, the building blocks for what will be a richly rendered narrative “universe,” originally created by Nickson-Lopez and her team. Set in the “dystopian cyberpunk society” of 2081, after the “climate has gone to hell,” MV3 focuses on “a ragtag group of idealistic” rebels struggling to “take power from the corporation that owns the city.” NFT owners will participate in the IP, have a say in their character&#39;s arc, and even co-create the story with the MV3 team. These different character assets could ultimately appear in film, TV, and other storytelling media. They could be playable characters in videogames or avatars in the metaverse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing that fans will support a project is key for firing up the Hollywood machine to spend $100 million or more on a film or TV show. Nickson-Lopez said, “So we reverse-engineered it, and I created the world of Eluna City and the characters that reside in it.” Though Nickson-Lopez architected this world and crafted story lines for main characters, MV3 will not decide the direction of the story. “For me, what&#39;s been most exciting is seeing how much creativity we&#39;re inspiring in people who have never created before but are consumers of dystopian worlds and of fiction. There&#39;s this hunger to play. Our fans are our community and our co-creators. Because they&#39;re invested in the world and in the characters, they&#39;re really excited to build it up with us.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MV3 inverts the Hollywood model. “As my lawyers say, &#39;It&#39;s like you&#39;re ripping off pieces of value and just giving it to people.&#39; And we&#39;re like, &#39;Exactly! That&#39;s exactly what we&#39;re doing.&#39;” Recently, the founders handed control day-to-day control of the MV3 universe to the community.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Ultimately, projects like OctaneRender and MV3 will work because they engage their communities not only in the economic upside but also in the governance. Handing over control and economics to fans is antithetical to the Hollywood model, and Nickson-Lopez recognizes that. Engaging people in the creative process, for love of the experience and not just for money, is what clearly drives these creators and gives their projects purpose and meaning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology tools and human capital are more distributed than ever. If Web1 and Web2 democratized access to information and made it easier to collaborate online, Web3 equips creators with a new toolkit to build real wealth from their work, on a globally level playing field. As the saying goes, the future is not to be predicted; it is to be achieved. For cultural industries and much else, Web3 can help us do it.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>