<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[What&rsquo;s Lost When Data Systems Don&rsquo;t Communicate]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/whats-lost-when-data-systems-dont-communicate]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_11_6551-000359-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Raimund Koch/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot; close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;在每个行业，许多大公司都拥有帮助桥接过时、断开连接的系统和数据库的团队。没有它们，公司就无法在不中断运营的情况下升级技术。问题在于，在断开连接或几乎不修补的系统上运行公司会影响各个级别的员工。要了解断开连接的系统给公司带来的成本是什么？ “断网债务” &amp;#8212;作者测量了由于断开连接的系统而产生的信息孤岛对公司 100 多个团队的业务成果的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/whats-lost-when-data-systems-dont-communicate?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/whats-lost -when-data-systems-dont-communicate?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;想象一个场景。凯利是一家大型医院网络的一名敬业员工，她准备好迎接新一天处理心烦意乱的顾客的情况。作为消费者关系团队的成员，她处理了多次被转接的患者的升级电话。她当天的挑战涉及一位潜在的阿尔茨海默病患者从不同的医院网络寻求第二意见。不幸的是，这位患者被告知凯利的网络无法以电子方式传输医疗记录，因此可能需要花费 90 分钟来收集 CD 上的记录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在通话的压力下，凯利认为根本原因是内部系统内的同步问题。她采取了主动行动，浏览了各种系统，包括电子健康记录系统、档案、健康交换和健康信息服务提供商系统。 Kelly 手动解决了同步问题并确保记录发送完毕，赢得了患者的感激。这种服务行为特别有意义，因为她自己有年迈的父母，给凯利带来了巨大的快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天，像凯利这样的几位超级倡导者在医院网络中工作，解决众多会员问题，这些问题主要源于现代化进程已经成熟，或者不同的系统需要相互通信。事实上，在每个行业，许多大公司都有这样的团队，他们帮助弥合过时、脱节的系统和数据库。没有它们，公司就无法在不中断运营的情况下升级技术。这种情况虽然是想象出来的，但在现实中在公司和行业中普遍存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于，在断开连接或几乎不拼凑在一起的系统上运行公司会影响各个级别的员工。在另一个真实的案例中，一位《财富》500 强企业的首席财务官每个季度都在努力整合来自 50 家子公司的 70 多个系统的财务数据。该团队必须精心提取、协调、集成和验证来自这些系统的数据，这是一个耗时且危险的过程，容易出现错误。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight =&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;工作的未来&quot; dek=&quot;您的公司会适应还是被抛在后面？&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black ;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;工作的未来&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 您的公司会适应还是被抛在后面？ &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;每个季度财务团队和 IT 团队都会争论&lt;em>;相同&lt;/em>;问题：&lt;em>;为什么我们有大量不同的系统？为什么这些系统不互相通信？我们可以做些什么来消除这些造成更多风险、延误和工作量的数据孤岛？ &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;我们如何拆除这些导致风险、延迟和额外工作的数据孤岛？&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;像 Kelly、财务和 IT 团队以及 CFO 一样，大多数人无论从事什么工作、部门或行业，员工都熟悉这些挫败感的某些形式。他们花费数小时将数据从一个系统移动到另一个系统，对不兼容的应用程序进行故障排除，并且经常将这种功能障碍视为工作中不可避免的摩擦。但大多数公司并不知道问题有多严重，因为他们没有花时间来量化这种断开连接对业务成果的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;了解断开连接的系统给公司造成的损失 - 我们称之为“断网债务”——我们衡量了因断网系统而产生的信息孤岛对公司 100 多个团队的业务成果的影响。以下是公司需要了解的有关此问题的信息以及如何解决该问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;断开连接债务：业务中断开连接的系统的成本&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在理想的世界中，所有系统都处于一个组织将在后端通过 API 相互集成，并无缝地相互通信。对于用户（即员工）而言，这意味着避免从多个来源复制或提取信息的重复性手动工作。相反，理想情况下，用户应该利用他们的经验、判断和培训，根据系统提供的信息做出决策或建议，系统负责从多个来源收集信息的繁琐工作。 &amp;nbsp;但这种情况很少发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;存在断开连接的系统，因为每个系统都是为了满足组织在特定时间点的需求而构建的。但随着时间的推移，随着业务需求和工作流程的发展，这些系统的设计方式与不断变化的业务需求之间存在着差距。例如，云系统不与大型机系统通信。今天的新系统很可能是明天断开连接的遗留系统。当组织认为这是一个不可避免的问题时，他们就隐含地接受了长期成本：客户或最终消费者遇到的低效率、错误、延迟，以及收入风险、扩展障碍、客户体验、客户流失等方面的业务风险。 ，或市场份额的损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了弥合这些差距，所有组织都倾向于“让人员解决问题”：员工手动从多个系统中提取数据，做出决策，然后将数据输入回相关系统系统。这些员工充当不同系统之间的人类粘合剂，承担“转椅”的角色。当然，这会带来与&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/how-much-time-and-energy-do-we-waste-toggling- Between-applications&quot;>;在众多应用程序之间切换相关的认知和生产力成本&lt;/a>;。但这只是总成本的一部分。断开连接的系统会产生信息孤岛，导致大量的手动工作和执行过程中的过度延迟。最终，这些缺点凸显了脱节债务的真正成本：对组织成果和关键绩效指标持续产生负面影响，从而加剧风险。组织需要在很长一段时间内支付这些成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了了解断开连接的系统的拖累给公司带来了多大的损失，我们研究了超过 103 个团队，他们在 13 个关键领域的 1,000 多个实例中参与了超过 42 个流程。业务涵盖 10 家财富 500 强企业和 8 家中小企业。我们使用工作图（组织中团队如何工作的数字地图）来确定这些成本的产生地点和方式，并根据成本、客户体验、员工体验、收入和风险对它们进行排序。我们研究的公司涵盖银行、零售、电信、生命科学和消费品。为了估计断开连接的系统对业务成果的唯一影响，我们忽略了团队支付的切换税。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们发现断开连接的系统对业务成果的影响存在很大差异。在某些情况下，团队将多达 60% 的工作日时间花在此类系统产生的活动上——从多个系统提取信息、将数据输入其他系统等。这种低效的工作利用导致了“断网债务”——组织付出了高昂的代价下表总结了我们在各个职能部门和团队中发现的结果及其对业务成果的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;! -- table start -- 断开债务 -- ajrp 2023 -->;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;h4>;断开债务&lt;/h4>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;企业断开系统的成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;5&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot;>; &lt;thead>; &lt;tr>; &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;>;函数&lt;/th>; &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;>;流程&lt;/th>; &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/th>; &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot; 25%&quot;>;业务维度&lt;/th>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/thead>; &lt;tbody>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;职能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;供应链&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td >; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;订单管理&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class= &quot;&quot;>;订单创建和处理延迟了 11%&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;收入&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr >; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;职能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;供应链&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;规划&lt;/p >; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开系统的估计平均影响（断开债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;所有规划工作延迟 10%，影响季度收入&lt;/p>; &lt;/td >; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;成本&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;供应链&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;退货&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;估计平均影响（断网债务）断开连接的系统&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户退货延迟了 12%–18%，导致糟糕的客户体验和保留挑战&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/ p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客户服务&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;计费&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class =&quot;&quot;>;客户账单处理速度慢了 7%，导致客户保留率较差&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户体验&lt;/p>; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客户服务&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot; &quot;>;客户加入&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户加入速度慢 5%，可能导致客户数量减少满意度 (CSAT) 分数和较低的市场份额&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客户服务&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;订单履行&lt;/p >; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户订单处理速度减慢 15%，可能导致 CSAT 分数降低&lt;/p>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;收入/客户体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;客户服务&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;服务保证&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;预计断开连接的系统的平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;客户服务速度比预期慢 34%，导致 CSAT 分数较差&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt; /p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;成本/客户体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财务&lt;/p>; &lt;/ td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;应收账款&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开系统的估计平均影响（断开债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;由于应收账款延迟 16%，营运资金减少&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务规模&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;成本/风险&lt;/p >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;功能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财务&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class= &quot;&quot;>;应付账款&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开系统的估计平均影响（断开债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;供应商付款比预期慢 20%，可能领先更高的供应商流失率&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;成本&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;职能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人力资源&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;录用信&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt; td>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;新员工收到录用通知书慢了 8%&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;员工体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;职能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人力资源&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class= &quot;&quot;>;员工入职&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开系统的估计平均影响（断开债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;新员工在入职期间面临 11% 的延迟&lt; /p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;员工体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;职能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人力资源&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;招聘&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;招聘流程慢了 14%&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class =&quot;&quot;>;成本/员工经验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;职能&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人力资源&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;流程&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;培训&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;断开连接的系统的估计平均影响（断开连接债务）&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot; >;培训相关功能运行速度慢8%&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;p>;业务维度&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;成本/员工体验&lt;/p>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/ tr>; &lt;/tbody>; &lt;/table>; &lt;div>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;!-- 来源：此处 -->;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;!-- table end -- 断线债务 -- ajrp 2023 -->;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论公司规模如何，我们发现断线债务会导致执行速度变慢、手动工作过多以及出现更多错误。对业务成果的最终影响可能有多种可能性，包括收入增长放缓、成本增加、风险增加以及客户和员工体验较差。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，在上表中，断开连接的系统导致了总部位于美国的快速消费品零售商每年向分销渠道销售价值 3 亿美元的产品时，会额外延迟 10%（相当于额外几天）。同样，一家 F500 生命科学公司的 6,000 多名新员工在完成入职手续时又延迟了四个星期。最后，在一个例子中，注册新银行账户的客户在获得批准方面经历了几天的延迟。在此过程中，由于后端系统整合得不好，该组织与客户反复沟通，要求他们填写额外的表格和详细信息。而且内部流程缓慢，需要将多个系统的数据汇集在一起​​，然后将它们拼接在一起。所有这些不仅导致糟糕的客户体验，而且管理层担心他们可能会在竞争中失去潜在客户，因为竞争提供了更简化的注册体验。我们尚未研究的组织的其他领域也将遭受类似的断开系统成本。在团队没有遭受断线债务的少数情况下，我们发现他们要么在一个系统内执行所有工作，要么主要根据一个系统的数据参与决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;领导者可以做什么&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;随着业务需求的发展，由断开的系统产生的信息孤岛及其对业务成果造成的风险将继续成为现实。此问题会影响组织的所有部分，并给企业带来风险。因此，处理这个问题需要列入组织中所有领导者的议程。董事会中的首席执行官和风险委员会必须设定季度目标和指标，以积极跟踪和减轻因断开连接的系统而产生的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从本质上讲，组织需要采用产品管理生命周期方法来管理断开连接的系统，并始终保持在线状态&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;优先考虑哪些领域需要进一步调查和改进的经验法则 - 业务关键部分的团队花费超过 5% 的工作日从至少 2-3 个离线的地方提取信息系统。因此，首先，领导者的首要任务应该是获得可见性——找到可能损害业务的孤岛并减轻其影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1.了解断开连接的系统的存在及其对业务成果的影响&lt;/h3>; &lt;h3>;找到您的“Kellys”：&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;找到通常在一线的同事，对因断开连接而造成的客户挫败感有第一手的见解系统。培养一种文化，让他们可以公开与高层领导分享摩擦点，生成客户挑战的热图。通过社交倾听和高级领导者直接接触遇险电话来补充这一点。一些公司采取了“&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbsp.harvard.edu/product/115006-PDF-ENG&quot;>;零距离&lt;/a>;”方法，努力理解一线问题并系统地解决它们。&lt; /p>; &lt;h3>;为您的系统和流程创建遥测：&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;使用当今的工具，您可以绘制和测量系统交互，&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/12/do-you-know-how -your-teams-get-work-done&quot;>;创建“工作图”，即您的团队如何完成工作的地图&lt;/a>;。这有助于识别和量化断点，尤其是部门和系统之间的断点。因此，它允许您列出流程中最繁忙的断点的优先级列表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查找“Kellys”和工作图的组合为您提供了短期和长期攻击的优先级列表修复。 “Kellys”和工作图表测量中突出显示的重叠断点或摩擦点会产生您可以坚定地解决的优先事项。将此作为公司的每周纪律。根据这种可见性创建指标和目标，并将其一路发送给董事会的风险委员会。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;2.短期修复可以赢得时间。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;这些问题有短期修复，其功能更像是创可贴解决方案，容易受到业务变化的影响，包括收购、监管变化、流程变化、等等。但他们可以改善情况并为长期变革赢得更多时间。解决方案包括：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;构建单窗格应用程序：它们的唯一目的是从多个系统收集数据并将它们聚合到单个视图中。因此，用户不会花费精力从多个系统手动提取数据，而是专注于 &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/wellarchitected/latest/sap-lens/best-practice-1- 7.html&quot;>;单一应用程序窗口&lt;/a>;。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;自动化任务：从多个系统提取数据、预填充应用程序中的字段以及将数据写回到系统中。然而，这个解决方案是暂时的，因为它不能解决根本问题，并且可能只会导致在断开连接的解决方案之上激增更多的自动化解决方案。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;利用计算领域的最新进展：LLM 以及其他工具可能是对于从多个系统中提取非结构化信息、减少手动工作并将其标准化为结构化格式非常有用。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;这些解决方案将从断开连接的系统中提取信息的机械手动工作从人类转移到了软件。这种方法降低了脱节的风险，并为企业领导者提供了解决根本问题的空间。例如，尽管建立了自动化，但过时且缓慢的系统仍然会减慢整个航空公司预订流程和客户体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;3.长期修复。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;可持续的长期解决方案成本高昂且难以实施。通常，它们可能涉及：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;利用更新的技术从根本上重新设计系统：这些举措需要 18-36 个月的时间，并且通常涉及需要大量纪律的更大规模的变革管理工作。&lt;/li >; &lt;li>;要求构建更多更快、更可扩展且更安全的 API 和适配器。随着业务需求的发展和新工作流程的创建，这些 API 和接口将需要更新。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;但是这些类型的变化并不是离散事件，因为业务需求不断发展，因此这些新的变化也不是孤立的事件。工程系统也很快就会过时。因此，组织需要一种不断迭代的策略——了解离线系统对业务目标的当前影响，短期修复以赢得一些时间和空间，以及长期更深入的修复。然后从头开始再次迭代。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Ways to Determine What Your Customer Really Values]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/3-ways-to-determine-what-your-customer-really-values]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_11_1219096552.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Klaus Vedfelt/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt; span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;公司经常陷入麻烦，因为他们对利益相关者的价值做出了错误的假设。避免这个陷阱的一个好方法是反映您的公司在这三个尺度上的位置，您应该按照提供的顺序进行操作：商品化与定制化；理性与感性；可评估与不可知。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/3-ways-to-define-what -your-customer-really-values?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/3-ways-to-define-what-your-customer-really- value?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;创造价值是商业战略和竞争优势的核心。例如，这就是新加坡航空&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com.au/Airline_Review-d8729151-Reviews-Singapore-Airlines&quot;>;始终跻身顶级航空公司名单&lt;/a>;的原因例如，为什么丰田是 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/martyswant/2021/12/16/why-toyota-is-the-top-auto-brand-in-the- halo-100/?sh=7ed923e16171&quot;>;在同行中评价如此之高&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但“价值”这个术语却令人惊讶地被误用和误解。在“创造价值”方面，由于对利益相关者有价值的错误假设，有很多地方会绊倒和跌倒。避免这个陷阱的一个好方法是反映您的公司在这三个尺度上的位置，您应该按照提供的顺序进行操作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1.商品化与定制化&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;几年前，我为一群来自不同行业的经理举办了战略研讨会。我指出，价值是由许多因素创造的，我告诉大家，为了获得竞争优势而降低价格通常是错误的，因为价格不等于价值。澳大利亚最大矿业公司 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bhp.com/&quot;>;BHP&lt;/a>; 的高管特雷弗 (Trevor) 尖声说道：“如果你是价格接受者而不是价格制定者怎么办？ ?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必和必拓在全球销售铁矿石、冶金煤、铜和其他矿物。特雷弗指的是必和必拓销售“商品”的事实。我就其他可能的差异化领域提出了建议，例如准时交货和客户服务。但对于中国公司的买家来说，这些并不是选择的主要推动因素。他们倾向于认为这些事情是理所当然的。即使产品的质量也不是区别因素，因为煤炭、铁矿石和其他矿物都是按照规格分级的。换句话说，Trevor 是对的，当所有其他&lt;a href=&quot;/2014/05/dialing-up-the-volume-on-strategic-innovation&quot;>;战略因素&lt;/ a>; 在购买决策中是平等的，这在商品中经常发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我也是对的。许多其他产品和服务是定制的而不是商品化的，在这些情况下，价格不等于价值。例如，史蒂夫是一家专门从事大型和昂贵住宅的厨房设计和安装公司的首席执行官。当他的询问减少时，他立即认为自己“太贵了”。于是，他开始了一轮降价。但成本真的是问题吗？为了找到答案，我们采访了他的一些选择竞争对手的客户。一个典型的例子是珍娜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她为她的大房子的厨房寻求了三份报价。 “自然，它们的价格不同，”她说。 “我本可以按照提供的价格购买一辆新车。”她解释说，她选择的厨房承包商并不是最便宜的。对珍娜来说更重要的是其他四个因素：创新设计（她花了很多时间与每个承包商一起寻找最佳的设计解决方案）、工作质量（以前的客户对厨房装修的建议）、客户服务（易于处理和良好的倾听技巧）以及内含物的质量（推荐洗碗机、水槽和水龙头的品牌）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说，最后一个因素是“信任”。这“非常重要，因为她不会每天都在那里检查管道和电气配件的安装。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您在商品化与定制化规模上的地位取决于独特价值的多少你为你的产品做出了贡献，这就是为什么你需要从这个规模开始。如果您从事供应原材料的业务，那么您可能不会增加太多价值。这意味着降低价格是增加竞争优势的唯一选择。但大多数企业的情况并非如此。您的“增值”可以包括从客户对您的服务的体验到您的材料质量的各种因素。这些是客户愿意支付更多费用的价值因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一个量表可帮助您了解您提供的价值类型。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;2.理性与感性&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;几年前，我是一家制造房屋桁架和框架的公司的首席执行官。这些是在我们的工厂预制的，装载到卡车上，然后拖到客户的建筑工地。我们为建筑商提供了建造房屋骨架所需的一切。我的任务是让公司扭亏为盈。这要求我们获得竞争优势。因此，我们需要充分了解客户判断“价值”的标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建筑商的价值是通过权衡价格与其他&lt;a href=&quot;/2014/05/dialing-up-the -volume-on-strategic-innovation&quot;>;战略因素。&lt;/a>;其中包括产品质量（产品必须符合规格并在安装过程中保持在一起）、交付（准时很重要，延误会产生金钱）和客户服务（技术建议和处理任何问题）。对于建筑商、我们的客户来说，购买决定是非常理性的，涉及仔细评估的成本和收益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/01/when-to-sell-with-facts-and-figures -and-when-to-appeal-to-emotions&quot;>;但并非所有产品和服务都能以如此理性的方式增加价值&lt;/a>;。 Angeline是一家国际知名化妆品公司的产品经理。其产品主要通过大型零售百货商店销售。我问她对于她的消费者（即化妆品的使用者）的“价值”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她回答说，“这个决定并不纯粹是理性的，因为形象非常重要。消费者与品牌产生情感联系。”她补充道，“这就是我们将我们的产品与知名名人联系起来的原因。”她还指出，在线影响者变得越来越重要：“他们可以成就或毁掉一个产品。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在理性与感性的尺度上找到自己的位置需要仔细审查客户的决策过程。他们是否受到情绪因素的影响，或者是否能够完全抛开情绪，采取务实、理性的态度？许多消费者的决定都包含情感成分，而相关公司的广告就完全泄露了信息。想想我们看到的汽车、旅行或软饮料等产品的广告。这些广告通过品牌和形象来定位产品，以最大化非理性价值因素，例如名人代言和高端形象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这将我们带到了第三个尺度，这有助于阐明客户如何选择你.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3.可评估与不可知&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;想象一下。朱莉下班开车回家，她意识到自己需要牛奶、面包和大米。她不想在超市排队，所以她去了当地的便利店。在做出这个决定时，她会评估价格（她会比在超市支付更多费用）、客户服务（快速而愉快）、位置（方便，在回家的路上）、产品范围（他们有她想要的东西）、营业时间（它们是开放的）和商店展示（干净且组织良好）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有这些对她来说都是非常重要的，她决定进入当地的便利店而不是繁忙的地下停车场在超市。与她的决定相关的标准是已知的，并且可以由她进行评估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在其他情况下，情况并非如此。以我的朋友吉姆为例，他最近做了膝关节置换手术。我问他是如何选择他的外科医生的。 “他是我当地医生推荐的，”他说。 “看来他的名声不错。但是，天哪，他很贵。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉姆的决定并不是基于价格。事实上，我还没有听到有人说他们刚刚被“镇上最便宜的外科医生”替换了髋关节或膝盖。那么，它是基于什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉姆没有评估价值的专业知识和技术知识。他对价值的看法是基于声誉和口碑。他认为这些因素会反映在价格中 - 因此价格越高，价值就越高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您从事向没有背景的客户销售产品或服务的业务要准确了解它们是如何工作的，您需要弄清楚您在可评估与不可知范围内的位置。在这些地区进行购买的客户被迫依赖其他信息来源来做出购买决定。您必须确保您在其他来源中表现出色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是为什么吉姆的专家在他向患者提供的小册子中参考了著名教学医院的大量最新研究成果。网站和亲自。他还详细描述了他使用的尖端技术，以证明他是最新的。 Finally, he includes many testimonials from former patients telling their stories in their own words.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;• • •&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many ways you can get confused when it comes to figuring out what your customers value. But thinking where you stand on the three value scales will help you identify what kind of unique value you deliver, whether it&#39;s tangible or intangible, and how your customer recognizes it. That&#39;s how you&#39;ll build a real, sustainable competitive advantage.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Future of Mental Health at Work Is Safety, Community, and a Healthy Organizational Culture]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/the-future-of-mental-health-at-work-is-safety-community-and-a-healthy-organizational-culture]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_10_1446656906.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Alexandr Dubynin/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;A new study exploring the ever-changing landscape of workers&amp;#8217; experiences and perspectives around mental health, stigma, and work has uncovered new insights about how workplace mental health has changed from before, during, and after the pandemic. The findings show that mental health isn&amp;#8217;t improving in the US, but there are some new bright spots, too. Workers are demonstrating greater awareness around mental health at work and are looking beyond traditional benefits and the latest technologies. What they increasingly want is what the research has always shown works: mentally healthier cultures. The authors break down what employees need and &amp;#8212; increasingly expect &amp;#8212; from their employers when it comes to mental health support and offer several strategies for leaders to foster sustainable, mentally healthy cultures.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/the-future-of-mental-health-at-work-is-safety-community-and-a-healthy-organizational-culture?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/the-future-of-mental-health-at-work-is-safety-community-and-a-healthy-organizational-culture?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The state of workplace mental health has shifted substantially in the past four years, expedited by the global pandemic, racial justice reckoning, and other macro challenges. Employers have made noteworthy gains since then by providing expanded benefits, meditation apps, mindfulness programs, mental health days, and awareness campaigns. However, these investments on their own aren&#39;t enough.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Mind Share Partners began our biennial Mental Health at Work Report in partnership with Qualtrics to explore the ever-changing landscape of workers&#39; experiences and perspectives around mental health, stigma, and work. Each report collected nationally representative samples of 1,500 full-time US workers. Each also included statistically significant sampling from historically marginalized populations: women, people of color, LGBTQ+ workers, and more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/mentalhealthatworkreport-2023&quot;>;third study&lt;/a>; uncovered new insights about how workplace mental health has changed from before, during, and after the pandemic. Here&#39;s what we found about what workers want and need when it comes to mental health at work —&amp;nbsp;and how employers can provide it.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;The Changing Landscape of Workplace Mental Health&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In Mind Share Partners&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/mentalhealthatworkreport-2019&quot;>;inaugural 2019 report&lt;/a>;, we described mental health as a “crucial factor” in workplace well-being, engagement, and productivity, as well as for diversity, equity, and inclusion. Despite ever-growing rates of mental health challenges, most employers were barely scratching the surface in terms of effective mental health support.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/mentalhealthatworkreport-2021&quot;>;2021 report&lt;/a>;, we described workplace mental health as being at a &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/10/its-a-new-era-for-mental-health-at-work&quot;>;catalytic point in time&lt;/a>;. The prevalence of mental health challenges spiked amid the pandemic, and work itself became a greater strain on mental health. Simultaneously, our collective awareness of mental health grew, too. We were talking about it more and employers were investing in more mental health supports like benefits, meditation apps, and mental health days.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Will your company adapt or be left behind?&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The Future of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Will your company adapt or be left behind? &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the very ethos of work has been undergoing its own transformation. As the world emerges from the pandemic, workers are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2022/09/13/1122059402/the-economics-behind-quiet-quitting-and-what-we-should-call-it-instead&quot;>;re-evaluating&lt;/a>; what truly matters to them, leading to broader trends like quiet quitting, the Great Resignation, and more. Meanwhile, employer investments continue to shift. Some have continued to innovate and improve the workplace experience — for example, by increasing base pay, piloting four-day work weeks, and giving workers greater autonomy over where and how they work. Others have scaled back in hopes of achieving a “pre-pandemic normal.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Key Findings From Mind Share Partners&#39; 2023 Mental Health at Work Report&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This year&#39;s study shows that mental health isn&#39;t improving in the US, but there are some new bright spots, too. Workers are demonstrating greater awareness around mental health at work and are looking beyond traditional benefits and the latest technologies. What they increasingly want is what the research has always shown works: mentally healthier cultures. Here&#39;s what we found:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Workers are shifting from crisis to languishing.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;From 2019 to 2021, mental health symptoms spiked and workers&#39; overall views of their mental health declined. In 2023, we saw a 20% decline in those reporting any symptoms — a hopeful trend. But when asked to rate their overall mental health out of 10 in the past year, workers&#39; ratings continued to decline. In 2019, 78% gave ratings between seven and 10. In 2021, 67% did. In 2023, 61% rated between seven and 10, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shrm.org/resourcesandtools/hr-topics/organizational-and-employee-development/pages/financial-strain-impacts-workers-mental-health.aspx&quot;>;finances&lt;/a>; and work itself reported as having the greatest negative impacts on mental health.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How is mental health seemingly improving and worsening at the same time? Mental health comprises a diverse spectrum of experiences, from diagnosable conditions and symptoms to challenges like grief, burnout, and stress. And emerging from the pandemic&#39;s many crises alleviated the severity of many mental health challenges at the time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But workers entered a new world rife with its own challenges: inflation, growing &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/5888024/50-trillion-income-inequality-america/&quot;>;income inequality&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2023/income-poverty-health-insurance-coverage.html&quot;>;poverty rates&lt;/a>;, layoffs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/companies-making-workers-employees-return-to-office-rto-wfh-hybrid-2023-1&quot;>;forced returns&lt;/a>; to offices, employers doubling down on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/07/31/google-ceo-to-employees-productivity-and-focus-must-improve.html&quot;>;productivity&lt;/a>;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/22841490/work-remote-wages-labor-force-participation-great-resignation-unions-quits&quot;>;growing tensions&lt;/a>; between employers and workers amid growing waves of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2023/09/03/business/economy/strikes-union-sag-uaw.html&quot;>;unionization&lt;/a>;. These issues are social, political, and economic in nature. And while therapy and meditation may certainly help an individual worker to cope, fundamentally solving these issues requires systemic interventions. Many populations, like young people, are still navigating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/07/science/pandemic-adolescents-depression-anxiety.html&quot;>;crisis&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, many fell into an overwhelming feeling of, well, “blah,” or as renowned organizational psychologist Adam Grant coined in 2021, they&#39;re “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/19/well/mind/covid-mental-health-languishing.html&quot;>;languishing&lt;/a>;.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Investing in organizational culture outperforms therapy and self-care.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Historically, mental health support from employers has primarily centered around a productized, individualized approach — therapy, apps, time off. This equips workers with the resources to self-manage their mental health on their own time outside of work. At the same time, it also implies that it should be dealt with personally in private.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last few years, however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/business-news/poor-working-conditions-can-impact-your-mental-health/450455&quot;>;research&lt;/a>; around the interdependencies between mental health and work itself continued to grow more robust. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/12/burnout-is-about-your-workplace-not-your-people&quot;>;Burnout&lt;/a>; in particular was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/news/item/28-05-2019-burn-out-an-occupational-phenomenon-international-classification-of-diseases&quot;>;defined&lt;/a>; by the World Health Organization as fundamentally rooted in poorly managed workplace stress. Similarly, leading burnout researcher Christina Maslach identifies &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/02/beyond-burned-out&quot;>;six main causes of burnout&lt;/a>;: unsustainable workloads, perceived lack of control, insufficient rewards for effort, lack of a supportive community, lack of fairness, and mismatched values and skills — all workplace factors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To better understand workers&#39; needs, we asked this year&#39;s respondents to rate how helpful the following were to their mental health:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Mental health treatment&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Self-care resources for mental health&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;A safe and supportive culture for mental health&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;A healthy and sustainable culture of work&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Among all respondents, a healthy and sustainable culture emerged as the clear winner, with 78% rating it as moderately, very, or extremely helpful. This remained true when segmenting outcomes across gender, generation, LGBTQ+ identity, race and ethnicity, caregiver status, and seniority levels. Next highest was a safe and supportive culture for mental health at 67%, followed by mental health treatment at 64%, and self-care resources at 60%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Growing awareness of mental health among workers also came with a better understanding of what kind of support is truly helpful — beyond simply coping through work. Workers are seeing mental health as a collective workplace responsibility rather than an individual one. Increasingly, supporting mental health at work means fundamentally realigning an organization&#39;s culture with human well-being.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Psychological safety has declined.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;From our 2019 to 2021 studies, workers grew more comfortable talking about mental health and developed healthier beliefs about it and those with mental health conditions. Both indicate a reduction in mental health stigma. More workers also reported feeling supported as employers grew their investments in mental health resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering 2023, however, a paradox emerged. Workers&#39; personal beliefs continued to reflect a greater awareness and understanding of mental health. However, they also felt less safe talking about mental health at work, were less likely to do so, and felt less supported by their employers around mental health this year — and these declines neared pre-pandemic levels. In fact, workers&#39; comfort with talking about their mental health to senior leaders nearly halved from 37% in 2021 to just 19% in 2023.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, this isn&#39;t surprising. Despite many employers investing in mental health, many also went “back to business” in terms of &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/news/2023/03/mark-zuckerberg-meta-year-of-efficiency/&quot;>;productivity&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2023/06/01/marc-benioff-salesforce-performance-culture-earnings-call/&quot;>;performance&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech.co/news/heres-what-google-meta-and-co-have-cut-to-save-costs&quot;>;bottom-line costs&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2023/01/10/resistance-attrition-quiet-quitting-drop-diversity-forced-return-to-office-gleb-tsipursky/&quot;>;return to office plans&lt;/a>;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/corporate-america-slashing-dei-workers-amid-backlash-diversity/story?id=100477952&quot;>;investments in DEI&lt;/a>; — all while still encouraging flexibility and work-life balance, despite the realities of work making it much more difficult to achieve. Amid mixed signals, workers&#39; sense of psychological safety within their organizations deteriorated despite greater awareness and healthier beliefs at the individual level.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Investments in DEI are improving mental health and engagement.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;In all three studies Mind Share Partners has conducted in partnership with Qualtrics since 2019, people from marginalized identity groups faced disproportionate challenges around mental health and work. This year, women, Gen Z, Black, Latinx, and LGBTQ+ respondents all tended to have worse mental health outcomes than their counterparts; were less likely to get a supportive response when they talked about their mental health at work; and were overall less engaged around job satisfaction, trust, pride, and intent to stay at their employer. These outcomes represent the persistence of cultures and systems that drive not only outright acts of discrimination but also of biases embedded in hiring, growth, and support processes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bright side? Employers&#39; efforts paid off and created meaningful changes to workers&#39; experiences. Respondents who felt their employer supported their identity showed better outcomes around mental health and the impact of work on mental health and were overall more engaged and committed to their employer compared to those who didn&#39;t feel supported.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The answer to the return-to-office question is autonomy.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The hybrid work debate continues to grow ever &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2023/07/remote-work-return-to-office-policies/674736/&quot;>;contentious&lt;/a>;. In this year&#39;s study, we asked participants whether they were working in person, hybrid, or fully remote. Additionally, we asked if they were doing so by choice or were mandated by their employer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When comparing key outcomes across work situations, no consistent themes emerged. However, hybrid workers who had the freedom to decide where they work reported a shorter duration of mental health symptoms, a more positive impact of work on mental health, greater comfort talking about mental health at work, lower likelihood of leaving roles for mental health reasons, and greater pride and intent to stay at their current employer for two or more years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is not — and never will be — a single, universal way of working that is unequivocally “better” or “worse” than the other. (Remember &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/the-truth-about-open-offices&quot;>;open offices&lt;/a>;?) The benefits will always vary depending on the company, function, industry, region, culture, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/worklab/in-the-office-it-is-all-about-moments-that-matter&quot;>;stage in an employee&#39;s life cycle&lt;/a>;, individual team members&#39; needs and preferences, and more. Yet the focus on work location detracts from the many other dimensions of working, like when we work or how we communicate. More importantly, it overshadows an even more fundamental question: the individual&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2023/07/20/hybrid-work-problems-annie-dean-meta-atlassian/&quot;>;ability to choose&lt;/a>; what works for them.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;What Employers Can Do&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Since our founding in 2017, Mind Share Partners has worked with global organizations across industries, sizes, and regions. As we&#39;ve continued to grow our training, strategic advising, and implementation work within employers alongside our broader movement building and advocacy initiatives, we offer five key strategies for organizations based on this year&#39;s findings:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Collectively re-envision a mentally healthy workplace.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;There will never be a one-size-fits-all vision of what a mentally healthy workplace looks like. Achieving this requires a collective re-envisioning of what workplace mental health means to everyone in the organization — leaders and workers alike — tailored to its size, stage, industry, region, individual roles, and more. This starts with understanding your organization, what mental health looks like within it, and ultimately, what your people want. This means &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/post/5-workplace-mental-health-questions-to-include-in-employee-pulse-and-employee-engagement-surveys&quot;>;measuring&lt;/a>; mental health and workplace factors, asking about workers&#39; perspectives on a regular basis, and enacting real, meaningful change tailored to the needs of your people. Further embedding these efforts into your organization&#39;s culture, systems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/post/prioritizing-mental-health-throughout-employee-journey-mapping&quot;>;employee life cycle&lt;/a>;, and business strategy ensures that well-being is built into the business itself, not simply relegated to an HR &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/what-wellness-programs-dont-do-for-workers&quot;>;wellness program&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Enable culture change from top down and bottom up.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;This year&#39;s study showed that workers want safer and more supportive cultures for mental health and healthier and more sustainable work cultures in general. Inevitably, this kind of culture change requires both top-down and bottom-up approaches.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the top, leaders can tell their own &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/leaders-sharing-your-own-mental-health-story-can-help-you-become-a-better-ally&quot;>;mental health story&lt;/a>; within their organization or turn outward and share publicly like in Mind Share Partners&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/leadersgofirst&quot;>;Leaders Go First &lt;/a>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/leadersgofirst&quot;>;campaign&lt;/a>;. This normalizes mental health and helps others feel comfortable talking about it at work if they want to. They can also model healthy work practices and, specifically as leaders, resource teams and individuals to maintain healthy and sustainable ways of working.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the bottom-up, employers and individual workers alike can explore forums for conversation, such as &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/how-to-form-a-mental-health-employee-resource-group&quot;>;employee resource groups&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/peerlisteningprograms&quot;>;peer listening programs&lt;/a>;, a cross-functional mental health working group, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/casestudy-pgim&quot;>;mental health champion networks&lt;/a>;. These conversations can be about mental health, but they can also take place within teams to establish work norms, explore &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/08/the-radical-promise-of-truly-flexible-work&quot;>;inclusive flexibility&lt;/a>;, and empower individuals to decide how they work best.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One natural step forward is to equip your people to lead this change. This typically happens through training across levels, taking a proactive, preventive approach with a management and equity lens that goes beyond simply “noticing the warning signs.” Workers and leaders alike need the strategies to create psychological safety and sustainable work cultures. Upskilling your people can also include &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/8-ways-managers-can-support-employees-mental-health&quot;>;manager programs&lt;/a>;, leadership coaching, mentorship, and more.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Explore root-cause solutions alongside wellness perks.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;When managing any strategy or budget, it&#39;s easy to fall into the trap of investing in “quick fix” programs and products without critically evaluating their purpose. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mindsharepartners/2019/10/10/the-futility-of-mental-health-days/&quot;>;mental health days&lt;/a>; allege benefits of rest and rejuvenation and are often accompanied by optimistic awareness slogans like “It&#39;s OK not to be OK!” This can accomplish commendable intentions: giving rest, raising awareness, and sparking a broader dialogue. But what comes after? Well, in many cases, it&#39;s back to the same churn and burn(out). Even worse, it enables employers to continue “not okay” (ie, unsustainable) business practices under the guise of personal resilience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leaders need to offer ways to cope &lt;em>;and &lt;/em>;solve for root causes. There&#39;s an ever-growing number of players in the space — &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/6308096/therapy-mental-health-worse-us/&quot;>;health care providers&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/what-wellness-programs-dont-do-for-workers&quot;>;wellness programs&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/the-unbearable-irony-of-meditation-apps/&quot;>;meditation apps&lt;/a>; — each with its own philosophy, approach, product, and business objective. All have their unique benefits often steeped in scientific literature, but when workers are asking for a healthy and sustainable culture of work, these approaches &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eidCHlP8_bQ&quot;>;may not solve the right problem&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Recommit to the foundations of work itself.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;While every organization is different, there are still core foundations every workplace must meaningfully address in order to cultivate a mentally healthy workforce:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Safety:&lt;/strong>; This includes physical and psychological safety, financial stability, as well as balance and sustainability in the long term.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Autonomy: &lt;/strong>;This includes the time, bandwidth, and resources to do one&#39;s job; control, flexibility, and predictability over one&#39;s work; and having a voice.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Belonging: &lt;/strong>;This includes the ability to show up authentically to work, make meaningful connections and be supported, and feel a holistic sense of community with others.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;These are core human needs that, unfortunately, tend to be overlooked as employers pursue wellness perks without addressing the fundamentals. For a deeper dive, explore the US Surgeon General&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hhs.gov/surgeongeneral/priorities/workplace-well-being/index.html&quot;>;recently launched framework&lt;/a>; on workplace mental health and well-being, which Mind Share Partners collaborated on.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Stay the course on DEI.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Employers&#39; place in solving the inequities of the world has been heavily debated, to say the least. But let&#39;s look even more simply at what&#39;s well within the realm of their control: the workplace. Organizations not only have the ethical responsibility to avoid perpetuating inequity but also the opportunity to help employees flourish from human diversity, camaraderie, and shared purpose. This year&#39;s data shows that when social identities are supported, workers have better mental health and engagement outcomes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mental health and DEI are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/diversityinclusion&quot;>;intrinsically tied&lt;/a>;. Historically marginalized groups face added cultural and structural barriers both at work and when &lt;a href=&quot;https://steinberginstitute.org/bipoc-mental-health-month-common-barriers-to-mental-health-services/&quot;>;seeking&lt;/a>; mental health support. Mental health is also a category within DEI given the prevailing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychiatry.org/patients-families/stigma-and-discrimination&quot;>;stigma and marginalization&lt;/a>; of those navigating mental health challenges or living with conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ultimately, DEI is about making the work work for everyone. Of course, like any visionary goal, this requires people power, budget, strategic planning, and cross-functional investment. Unfortunately, some employers have &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy-for-companies-to-walk-back-th-1850686363&quot;>;shied away&lt;/a>; from DEI amid the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/30/business/economy/hiring-affirmative-action.html&quot;>;rollback&lt;/a>; of affirmative action. Others remain steadfast and committed, in part as a business imperative. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/post/mind-share-partners-to-corporate-america-stay-the-course-on-dei&quot;>;Our message&lt;/a>;? Stay the course.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;What would typically take decades for a social movement, the workplace mental health movement achieved in a matter of years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we look to the future, the workplace mental health movement will ultimately need to go “back to basics.” Workers no longer want frivolous perks to distract them from work. They want stable employment to mitigate financial anxiety, recognition to know they matter, sustainable workloads to prevent burnout, a supportive community to find belonging, the flexibility to decide how work works for them, and the autonomy and voice to feel respect, agency, and ownership over their work and their lives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The future of mental health at work won&#39;t be an emerging technological renaissance or a transformation of hybrid work. The future will be a recommitment to core human needs. It will be safety, community, and a healthy organizational culture. It will be sustainable work rooted in equity and workers&#39; voices. The future of workplace mental health will start with exactly that: work itself.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Your Organization Should Use Salary Benchmarking]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/why-your-organization-should-use-salary-benchmarking]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_09_1372212398.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Jorg Greuel/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;In a growing number of states and countries, employers are not allowed to ask job candidates&amp;#8217; salary history or even their salary expectations. That means employers must find new ways to determine appropriate compensation. A key solution lies in salary benchmarking &amp;#8212; using aggregated market data to establish competitive pay rates. Recent research in collaboration with a leading US payroll processing company revealed that access to robust benchmarking tools doubled the probability of firms setting the &amp;#8220;right&amp;#8221; salary. Data sources vary from government-released data to crowdsourced information on platforms like Glassdoor. Despite the availability of various tools, ensuring that salary decisions align with market trends is crucial, not just for compliance but also for retaining talent. As pay transparency grows, leveraging high-quality benchmarking sources effectively can optimize employer&amp;#8217;s wage expenses and bolster employee retention.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/why-your-organization-should-use-salary-benchmarking?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/why-your-organization-should-use-salary-benchmarking?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Recent transparency policies across several US states, like salary history bans that prevent employers from requiring candidates to report their compensation or even their salary expectations, have heightened the focus on fair salary practices in the workplace. As a result, there&#39;s an increased demand for strategies to determine appropriate compensation. A key solution lies in salary benchmarking: using aggregated market data to establish competitive pay rates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Setting salaries is a balancing act: you do not want to offer salaries that are too high relative to the market, because that&#39;d be wasteful; but offering salaries that are below market may make it difficult to attract, retain and motivate your employees. How do employers find their sweet spot?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/papers/w30570&quot;>;recent study&lt;/a>;, we developed a theoretical model to shed light on the demand for salary benchmarking. In our model, firms know exactly how much value the job candidate would bring to the table. The firm would like to offer the candidate below that value to keep some of the value as profit. However, how much lower should the offer be? The lower the offer, the better the savings. On the other hand, if the offer is too low, the firm risks losing the job candidate to another firm — they may turn down the offer, or accept the offer and leave shortly thereafter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, whether the company wants to make a more or less aggressive offer depends critically on what the firm believes is the market value of the job candidate: ie, how much &lt;em>;other firms&lt;/em>; are willing to pay for the job candidate. That&#39;s where salary benchmarking comes in: firms can use data on the offers accepted by similar employees (eg, with the same position title and industry) to make sure that their offer is not too low, or too high, relative to the market benchmark.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our research also provides empirical evidence that access to salary benchmarks has a significant effect on the salaries that firms set. We conducted it in collaboration with the largest US payroll processing company, ADP, serving 650,000 firms and processing paychecks for 20 million Americans. In addition to the payroll services, the company aggregates the salary data from their payroll records in the form of salary benchmarks. Clients can then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adp.com/what-we-offer/products/adp-datacloud.aspx&quot;>;search&lt;/a>; for any job title they want in a user-friendly way. It is one of the most advanced benchmark tools and is being used by many prominent firms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our data covers the roll-out of the tool when it was first introduced to the market, late 2015, through the start of the pandemic in 2020. Our sample includes 584 “treatment” firms that gained access to the tool and 1,431 “control” firms that did not gain access to the tool but were selected because they shared similar characteristics to the treatment firms. We studied the evolution of salaries in the treatment firms shortly before and after they gained access to the benchmarking tool, and we compared that to the corresponding evolution of salaries in the control firms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here&#39;s what we found: let&#39;s say that a firm sets the “right” salary when they choose a salary that is in a narrow (5%) band of the median salary for the same position, industry, and state. Prior to gaining access to the benchmarking tool, there was an 11.6% probability that a firm sets the “right” salary. After gaining access to the benchmarking tool, the probability of setting the “right” salary increased two-fold, to 22.1%. This is compelling evidence that these salary benchmarks are truly influencing pay-setting, and causing position-level salaries to converge across companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We also found that the effects of salary benchmarking are quite symmetric. After looking up the benchmark, firms are less likely to pay significantly above-market, presumably because it would be wasteful; but firms are also less likely to pay significantly below-market, presumably because it would be costly in terms of attracting, retaining and motivating employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For standardized positions, such as bank teller and receptionist, we found some evidence of a modest increase in the average salary. If employers are choosing to raise salaries for this group, it must be because they expect to get something in return, right? For instance, bumping salaries up to market may allow employers to retain their employees and save those pesky turnover costs. Our research shows that, indeed, benchmarking improves retention. Among employees in these roles, the gain of about 6% in average salary was followed by an increase of about 16% in the retention rate over the following 12 months.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;How can I use salary benchmarking?&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The payroll data show that high quality salary benchmarks sway employers to set pay closer to the marketplace median pay, and that benchmark users benefit from a boost in employee retention. But how exactly does one go about sourcing and using a salary benchmark?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Salary benchmarks are wide ranging; some are created by the government and others exclusive to the clients of consulting firms. Still others are crowdsourced data from anonymous employees. For example, the US government reports average earnings at the six-digit occupation code, within industry and state, each year using surveys of businesses and households. These data are highly representative, but are released infrequently and at a higher level of aggregation than the sought after position level information. Meanwhile, several large consulting firms offer exclusive access to the aggregated earnings of their clients, often using proprietary standardized corporate titles. Most recently, firms that collect salary information as part of their core businesses, like ADP, have added user interfaces that make these data accessible as benchmarks. And platforms like Glassdoor have encouraged millions of users to volunteer their salary information anonymously in exchange for seeing the average inputs of others at the position level.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To better understand how firms use salary benchmarking, we also conducted a survey with the members of the Society for Human Resource Management Research Institute (SHRM). We collected responses from a large sample of 2,085 HR managers in charge of pay-setting. This sample spans organizations of every size, state and industry, including both public and private sectors. To complement this data, we conducted an additional survey with a sample of clients from ADP, in which we obtained responses from 720 HR managers in charge of pay-setting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Employers use salary benchmarking for a wide range of purposes. For instance, 54% of respondents use benchmarking when setting the pay of new hires. Other popular uses include salary negotiations (53%), setting ranges for specific job titles (90%), and setting the salary for a job advertisement (41%). Employers also vary in terms of how frequently they consult salary benchmarks. For instance, while some employers do benchmarking for every single new hire (37% of respondents), the rest prefer to do it for some specific new hires or for some specific positions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our survey data indicates that employers differ in which data sources they use. The most popular option is to use industry surveys, chosen by 68% of respondents, but hiring a consulting firm to conduct these surveys can be quite expensive, and there is no guarantee that the survey data will live up to the expectations. If you do not have a big budget, you may also want to try the second most popular option: free online data sources (58% of respondents) such as Glassdoor.com. More recently, payroll service companies have gained popularity (used by 23% of respondents and the fastest growing source), which may give the best bang for your buck in terms of data quality. Most employers, however, use a combination of data sources. While the majority look at free online sources, on a scale of 1-5, HR professionals report that other sources are twice as trustworthy as free online sources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Labor market trends can sometimes change rapidly, especially in the post-pandemic world. You do not need to check the benchmarks on a daily basis, but try to at least do it from time to time — remember that information, too, has an expiration date. Likewise, you may not have time to sit down to study market trends for every position in which you hire. However, make sure to at least do due diligence for the positions that are most critical for your business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When using a benchmarking tool, you may feel information overload. Some tools provide not only the median pay, but also the mean, 10th percentile, 25th percentile, and so on and so forth. And some tools allow you to filter by industry, state, and other criteria. There are trade-offs. For instance, filters can allow you to focus on peer employers, but at the cost of smaller sample sizes and thus statistically imprecise benchmarks. While the right approach depends on the context at hand, according to our survey, there are some clear favorites: most firms (89%) prefer to look at the median market pay or the average market pay, and the most popular filters are by industry (87%) and state (84%).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We also gave the survey respondents an opportunity to share their own tips and advice for salary benchmarking. Some recommended not relying on job title information alone, but rather to pay attention to the job description to ensure it&#39;s a good match. Another manager suggested that, to the extent possible, you should review the benchmarks regularly to stay in sync with the latest trends in the job market. In the same spirit, one manager recommends being proactive — do not wait until employees are unhappy about low pay and reach out to you, or you risk higher turnover.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sum, the pay transparency revolution extends to firms knowing much more about what their competitors are offering. New high-quality sources have changed pay-setting practices. According to our latest study, keeping up with pay in the marketplace, and knowing how to use those sources, can affect your bottom-line retention and payroll costs. And from a societal perspective, this is closing the gap between pay across firms.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 22:25:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 Reasons Why Inclusion Is a Competitive Advantage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/10-reasons-why-inclusion-is-a-competitive-advantage]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_10_457893079.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Michael H/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;In their new book, &lt;em>;Move Fast and Fix Things&lt;/em>;, Frances Frei and Anne Morriss outline five strategies to help leaders tackle their hardest problems and quickly make change. Their third strategy is creating an inclusive environment that allows all employees to thrive. Although it can be hard to measure a complex outcome like inclusion, researchers are working to identify and quantify the many effects of inclusion on firm performance, and the insights they&amp;#8217;re generating are persuasive.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/10-reasons-why-inclusion-is-a-competitive-advantage?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/10-reasons-why-inclusion-is-a-competitive-advantage?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Facebook made “Move fast and break things” an informal company motto. But leadership experts Frances Frei and Anne Morriss argue that this belief is deeply flawed — and that it keeps leaders from building a great company. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;The best leaders move fast and fix things — they solve hard problems while making their organizations stronger. In their new book &lt;/em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/move-fast-and-fix-things-the-trusted-leader-s-guide-to-solving-hard-problems/10546&quot;>;Move Fast and Fix Things&lt;/a>;&lt;em>; (Harvard Business Review Press), Frei and Morriss outline five strategies to help leaders tackle their hardest problems and quickly make change:&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;Identify your real problem. (See &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/10-signs-your-company-is-resistant-to-change&quot;>;10 Signs Your Company Is Resistant to Change&lt;/a>;)&lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;Build — or rebuild — trust with your stakeholders. (See &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/10-pitfalls-that-destroy-organizational-trust&quot;>;10 Pitfalls That Destroy Organizational Trust&lt;/a>;)&lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;Create inclusive conditions that allow your whole team to thrive. &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;Tell a compelling story about the change you need to make. &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;Execute your plan with a sense of urgency. &lt;/em>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;This month, we&#39;ll be publishing a series of excerpts that correspond to each strategy. Today&#39;s excerpt is about inclusion, which Frei and Morriss define as the act of creating conditions that allow other people to thrive — not in spite of their differences as complex, multidimensional humans, but precisely because of those differences.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Although it can be hard to measure a complex outcome like inclusion, researchers are getting better at it. Serious people are working to identify and quantify the many effects of inclusion on firm performance, and the insights they&#39;re generating are persuasive. Below is a list of some of our favorite findings, many of which remain generally underappreciated.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;1. Inclusion helps you recruit good people. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Inclusion is now a tell for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/employers/blog/diversity/&quot;>;all kinds of talented people&lt;/a>; — not only the underrepresented — that you&#39;ve built a healthy workplace and understand what it takes to collectively excel. Expect candidates to look for evidence of inclusiveness in everything from where you recruit to the fine print of your benefits package. For example, they may not need those same-sex fertility benefits or veteran mentorship services, but they&#39;ll still see them as a sign that you appreciate difference.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;2. Inclusion helps you retain good people.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;It turns out that those same candidates &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/12/to-retain-employees-focus-on-inclusion-not-just-diversity&quot;>;will stick around as employees&lt;/a>; if you truly walk the talk on inclusion. Inclusion drives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/25067557&quot;>;higher rates of retention&lt;/a>; at all levels of the organization, and some employee segments (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shrm.org/foundation/ourwork/initiatives/engaging-and-integrating-military-veterans/Documents/13056-G-01_SHRMF_WhyHireVet.pdf&quot;>;military veterans top the list&lt;/a>;) will reward your ability to value their unique contribution with industry-leading loyalty.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;3. Inclusion increases the engagement of your people. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Engagement scores are consistently higher for companies labeled “inclusive,” and we now have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/joshbersin/2015/12/06/why-diversity-and-inclusion-will-be-a-top-priority-for-2016/?sh=fc0a6632ed5b&quot;>;some interesting data&lt;/a>; that helps to explain these numbers. Inclusive companies are &lt;em>;also &lt;/em>;almost three times better at coaching people for improved performance and four times better at identifying and building leaders. Making people better is the key to their engagement, and inclusion seems to give you an advantage.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;4. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Inclusion makes you more resilient.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When different types of people are thriving in your organization, &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/11/why-diverse-teams-are-smarter&quot;>;you&#39;re better at navigating crises&lt;/a>; and (our favorite business euphemism) “turbulent times” in general. You&#39;re more adaptable, more comfortable with change, and better at dealing with personnel problems. One fun fact: while the S&amp;amp;P saw a 35% decline in stock performance between 2007 and 2009 (remember that ride?), the shares of inclusive companies went in the other direction, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mursalhedayat/2020/06/24/diversity-in-the-workplace-is-now-more-critical-than-ever/?sh=5172eb6e60aa&quot;>;gaining over 14% in value&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;5. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Inclusion grows your marketplace.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Inclusive teams are &lt;a href=&quot;/2013/12/how-diversity-can-drive-innovation&quot;>;better at identifying and cultivating new markets&lt;/a>; because they expand a firm&#39;s peripheral vision and help eliminate its blind spots. &lt;a href=&quot;/2004/09/diversity-as-strategy&quot;>;More women in decision-making roles&lt;/a>;, for example, improves a company&#39;s ability to solve problems for female clients. And this is before we even get to the macro implications of &lt;em>;economic &lt;/em>;inclusion. For example, the US GDP could get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accenture.com/_acnmedia/pdf-89/accenture-disability-inclusion-research-report.pdf&quot;>;a boost of up to $25 billion&lt;/a>; if just 1% more of persons with disabilities joined the labor force. What percentage of that boost would represent new customers for your business?&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;6. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Inclusion makes you more innovative.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Inclusion creates a healthier meritocracy for new ideas &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/04/research-adding-women-to-the-c-suite-changes-how-companies-think&quot;>;where out-of-the-box thinking is more likely to break through&lt;/a>;. This happens in part because people in inclusive organizations are more likely to surface and hear the &lt;em>;what &lt;/em>;of a good idea rather than allow that idea to be diluted or buried by an unexpected &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>;. How much of an innovation bump does true inclusion buy you? Depending on your starting place, estimates range from &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/how-and-where-diversity-drives-financial-performance&quot;>;roughly 20%&lt;/a>; all the way &lt;a href=&quot;/2013/12/how-diversity-can-drive-innovation&quot;>;up to 70%&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;7. Inclusion turns you into better decision-makers. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Decision quality goes up when a range of voices are &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/11/why-diverse-teams-are-smarter&quot;>;not only present but also integrated&lt;/a>;. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/eriklarson/2017/09/21/new-research-diversity-inclusion-better-decision-making-at-work/?sh=627907124cbf&quot;>;one delightful study&lt;/a>;, all-male teams beat individuals nearly 60% of the time, but gender-diverse teams outperformed individuals almost 75% of the time. Teams that were gender diverse, geographically diverse, and had at least one age gap of more than 20 years made better decisions than that lone individual &lt;em>;87% of the time&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;8. Inclusion helps you manage risk.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In the wreckage of the 2008 financial crisis, a serious “Lehman Sisters” argument emerged positing that the story would have played out differently if more women had been in the room for the most consequential decisions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0148296315002143&quot;>;Subsequent&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aom.org/doi/abs/10.5465/amj.2018.1039?journalCode=amj&quot;>;studies&lt;/a>; have since explored this argument, concluding that gender inclusion in the C-suite and boardroom is associated with a healthier firm relationship to risk—neither overly risk-averse nor risk-seeking—and better overall performance.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;9. Inclusion improves your stock price. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Estimated bumps to shareholder returns range &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.catalyst.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/The_Bottom_Line_Connecting_Corporate_Performance_and_Gender_Diversity.pdf&quot;>;from 10% to over 30%&lt;/a>; (seriously) when you get inclusion right. This may be why Goldman Sachs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/bc-finreg-unlocking-diversity-inclusion/unlocking-diversitys-promise-psychological-safety-trust-and-inclusion-idUSKBN2C01N2&quot;>;recently announced&lt;/a>; that it would no longer take any company public where the board is made up exclusively of straight, white men. Whatever your organization&#39;s own return on inclusion may end up being, the question we often ask companies is, “What else are you doing to chase those kinds of returns?”&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;10. Inclusion makes you more money. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;For all the reasons we&#39;ve covered in entries one through nine, inclusion ends up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/diversity-and-inclusion/diversity-wins-how-inclusion-matters&quot;>;boosting both your top line and bottom line&lt;/a>;. Your talented, engaged teams will drive higher revenues through better innovation and smarter market development, while allowing you to spend capital more efficiently through better decision-making, higher retention, and higher productivity. And when you hit some turbulence along the way, you&#39;re more likely to land the plane safely. We hope to live in a world where inclusion is an organizational given. Until we get there, we know of no other distinction that can deliver these kinds of advantages.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;This excerpt has been lightly edited.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[It&rsquo;s Time to End the Battle Between Waterfall and Agile]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/its-time-to-end-the-battle-between-waterfall-and-agile]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_10_501194249.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;MirageC/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Too many project leaders think rigidly about Waterfall and Agile project management methodologies and believe that they need to choose between the two. But many projects &amp;#8212; especially those with diverse stakeholder needs and complex structures &amp;#8212; benefit from a hybrid approach that combines aspects of Waterfall and Agile. The rise of hybrid methods isn&amp;#8217;t tied to a particular time or event; instead, they have evolved organically as a response to the needs of modern, complex projects. A review of the key components of Waterfall and Agile allows project leaders to select among them to build a hybrid approach based on the unique demands of each project.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/its-time-to-end-the-battle-between-waterfall-and-agile?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/its-time-to-end-the-battle-between-waterfall-and-agile?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;When you are leading a high-stakes project, choosing between the rigor of Waterfall and the flexibility of Agile can make or break your initiative. For the last two decades, too many academics, leaders, project managers, and organizations have thought they have to choose one or the other. Worse, the emergence of Agile methods led to tribalism in the project community, stifling innovation and limiting the potential for truly effective solutions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bring a bunch of project managers together and inevitably they&#39;ll share their thoughts about their least-preferred methodologies. I&#39;ve heard it all: “Waterfall is a process designed for a world that no longer exists.” “Agile is a way of delivering failure faster.” “Waterfall is a dinosaur.” “Agile makes eagles team up with turkeys.” Entire organizations choose to “go agile,” setting aside the fundamentals of traditional methodologies that some projects need. This rigid and divisive thinking leads to real losses.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to navigating this landscape lies in &lt;em>;hybrid project management methodologies&lt;/em>; that combine the planning rigor of Waterfall with the flexibility of Agile. Indeed, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pmi.org/learning/library/forging-future-focused-culture-11908#:~:text=The%20survey%20results%20for%20this,of%20their%20projects%20failing%20outright.&quot;>;Project Management Institute&#39;s 2020 report&lt;/a>; indicated that 11.4% of investment is wasted due to poor project performance. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.standishgroup.com/news/45&quot;>;Standish Group&#39;s CHAOS report&lt;/a>; showed only a 31% project success rate, with 19% of projects failing outright. This indicates an estimated annual global financial loss of an astounding $3 trillion, not to mention wasted resources, missed opportunities, and negative societal impacts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Embracing hybrid methods can help organizations begin to remedy some of these outcomes. In this article we look at how, with this blended approach, organizations can achieve an optimal balance, allowing them to nimbly adapt to unforeseen challenges without losing sight of their ultimate objectives. First, let&#39;s briefly review the core components of Waterfall and Agile, which both contain the building blocks of hybrid methodologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Waterfall: The Structured Approach&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The traditional Waterfall methodology is structured and sequential, where progress “flows” downward through distinct phases: conception, analysis, design, planning, construction, testing, implementation, handover, and maintenance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Key characteristics of the Waterfall method are highlighted through various examples:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Sequential phases&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learninglegacy.crossrail.co.uk/learning-legacy-themes/project-and-programme-management/initiation-and-development/&quot;>;London&#39;s Crossrail project&lt;/a>;, a significant infrastructural undertaking budgeted at £14.8 billion, illustrates the effectiveness of the Waterfall model&#39;s distinct and sequential phases. Each phase had to be meticulously completed before the subsequent one began, ensuring a structured progression that left no room for oversights. Despite the challenges involved, the Crossrail project, upon its completion, was hailed as an engineering marvel, connecting 41 stations over 118 km and forecasted to serve about 200 million people annually.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Detailed documentation&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://everything-everywhere.com/the-large-hadron-collider/&quot;>;Large Hadron Collider&lt;/a>; (LHC) project by CERN, with an estimated cost of €7.5 billion, showcases the importance of the Waterfall model&#39;s emphasis on thorough documentation. Given the LHC&#39;s complexity, including a 17-mile-long circular tunnel and thousands of custom parts, detailed documentation was essential to ensuring everyone involved in the project comprehensively understood each phase.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Predictability&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arabianbusiness.com/industries/real-estate/burj-dubai-cost-1-5bn-build-27430&quot;>;Burj Khalifa project&lt;/a>; in Dubai, valued at $1.5 billion, stands as a testament to the predictability in cost and timeline offered by the Waterfall method. The meticulous upfront planning facilitated the construction of the world&#39;s tallest building (828 meters), completed within six years as per the original timeline, despite the project&#39;s immense scale and complexity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, numerous high-profile project failures have exposed the limitations of the Waterfall approach:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Rigidity&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audit.vic.gov.au/report/operational-effectiveness-myki-ticketing-system?section=&quot;>;Myki ticketing system&lt;/a>; project in Melbourne, Australia, starkly underscores the Waterfall method&#39;s rigidity. With a budget exceeding AUD 1.5 billion, the project took four times more than the expected two years. Yet, the system was riddled with issues due to its inability to adapt to evolving user requirements and technological advancements.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Late discovery of issues&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The US government&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessofgovernment.org/sites/default/files/Viewpoints%20Dr%20Gwanhoo%20Lee.pdf&quot;>;HealthCare.gov project&lt;/a>;, which cost over $2 billion, illustrates the repercussions of late-stage testing, a characteristic of the Waterfall model. System defects identified during the late testing phase resulted in a flawed launch and considerable public and political uproar, leading to expensive and time-consuming repairs and improvements.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Incompatibility with change&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-08-31/nbn-cost-revised-up-to-51-billion-dollars/10187108&quot;>;National Broadband Network&lt;/a>; (NBN) project in Australia, an AUD 51 billion endeavor, experienced frequent shifts in strategy and technology, resulting in delays and budget overruns. This highlighted the Waterfall method&#39;s inadequacy in managing projects where requirements are dynamic and continually evolving.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Unsuitability for undefined projects&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Cerner, a health care technology company that provides electronic health records software, began a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.va.gov/oig/pubs/VAOIG-19-08980-95.pdf&quot;>;project&lt;/a>; to develop a new system for the US Department of Veterans Affairs. The project, which was using the Waterfall model and was estimated to cost $16 billion and take 10 years to complete, quickly ran into problems. The VA&#39;s requirements for the new EHR system were not well defined in advance, and the Waterfall model made it difficult for Cerner to change course. By 2018, the project&#39;s cost had &lt;a href=&quot;https://federalnewsnetwork.com/veterans-affairs/2022/07/house-lawmakers-pan-va-ehr-as-bad-investment-with-upcoming-39b-cost-estimate/&quot;>;increased to over $20 billion&lt;/a>; and was still years behind schedule forcing the VA to terminate the project. The Cerner VA EHR project is considered to be one of the most expensive and disastrous IT projects in US government history.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The digital era, characterized by rapid changes and unpredictable environments, has tested the Waterfall method&#39;s limits, recognizing a need for more adaptable project management methodologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Agile: The Adaptive Approach&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Agile methods focus on enabling teams to deliver work in small increments, thus delivering value to their customers faster. Because the team continuously evaluates project requirements, plans, and results, it can make changes rapidly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Key characteristics of Agile, exemplified in various projects, include:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Iterative development&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The development of Google&#39;s search engine is a fitting example of iterative development. It started as a research project in 1996 and evolved into the most widely used search engine today, servicing over &lt;a href=&quot;https://fitsmallbusiness.com/google-search-statistics/&quot;>;8.5 billion&lt;/a>; daily searches. The continuous enhancements, adjustments, and improvements made over the years underline the concept of iterative development intrinsic to Agile.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Customer collaboration&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Amazon, a pioneer in customer centricity, epitomizes the Agile principle of customer collaboration. Its constant solicitation and incorporation of customer feedback into its products and services have propelled it to its&amp;nbsp;stratospheric market value.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Response to change&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Spotify, the world-leader in streaming music, is a classic case of Agile&#39;s adaptability. It has consistently evolved its business model and product offerings in response to market changes and user demands, moving from a simple music streaming platform to offering podcasts, videos, and personalized playlists.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Agile methodology has its share of limitations:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Inadequate documentation&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The Agile method&#39;s focus on rapid delivery often leads to insufficient documentation. In 2015, the German supermarket chain Lidl launched a project to implement a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.henricodolfing.com/2020/05/case-study-lidl-sap-debacle.html&quot;>;new SAP system&lt;/a>;. The project failed to accurately map out Lidl&#39;s unique business processes onto the new system. The lack of sufficient documentation led to misunderstandings between the development team and the stakeholders, causing discrepancies in the system&#39;s design and functionality and leading to the project&#39;s cancellation in 2018, incurring a loss of around €500 million.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Unpredictable delivery time and costs&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The UK&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerweekly.com/news/2240185166/Universal-Credit-will-cost-taxpayers-128bn&quot;>;Universal Credit welfare reform project&lt;/a>;, budgeted initially at £2.2 billion, illustrates Agile&#39;s difficulty in estimating delivery times and costs. The project&#39;s costs escalated to over £12 billion, and it&#39;s still not fully implemented nearly a decade later due to its complex nature and continuous changes in requirements.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Dependence on client involvement&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Projects where the client cannot commit significant time or does not provide timely feedback can face significant hurdles. A notable example is the $60 million &lt;a href=&quot;https://federalnewsnetwork.com/tom-temin-commentary/2018/02/the-coast-guards-epic-fail/&quot;>;US Coast Guard payroll system project&lt;/a>;, which was terminated in 2017, partly due to insufficient stakeholder engagement.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Inadequacy for certain types of projects&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Agile&#39;s flexibility and adaptability do not translate well to projects with fixed requirements or requiring high predictability. For instance, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://interestingengineering.com/innovation/engineering-nycs-iconic-structure-one-world-trade-center&quot;>;One World Trade Center construction&lt;/a>;, a project with a budget of approximately $3.9 billion, required strict regulatory compliance and precise planning, which wouldn&#39;t have been feasible with Agile.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Agile continues to evolve, these limitations underline the need for project management methodologies that can blend the strengths of both Waterfall and Agile, effectively mitigating the weaknesses inherent in each. Thus, the case for a hybrid approach becomes increasingly compelling.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Embracing the Hybrid Approach&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The emergence of hybrid methodologies represents a new era in project management that draws on the strengths of both Agile and Waterfall while mitigating their limitations. The rise of hybrid methods isn&#39;t tied to a particular time or event; instead, they have evolved organically as a response to the needs of modern, complex projects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Key characteristics of Hybrid Project Management and their real-world implications include:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Flexibility and structure&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Hybrid methodologies, such as the one implemented by Philips for their digital transformation initiatives, offer a mix of Agile&#39;s flexibility and Waterfall&#39;s structure. Philips adopted a hybrid approach for its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usa.philips.com/healthcare/innovation/about-health-suite&quot;>;HealthSuite digital platform&lt;/a>;, delivering rapid, iterative releases for software development while still adhering to strict documentation and safety guidelines. By combining these two approaches, Philips was able to create a hybrid approach that was both flexible and structured. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.philips.com/c-dam/b2bhc/master/hts/healthsuite/brochure-philips-ealthsuite.pdf&quot;>;resulted&lt;/a>; in better product quality, reduced time to market, predictable costs and savings.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Phased and iterative&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Hybrid methods&amp;nbsp;employ a phased approach for well-defined components and an iterative approach for uncertain ones. On its way to becoming the world&#39;s best digital bank, DBS Bank executed well-planned phases for infrastructure overhaul while implementing iterative development for its customer-facing digital services. This approach enabled them to revamp their legacy systems and simultaneously bring innovative services to market, boosting their revenues from S$9.6 billion in 2014, the year it launched its digital transformation, to S$14.6 billion in 2020.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Customer involvement and predictability&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Hybrid methodologies strike a balance between customer involvement and predictability. British Telecom (BT) uses agile methods for digital services, such as its new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalservices.bt.com/en/solutions/products/5g-private-networks&quot;>;5G network&lt;/a>;, to ensure customer involvement by getting feedback early and often. This helps to ensure that the final product meets the needs of customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalservices.bt.com/en/aboutus/unlocking-the-future-of-infrastructure?cid=ppc_(sc)google(cam)infrastructure(md)ppcad(id)infrastructure&amp;amp;gad=1&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwl8anBhCFARIsAKbbpyQVcAlVAgU3VYlwMUe8G6mZK1tx6wYwFKM4fOpPHtwxVSEYN9tReLEaAoBeEALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&quot;>;infrastructure projects&lt;/a>;, such as its new data centers, BT uses Waterfall methods to plan and execute projects more predictably. This helps to ensure that projects are completed on time and within budget. The hybrid approach ensures customer involvement and offers predictable delivery timelines, helping BT achieve an annual revenue of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/290320/bt-group-adjusted-revenues/&quot;>;£21.37 billion in 2021&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benefits of Hybrid Project Management and its related examples include:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Balanced approach&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Hybrid methodologies offer the best of both worlds, as shown by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/company/how-we-make-games/technology&quot;>;Ubisoft&lt;/a>;. The video game developer used Waterfall to plan and develop assets like characters and initial coding to ensure that the base game would be robust and well-constructed. They switched to Agile when it came to gameplay mechanics, debugging, and post-launch updates. By applying a hybrid approach, Ubisoft successfully launched &lt;em>;Assassin&#39;s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em>; to commercial acclaim in November 2020.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Risk mitigation&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;A hybrid approach allows for risk mitigation by blending Agile&#39;s adaptability with Waterfall&#39;s structured planning, as demonstrated by Tesla&#39;s hybrid approach to the development of their Model 3. To build the Gigafactory, where the vehicle&#39;s batteries are produced, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/blog_attachments/gigafactory.pdf&quot;>;Tesla utilized rigorous planning and risk assessment methods&lt;/a>;. At the same time, Tesla&#39;s capability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-software-updates-allow-quick-fixes-taking-risks-2022-02-18/&quot;>;update vehicle software over the air&lt;/a>; allows for rapid issue resolution and feature addition post-production. This dual strategy enables Tesla to mitigate risks effectively while maintaining flexibility in a high-stakes manufacturing landscape.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Efficient use of resources&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Hybrid approaches offer the stability of resource-intensive, long-term planning while providing the flexibility to adapt rapidly to market demands. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://quickbooks.intuit.com/r/supply-chain/zara-supply-chain-its-secret-to-retail-success/&quot;>;​Zara&#39;s&lt;/a>; detailed planning and staggered development phases ensure that there is minimal resource idling.​ On the other hand,​ cross-functional teams consisting of designers, marketers, and store managers engage in iterative cycles and sprints. These quick feedback loops allow ​Zara to allocate or reallocate resources immediately based on real-time sales data and new fashion trends.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;When Hybrid Methods Work Best&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Recognizing when to use a hybrid method is pivotal to a project&#39;s success. The approach offers adaptability without sacrificing the vision and detailed planning that many projects require, making it an invaluable approach that every organization should develop. So, how can you determine whether your project would benefit from a hybrid approach? Here are some indicators:&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Diverse stakeholder needs:&lt;/strong>; When you&#39;re dealing with a broad range of stakeholders, each with their own requirements and expectations, a hybrid approach can cater to all. It can allow for iterative feedback, like in Agile, while maintaining a structured roadmap, as in Waterfall.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Varied project phases:&lt;/strong>; A hybrid method can offer the best of both worlds if different stages of your project require different approaches — such as an initial research phase requiring strict structure, followed by a development phase needing more flexibility.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Uncertain requirements:&lt;/strong>; For projects where requirements may change or need to be fully clear at the outset, but there&#39;s a need for a definite structure or end goal, a hybrid approach can accommodate evolving needs without losing sight of the final objective.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Risk management:&lt;/strong>; If your project encounters high levels of uncertainty or risk that require iterative testing and review but also require thorough documentation and planning, a hybrid method can strike the right balance between adaptability and meticulousness.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Complex project structures:&lt;/strong>; For projects characterized by intricate interdependencies, multifaceted components, or multifunctional teams, a hybrid method can cater to the nuanced demands, balancing rigorous planning with nimble execution.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s time to end the destructive battle between Waterfall and Agile. The key to unlocking the true potential of projects lies in bringing a diverse set of tools to every initiative — an assortment of approaches, methods, and techniques that can be adapted and applied per each project&#39;s unique demands.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hybrid project management methodologies present a promising step in this direction, embracing the strengths of both Waterfall and Agile while offsetting their weaknesses. By having hybrid methods as a tool in our toolbox, we equip ourselves to increase the success rate of projects, deliver more value for our organizations, and navigate the complexities of the &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11/the-project-economy-has-arrived&quot;>;project economy&lt;/a>; more effectively.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Transform Business Operations with Process Mining]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/transform-business-operations-with-process-mining]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sept23_28_596456570.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Bernd Vogel/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;The most effective companies we interviewed use process mining to generate operational insights at scale, identify process inefficiencies, define targeted actions, and measure process improvements &amp;#8212; all of which lead to value realization. It is often a major cultural change to fully embrace this level of process management. Leaders describe a cultural journey from a hero-focused company to a process-focused company. The goal is to establish efficient processes with consistent, smooth execution rather than relying upon local heroes to save the day.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/transform-business-operations-with-process-mining?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/transform-business-operations-with-process-mining?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Process mining has evolved from an academic concept (first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vdaalst.com/publications/p128.pdf&quot;>;published&lt;/a>; in 2001) to a&amp;nbsp;popular software tool for analyzing, monitoring, and improving process performance. As we have described in a &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/04/what-process-mining-is-and-why-companies-should-do-it&quot;>;previous article&lt;/a>; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-3-030-40172-6&quot;>;book&lt;/a>;, process mining analyzes logs of&amp;nbsp;enterprise transactional system events to create a detailed picture of the processes, thus providing a digital twin of actual process flows. It is quickly replacing previous observational and subjective approaches to understanding business processes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Process mining began as a tool used to investigate process performance issues on an ad hoc basis, but has evolved into a platform for monitoring and improving operational process execution at scale to drive process efficiency and help realize business value. As an indisputable, fact-based visualization of de-facto process flows, it provides a unique source of truth to scale operational transformation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our research has focused on the business context and critical success factors behind the success of process mining in large organizations. We interviewed process mining leaders in eleven companies. One of us (Lars) has observed many other efforts to scale process mining using Celonis, a leading provider of the technology, in the course of his customer advisory role. There are now many vendors of process mining software, including established firms like Microsoft and SAP, and we have also interviewed customers of other vendors in this research.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;The Context for Employing Process Mining&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We found two alternative contexts in which companies were applying process mining to their businesses and scaling it over time. One involves companies that have broadly adopted a process orientation across their businesses; the other context is within firms that are attempting to become more process-focused, but have not yet fully done so. Process orientation became somewhat popular with process improvement and reengineering efforts over the last several decades, but many companies have not fully institutionalized a process view of their businesses. Process-oriented firms have clearly-defined end-to-end processes like order-to-cash and procure-to-pay, owners of those processes, and clear goals and performance metrics for them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those companies we interviewed with an established process orientation — primarily companies in central Europe — were using process mining to go beyond traditional business process modeling toward mining and improving the actual execution of process-based operations. They use it for generating operational insights at scale, identifying process inefficiencies, defining targeted actions and measuring process improvements — all leading ultimately to value realization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies without a strong process orientation were using process mining to further inculcate the idea of end-to-end processes, motivate better process execution, and to push for less variation and complexity in process flows across the business. Both groups found the technology useful, although process mining leaders in companies without a strong process orientation had to spend more time evangelizing for the technology and recruiting business sponsorship. It is often a major cultural change to fully embrace process management, as evidenced by a large global shipping and logistics company we interviewed. Its process leaders described a cultural journey from a hero-focused company to a process company. The goal is to establish efficient processes with consistent, smooth process execution rather than relying upon local heroes to save the day.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Critical Success Factors for Scaling&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;There are a variety of possible factors that might drive success in scaling process mining initiatives. Some that we have identified include:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Executive buy-in to the idea of process mining and continuous support&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Business ownership to drive projects within their domains&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Creating a center of excellence (CoE) — a dedicated team to accelerating process mining&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Change management, training, and community development of users&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Connecting process mining to strategic objectives and internal programs&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;An emphasis on business value realization (value-first) from process mining&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Real-time integration and data access, with connection to feeder systems&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Operational process execution efforts embedded into ongoing management.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;When we discussed these factors with the process mining leaders we interviewed, we asked which ones were most important in their own organizations. The most common response was executive buy-in — recruiting executives sponsors in the first place, securing their ongoing support, and driving adoption of new projects throughout the organization. At the consumer products company Reckitt, the process mining program has been supported right from the start by the CEO, CFO, and CIDO. They not only sponsor the program, but connect it to strategic priorities and managing transformation through measurable KPIs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Business ownership is a lower-level version of executive buy-in that was also mentioned&amp;nbsp;by several process mining leaders. Business stakeholders or process owners need to&amp;nbsp;understand and support the idea of mining, analyzing, and acting on process&amp;nbsp;performance data, or it will not happen at all or become established into daily practice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At PepsiCo, business stakeholders view process mining as a key enabler on a mission to create a totally different company, as part of their digital transformation strategy. Merck has a well-defined process for engaging with new business areas with the goal of building ownership. It includes presentation of existing Merck examples as references and discussion of pain points, important pockets of resources, and improvement potentials for that business area.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several process leaders also mentioned the importance of a strong emphasis on value. Process mining has costs — eg for software and organizational support — and it is important in most companies to ensure that the value derived from it is calculated, validated and realized.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Business value focus implies that the most valuable projects are prioritized, leading to a positive business case. At the healthcare company Cardinal Health, for example, there are stated goals for value from process mining each year. The process mining team reports true actual values for each project each month, and the finance organization and the business stakeholder must agree to them. Already in the second year, process mining efforts at Cardinal Health over-delivered on value goals by 2.5X.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some process mining leaders — who generally head CoEs for the technology — acknowledged that such centers are critical to accelerate adoption. However, they would not be established in the first place without some degree of executive buy-in and a competent team. The candy and pet food giant Mars mentioned that its primary success factor was finding the right talent for process mining — people who are capable of connecting both technology and the business domain. The individuals need to be able to code, build data models, consult, understand requirements, deploy, and support improvement of processes. Not surprisingly, they are difficult to find.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To make process mining a strong driver for operational transformation, it always comes back to people. Change management is a key factor at a pharmaceutical giant in Europe. It has a dedicated process mining community program including bi-weekly all hands calls, internal training sessions for personal development, showcasing best practice success stories, and continuous community activities.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;From Insights to Action&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The process mining leaders we interviewed agreed that it is important to move beyond insights on how processes are performing — the original intent of process mining — to actions for sustainable improvements.&amp;nbsp;From a software perspective, moving from insights to action involves targeted apps and problem areas for particular types of processes, such as preserving cash in accounts&amp;nbsp;payable or improving cash flow in accounts receivable (both popular in recessionary&amp;nbsp;economies), improving supplier reliability in procurement and building supply chain&amp;nbsp;resilience, or optimizing inventory levels. Many companies also focus on identifying and&amp;nbsp;speeding up slow or low-quality deliveries in order management processes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a management perspective, the companies we interviewed took various steps in order to translate insights into action. At the Nordic and Baltic telecom company, Telia Company, a combination of factors helped drive action. Its CoE focused on finding the right part of the business that was curious about process mining and open to trying it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many cases, the Telia Chief Operations Officer opened the doors for them.&amp;nbsp;The center staff also worked to identify the right people in that business area to work with them and get them engaged in data-driven process improvement. They consulted with the&amp;nbsp;internal client to identify a process problem they wanted to solve. The ultimate goal was&amp;nbsp;to use the insights from process mining operationally and to drive value on a daily basis.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;The Future of Process Mining&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In addition to asking process mining leaders what made their organizations successful (and what was less helpful in that regard), we also asked about their future plans for process mining and operational transformation. Some of the companies were focused on using technological innovations; others on fleshing out the organizational infrastructure for process mining.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the technology front, Mars is focused on determining how advances in automated analytics can make process mining easier to use and scalable across the organization. The goal is to enable a seamless generation of tailored insights and recommendations that drive business value. In a similar vein, several parties want AI to help users identify big improvement levers and support better process execution. BMW is focused on making process mining accessible to almost everyone in the organization, and is currently engaged in training 80,000 employees on digital skills that would enable process mining and other user-initiated activities. Cardinal Health wants to add a focus on task mining and execution management technologies to its basic process mining software. Merck is working on object-centric process mining to achieve a 3D perspective on processes and facilitate cross-silo improvements with a digital process twin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of organizational development of process mining, several organizations, including the filter manufacturer MANN+HUMMEL, wanted to expand both a user community for process mining as well as a process management organization that can help with improving processes. Ingka (an IKEA retailer) similarly wants to build a community of process mining practitioners and champions. Its process mining leaders envision that the global furniture retailer will eventually enable each country to have its own process mining sandbox to experiment with, and a federated set of process mining CoEs around the globe. Mars wants to establish a federated network of superusers, while Telia aims at enabling citizen developers for process automation. Cardinal Health, which works with a network of pharmaceutical and medical device companies, wants to extend process mining to optimize processes interorganizationally.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;These companies provide evidence that process mining is a technology that is here to&amp;nbsp;stay. Multiple vendors now offer it, big companies are building technical and&amp;nbsp;organizational infrastructures to support it, and many companies are getting substantial&amp;nbsp;value from it. Insights are being turned into action, ultimately delivering value in respect&amp;nbsp;to the top, bottom and green line of organizations.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Ways to Develop Talent for an Unpredictable Future]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/5-ways-to-develop-talent-for-an-unpredictable-future]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_09_1582805042.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;designer491/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;We may not know what tomorrow&amp;#8217;s jobs will look like, but we can safely assume that when people are more curious, emotionally intelligent, resilient, driven, and intelligent, they will generally be better equipped to learn what is needed to perform those jobs, and provide whatever human value technology cannot replace. Rather than betting on specialists or forcing people into specific niches, organizations need to focus on expanding people&amp;#8217;s talents. What we need is not just re-skilling or up-skilling, but &lt;em>;pre&lt;/em>;-skilling: that is, being able to future-proof&amp;#160;talent and reinvent peoples&amp;#8217; careers before we even know what tomorrow&amp;#8217;s jobs and in-demand skills will be. This article makes five broad recommendations for preparing your workforce for an uncertain future.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/5-ways-to-develop-talent-for-an-unpredictable-future?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/5-ways-to-develop-talent-for-an-unpredictable-future?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Despite the many clickbaity headlines and apocalyptic fearmongering around AI and job automation, the data are rather clear: As I highlight in my latest book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Human-Automation-Quest-Reclaim-Unique-ebook/dp/B099KQV3ZJ&quot;>;&lt;em>;I, Human: AI, Automation, and the Quest to Reclaim What Makes Us Unique&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;em>;, &lt;/em>;you are less likely to lose your job to AI than to &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/3-human-super-talents-ai-will-not-replace&quot;>;another human&lt;/a>; using AI, especially if you don&#39;t use AI yourself. In that sense, there&#39;s nothing new about the AI age; just like previous disruptive technologies, AI is eliminating some jobs but creating many more new jobs in turn, which desperately require humans.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As illustrated in our recent ManpowerGroup report, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manpowergroup.com/en/news-releases/news/58-of-employers-believe-artificial-intelligence-and-virtual-reality-will-be-job-creators&quot;>;58% of employers&lt;/a>; see AI as a net creator of new jobs. The problem is that people who are displaced by job automation (for example, brick-and-mortar store managers) don&#39;t automatically have access to all the new jobs that are created by technology (for example, cybersecurity analyst, digital marketer, or AI ethicist). According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10796-022-10308-y&quot;>;World Economic Forum&lt;/a>;, half of employees will need reskilling by 2025 to keep up with new technologies, and this figure predates the current generative AI boom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LNX_6gzLIvI&quot;>;Erik Brynjolfsson&lt;/a>; estimates, for every dollar organizations spend on technology, they need to invest an additional nine dollars in talent and related processes, such as identifying people with the right skillsets and potential; developing the right skills; enabling proper change-management processes; and creating the conditions for people to &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/07/when-your-employee-isnt-reaching-their-full-potential&quot;>;live up to their potential&lt;/a>;. Indeed, as my colleague Becky Frankiewicz and I &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/digital-transformation-is-about-talent-not-technology&quot;>;noted&lt;/a>;, what makes or breaks digital transformation is not the actual technology, but the human factor: talent.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Will your company adapt or be left behind?&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The Future of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Will your company adapt or be left behind? &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;So, what we need is not just re-skilling or up-skilling, but &lt;em>;pre&lt;/em>;-skilling — that is, being able to future-proof talent and reinvent peoples&#39; careers before we even know what tomorrow&#39;s jobs and in-demand skills will be.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Pre-Skilling Your Workforce for an Unknown Future&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;How can this be done? Although nobody has the exact recipe, not least because there&#39;s no data on the future, we can extrapolate from macro historical trends, as well as draw lessons from recent economic and human capital patterns, to make five broad recommendations:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1) Focus on potential&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;As the lifespan of current skills, expertise, and performance shrinks, it is advisable to hire and promote people for what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myhrfuture.com/digital-hr-leaders-podcast/how-ai-can-unlock-human-potential-and-make-work-more-meaningful&quot;>;they &lt;em>;could&lt;/em>; do&lt;/a>;, rather than what they &lt;em>;have done &lt;/em>;in the past. This means prioritizing soft skills — such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.learnabilityquotient.com/&quot;>;learning ability&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/12/assessment-whats-your-curiosity-profile&quot;>;curiosity&lt;/a>;, resilience, and adaptability — over hard skills — such as programming or data mining — focusing on the foundational &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/iops.12001&quot;>;ingredients of employability&lt;/a>; rather than current technical expertise or past employment history, both of which still dominate modern hiring approaches.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simply put, we may not know what tomorrow&#39;s jobs will look like, but we can safely assume that when people are more curious, emotionally intelligent, resilient, driven, and intelligent, they will generally be better equipped to learn what is needed to perform those jobs and provide whatever human value technology cannot replace. One advantage with potential is that we have reliable and proven methods to measure it, notably &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Talent-Delusion-Intuition-Unlocking-Potential/dp/0349412480&quot;>;psychological assessment tools&lt;/a>;, which can also be used to &lt;em>;develop&lt;/em>; people&#39;s potential, particularly through normative and &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2019-21619-003&quot;>;data-driven feedback&lt;/a>; that helps them identify gaps between where they are and where they need to be (see next point).&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;2) Provide crucial feedback&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Even before AI&#39;s arrival, there was already a great deal of confusion and misunderstanding around aligning people&#39;s talents and potential with the best career choices. Things are even more complex now, and most employees (and managers) are rightly wondering what they will do in the future, whether their experience and expertise — and all the time and money they invested in their careers — will still be relevant, and if so, where.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharing data-driven feedback (from assessments, internal data, and peer-ratings) and helping people understand how their interests and skills can be a future asset to your organization is key. This means thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/the-leader-as-coach&quot;>;leaders as coaches or talent agents&lt;/a>;, where their main job is to proactively nurture people&#39;s talents, as well as harness their full potential. Remember: Most people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fair-Talk-Three-Powerful-Feedback/dp/1912555093&quot;>;feedback-deprived&lt;/a>;, and a staggering &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1996-02773-003&quot;>;two-thirds of feedback interventions&lt;/a>; fail to produce desirable results. The key is to tell people what they &lt;em>;need&lt;/em>; to hear even when they don&#39;t &lt;em>;want&lt;/em>; to hear it, and above all, that you tell them something they didn&#39;t know and that can motivate them to get better.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crucially, it is not enough just to provide people with feedback on their skills gaps; organizations also need to incentivize them to develop the relevant skills while providing the most efficient, enticing, and impactful programs to develop them.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;3) Focus on talent expansion&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Rather than betting on specialists or forcing people into specific niches, focus on broadening or expanding people&#39;s talents. This means &lt;em>;not&lt;/em>; playing to &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/01/strengths-based-coaching-can-actually-weaken-you&quot;>;people&#39;s strengths&lt;/a>;, but rather, helping them develop &lt;em>;new&lt;/em>; strengths, so they become a more versatile version of themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all have a natural tendency to adapt the world to our current skills so that we can do “more with less” and optimize for lazy efficiency rather than stretch goals or new skills acquisition. In reality, unless your employees are in the top 1% of any area of expertise (which, by definition, can only apply to a very small selection of individuals), they will be better served becoming a jack of all trades, not least because with every new task or skill you learn, there will be many new underlying skills with adjacencies to other tasks, jobs, and careers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This will also increase diversity and inclusion. As Harvard&#39;s Joseph Fuller and Christina Langer and Burning Glass Institute&#39;s Matt Sigelman &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/02/skills-based-hiring-is-on-the-rise&quot;>;point out&lt;/a>;: “The shift to skills-based hiring will open opportunities to a large population of potential employees who in recent years have often been excluded from consideration because of degree inflation.” If organizations complain about their inability to find diverse and creative talent, they should stop looking for talent in the same old places and ways.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;4) Invest in mid-level managers&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;As &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/07/3-ways-to-reenergize-your-team-when-morale-is-low&quot;>;Amy Edmondson and I&lt;/a>; recently noted, managers hold the key to unlocking human potential at work, especially when the challenge is to revitalize, reenergize, and reimagine talent. Even before the AI age, the role of middle managers was critical and accounted for &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1037/1089-2680.9.2.169&quot;>;30 to 40% of team performance&lt;/a>;, but the role has increased massively in complexity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, a manager was someone with proven technical expertise and strong past performance as an individual contributor. Today, they need to understand not just the “classic” managerial tasks (hire the right people, give them the right tasks and direction, use feedback to motivate them, and enable team performance), but also some very complex specific new challenges, such as &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/10/how-to-manage-a-hybrid-team&quot;>;managing hybrid&lt;/a>; and virtual teams, &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/12/a-guide-to-building-psychological-safety-on-your-team&quot;>;creating psychological safety&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/5-strategies-to-infuse-di-into-your-organization&quot;>;boosting DEIB&lt;/a>; (which includes hiring and motivating people who are different from themselves), and helping people &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/06/what-will-working-with-ai-really-require&quot;>;manage the human-AI age&lt;/a>;, including all the uncertainties and stress that evokes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, there has never been a better &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/the-case-for-investing-a-lot-more-in-middle-managers-in-1850548862&quot;>;time to invest&lt;/a>; in mid-level managers, especially harnessing the critical soft skills that will likely future-proof them by enabling them to keep up with technological advancements and drive the value realization their organizations expect from new innovations.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;5) Invest in leadership skills&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;If you are worried about an AI-fueled future but still think humans will be part of the picture, then you should be worried about pre-skilling your leaders, for they will (still) be tasked with setting and selling the company&#39;s strategy, and driving the evolution of its culture, in tomorrow&#39;s uncertain time. In part, this is still about promoting individuals with the right soft skills (as per Step 1) and developing those skills. It is also about &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/hire-leaders-for-what-they-can-do-not-what-they-have-done&quot;>;moving on&lt;/a>; and understanding that today&#39;s top leaders may be a poor fit for the future, not least because their success is based on replicating what has worked in the past, which is often an obstacle to changing or learning new things.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Importantly, investing in leadership means harnessing the skills that enable people to collaborate effectively and become a high-performing team. It is not about promoting individuals to senior positions or glorifying status, let alone about the popularity contest that often underpins &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/10/what-science-says-about-identifying-high-potential-employees&quot;>;“high-potential” nominations&lt;/a>; — rather, it is about the qualities people must have to inspire, motivate, and bring others along into a future that will surely include AI, but should ideally also be defined as the human-AI age. This is the critical leadership challenge of today. If organizations can upgrade their leadership-selection systems, shifting from replicating past success profiles to selecting and nurturing for future skills, all other challenges will become easier. In particular, this means de-emphasizing things like “culture fit,” past performance, and technical expertise to focus more on learning ability, curiosity, integrity, and people skills. More importantly, if organizations are truly interested in harnessing diversity, they must prioritize &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-makes-an-inclusive-leader&quot;>;inclusive&lt;/a>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/key-attributes-inclusive-leader-professor-business-psychology?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;>; leadership&lt;/a>;&amp;nbsp;and cognitive diversity, breaking the homogeneity in leadership profiles.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Technology is always changing, but to ensure that those changes are actually an evolution (ie, contributing to progress), we must make every possible effort to enable humans to develop and deploy the relevant talents to reap the potential benefits of technology. Although this is by no means a given, we should have faith and confidence in our species&#39; ability to continue to adapt to its own technological inventions.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Middle Market Companies Can Avoid a Liquidity Crisis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/how-middle-market-companies-can-avoid-a-liquidity-crisis]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_06_1551147627.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;PM Images/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Managers tend to think about liquidity as a finance issue, but in face the behaviors of the sales and operations team &amp;#8212; and how they communicate and work together &amp;#8212; can have a direct affect on a company&amp;#8217;s cash position. To improve this working relationship, focus on aligning the teams, improving the quality of forecasts, map forecasts to the supply chain, and optimize for profitability rather than predictability. Following these steps can reduce a company&amp;#8217;s working capital needs and increase earnings and cash flow.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-middle-market-companies-can-avoid-a-liquidity-crisis?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-middle-market-companies-can-avoid-a-liquidity-crisis?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;This is no time to be caught short of cash, or long on inventory, or both: not when interest rates &lt;a href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/FEDFUNDS&quot;>;are double what they were a year ago&lt;/a>; and revolving credit is hard to find. Not when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/WEO/Issues/2023/07/10/world-economic-outlook-update-july-2023&quot;>;International Monetary Fund projects&lt;/a>; that the world&#39;s advanced economies will grow just 1.4% next year. Not when it&#39;s harder than ever to predict and balance supply and demand, which were whipsawed by the pandemic and have not yet regained equilibrium. Not when the number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uscourts.gov/news/2023/07/31/bankruptcy-filings-rise-10-percent&quot;>;business bankruptcies,&lt;/a>; while lower than at the peak of Covid, is up 23% over last year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even short of bankruptcy, many otherwise viable companies could face a liquidity crisis caused by the combination of rising costs, pandemic-driven changes in customer behavior, lingering supply chain problems, uncertain sales in a wobbly business environment, and the nearly certain difficulty of finding short-term capital.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liquidity is often seen as a problem for finance, but, in fact, operations play a leading role in preventing or addressing cash problems. Companies that revamp how operations, sales, and finance work together can generate cash and earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) — often quite a lot and often very fast. Strengthening sales and operations planning allows companies to take charge of their destiny regardless of external disruptions — which is a particularly useful capability right now.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Middle market companies have much to gain by making this transformation. We&#39;ve seen companies improve working capital by 20–30% and increase EBITDA substantially in just a few months. One private-equity-owned manufacturer of vitamins and nutritional supplements, for example, saw a 10% gain in EBITDA largely by making its overseas sales and distribution (where most of its growth potential lay) more connected with manufacturing operations in the United States. That helped drive down production and shipping costs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the same token, the impact of poor sales and operations planning hits the middle market hard. That&#39;s partly because these companies are disadvantaged if they need outside capital. In an AlixPartners&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;https://features.alixpartners.com/turnaround-transformation-survey-2023/&quot;>;2023 survey&lt;/a>;, 96% of turnaround and restructuring experts said the middle market is most at risk from today&#39;s capital constraints. Midsized companies are also threatened because they often sell to large multinationals, which increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/some-companies-are-taking-longer-to-pay-suppliers-despite-recovery-11623058200&quot;>;use their muscle to pay suppliers later, &lt;/a>;in some cases trying to lock in easy terms they won during the pandemic. Because middle market companies tend to be less diversified, they are more vulnerable to shocks. And, because of their size, their “liquidity runway” — the time they have before a cash shortage becomes a crisis — is shorter than for big companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every company has some kind of process for aligning supply and demand. In smaller companies, it&#39;s often very informal: Sales comes in with a forecast, the CFO discounts it, production adds some back as a cushion, and every quarter people adjust things. Many have a more sophisticated process, but it tends to be rigid and unresponsive to weak signals from the market, which leads to fire drills in production, if business is unexpectedly good, and fire sales, if things fall short. In both cases, the emphasis in the process is on managing production smoothly, not on generating cash and margin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s needed — especially by the middle market — is a transformed sales and operations planning process that threads the needle between informality and bureaucracy and gives executives the ability to adjust operations to increase cash generation and profitability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This transformation has four elements:&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;An aligned team among operations, sales, and finance.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When these teams are aligned, they are &lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;empowered with knowledge of how the company uses and generates cash. “Aligned” is the key word. Operations and sales planning should be managed in a cross-functional “war room,” but it won&#39;t work unless all participants are explicitly motivated by items that affect cash generation and margin, which aren&#39;t usually among the KPIs ops and sales track. In most companies, the operations team is measured on cost of goods, defect rates, machine utilization, and the like; sales teams tend to track and reward volume, with special incentives for promotions and so on. Those incentives should be changed to include cash and working capital measurements (eg, days of inventory, average discounts, average days outstanding for receivables).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Forecasts need to be recast, too, so they model how predicted levels of production and sales will affect all three views of the enterprise: income statement, cash flow, and balance sheet. The team also needs an enterprise-wide view of liquidity needs, biggest threats to liquidity, and biggest sources of cash — that is, which products or lines of business consume or churn out the most cash. Those reveal what levers you can pull.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;More rigorous and flexible forecasts.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s not uncommon for CFOs to cut the sales team&#39;s forecasts by &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/to-maximize-growth-get-sales-and-finance-in-sync&quot;>;as much as 25%&lt;/a>;, partly because sales teams tend to be too optimistic and their predictions sometimes aren&#39;t defensible enough. Another problem is their time horizon. In our experience, it&#39;s best to build rolling mid-to-long-term (3–14 month) views of demand, use them to produce three-month forecasts that are solid enough so you can make purchasing and marketing decisions, and tweak them weekly or monthly. Too far out, plans won&#39;t be reliable; too close in, you can&#39;t act strategically.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don&#39;t forget — as many companies do — to use data on customer churn and loyalty to test, validate, and adjust forecasts. You&#39;ll want to tune that view of demand in four ways: First, to get a clear picture of where cash and EBITDA are (and are not) coming from, build out a picture of profits as well as volume; you want to know which products and customers provide the most — and least — profit, and &lt;a href=&quot;/1987/09/manage-customers-for-profits-not-just-sales&quot;>;pay close attention&lt;/a>; to their orders and behavior. Second, &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/09/setting-your-annual-budget-amid-economic-uncertainty&quot;>;as you should with your overall budget,&lt;/a>; create scenarios for the long-term view — for example, what high, medium, or low demand would be, or what would happen if sales suddenly skewed to the lowest-price or least profitable items you sell. Third, predetermine the indicators that would tell you whether a scenario is coming to pass; this will make it harder to ignore warnings. Finally, use monthly and quarterly reviews not just to track the forecast to plan, but to revalidate its premises.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;A similarly rigorous map of supply.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The should include material, component, and labor availability. Among other things, you will want to identify components or supplies that have the longest lead times or where your knowledge of conditions upstream tells you to beware of price or supply shocks. Many providers help companies build supply chain “control towers” to track availability and pricing in near-real time, often with help from AI. These used to be the nearly exclusive province of multinationals, but they are now within the reach of most middle-market budgets.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Operations that optimize profitability, not predictability.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;An operations plan that guarantees uninterrupted production of your least profitable products isn&#39;t good. With the knowledge you now have about the profitability of products and customers, a better flow of information from the field, and an empowered cross-functional team, you can now exploit whatever flexibility your operations have to shift production from one location or product to another or prioritize orders from profitable customers. You can make analogous changes to inventory management. Viewed strategically, inventory can be a liquidity drain or a new customer-acquisition tool — “bad” or “good” inventory — and managed accordingly. Thinking long-term, you can reorient capital spending to increase operational flexibility in the areas that have the most direct impact on cash and margin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A program like this released $17 million in working capital — a reduction of about 180 days — for a $2 billion-in-sales consumer goods company based in the Mississippi Valley. The company&#39;s operations were knocked off balance after Covid wreaked havoc on its supply chain and caused demand to whipsaw, as big online retailers suddenly scooped up business from local shops. Its forecasting model was shot; unable to know where sales were coming from, one business unit was forking over nearly a million dollars in late-delivery penalties and air freight. Working from guesstimates, factories produced the wrong mix of products and procurement purchased too little of some components and too much of others, so that fill rates (the percentage of orders completed in full and on time) plunged from 95% to about 75%. To try to cover orders, the operations team stocked up $12 million more in finished-goods inventory than the company needed. Previous attempts to address the problem had looked at it piecemeal — at supplies and components, at production planning, at forecasting — rather than systematically. We worked with them to build a rough-cut capacity model that allowed revealed potential supply-demand imbalances months earlier than before; improve analytics skills on the forecasting team; and institute a monthly cadence of sales-and-operations-planning meetings that brought data and decision-makers into the same room.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;• • •&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without a systematic view, the incentives and good intentions of each player in this game — procurement, production, and sales — will almost always pull it out of balance. The operations team is uniquely placed to bring the system together, because the pain is felt there first, in the form of stockrooms that aren&#39;t being emptied or orders that can&#39;t be filled. By the time the pain appears in cash and EBITDA, it&#39;s late — sometimes too late.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 23:25:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Help Your Employees Develop the Skills They Really Need]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/help-your-employees-develop-the-skills-they-really-need]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_06_532771834.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Steve Chenn/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;The future of work will not be determined by technology, but by creating the right mix of education, exposure, and experience needed to develop skills and put them to work, creating a vastly more productive workplace and economy. In this article, the authors recommend a &amp;#8220;70/20/10&amp;#8221; learning model, in which only 10% of learning comes from formal instruction (education), 20% from social learning or mentorship (exposure), and 70% from hands-on, experiential practice with feedback (experience). By adopting this model, organizations can ensure that employees not only understand new skills, but that they can apply them effectively in different contexts. It is the crucial 70% of learning in the flow of work that is most often neglected, and most needed to build the skills needed to succeed in the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/help-your-employees-develop-the-skills-they-really-need?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/help-your-employees-develop-the-skills-they-really-need?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;In an age of disruption, the only viable strategy is to adapt, and that has never been more true than it is today. A generation ago, the half-life of the value of a skill was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20190127-humanics-a-way-to-robot-proof-your-career&quot;>;approximately 26 years&lt;/a>;. Now the half-life is often &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/reskilling-in-the-age-of-ai&quot;>;less than five years&lt;/a>;. So, it is perhaps not surprising that, globally, corporations are expected to invest more than&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/2022-corporate-training-landscape-training-industry-inc-&quot;>; $380 billion&lt;/a>; in learning and development programs this year.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yet we need to do better. We know that, after decades of trying, skills related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.industryweek.com/operations/continuous-improvement/article/21267990/widespread-lean-adoption-would-make-the-us-more-competitive&quot;>;lean manufacturing&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmessentials.us/agile-better-adoption-low/&quot;>;agile development&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/12/the-failure-of-the-dei-industrial-complex&quot;>;overcoming unconscious bias,&lt;/a>; just to name a few, are woefully under-adopted in most organizations. In fact, a recent report by McKinsey &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/Business%20Functions/Organization/Our%20Insights/Beyond%20hiring%20How%20companies%20are%20reskilling%20to%20address%20talent%20gaps/Beyond-hiring-How-companies-are-reskilling.pdf&quot;>;found&lt;/a>; that 87% of firms surveyed expect to have a skills gap in the next five years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More training is not the answer. We can&#39;t simply send employees to workshops focused on whatever proficiency is fashionable at the moment and expect to get results. What is essential is to build coherent skills-based strategies. We must think seriously about which specific skills are to be targeted, who has to learn them, and what mix of education, experience, and exposure will be effective to create the skills-based organizations we need to meet the challenges of the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, at the software company PKWARE, where Todd was executive vice president, the company invested more than 1% of revenues on sales training focused on aligning the team around a particular process. While the staff was educated, it failed to yield the expected impact because the employees weren&#39;t consistently getting the mentoring and real-time coaching they needed to sustain the initial improvements.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Will your company adapt or be left behind?&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The Future of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Will your company adapt or be left behind? &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;Compare that with Wipro, where Abhijit was previously chief learning officer. Business leaders from the insurance unit were trained in a specific skill: storytelling. Executives went to a literary festival in which they were &lt;a href=&quot;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/company/corporate-trends/wipro-senior-executives-at-jaipur-literature-festival-to-polish-narration-skills/articleshow/11573005.cms&quot;>;exposed to professional storytellers&lt;/a>; over three days. Each night they also attended a structured workshop that helped them process what they observed. After returning to the office, they received continued peer mentoring for an extended period and were encouraged, in turn, to train their own teams on storytelling. This not only helped spread the skills, but gave the leaders the opportunity to further deepen their own proficiency as they taught others. The result: a dramatic improvement in winning deals and a significant boost in revenue growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anders Ericsson, who has spent decades researching expertise, points to the importance of &lt;a href=&quot;/2007/07/the-making-of-an-expert&quot;>;deliberate practice&lt;/a>; in developing world-class performers. Mere instruction is not enough, you also need to practice skills, identify areas for improvement, and receive coaching. It is this combination of education, experience, and exposure that improve performance.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;The 70/20/10 Learning Model&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If our organizations are to learn the skills needed to win the future, we recommend a “70/20/10” learning model incorporating education, exposure, and experience. Here&#39;s how it works:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;10% Formal Instruction (Education):&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;This portion of the learning strategy involves structured educational experiences, such as the storytelling workshops the Wipro executives attended at night. Other examples include webinars or in-person courses that focus on specific skills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;20% Social Learning (Exposure):&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;Social learning involves learning from others. This is the role the professional storytellers played in the Wipro example. Other options include mentoring, coaching, or peer-to-peer interactions. For example, setting up a mentorship program within an organization can help employees learn from more experienced colleagues. Regular team-building activities can also foster a culture of continuous learning and help improve skills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;70% Learning in the Flow of Work (Experience):&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;This is the most significant part of the learning strategy. It involves learning on the job through real-life experiences and tasks. For example, employees can improve their problem-solving skills by working on complex projects. Regular feedback sessions can help employees reflect on their performance and identify areas for improvement. When the participants of the storytelling workshop continued to teach their own colleagues and apply it in their business pitches and reviews, they got precious hands-on experience that deepened their storytelling skills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is very different from more traditional corporate learning approaches that focus primarily on MBA-style classroom instruction, like the one General Electric made famous at the Management Development Institute at Crotonville during the Jack Welch era. To be successful in the 70/20/10 learning model, managers need to take an active role as &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/the-leader-as-coach&quot;>;coaches&lt;/a>;, rather than as taskmasters, working to mentor their staff to improve performance. At the same time, Learning and Development (L&amp;amp;D) departments are going to have to do more than merely source curricula; they need to collaborate intensively with leaders to design personalized learning environments. Learning needs to be inclusive, continuous, and collaborative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, as part of a regional initiative to reinvigorate the Texas Panhandle region, BOC Bank sought to help its managers make the transition from seeing their roles as performance evaluators to upskilling coaches. The L&amp;amp;D team didn&#39;t start with a preexisting learning plan, but first spent time with leaders to identify tasks for performance improvement. Those tasks were then broken down into skills that individual employees needed to learn, and the L&amp;amp;D team mentored managers as they took the lead coaching their staff through personalized learning plans, using the 70/20/10 model. Within nine months, they started seeing measurable results in terms of the company&#39;s standard business metrics. “Our adoption of the 70/20/10 model is directly fueling our ability to innovate, enabling us to build distinctive core software that sets us apart in the banking sector,” said Alex O&#39;Brien, CEO of the bank.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we are to compete for the future, we need to shift from a “war for talent” mindset to a skills-based mindset. Talent isn&#39;t an innate property that firms can attract and bid for, but a capacity that needs to be built — and in any case, the most vital skills of the future don&#39;t exist yet. In the same way that venture capitalists invest in and manage portfolios of companies, corporate leaders need to pursue portfolios of skills, divesting in some that become obsolete while doubling down on others that begin to pay off.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The future of work will not be determined by technology, but by creating the right mix of education, exposure, and experience needed to develop skills and put them to work, creating a vastly more productive workplace and economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Avoid the Unexpected Consequences of Your DEI Policy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/10/how-to-avoid-the-unexpected-consequences-of-your-dei-policy]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/10/Oct23_06_1257013702.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;MirageC/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Will the DEI policy you&amp;#8217;re about to implement actually hurt some of the people you&amp;#8217;re trying to help? New research on this question shows that, yes, this can happen if you fail to take a systems-level view &amp;#8212; but the good news is there are three key ways to avoid unintended consequences. First, consider subgroups. Think about variation within the group of people the policy is aimed at helping; for example, whether the experiences of most women employees might differ from women managers. Second, think big. Recognize that the interactions between people at your organization are diverse and complex. When policies reverberate, they can harm groups or subgroups in unanticipated ways. Third, track closely. Monitor the policy as it is being rolled out for any negative effects on employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-to-avoid-the-unexpected-consequences-of-your-dei-policy?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/10/how-to-avoid-the-unexpected-consequences-of-your-dei-policy?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;While many managers are attempting to improve inequalities facing employees by implementing diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) policies, &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/07/why-diversity-programs-fail&quot;>;these policies often have unexpected, negative consequences for the employees&lt;/a>; — including those the policies are trying to help. How can managers avoid this?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/epub/10.1177/00018392231174235&quot;>;My research&lt;/a>; shows that there is a need to take a systems-level view of inequality when implementing DEI policies. That is, when designing and implementing a policy, managers must consider how it will reverberate throughout the organization — and how it might ultimately backfire.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;The Policy&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;At the midsize American professional services organization I studied, leaders had the well-intentioned aim of implementing a flexible work policy that allowed employees more control over where and when they worked. The company was already considered life- and family-friendly by employees, and leaders wanted to cement this, both because it would help current employees&#39; well-being and also because it could provide the company with a competitive edge in hiring. Leaders also recognized that these policies could help women in particular, because at this professional organization — &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/09/the-surprising-benefits-of-work-life-support&quot;>;as in many others&lt;/a>; — women performed more family care than men.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once the policy was rolled out, it did in fact help many employees. And as anticipated, I found that the policy helped women in particular integrate and balance work and life demands. For instance, it helped them break up their schedule and spend more time with their kids, and lessen the time they spent commuting so they could spend time with family.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;The Problem&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;However, what the organization&#39;s leaders — and I — did not anticipate was how the flexible work policy harmed a specific group of women: women managers. This was despite the fact that these managers were almost all very vocal supporters of improving gender equality, and had advocated for and supported a wide variety of other women- and family-friendly initiatives, including backup childcare, onsite daycare, and a women speaker series.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did this happen? My research found that many women managers had developed a managerial style focused on close, day-to-day interactions with subordinates. For instance, many would regularly stop by the offices of each of their subordinates daily, asking them how they were doing and if they could offer any help or guidance with their work. Others would work with their doors open so that subordinates could stop by their office whenever they needed help. Employees appreciated these managers&#39; efforts, not only because they provided more immediate task-based assistance but also because, over time, these managers came to know their employees very well and could offer custom-tailored advice on project staffing, career training, and so on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Importantly, the women managers did not develop this managerial style in a vacuum. Rather, it seemed to reflect stereotypes they faced on the job: They experienced pressure to be helpful and communal, rather than direct and assertive like their male manager counterparts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem from the women managers&#39; perspective was that the flexible work policy would make the style they had developed difficult to maintain. While video calls were an option, managers did not view them as an easy or natural way to spark interaction. Others pointed out that with their subordinates working different schedules with varied hours, this meant that they needed to be available at a broader range of hours as well if they were to remain available and helpful to their workers. Not only would this be difficult for anyone to do, it also threatened to make women managers&#39; own work-life conflict much worse because it made it hard for them to have time with their own families.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While my research was specifically on gender, what I found was consistent with &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/07/update-your-dei-playbook&quot;>;other&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/00018392231183649&quot;>;research&lt;/a>; that emphasizes the need to consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aom.org/doi/abs/10.5465/amr.2017.0087&quot;>;the whole organization to effectively implement a DEI effort&lt;/a>;, as well as research that highlights the importance of considering &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aom.org/doi/abs/10.5465/amr.2017.0062&quot;>;how individuals engage and interact with one another within the organizational system&lt;/a>;. This is in addition, of course, to considering other important causes of DEI policy failure, such as &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/10/is-your-dei-progress-undermined-by-attention-inequality&quot;>;various&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/03/to-overcome-resistance-to-dei-understand-whats-driving-it&quot;>;individual-level biases&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Avoiding Unexpected Consequences from Your DEI Policy&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Given that DEI policies can reverberate in organizations in unexpected ways — and potentially undermine hard-won progress on equity- and equality-related outcomes — it is important for managers to anticipate such issues. My research, and complementary research by other scholars (some of which I detail below) presents three key suggestions for how managers can limit the chance of their policies backfiring. These suggestions are all rooted in taking a systems-level view of inequality when designing and implementing DEI policies.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1. Consider subgroups.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;When designing a DEI policy, think about variation within the group of people the policy is aimed at helping. In my research, there was an important difference between the experiences of most women employees (who benefited from the policy) and women managers (who were harmed).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As another example, imagine if managers attempted to help Black employees through creating a peer mentorship program. This program might provide vital help, advice, and connection at work for enrolled Black employees, who researchers finds are &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/02/20-of-white-employees-have-sponsors-only-5-of-black-employees-do&quot;>;much less likely to have internal sponsors when compared to white workers&lt;/a>;, despite the fact that such aid is &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/06/a-better-approach-to-mentorship#:~:text=The%20evidence%20is%20clear%3A%2075,mentor%20are%20happy%20at%20work.&quot;>;vital for career success&lt;/a>;. However, if there are &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11/what-do-black-executives-really-want&quot;>;relatively few senior Black employees in a company&lt;/a>; — a common occurrence given historical patterns of systemic racism — then these few employees may each have many mentees. The unexpected, unanticipated result may be that senior Black employees end up spending a lot of time coaching junior Black employees instead of focusing on pushing their own careers forward.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lesson here is not that DEI policies should not be introduced, of course. It is that with better planning, such negative results can be anticipated and curbed. And once noticed — whether this is before or even after rollout — solutions can be found. For instance, in our example, could senior Black employees be relieved of other “helping” duties so common in organizations to free up more of their time? Or could these employees be given more &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/07/update-your-dei-playbook&quot;>;“glamor work”&lt;/a>; to help them shine? In general, the point here is to not think about a given group — women, LGBTQ+ people, Black people, and so on — monolithically, but rather to recognize the varying organizational ranks, roles, and tasks of employees as well as their &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/06/an-intersectional-approach-to-inclusion-at-work&quot;>;intersectional identities&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;2. Think big.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;A systems-level perspective draws attention to the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/01/todays-most-critical-workplace-challenges-are-about-systems&quot;>;the interactions and connections between people in organizations are diverse and complex&lt;/a>;. As my research demonstrates, when policies reverberate, they can harm groups or subgroups in ways that are entirely unanticipated by organizational leaders and policy designers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For instance, well-intentioned “ban the box” initiatives aimed at preventing discrimination against people with criminal records — and adopted by many companies and mandated in over a hundred states, cities, and counties in the United States — have also been found to in some cases &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/21/upshot/ban-the-box-an-effort-to-stop-discrimination-may-actually-increase-it.html&quot;>;increase racial discrimination against Black applicants&lt;/a>;, because when these policies are in place, it seems employers are more likely to incorrectly presume Black applicants have a criminal past.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Again, the solution here is not to disavow DEI policies. Rather, it is important to think big when considering how policies could potentially result in unexpected negative consequences for workers, because you never know where or when such consequences will arise. To do this, gather &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/11/why-diverse-teams-are-smarter&quot;>;a diverse group of employees to brainstorm&lt;/a>; what potential challenges could come about from the introduction of a new DEI policy. Also read about and research the experiences of other companies that have implemented similar policies, to see what (if any) unintended consequences may have arisen through their policy adoption.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;3. Track closely.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Monitor the policy as it is being rolled out for any negative effects on employees. There are different layers to monitoring. One is to get immediate, qualitative feedback on employees&#39; experiences through focus groups or anonymous suggestion boxes that let employees provide comments without fear of backlash. Longer term, it is important to analyze internal administrative data to check that there are no concerning or unexpected patterns. This includes looking to see if there is variation between groups or subgroups (eg, women versus men, or black women versus white women) on important markers of individual career success such as performance evaluations, salary, bonuses, and promotions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some organizations have even started piloting their DEI initiatives before rolling them out organization-wide, and such efforts can improve policy quality by identifying issues before the policy has even been officially implemented. Ericsson, a global telecommunications company, &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/04/why-you-should-start-ab-testing-your-dei-initiatives&quot;>;tested a policy intervention aimed at improving women&#39;s interest in internal job openings&lt;/a>;. This testing helped Ericsson identify the message that seemed most likely to decrease the gender gap. And before rolling out a flexible work policy more broadly, &lt;a href=&quot;/2009/10/making-time-off-predictable-and-required&quot;>;Boston Consulting Group tested it with smaller groups of consultants&lt;/a>;. Here, it is important to collect data on employees&#39; experiences at baseline (before rollout) to compare with their experiences after policy implementation&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;DEI policies remain important ways to achieve positive improvements in equality within organizations. These three steps — which take a systems-level view of inequality — are purposeful, meaningful changes that managers can enact to design effective and impactful DEI policies. Of course, the research I present here is just a starting point. More is needed — particularly that accounts for different actors&#39; perspectives and the connections between them — to understand how DEI policies can be designed to best help employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>