<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[How to Be a Better Leader Amid Volatility, Uncertainty, Complexity, and Ambiguity]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-to-be-a-better-leader-amid-volatility-uncertainty-complexity-and-ambiguity]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_28_sb10063113cd-001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria- label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;ColorBlind Images/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot; >; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;三十多年前，美国陆军战争学院开发了一个框架，用于了解领导者如何在动荡、不确定、复杂的时期取得成功，和歧义。该框架被称为 VUCA，此后得到了广泛的讨论和采用，但事实证明，它更适合描述成功领导者所做的事情，而不是教导所有领导者如何取得成功。作者提出了一种更新的方法，已在军事、商业和体育领域产生了积极的成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot; /2023/09/how-to-be-a-better-leader-amid-volatility-uncertainty-complexity-and-ambiguity?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/ 2023/09/how-to-be-a-better-leader-amid-volatility-uncertainty-complexity-and-ambiguity?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;您的环境是变化很快。您缺乏数据来做出自信的决策。您的运营充斥着各种流程。您正在发现的趋势可能是好的，也可能不是。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是波动性、不确定性、复杂性和模糊性这四个挑战。它们是当今商业的现实。但它们&lt;a href=&quot;/1992/11/is-management-still-a-science&quot;>;并不新鲜。 &lt;/a>;它们是市场、销售、制造以及一般生活所固有的。那么为什么有些组织反应更好呢？当其他人陷入困境甚至投降时，他们如何取得成功？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20 世纪 80 年代末，苏联解体引发全球不稳定局势加剧后，美国陆军战争学院开始寻找答案。他们提出了 VUCA 的概念，这是波动性、不确定性、复杂性和模糊性的缩写。他们确定，在 VUCA 中表现最好的领导者有能力创造和传达未来的故事，这个故事足够广泛以适应不断变化的环境，但又足够准确&lt;a href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit. edu/article/beyond-forecasting-creating-new-strategic-narratives&quot;>;产生竞争优势&lt;/a>;。他们将这种技能称为“愿景”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2008 年全球金融危机之后，《哈佛商业评论》发表了&lt;a href=&quot;/2010/11/leading-in- a-vuca-environment&quot;>;关于 VUCA 的四部分系列&lt;/a>;，详细介绍了有远见的领导力的核心特征：灵活性、协作、远见、积极倾听、清晰沟通。从那时起，战争学院的理论就成为了现代商业在不确定的变化时期的标准资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在 2010 年代，陆军研究人员盘点了 VUCA，发现战争学院的理论更适合描述领导者，而不是描述领导者。生产它们。它解释了优秀领导者在 VUCA 中做了什么，但没有解释如何在不太成功的领导者中培养这些行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了填补这一空白，我们（本文的作者）回到了 VUCA。我们中的两人拥有数十年训练军事指挥官和前线领导人的经验；第三位是脑科学专家，负责制定和传达计划和其他叙述。我们与美国陆军特种作战部队合作，开发了一套新技术，用于训练大脑在黑暗和快速变化的环境中启动有效的计划和策略。我们在军队之外的职业体育（例如 NFL）和商业领域（从 Cardinal Health 等财富 15 强公司到 Faire 等价值数十亿美元的科技公司）测试了这些技术。我们将我们的研究结果综合成一种方法，美国陆军已正式认可该方法，并因“突破性研究”而授予表彰奖章。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是这种方法，从心理学家所说的心态转变开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是这种方法。 >; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;更多数据并不总是能改善决策&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;当生活稳定且透明时，更多数据会带来更好的决策。但当生活变得波涛汹涌或阴暗时，数据就会变得脆弱且难以捉摸。更多数据不是一种选择，而寻求数据会导致被动、任务偏离和犹豫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;VUCA 智能领导力的关键是低数据决策。对于计算机来说，低数据决策是不可能的，这就是为什么波动性会导致人工智能变得脆弱并容易出现灾难性错误。但低数据决策是大脑的一种固有能力，它的进化是为了在不可预测的环境中茁壮成长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要激活这种能力，需要瞄准“异常信息”。例外信息是现有规则的例外情况。这是紧急威胁或机遇的最初迹象，就像 1975 年 3 月 5 日大型机工程师 Steve Wozniak 在 Homebrew 计算机俱乐部第一次会议上看到 Altair 8800 微型计算机时一样。其他大型机工程师认为 Altair 太小，没有什么用处。 。但在 Altair 不同寻常的小尺寸中，沃兹尼亚克瞥见了未来的新故事：一个用计算机在家工作和玩游戏的世界。他冲回自己的家，设计了 Apple I。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您认为除非像沃兹尼亚克一样聪明，否则无法发现特殊信息，那么请再想一想。当你还是个孩子的时候，当人行道上不寻常的裂缝和天空中独特的云彩促使你的大脑想象：&lt;em>;如果怎么办？&lt;/em>;要回到早期的思维模式，请摆脱成人大脑对抽象推理的偏见。相反，你应该专注于识别你遇到的每个人和你访问的每个地方的独特之处，比如公司会计师如何利用晚上的时间学习尼日利亚诗歌，或者当地厨师如何像其他人一样混合两种香料。如果您发现自己体验到那种孩子般的力量去梦想新的明天，想象接下来会发生什么，那么您就会知道自己正在接受特殊的挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;新的领导技巧&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h2>; &lt;p>;既然您已经转变了心态，这里有三种训练自己在 VUCA 中更好地领导的技巧。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;不要依赖积极倾听。&amp;nbsp;一定要使用主动提问的新科学。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;主动倾听是一种古老的商业方法，由 Carl Rogers 和 Richard Farson 在 20 世纪 50 年代定义，在紧迫性低且透明度高的情况下非常有效。但在 VUCA 中，您可以通过主动提问来提高效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主动提问通过一种简单的技巧呈现特殊信息：延迟询问&lt;em>;为什么&lt;/em>;。当我们问&lt;em>;为什么&lt;/em>;时，大脑会在现有规则和先前判断中寻找答案，这些规则和判断会驳回或解释新的和意外的情况。相反，优先考虑&lt;em>;什么&lt;/em>;、&lt;em>;谁&lt;/em>;、&lt;em>;何时&lt;/em>;、&lt;em>;地点、方式 - 专注于引发惊喜的答案。这种惊讶是例外的一个指标，迫使大脑制定新的规则和判断。可以收集并同时考虑的例外情况越多，领导者就越能有效地想象新的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们最近与一家财富 50 强金融公司合作，该公司自 2019 年以来一直在失去越来越多的份额其初级人才。为了了解发生了什么，人力资源部问离职者：“你们为什么要去我们的竞争对手？”他们回答说：“钱。”因此，该公司提高了保留率，但人才仍在流失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了帮助公司更有效地应对这一紧急挑战，我们培训其人力资源人员推迟询问&lt;em>;为什么&lt;/em>;和相反，让初级人才提出这样的问题：&lt;em>;你周末做什么&lt;/em>;？ &lt;em>;你和谁一起做这件事&lt;/em>;？ &lt;em>;你去哪里度假&lt;/em>;？从这些问题中，HR 确定公司的初级人才存在多种生活满意度低的问题。金钱并不是他们不满的根本原因；金钱并不是他们不满的根本原因。这只是一种替代解释，用于传达他们对某些东西缺失的感觉，并合理化为什么他们想要探索外部职业选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过使用主动提问来确定年轻员工实际上缺失了什么。随着生活的改善，公司在留住人才方面变得更加有效。一位初级高管很不高兴，因为他们和他们的伴侣正在努力怀孕。该公司支付生育治疗费用，然后举办迎婴派对。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;不要优化计划。优化规划器。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;1957 年，美国总统德怀特·艾森豪威尔 (Dwight Eisenhower) 授予&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/remarks-the-national-defense-executive-reserve -会议&quot;>;演讲&lt;/a>;，他回忆起早年在陆军参谋学院度过的时光，为从未发生过的战争进行规划。他说，这是浪费时间，但事实并非如此，因为这个过程训练了他和他的同事为任何事情做好准备。他对听众说：“制定计划之所以如此重要，是为了让自己始终了解问题的本质，有一天你可能会被要求解决这个问题。”换句话说，正如他在那次演讲中所说的那样，“计划毫无价值，但计划就是一切。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久前，我们与一家价值 1 亿美元的销售公司合作，该公司的销售比例异常高。未能成功过渡到领导层的高级管理人员。我们深入了解他们，发现他们认为领导力的关键是制定最佳计划。他们的高级经理集思广益，对每一个可能的挑战或机遇进行了集思广益，计算了可能性，并制定了宏伟的战略。为了以防万一出现意外，他们还制定了B计划。然而，尽管对每一个可能发生的意外情况都有计划，他们还是总是措手不及。他们的最佳计划一次又一次被打破，他们的 B 计划也是如此——此时他们对自己的领导力失去了信心，促使他们的团队也失去了信心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些管理者因为相信计划而让自己走向失败B. 在 VUCA 中，B 计划只不过是 A 计划的变体。两者都基于相同的基本方法和假设，因此如果一个失败，另一个通常会效仿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当高级管理人员过渡到领导层时，我们培训他们超越 B 计划并制定一整套计划，不仅涵盖最可能的突发事件，还涵盖所有可能的突发事件，特别强调极端和前所未有的突发事件。这个过程的目标不是制定更好的计划。这是为了培养更好的规划者，当他们的计划失败时，他们会通过再次规划来做出动态反应。根据公司内部指标的评估，这种方法使高级管理人员转变为领导者的速度提高了一倍以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;不要摆脱恐惧和愤怒。一定要使用情绪重置。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;恐惧和愤怒通常被认为是负面情绪。领导者被教导通过正念、冥想、流行斯多葛主义和其他解离技巧来压制或绕过它们。但是，尽管恐惧和愤怒可能会导致消极行为，但它们的出现，就像所有情绪一样，都是出于积极的原因——特别是，标志着逃跑或战斗反应的开始。当你的神经系统检测到环境波动和其他 VUCA 指标时，就会触发这种反应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你忽视或抑制恐惧和愤怒，你就剥夺了自己经过数百万年生物进化调整的警告系统，当您受到威胁并需要开启领导力愿景时向您发出警报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该警告系统并不完美。但你可以改进它。下次您感到恐惧或愤怒时，请详细回忆一下您成功处理类似情况的一次，提醒您的大脑，&lt;em>;您以前曾经这样做过&lt;/em>;。我们将这种技术称为“情绪重置”。它可以让您快速评估您的飞行和战斗是否适合您的环境。如果当你进行情绪重置时，你的恐惧和愤怒平静下来，那么你的“逃跑或逃跑”反应就是过度反应。您想象的 VUCA 比实际存在的要多，因此最好的行动方案是坚持现有计划并继续收集数据。但是，如果在执行情绪重置时您的恐惧和愤怒仍然持续存在，那么 VUCA 是真实的，并且您的情况很紧急。通过快速重新计划和果断行动，积极应对这种紧迫性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们与一位 NFL 四分卫候选人合作，他在比赛中即兴发挥太多。为了控制他的行为，他的教练训练他遵守比赛计划。这阻止了他即兴发挥，但对他的表现产生了负面影响，使他变成了一个失去游戏感觉的机器人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了帮助他保持即兴发挥而不过度，我们研究了他的比赛录像。我们注意到，他的即兴创作率在失败的比赛后有所增加，这表明他的即兴创作率通常是由过度活跃的“战斗或逃跑”驱动的。为了让他更好地评估他的战斗或逃跑反应的可靠性，我们与他一起进行情绪重置。从比赛录像中，我们重点介绍了他成功执行计划比赛的例子，并让他在心里一遍又一遍地回顾这些情况，详细查看它们。这为他大脑中的记忆做好了快速回忆的准备。然后我们让他创建一个“触发器”，一个他与这些记忆相关联的纪念品。他扣动扳​​机进入下一场比赛，并在每次糟糕的比赛后都会审视它，记住&lt;em>;我以前也这样做过&lt;/em>;。通过调整自己的情绪，他避免了自己不必要的焦虑或攻击性，从而更加一致地遵守教练的比赛计划。通过不强迫自己机械地遵守该计划，他保留了在 VUCA 中即兴创作的能力，领导他的团队在需要时发明新的计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;* * *&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明天充满迷雾和波动。市场、供应链、技术和消费者趋势都是模糊且不断变化的。但您可以带领您的组织取得成功。陆军最初的 VUCA 理论定义了有远见的领导力。现在，利用我们在本文中阐述的内容，您将拥有一种可以在您自己以及您未来的团队中培养这种能力的特殊作战方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div >; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. NET&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/分区>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Deep Tech Can Drive Sustainability and Profitability in Manufacturing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-deep-tech-can-drive-sustainability-and-profitability-in-manufacturing]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_28_97971080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;亚当·高特/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt; span>;摘要。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;公司面临着更大的压力，需要在保持盈利的同时变得更加可持续发展 &amp;#8212;深度技术可以提供帮助。结合物理技术和数字技术的深度技术正在走出实验室，进入现实世界的供应链。年轻的公司，单独工作或与大公司合作，正在做大量工作将其商业化。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href =&quot;/2023/09/how-deep-tech-can-drive-sustainability-and-profitability-in-manufacturing?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/ 09/how-deep-tech-can-drive-sustainability-and-profitability-in-manufacturing?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;追求速度和质量的运营时代，成本效益高于一切的时代已经结束。如今，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2022/product-as-a-service-benefits-opportunities&quot;>;制造商必须追求的目标&lt;/a>;以确保竞争力已经发展。可持续发展长期以来被认为与这些传统目标不相容，但现在已成为一项战略要务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这向制造商提出了一个问题：他们如何才能使产品和生产流程更具可持续性，同时保持盈利？&lt;/p>; &lt;一个充满活力的公司生态系统已经开始打破这种与深度技术的权衡：创新地使用由数字技术支持的新兴物理技术来解决大规模问题。当制造商试图提高盈利能力和可持续性时，是时候更广泛、更大规模地使用深度技术了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多种因素正在汇聚，使这一切成为可能。首先，在净零承诺和利益相关者需求的推动下，实现可持续发展的紧迫性不断上升。其次，对发展绿色技术的金融和监管支持从未如此之大。美国的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/cleanenergy/inflation-reduction-act-guidebook/&quot;>;通货膨胀减少法案&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;https:// Commission.europa.eu/strategy-and-policy/priorities-2019-2024/european-green-deal_en&quot;>;欧盟的欧洲绿色协议&lt;/a>;就是最好的例子。第三，潜在的变革技术正在走出实验室，进入现实世界，其中许多技术已经取得了规模化的成功。这些不断变化的动态为制造商提供了机遇，例如创建或进入新市场或确保在解决&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2023/how-scarcity-will-reshape-sustainability -strategy&quot;>;供应短缺&lt;/a>;，尤其是绿色材料。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;新时代运营&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率并增强弹性。&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;为了抓住这些机会、打破权衡并实现可持续发展，领导者应该深入应用其产品和流程中的技术。他们还需要考虑如何与创新生态系统合作，尤其是与年轻的深度科技公司合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;深度科技可以增强产品的盈利能力和可持续性&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;借助深度科技，制造公司可以重新构想其产品的本质。企业必须考虑更根本的产品更新，而不是提供增量增强或部分替代（这通常不会产生显着效益，甚至可能适得其反）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;制造商可以开发和使用新材料与传统材料的供应链或环境足迹脱钩。合成生产的生物材料可以作为可持续的基础材料或直接替代品。将可持续制造产品转化为新的相关产品声明的细分市场更有可能获得绿色溢价，例如在个人美容领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考虑&lt;a href=&quot;https://www .genomatica.com/&quot;>;Geno&lt;/a>; 是一家总部位于圣地亚哥的公司，基于其合成生物学平台，开发了棕榈油和化石美容、清洁和服装成分的植物替代品。 Geno 的合成生物学棕榈油的碳足迹比传统棕榈衍生成分低 50%。通过提供可追溯性并降低对传统棕榈油供应链的依赖，其使用还提高了供应链的透明度和弹性。同样，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.modernmeadow.com/&quot;>;Modern Meadow&lt;/a>; 开发了一种合成生物学衍生的胶原蛋白，具有独特的生物活性作用。特种原料供应商&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.modernmeadow.com/news/evonikpartnership&quot;>;赢创与Modern Meadow合作&lt;/a>;，将其推广到个人护理和化妆品领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深科技可以有助于原材料的供应和价格稳定，这对制造商来说至关重要。改用可再生或更丰富的材料可以满足这两个需求，甚至可以缩短供应链，降低物流网络的复杂性和碳足迹。例如，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nironMagnetics.com/&quot;>;Niron Magnetics&lt;/a>; 已开发出高性能磁体，并正在扩大其生产规模。他们的磁铁由丰富的氮和铁制成，这是缓解稀土金属供应链的可行替代方案，稀土金属供应链集中在少数来源，并且仅在全球少数几家工厂加工。虽然最初针对的是传感器或扬声器等应用，但这些磁铁很快就会&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/permanent-magnet-tesla&quot;>;为制造电动汽车电机&lt;/a>;做出贡献，例如来自特斯拉，不含稀土。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提高盈利能力和可持续性的另一种方法是改变产品的性能特征，例如延长其使用寿命或赋予可持续产品特性，而这是不可能的例如，Basilisk 开发了一种生物基直接处理剂，由使用合成生物技术的工程微生物制成，可以与砂浆混合或应用于现有的混凝土结构。该修复系统使用产生石灰石的微生物来消除裂缝修复和维护的需要。根据产品的不同，这可以将 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 排放量降低 &lt;a href=&quot;https://basiliskconcrete.com/en/products/product-healing-agent/&quot;>;30–50%&lt;/ a>; 与传统混凝土相比，延长了混凝土的使用寿命并减少了加固所需的钢材用量。如果大规模应用，这可能意味着全球 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 排放量减少 1.5% 以上，因为目前全球 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 排放量中有 6% 以上来自混凝土。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;深度技术可以使可持续流程经济学更具吸引力&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;产生约束的不仅仅是产品本身，还有用于制造这些约束的流程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2023/05/31/there-is-more-than-one-way-to-make-green-steel&quot;>;波士顿金属&lt; /a>; 通过发明一种新的电解工艺和相关设备，能够使用 100% 可再生电力运行且不排放 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;，重新构想了传统的碳密集型炼钢工艺。熔融氧化物电解技术采用新型电极材料，能够承受高温并在氧气存在下保持稳定，有可能减少钢铁行业的碳足迹，目前钢铁行业占全球碳足迹的 8%。温室气体排放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深层技术可以实现流程创新，从而实现能源效率的逐步改变。结合新的生产推动因素（例如从线性装配线向小型蜂窝工厂的转变），制造商可以提高灵活性，引入本地制造的可选性，并过渡到碳足迹较低的生产网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如， &lt;a href=&quot;https://plasmonics.tech/&quot;>;Syzygy Plasmonics&lt;/a>; 的可扩展光反应器结合了 LED 光和光催化纳米粒子来进行化学反应，这是通过结合建筑材料的进步和光子学的创新而实现的。由于反应堆将光能精确地集中在需要的地方，因此转化变得比传统反应更加高效和可持续。通过消除排放量大的化学工业中的燃烧需求，Syzygy Plasmonics 的目标是到 2040 年避免 10 亿吨 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 排放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，制造商可以完全开发和使用新工艺，例如新的增材制造或精密发酵技术，可以实现传统上无法制造的可持续产品。借助深厚的技术，制造商可以通过从原子开始构建来设计工艺，减少所需能量的转化次数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geno 已成功扩展其合成生物技术和基于农场的供应链，以应对大型原料市场例如工业化学品丁二醇 (BDO) 和对其品牌合作伙伴可持续发展目标至关重要的尼龙，例如 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unilever.com/news/press-and-media/press-releases/2022 /unilever-and-geno-launch-120m-venture-to-scale-alternative-ingredients/&quot;>;联合利华&lt;/a>;，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loreal-finance.com/eng/news- event/loreal-invests-biotechnology-venture-scale-development-plant-based-ingredients&quot;>;欧莱雅&lt;/a>;，以及&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.genomatica.com/news-content/lululemon -partners-with-genomatica-on-plant-based-nylon/&quot;>;Lululemon&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;运营高管应寻找近期&lt;a href=&quot;创造的激励、补贴和其他机会/2023/09/the-new-era-era-of-industrial-policy-is-here&quot;>;政府政策&lt;/a>;。在美国，仅 IRA 一项就涵盖&lt;a href=&quot;https://media-publications.bcg.com/BCG-Executive-Perspectives-US-IRA-Clean-Tech.pdf&quot;>;710 亿美元&lt;/a>;刺激先进制造业、工业设施和能源效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;建立创新生态系统&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;深度技术在合成生物学和 3D 打印等多种新兴技术的交叉点上运行。它解决了跨不同科学领域的复杂问题。它需要满足真正的市场需求，同时通常需要大量资金和延长开发周期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传统公司可能会发现很难驾驭这个快速变化的环境。很少有（如果有的话）拥有单独完成这项工作的工具和能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要开始取得进展，制造商应该寻求&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/ 2023/fast-tracking-new-green-technologies&quot;>;与合作伙伴合作&lt;/a>;——通过商业联盟、孵化器或生态系统，例如甚至包括政府和学术界。尽管看起来违反直觉，年轻的深度科技公司和现有制造商不应该竞争，而应该合作。成熟的制造商可以期望获得新技术和特定的专业知识，使他们能够在其产品和流程中应用深层技术。在与深度技术初创公司合作时，制造商应寻找与其领域最兼容的解决方案，并建立在&lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2023/02/03/synthetic-biology-startups-incumbents-合作/&quot;>;他们可以利用独特的资产和能力&lt;/a>;为共同努力创造价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，总部位于芝加哥的生物技术公司 LanzaTech 开发了一种基于微生物的技术，该技术利用残留物含有一氧化碳和氢气的气体作为原料生产生物乙醇。在&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.basf.com/global/en/media/news-releases/2021/05/p-21-206.html&quot;>;与巴斯夫&lt;/a>;等合作伙伴关系中，作为全球最大的化学品制造商，LanzaTech 致力于将炼钢等工业流程废气中的碳转化为各行业的可持续原材料。通过以这种方式捕获和利用碳，该技术可以帮助减少许多制造商和相关供应链的碳排放。因此，巴斯夫提高了客户资源使用的可持续性，并帮助创造对 LanzaTech 技术的需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个例子只是众多例子之一。在寻求与深度科技初创公司合作时，制造商可以考虑&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2023/what-is-your-synthetic-bio-strategy&quot;>;合作伙伴关系、合资企业或并购临近&lt;/a>;。最佳的参与策略和合适的合作伙伴将取决于制造商在其领域面临的具体限制、补充缺失的内部能力的需要以及期望的雄心水平或规模。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了实现商业成功，由于技术规模庞大，制造商应将其产品或工艺创新与根本不同的价值链结合起来。我们对商业生态系统的广泛研究表明，价值链转型虽然具有挑战性并且通常需要广泛的合作，但将释放巨大的价值。制造商可以利用其独特的能力和现有的关系来影响供应商和分销商过渡到支持新流程和产品或帮助应对监管环境的解决方案或基础设施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以时尚行业为例，该行业占约占全球温室气体排放量的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://fashionforgood.com/our_news/fashion-for-good-launches-the-renewable-carbon-textiles-project/&quot;>;4%&lt;/a>;。可持续发展创新工作尤其需要在复杂的全球时尚价值链中发挥作用&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glossy.co/fashion/a-tough-sell-to-ceos-fashion-sustainability-is -take-a-hit-in-the-current-economy/&quot;>;在当前经济环境下面临挑战&lt;/a>;。公司通过像 Fashion for Good 这样的联盟进行跨行业合作来分担风险。 Fashion for Good 建立了一个&lt;a href=&quot;https://fashionforgood.com/innovation-platform/&quot;>;创新计划&lt;/a>;，将品牌、零售商、制造商和投资者联系起来，开发和规模化纺织行业的颠覆性解决方案&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个全行业倡议的成员正在寻求实现在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://fashionforgood.com/innovation-platform/focus-areas/ 实现可持续变革的集体目标”材料、加工或最终使用等领域&lt;/a>;，但无法单独完成。例如，该集团启动了&lt;a href=&quot;https://fashionforgood.com/our_news/fashion-for-good-launches-the-renewable-carbon-textiles-project/&quot;>;可再生碳纺织品项目&lt;/ a>;，专注于用聚羟基脂肪酸酯（PHA）聚合物纤维生产纤维，这可以为传统化石纤维提供可持续的、可生物降解的替代品，有可能显着减少时尚价值链中的排放，同时允许制造商进行微调织物特性。该项目将 Danimer Scientific、Bio Craft Innovation、Paques Biomaterials、Helian Polymers 和 Newlight Technologies 等创新者的专业知识与业内其他参与者相结合，他们将测试解决方案、提供资金并帮助扩展解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2 >;&lt;strong>;结论&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;深度技术企业以及与制造业现有企业合作的例子表明，深度技术已经可以帮助公司实现运营模式，在不牺牲长期利益的情况下推进共同的可持续发展议程。期限盈利能力。 The real challenge is not the technology itself, but the inertia of long-established capital investments and time-tested manufacturing approaches — overcoming this is no small feat.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Given the pressing urgency for sustainability, manufacturers need to act swiftly and decisively. Manufacturers that leverage their unique capabilities and succeed in identifying the right engagement models can use deep tech as their critical driver of competitive advantage — and now is the time to get started.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Ways to Prepare for the Future of Work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/3-ways-to-prepare-for-the-future-of-work]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/07/Jul23_20_alanahsarginson.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Alanah Sarginson&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Many forces are converging today in unprecedented ways to reshape the nature of work. To understand and adapt to these forces, leaders need to start thinking seriously about three important areas of concern: the future of &lt;em>;workers&lt;/em>; (who are questioning the role that work plays in their lives and demanding more from the organizations they work for); the future of &lt;em>;working&lt;/em>; (which is evolving rapidly thanks to hybrid and flexible work arrangements, digitalization, and automation); and the future of &lt;em>;work &lt;/em>;itself (which always involves in response to macro forces and societal shifts). The authors refer to these three areas as the &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>;, the &lt;em>;what&lt;/em>;, and the &lt;em>;why &lt;/em>;of work. Each has its own particular set of challenges. Leaders need to confront and address these challenges, and the authors of this article provide suggestions for how they can best do that.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/3-ways-to-prepare-for-the-future-of-work?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/3-ways-to-prepare-for-the-future-of-work?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The last few years have been marked by generation-defining crises — political, economic, societal, and environmental. Much that we once took for granted about the world of work has been called into question, and much that was previously unimaginable is now an everyday fact of life. But the churn is far from over. As a recent recruit at a global consulting firm told us, “We are at the beginning, not the end, of massive upheavals in our work lives.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These upheavals have prompted all sorts of questions about the future of work. Where are we headed? What does the future hold, and how can leaders prepare? What should they focus on as they move their organizations forward? Digitalization and the rapidly growing capabilities of AI? The many repercussions of the shift to hybrid work? Employee wellbeing? The changing priorities of millennials and boomers? Questions of social and environmental responsibility? The unstable geopolitical context and our unclear economic future?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with these multiple competing — yet interdependent — issues, leaders are feeling understandably overwhelmed. “I have done all I can to hold this firm together through the pandemic,” the CEO of the above-mentioned consulting firm told us. “When I contemplate the scale of the challenges that lie ahead, I feel I have nothing left to give.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re scholars of leadership, sustainability, and organizational change. In recent years we have focused our attention on how leaders and organizations can best rise to meet these challenges. And what we&#39;ve learned, in both our academic research and our professional consulting, is that if leaders hope to understand and adapt to the forces that are reshaping work, they&#39;re going to need to start thinking more specifically about three important areas of concern: 1) the future of &lt;em>;workers&lt;/em>;, 2) the future of &lt;em>;working&lt;/em>;, and 3) the future of &lt;em>;work &lt;/em>;itself.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>;, the &lt;em>;what&lt;/em>;, and the &lt;em>;why &lt;/em>;of work.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Three Areas of Concern&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>;, &lt;em>;what&lt;/em>; and &lt;em>;why&lt;/em>; of work are deeply connected. Thinking about how they are related won&#39;t help us accurately predict the future, but it will help us prepare for it. So let&#39;s consider each in turn.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The future of workers (the &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>;).&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Pandemic-induced introspection and the frame-breaking experience of lockdown have caused a lot of people to question the role of work in their lives. They&#39;re asking profound questions about what their organizations are demanding of them and questioning whether their organizations are worthy of their commitment. At the same time, they&#39;re often demanding the right to bring more of their “whole selves” to work, which has forced leaders to pay much more attention than in the past to questions concerning, among other topics, employees&#39; gender, race, religion, and sexuality.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Work&quot; dek=&quot;Will your company adapt or be left behind?&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-future-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Insight Center Collection &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;The Future of Work&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; Will your company adapt or be left behind? &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;But leaders who become too focused on addressing diverse individual needs can lose sight of the bigger picture. Employees&#39; questions and concerns about work arise from a collision between two powerful forces: today&#39;s macro socio-economic realities, on the one hand, and long-accepted understandings of what belonging to an organization and doing “good” work look like, on the other. Any reflections on the future of work must take stock of this evolving status of the &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>; and how it relates to the &lt;em>;what &lt;/em>;and &lt;em>;why&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The future of working (the &lt;em>;what&lt;/em>;).&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Hybrid, remote, and flexible working are here to stay. In spite of attempts to compel staff to return to the office, levels of remote working remain four to five times higher than before the pandemic. These new practices fundamentally alter how people work, where they work, and when they work, but their consequences are not yet fully understood.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leaders feel themselves under pressure to announce “standardized” policies, as a way of providing some reassuring certainty in the midst of uncomfortable ambiguity. But in the current unsettled macro context, a sense of certainty about how we should work can only be illusory and transient.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile digitalization is rapidly reshaping the ways people and machines interact, affecting the tasks we do, the roles we fulfill, and the organizational arrangements that guide and support us. By the mid 2030s, up to 30% of jobs may be at risk of automation, and today&#39;s rapid developments in AI have brought the future into the present much faster than most predicted. How can leaders shape work environments and employee tasks that are in constant flux as a result of rapidly evolving technological systems?&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The future of work (the &lt;em>;why&lt;/em>;).&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Long-term macro forces and short-term shocks are creating a host of new demands on business as we adapt to new energy infrastructures, aging populations, and a hotter, more turbulent planet. Supply-chain disruptions are becoming increasingly frequent. Political events are also galvanizing rapid shifts in public sentiment — about racial inequality, for example, or business relations with Russia and China. Alongside these macro shifts, people&#39;s desires and actions are evolving, reflecting deepening differences in values, aspirations, and life choices.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some leaders are responding with renewed statements of purpose, defining how they will serve societal needs alongside shareholders&#39; increasingly diverse expectations. But these attempts to take the long view are fraught with short-term ambiguities, as moves toward redefining the role of business in society trigger backlash. This is to be expected as we work through cultural shifts and start to develop a new understanding of “what good business looks like,” and hence what good work comprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;We Have More Agency Than We Realize&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The upheavals that are reshaping the who, what and why of work feel beyond our control, and to some extent that will continue. Even if the direction of travel is clear, no one can predict with certainty when and where the next operational or human crisis will arise, nor whether it will be triggered by technology, war, climate, or social unrest. Regaining agency starts with recognizing our role in this complex system, and noting how workers, working, and work itself are intertwined. Ultimately, the future of work is not “out there.” It&#39;s within us and our organizations, and we can help shape it with our colleagues through the steps outlined below.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Lead collectively through uncertainty.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;For complex environmental and geopolitical challenges, it&#39;s generally accepted that localized action can only have a limited effect, and that the solutions lie in collective action. Just as nations acting alone are weak and ineffective at dealing with complex system-level challenges, so too are leaders in organizations. To address the challenges of the future of work, leaders need to understand that theirs is not an individual responsibility but rather a collective one that brings together a complex coalition of colleagues across the organization. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/03/how-to-lead-your-fellow-rainmakers&quot;>;Collective leadership&lt;/a>; is a core component of the future of work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remember the exhausted consulting-firm CEO we mentioned at the start of this article, who feels he has “nothing left to give”? He is overburdened by his sense of responsibility for shaping the future of work in his organization. But he shouldn&#39;t have to bear that responsibility alone. The burden is collective. His job is to bring together potential leaders at all levels across the organization to work on this issue, to expand collective insight, and contain emotional uncertainty.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Expand collective insight.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The current complexity of challenges in the world of work cut across hierarchies, generations, functions, and geographies. They can only be addressed by bringing together multiple sets of stakeholders with competing interests who collectively can generate a broad set of insights and help the organization and its leaders successfully navigate uncertainty. By definition those at the top of an organization have the most to lose in the short term and so may be resistant to asking the most challenging questions about the future. Meanwhile, the youngest employees have the most to gain in the long term, because the status quo is of little value to them. For this reason, many of the organizations we work with are exploring ways of integrating new and unfamiliar voices into their leadership discussions.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Contain emotional uncertainty.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;While leaders need to reach out across their organization to instigate and sustain leadership initiatives, they also need to create some emotional guard rails. A key role for leaders at any time is to work out how best to balance individuals&#39; need for autonomy with their organization&#39;s need for control. While younger colleagues in particular may crave autonomy and opportunities to pursue their passions at work, they still need the reassurance of believing in the collective identity of their organization and their position within it. Leaders should remind employees of the best aspects of their organization&#39;s past, to reaffirm their cultural identity and to provide a firm base from which to build a collective future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;* * *&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ultimately, we all want to belong to something greater than ourselves that is worth committing to. But the organizations we belong to have changed, and &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/how-has-the-past-year-changed-you-and-your-organization&quot;>;so have we&lt;/a>;. Faced with cumulatively overwhelming challenges, it is tempting to turn away from them and try just to carry on as “normal.” But when the old sense of normal is no longer relevant, as is the case today in the world of work, we have to learn how to think clearly about what&#39;s happening.&amp;nbsp; We have to recognize that we will ultimately make sense of this difficult and exciting transformative period only by creating a new sense of normal for ourselves, one that accommodates rather than resists ambiguity and ongoing uncertainty. That&#39;s simply not something we can do in isolation. But within our organizations, focusing on collective leadership, we can begin to do it together.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:25:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Personalize Your IT Service Delivery With Persona Mapping - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM UNISYS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/personalize-your-it-service-delivery-with-persona-mapping]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364744&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/WRQ-1240-3177-Harvard-Business-Review-Sponsor_Header-Image.jpg&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;By Alan Shen&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anyone who has worn a one-size-fits-all T-shirt knows that not every fit is a good fit, despite what the label says.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same holds true for the delivery of enterprise technologies to employees. A one-size-fits-all strategy may loosely fit the needs of some of your employees—but not all.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some successful organizations have embraced a promising alternative: persona mapping, the strategy of identifying individuals (or personas) within your organization and tailoring the technology experiences you deliver to each persona group. It&#39;s a shift from the mindset of “a user is a user” that maps each employee to the business function they serve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Persona mapping is a must for any organization prioritizing business for understanding and refining the employee experiences (EXs) you provide. By creating persona groups, you can measure and optimize the business impact of your enterprise technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;How can persona mapping optimize IT service delivery? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Persona mapping enables your IT teams to recognize the unique needs of every employee rather than focusing on a broad picture of a generic end user. Beyond improving EX, a persona-mapping strategy can align to organizational priorities, making it easier to achieve key business outcomes.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Here are two of many applications for persona mapping.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Help desk ticket routing&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Organizations often struggle to efficiently allocate limited IT support resources and prioritize service tickets, especially when multiple specialized service desks are involved.想象一下，向服务台代理解释您的问题，然后将其转移给其他代理，然后要求您重述问题的详细信息。这种低效率可能会导致员工寻求帮助时出现令人沮丧的延误。 Us for better customer service and reduced response times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When an employee contacts the service desk, a dynamic lookup system identifies their persona group and directs them to the right specialist immediately. A field salesperson might be sent directly to a team specializing in their specific sales software, while a health care worker could be directed to an expert familiar with their hospital&#39;s electronic medical record system. This approach not only improves the support experience but also enhances employee productivity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Equipment refresh&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adopting a persona-driven approach to device life cycle management ensures your workforce has the tools it needs for optimal performance. Engineers using heavy-duty applications may need frequent device updates, while occasional equipment upgrades may suffice for a salesperson, saving costs and benefiting the environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, frontline employees, like airline crews using corporate tablets, benefit from tailored support solutions. Providing support at briefing centers or a “device help” button for airport staff ensures efficient on-site troubleshooting without inconveniencing passengers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;How do you choose your personas?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The number of personas your organization should create depends on what&#39;s both manageable and useful for IT. If you&#39;re new to persona mapping, start with up to ten personas to balance benefits and administrative ease. Scaling up can occur as needed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remember, personas shouldn&#39;t be aligned solely by job role, because roles can vary widely in technology needs. Instead, create personas based on clusters of employees with similar needs, such as a group comprising finance, legal, and marketing staff or another based on geographic location.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When developing personas, consider these key factors:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Seniority and role: &lt;/strong>;High-ranking executives and mission-critical employees like trauma center doctors may need prioritized IT support. Organizations often create a VIP persona for such roles.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Customer experience:&lt;/strong>; Roles that are customer facing, like retail staff, may require quicker support to minimize downtime and its impact on the customer experience.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Location:&lt;/strong>; Employees at a manufacturing plant may require immediate Tier 1 service desk attention to avoid costly downtime. Location-based personas also help tailor services for remote and in-office staff.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Some employees may fit multiple personas, such as a doctor who is both customer facing and of high seniority.在这种情况下，建立一个流程来帮助 IT 部门决定在不同场景中哪个角色优先。 Whatever the circumstance, understanding a day in the life of each of your user personas is a must.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What&#39;s involved in setting up persona mapping? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;Persona mapping involves qualitative research, often through workshops with key stakeholders, to understand employee tech needs and daily experiences. However, merely listing personas isn&#39;t enough; significant engineering is required to map this data in your identity database for tailored IT services.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A common hurdle for adoption is unclear responsibility for planning, implementation, and maintenance of personas. To avoid setbacks, it&#39;s crucial to assemble a dedicated team and clarify stakeholder responsibilities early on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Maximize your business value with persona mapping&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prioritize your IT resources based on personas to better inform equipment refreshes, service ticket routing, EX initiatives, and other business processes.角色映射可以帮助您的员工提供更好的客户成果，从而提高客户忠诚度和续订率。 Unlike a one-size-fits-all T-shirt, persona mapping leads to a much better fit for everyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Learn more about crafting a persona-powered workplace &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unisys.com/solutions/employee-experience/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;here&lt;/a>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Alan Shen is &lt;i>;Vice President of Solution Portfolio and Development, Digital Workplace Solutions at Unisys&lt;/i>;&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Research: How Some Companies Avoid Accusations of Greenwashing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/research-how-some-companies-avoid-accusations-of-greenwashing]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/08/Aug23_25_9FvZfRKKfH8_wpce-AsLxk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff/Unsplash&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Recent research reveals a troubling trend: apex firms in Business Groups often promote sustainability without substantial action. Analyzing data from 515 companies in 35 countries, the authors found that apex firms, especially those sharing a brand with affiliates, engaged less in sustainability initiatives than their lower-tier counterparts. This potential &amp;#8220;greenwashing&amp;#8221; might be tolerated due to the unique BG structure, where apex firms play communicators and affiliates act as implementers. Despite market tolerance, such discrepancies could harm long-term reputations. For genuine sustainability, firms must ensure accurate communication, inspire affiliates with shared values, diffuse best practices groupwide, and stay attuned to evolving stakeholder expectations. Sustainability is not just a symbolic gesture but a commitment requiring consistent, substantive action.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/research-how-some-companies-avoid-accusations-of-greenwashing?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/research-how-some-companies-avoid-accusations-of-greenwashing?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Sustainability has rapidly become an indispensable part of corporate governance. But as companies commit to green practices, a worrying trend is also surfacing: Some corporations are painting themselves as green while failing to back their claims with concrete actions. Numerous examples abound: The UK Advertising Standards Authority (ASA) has recently banned a number of ads from prominent companies, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-63309878&quot;>;HSBC&lt;/a>; for being “misleading” about efforts to tackle climate change. The ASA also &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sky.com/story/ryanair-adverts-banned-for-making-misleading-co2-emissions-claims-11926471#:~:text=%22Misleading%22%20Ryanair%20adverts%20have%20been,radio%20ads%20from%20September%202019.&quot;>;banned the ads of Ryanair&lt;/a>; for the company&#39;s unsubstantiated claim of being Europe&#39;s lowest emissions airline.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to regulators, companies that project an unsubstantiated green image are&amp;nbsp;also being&amp;nbsp;called out by investors, and consumers, who may punish such “greenwashing” through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/sustainable-finance-reporting/us-sec-readies-penalty-dws-greenwashing-probe-by-end-september-sources-2023-07-25/&quot;>;penalties&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/policy/tax-and-super/hesta-members-call-for-divestment-from-woodside-warn-of-greenwashing-20230910-p5e3g1&quot;>;divestment&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/business/more-than-half-of-shoppers-prepared-to-boycott-greenwashing-firms-poll-suggests-b2413496.html&quot;>;boycotts&lt;/a>;, or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2023/apr/22/appalling-earth-day-greenwashing-a-risk-to-progress-says-protest-founder-aoe&quot;>;protests&lt;/a>;. Yet, our recent research suggests that some companies may be engaging in similar behavior while escaping, to a certain degree, scrutiny and sanctions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We found that a certain type of firm — specifically, a firm that sits atop of what is known as a Business Group (BG) — seems to largely avoid scrutiny for greenwashing. BGs are prevalent yet understudied entities across the globe in both developing and developed economies, accounting for much, if not the majority, of economic activity in countries as varied as India, Korea, Turkey, and Chile. Each BG is essentially a web of affiliate companies that typically span multiple industries, share resources, and are interconnected through both equity holdings and social ties. The firms in a BG are typically coordinated by a core or apex firm that is often the top corporate owner.&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;Our research reveals a curious dynamic within these arrangements: we found that apex firms are able to report on the sustainability efforts of their lower-tier affiliates “for free,” ie, without substantiating them with their own actions. And they can do this without incurring the greenwashing label.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To shed light on this phenomenon, we analyzed data from 515 publicly listed companies that are members of BGs across 35 different countries. Specifically, we obtained environmental, social, and governance (ESG) data from Refinitiv (formerly ASSET4) which measures each company&#39;s ESG performance relative to its industry peers, relying on company-reported information. We used it to distinguish between a company&#39;s substantive sustainability actions (ie, those related to socially responsible policies and programs) and symbolic ones (ie, reporting, claims, or disclosures). The gap between these two sets of actions was our measure of the extent to which companies decouple “talk” from “action.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We found that apex firms engaged in fewer substantive sustainability actions despite communicating sustainability at similar levels to their lower-tier affiliates. Put differently, these firms systematically “advertised” more than they actually “did” relative to other group members. Adding another layer to this dynamic, we observed that apex firms sharing a brand name with their affiliates engaged in even fewer substantive sustainability actions compared to apex firms that did not have a shared name. Unfortunately, the equity markets appear to extend some tolerance towards this particular type of greenwashing by apex firms compared to their lower-tier affiliates.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What explains this discrepancy? It&#39;s possible that what might be perceived as blatant greenwashing elsewhere could be interpreted as a legitimate division of labor in the unique BG ecosystem. Apex firms, using their influential role and symbolic power, can act as “communicators,” that amplify the group&#39;s overall sustainability initiatives; lower-tier affiliates, in contrast, take on the role of “implementers,” substantively implementing these initiatives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This may provide a short-term advantage to apex firms who essentially attempt to free-ride on the global sustainability movement. However, it&#39;s vital to recognize that the markets&#39; tolerance of apex firms&#39; apparent greenwashing does not absolve them of their responsibilities. Eventually, greenwashing may severely damage long-term reputation and erode stakeholder trust. Leaders should seize upon this understanding as an opportunity to bolster their sustainability practices and reporting. Indeed, our study has important implications for managers, not just within BGs but, more broadly, within firms that are affiliated to others (eg, through alliances and joint ventures).&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Be honest about sustainability efforts.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Overstating sustainability efforts can severely backfire if a gap between rhetoric and reality is exposed. Like the way in which one affiliate&#39;s good reputation reflects well upon the whole group, so would a greenwashing scandal reflect poorly beyond the affected affiliate. Leaders should therefore ensure that public communications about sustainability accurately reflect the group&#39;s actual practices. They should report on and rectify potential discrepancies between sustainability actions and communications. Additionally, establishing comprehensive monitoring through external assurance services can promote transparency and accountability, reducing the chance of perceived greenwashing.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Motivate sustainability among affiliated firms through a shared identity.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Leaders of apex firms should not solely rely on their coordination abilities within the group to ward off perceptions of greenwashing. They also benefit from being the source of a group identity — that includes core values and principles — that can and should be used to mobilize group members towards achieving long-term sustainability. In fact, many BGs do this through appeals to their history. For instance, Japan&#39;s Sumitomo group builds upon its 400-year-old founding principles (the “Sumitomo Spirit”) about mutual prosperity and respect for the public good to motivate its sustainability efforts.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Share sustainability best practices and talent.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Managers at apex firms should not only report on the sustainability efforts carried out by other affiliates, but also diffuse them across the group affiliates. Managers can leverage the well-developed internal HR networks within BGs to recruit personnel adept at corporate sustainability practices or develop teams that can identify and diffuse sustainability actions throughout the group. One example of this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tatasustainability.com/AboutUs/TataSustainabilityGroup&quot;>;the Tata Sustainability Group (TSG)&lt;/a>;, a team of the apex firm Tata Sons that has the “mission to guide, support and provide thought leadership to all Tata group companies in embedding sustainability in their business strategies.” In other words, extending the communication role of apex firms towards internal stakeholders can help develop groupwide substantive sustainability strategies.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Be mindful of evolving stakeholder expectations.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The business world is rapidly shifting, and stakeholders&#39; expectations for sustainability are no exception. Ignoring this evolution can strain relationships with essential stakeholders, including customers, employees, and investors. Leaders should strive to stay in tune with their expectations and make sure their commitment to sustainability is transparent and genuine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, the pursuit of sustainability is not a marketing gimmick, but a commitment that demands substantive, long-term action. A strong group identity may provide some protection for apex firms within BGs, but beneath it, the audience, the stakeholders, and indeed the world, are demanding substantive, not just symbolic, actions. Particularly in the context of BGs and similar organizational setups, any reputational damage is likely to spill over to the entire group of firms, severely damaging the entire organizational ecosystem. Therefore, over the long run, companies will consistently benefit only through a sincere commitment to sustainable practices.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Ways to Live Out Your Values at Work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/3-ways-to-live-out-your-values-at-work]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_-3751006_-5669629.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff/Pexels&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;The landscape of work is changing, yet people&amp;#8217;s aspiration to build careers with moral value &amp;#8212; that is, work that aligns with shared understandings of what&amp;#8217;s right and good &amp;#8212; remains constant. While doing so is difficult, it&amp;#8217;s also worthwhile: Our careers take up an enormous amount of our time and energy, and it&amp;#8217;s essential to feel that we&amp;#8217;re creating careers aligned with our moral values. The authors&amp;#8217; research suggests that people can hold onto their moral values while building careers by staying attuned to moments of moral reckoning, questioning common purity rules, and being willing to change to whom they turn for validation.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/3-ways-to-live-out-your-values-at-work?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/3-ways-to-live-out-your-values-at-work?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;What makes for a satisfying career? As professors, we&#39;ve taught many young adults preparing to embark on their careers, and we&#39;ve also studied professionals at all experience levels in a variety of fields, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.2021.1514&quot;>;journalists&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aom.org/doi/full/10.5465/amj.2017.0506&quot;>;educators&lt;/a>;, architects, &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/04/why-some-men-pretend-to-work-80-hour-weeks&quot;>;consultants&lt;/a>;, and health care workers. Time and again, in our interactions with students and interviews with professionals, we&#39;ve observed that people&#39;s desire to pursue careers aligned with their moral values is often central to their decisions about which jobs to pursue and which ones to forgo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having a “moral career” means doing work that allows one to enact their moral values — in other words, work that aligns with &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/M/bo16956514.html&quot;>;shared understandings of what&#39;s right and good&lt;/a>;. Actually charting a moral career, however, can be challenging. Internal organizational changes as well as uncontrollable socioeconomic shocks can interfere with people&#39;s abilities to build moral careers. For instance, in times of economic uncertainty, people must navigate immediate problems like increased cost of living and threats of layoffs, which may in turn require them to make painful trade-offs about the kind of work they do. This was the case for journalists we studied, for whom the precarity of the industry threatened their search for jobs that would allow them to live out their moral value to “tell the truth to society.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through our teaching and research, we&#39;ve gleaned some key lessons about how people can pursue careers that allow them to live out their moral values. These center on tuning into moral reckonings, questioning rules about what kind of work is morally “pure,” and seeking communities that share your moral values. Here&#39;s how to put those strategies to work if you&#39;re embarking on your own moral career journey.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1. Tune into revelations about the morality of your work.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Professionals often experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubsonline.informs.org/doi/full/10.1287/orsc.2021.1514&quot;>;moral reckonings&lt;/a>;: transformational moments that wake us up to misalignments between what we&#39;re doing and who we want to be. These reckonings can emerge in the wake of pivotal personal or &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/10/supporting-employees-after-violence-against-their-community&quot;>;social events&lt;/a>;. For example, one person recalled that living through Hurricane Katrina while studying to be an architect had been a “wake-up call” that shaped his career trajectory:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I was studying architecture, doing all this theoretical work in a beautiful Richardson Romanesque building that was 120 years old on a [university] campus uptown. At the same time, the city had no infrastructure, and there were piles of trash and bodies still surfacing in homes. I really started to feel a visceral disconnect between what we were studying as perfectly envisioned environments for people and then the realities of what had happened and what was happening with the city of New Orleans.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;People can also become attuned to moral contradictions as they perform their duties within their organizations. For instance, one nurse we spoke with pointed out that some of the hospital practices that keep the lights on, such as VIP treatment of hospital donors, also promote disparities in equitable health care treatment. Such realizations can accumulate and prompt people come to see the work they do as incompatible with their desire to build a moral career.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether triggered by an acute event or a slowly building realization, these moments of revelation can be ambiguous and therefore a source of &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/embrace-ambivalence-when-making-big-career-decisions&quot;>;discomfort&lt;/a>; and distraction. Our first instinct in the face of discomfort is often to look away, in part because addressing the reckoning might require challenging the status quo. Yet building a moral career requires that you notice, turn toward, and address the discomfort in order to figure out how to shift your career in a moral direction. And indeed, many of the professionals we studied were able to face this discomfort.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;2. Question “purity” rules.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Addressing the discomfort that arises from moral reckonings often requires identifying and questioning “purity rules”: shared views about what kind of work — and what kind of job — is morally right. Every professional community shares such a set of rules. Among journalists, for example, jobs in traditional news organizations are often regarded as “pure” because the organizations align themselves with the moral value of telling the unbiased truth about current events. Indeed, The Washington Post&#39;s slogan, “Democracy dies in darkness,” attaches clear moral meaning to the work its employees do.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The central assumption behind purity rules is that we should be willing to sacrifice aspects of our personal lives and deprioritize our needs in order to take morally “pure” jobs. For journalists, the personal sacrifice is often salary. One veteran reporter we interviewed explained the trade-off between a moral career and financial stability: “You&#39;re telling the truth. You&#39;re not spinning. You&#39;re trying to be fair in your work. You didn&#39;t choose your career to make money. That&#39;s why I took a pay cut to move to [a news organization].” But not all personal sacrifices are monetary. For instance, the charter school educators we studied forfeited personal time to dedicate themselves to their students&#39; success. And in one study, international aid workers &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/joms.12411&quot;>;reported sacrificing stable personal relationships&lt;/a>; in service of their work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over time, it&#39;s difficult to keep making these sacrifices. Our work suggests that, in the long term, many people question their fields&#39; generally accepted purity rules and moral status quo and find other creative ways to fulfill their moral values. For example, several journalists we studied decided they were exploited by traditional news media outlets and found nontraditional jobs where they felt they could do work that aligned with their moral values and required fewer personal costs. Some joined universities and research organizations, while others started their own news outlets. In departing from the moral status quo, however, people often find that they have to change the community they look to for moral guidance and validation.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3. Seek communities that share your moral values.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;As the examples above show, our moral values and their accompanying trade-offs can be out of alignment with our own career goals. But people are often slow to make a change because they fear that their colleagues and employers will disapprove of their desire to step away from the status quo career. Our research suggests that often, to truly build careers aligned with our moral values, we need to be willing to reconsider whom we seek guidance and validation from. In particular, we need to seek out people who support both our careers and our moral values.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We found that professionals who stay in their jobs but challenge the moral status quo are often in need of validation and assurance from outside of work. For example, a NICU nurse who did not change jobs following her moral reckoning mentioned that she often turns to her husband or best friend for reassurance and centering when she grapples with moral dilemmas around issues of patient care, rather than her colleagues at the hospital.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, professionals who depart from traditional career trajectories to pursue moral values often find themselves looking outside their workplaces for moral support. Journalists who struck out on their own as freelancers, for instance, described how building a career aligned with their moral values often required looking to the public and their readers for validation that their work was moral, not within their industry.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The landscape of work is changing, yet people&#39;s aspiration to build careers with moral value remains constant. While doing so is difficult, it&#39;s also worthwhile: Our careers take up an enormous amount of our time and energy, and it&#39;s essential to feel that we&#39;re creating careers aligned with our moral values. Our work suggests that people can hold onto their moral values while building careers by staying attuned to moments of moral reckoning, questioning common purity rules, and being willing to change to whom they turn for validation.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A New Approach to Production and Inventory Planning]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/a-new-approach-to-production-and-inventory-planning]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_27_2882314.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Martí Sans/Stocksy&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Disruptions have become a way of life for manufacturers. But the production and inventory planning process that many companies, especially SMEs, use are not capable of handling the uncertainty. A new inexpensive method that was developed in research involving two companies can. It doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be automated but can be.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/a-new-approach-to-production-and-inventory-planning?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/a-new-approach-to-production-and-inventory-planning?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Production and inventory-planning processes commonly used by companies, called sales &amp;amp; operations planning (S&amp;amp;OP), require predictable demand and supply to function properly. In the post-pandemic world, as uncertainty and disruptions have increased in frequency, this approach is no longer suited to the job.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies, including small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs), need a better system to make decisions when there is uncertainty. In research studies that my colleagues and I conducted with two companies, we devised new data analytics methods that are up to the challenge. They can be performed in Excel but also can be automated, using SQL and Python programming tools for data management, computations, and visualization. In this article, I describe how they work.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;The Current S&amp;amp;OP Process&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The predictability of demand and supply are necessary for traditional supply-chain-planning systems to work. In these systems, a manager or a cross-functional team begins by making forecasts of demand for the upcoming weeks. Near-term forecasts are frozen and converted into targets. Production and inventory flows are then planned to meet those targets at minimum cost. Performance is measured through metrics such as “days of cover,” the number of days of demand forecast covered by inventory. For instance, if I have 100 pallets of inventory on hand and the average forecast of daily demand is four pallets, then I have 25 days of cover. If I then want to increase the days of cover to 30, I will have to order 20 more pallets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This system works beautifully when there is limited uncertainty in demand and supply. If the forecast of demand is accurate and supply is reasonably certain, the days of cover can be controlled easily, and the company can focus on increasing cost efficiency, on-time fulfillment, and capacity utilization. Benefiting from this clockwork system, companies have been able to create efficient supply chains reliant on large-scale, global, single-source factories, ports, and shipping lines.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This system has the added advantage of simplicity. It does not require significant data-analytics capabilities because the weekly demand forecast is a single number and the inventory plan follows from the forecast. SMEs can run the entire process on Excel spreadsheets.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;But even ardent supporters of the conventional S&amp;amp;OP process acknowledge that plans don&#39;t always succeed. Their response to an unexpected event is to make a new plan. But this can be challenging. Consider the previous example: If average weekly demand were still four pallets but actual demand varied between one to 10 pallets, then days of cover could be 100 days or it could be 10 days, so it&#39;s difficult to set a target and determine how much to order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the post-pandemic world, when uncertainty arises almost daily from any number of sources — demand and price shocks, supply disruptions, shipping delays, and labor shortages — managers need a better system that doesn&#39;t just whipsaw in reaction to uncertainty but tells them proactively what to do and what to expect over the medium and long-term time horizons. Creating such systems requires new data analytics tools to measure uncertainty and explicitly incorporate those measures in future planning. Here is how two different companies built new models of demand uncertainty and price uncertainty to solve this problem.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;A Distributor of Packaged Foods&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The US distributor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://casecent.re/p/185436&quot;>;a multinational sweet baked goods company&lt;/a>; imports cakes and croissants from Europe for sales to retail chains in the United States. Before the pandemic, the company had a predictable lead time of about 50 days from placing an order to receiving goods in its New Jersey distribution center, including production (21 days) and ocean freight (28 days). After receiving a shipment, the company would distribute product to retail stores throughout the country. Timeliness was of the essence because shipments of perishable food products to retailers must meet a minimum shelf-life requirement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the pandemic, shipment lead times grew significantly longer, more uncertain, and costlier. Due to the resulting uncertainty in inflows and outflows, the days of cover in the New Jersey distribution center stopped being a reliable indicator at any point in time. Planning inventory became akin to guesswork. The result: increased stockouts, an inability to meet growth targets, higher cost of waste from perishable food products, and significant senior management time spent on managing inventory item by item.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To solve this problem, historical demand and shipment data, stored in Excel spreadsheets, was harvested and used to estimate the standard deviation of weekly demand forecast and supply lead times. This gave the company a measurement of the amount of uncertainty that it needed to incorporate in its plan. Then, days of cover was replaced by a new inventory planning metric: the target inventory position for each product — the sum of the forecast of demand over the lead time plus an inventory buffer for the standard deviations of demand and lead time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, suppose the weekly demand forecast has an average value of 25 pallets and standard deviation of three pallets, the order lead time has an average value of 10 weeks with standard deviation one week, and the company desires a 98% fill rate. Then the average forecast of demand over the lead time is 25 x 10 = 250 pallets and the desired buffer is 2 x square root of (3 x 3 x 10 + 25 x 25 x 1 x1) = 2 x 27 = 54 pallets, where the multiple 2 corresponds to the 98% fill rate and the other numbers come from the average and standard deviation of demand and lead time. The resulting target inventory position is 250 + 54 = 304 pallets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This approach was superior to days of cover because the target inventory position was computed from the lead time and uncertainties via an exact formula, whereas the target days of cover was an arbitrary number. The process was run weekly. First, data was updated, then the target inventory position was calculated in Excel, and finally order quantities were determined to make up the difference between the target and the actual inventory and checked by a manager.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This new method enabled the company to replace guesswork that required experience and judgment with a standardized, unambiguous formulaic approach that workers could execute with little training. Moreover, as new data came in weekly, the new method automatically adjusted to changes in the marketplace. If the degree of uncertainty increased, the inventory target would get revised upwards. Larger inventory buffers were built for products whose demand was more uncertain. As uncertainty increased further during the pandemic, the company found that the advance planning prepared it well for the challenge.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;A Manufacturer of Durable Seasonal Goods&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A medium-sized &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssrn.com/abstract=2677045&quot;>;manufacturer of recreational durable goods&lt;/a>;, such as barbeque grills, swimming-pool equipment, and camping equipment, faced a different kind of challenge as its supply chain shifted. Previously, it sold its products through a network of dealers spread throughout the United States. Since the products were seasonal, with most of the demand occurring in May and June, the company required distributors to place orders six months in advance for optimal scheduling of manufacturing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a few years ago, when the company&#39;s distributors started selling online, the consumer market for the products became more competitive and prices became volatile. The distributors responded by placing fewer advance orders and more just-in-time orders during the selling season. This upended the company&#39;s S&amp;amp;OP process: Inventory build-ups and ramp-downs could not be planned in advance, and past sales and cash flows stopped being a predictor of the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The novelty of this situation was that it arose from a new variable: downstream price uncertainty, which the company had previously not considered. We used daily prices from the online marketplace to measure price uncertainty and the company&#39;s historical orders data to measure the timing of orders for each product. The data told us that products with more price uncertainty received more just-in-time orders. This gave the company a method to predict when distributors would place orders as a function of price and demand uncertainty. Thus, the company was able to obtain more informed internal guidance as well as be more effective in its negotiations with distributors. In particular, it could give higher discounts for early orders for products with large price uncertainty to incentivize distributors to order early, which helped reduce inventory risk.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In both examples, the companies focused on measuring uncertainty and directly including it in supply-chain planning. This enabled them to easily solve problems that previously seemed unmanageable. And the beauty of the approach is that it was inexpensive and fast to create. It took only a few months and could be implemented in Excel, which made it easy to use.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the number of products and customers grows, a company should consider automating the analytics in a programming language, such as Python, to reduce the chances of human errors and improve productivity. A good supply-chain engineer with knowledge of programming can create these tools in a few months. Typically, this would require converting all the manual data management tasks from Excel sheets into database management rules in SQL, implementing the computation of target inventory position in Python, and building visualization dashboards in Python, Tableau, PowerBI, or an equivalent tool for performance monitoring and reporting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An SME organization should automate one step at a time, starting with building a database and visualization dashboards, then creating software for estimating demand, price, and lead time uncertainty, and finally computing the target inventory position. This approach offers SMEs a fairly inexpensive way to manage their inventory and production processes in uncertain times.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 21:25:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What Makes an Inclusive Leader?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/what-makes-an-inclusive-leader]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_27_ChenWu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;陈舞插画&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span >;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;领导者在促进组织内的包容性方面发挥着关键作用。它们在员工的满意度中所占的差异高达 70 个百分点。归属感和心理安全感以及包容性领导者的团队绩效提高了 17%，决策质量提高了 20%，团队协作提高了 29%。包容性领导者还降低了员工流失风险。如果包容性领导者如此有影响力，那么谦逊、好奇心和同理心等包容性特质就应该被视为关键的领导能力，而不仅仅是令人向往的。作者对来自不同工作职能、组织和行业的 40 名 DEI 获奖或同行提名的包容性模范领导者进行了结构化访谈。他们确定了帮助领导者使组织更具包容性的五种关键行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what -makes-an-inclusive-leader?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-makes-an-inclusive-leader?language=pt&quot;>;阅读em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;组织领导者越来越多地利用包容性来吸引人才、留住员工并激发高度创造力和卓越性。事实上，包容性组织获得创新收入的可能性&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcg.com/publications/2018/how-diverse-leadership-teams-boost-innovation&quot;>;73%&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecp.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cecp_di_whitepaper_FINAL.pdf&quot;>;占领新市场的可能性提高 70%&lt;/a>;，最高&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.cloverpop.com/hacking-diversity-with-inclusive-decision-making-white-paper&quot;>;做出更好决策的可能性提高 50%&lt;/a>;，最高&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.mckinsey.com/~/media/mckinsey/featured%20insights/diversity%20and%20inclusion/diversity%20wins%20how%20inclusion%20matters/diversity-wins-how-inclusion-matters-vf.pdf?shouldIndex=false&quot; >;36%&lt;/a>; 的盈利能力高于平均水平的可能性更高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导者发挥着特别关键的作用：他们造成了高达 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.deloitte 的差异.com/us/en/insights/deloitte-review/issue-22/diversity-and-inclusion-at-work-eight-powerful-truths.html&quot;>;员工的归属感和归属感体验提高了 70 个百分点&lt;/a>;心理安全和包容性领导者的团队绩效提高了 17%，决策质量提高了 20%，团队协作提高了 29%。包容性领导者还&lt;a href=&quot;https://web-assets.bcg.com/4c/ca/dfd11bc1457a8668048a10606859/bcg-inclusion-isnt-just-nice.-It&#39;s-Necessary_Feb-2023.pdf&quot;>;减少员工流失风险&lt;/a>;降低了76%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果包容性领导者如此有影响力，那么谦逊、好奇心和同理心等包容性特质就应该被视为关键的领导能力，而不仅仅是令人向往的。领导者采用哪些具体实践来持续培养组织中的归属感和真实性——尤其是在现有的截止日期和要求的情况下？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们对 40 位 DEI 获奖或同行提名的模范进行了长达一小时的结构化访谈来自各种工作职能、组织和行业的包容性领导者。我们确定了五种关键行为，可以帮助领导者使其组织更具包容性。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1.包容性领导者追求的是真实性，而不是领导力存在。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;领导者优先考虑真实性和&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/02/what-is-psychological-safety&quot;>;心理安全&lt;/a>;，两者是创造一个人们可以自由表达自己并发表不同意见而不必担心遭到报复的环境的重要组成部分。他们通过塑造好奇心、谦逊和脆弱性来做到这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，几位受访者批评了领导力存在的观念，这种观念传达了一个人必须表现出的无误且优越的形象，才能被视为是一个领导。相反，他们强调分享自己的弱点的重要性，并将其视为在团队成员之间建立信任和心理安全的关键因素。一位领导者谦虚地向员工透露了自己的弱点，而另一位领导者则在公共论坛上勇敢地分享了她职业生涯的坎坷历程。另一位领导者主动与团队成员分享她的失败，努力使错误正常化并培养学习和成长的文化。最后，设计团队的一位领导者经常在团队面前与老板意见不同，这样她的团队成员就知道质疑权威是可以的。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;2.包容性领导者重新定义规则，而不是毫无疑问地遵守规则。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;包容性领导者的典范并不害怕挑战那些已经过时的既定实践。他们积极寻找方法来发现排除某些人群的做法，并用新的做法取而代之，为代表性不足的群体提供更多机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，一个以安全为重点的组织的一位领导者扩大了该组织的着装政策，包括与头发（更加包容女性和非裔美国人）和纹身（更加包容年轻人）有关的内容，并指出以前的做法与安全关系不大，更多的是基于刻板印象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; 一家专业服务公司的另一位领导主张从合作伙伴晋升标准中删除候选人的全职或兼职身份，因为这与一个人对组织的价值无关，而且往往会惩罚职业母亲。一位人力资源领导者要求管理者阐明“文化契合度”在其组织中的含义，并将其明确的定义正式纳入组织的招聘指南中。几位领导者制定了新的团队规范，以确保每个人的意见都得到倾听，例如轮换团队成员在会议期间发言的顺序或轮换议程制定者的角色，以便随着时间的推移，不同领域的优先事项都能得到表达和解决。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;通过不断重新审视和修改根深蒂固的做法，包容性领导者能够招募和支持更加多元化的员工群体，为组织贡献新想法并增加互补价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3.包容性领导者拥护主动学习和持续执行。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;受访领导者强调，包容性的努力是主动学习的，而不是被动获得的。他们认为，我们的自然习惯或倾向通常含有偏见，需要以有计划和一致的方式不断地检查、挑战和改变，为包容性铺平道路。正如一家金融服务公司的领导者所说，我们不能仅仅&lt;em>;希望&lt;/em>;招聘更多女性和代表性不足的员工 - 我们需要部署有意识的、系统化的流程来招聘她们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些有意识的努力有多种形式；然而，特别有用的是将 DEI 实践嵌入到现有流程和系统中，以确保一致性和问责制。例如，在招聘中要求多元化的候选人库、将包容性工作纳入绩效指标、指导经理促进其直接下属提供反馈，以及让经理对其直接下属的职业发展负责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;确保问责制例如，一家制造公司的人力资源主管培训所有经理如何与团队成员进行倾听会议，然后让经理分享如何根据反馈修改其实践的想法。另一家公司使用跟踪系统来监控不同人口群体在招聘、自愿减员、晋升和内部流动方面的代表性，以及不同业务领域的员工满意度，并每季度与业务领导者就需要加强和改变的领域进行对话。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;除了正式实践之外，领导者还可以通过非正式方式持续培养包容性。例如，在一家保险公司，为了致力于了解不同人的经历，主要是白人的高级领导团队定期举行会议，讨论《白人脆弱性》等书籍以及有关美国黑人女性经历的书籍。其他领导者分享了他们将所有文化节日和庆祝活动纳入公司日历的做法，定期发送消息不仅庆祝每个节日，还提供一些与每个人相关的有意义的收获。通过这样做，他们确保包容性成为首要考虑因素，并激励个人积极促进包容性，无论其个人背景如何。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过不断追求新的学习并将其融入既定的惯例和政策中通过扩展他们的默认观点和习惯，领导者可以更好地理解和满足多元化员工的需求，从而创造更有活力的工作场所文化。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;4.包容性领导者确保平等机会和公平结果。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们采访的领导者高度致力于为员工提供平等的成功机会。为此，他们承认个人的特殊需求，尤其是背景代表性不足的团队成员的特殊需求。他们还敏锐地意识到这些团队成员所面临的无形障碍，并采取积极主动的措施来支持他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，一位律师事务所合伙人认识到第一代律师面临的更大挑战，而第一代律师往往来自与非第一代同龄人相比，代表性不足的背景。她确保为这些律师提供额外的支持，分享更多过去实践的例子，为他们分配更多时间研究案例，确保他们在客户会议上发言，并在绩效评估中包含更多细节。一家全球科技公司的 DEI 官员不仅为经理提供培训，让他们进行辅导对话以支持其团队成员，还为团队成员提供如何要求加薪、制定职业发展计划和获得购买力的培训。来自他们的经理，因为来自边缘群体的员工报告说这些特别具有挑战性。一家专业服务公司的一位高级经理将自己视为代表性不足的个人的放大器，并定期在高级领导面前表达自己的观点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过提供根据人们的背景考虑不同需求的支持，领导者提供了为所有团队成员提供更公平的竞争环境。当大多数成员认为某些做法不公平时，领导者会花时间帮助他们理解为什么需要差异化支持，讲述他们的个人经历，产生同理心，并解释这种支持可以为整体带来的好处团队和组织。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;5.他们认为包容性领导是每个人的责任，而不仅仅是人力资源部门的责任。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;受访者一致认为，组织不能指望通过配备一小部分领导干部来承担包容性工作，从而营造包容性环境。为了创造一个包容性的环境，每个人都需要对此进行投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多领导者遇到的一个共同挑战是期望 DEI 计划主要由人力资源部门负责和推动。事实上，最成功的 DEI 举措是那些融入组织核心价值观的举措，因为核心价值观有助于将人们团结起来，并成为抵制阻​​力和怀疑的强大力量。它们还允许组织中的包容性努力超越可能来来去去的个人领导者，通过将其固化到组织的 DNA 中来维持包容性承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些组织中，这种整体包容性方法体现在将 DEI 嵌入到员工生命周期的各个方面：招聘、选拔、发展和保留。在其他情况下，它被纳入人们履行日常工作职责的方式中，而不是具体的 DEI 计划中。各种实践支持这种整体组织方法，例如将包容性纳入组织战略；向员工传达包容性不是一种愿望，而是一种期望；将纳入标准纳入所有招聘、薪酬、培训、晋升和保留考虑因素中；定期传达包容信息；获得高层领导对包容性的明显和一致的支持；并培养代表所有领域的包容性大使。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;包容性领导力的力量&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;所有这些包容性实践都鼓励组织中的所有个人蓬勃发展。虽然包容性可能被误解为“对人宽容”或“只是对每个人都友善”，但接受采访的领导者强调了包容性可以为每个人带来切实的好处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，领导者发现多元化和包容性的工作场所对所有人来说都是更好的工作场所，因为它挑战人们想出与与自己不同的人合作的新方法；允许人们以创造性的方式协作，打造更好的产品和服务；产生不同的完成任务的方法；取得意想不到的突破；向人们灌输自豪感；并支持福祉。此外，这些积极的员工互动不仅有利于内部利益相关者，而且有助于吸引更广泛的客户并增强组织的声誉，所有这些都有助于吸引人才并增加利润。举例来说，一家工程公司的首席执行官讨论了他的公司在合同投标中与强大竞争对手正面竞争的一次经历。他的公司多年来培育多元化和包容性，最终为他赢得了大合同。他评论说，包容性正在“把蛋糕做大”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，包容性的模范领导者会认真地利用信息、思维方式、日常实践和组织系统来促进包容性。包容性领导需要行动、勇气和创造力。在我们日益混合的工作场所中，具体做法可能会根据具体情况而变化，但我们上面确定的原则仍然存在。当有意识地、适应性地实践时，这些努力可以提高员工的福祉和可衡量的业务成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Keeping Procurement and Supply Chain Strategy Rooted in Real Time and in the Real World - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/keeping-procurement-and-supply-chain-strategy-rooted-in-real-time-and-in-the-real-world]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img 咏叹调-scribedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364594&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/07/shutterstock_1779391529.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;作者：Etosha Thurman&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通货膨胀、经济不稳定、材料和劳动力短缺、气候变化——几乎任何你能想象到的干扰都是一个压力点，使采购和供应链管理变得更加复杂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当他们努力应对持续的干扰时，采购领导者还必须管理不断变化的战略，以控制支出、满足利益相关者的需求并降低风险暴露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据过去几年我们在全球经济中的经历，预测风险从未如此难以预测。气候变化和网络攻击增加了停电风险。无法衡量和跟踪您的供应链或在价值观和流程上与供应商保持一致会带来声誉风险。如果没有对市场进行自动实时监控，您的成本风险就会很高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采购范围已经远远超出了通过具有成本效益的解决方案满足组织需求的范围。并非所有供应商都是平等的，价格不应成为采购决策中的唯一标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了满足您的采购优先级，采购领导者必须建立广泛的供应链关系并做出包含以下因素的采购决策：材料和劳动力、供应商多样性和可持续性等因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;不断变化的采购格局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt; script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;p>;如果您的组织正在尝试使用传统的供应链管理基础设施来管理寻源和采购，而这些基础设施将您的数据锁定在孤岛和手动更新的电子表格中，那么您就无法跟上不断变化的实时变化出现在现实世界中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在比以往任何时候都更需要您对公司所有团队的采购和支出数据有一个统一、透明的实时视图，以跟上变化的步伐。掌控供应链生态系统中的许多移动部件需要强大的基于云的采购技术，该技术可以帮助您的组织提高数据透明度、减少支出、最大限度地降低风险并改善供应商协作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;人工智能 (AI) 和自动化对于从供应链数据中收集实时见解至关重要，可以帮助您提高效率。将人工智能和自动化应用于流程和工作流程管理的成长型组织发现，他们可以加快采购周期、提高生产力、更好地量化支出和节省、明确定义和观察供应商参数以及处理发票，所用时间仅为过去的一小部分。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;​改进采购流程可以为您的组织和供应商提供请购、审批工作流程以及发票和付款处理的无缝体验。采用人工智能和自动化技术的流程和工作流程管理还可以帮助您加快采购周期、提高生产力，并捕获和报告节省的成本。​更重要的是，它可以使采购和采购团队能够做出最佳的支出决策。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2020/12/daf1af4d-c27d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html&quot;>;波士顿大学&lt;/a>;正在使用与老化、低效的采购到付款平台以及基于电子邮件、传真和纸质的流程相比，数字化采购有助于做出更明智的支出决策。 BU 升级为&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/products/spend-management/procure-to-pay.html?campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517074&amp;amp;source=ppc-1na-google_ads -search-71700000111875678-58700008460611821-ism_ism-xxx&amp;amp;dfa=1&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw0IGnBhDUARISAMwFDLnwiBK6p1EXScf2cLhUS-​​cB22YFVNiezalphsnbiH3CNwduKeORQtAaAvwr EALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&quot;>;云解决方案&lt;/a>;，用于与其企业资源集成的采购、合同管理、发票和采购规划 (ERP) 软件，自动化其手动流程，并支持与供应商就数千个采购订单和发票进行更密切的协作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;管理业务流程生命周期&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;日益复杂的全球供应链生态系统要求组织管理整个业务流程生命周期的支出，从供应商寻源和管理到采购和付款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您的组织依赖于时间敏感的交易，那么实时供应商管理数据可以为您提供基于透明度、可见性和弹性的见解。人工智能的力量可以帮助您增强数据驱动的采购决策以及安全性和风险缓解。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>; if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;您可以&#39;不要改进你无法衡量的东西。如果您看不到合同或绩效指标，如何才能变得更好？使用一个由人工智能驱动、易于部署的集成采购平台，清晰透明地呈现所有团队的指标，可以为您的组织提供更加简化的用户体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总部位于蒙特利尔的 &lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.sap.com/uk/about/customer-stories/cirque-du-soleil.html&quot;>;太阳马戏团&lt;/a>;依靠全球 1,900 家供应商通过定制设备和数千种服装提供复杂的表演。 Cirque 在敏捷的云平台上标准化其核心业务功能后，极大地改善了其供应链管理，使采购变得透明和无缝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“最终用户选择首选供应商，订购他们需要的产品，然后太阳剧团娱乐集团采购高级总监 Stéphanie LeRoy 表示：“我们很高兴能按时收到。” “它比我们以前的系统快五倍，并且具有积极的财务影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采购的成功取决于能够分析实时数据、快速响应不断变化的市场状况并降低风险。 An AI- and automation-powered cloud-based procurement infrastructure has become essential to reducing risk and cost, boosting efficiency, and strengthening agility across your supply chain.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.363364705;dc_trk_aid=554534923;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Learn More.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Etosha Thurman is chief marketing and solutions officer for SAP&#39;s Intelligent Spend and Business Network.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Video Quick Take: SAP&rsquo;s Etosha Thurman on Mitigating Risk and Building Resilience in Supply Chain and Procurement - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/video-quick-take-saps-etosha-thurman-on-mitigating-risk-and-building-resilience-in-supply-chain-and-procurement]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div data-props=&quot;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;6337165321112&quot;}&quot; js- target=&quot;video-player-page&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;加载中.. . &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，HBR&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢迎观看 HBR 视频快速观看。我是托德·普鲁赞 (Todd Pruzan)，《哈佛商业评论》研究和特别项目的高级编辑。今天我们采访了 Etosha Thurman，他是 SAP Intelligence Spend and Business Network 的首席营销和解决方案官。她和我们一起讨论供应链和采购的风险管理和弹性。 Etosha，非常感谢您今天与我们在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢谢您邀请我，Todd。我很高兴来到这里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text /javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p >;Etosha，企业如何更好地预测风险？他们如何衡量弹性？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过过去三年全球经济的经历，风险，而不仅仅是风险采购是许多高级管理人员（包括首席财务官和首席运营官）最关心的问题。我们都在努力找出如何降低风险的方法。我们如何预测可能的风险并尽力减轻风险？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在采购领域，当我们考虑风险时，我们会考虑几个组成部分。首先是我们如何理解供应链中的风险？我是否面临供应中断的风险，我们许多人在过去几年都经历过这种情况？然后是供应商风险，无论是供应商的质量还是使用供应商的潜在声誉风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，还有成本风险。因此，当你问企业如何更好地预测风险时，我的第一个答案是监控风险。考虑供应链风险，特别是供应风险，它能够具有可见性和透明度，能够根据您的需求、他们的能力以及您在该能力中的位置与供应商进行协作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并且有解决方案可以帮助促进这种类型的透明度和协作，包括我们在 SAP 的那些。然后，当你想到供应商、供应商风险时，我的意思是，这可能是企业在供应链方面管理风险的首要方法之一，通过测量、跟踪和与供应商合作来了解他们的风险。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;那么，无论是跟踪供应商绩效并制定工作基准，该供应商是否向我们提供优质产品或提供优质服务？它符合我们预期的时间准则吗？因此拥有供应商绩效管理流程和解决方案非常重要。当然，还有风险监控，您可以在其中提出问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对供应商进行风险评估。最重要的是，拥有可以监控供应商提供的数据之外的数据的技术，以便您深入了解整体风险。例如，SAP Ariba 风险管理解决方案具有监控功能，可以监听媒体、监听外部数据源，并通知您供应商的风险是否有可能增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt; div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;假设供应商正处于即将到来的海啸路径上。该解决方案会提醒您该供应商发生的风险因素。因此，公司可以采取很多措施来主动发现或监控风险。当然，一旦您意识到，您就可以采取主动措施来解决已识别的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是各种规模的公司都面临的问题。但我很高兴地说，有一些解决方案可以提供帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很高兴知道这一点。是的，听起来有很多不同的因素。 Etosha，采购和供应链领导者如何指导更广泛的企业降低风险？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先要做的事情之一思想就是将风险意识融入到采购过程中。举个例子，假设您有一位最终用户想要一项新服务。我需要一家新公司来提供任何服务，以便我能够满足最终客户的需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从采购角度解决风险的首要方法之一是在采购过程中进行采购并具有信息风险意识。采购流程。因此，当您组织采购活动寻找能够提供所需服务的公司时，您可以在采购活动中进行风险评估，以了解哪些选择中风险最小，并做出决定然后，一旦您选择了供应商并将其纳入您的供应商社区，并且您企业中的实际最终用户希望与这些供应商开展业务，就会向他们提供相同的风险信息。并非所有供应商都是生来平等的。价格并不总是唯一的关键决策标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，在最终用户想要购买笔记本电脑的地方利用技术。您有三个首选供应商与之签约。在做出购买决策时，您可以与他们分享风险评估——每个供应商的风险分析或评分，以帮助降低风险。如果我在一周内需要这台笔记本电脑，并且我可以从风险评分中看到，由于交货或质量问题，该供应商可能对我们来说是黄色的，也许我不会选择该供应商。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后，当然，另一种方法是确保公司的价值观和风险政策作为公司内部供应商管理方法的一部分进行沟通和共享。因此，当我们邀请供应商时，我们会与他们一起进行风险评估，询问他们与我们的价值观和政策相关的问题，并让他们回答这些问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这会围绕我们如何进行对话。想要表现良好并设定期望，这也可以减轻公司内部的风险。所以这些只是一些方法。当然，我不是在这里谈论企业范围的风险。但公司在法律和财务方面也做出了这些努力，特别是在采购方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;供应商管理、供应商绩效跟踪以及将风险意识引入采购和购买流程都是采购可以帮助减少或减少风险的方法。减轻公司内部的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan，《哈佛商业评论》&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好的。那么，Etosha，考虑到采购中的所有这些考虑因素，采购团队目前关注的最高组织风险优先事项是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman，SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;这是一个很好的问题，托德。如果我考虑一些最重要的风险优先事项，我首先想到的是确保我清楚自己的支出情况。首先，我们的钱去哪儿了？我们与哪些公司合作？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个是评估和了解这些供应商的风险评分。根据我的价值观、我公司的政策，与该供应商开展业务的风险有多大？因此，如果我考虑最重要的风险优先事项，那就是可见性。一旦我知道我与哪些公司合作，我就能了解供应商的风险状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企业（尤其是采购部门）最感兴趣且持续增长的一个问题是网络安全。我们的供应链是否存在网络攻击的风险？在过去几年中，我们听说过一些备受瞩目的案例，其中存在影响供应链的网络攻击。所以这是一个正在增长的领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后我认为我之前谈到的一直存在的一个实际上围绕风险评估的实际上是供应商管理。它是了解供应商、分享期望以及拥有允许供应商管理透明和协作的流程和技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以这些是一些风险领域。我想我还要补充一点。这就是对未知事物的预测风险分析，这确实很难。 And it&#39;s driving back the process of leveraging things like category management to be able to set a baseline for the industry for key categories and key materials, and then being able to analyze risk across many factors, whether that&#39;s financial risk, capacity risk, supplier concentration risk, geopolitical risk—they all come into play and are on the minds of our customers and the market at large today.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Todd Pruzan, HBR&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s an amazing range of things everybody has to think about. Etosha, thank you so much for a great conversation today and for all your insights.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;Etosha Thurman, SAP&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thank you for having me, Todd. I&#39;ve enjoyed having this moment with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.375512081;dc_trk_aid=566751456;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Learn more.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Etosha Thurman is chief marketing and solutions officer &lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;for SAP&#39;s Intelligent Spend and Business Network.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 04:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Steps that Move Corporate Purpose From Words to Action - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM BRANDPIE]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/5-steps-that-move-corporate-purpose-from-words-to-action]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img 咏叹调-scribedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364693&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/BP_HBR_Hero_1200x675.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;作者：MaryLee Sachs&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实现商业目的的好处是毋庸置疑的——那些成功实现商业目的的人比那些没有目的的竞争对手享受到更多好处。近十分之九的首席执行官表示他们的企业有一个目标。但是有多少企业利用目标来做出有意义的改变并推动可持续增长？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你的企业是这样吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;将目标付诸实践&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，所有组织都在全球地缘政治变化的背景下开展工作，其中包括气候危机、猖獗的通货膨胀和生成人工智能的稳步发展。如果您的公司现在没有定义自己的立场和未来的方向，那么以后这样做就会困难得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brandpie 的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brandpie.com/ thinking/ceo- Purpose-report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;第五届年度全球首席执行官目标报告&lt;/a>;带来了好消息。我们看到越来越多的组织将宗旨作为战略业务工具——我们调查的 1,000 名各行业首席执行官中，有 63% 表示他们将宗旨纳入高层决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，要实现宗旨，还有很多工作要做发挥其潜力。目前还没有领导者使用目的来指导他们的所有决策。 Why not?超过一半的首席执行官提出的响亮答案和持久挑战是如何将目标付诸工作的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type= &quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;如果您的组织难以将目标置于其业务战略的中心，这五个步骤可以帮助您从声明转向行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.确保你的目标是可行的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我们回顾一下。对于调查中近一半的领导者来说，定义目标陈述是一个挑战。您的目标以有意义的方式将您的业务与世界的需求联系起来。它应该激励、挑战并帮助您建立长期价值。您的目标还应该对所有内部和外部利益相关者相关且有意义。他们需要与之联系。对于以书面意向声明开始生命的事物来说，有很多要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这是在定义目的时要考虑的第一个问题：它是否可行？矛盾的是，目的陈述不应该是可以实现的。 （把它留给你的组织野心。）设定一个常青的目标，你总是努力改进的目标。最简单的目的陈述往往是最有力和持久的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.让领导力与您的目标保持一致&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要拥有与整个员工产生共鸣的强大目标，您必须自上而下地工作。如果要有效地嵌入目标，为组织注入活力，并成为每个决策的指南针，执行领导团队就需要接受目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着员工越来越多地在孤岛中远程和虚拟地工作，它变得越来越重要。让组织中的每个人都了解您的目标更加困难，更不用说将其用作行动的起点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有 26% 的调查受访者表示，目标有助于他们与高层领导保持一致。这标志着错失了一个机会；我们亲眼目睹了目标在行政领导层所具有的强大激励作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync() ) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.在内部实现目标驱动。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然薪资和福利对员工来说始终很重要，但&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey. com/capability/people-and-organizational-performance/our-insights/help-your-employees-find- Purpose-or-watch-them-leave&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;人们现在也希望为有明确目标的组织工作&lt;/a>;，他们可以做出有意义的贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有目标源于形成一个单一的想法，将你所做的事情牢牢地置于业务的核心。但这个想法必须既具有启发性，又具有可操作性，并且植根于企业业务和运营方式的日常现实。传达的信息是，整个企业的每个人都可以共同努力实现其目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，将目标和文化融入员工体验中。从中汲取经验来创建您的员工价值主张。将其应用到员工的日常工作流程中。将其嵌入到您的文化计划中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4.向外部利益相关者传达您的目标&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;组织的目标越明确，就越容易与关键的外部影响者（而不仅仅是其客户和客户）进行有意义的对话。除了激励员工之外，目标还必须成为做出更大战略决策的透镜。目标远非一次性项目，而是一个长期、持续的过程，它存在于组织的文化、品牌、活动、计划和抱负中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.倡导变革&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到目前为止，企业在帮助世界实现有意义的变革方面的作用不仅被接受，而且被期待。商业是创新的强大引擎，并且具有独特的优势来实现大规模变革。然而，调查中只有 28% 的首席执行官表示，他们利用目标来“倡导重要话题的积极变革”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种情况需要改变。负责任的领导者利用目标来赋予团队权力并创造可以发生变革的文化。他们带领合作伙伴、供应商和股东踏上构建共享价值的旅程，并在此过程中成为未来的市场领导者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是时候将目标从言语付诸行动了。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;需要帮助将您的目标从言语转化为行动吗？ Brandpie&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;哈哈&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;s&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;帮助企业通过以下方式推动进步超过15年的目标。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hello@brandpie.com?subject=HBR%20article:%20I&#39;d%20like%20to%20learn%20more%20about%20purpose-driven%20business&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Get in touch to learn more&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryleesachs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;MaryLee Sachs&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>; is CEO U&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;S&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>; at the purpose-driven transformation consultancy&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Brandpie&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>