<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[A More Impactful Strategy for Sustainable Investing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/a-more-impactful-strategy-for-sustainable-investing]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sept23_15_1589828250.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;渡边宏/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt; span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;可持续投资的有效性受到了挑战，Tariq Fancy 等评论家将其描述为仅仅是安慰剂。在质疑声不断上升和披露要求越来越严格的情况下，更深入的研究表明，影响公司的传统方法，即“声音”，已经不再适用。 （股东参与）和“退出”； （投资组合筛选）并不详尽。通过对 3,500 多篇研究论文的全面审查，一种新方法“ “场地建设” &amp;#8212;出现。这种策略承认公司周围的利益相关者相互关联的网络，称为“领域”，深刻影响公司行为。通过重塑这些领域，投资者可以间接推动公司的可持续变革。重点强调了五种策略：（1）转移其他投资者——评估问题，(2) 分享专业知识，(3) 取消某些商业活动的合法性，(4) 建立自愿标准，以及 (5) 支持监管变革。尽管前景光明，但领域建设也带来了盈利能力和政治风险等挑战。然而，通过采用这个扩展的工具包，投资者可以放大其积极影响并吸引越来越有意识的投资客户。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/a-more-impactful-strategy-for-sustainable-investing?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/a-more -impactful-strategy-for-sustainable-investing?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;可持续投资者能否对商业和社会产生积极影响一直是近年来争论的中心年。阻碍可持续投资发挥最大影响力的一个主要障碍是，大多数投资者对如何产生影响的理解过于狭隘。大多数投资者认为他们有两种主要方式来影响公司。首先是投资组合筛选，通常称为“退出”。通过这种方法，投资者将资本从不可持续的公司转移到可持续的公司。第二个策略是股东参与，通常称为“声音”。在这里，投资者通过会议、股东提案或投票等方式直接敦促公司采取更可持续的做法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在我们的研究中，我们发现一些非常规投资者超越了“退出”而不是“声音” ” 二分法。我们通过 &lt;a href=&quot;https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fonlinelibrary.wiley.com%2Fdoi%2Fepdf%2F10.1111%2Fjoms 映射了他们的活动.12957&amp;数据=05%7C01%7Cmarti%40rsm.nl%7C5617faa4f4e6474822f608dbae59fdb1%7C715902d6f63e4b8d929b4bb170bad492%7C0%7C0%7C6382954742070719 01%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=qcr%2FaLPS2qF%2FkUPnG%2FDtSQEMQjLx0nl %2BrNN2UuL8oD8 %3D&amp;reserved=0&quot;>;对研究进行系统回顾&lt;/a>;，我们筛选了 3,500 多篇有关可持续投资的研究论文。根据本次审查以及我们与从业者的对话，我们提出了第三种可能更具影响力的可持续投资策略：&lt;em>;现场建设。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现场建设之所以有效，是因为公司总是扎根于领域。 “领域”一词与行业密切相关，但范围更广。这些领域既包括公司（例如石油和天然气公司），也包括与公司互动最频繁的利益相关者（例如投资者、监管机构或媒体）。通过这些互动，领域内的参与者制定了塑造该领域内公司行为的假设、规范和规则。简而言之，领域捕获了公司外部环境中对公司影响最直接的部分。场域建设是指投资者通过改变（1）利益相关者和（2）围绕公司的假设、规范和规则来影响公司，从而间接对公司施加影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们发现了五种场域策略建立可持续投资者可以用来增加其影响力的平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;改变其他投资者对问题的评估&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;作为领域建设的第一个策略，投资者可以改变其他投资者对环境和社会问题的评价。通过公开、持续地强调这些环境和社会问题，投资者可以引起其他投资者对环境和社会问题的关注，从而激励其他投资者影响公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种策略对于那些关注环境和社会问题的投资者尤其重要。没有足够的管理资产或地位来直接影响公司。通过对公司产生更直接的影响力来影响更大的投资者，投资者可以改变公司经营的领域，从而使公司在企业可持续发展方面面临更大的压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;荷兰股东“FollowThis”使用了第一种策略自 2014 年以来非常成功地影响石油和天然气公司。 FollowThis 代表超过 10,000 名购买了石油和天然气公司股票的个人提交股东提案。尽管FollowThis既没有管理的资产，也没有石油和天然气公司本身非常重视的精英地位，但他们的方法在影响荷兰大型养老基金方面非常成功。一些养老基金最初拒绝支持 FollowThis，导致受益人抗议和媒体负面关注，随后也纷纷效仿，其中包括荷兰最大的养老基金 ABP，管理着超过 5000 亿欧元的资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;分享与其他投资者分享专业知识&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;领域建设的第二种策略是与其他投资者分享专业知识。刚刚接触可持续投资的投资者往往会因环境和社会问题固有的复杂性而苦苦挣扎，他们既不知道哪些需求是现实的，也不知道如何以对公司具有商业意义的方式提出需求。通过公开私人信息，投资者可以授权其他投资者影响公司。当其他投资者对可持续发展了解更多时，就会给公司所在领域内的企业可持续发展带来额外压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际资产管理公司荷宝 (Robeco) 自 2022 年 8 月公开制定可持续发展目标框架以来就一直在使用这一策略。无障碍。该框架评估了 2,900 多家公司推进或破坏 17 项可持续发展目标 (SDG) 的程度。自 2018 年以来，荷宝在内部使用该框架，决定将其可持续发展目标框架开放获取，这不仅使荷宝成为该领域的领导者。访问此框架可以帮助经验不足的投资者将可持续性纳入其投资决策中。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;使某些商业活动合法化&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;领域建设的第三种策略是使某些商业活动合法化对环境和社会特别有害的商业活动。公司只能在政策制定者、消费者、供应商或媒体等关键利益相关者认为其活动合法的领域开展业务。如果这些利益相关者开始将某些商业活动视为非法，则可能会给公司带来生存问题。鉴于这些动态，公开质疑某些商业活动的投资者可以在改变关于这些商业活动是否合法的广泛共识的假设方面发挥关键作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;化石燃料撤资运动中的投资者非常利用这种策略。成功地。自 2012 年以来，已有超过 1,500 名投资者公开宣布将从化石燃料公司撤资，其中包括 2022 年芝加哥市和 2023 年英国教会。撤资运动的支持者明确表示，“&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fgofossilfree.org%2Fusa%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2Fsites%2F6%2F2015%2F03%2FFossilFreeFrequentlyAskedQuestions.pdf&amp;amp;data=05%7C01% 7Cmarti%40rsm.nl%7C5617faa4f4e6474822f608dbae59fdb1%7C715902d6f63e4b8d929b4bb170bad492%7C0%7C0%7C638295474207071901%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d 8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=AQBOvhTOgqMHpVyU1VprefUIR%2Foa%2BwCWQxS8Ns1s31g%3D&amp;保留=0 ”撤资并不是主要的这是一种经济战略，更是一种道德和政治战略。”他们意识到，他们的主要影响力并非来自短期内增加化石燃料公司的资本成本，而是逐渐改变公众对化石燃料公司的看法。研究表明，撤资运动影响了重要利益相关者的观点和行动，包括拒绝向化石燃料公司提供信贷的银行以及承诺不为化石燃料公司工作的学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;建立自愿标准&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;现场建设的第四个策略是建立自愿的可持续性标准。自愿标准已成为促进企业可持续发展的核心工具。它们包括行为准则、认证标准和报告标准，并且可能侧重于单个领域（例如，项目融资的赤道原则）或多个领域（例如，GRI 报告标准）。投资者在建立自愿标准方面发挥了重要作用，从而重塑了公司运营领域的规则。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;积极参与“自然相关财务披露工作组”的投资者已经采用了这一方法战术。生物多样性丧失和其他与自然相关的风险是复杂的挑战，许多公司在如何应对这些问题方面缺乏专业知识。自 2020 年以来，投资者利用该工作组制定了企业报告的自愿标准，内容涉及企业如何损害自然以及自然如何给企业带来风险。经过广泛的利益相关者对话、试点测试和行业反馈后，工作组将于 2023 年 9 月发布最终版本，我们预计这将改变可持续发展报告中与自然相关的部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;支持监管变革&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;现场建设的第五个也是最后一个策略是支持为企业可持续发展制定强制性标准的监管变革。一旦某个领域内的多家公司自愿参与与可持续发展相关的活动，从而证明此类活动在技术和财务上是可行的，则可能需要进行监管干预，以迫使落后的公司效仿。按照这个逻辑，与企业可持续发展相关的法律数量有 &lt;a href=&quot;https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.unpri.org%2Fpolicy%2Fregulation -数据库&amp;数据=05%7C01%7Cmarti%40rsm.nl%7C5617faa4f4e6474822f608dbae59fdb1%7C715902d6f63e4b8d929b4bb170bad492%7C0%7C0%7C638295474207071901%7 CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=ZU3kycbEnn1GGmNwOIEHqUZNY11kMLAbEez1q7Cfgc M%3D&amp;保留=0&quot;>; 2013 年至 2023 年间几乎增加了两倍&lt;/a>;，从约 300 家增加到近 900 家。鉴于投资者对不同类型公司的投资，投资者可以为政策制定者和监管机构提供有关旨在促进企业可持续发展的监管变化的宝贵见解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些投资者已利用这一策略制定即将出台的欧洲可持续发展报告标准，该标准将从 2028 年起对所有在欧盟运营的公司强制执行。虽然该法 2022 年 4 月的草案包含严格的披露要求，但由于企业的反对，披露要求在随后的草案中被削弱。 2023 年 2 月，十一位投资者和几个可持续投资行业协会撰写了一份 &lt;a href=&quot;https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cdp.net%2Fen% 2Farticles%2Fcompanies%2F60公司和投资者价值6510亿告诉欧盟同意雄心勃勃的可持续发展报告标准和数据=05%7C01%7Cmarti%40rsm.nl%7C5617faa4f4e6474822f608dbae59fdb1%7C715902 d6f63e4b8d929b4bb170bad492%7C0% 7C0%7C638295474207071901%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=dR4a7ipq lhcBhrCvxZCvnS4Td9USAyRarHM%2FEP%2FZJq8%3D&amp;reserved=0&quot;>;致欧盟政策制定者的公开信&lt;/a>;，其中敦促政策制定者回到严格的披露要求，“确保为那些已经为自然积极型经济做出贡献的公司提供公平的竞争环境。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;。 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;这五种策略中的每一种都可以改变公司运营的领域，从而为公司变得更加可持续带来额外的压力。尽管有这些增加影响力的机会，但有两个原因可能会阻止投资者冒险进入油田建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中一个原因是盈利能力。短期内很难为现场建设制定商业案例。油田建设主要为投资者带来成本，而收益将由其他投资者（包括未来的投资者）获得。然而，鉴于许多人愿意接受较低的回报，如果他们的投资产生更大的影响，他们可能会寻找从事领域建设的资产管理公司，即使较高的管理费会稍微降低他们的回报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个原因是政治曝光。现场建设要求资产管理公司在可持续发展问题上公开表明立场，这可能会导致持不同观点的人的强烈反对——对于迎合广泛客户的资产管理公司来说，这种风险更高。这些资产管理公司可以通过对可持续发展问题进行现场建设来限制这种风险，这些问题在客户中存在广泛的共识，并有强大的业务案例支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过扩大他们的策略工具箱，并掌握领域通过建设，投资者可以更好地定位自己，对环境和社会产生更积极的影响，并以此吸引更多关心影响的个人投资者。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Get Honest and Substantive Feedback from Your Customers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-to-get-honest-and-substantive-feedback-from-your-customers]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sept23_15_1433543803-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria- label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;SvetaZi/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;如果没有诚实和实质性的反馈，企业就无法改善运营。由于多种原因，客户可能不愿意提供它。公司可以尝试克服这一问题，方法是将反馈请求集中在改进（而不是员工评估）上，关注客户的行为而不是言语，并将收集反馈作为一种习惯而不是偶尔的努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-to-get-honest-and-substantive-feedback-from-your-customers?language=es&quot; >;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-to-get-honest-and-substantive-feedback-from-your-customers?language=pt&quot;>;葡萄牙语&lt; /a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;“到目前为止一切还好吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很好，谢谢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在世界各地的餐厅里，“登记舞”服务器和客户之间的“”是普遍存在的。服务员在顾客收到餐食后询问情况如何，几乎所有顾客都会条件反射地回应“好的，谢谢”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从表面上看，这似乎是一个反馈循环的开始，但真正的反馈很少实现。服务员很可能并没有寻求详细的评论，比如鱼皮是否足够脆或蔬菜是否调味过头。他们确保膳食是可以接受的，以便用餐过程得以顺利进行。同样，用餐者经常回避真诚的、建设性的反馈，选择维持社交礼仪并避免长时间的互动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方都在这场友好的舞蹈中失败了。该餐厅失去了识别运营缺陷、改进产品以及扩大声誉和客户群的机会。用餐者失去了对他们所获得的体验感到兴奋的机会，甚至失去了对业务进行情感投资的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近，我们中的一位（史蒂夫）和他的妻子米歇尔会见了布鲁克林一家高档快闪店的舞蹈的不同版本。主厨亲自推出一道菜肴，意图将多种“奢华”食材结合在一起。这道菜根本不起作用。米歇尔和史蒂夫礼貌地指出了这一点。但舞蹈与典型的舞蹈设计不同，厨师出来问了一个更尖锐的问题，而不是服务员过来，明确表示他并不是在寻求礼貌。 “我已经研究这道菜有一段时间了，知道它有很多元素，但它&lt;em>;适合你&lt;/em>;吗？如果我听不到诚实的反馈，我就无法变得更好。”厨师在谈话中表现出的诚意和安全感让食客们都知道这道菜不适合他们。这也让史蒂夫和米歇尔对餐厅的成功更加投入和感兴趣，几周后他们回来看到菜肴已经过调整和改进。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;运营新时代&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率并增强弹性。&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;许多企业已经忽视了这一基本运营原则，并将客户反馈机视为必要的以尽可能成本最低、最不尴尬的方式来实现邪恶。规模较小的公司往往资源紧张，可能不会花太多精力来获取客户反馈。中小型公司的经理可能会觉得强大的客户反馈机制是一种奢侈品，必须等到公司规模更大时才必须这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是短视的，因为真正的运营效率来自于调整需要的东西&lt;em>;从客户的角度进行更改&lt;/em>;。虽然获得反馈至关重要，但只有真实的反馈才有价值。挑战在于，客户常常回避此类对话，而不幸的是，企业在寻求反馈的过程中往往会强化这种不情愿。整个系统已经变得如此阻碍和混乱，偏离了最初的目的，以至于在大多数情况下它已经成为一种无用的仪式——甚至可能会破坏价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;解决问题&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;错误这种功能失调的反馈循环由公司和客户共同承担。公司设计的反馈系统主要是为了方便客户输入和量化，导致我们收到无数的请求“请在通话后保持在线状态，进行简短的调查”。大多数客户在致电客户服务后最不想做的事情就是在电话上花费&lt;em>;更多&lt;/em>;时间。在极少数情况下，当客户试图亲自提供诚实的反馈时，他们经常会遇到工作人员的防御姿态，这些工作人员接受过“化解”情况的培训，而不是更深入地挖掘可行的反馈。事实上，化解这种情况的最佳方法通常是表现出听取反馈的合法兴趣！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客户也是这个问题的罪魁祸首。人类厌恶风险和冲突，因此我们通常会尽量避免“高风险”的互动。修复反馈系统的第一步是了解为什么客户会这样看待它们：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;诚实的反馈感觉像是一种认知负担&lt;em>;。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;大多数我们中的一些人会避免困难和情绪化的对话，因为它们确实很困难。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gse.harvard.edu/ideas/news/13/11/remembering-professor-chris-argyris&quot;>;Chris Argyris&lt;/a>;，该著作的已故创始人&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesystemsthinker.com/overcoming-defective-routines-in-the-workplace/&quot;>;&lt;em>;富有成效的互动&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;em>;，&lt;/em>;指出在发生冲突的情况下，人们可以使用三种策略： (1) &lt;em>;绕过&lt;/em>; &lt;em>;——&lt;/em>;避免讨论问题并继续前进； (2) &lt;em>;Name&lt;/em>;——记下问题，但不要讨论它； (3)&lt;em>;参与&lt;/em>;——实际讨论问题。随着级别的提升，关系面临的风险也会更高，因此在大多数情况下人们倾向于采用旁路方式。就客户反馈而言，绕过就是说一切都很好，即使事实并非如此。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;反馈的后果让人感觉不必要的高。当论坛是众多在线公共评论网站之一时尤其如此。我们中的一个人（伊丽莎白）最近发现自己在争论是否要对一家小企业写一篇诚实的评论——她一直支持这家小企业取得成功。它有很棒的产品，但服务低于标准。但诚实的审查可能会产生意想不到的效果，即公开服务问题，所以她就通过了。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;担心遭到报复。 &lt;/strong>;一些客户因担心遭到报复而拒绝提供反馈。继续用餐馆做类比，这可能会带来厨房工作人员以某种方式污染食物的可怕形象。事实上，我们经常听到客户的故事，他们一再对企业的某些小方面感到失望，但又不想提供反馈，因为担心这会影响双方的关系。实际上，客户似乎更重视与企业的关系，而不是其提供的服务或产品。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;反馈请求已变得像白噪音。&lt;/strong>;每个企业都要求提供反馈每一次互动，都会造成类似于公地悲剧的逆转。不是个人以牺牲集体的利益来消耗资源，而是集体以牺牲企业的利益为代价来忽略请求。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;有些人可能会问这是否是一个值得解决的问题。难道我们从今天的反馈系统中得到的问题提示还不够多吗？我们认为不。问题是不满意的顾客往往会直接退出。他们不会发出警告——他们只是不回来。因此，真正要解决的问题是，您的“正式”反馈机制可能会说一切都很好，但您可能会遇到服务问题。这可能会导致快速下滑和难以恢复的声誉问题。与大多数健康问题一样，一旦情况变得更糟，预防和/或及早发现比采取更强有力的干预措施要好得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们提供了一些关于如何改进的想法：&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;让改进成为你的选择目标，而不是评估。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;由于公司使用客户反馈来评估员工绩效，因此我们中的许多人都经历过客户服务代表对他们进行“5 分（满分 5 分）”评分的请求，这可能是一次积极的体验并以一种尴尬的（如果不是完全消极的）方式结束它。这不是员工的错，而是正在使用的系统的错。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们建议重新组织反馈问题，以明确组织正在寻求改进，而不是被告知它做得很好。而不是问“我做得怎么样？”问“今天我可以做哪一件事来为您提供更好的服务？”邀请客户加入您的旅程，以获得更好的体验。您可能需要教您的员工提出好的第二个问题和第三个问题，以征求更好的反馈，因为基础广泛的初始问题可能不足以让某些客户产生想法。训练他们做到这一点是值得付出努力的。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;过度关注客户所做的事情，而不是他们所说的。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;如上所述，客户不愿意分享他们的想法或想法除非事情真的很糟糕或者互动是以正确的方式进行的，否则就会产生感情。因此，与其跟踪可能会产生误导的“情绪”，不如跟踪并观察客户行为。顾客重复购买的频率是多少？他们访问您的商店或网站的频率如何？他们在那里做什么？就餐厅而言，哪些主菜被吃掉一半，哪些主菜会干净盘子？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;系统地捕获这种行为反馈需要结合数据分析来跟踪大量顾客以了解模式，但也需要，一线员工的非统计显着观察结果。他们是否注意到客户所做的事情表明了不满？例如，咖啡摊的员工可能会观察到顾客用餐巾纸包裹杯子；也许这意味着杯子太热而无法握住？通过将客户行为数据与观察力相结合，企业可以就如何不断提高运营质量提出假设。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;让这成为一种习惯，而不是定期干预。&lt;/h3>; &lt;如上所述，服务问题可能会随着时间的推移而恶化，导致客户在没有警告的情况下退出。在这种情况下，预防是有效的。因此，请更换半年一次或每季度一次的调查工具，转而采用持续的、成为您文化一部分的机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，如果您想将其提升到一个新的水平，请考虑将实验与您的反馈结合起来努力。进行一些小的更改并寻求反馈。或者在业务的一个小领域做出更重大的改变，看看客户的反应如何。将实验与观察客户和寻求诚实的意见相结合是一种持续改进运营的机制，就像将反馈视为礼物和命令一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢迎反馈，将其视为宝贵的见解和帮助。根据授权，组织可以营造一个充满活力和适应性的商业环境，以响应客户的需求和偏好。建立真实且有意义的反馈循环有可能大大提高企业的运营标准。创建一种鼓励反馈的文化，并将客户视为可以为改进公司产品做出贡献的合作伙伴，而不是将客户视为批准或反对的来源，这是重新思考当今存在的典型、无益的反馈舞蹈的重要方法。&lt;/p >; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sustainability Is About Your Workforce, Too]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/sustainability-is-about-your-workforce-too]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sept23_15_1219011427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;哈维尔扎亚斯摄影/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;近年来，许多企业聘请了首席可持续发展官，并制定了一系列高优先级计划，以减少碳排放和全球气候风险改变。随着欧盟推出一系列旨在保护劳动力的法规，是时候扩展可持续发展的概念了。人员可持续发展对企业人力资本实践采取整体方法，包括多样性和包容性、福祉、员工安全和公平薪酬。它向最高管理层提出了这些人力资本问题，并要求首席人力资源官与首席可持续发展官就这些计划进行合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/sustainability-is-about-your-workforce-too?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/sustainability -is-about-your-workforce-too?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;欧盟长期以来一直致力于改善工人福祉，声称希望创造更加透明的环境为所有 1.82 亿工人提供可预测的工作条件。现在，它正在多个方面推进这一目标：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;它的&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/social/main.jsp?langId=en&amp;amp; catId=1313&quot;>;透明且可预测的工作条件指令&lt;/a>;，成员国必须在 2022 年 8 月之前颁布，旨在改善员工保护并提高劳动力市场透明度。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;其 &lt;a href =&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/social/main.jsp?catId=1311&amp;amp;langId=en&quot;>;工作与生活平衡指令&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;于 2019 年生效，旨在制定陪产假、育儿假和职业假以及灵活工作安排的最低标准。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;其&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2022/11/28/council-gives-final-green-light-to-corporate-sustainability-reporting-directive/&quot;>;企业可持续发展报告指令 (CSRD)&lt; /a>; 规定，从 2024 年 5 月开始，任何净营业额为 4000 万欧元、资产为 2000 万欧元、或拥有 250 名或以上员工、在欧洲开展业务的公司必须发布有关其为应对一系列可持续发展挑战所做努力的详细信息。 &lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;近年来，许多公司聘请了首席可持续发展官，并制定了一系列高度优先的计划，以减少碳排放和全球气候变化的风险。这些新法规的颁布标志着一个新时代的到来，在这个新时代中，是时候将可持续发展的概念扩展到包括劳动力方面的类似关键问题——我将这一想法称为“人的可持续发展”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人的可持续发展采用整体方法来解决企业人力资本实践，包括多元化和包容性、福祉、员工安全和公平薪酬。它向最高管理层提出了这些人力资本问题，并要求首席人力资源官与首席可持续发展官就这些计划进行合作。这意味着您的员工福利工作不再是零敲碎打的，无论他们的意图多么善意或资源多么丰富，这种努力都是无效的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧盟本质上是在说所有这些“人力资源计划”都是比人力资源更大：它们现在属于全球公民义务的范畴，公司必须这样对待和报告它们。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;如何将人员可持续发展融入您的公司&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h2>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m talking to European and US firms about how they are gearing up for the Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive and developing people sustainability metrics.&amp;nbsp;Here are examples of how a few companies are approaching this:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Heineken has developed standard measurements of human rights, fair pay, and even living conditions for all its contract workers helping it deliver beverage sales around the world.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Enterprise software leader SAP has &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sap.com/2022/10/people-sustainability-investment-sap-research/&quot;>;coupled its industry-leading diversity program to new pay equity and sustainability initiatives&lt;/a>;. For example, the company now openly publishes all pay bands so employees can see where they are and the pay scales for all new jobs posted. In parallel, it provides hiring and workplace support for neurodivergent employees. After undertaking a progressive gender pay equity analysis, it inaugurated a very aggressive program of promotions of women into senior leadership — all long-term “people sustainability” strategies.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Financial services firm Liberty Mutual sees people sustainability as a factor in limiting the global risks of its customers, partners, and employees in the face of accelerating climate change. Chief sustainability officer Francis Hyatt, who previously served as executive vice president of enterprise talent practices, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libertymutualgroup.com/about-lm/corporate-information/sustainability/corporate-sustainability&quot;>;oversees the integration of global climate issues&lt;/a>; in the firm&#39;s risk management approach and promotes sustainability solutions for employees, resellers, and customers. The company promotes thought-through generational and gender equality programs, and Hyatt ensures that every employee understands how their long-term safety and success is part of the company&#39;s overall sustainability strategy. In other words, this new job function unifies all the brand&#39;s existing HR work into the context of sustainability and helping the planet.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;What links all three of these major corporations is the way each separately discovered that when you frame human capital investment in the context of sustainability, it assumes even more importance than it did before.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you see value in this approach, where should you start at your organization? Building on the European Union&#39;s new detailed CSRD reporting requirements, leaders will need to address issues ranging from greenhouse gas emissions to gender pay across their own operations, as well as that of their suppliers and business partners. You should try to ensure sustainability becomes a pillar of operations as early as possible, as the compliance clock is ticking.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real action is to get your HR team to start working as soon as possible with their ESG colleagues to get people sustainability metrics and strategies into your business goals. To drive this, bring together a team including your heads of HR, DEI, and ESG, as well as representatives from your corporate finance and legal teams, to design your people sustainability program. You&#39;ll ultimately want to see these goals reflected in your annual report and other stakeholder communications, so that these programs are seen as a core part of company strategy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recent survey by PwC reveals that many CEOs anticipate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/news-room/press-releases/2023/pwc-26th-ceo-survey.html&quot;>;climate risk will affect their cost profiles&lt;/a>; and supply chains in the next year. However, despite these challenges, 60% of the surveyed CEOs do not plan to reduce headcount, and 80% do not plan to decrease compensation, as they recognize the importance of retaining talented employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data like this underlines how people sustainability has become an integral strategy for corporate growth. Investors will soon begin to measure the effectiveness of a company&#39;s well-being initiatives as a key metric of overall performance as much as its P&amp;amp;L.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You don&#39;t have to be directly affected by Europe&#39;s new sustainability laws to see that bringing together previously disconnected efforts such as DEI, purpose, or L&amp;amp;D under the umbrella of “long-term organizational sustainability” makes a lot of sense. You might even see it as meeting the needs of the present without compromising your future: a measure of sustainability that certainly gets my support.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The UAW and Other Unions Must Focus More on AI and Automation in Their Negotiations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/the-uaw-and-other-unions-must-focus-more-on-ai-and-automation-in-their-negotiations]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_15_N_FDXbXwQmc_h4elZPxUXLU_aQYgUYwnCsM_JUJzjthZnYU_1570020988.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR 员工； Frazao Studio Latino/Getty Images； Umsplash&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span >; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;在与三大汽车公司的谈判中，美国汽车工人联合会 (United Auto Workers) 表示：首要任务是薪酬最大化——为其成员增加。 UAW 和许多其他工会应该同样关注人工智能和自动化对就业的影响，以及如何让其成员为这个新世界做好准备。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/the-uaw-and-other-unions-must-focus-more-on-ai-and-automation-in-their-negotiations?language=es&quot; >;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/the-uaw-and-other-unions-must-focus-more-on-ai-and-automation-in-their-negotiations ? language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;工作场所人工智能和自动化技术的进步需要新的劳动关系方法。然而，汽车工人联合会、卡车司机联合会、国际仓库和码头工会等工会为其成员争取更美好未来的努力似乎已经停留在过去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种短视尤其严重。这让年轻工人感到担忧，在人工智能驱动的工作场所正在形成之际，他们需要有效的代表。雇主也应该担心，因为工人在今天的变革过程中缺乏参与，会为未来埋下问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方都应该牢记涉及好莱坞演员和作家的旷日持久的罢工。演员工会 SAG-AFTRA 最近加入了美国作家协会，为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2023-06-29/what- to-know-sag-aftra-strike-actors-hollywood&quot;>;63 年来的第一次&lt;/a>;。影视制作人对人工智能的使用是双方分歧的关键问题之一。例如，有人担心演员的计算机模拟可能会取代演员本身，而编剧将不得不负责完善人工智能生成的剧本。解决这些问题需要时间，但至少在本例中，各方在人工智能成为行业支柱之前就已经开始了这一进程。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;熟悉的模式&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;但其他工会似乎并没有正视技术进步将改变工作的方式。考虑一下 UPS 和卡车司机协会最近达成的协议，将全职司机的平均年薪提高到约 170,000 美元，&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamster.org/2023/07/weve-changed-the-game -teamsters-win-historic-ups-contract/&quot;>;被工会吹捧为具有历史意义和游戏规则改变者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该协议为工人带来了显着的工资增长，但未能充分解决问题诸如如何让员工为自动化做好准备等问题。未来，在管理自动驾驶车队时，司机可能不再坐在卡车或货车的方向盘后面，而是在控制台后面操作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;港口行业最近的一项劳工协议表明，同样缺乏对以下问题的关注：技术相关的挑战。 2023 年 8 月，国际仓库和码头联盟 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/dockworkers-ratify-labor-deal-at-west-coast-ports-f0dc23e?mod=djem Logistics_h&quot;>;确认&lt;/a>;它批准了与港口雇主签订的一份为期六年的新合同，其中包括加薪 32%，并为在疫情期间工作的码头工人提供一次性（且当之无愧的）“英雄奖金”。与此同时，洛杉矶等北美港口与新加坡、迪拜、鹿特丹和汉堡等亚洲和欧洲设施之间的自动化差距已经变得令人不安。解决这种差异并让工人为自动化的未来做好准备应该成为劳资关系议程的重要议题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汽车工人也面临着变革。他们的行业正在从化石燃料汽车转向电动汽车和自动驾驶技术。这种转变需要充分利用自动化和不同技能组合的新型现代化制造平台。与此同时，美国汽车工人联合会成员&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/business/autos/uaw-members-vote-to-authorize-pottial-strike-db4dbd7a&quot;>;最近授权&lt;/a>;罢工如果今年未能就加薪 46% 和每周工作 32 小时的协议达成协议，将对底特律汽车制造商采取行动。但其他问题，特别是如何让工人为不断变化的工作场所做好准备，也应该成为谈判的核心。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;新出现的问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;大多数人特别关注随着算法接管计算机编程、法律研究和产品装配线等领域年轻员工的大部分工作，预计许多入门级工作将会消失。但是，如果没有这些工作，初级员工将如何获得攀登职业阶梯并成为其所选学科的未来领导者所需的在职经验？明天的高级程序员或经验丰富的律师从哪里来？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个需要解决的问题是如何培训人们在工作场所与人工智能一起工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有多种模型可供选择这样的同事关系。例如，人工智能生成的信息被传递给人类管理者做出决策。芯片制造商英特尔使用这种方法来改善购买决策。采购经理在决策中使用人工智能系统生成的供应商绩效评估等信息。另一种框架采用人工智能系统来执行日常工作，但当操作环境发生异常变化时需要人类进行干预。流行病的爆发或系统的意外行为都是不常见情况的例子，这些情况需要独特的人类属性，例如了解背景以识别问题以及解决问题的灵活性和适应性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工人代表和雇主必须制定方法将这些框架和其他框架嵌入到工作实践中，以确保员工能够履行这些角色，并在新角色出现时根据需要进行调整。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;紧迫性的理由&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;现在是开始思考这些问题的时候了，因为向人工智能驱动的工作场所的过渡不会一蹴而就。我们在过去的技术变革浪潮中已经看到了这一点。例如，2003 年，沃尔玛告诉其前 100 家供应商，它将强制要求每年在约 10 亿件货箱上安装 RFID 标签。该技术将带来多种好处，例如提高库存准确性和减少缺货情况。行业权威人士预测，RFID 将很快在供应链中普及。事实上，技术故障和标签的高成本阻碍了该技术的采用。又过了 16 年，物品级 RFID 才重新流行起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人工智能的采用速度可能会更快，但雇主和员工有时间为它不可避免地带来的工作场所变化做好准备。此外，即使许多工人在中短期内继续从事同样的工作，拥有同样的头衔，他们的工作也会发生变化。他们可能会看到更多重复性任务委托给自动化系统，并且必须执行更多监控功能。对新技能的需求（例如使用越来越多的数据和发现可能破坏自动化流程的异常的能力）将会增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当今的工人需要持续、增量的重新技能或提升技能来维持稳定或改善的职业道路。流离失所的工人需要进行实质性的再培训才能找到下一份工作或职业。进入劳动力市场的年轻人需要具备与他们的才能和普遍的劳动力需求相一致的技能基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一系列的教育计划，从小型的按需学习到中等长度的技能-需要认证计划来响应这些不断变化的需求。还需要更新高中、大学和研究生学位课程。工会应该要求公司投资于其成员的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;短暂的优势&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;谈判薪酬和福利让步永远是贸易的重中之重工会及其成员。如今，在当前的后疫情时期，劳动力短缺增强了工会的谈判地位。然而，随着人工智能和自动化的加速，这种环境将会发生变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;变化的速度令人担忧。人工智能正在迅速发展，因此劳工和雇主代表面对工人相关问题的时间越长，解决这些问题就越困难。现在是工会发挥影响力的时候了——这种影响力可能不会持续太久，因为人工智能工具变得更好——以确保其成员的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Off-the-Shelf Tech Can Make Factories More Profitable]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-off-the-shelf-tech-can-make-factories-more-profitableespecially-for-smaller-companies]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/08/Sep23_09_BLeOMjOFl1Y_343457_459728.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff/Unsplash/Pexels&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;小型公司常常被高端智能工厂系统所需的高成本、复杂性和长安装时间吓倒。这是短视的。通过利用现有数据和更简单的技术来减少浪费、劳动力成本、管理费用和公用事业费用，公司可以看到巨大的经济效益。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div >; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-off-the-shelf-tech-can-make-factories-more-profitablespecial-for-smaller-companies?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt; br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-off-the-shelf-tech-can-make-factories-more-profitablespecial-for-smaller-companies?language=pt&quot;>;葡萄牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;将工厂转变为智能工厂的速度比大多数高管想象的要快得多，成本也低得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当许多人想象智能工厂时，他们会想到一些复杂而昂贵的东西 - 那种大型“制造执行系统”（MES）的实施可能需要一年多的时间和数百万美元的时间。如果你是埃隆·马斯克，你可以将资金投入到先进的自动化和机器人技术上——并且持续投入。但你不需要成为埃隆·马斯克。智能制造的许多最大好处需要更少的时间和金钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多智能工厂的支持者被技术迷惑了，忽视了价值创造的最大潜在来源。我们在过去五年对数百个制造工厂的访问中看到了这一点：大多数制造商对现成数据的利用太少。例如，劳动时间；这些数字是为工资单收集的，但很少从打卡/下班系统中提取并进行分析以发现更有效运营的方法。同样，现成的 RFID 技术可以追踪废料来源，简单的物联网 (IoT) 传感器可以实时洞察公用设施的使用情况。立即查看、分析信息并根据信息采取行动的能力可以对工厂盈利能力产生与先进机器人技术一样大的影响，而且成本要低得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通往智能工厂的低技术、低成本之路是行之有效的适用于任何规模的公司，特别适合中型公司的胃口和能力。中型市场高管表示，&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/how-midsize-companies-can-make-the-most-of-disruption&quot;>;对颠覆感到畏惧，尤其是在技术领域&lt;/a>;。 AlixPartners 今年夏天进行的一项未发表的调查显示，年收入低于 5 亿美元的公司中有 55% 表示技术变革发生得太快，他们无法跟上；只有 24% 的大公司也这么说。他们不需要害怕。相反，中间市场可能是数字领域革命性民主化的主要受益者。近年来，云计算平台为几乎每家公司带来了复杂的功能，曾经需要定制的传感器和摄像头现在可以以低廉的价格获得和改造。这些变化为各种规模的企业提供了最先进的智能工厂工具。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果设计和部署得当，智能工厂战略可以加速解决工人短缺问题，连接技能缺口、脱碳作业、缩短交货时间或近岸。关键是知道从哪里开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;运营新时代&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率和增强韧性。” cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;首先确定您要解决的业务问题。公司应关注工厂损益表，并确定直接影响工厂损益表的 KPI 和指标。下一步是弄清楚如何应用智能工厂概念和工具来提高这些特定基准的性能，这些基准通常包括整体设备效率、机器/资产利用率、生产率和吞吐量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采取，例如，美国东北部的一家商业面包店，年收入约为 2 亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过以以下三个方面为中心的有针对性的智能工厂解决方案，该公司每年节省 150 万美元，使 EBITDA 增加 4.8%业务问题：减少废品和其他废物、提高劳动力成本以及减少能源使用。该公司能够通过相对简单的技术解决所有三个问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，浪费的一个主要原因是烘焙食品从生产线下线时重量过轻（必须丢弃）或超重（必须丢弃）。使用了比需要更多的面团）。通过在现有生产线上安装数字秤和传感器，该公司在废物（名副其实）烘烤之前捕获了这些废物，从而将废品减少了 25%。自制的劳动力可视性和利用率仪表板提供了工厂车间劳动力存在的类似实时视图，显示大量工人在轮班后仍在工作；由于没有实时方式跟踪行为，管理人员无法强制执行轮班时间；使用该工具，加班时间减少了 50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，通过安装物联网传感器并将数据馈送与现有系统连接以监控公用事业消耗，年度公用事业支出减少了 5%，因为除其他外，它透露当设备不必要地运行时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是什么让这些耗时不到六个月的成果成为可能？在与制造商的合作中，我们确定了四种最佳实践，有助于使智能工厂项目经济实惠且取得成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;以工厂的损益为重点。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;大多数从业者定义“智能工厂” “工厂”的软件技术（如人工智能、机器学习和仓库管理系统）或智能硬件（如互联设备和计算机视觉）。所有这些都可以成为智能工厂的一部分，但专注于工具或技术可能会带来看不到机会的风险。根据我们的经验，从工厂损益角度定义智能工厂的方法会带来工厂成功所需的实用主义。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;确定所有成本驱动因素。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p >;大多数智能工厂计划只关注工厂四墙内的运营，尤其是生产线本身。仅关注整体设备效率 (OEE) 的计划仅解决工厂全部成本的不到四分之一，这些成本分散在公司各个部门。在典型的消费品运营中，原料约占成本的 45%，包装约占 20%；直接人工、间接人工、管理费用各占10%左右（分别由不同团队管理）；公用事业约占5%。所有这些都可以成为数字驱动的价值创造的来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;利用现有工厂资产。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;您无需用单一数字平台替换现有设备。向现有设备添加数字功能将获得重建的大部分好处，并且花费更少的资金、更短的时间，并且无需解决新平台始终存在的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;让制造领导者负责。&lt; /h3>; &lt;p>;智能工厂项目的最佳领导者是经验丰富的高管，他们将制造实用主义与数字化悟性结合起来。太多的资产负债表显示了未交付产品的工厂现代化冲销——有时是字面上的冲销。在这方面，许多中型市场公司比大型竞争对手具有优势，因为他们的高级领导者在经验和身体上都更接近运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们一次又一次地看到这种能力组合发挥作用。几年前，我们与美国东海岸一家金属制品制造​​商合作，该制造商的收入约为 1 亿美元，当新冠疫情扰乱其海外竞争对手的供应链时，该制造商的订单不堪重负。由于没有时间对工厂进行大修，也无法知道激增会持续多久，该公司在切割机上安装了物联网计数器和显示器，每台成本约为 100 美元，这使得工厂主管能够实时监控和协助操作员。同时，柜台数据与订单系统集成，订单可即时纳入生产排程、跟踪、匹配发货，极大简化了接单和履行流程。&lt;/p>; &lt;这个实用的数字解决方案示例在一年内使产量和收入翻了一番，而无需任何资本投资或实体工厂扩建。两年后，尽管全球供应链恢复正常，但该公司的销售额又增长了 15%，因为效率的提高使他们能够更好地满足全球价格并从“购买美国货”政策变化中受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当公司的智能工厂方法根据业务优先级进行布局并且领导者寻求最简单的解决方案时，廉价、快速的策略可以提高产量和质量，提高劳动力和机械的生产率，节省能源和材料的使用，减少receive-store-pick-pack-ship 交货时间等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;像这样的举措更适合 &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/03/bridging-the-gap- Between-capital -providers-and-midsize-companies&quot;>;中型和小型制造商面临的资本限制&lt;/a>;。它们能够更快地交付结果，并且符合中型企业快速行动的能力，不受公司官僚机构的阻碍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且它们还提供其他东西。大型跨国公司在许多地方拥有许多部门和工厂，能够更好地建立试点项目、实验或臭鼬工厂。 They can try, fail, learn, and adapt with less danger than a company that has just one or two plants and P&amp;amp;Ls.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A low-tech, low-cost approach to smart factories provides middle market companies with low-risk gains while at the same time providing valuable learning and experience — for executives, managers, and production workers — that can pave the way to bigger, more technologically-advanced investments later.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[AI Adoption in U.S. Health Care Won&rsquo;t Be Easy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/ai-adoption-in-u-s-health-care-wont-be-easy]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_14_1473680688_488500297.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff/lcs813/Aleksandra Konoplia/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption= &quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;美国卫生部门一直在努力将创新付诸实践。人工智能承诺也不会有什么不同。但 3 个步骤可以帮助克服障碍。电子健康记录和微创胆囊切除手术的对比经验可能具有启发性。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot; /2023/09/ai-adoption-in-us-health-care-wont-be-easy?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/ai-领养-in-us-health-care-wont-be-easy?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;人工智能有潜力改善医疗保健的各个方面。人工智能应用可以&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.370.6521.1144&quot;>;加速科学发现&lt;/a>;，帮助医生和护士&lt;a href=&quot;https://学术.oup.com/jamia/advance-article/doi/10.1093/jamia/ocad072/7136722&quot;>;做出更好的决策&lt;/a>;，&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article- Abstract/2804309&quot;>;改善患者的医疗建议&lt;/a>;，并减少有时令人崩溃的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/26/technology/ai-health-care- Documentation.html&quot;>;文书工作的负担&lt;/a>;。但历史表明，美国卫生部门很难将人工智能等创新付诸实践，部分原因是经济学家所说的“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/mic.4.3”。 1“转换中断”，这是新技术的昂贵的分阶段阶段，可能会颠覆盈利运营。为了减少人工智能的转换中断并加速采用，医疗保健创新者必须在三个关键群体中建立对人工智能的信任：提供者、患者和公众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创新者可以做三件事来建立必要的基础：信任：&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;1。改变关于人工智能目的的叙述。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;创新者不应设计新技术来替代人类决策，而应致力于开发补充和增强提供商专业知识的新工具。例如，人工智能应用程序有潜力通过减轻提供者的&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/how-ai-in-the-exam-room-could-reduce-physical-burnout&quot;>;来支持患者与提供者的关系死记硬背的任务，例如将信息输入电子健康记录 (EHR)，使他们能够将有限的时间和注意力更多地花在患者身上以及解决问题和沟通等更高阶的任务上。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;一些提供商甚至正在尝试使用人工智能作为工具来帮助他们进行更多沟通&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/12/health/doctors-chatgpt-artificial- Intelligence.html&quot;>;富有同情心&lt;/a>;对待患者。这些工具的目的应该是让医疗服务提供者能够在更多的地方为更多的患者做更多的事情，而没有这些工具就不可能做到这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;2.请特别注意人工智能应用程序的实施方式。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在实施之前，人工智能应用程序（就像所有新的诊断和治疗创新一样）应该明显改善结果，并为患者和提供者提供更好的体验。付款人、卫生系统和提供者需要就何时适合使用人工智能应用程序、应如何使用它以及如何识别和减轻潜在的副作用达成共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于例如，人工智能驱动的在线症状检查器、预测模型和诊断程序必须由医生精心策划，以减少幻觉（捏造的事实）或&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science. aax2342&quot;>;基于种族或其他特征的诊断偏差。付款人和卫生系统还应依赖临床医生的意见，使人工智能应用程序适应临床和管理工作流程。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;3.向患者和公众保证人工智能应用程序可以满足他们的需求，而不威胁他们的权利。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;为了解决这些问题，创新者应该寻求新兴框架，例如欧盟委员会的&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40804-021-00224-0&quot;>;&lt;em>;值得信赖的人工智能道德准则&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;或拜登政府的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www .whitehouse.gov/ostp/ai-bill-of-rights/&quot;>;&lt;em>;人工智能权利法案蓝图&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;。这些框架为值得信赖的人工智能提供了设计原则，例如：人工智能系统应该安全有效。人工智能算法应该公正并促进公平的医疗保健结果。应维护数据隐私。当使用自动化系统时，应告知患者，并且他们应该能够在适当的情况下选择退出自动化系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两种早期变革性技术（EHR 和微创胆囊手术）的对比示例说明了这一点为什么减少人工智能在医疗保健领域的转换中断是必要且紧迫的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1991 年，&lt;a href=&quot;https://nap.nationalacademies.org/catalog/5306/the-美国国家科学院医学研究所 (IOM) 的报告&lt;/a>;确定了 EHR（当时称为基于计算机的患者记录）作为医疗保健的一项重要技术。但到 2007 年，只有 4% 的医生和不到 2% 的医院报告拥有功能齐全的 EHR。尽管研究表明电子病历与降低成本和提高护理质量有关，但大多数其他经济部门正在迅速数字化，情况确实如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到奥巴马政府将数十亿美元纳入其中时，情况才有所改善。 2009 年经济大衰退期间的&lt;a href=&quot;https://crsreports.congress.gov/product/pdf/R/R40161/9&quot;>;刺激计划&lt;/a>;中对电子病历的补贴 - 近二十年IOM 报告发布后，电子病历开始蓬勃发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比之下，微创胆囊切除手术（一种改变最常见外科手术之一的方法）只需 &lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3016026/&quot;>;从 1988 年在美国首次使用到几乎完全采用，用了几年&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; EHR 的切换中断较高，而新外科手术的切换中断较低。为什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;EHR 的引入需要大量的初始软件支出以及为每个临床环境购买计算机。成本更高的是对员工进行新系统培训，以及随着他们攀登学习曲线而导致生产力下降。额外的成本和中断来自于重新设计临床和管理工作流程，这些工作流程需要捕获 EHR 信息并将这些信息用于有意义的用途。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;向 EHR 的转换还涉及因现有电源挑战而产生的隐性成本关系和职业身份。许多医生将电子病历视为他们日益服从管理人员和付款人要求的证据，特别是当他们用于向系统提供信息的时间比例增加时。除了加快计费和接收速度的系统模块外，大多数医生并没有强烈要求电子病历，也不认为它们能解决紧迫的问题。许多人喜欢并信任他们的纸质记录，而电子病历似乎加剧了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.healthaffairs.org/content/forefront/physical-burnout-public-health-crisis-message-our- Fellow-health-care-ceos&quot;>;医生倦怠&lt;/a>;和提前退休。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微创胆囊手术与以前的技术相比也是一个巨大的变化，需要大量投资于昂贵的新工具、培训和技术。流程。但外科医生和医院已经开始切除胆囊，而且变化主要限于手术室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;改用新的、更好的手术技术并没有挑战现有的权力关系和职业身份。许多外科医生&lt;em>;想要&lt;/em>;学习新方法。此外，微创手术的想法对付款人、患者和广大公众很有吸引力，这可以大大简化向新技术的过渡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些人工智能应用程序的切换中断相对较低。例如，人工智能可用于分析医疗记录，以预测哪些患者在医院跌倒的风险较高。然后可以在 EHR 中标记高风险患者。任何遇到患者的人都可以采取措施降低跌倒的风险。该应用程序可以轻松整合到现有工作流程中，甚至可以消除诸如护理团队每天聚集在一起评估跌倒风险之类的步骤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，当前对人工智能的兴奋很大程度上来自于大语言模型 (LLM)，例如 &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt&quot;>;ChatGPT&lt;/a>;，有潜力自动制定有关诊断和治疗的决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;这些人工智能应用程序可能会带来巨大的转换中断，有可能使医生、护士和其他提供者来之不易的人类专业知识贬值，甚至消除他们的工作岗位。对这种自动化的恐惧会产生对变革的抵制。法学硕士倾向于“产生幻觉”（即编造事实），这种阻力被放大。检查幻觉给提供者已经过满的工作量增加了另一个复杂性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/science/2023/02/22/60- of-americans-would-be-uncomfortable-with-provider-reliing-on-ai-in-health-care/&quot;>;最近的调查&lt;/a>;显示，大多数美国人对人工智能的前景感到不安用于自己的医疗保健。大多数人怀疑人工智能是否会改善健康结果，并担心它可能会恶化医患关系。患者和公众的这些担忧是另一个潜在的阻力来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幸运的是，人工智能是一项新技术，人们的态度还没有一成不变。有时间采取行动。然而，高度的转换中断降低了企业采用创新的动力，特别是在医生和医院服务以及健康保险等市场，这些市场高度集中，并受到监管和其他障碍的保护，免受外部竞争。如果不采取行动，卫生部门可能会推迟或放弃有价值的人工智能应用，就像电子病历一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国是人工智能发展的世界领先者。但技术并不是命运。人们选择如何以及何时使用技术。如果美国卫生部门未能从这项变革性新技术中获益，那将是非常讽刺的。关键是要设计和实现人工智能应用，让它们值得我们信任。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Support New Workers&rsquo; Mental Health]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-to-support-new-workers-mental-health]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_14_1284269493_1056349510.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR 工作人员/artisteer/ Jose A. Bernat Bacete/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close -caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;我们通常将新进入劳动力市场的人视为年轻人和应届毕业生，但该群体还可以包括现有工人进入新的就业类型，例如一线工人过渡到办公室工作，零工工人转向受薪职位，或者人们从无偿护理转向正规就业。 “下一代”的每次迭代都在不断改进。劳动力是不断发展的社会和环境因素的复杂副产品。一旦您了解新入职者的背景并了解驱动他们的独特力量，您就可以更有效、更有意义地支持他们在工作中的心理健康。作者提出了三个行动来指导您的策略。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-to-support -new-workers-mental-health?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-to-support-new-workers-mental-health?language= pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;对于职场新人来说，心理健康不仅是一个优先事项，而且是必需品。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://learnmore.monster.com/2023-state-of-the-graduate-report&quot;>;92%&lt;/a>; 的应届毕业生和即将毕业的毕业生表示，让他们能够轻松地讨论心理问题非常重要工作中的健康。 61% 的人会为了更好的心理健康福利而离开目前的职位，54% 的人会拒绝工作机会（如果工作与生活不平衡）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;了解心理健康和福利状况至少可以说，除了工作本身的日常需求之外，作为一名新员工可能会感到困惑。在雇主方面，心理健康支持市场越来越多地充斥着福利、产品、津贴和服务，这些福利、产品、福利和服务可能很难拼凑在一起，更不用说针对日益多元化的劳动力进行量身定制了。由此产生的模糊性和差距可能会让新员工感到迷失、脱离，并倾向于寻求其他机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，在心理健康方面，我们如何为新员工提供有意义的支持呢？什么实际上有效？在与全球多元化雇主的合作中，我们发现领导者针对新进入者的价值观、挑战和激励因素制定明智且创新的战略至关重要。方法如下。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;了解新工人不断变化的格局&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们通常将新进入劳动力市场的人视为年轻人和应届毕业生，但该群体也可以包括进入新劳动力市场的现有工人。就业类型，例如一线工人过渡到办公室工作、零工工人过渡到受薪职位，或者人们从无酬护理转向正规就业。更好地了解这些人群的差异可以帮助领导者制定更有效的策略来支持他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多新进入者由于其职业阶段而面临着共同的挑战，无论年龄如何。这些可能包括需要适应新的组织工作文化（例如，从学校到工作，或新的就业类型），社会支持网络的损失或变化（例如，跳槽时），以及成功和加速职业生涯的压力生长。总的来说，这些挑战反映了工作结构的调整，可以通过提供清晰和有效的入职、资源配置和联系建设来解决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有与代际分组相关的独特挑战。对于最新一批 Z 世代员工来说，他们的愿望和需求受到更广泛的社会转变的影响，例如 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/2020/05/14/on-the-成年期和面对不确定的未来-我们对 gen-z-so-far-2/&quot;>;多样性日益增长&lt;/a>;、生活成本上升、&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2022/03/23/key-facts-about-housing-affordability-in-the-us/&quot;>;住房负担能力&lt;/a>;，将技术融入工作和日常生活，提高人们对枪支暴力、生殖正义、气候变化、LGBTQ+ 权利等社会问题的认识。 Z 世代工人还面临着前所未有的劳动力挑战，包括失去与大流行和混合工作等新的工作规范。新员工和年轻员工的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/mentalhealthatworkreport-2021&quot;>;意识&lt;/a>;、读写能力和&lt;a​​ href=&quot;https://health.clevelandclinic.org /Z世代-最有可能-心理健康状况不佳/&quot;>;对心理健康的舒适度&lt;/a>;，以及雇主对支持工作中心理健康的更高期望。这些因素共同反映了我们世界不断变化的状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;支持新工人的策略&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;“下一代”劳动力的每一次迭代都是不断发展的社会和社会的复杂副产品。环境因素。一旦您了解新进入者的背景并了解驱动他们的独特力量，您就可以更有效、更有意义地支持他们的心理健康。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考虑以下三个行动来指导您的策略：&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1.将心理健康融入到您的端到端新员工体验中。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;新员工正在第一次适应工作环境。与此同时，他们越来越重视心理安全和积极主动的心理健康正常化。为了满足这种不断增长的需求，请考虑&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsharepartners.org/post/prioritizing-mental-health-throughout-employee-journey-mapping&quot;>;新员工体验的以下方面&lt;/a >;：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;人才吸引力。 &lt;/strong>;创建心理健康或员工福祉声明，明确定义心理健康对您的组织意味着什么。您还可以在招聘信息中包含有关您的公司如何支持心理健康的示例，将员工关于工作与生活平衡的感言添加到您的职业页面，以及与求职者分享有关心理健康福利的信息。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;展示安全文化并支持新员工的心理健康&lt;/strong>;。例如，科技公司 Buffer 与新员工分享了其首席执行官 Joel Gasciogne 的故事，他 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mindsharepartners/2019/08/26/how-one-ceo -used-his-experience-with-burnout-to-better-support-his-employees-mental-health/?sh=1298088957a4&quot;>;休假&lt;/a>;以从倦怠中恢复过来。这有助于预先建立公司围绕心理健康的价值观和可持续工作的方法。心理健康可以在员工手册、福利导航深入指南和学习机会（特别是对于管理人员）中得到进一步强调。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;持续参与。 &lt;/strong>;围绕心理健康建立持续的联系和社区。尝试使用加入好友系统来保持一致的连接点。社交化并推广&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/how-to-form-a-mental-health-employee-resource-group&quot;>;员工资源团体&lt;/a>; (ERG)，以培养归属感并为员工创造安全空间讨论、学习和创新。采用&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/10/why-reverse-mentoring-works-and-how-to-do-it-right&quot;>;反向指导&lt;/a>;来利用新员工的知识、意识和舒适度围绕心理健康，使更广泛的组织受益。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3>;2.共同创造可持续的、心理健康的工作文化。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;关于压力和倦怠的研究引用了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/mhi/our-insights/addressing-employee的影响-倦怠-你解决了正确的问题&quot;>;有毒的工作场所文化&lt;/a>;和关系对个人福祉的影响。与此同时，&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/01/helping-gen-z-employees-find-their-place-at-work&quot;>;越来越多&lt;/a>;的新员工正在积极优先考虑自主权，&lt; a href=&quot;/2023/08/the-radical-promise-of-truly-flexible-work&quot;>;职业生涯的灵活性&lt;/a>;、成长和目标。有几种策略可以帮助创建更健康、更具包容性和更可持续的工作文化：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;围绕工作的教学规范要清晰、一致和关怀。 &lt;/strong>;这包括“硬规范”，例如角色、时间表和截止日期；围绕紧迫性、响应性以及人们沟通方式的“软规范”；定期鼓励员工进行自我保健和健康的工作实践。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;围绕工作需求、风格和偏好进行协作。 &lt;/strong>;邀请员工分享他们在工作和想法方面的个人需求，以促进团队福祉、联系和生产力。这些可以是明确的开始和结束时间或焦点时间界限、将会议限制在一天中的特定时间，或者提供通勤或儿童保育方面的支持。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;探索学习和成长的机会。 &lt;/strong>;考虑培训等正式学习和影子学习等非正式学习，以培养技能并塑造公司价值观。对职业发展的期望和途径保持透明。确保绩效认可和晋升以支持公司和团队健康的行为和价值观为基础。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3>;3.采用用户体验视角来提供心理健康支持。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;说到正式的心理健康支持，第一次学习如何驾驭雇主资源并不是一件容易的事。 （什么是共付额？）对于可能需要强大的专业和自我护理资源组合的新员工来说尤其如此。针对与资格、承保范围、隐私和保密政策相关的复杂规则，为新员工提供额外指导至关重要。以下策略可以提供帮助：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;围绕“如何”获得好处进行额外沟通。 &lt;/strong>;使用多种渠道持续共享信息。与您的福利团队举行学习会议和问答，并在您的内部网上发布简单的操作指南，详细说明如何导航和权衡不同的福利选项。在入职期间执行此操作，并定期重复，包括公开注册、压力工作期间以及响应 &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/06/is-your-company-prepared-for-the-effects-of-wildfires&quot; >;本地和全球&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;提升领导者和管理者的技能。 &lt;/strong>;这通常是通过培训发生的，但也可以包括新闻通讯、资源指南等。有效的方法不仅仅限于应对危机，还强调创造安全文化和可持续的工作方式。这些计划应贯穿入职、晋升和年度培训的整个过程。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;补贴健康的生活方式和行为福利&lt;/strong>;。个人进行自我保健的方式有无数种。补贴他们——特别是可支配收入较低的新工人——可以激励并赋予他们追求这些积极行为的能力，无论他们是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/d1d58aae-437c-11ea-abea -0c7a29cd66fe&quot;>;冥想应用&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://healthcareexecutive.org/archives/may-june-2022/cleveland-clinics-coaching-approach-is-improving-retention&quot;>;辅导解决方案&lt; /a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2020/02/14/sleep-wellness-employer-oura/&quot;>;睡眠工具&lt;/a>;、健身房会员资格等等。 &lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;。 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;更强大和更具包容性的心理健康策略不仅可以帮助新加入的劳动力队伍，而且可以帮助所有员工提高健康、生产力和敬业度。虽然这需要采取全面的方法，但可以从 &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/05/leaders-sharing-your-own-mental-health-story-can-help-you-become-a-better-ally&quot;>; 开始领导者盟友&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/8-ways-managers-can-support-employees-mental-health&quot;>;经理主导的支持&lt;/a>;，并对组织的&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/12/burnout-is-about-your-workplace-not-your-people&quot;>;工作文化&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不可避免地，您的新员工会成为经验丰富的员工。 &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/04/onboarding-can-make-or-break-a-new-hires-experience&quot;>;今天投资新员工&lt;/a>;确实是对劳动力的长期投资。&lt; /p>; &lt;!-- 引文 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why a Single Source of Truth Belongs at the Heart of a Midsize Finance Strategy - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/why-a-single-source-of-truth-belongs-at-the-heart-of-a-midsize-finance-strategy]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img 咏叹调-scribedby=&quot;caption-attachment-362261&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/07/283738_6148.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;作者：Eric van Rossum&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;中型组织的首席财务官 (CFO) 面临着满足财务报告和合规要求、监督复杂的预算和规划需求以及管理现金流的巨大压力。不幸的是，许多首席财务官用于财务规划和分析 (FP&amp;A) 的遗留工具和流程，无论它们看起来多么可靠，可能会阻碍最佳决策、有效资源分配和提高运营效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坚持使用过时的企业资源规划 (ERP) 技术和拼凑的财务规划解决方案的公司往往发现很难建立市场领导地位所需的透明度和信任；满足合规要求；并实施有效的环境、社会和治理 (ESG) 战略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有效财务战略的关键是从传统数据孤岛中释放情报和见解。 PayPal Giving Fund 和 Topcon Positioning Systems 等组织发现，将其财务系统整合到单个云 ERP 平台上可以提高准确性、一致性、效率和数据完整性。跨所有团队拥有单一的财务数据真实来源可以使组织更加灵活、可扩展和适应性强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;不断发展以满足财务和会计需求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;依赖手动和过时的 FP&amp;A 流程的中型公司很快就会意识到，不完善的财务系统会导致耗时的任务、数据输入错误和重复工作。低效的运营会消耗宝贵的资源，限制生产力，并阻碍员工专注于增值活动，从而阻碍公司的适应和发展能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;组织的成长取决于其实施内部控制和实施内部控制的能力。满足日益增长的财务报告要求，例如公认会计原则和国际财务报告标准。中型公司尤其需要强调财务战略、分析和决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;随着他们的成长，这些组织需要一个结构化和复杂的财务和会计方法符合其运营和报告要求的复杂性：预算和规划工具可以帮助确保准确的预测和现金流管理。一些雄心勃勃、具有成长性的组织发现，将其 FP&amp;A 业务从旧平台迁移到基于云的 ERP 平台有助于他们找到更好的见解、做出更好的决策并实现更大的目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2020/11/7262ff35-be7d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html&quot;>;PayPal Giving Fund&lt;/a>; 取代了其低效的旧会计系统以来借助基于云的 ERP，其结果是“一个质量更高且最新的系统，具有干净的数据和新功能，我们可以依靠它们来支持业务”， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;更新分散的 ERP 系统&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整合到统一的、基于云的 ERP 平台上的组织可能会发现竞争优势，能够更快地响应市场变化。更好的自动化、可扩展性和功能可以减少手动输入错误、财务报告延迟和成本增加。此外，改进的分析和预测能力可以使 CFO 更有效地分配资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迁移到云 ERP 解决方案可以保护企业免受数据泄露和未经授权的访问，从而减少与分散系统相关的安全漏洞。保护敏感的财务和客户数据还可以最大限度地减少潜在的、代价高昂的业务中断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保留传统技术的组织可能会发现跟上不断变化的监管要求越来越具有挑战性。一流的基于云的 ERP 系统使组织能够识别并满足最新的监管要求，从而减少违规风险，否则可能会导致罚款、处罚，甚至声誉受损。&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;公司更新和统一其旧 ERP 系统的另一个原因是提高跟踪和报告整个企业的 ESG 指标的能力。最先进的财务和会计工具利用自动化、高级分析和集成系统来提高准确性、及时报告、增强合规性并提供对 ESG 绩效的更好可见性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“实时数据的可见性改变了游戏规则。” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/11/94b6d447-067e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b 的高级项目经理 David de Jong 说道.html&quot;>;拓普康定位系统&lt;/a>;。 “我们过去在每个国家/地区进行月末数据转储，现在我们可以随时检查库存水平或销售情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot; text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; p>;&lt;strong>;从单一事实来源中受益&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使用基于云的 ERP 解决方案的公司可以从反映实时财务、供应链和劳动力规划数据的单一事实来源中受益。改进的洞察力和协作有助于确保一致性、准确性、效率和明智的决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;统一的财务数据视图需要一个能够促进预测、预算和战略规划的 ERP 系统。成长中的公司需要获得人工智能和高级分析等智能技术，以及从 FP&amp;A 到治理、风险和合规性的一切自动化能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于所有这些原因以及其他原因，取代传统的孤岛使用云 ERP 平台是更有雄心的组织正在使用的一种策略，以提高效率并释放增长潜力。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.363364702;dc_trk_aid=554356724;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=&quot;>;&lt;em>;&lt;strong >;了解更多。&lt;/strong >;&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Eric van Rossum 是 SAP 云 ERP 首席营销和解决方案官。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 02:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Worker Safety Needs to Be Central to Your Company&rsquo;s Operations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/worker-safety-needs-to-be-central-to-your-companys-operations]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/08/Sep23_13_532029699.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Jacobs Stock Photography Ltd/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot; >; &lt;span>;摘要。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;特别是在高危险行业，对于公司的运营来说，没有什么比工人安全更重要的了。通过将工人安全作为公司运营的核心，不仅可以挽救生命并防止伤害，而且从首席执行官到车间的全体员工都将更加致力于实现卓越运营。在本文中，作者重点介绍了一种独特的战略合作伙伴关系，该合作伙伴关系帮助输电和配电建筑行业控制因暴露于工作场所危险而造成的伤害和死亡。它确定了任何行业或公司都可以应用的大量最佳实践，以降低受伤率并提高工人安全，从而使员工和您的公司能够蓬勃发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/p>; div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/worker-safety-needs-to-be-central-to-your-companys-operations?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/worker-safety-needs-to-be-central-to-your-companys-operations?language=pt&quot;>;葡萄牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;至对于一些雇主来说，职业安全与健康管理局 (OSHA) 最出名的是突击检查，检查企业是否符合该机构的标准，如果不遵守就会处以罚款。但对于建设和维护美国电网（国家输电和配电基础设施）的公司来说，OSHA 已成为一家集体企业的合作伙伴，该企业避免了数百人的严重伤害并挽救了数十人的生命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建设和维修带电线路的工人通常在高处甚至&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?app=desktop&amp;amp;v=xIrcRu-dsV0&quot;>;悬挂在高处时面临的危险直升机非常巨大。飓风或其他灾难发生后，许多人工作时间很长，而且往往远离家乡，这增加了受伤的风险。例如，2022 年 9 月伊恩飓风过后，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eei.org/hold-items/Ian&quot;>;来自至少 33 个州的超过 44,000 名工人&lt;/a>;暂时搬迁到佛罗里达州帮助超过 300 万家陷入黑暗的人们恢复供电。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十年前，输配电建筑行业正在努力控制因暴露于工作场所危险和环境而造成的伤害和死亡。出于这个原因，OSH​​A 已将该行业直接置于执法的目标范围内。 2002年，一家公司甚至因两名电线工人死亡而面临涉嫌故意违反OSHA标准的刑事指控。但这个问题在整个行业范围内更为严重。根据 OSHA 内部报告，仅 2003 年，电气建筑行业约 22,000 名工人中就有 15 人死亡，每 100 名工人中近 6 人在工作中受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;认识到这一需要为了实现彻底变革，承包商 MYR Group, Inc. 的首席执行官与劳工律师丹尼斯·J·森川 (Dennis J. Morikawa) 联系了业内其他首席执行官，并建议他们联手共同提高承包商的安全绩效。所有的公司。他们还要求 OSHA 加入这一努力。 OSHA 可能以检查而闻名，但它根据承诺在不同情况下&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osha.gov/news/testimonies/10072015&quot;>;应用各种工具和方法&lt;/a>;以及雇主解决安全问题的意愿。预防始终是 OSHA 的首要任务：该机构的目标是说服雇主在检查之前，尤其是在工人受伤之前减少危险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首席执行官们还邀请了国际电力工人兄弟会 (IBEW)代表一些参与公司工人的工会也加入了这一努力。这对于向员工表明雇主认真保护他们的安全至关重要。首席执行官们还引入了两个重要的行业协会——代表大小承包商的国家电气承包商协会和代表拥有电网并与建筑公司签订电网建设和维护合同的公用事业公司的爱迪生电力研究所。&lt;/ p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;运营新时代&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率并增强弹性。&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;他们共同推出了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osha.gov /partnerships/national/325-electrical-transmission-and-distribution-construction-contractors-ibew&quot;>;2004 年输电和配电 (ET&amp;D) 战略合作伙伴关系&lt;/a>;。合作伙伴同意只关注安全，并承诺不要利用该论坛来解决其他问题，例如公司之间的竞争纠纷或劳工管理问题。这也有助于消除人们对这将被视为违反反垄断法的担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次合作首先侧重于数据分析、最佳实践和培训。他们的专家分析了过去五年中发生的每一起伤害，并确定了可以通过最佳实践来修改或消除的因果因素，其中包括对岗前简报的新要求以及要求使用绝缘手套和袖子。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neca-neis.org/powerlinesafety/training&quot;>;培训计划&lt;/a>;是为了支持这些最佳实践而制定的。收集、匿名和分析公司特定的伤害数据，从而实现持续改进和基准测试。各合作伙伴的代表经常以小组形式开会，分析事故和未遂事故，以确定如何有效防止此类事故再次发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osha.gov /sites/default/files/ETD_Whitepaper_FINAL.PDF&quot;>;ET&amp;D 战略合作伙伴关系已从最初的五个合作伙伴发展到&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neca-neis.org/powerlinesafety/partners&quot; >;12&lt;/a>; 自成立以来的 19 年里。它确定了许多&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neca-neis.org/powerlinesafety/best-practices&quot;>;最佳实践&lt;/a>;，并为数千名工人和主管制定和提供了培训计划。 OSHA 估计，从 2018 年到 2022 年，该行业的平均死亡率从合作前的每年每 10 万名工人中超过 40 人死亡下降到每年不到 4 人。严重受伤率也有所下降，但仍然只是之前的一小部分该计划开始了。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;高级领导者如何更积极地解决工作场所安全问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这一战略合作伙伴关系的成功表明，关注工人安全可以帮助公司实现卓越运营。拥有这一目标的高管可以通过亲自拥抱和传达安全的重要性来取得巨大进步。传达安全信息的一种非常有效的方法是使其成为招聘、晋升和奖金的重要组成部分，注意不要建立一个让管理人员可能倾向于少报伤害或危险以使他们的安全绩效看起来比实际情况更好的系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一次伤害，以及工人侥幸避免严重伤害的险情，都应被视为了解伤害发生原因的工具，并应用于制定工作要求和培训计划。应鼓励工人在造成伤害之前识别危险。承认并及时消除严重危险表明了公司及其领导层对安全的承诺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何具有高危险工作实践的公司的高管都可以采用这些方法。但 ET&amp;D 战略合作伙伴关系也表明，当通常竞争的公司领导者能够迈出最初可能让人感觉不舒服的安全合作第一步，却发现这样的合作可以提升整个行业时，可以获得很大的收获。自合作伙伴关系开始以来，输配电行业一些最大的建筑公司的首席执行官定期会面，考虑需要采取哪些措施来确保工人的安全。这向公司中的每个人发出了强烈的信息：安全不仅是一个优先事项（可能每年都会发生变化），而且是整个企业的核心原则。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种类型的协作提供了许多额外的功能好处。更多的公司为分析活动提供数据，使统计数据更加可靠，并使公司能够将其绩效与竞争对手进行比较。更多的事件调查有助于制定最佳实践并改进培训计划和安全信息的设计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我看到公司在工作场所安全方面从领先者变成了落后者，特别是当存在&lt;a href=&quot;/ 2018/03/7-在不牺牲工人安全的情况下改善运营的方法&quot;>;降低成本的财务压力&lt;/a>;，或者当首席执行官退休而其继任者接受新的优先事项时。这种合作伙伴关系的协作性、跨行业性质使每位首席执行官都积极参与并做出承诺，即使是在组织中发生领导层变动的情况下也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;线路工人修复电网的公司认识到，未来几年将带来更多的挑战。维护不善的电线&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/16/business/energy-environment/pge-camp-fire-california-wildfires.html&quot;>;引发了巨大的野火&lt;/ a>;，飓风和龙卷风之后的停电&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/increasing-power-outages-dont-hit-everyone-equally1/&quot;>;规模和频率都在增加&lt; /a>;. ET&amp;D 战略伙伴关系推动的安全实践变革无疑将防止更多的工作死亡和重伤，从而降低另一场自然灾害导致该行业工人进一步发生个人悲剧的可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其他高危行业的 ET&amp;D 伙伴关系的教训是，工人安全不应被视为成本，而应被视为投资。 By making worker safety central to a firm&#39;s operations, not only are lives saved and injuries prevented, but there is a greater commitment among the entire workforce, from the CEO down to the shop floor, to achieving operational excellence.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the Best Chief Data Officers Create Value]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-the-best-chief-data-officers-create-value]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/08/Sep23_13_ChenWu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Chen Wu&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Despite the rapidly increasing prominence of data and analytics functions, the majority of chief data officers (CDOs) fail to value and price the business outcomes created by their data and analytics capabilities. It comes as no surprise then that many CDOs fall behind expectations and have short tenures. The authors conducted 17 in-depth interviews with CDOs who are largely considered to be at the frontier of the role. Based on the interviews, they synthesized where CDOs can create value and how they can measure and price it. Beyond strategies for creating and demonstrating value, they provide insights into qualitative and quantitative measurements that data analytics leaders are currently adopting.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-the-best-chief-data-officers-create-value?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-the-best-chief-data-officers-create-value?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Data is fast becoming an integral element of every decision, customer touchpoint, and internal process. The opportunities that come with greater data and analytics capabilities are apparent across the entire value chain — from customer-facing algorithmic tools that yield personalized recommendations to enterprise tools that automate applicant résumé screening. With data and analytics becoming important drivers for increased efficiency, better decision-making, and greater innovation, CEOs have started to invite a new member to their C-suite: the chief data (and analytics) officer (CDO).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite the rapidly increasing prominence of data and analytics functions, the majority of CDOs fail to value and price the business outcomes created by their data and analytics capabilities. It comes as no surprise then that many CDOs fall behind &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/08/why-do-chief-data-officers-have-such-short-tenures&quot;>;expectations&lt;/a>; and have &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/06/why-chief-data-and-ai-officers-are-set-up-to-fail&quot;>;short tenures&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As part of a research project at the Digital Value Lab at Harvard&#39;s Digital, Data, and Design Institute, we conducted 17 in-depth interviews with CDOs who are largely considered to be at the frontier of the role. Based on the interviews, we synthesized where CDOs can create value and how they can measure and price it. Beyond strategies for creating and &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/01/8-strategies-for-chief-data-officers-to-create-and-demonstrate-value&quot;>;demonstrating value&lt;/a>;, we provide insights into qualitative and quantitative measurements that data analytics leaders are currently adopting.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;How CDOs Create Value &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;CDOs typically influence four interconnected areas. Depending on the level of &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/building-the-ai-powered-organization&quot;>;federation&lt;/a>; of data responsibilities, CDOs wield more or less influence over these areas. The first sphere of influence is directly linked to business value and can be termed as data products that directly link to use cases. These products are developed, maintained, and continuously improved (predominantly by the CDO unit) to solve a specific business problem for an internal or external customer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, CDOs typically curate the organization&#39;s data assets and platforms (sometimes also referred to as multi-purpose &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/07/a-better-way-to-put-your-data-to-work&quot;>;data products&lt;/a>;): essentially reusable assets that allow teams across the organization to easily and efficiently access data and build use case–driven data products (including reports) on top of. For most companies, the first asset is the “Customer 360,” which brings together all information collected on a customer across business units.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third sphere of influence, which conceptually sits below the first two, comprises the organization&#39;s data architecture and governance. It hosts the underlying technical and administrative infrastructure needed for the data product teams to operate efficiently and in a standardized way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The CDO&#39;s fourth sphere of influence is the organization and, more specifically, its people. The organization reflects the foundation for any data initiative as it provides and develops both general data literacy and specialized data talent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Understanding the playing field is important. Businesses typically hire a CDO with a portfolio of diverse expectations, including being a technology leader for data and analytics, a visionary for the overall business, a cultural revolutionary to promote data-driven decision-making, a data governance expert, and so on. Yet success requires a concerted effort between these different roles. An emboldened CDO needs to propose value, measure value, and claim value for each sphere of influence.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Proposition for Data Products &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Data products are applications that are developed and managed by the CDO to provide the right data of the right quality at the right moment for a specific business process. Their objective is to generate actionable insights to improve internal operations, enhance product or service offerings, create an entirely new offering, or make data available to external partners. The CDO unit should mirror each line of business and then, for each one, develop a data product roadmap (jointly with the business side), prioritize the most impactful use cases, and deploy interdisciplinary teams to develop, maintain, and improve the data product following the principles of &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/07/a-better-way-to-put-your-data-to-work&quot;>;agile product development&lt;/a>; and DataOps.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each of these teams should have all the necessary capabilities to run independently, from understanding the business problem to creating the data science models and visualizations to building the data pipelines. These lighthouse projects are important at a tactical level: They inspire buy-in and trust from other C-level executives and business units, and they demonstrate the feasibility and impact of data initiatives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mohammed Aaser, CDO of Domo Inc., a data and analytics platform provider, says, “CDOs are fighting a two-front war. In one case, they have to show value rapidly. At the same time, they have to build platforms that can endure and can create value. The reality is, if you start with the platform, it will take you two years, you will not show much value, and you will not have a job.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Proposition for Data Assets and Platforms&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The second sphere of influence comprises data assets and platforms that can be leveraged to build data products for all kinds of challenges. They integrate different data sets and elements from source systems from across the business into a single asset or platform, which, cohesively, can give a better view of the issue being considered. Their objective is to enable scale: The data asset or platform makes data available for easy and fast delivery by anyone in the organization (through data products or self-service APIs).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CDOs need to align with unit heads on which data asset or platform to prioritize. Then, dedicated teams own each asset or platform and use an agile product-centric delivery approach (similar to that of data products). They start by compiling user requirements, prioritizing features, and developing, maintaining, and improving the asset. This includes measuring adoption and collecting user feedback. As these assets span multiple lines of business, they typically require the alignment of definitions and calculations of central business metrics — a powerful demonstration of how the cross-functional role of the CDO can help lines of business speak the same language and forge a holistic understanding of the business.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Proposition for Data Architecture and Governance &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In most businesses, the proliferation of data has led to a proliferation of systems, practices, and policies. Accordingly, it is one of the CDO&#39;s core responsibilities to manage the data architecture and governance — what we consider the third sphere of influence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The objective of both data architecture and governance is to manage the basics of the data organization by providing the required data systems in a cost-efficient way and by ensuring data is produced, documented, and consumed in a streamlined manner. Regarding the data architecture, the CDO&#39;s value proposition is to define and align which systems and tooling (eg, security) are required in the target data architecture to support the desired data products and then acquire or build and run these systems.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Additionally, the CDO should centrally manage licenses and instances of often extremely costly data-specific systems and define usage criteria. For data governance, the CDO&#39;s value proposition includes the development of data policies with regard to accessibility, quality, interoperability, and security, as well as the development of a data catalog as the single source of truth of how, where, and which data is stored in the data assets and platforms. Data governance should also include central best practices and standards for data operations and the use of algorithms and AI.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Proposition for Organizational Data-Readiness &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The CDO&#39;s objective should be to develop the required data-specific roles and organization-wide competencies to support all other data-related activities. While this requires that sufficient data talent is hired and retained, real success comes from the activation of the entire organization: Leading CDOs define different internal data personas, categorize every role in the organization, and map professional development journeys for them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Upskilling employees outside of the CDO unit, for example, through “data translator” training for business leaders and subject-matter experts, creates a strong demand for data products. Upskilling also creates local champions that ensure the embeddedness and adoption of data products in their business units. Frontline employees need to understand the basics (eg, how a metric is calculated, how to de-average and identify lower-level trends) because otherwise, the fear of making a mistake, taking the wrong number, or misinterpreting it makes them revert to their old processes.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;How Can CDOs Measure, Show, and Price Their Value Contribution? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;For CDOs, clearly defining the value proposition across all spheres of influence is a necessary precondition to measure, demonstrate, and sometimes price their value. Leading CDOs have started to develop qualitative and quantitative measurements that can prevent organizations from under- or over-investing in their data initiatives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One CDO claimed that business units would no longer (or less frequently) request or use data products if they had to consider the associated price of the data teams and the underlying data asset/platform, which may explain why some organizations shy away from internal chargeback models. However, pricing data allows business leaders to better evaluate the most efficient use of their budget. Additionally, if business units allocate funds from their own budgets, they have skin in the game and want to achieve measurable results with it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data leaders often start with a “shadow” chargeback (ie, the theoretical internal transfer price) and a “shadow” revenue account (ie, the enabled revenue increment) for every service, product, or asset owned by the CDO unit — with “shadow” indicating that it is not (yet) a formal profit and loss record. The shadow chargeback helps put a price tag on CDO projects, which is important to know regardless of who pays for them. Both the CDO and business units often tap into CFO-controlled central budgets to cover the chargeback, given the strategic relevance of data initiatives. The upside of (shadow) chargebacks and revenue accounts? Resources are allocated efficiently, business units have a deeper interest in driving adoption and success, CDOs are incentivized to go into selling mode, and CDOs can more easily show their value contribution.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Measurement of Data Products &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The CDO role requires a great deal of persuasion and storytelling. Demonstrating the potential of data products for concrete business use cases is pivotal in this regard. CDOs should measure at least the following set of indicators:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Business impact of lighthouse data products&lt;/h3>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Adoption rate of the data product for internal customer (eg, frontline employee) or external customer&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Improvement of the data product against a pre-implementation baseline or reference case (through A/B testing), eg, churn reduction&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Operational efficiency and maturity of data product teams&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Resources used in the development and operations of the data products (eg, person-hours per data product or feature, additional CPU needed)&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Ability to support business, responsiveness to feedback, and SLA fulfillment through surveys&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Maturity of the agile data product teams (eg, sophistication of agile ceremonies) through surveys&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Most business leaders still struggle to understand how data can change the way their core processes work. Showcasing high-value lighthouse data products and their business impact helps business unit leads get a sense of what is possible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, sensible investment decisions require an estimation of costs. Before deploying their teams, CDOs need to engage them in project-sizing exercises to determine which roles and how many person-hours are needed for potential data products. For each line of business, the CDO unit should keep a data product roadmap that mirrors and follows their respective business strategy and objectives/key results. One CDO told us that he holds an annual executive value-engineering workshop where they boil down a long list of 60 to 70 data product ideas to 10 candidates, and then to four data products that are realized in the upcoming year. Their decision is based on a 2×2 matrix with estimated business impact on one axis and estimated resource requirements (ie, costs) on the other axis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One CDO pioneer, Sebastian Klapdor, CDO of Vista, a marketing and design company, established various metrics to capture the value created by his team. Through the adoption of data products and pre- and post-implementation measurements, Vista has been able to generate an incremental $90 million in profits with a large share of it recurring on an annual basis.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Measurement of Data Assets and Platforms &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Mohammed Aaser of Domo Inc. describes multi-purpose data assets and platforms as the “assembly line” that allows for the development of data products at scale across the organization. The CDO develops and continuously improves the assembly line, relentlessly removing all bottlenecks and incorporating user feedback. However, value is added by the teams building data products on top of data assets and platforms, which, with increasing maturity, may become increasingly decentralized and performed by the respective lines of business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, CDOs need to implement various qualitative and quantitative measurements to measure, show, and claim the value they provide with the data assets/platforms.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Business impact of multi-purpose data products/platforms&lt;/h3>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Usage and engagement of the data asset and platform (eg, number of users, data volume accessed)&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Processing time of queries using the data asset and platform&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Anecdotal stories of the improvements for the use case–driven data product development process (from business unit and CDO unit teams)&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3>;Operational efficiency of data product/platform team&lt;/h3>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Resources used in the development and operations of data asset/platform (eg, person-hours per data asset/platform)&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Speed of the feature development and source system integration&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Building a multi-purpose data asset/platform such as the “Customer 360” asset requires a significant budget and usually has a long development time (one to three years, depending on the business).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to development, CDOs should prioritize with the business unit leads the most relevant multi-purpose data assets and platforms. They should estimate per domain the associated value pool based on the 30 to 40 data products it could enable within five years (a back-of-the-envelope estimation is suitable here).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the average ROI of existing data products and a flat-rate reduction for additional development needs (to build on top of these multi-purpose data assets/platforms), the investment size should be budgeted. Given that such assets and platforms are cross-functional and have strategic value, the CFO functions most often as the project sponsor. Nonetheless, CDOs should implement an internal (shadow) chargeback once they are developed, using the estimated impact the business unit aspires to generate and the average ROI of use case–driven data products. Alternatively, CDOs can define user- or usage-based pricing models.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Measurement of Data Architecture and Governance &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Most of the responsibilities of providing the data architecture center around central and efficient management through, for example, central allocation of licenses and instances or rationalization of systems. Wendy Batchelder, SVP and CDO of Salesforce, explains that these are often quick wins, and that the CFO becomes a great partner in driving the projects. By implementing a tiering scheme that regulated when a query is considered a high/medium/low-velocity query, she was quickly able to realize significant cost savings.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Business impact of data architecture&lt;/h3>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Improvement of the cost base through central management and rationalization of systems against a pre-implementation baseline&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Future-readiness of data architecture and governance &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Progress on the systems roadmap (status quo versus target state)&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Progress on the data policies (status quo versus target state)&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Progress on the data catalog (status quo versus target state)&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Value Measurement of Organizational Data-Readiness &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Creating a data culture is often cited as one of the biggest challenges for CDOs. Leading CDOs work closely with internal partners such as HR and external partners such as universities to curate an educational program and to develop data-specific professional development journeys.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To understand the effectiveness of their educational efforts, CDOs should set up Net Promoter Score (NPS) surveys. One of the CDOs interviewed has garnered a world-class NPS of 80 to 90 for his middle-management training focusing on business value creation and ethical use of data.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three measurements form the basis of performance tracking in the organizational sphere of influence:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Completion rate of the data literacy employee training, academies, bootcamps, and e-learnings&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Quantitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Net Promoter Score of the data literacy employee training, academies, bootcamps, and e-learnings&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;Qualitative measurement:&lt;/strong>; Concept for the data personas and development journeys&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Stepping out of the shadow as a CDO is much more than a career ambition. It heralds an important shift in how the organization thinks about data and ensures that data-related projects are funded or de-funded according to their value contribution. Given the vast opportunities associated with data, analytics, and AI, businesses can no longer afford uncoordinated data efforts without a clear link to value. While AI dominates the headlines, there is consensus on the following: data maturity necessarily comes before AI maturity.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Myth of the CEO as Ultimate Decision Maker]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/the-myth-of-the-ceo-as-ultimate-decision-maker]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_13_5381478.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Yaroslav Danylchenko/Stocksy&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Chief executives are responsible for guiding corporations, so the role inevitably requires making many decisions. But people overestimate the level of personal involvement CEOs have in this process. Instead of making decisions, CEOs tend to shape decisions, by designing the process, choosing when to participate directly, and monitoring the work &amp;#8212; a selective process that mirrors the choices CEOs must make when carrying out other responsibilities.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/the-myth-of-the-ceo-as-ultimate-decision-maker?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/the-myth-of-the-ceo-as-ultimate-decision-maker?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;A common misperception about the CEO&#39;s role is that they are the ultimate decision-maker, and that the prize of getting this coveted position is that you now get to make all the decisions. In reality, the CEO&#39;s role is much more about &lt;em>;shaping&lt;/em>; rather than making decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a fundamental reason for this subtle difference. Organizations face countless decisions daily, and it would be impossible for a CEO to be involved in each one. Attempting to do so would slow down the entire operation and could even bring it to a standstill. As a result, rather than making decisions directly, the proper role of the CEO is to enable others to make decisions the CEO can support. Of course, there are times when the CEO must be the ultimate decision-maker, but the CEO&#39;s approach should be inspired by Occam&#39;s razor: The fewer decisions the CEO can make, the better.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CEOs have several tools at their disposal to shape decisions in their organizations. Some are at the level of the organization as a whole. CEOs can shape decisions by aligning everyone around a shared purpose, articulating priorities, and setting goals. Decisions are also shaped by developing a clear strategy, adopting an organization structure that allows for the proper distribution of responsibilities, and fostering a strong culture. A clear performance measurement and reward system can also help.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even as they build the broader context that shapes decisions across the organization, CEOs cannot step away from decision-making entirely. Indeed, they must choose where and how they personally engage in decision-making.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision-making landscape in any organization is vast. A useful map is to think of categories of decisions on one axis (eg, strategy, structure, culture, people, products, investments, etc.) and the organizational level at which decisions need to be made on the other axis (eg, corporate, business unit, region, function, subsidiary, plant, office, etc.). CEOs must choose how to personally engage to shape decisions across this entire landscape. This involves, at each intersection of category and level, determining the extent to which they are involved in designing the decision-making process, choosing when to participate directly, monitoring the work, and creating clarity around when and by whom a decision will be made. This framework is based on the 25 years I have spent alongside colleagues teaching CEO workshops at Harvard Business School, as well as my own experience leading organizations and advising CEOs as a board member and advisor.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Designing the Process&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;CEOs can influence any decision by thoughtfully designing the decision-making process. This involves setting parameters such as who is to be involved, what questions to answer, what kinds of information to gather, what guardrails to keep in mind, how many meetings to have, the structure of the discussions, and what gets decided when and by whom. The CEO may play a major role in designing some decision-making processes and a lighter role in others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, a CEO we studied was heavily involved in designing the process for making key portfolio choices, such as keeping, divesting, and acquiring businesses. Working with his direct reports and a small group of high-potential managers, he defined the metrics against which to evaluate each business, chose a set of rivals to benchmark performance against, set a time frame of three months to complete the analysis, and established weekly three-hour meetings during which the team reviewed progress and agreed on next steps.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same CEO delegated to his CFO and CHRO the task of preparing recommendations for structural changes that would result in cost-reduction goals in shared services such as HR, IT, and finance. Other than specifying that he wanted the two to work together to identify cost savings exceeding 15%, he gave them full leeway to design a process to generate these recommendations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two examples illustrate the intentionality CEOs must bring to these design choices. Depending on the specific matter they want to influence, they must choose the various parameters (eg, who to task, what goals/metrics to set, what time frame to establish, and what expectations to create), and identify which issues they want to personally be involved in, and which others they are happy to delegate and trust others to make.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Participating in the Process&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;CEOs must then choose how much they want to participate at various stages of the decision-making process. The CEO may be active at every step, check in from time to time, or get engaged at a specific point, such as the beginning, middle, or end.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CEOs&#39; choices about when and how to personally step into decision-making situations often reflects their desire to make their teams active participants in the decision, as a way to increase buy-in. If you watch CEOs in these settings, what&#39;s striking is how many of their actions are aimed at guiding others toward a decision, instead of overtly influencing the decision in a way that may feel heavy-handed. They provide this guidance by challenging the process, raising the bar, asking tough questions, and demanding better answers. Even though the CEOs are involved, they are careful to leave actual decision-making to their colleagues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the CEO who designed the strategic portfolio review process attended five of the 12 meetings. He attended the first two to set the right tone and direction. He then allowed the team to do its homework. He did one check-in in the middle of the process to ensure things were on track. Finally, he re-engaged by attending the last two meetings when the group presented its recommendations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, on the cost-cutting workstream, he attended no meetings and instead asked the CFO and CHRO to brief him on their progress and to seek his input whenever they felt it would be helpful.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The level of personal participation CEOs choose in situations such as these reflect how tightly they want to manage each process, the importance they attach to the decision, the level of confidence they have in the leaders involved in each case, and how costly they feel it would be to intervene and change course as the process unfolds.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Monitoring the Work&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;CEOs must also choose how much they want to be personally engaged in monitoring the work. Providing feedback as any decision-making process unfolds is a vital element of the CEO&#39;s role. In the case of periodic reviews, CEOs describe themselves as monitors who must check to ensure things are on track and that the organization is executing as planned. Sometimes, CEOs describe their role as a coach, educating people, providing constructive feedback, and helping improve performance while doing little to actually influence the final decision under discussion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By monitoring decision-making processes personally, CEOs set standards, encourage alignment, and enable course correction. In some cases, the CEO may meet regularly with the team to monitor progress. In others, they may only check in occasionally to ensure things are on track.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A key choice while monitoring decision-making processes is the altitude, or level of granularity, at which the CEO wants to engage. CEOs can choose to engage at a high level or dig deeply into the details. Some CEOs set these altitude expectations in advance; others choose them strategically in real time to keep the team alert and prepared to engage with them at any altitude they choose. Although the team may experience this as inconsistency or unpredictability, imagine yourself in this position: Might you prepare more thoroughly for a series of meetings if you know the CEO might ask questions that range from the big picture to the most nitty-gritty details?&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Making the Decision&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;For some matters, such as setting the overall performance targets of the company, the CEO may be the principal decision-maker, choosing to make the final call after a set of recommendations have been presented. In other situations, the CEO may choose to consult with a small group of key executives and board members, as in the case of M&amp;amp;A deals, or while selecting top management team members. In other situations, such as formulating a business unit&#39;s strategy, the CEO may let others, such as the business unit heads, make decisions, and then endorse them. In yet other circumstances, such as deciding which R&amp;amp;D projects the company should pursue, although the CEO may participate at some stage to better understand the choices under consideration, the CEO may delegate the final decision to a senior manager such as the head of R&amp;amp;D, because the CEO may lack the technical expertise to weigh in.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Factors to Consider in Choosing How Much to be Engaged&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;CEOs often use various criteria to determine the level of personal involvement they have across the decision-making landscape. These include the decision&#39;s strategic importance: Does it matter for the CEO&#39;s key priorities and have long-term implications for the company&#39;s direction, vision, or mission? High-level strategy decisions almost always warrant the CEO&#39;s direct engagement. Other factors that may influence the CEO&#39;s involvement include the decision&#39;s impact on the company&#39;s financial health, either in terms of revenue, costs, or profitability; or the risk associated with the decision, either in terms of potential loss, legal implications, or harm to the company&#39;s reputation. If a decision involves the allocation or reallocation of significant resources — like capital investments or human resources — it may warrant CEO oversight.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CEOs may also factor the extent to which the decision impacts the company&#39;s core values and ethics. Any decision that could challenge or redefine these values require greater CEO involvement. Decisions that set a precedent for future company actions or policies often also require CEO engagement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a decision spans across multiple segments of the organization or has the potential to lead to significant internal disagreement or conflict, the CEO should get more involved and consider making the final call. Decisions that will notably impact key stakeholders — including shareholders, major customers, regulators — might also draw the CEO&#39;s attention. Urgent decisions, especially those that must be made rapidly to address immediate challenges or capitalize on opportunities, may warrant the CEO&#39;s prompt attention.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although CEOs tend to focus on these more significant decisions, some CEOs wisely note that they find benefit from periodically involving themselves directly in decision-making on smaller issues or at lower levels in the organization. For example, the CEO may engage with some decisions far removed from the top, such as the strategy for a fledgling business unit or the design of an executive development program, because they want to signal its importance to the company. These symbolic opportunities for engagement can be just as important as the more substantive matters that warrant the CEO&#39;s involvement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Decision-making isn&#39;t the only activity in which a CEO must make conscious choices about the right level of personal involvement. CEOs must be strategic about when to personally engage with customers, investors, regulators, the media, and other stakeholders. They must decide which senior roles require an interview with the CEO as part of the hiring process. They must decide when and how often to engage with individual directors in one-on-one conversations between full board meetings. Making the right choices about the level of personal involvement is key to a CEO&#39;s overall effectiveness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In conclusion, the role of the CEO is not about making every decision, but rather about creating an environment in which decisions are made effectively. By shaping decisions rather than making them, CEOs empower their teams, foster agility, and drive the organization toward success. The CEO is more of a conductor, orchestrating the many parts to produce harmonious results, than a dictator issuing commands. It&#39;s a shift in perspective that is required when leaders assume this pinnacle position and can be transformative for many leaders and organizations alike.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>