<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[Good Judgment Is a Competitive Advantage in the Age of AI]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/good-judgment-is-a-competitive-advantage-in-the-age-of-ai]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_ChenWu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;陈舞插画&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span >;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;借助生成式人工智能，技术游戏已经发生了变化。突然间每个人都是潜在的程序员。但当我们实现这些技术飞跃时，每个组织仍然需要一项基本的、长期的能力来实现人工智能的真正潜力：判断力。人工智能时代的判断思想是作者工作的核心原则。已故同事、富有远见的朋友、《哈佛商业评论》长期撰稿人亚历山德罗·迪·菲奥雷 (Alessandro Di Fiore)。亚历山德罗坚信以人为本，并认为技术是帮助人们增强创造力、自主性和批判性思维的一种方式。他认为，随着人工智能系统上升到新的通用操作标准，判断力将成为组织真正的竞争优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href =&quot;/2023/09/good-judgment-is-a-competitive-advantage-in-the-age-of-ai?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/ 2023/09/good-judgment-is-a-competitive-advantage-in-the-age-of-ai?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;事实并非如此很久以前，人工智能被认为是精英专家或数据科学家的领域。公司热情洋溢地谈论它改变业务的潜力，但只有一小部分员工能够使用它。借助生成式人工智能，游戏规则发生了变化——突然间，借助 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT、Google 的 Bard 或 Anthropic 的 Claude 2 等工具，每个人都成为了潜在的程序员。但是，当我们实现这些技术飞跃时，每个组织仍然需要一项基本的、长期的能力实现人工智能的真正潜力：判断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2HRqRUWWj58&quot;>;人工智能时代的判断&lt;/a>;的想法这是我们已故同事和富有远见的朋友亚历山德罗·迪·菲奥雷 (Alessandro Di Fiore) 工作的核心原则。亚历山德罗坚信以人为本，并认为技术是帮助人们增强创造力、自主性和批判性思维的一种方式。作为&lt;a href=&quot;/search?term=alessandro%20di%20fiore&quot;>;《哈佛商业评论》的频繁撰稿人&lt;/a>;（以及&lt;em>;哈佛商业评论意大利版&lt;/em>;前主席），他经常反思如何创新、领导力和人工智能齐头并进。在&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/08/why-ai-will-shift-decision-making-from-the-c-suite-to-the-frontline&quot;>;这篇 2018 年文章&lt;/a>;中，他认为随着人工智能越来越容易为所有员工所接受，判断力将变得与任何技术技能一样重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessandro 认为，随着人工智能系统上升到新的通用操作标准，判断力将成为组织真正的竞争优势。但仅靠强化技能并不能培养更好的判断力。公司将需要从根本上重新思考如何看待和部署判断，以适应变化的步伐。值得注意的是，亚历山德罗认为判断的三个关键方面对于此时至关重要：&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;访问&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这说明了谁有权或允许做出判断。作为&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hbr.org/product/the-democratization-of-judgment/ROT357&quot;>;判断民主化&lt;/a>;的早期倡导者，亚历山德罗知道做出正确的决策并不是一件容易的事仅限于最高管理层。随着知识、数据和技术的分布更加广泛，判断力也必须更加广泛地分布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司需要了解如何&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capgemini.com/insights/research -library/generative-ai-in-organizations/&quot;>;利用和扩展生成式人工智能，并试图禁止这种访问最终将是徒劳的。确保您的员工能够使用所有方式来释放这些工具的价值是转型的一部分，当然是以安全和受控的方式进行的。这需要信任和沟通。但领导者应该考虑到，越来越多的新用例和实践必然会自下而上地出现，而不是自上而下地搅动。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;练习&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;判断力&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这指的是决定或形成意见的行为或过程。亚历山德罗认为判断是一个连续的过程，而不是一个单一的时刻：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;判断不仅仅在评估数据和信息做出决策的时刻进行。判断比这更广泛，它始于提出正确的问题，构建正确的问题，评估更广泛的背景。判断是共同创造的，它是一个旅程。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这种判断的概念在今天更加正确。生成式人工智能的兴起将判断力扩展到了离散决策之外——现在它是一个人机协作过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;借助人工智能聊天机器人，上下文交互的重要性显而易见。判断是通过人类与人工智能的综合对话而不是分离的领域产生的。我们最近关于 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbritalia.it/userUpload/ebook_Generative_AI_inglese.pdf&quot;>;生成式 AI 如何增强 10 种流行管理实践&lt;/a>;的 ChatGPT 实验就是一个很好的例子。在与ChatGPT进行有意义的对话时，我们必须在提示之前、期间和之后锻炼我们的判断能力，输入正确的上下文，精心设计最佳的提示链，并仔细解释建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实验证实亚历山德罗的直觉：理想的结果出现在人类和机器智能的交叉点上。正确判断的未来就是这种共生的共同创造过程。这种转变要求全面的人员转型和再培训，为工人提供人工智能时代必不可少的判断能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;控制&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;这与系统有关或监督或检查决策的流程。传统的控制方法很快就会过时。严格的自上而下的监督可能会扼杀这种新范式的敏捷性。然而，如果道德人工智能开发和部署原则没有在组织中根深蒂固，那么完全不受约束的自治也会带来风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该解决方案由两部分组成：首先，在系统中建立信任和责任 &lt;a href= “https://www.capgemini.com/about-us/who-we-are/our-values/our-ethical-culture/our-code-of-ethics-for-ai/&quot;>;道德准则&lt;/ a>; 为了公平、安全和可持续的使用，并防止人工智能模型产生不准确的信息或产生与公司价值观相矛盾的响应；其次，为用户提供有关如何为人类人工智能决策设置正确背景的培训。第二部分涉及解释提示的适当界限并负责任地构建查询。领导层不应只关注微观批准的选择，而应重点关注为各个级别的员工提供这些技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这一愿景中，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imd.org/ibyimd/team-建立/控制系统-让员工自由的七种方法/&quot;>;控制从官僚把关转变为培养集体责任。正如亚历山德罗所写，“领导者有责任设定正确的背景和条件，使员工能够在数据和技术的帮助下做出更自主的决策。给予自由是好的。但帮助他们行使自由更为重要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessandro 的愿景强调了在人工智能重塑社会时做出正确判断的必要性。在我们努力实现人类与技术无缝协作、促进创新和进步的未来时，他的遗产仍然是源源不断的灵感源泉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未来仍然由我们通过愿景、道德和负责任的创新来塑造。&lt; /p>; &lt;!-- 引文 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using Technology to Improve Supply-Chain Resilience]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/using-technology-to-improve-supply-chain-resilience]]><description>&lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_GuillemCasasus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Guillem Casasus 插图&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span >;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 大流行导致许多全球供应链陷入停顿。当我们摆脱疫情影响时，许多公司采取了“以防万一库存管理”的做法，结果矫枉过正。更重要的是，当消费者信心每月差异很大且需求持续波动时，企业很难制定计划。例如，在服装行业，买家必须提前六个月下旺季订单。由于波动性较大，6 月份的需求预测可能与 12 月份的实际需求完全不同。这增加了要么因供应不足而错过季节的总体风险，要么在一月份面临大幅降价的风险。为了向前发展，供应链管理者需要在贸易伙伴之间建立更灵活、动态的连接，以取代目前无法适应突然、意外的供应链中断的点对点、静态连接。他们需要的是一个更现代化、反应更灵敏的供应链平台。本文讨论当今的供应链技术如何帮助企业增强其供应链的弹性。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/using-technology-to-improve-supply-chain-resilience?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/using -technology-to-improve-supply-chain-resilience?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Covid-19 大流行从根本上动摇了全球供应链，但它们尚未完全恢复。更重要的是，许多以前遵循“精益”原则（包括“及时库存管理”）的管理者已经通过采用“以防万一库存管理”而矫枉过正了。这种通过临时且不明确的“以防万一”库存策略进行过度纠正（和库存过剩）的倾向，导致零售、批发和制造业的全球库存飙升，而此时商业信心指数却处于低位。和消费者信心指数&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.oecd.org/leadind/consumer-confidence-index-cci.htm#indicator-chart&quot;>;均显示出异常波动&lt;/a>;。当消费者信心每月差异很大时，企业就很难制定计划。例如，在服装行业，买家必须提前六个月下旺季订单。由于波动性较大，6 月份的需求预测可能与 12 月份的实际需求完全不同。这增加了要么因为没有足够的东西而错过这个季节的总体风险，要么在一月份面临巨大的降价。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title =&quot;运营新时代&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率并增强弹性。&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;为了向前发展，供应链管理者需要贸易伙伴之间更灵活、动态的联系来取代他们的当前的点对点静态连接无法适应突然的、意外的供应链中断。他们需要的是一个更现代化、响应速度更快的供应链平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;利用现代技术平台构建供应链弹性&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;供应链管理技术平台可以通过允许企业在多个层面上建立弹性：&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;通过提高供应链可见性建立统一的商务。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;面临的最重大挑战之一如今的零售商正在跨多种渠道（例如在线、实体店以及将两者结合起来的混合模式）精心策划无缝的消费者体验。许多杂货店开发了创新技术，允许客户在线下订单，在订单准备好时通知客户，然后检测客户何时在附近，从而创造无缝的客户体验。网络范围内的库存可见性对于实现统一商务至关重要。通过网络范围内的库存可视性，公司可以避免缺货和库存过剩的情况，从而降低持有成本并提高客户满意度。通过利用 RFID、物联网传感器和数据分析等先进跟踪技术，企业可以实时了解库存水平、位置和移动情况，从而做出更好的数据驱动决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;进行销售和合作运营规划。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;成功的销售和运营规划 (S&amp;OP) 需要来自广泛职能部门的领导参与，包括财务、销售、营销、生产和履行。幸运的是，随着现代协作平台取代过时的工具以提供单一的真实数据源、直观的建模和性能仪表板，这变得更加容易。如果执行得当，S&amp;OP 使公司能够预测未来需求并主动响应市场变化。这种方法还有助于风险管理和应急计划，使企业能够减轻供应链中断或经济波动的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;实施 SaaS 系统。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;软件即服务 (SaaS) ）彻底改变了全球企业和个人的软件交付、访问和使用方式，对全球技术实施产生了深远影响。对于供应链管理人员来说，SaaS 通过允许每个阶段（例如原材料、生产、加工、仓储和分销）共享信息、操作和见解来扩展覆盖范围和可见性。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;创建灵活且开放的云&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;日益增加的复杂性和不断的重组要求供应链技术能够轻松集成并快速调整，这意味着可组合架构特别适合现代供应链。与乐高™套装一样，可组合架构允许通过组合更小的模块化组件来构建复杂的系统，这些组件可以轻松组装、互连和重复使用。管理员可以向池中添加新的硬件资源，而可组合基础架构可以自动将这些资源合并到可用池中。 New Balance 就是实践中的一个很好的例子。这家运动服装公司创建了一个单一的内容库，为其所有系统提供支持——可穿戴设备、移动设备、信息亭等。与从头开始为每个系统重建 New Balance 商务体验不同，使用适合各种情况的通用可组合架构要有效得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;技术是卓越供应链背后的驱动力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;虽然遵循这种方法对于构建能够承受不可预见的干扰的弹性供应链至关重要，但也可以利用最新技术来构建更强大的供应链系统，从而使整个组织取得成功。有远见的高管不会仅仅依靠技术来生存，而是会利用技术来帮助他们的企业蓬勃发展。这里采用的策略会因组织而异，但以下是可以创建更强大供应链的几种广泛方法：&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;利用人工智能/机器学习来支持供应链管理。&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;人工智能 (AI) 和机器学习 (ML) 引发了供应链管理的变革时代。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/capability/operations/our-insights/ai-driven-operations-forecasting-in-data-light-environments&quot;>;根据麦肯锡的说法&lt;/a>;，有效使用AI在库存控制中的应用，可实现库存持有成本降低20%，缺货率降低50%。通过利用先进的算法和数据分析，人工智能/机器学习技术提高了需求预测的准确性，使企业能够以前所未有的精度预测市场趋势、波动和客户偏好。这种预测能力有助于高效的库存管理、减少过剩库存并最大限度地减少缺货，从而优化营运资金。此外，人工智能/机器学习驱动的算法可优化物流、简化运输网络并降低成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;进一步加强协作。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;疫情最明显、最持久的影响之一是它迫使企业各个层面的员工学习新的协作技能。 Zoom 每日会议参与者&lt;a href=&quot;https://investors.zoom.us/static-files/a17fd391-13ae-429b-8cb3-bfd95b61b007&quot;>;短短四个月内从 1000 万增加到 3 亿&lt;/a>; 。现实情况是，虽然组织内部的协作常常被证明具有挑战性，但供应链经理更需要在组织外部与客户、供应商和合作伙伴进行协作。这些管理者尤其需要依赖适当工具的实施，例如基于许可的专用网络，以提供安全、简单且可信的环境来共享供应链数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;投资&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;自 2019 年以来，针对供应链的网络攻击&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1367208/us-annual-number-of-受影响的供应链实体攻击数量增加了一倍&lt;/a>;。就在去年，攻击&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1367208/us-annual-number-of-entities-impacted-supply-chain-attacks/&quot;>;增加了 200% 以上&lt;/a>;。在许多此类案例中，供应链中的安全漏洞是由供应商和承包商等第三方运营商暴露的。幸运的是，现代平台正在成为对抗网络攻击的最有效防御手段。虽然管理人员可能无法预测和防范每一种风险，但现代技术平台对于让组织领先威胁一步至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;建立更高的供应链可见性。&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;传统上，整个供应链的可见性仅限于“向上”和“向下”，这意味着管理人员通常只能“看到”其一级供应商和直接客户在做什么。然而，在多级供应链中，运营商不会感受到三级或四级供应链中断的影响，直到调整时为时已晚。如今，现代 IT 平台使贸易伙伴能够聚集在一个安全的、基于许可的交易所，在那里他们可以共享信息，提高可见性并增强整个供应链的弹性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场大流行病表明我们需要做我们不仅仅要投资建设有效的供应链，还需要同等重视维护它们。无论创建高效、有弹性的供应链需要多少专业知识，我们都必须认识到，在不断变化的世界中，供应链永远不是成品。通过使我们的供应链保持持续的测试状态，并投资于不断提升供应链所需的技术和见解，可以避免全球供应紧缩。建立一个响应实时输入并不断发展以满足不断变化的需求的供应链的任务永远不会真正完成，但这没有理由不开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Evaluate a Job Candidate&rsquo;s Critical Thinking Skills in an Interview]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-to-evaluate-a-job-candidates-critical-thinking-skills-in-an-interview]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_23_152401239.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;混合图像 - Peathegee Inc/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close &quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;培养批判性思维的最古老且仍然最有效的策略是苏格拉底方法，该方法由苏格拉底 (Socrates) 于 2,400 多年前开发，苏格拉底是一位伟大的哲学家。西方哲学的奠基人。苏格拉底式方法使用发人深省的问答探究来促进学习。它的重点是产生更多的问题而不是答案，其中答案不是停止点而是进一步分析的开始。招聘经理可以应用此模型在现代组织中与候选人建立不同的对话。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot; /2023/09/how-to-evaluate-a-job-candidates-ritic-thinking-skills-in-an-interview?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/ 2023/09/how-to-evaluate-a-job-candidates-critical-thinking-skills-in-an-interview?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;招聘是其中之一它是最具挑战性的能力之一，但却是最具战略性和影响力的管理职能之一。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/capability/operations/our-insights/operations-blog/ Winning-the-war-for-talent-in-product-development&quot;>;麦肯锡研究&lt;/a >; 量化显示，优秀人才的生产力高达八倍，这表明人才质量与业务绩效之间的关系非常显着。在困难时期寻求增长或仅仅生存的组织必须成功招募一流人才、思想领袖和主题专家。这通常是在时间有限的情况下完成的，因为您必须快速填补关键职位。本质上，您是在几次非常短暂的约会后承诺建立长期关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在让我们考虑一下招聘人才的典型流程。我们用来评估人才的主要工具是一系列工作面试。典型的面试过程是问答形式，向候选人询问一些常见问题：&lt;em>;请告诉我们您的背景。你为什么想为我们工作？分享您在工作中遇到的挑战以及您是如何应对的。你最自豪的是什么？你产生了什么影响？为什么你是这项工作的最佳人选？你最大的成就是什么？你的弱点是什么？&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管人们对面试本身的价值表示赞成和反对，但典型的问答工作面试流程未能评估最重要的因素之一，如果不是最重要的技能，您应该从您雇用的人身上寻找最重要的技能——批判性思维。批判性思维是从各种来源寻找信息，评估其可信度，并确定其相关性和准确性。批判性思维通常被归类为高阶技能，它不是单一技能，而是一系列技能的集合，涉及推理、构建合理的论点以及识别情况的缺陷、偏见、逻辑或不一致之处。批判性思维与创造性思维不同。创造性思维是产生新的、创新想法的能力。批判性思维要求考生仔细、逻辑性地分析事实并形成判断。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;批判性思维从根本上来说是一个提问的过程&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;一个关键见解&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.amazon.com/Decisions-Over-Decimals-Intuition-Information/dp/111989848X&quot;>;根据我们的研究&lt;/a>;，基于对数千名高管的调查和教学，房间里最聪明的人并不是那个人与答案，但提出问题的人。他们好奇、投入、无所畏惧，&amp;nbsp;好奇心强，准备探索一个可能还没有答案的新领域。根据问题的性质，他们展示了观察、分析、推理、询问、解释和解释。批判性思考者很好奇。与生俱来的好奇心已被证明与以下八个特征相关：热心的学习者、问题解决者、积极的倾听者、自我驱动、高生产力、成长心态、卓越的成就以及强大的利益相关者管理能力。这八个特质读起来就像是你想加入团队的人员的资格愿望清单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;咨询公司和技术公司通过使用基于场景或行为的问题来推动标准的面试问题。 em>;：在亚特兰大修剪草坪需要多少钱？为什么公用孔是圆形的？你会如何为盲人设计一个酒架？如果您获得 500 万美元来解决一个全球性问题，您会解决什么问题以及如何解决？&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些是评估候选人提出问题的能力的一个很好的进步，但在回答时这些问题将分析应聘者解决问题的能力、处理歧义的能力和创造性思维，但不会表明他们是否好奇、积极主动或对您的公司、产品、文化或八个特质中的任何一个充满热情前面提到过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，您如何识别具有这种多才多艺且引人注目的批判性思维和好奇心组合的个人呢？大胆地&lt;em>;翻转面试过程。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;培养批判性思维的最古老且仍然最有效的策略是苏格拉底方法，由苏格拉底在 2,400 多年前开发，苏格拉底是一位伟大的哲学家。西方哲学的奠基人。苏格拉底式方法使用发人深省的问答探究来促进学习。它的重点是产生更多的问题而不是答案，其中答案不是停止点而是进一步分析的开始。招聘经理可以应用此模型在现代组织中与候选人建立不同的对话。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;翻转面试&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;让候选人面试你。翻转面试是揭示候选人内在优势、首选工作方式以及他们的想法的另一种方法。面试将展示候选人的思维和决策过程，并表明候选人是否表现出领导特质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;翻转面试不仅仅是让候选人问您开放式问题，例如，&lt;em>;什么是公司文化？&lt;/em>;或&lt;em>;在该公司工作感觉如何？&lt;/em>;面试官带着业务场景、对相关信息的理解进行讨论，并邀请受访者进行指导通过一系列问题进行发现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受访者可能会使用四种类型的问题，这些问题的复杂性和参与度不断增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;事实问题： &lt;/strong>;基于事实或意识提供简单答案的问题。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;趋同性问题：&lt;/strong>;具有有限答案的封闭式问题。通常，这些问题只有一个正确答案。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;发散性问题：&lt;/strong>;鼓励多种答案的开放式问题。这些问题是更详细地分析情况、问题或复杂性并激发创造性思维的一种手段。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;strong>;评估性问题：&lt;/strong>;需要更深层次思考的问题。问题可以是开放式的，也可以是封闭式的。评估性问题引发多层次、不同角度的分析，从而得出新综合的信息或结论。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;h2>;进行翻转面试：四步流程&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;使用以下框架可以最大限度地提高与新员工对话的价值：&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1.框架&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;简要描述一个场景。预先说明您是该场景的信息来源，并要求受访者在接下来的 8 到 12 分钟内简单地说“您将如何开始这个发现？”当他们不可避免地陷入困境时，用决策树的一个分支来提示他们，进一步打开发现。邀请他们提问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;面试官评估&lt;/strong>;：在框架步骤中，您评估他们如何框架问题。他们是只看问题的表面还是探究问题的本质？他们提出的问题的质量应该决定他们需要的信息、所需的努力，并揭示要做出的重要决定。第一步更多的是发现问题而不是解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;2.链接&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;一旦他们定义了问题，请他们提出有关背景的问题。 “考虑到他们如何构建场景，他们还想知道哪些其他信息来做出推荐？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;面试官评估：&lt;/strong>;您希望了解他们的问题是否会引导他们将场景置于上下文中。语境为王。为了真正将情况置于背景中，他们的问题应该使他们能够通过以下方式进行三角测量：1）绝对值，2）随着时间的推移，3）相对于整个市场正在发生的事情，客户或竞争对手的行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3.解读&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;根据原始场景，结合所学知识，询问“需要做出的基本决策是什么？”或“他们对情况的理解发生了怎样的转变？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;采访者评价：&lt;/strong>;他们能够开始阐述叙述吗？您正在评估他们的叙述是摘要还是综合：摘要 = 数据陈述；综合就是数据+判断。批判性思考者将展示他们如何并行使用和综合不同的信息，以更深入地理解所需的场景或决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;4.继续&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在最后一步中，询问“您接下来会立即采取哪些步骤？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;面试官评估：&lt;/strong>;如果他们开始提问对于需要说服的关键利益相关者、影子影响者、倡导者或摇摆选民，候选人正在进行批判性思考。他们是否寻求了解逆风和顺风以使他们能够前进？请注意，这并不是要解决问题或评估他们是否提出建议，而只是他们如何解决问题和做出决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使用翻转面试，您可以评估候选人的逻辑和对工作的热情。根据他们的问题扮演角色。这些问题是多余的还是必然的？这些问题是通用的还是具体的？他们是否不仅提出事实性或趋同性的问题，而且还提出分歧性和评价性的问题？候选人是否会从不同角度进行转向、深入研究并重新审视某个主题？这些问题是否基于问题及其环境的背景？当他们向您提问时，您可以通过实时、旋转和探究的方式调整他们的问题来确定他们是否在积极倾听。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熟练的提问者会创建合作对话，通过以下方式引发新的学习：一系列问题。他们与对方互动。他们的问题应该引发推论和联系，并提出不明显的观点。这种探索心态鼓励尝试和迭代；意想不到的学习可能源自讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;微软改变面试流程&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;虽然没有被贴上“翻转面试”的标签，但一名候选人在 1998 年申请了微软的职位，结果发现自己陷入了一场面试。 。面试时，招聘人员要求他“卖给我一个烤面包机”。候选人停了下来。候选人毫不犹豫地问了几个问题：“家里有多少人？” “家里有小孩子吗？” “家里使用烤面包机的年龄范围是多少？” “他们住在狭小的空间里，比如公寓还是大房子？” “他们早餐吃得很多，还是他们的主餐是晚餐？” “他们多久出去吃饭一次？”在三分钟的时间里，这是一系列有关人口统计、心理统计和物理空间的问题。招聘人员要求应聘者停下来，并询问这与向她推销烤面包机有什么关系。候选人回答说：“一切。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发现并理解“烤面包机环境”的背景非常重要，以确保我向您推销您需要的东西。如果我将烤面包机的特性和功能与您的需求相匹配，销售的成功率就会提高，您将成为满意的客户。您需要烤面包机、弹出式 2 片烤面包机、4 片、宽片烤面包机、传送带烤面包机、商用烤面包机还是对流烤箱？也许帕尼尼压榨机最能满足您的需求。这项练习与烤面包机无关，招聘人员想了解候选人如何处理歧义。他是一个批判性的思想家吗？他是立即投入推销，还是暂停、转向并学习？如果您想知道，候选人得到了这份工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;建立好奇的文化&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;伟大的领导者建立伟大的文化。伟大的文化建立在好奇心之上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建立一支具有平衡好奇心的团队是致胜之路。具有不同背景的团队通过将不同的知识集引入到问题的解决中，可以进一步放大好奇心文化的影响，这些知识可以相互促进。从面试过程开始，从一开始就嵌入这种关键能力，将使您能够快速建立一种创造性思想家的文化。在翻转面试中取得成功的人都是持续学习者。他们将抓住这个机会——无论是作为个人还是作为一个充满活力的团队——并抓住这个机会。他们会表现出与生俱来的好奇心，并不断问“为什么？”或“那又怎样？”重要的是，“现在怎么办？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提出问题是我们的本能。十八个月。心理学家认为，这个年龄是孩子开始寻求信息的年龄。大约 36 个月大时，这种刚刚萌芽的好奇心转化为口头问题。这些问题看似无数且随机，似乎不加区别地从一个主题跳到下一个主题。为什么会下雨？月亮是由什么构成的？鸟儿是怎样飞翔的？狗去哪儿了？我们什么时候可以去公园？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，当孩子开始上小学时，这种通过提问来学习的永不满足的好奇心常常会发生转变。慢慢地，教育的重点从提出问题转向寻求答案。当孩子们知道答案时，他们会被要求举手，从而形成了一种新的习惯。这种心态——期望提供答案而不是提出更多问题——只会随着年轻人继续他们的教育旅程而加深。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当我们开始工作时，我们就被灌输了这样的观念：我们需要得到答案。在工作环境中，提问的价值经常被错误地忽视。答案受到拥护；预期解决方案；隐含地不鼓励提出更多问题。是的，结果很重要，但是通过更明智的资源分配或更具创造性的策略，这些结果是否可以更显着并以更低的风险实现？我们常常忽视这样一个事实：表现最好的人是那些提出问题并激发批判性思维的人，这些问题可以暴露策略中的弱点或揭示替代路径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到年轻、好奇的自我的道路是短的。事实上，这取决于问自己一个连接我们的职业和个人生活的问题：我们如何成长？这个问题是每个项目、每个请求、每次会议、甚至我们选择工作和生活的地方的基础。很少有人像这样直接问这个问题，但这个根本问题的答案是什么塑造了我们的职业和生活。我们在质疑中成长。了解这一点可以创建一个框架，帮助确定如何提高个人满意度或公司的市场份额、扩大我们的客户群、帮助提高产品使用率或推动更新。如果你寻求成长，你需要激发批判性思维。为此，你需要强有力的问题。这是翻转面试模型的基础。虽然我们从小就喜欢提问，但很少有人教导我们如何有效地培养提问技巧。在商业中，我们常常忽视提问的重要性。我们没有意识到提问是工作中不可或缺的技能。我们没有投入足够的时间和精力来培训自己和他人成为有效的调查员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在翻转面试中成功的候选人将表现出批判性思维的心态。这与了解分析工具和方法不同。批判性思维哲学是几乎每个领导者都寻求的技能，但许多团队都缺乏。分析性思考包括明确基本问题的目的，而不是在数据森林中徘徊，不是从统计角度好奇，而是质疑最初的表面价值，能够通过综合将各个点连接起来，并最终能够分辨出来一个基于更深层次的事实、判断和背景的知情故事，而不仅仅是重申最初的事实。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;。 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;公司的蓬勃发展需要反应能力、洞察力和独创性。您寻求敏捷的思想家，他们可以成为增长冠军、说真话的人、客户管理者和洞察创造者。能够概念化问题、构建情境并提出更深思熟虑的问题的候选人将胜过那些依赖教科书答案的候选人。雇用能够提出深思熟虑的问题的人才是建立成功团队的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，一旦你成功招募了出色的人才，你必须创造一个环境，让员工有动力集体工作，同时感到自己受到重视和认可。好奇和好奇。具有拥抱问题和好奇心的成长心态的整个组织可以将挑战重新定义为机遇，并更自由地适应业务条件。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What It Means to Be a Moral Leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;div js-target=&quot;video-player-page&quot; data-props=&quot;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;6337577423112&quot;}&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div >; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;加载中... &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption= &quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Dov Seidman 让人们认真思考，不仅思考他们做了什么，还思考他们如何做。他非常专注于“如何”做到这一点。他创建了 HOW 社会研究所，鼓励领导人走上道德领导之路。他甚至写了一本名为《如何：为什么我们做任何事意味着一切》的书。在我们每周直播系列节目“工作的新世界”的这一集中，塞德曼提供了关于当今良好的道德领导力的见解和灵感——在一个永远混乱的时代。他的中心思想是旧的领导方式不再有效。他向观众发起挑战，请他们选出一位近年来取得成功的指挥与控制型市长、大公司首席执行官或职业教练。他说得有道理。我们对领导者的要求的期望是：也许有一个明显的例子，那就是国家政治人物——现在包括同理心、脆弱性、正直和道德。 &lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader ?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader?language=pt&quot;>;阅读葡萄牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;还记得领导人何时可以通过说“商业就是商业”来回避在敏感的政治或社会问题上采取立场吗？ HOW 社会研究所创始人兼主席多夫·塞德曼 (Dov Seidman) 表示，这种冷漠的中立态度已经不再有效。 “我认为商业的本质就是社会，”他说。 “这是社区，以及我们如何应对遇到的一切，以及我们的深思熟虑和原则性。”坚持正义的领导者是员工、客户和其他利益相关者的新期望。更不用说感恩节餐桌上的亲戚了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着人工智能的发展并挑战人类对智力的垄断，道德判断和同理心等纯粹的人类技能对于领导者来说变得更加重要。塞德曼说，虽然机器可以被教导做正确的事情，但只有人才能带领他人做正确的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于我们视频系列“工作新世界”的这一集，《哈佛商业评论》主编Adi Ignatius 与 Seidman 进行了座谈，Seidman 也是《How: Why How We》一书的作者做任何事情都意味着一切&lt;/a>;&lt;/em>;，讨论：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;如何让你的原则指导你作为领导者&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;暂停的重要性为了反思、重新联系、重新思考和重新构想你的使命&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;随着人工智能原始智能的增长，哪些人类特征和能力的价值将会增长&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;“&lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;工作新世界&lt;/a>;”探讨了高层管理人员如何看待未来以及他们的公司如何努力为成功做好准备。每周，Ignatius 都会在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/harvard-business-review/&quot;>;LinkedIn Live&lt;/a>; 上与一位高层领导交谈 - 之前的采访包括 &lt;a href=&quot; /2021/10/microsofts-satya-nadella-on-flexible-work-the-metaverse-and-the-power-of-empathy&quot;>;微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11 /indra-nooyi-前百事可乐首席执行官谈动荡时期的人才培养&quot;>;前百事可乐首席执行官英德拉·努伊&lt;/a>;。他还在专门为《哈佛商业评论》订阅者提供的时事通讯中分享了对这些对话的内部看法，并为未来的讨论征求问题。如果您是订阅者，可以在&lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences?movetile=newworldofwork&quot;>;此处&lt;/a>;注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;工作新世界&quot; dek=&quot;前几集&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of -work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合&lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;工作新世界&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 前几集 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt; p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dov，欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢谢，阿迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您对领导力的道德方面思考了很多。在这个感觉像是永久颠覆的时代，优秀的领导力是什么样的？&lt;/p>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;newsletter&quot; name=&quot;The New World of Work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;follow-subscribe data -name=&quot;hbpnewworldofwork&quot; data-activity=&quot;newsletter&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div style=&quot;color: #000000&quot;>; &lt;svg>; &lt;use xlink:href=&quot;/resources/css/images/hbr- icon.svg#the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;&lt;/use>; &lt;/svg>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 订阅我们的每周通讯 &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;工作世界 &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; 关于人才、技术和商业未来的坦诚对话。为订阅者准备的特别电子邮件系列。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; js-target=&quot;subscribe-for-newsletter-tout&quot; data-method=&quot;subscribe&quot;>;注册&lt;/a>; &lt;/ div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/sign-in&quot; js-target=&quot;sign-in-this&quot;>;注册&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe&quot;>;登录向上&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 感谢您注册，&lt;span js-target=&quot;newsletter-success-firstname&quot;>; &lt;/span>;！ &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; 您可以查看我们的&lt;a href=&quot;/email-newsletters&quot;>;其他新闻通讯&lt;/a>;或通过管理您的&lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences&quot;>;随时选择退出电子邮件首选项&lt;/a>;。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/follow-subscribe>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;优秀领导者要做的第一件事他们会退后一步，试图理解他们所领导的世界。领导力与头条新闻无关。我们都可以阅读这些内容，推文到推文，帖子到帖子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是关于趋势线的，世界将走向何方？哪些熟悉和陌生的力量正在重塑它？我们用什么框架来判断未来？我们将使用什么剧本来吸引人们踏上通往未来的旅程？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我还喜欢说，平静的大海从来不会造就伟大的水手，而外面的大海并不平静。 。因此，如果你想成为一名伟大的领导者，在波涛汹涌的大海上航行就是其中的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导力始终很重要，它始终具有重要意义。我们将通过一些例子来说明领导力可能比以前更重要，因为它会产生回响。但我们正处于一个一切都被扰乱的时代，包括领导力和权威本身。负责一个组织、一个团队或其他人的意义已经与过去不同了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想构建我认为最伟大的 21 世纪领导力挑战，然后我们可以讨论什么样的领导层应对它。我想你和你的观众都会同意，如果没有正式的授权，你就无法管理一家公司、一个团队、一个国家。人们需要负责。我无法想象一支没有主教练的足球队，一所没有校长的学校，一家没有首席执行官的公司，或者一个没有总统或总理的国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我们都知道，组织当具有道德权威的个人占据这些正式权威的职位时，人类和社会才能真正发挥作用。在不太透明、更不透明的世界里，我们经常将两者混为一谈：“他一定是一个伟人，否则他是怎么达到那么高的地位的？”或者，“除非他是一位出色的领导者，否则董事会不会把他放在那里。”但现在我们看到，正式权力可以被夺取，你可以在选举中赢得它，其他人可以将其授予你，“我特此任命你为副总统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但道德权威确实是取决于你是谁、你体现的价值观、你如何领导、你如何做出决定以及你如何与他人相处。在这个颠覆的时代，我们面临的挑战是，正式权威已被破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;硅谷企业家，即使拥有 20 比 1 的超级多数股权，也无法保住自己的工作，如果他们没有以开明的方式领导，甚至更糟糕的是，存在一些不当行为。我们看到社会各个领域的正式权威被推翻和破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;挑战在于我们如何培养和发展以道德权威领导的道德领袖文化？这是第一步。我们如何确保他们是发号施令、担任正式权力职位的人？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想补充一点，就领导力而言，这场流行病的遗产是，它已经揭示并阐明了道德领导的重要性。不仅仅是最高层，学校校长、星巴克的咖啡师、组织、部门和社会各个层面的商店经理：领导力都很重要。因为特别是在危机时期，当人们自然地感到不确定和害怕时，他们会求助于任何对他们有一定权威的人。他们对他们的期望是真理，一些智慧，一些无私，真正把对方放在第一位。他们期待道德领导力，阿迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个很好的框架。你使用了“道德”这个词。在我们的世界里，为《哈佛商业评论》撰稿的人通常倾向于使用“良好的领导力”之类的术语。优秀的领导者除了拥有你需要的商业头脑之外，还具有同理心，他们很脆弱，但你使用“道德”这个词。你这是什么意思？为什么这是你的中心框架？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我所说的并不是说教、成为道德，或者成为如何应对道德困境的专家，或者如何在社会、政治、环境、宗教问题上采取立场的专家，即使它可能包括这些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道德领导实际上是关于如何。你如何领导、如何决策，是成本效益分析吗？还是有原则指导？你是否愿意做不方便、勇敢和困难的事情，因为这是原则或价值观对你的要求？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这实际上是关于你如何与他人相处和对话。是单向还是双向？这就是您结束会议的方式。你会说：“我们聊得很愉快吗？是谁的电话？哦，这是一个营销决定。谁有营销预算？”这是用权力来界定它，“这是谁的电话？”不如问：“什么是正确的选择？我们认为什么是公平的呼吁？什么是尊重并忠于我们价值观的召唤？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想了解一整套剧本，但现在我只想说，这不是道德说教。这实际上是关于如何做的。你如何运用权力，你如何做出决定，你如何行事，以及你在自己的价值观方面所体现的真正含义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许我们可以将这些纳入《哈佛商业评论》观众都在苦苦挣扎的问题中。阿迪，你在《哈佛商业评论》上写了很多关于我们在工作场所取得成功需要更多的行为和品质的文章。如果我能让你处于困境的话，你为什么不说出一些名字呢？为了赢得今天的胜利，我们希望我们的同事和队友有哪些行为？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好吧，相信。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;多夫·赛德曼：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信任。好吧，我要把这些写下来。信任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我之前谈到过诸如同理心、脆弱性、承诺之类的事情。我们不是在谈论个人贡献者，而是在谈论团队和公司，因此是共同的承诺和团队意识。请随意添加，这些只是一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些并不是可有可无的，这就是你所拥有的弄清楚今天很重要吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;您刚才没有提到的一些事情是效率、生产力和速度。你在呼唤人类品质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为道德领袖非常清楚改变行为和提升行为之间的区别。因为领导力是关于如何做的。我们如何让人们做事，我们如何在他们身上产生能量，我们如何让他们参与值得他们奉献和忠诚的旅程和任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我要出售产品，我可以获得你现在就买，而不是以后，或者更多而不是更少。如果我们制作一个很棒的政治攻击广告，我可以让你投票左派而不是右派，或者右派而不是左派。我们知道如何使用胡萝卜加大棒来改变或推动行为。如果你给我足够的胡萝卜和大棒，我可以让你更快地工作，也许更少的病假，工作 10 小时而不是 8 小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，阿迪，你所要求的行为，没有多少胡萝卜加大棒可以得到你，因为这是人类以最高尚的方式行事。你能想象对某人说，走进一个房间不要出来，否则如果你不能带着同理心和能力去建立对他人的信任，或者你在脆弱中找到更多的勇气，你就会被解雇。再多的胡萝卜也无法迫使人们做出这些行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我们试试奖金，再多的大棒也无济于事。我们来试试胡萝卜吧。如果你把每个人的工资增加两倍，阿迪，你会得到更多的同理心吗？你会得到更多信任吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你不会。可能不会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们可能会得到相反的结果。我们发现自己正处于领导力的一个不连续的时刻，我们想要从员工身上得到什么，无论有多少胡萝卜和大棒都无法实现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我并不反对大棒。应该有可解雇的罪行。但是，对被解雇的恐惧是否应该影响这个地方 2% 或 98% 的事情发生呢？我也真的很喜欢胡萝卜。我认为我们应该向同事支付尽可能多的工资，并希望比我们的竞争对手支付更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是道德领袖所理解的是，某些行为是不能强迫的。他们无法被激励，只能被激励。有道德的领导者是鼓舞人心的领导者，因为信任、同理心、脆弱性、协作、诚实、勇气，所有这些我们渴望在周围人身上看到的人类高尚品质必须而且只能受到启发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更多的领导者了解不同之处。回到办公室后，我们会看到这种情况的发生。更多的领导知道，如果你是我的下属阿迪，我可以坚持永远不骗我，永远告诉我真相，但我却永远不能坚持，永远忠于我。道德领袖知道，某些事情他们可以坚持，而另一些事情他们必须激发。我们实际上看到了这种情况，谁坚持让人们回到办公室，谁试图激励人们这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导范式确实发生了转变。过去是命令控制，“我是老大”。 “我说，你做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们现在所处的时代需要有同理心的领导者和脆弱的领导者。不久之后可能会出现另一次转变，并出现另一种领导范式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是否有科学依据，或者是否有指标表明这种领导方法不仅在大约 30,000 英尺的高空是正确的道德定义，但也包括机构的成果和绩效？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我们先了解科学和指标，但在我们之前这样做，这就是不会改变的事情。只有两种类型的行为。有什么可以做、什么不能做、什么应该做、什么不应该做。我相信最高法院法官波特·斯图尔特说过，做你有权做的事和做正确的事之间是有区别的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们曾经向人们说明，这就是你可以做的和可以做的不做。然后我们要求他们追求目标和战略，同时考虑到自己能做什么、不能做什么，并且要尽可能快、雄心勃勃，并且必须在此基础上赢得竞争。一位军事将领会说，在那个世界里，只有少数人占领了那座山。首席执行官会说：“这是我们的战略，这是我们的目标。”在那个世界里，每个人的工作就是把下一件事情做好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为当今世界的运作方式，我们希望越来越多的人不仅要做好下一件事情，而且还要做下一个正确的事情。我不认为这种转变会从要求人们做正确的下一件事情转变为激励他们做下一件正确的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;计算机可以通过编程来正确地做下一件事情。只有人类才能做下一件正确的事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为我们现在处于一个规范的环境中，规范就是规范中的，你应该做什么，不应该做什么。道德领袖起床去培育人们“应该有思想”的规范文化，这种文化将一直存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们对文化如此痴迷的原因是企业文化是被发明的，所有文化都是由企业文化创造出来的。发明，将规范从一代人传递到另一代人。规范是我们应该做什么和应该做什么。如果您只是要指定规则、政策和程序，则不需要文化，但如果您要规范化，则需要深思熟虑和有意识地扩展价值观、基于价值观的文化。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;我不认为这是一种时尚。我认为世界已经被重塑，使我们处于规范的环境中。我们在社会、社区和公司中看到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为这是事实。我认为也有一个反驳，也许这只是高层政治反驳，但我觉得历史学家会回顾这个时代，并将其定义为新的独裁统治之一，远离你所认为的一些理想。正在谈论。您认为这准确吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说过领导力与趋势线有关。让我们退后一步。您能说出一位在领导城市方面取得成功的独裁市长吗？你能想象一个专制的首席执行官管理着一家财富 500 强公司吗？你能想象一下在过去 10 年里，在篮球、棒球、足球、世界杯足球赛上赢得的冠军，说出这项运动的名字，通过命令和控制尖叫来运行，那个自上而下的教练吗？普京的独裁统治与泽连斯基的道德领导力之间存在着一场史诗般的战斗。但如果你退后一步，我会发现在许多其他地方的部门和我们生活的各个方面都存在一些关于道德领导力的奇妙趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我提出体育的原因是体育是为了获胜。这是关于成为冠军的事情，而谁在体育运动中获胜是令人难以置信的。我的意思是，金州勇士队的史蒂夫·科尔拥有出色的天赋，但他的竞争对手也是如此。有一年他的背部伤势严重，缺席了 43 场比赛。他甚至不在那里做教练，他们通过基于信任的文化做到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉尔·埃利斯（Jill Ellis），当她作为美国女子足球教练赢得冠军时，她知道她每一位球员的狗和猫。这只是她的教练开始时的个人化程度的象征。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你有&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/01/us-soccers-gregg-berhalter-on-rebuilding-trust-in-the-wake- of-controversy&quot;>;格雷格·伯哈尔特 (Gregg Berhalter) 在你的节目中&lt;/a>;，美国男队在上届世界杯​​上取得了令人难以置信的成功，并希望在下一届世界杯上超越这一点。但如果你听听球员们如何谈论他们在那里建造的东西，你会发现这是一种团结一致的身份。尽管他们是一支非常年轻的团队，但他们试图通过大胆和韧性等品质来超越竞争对手，从而在竞争中脱颖而出。我还有更多例子，但我对这里的一些大趋势非常乐观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;阿迪·伊格纳修斯：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当我问这是否是独裁时代时，部分原因是领导力，在某种程度上，至少是政治领导力，似乎不再感到羞耻。我已经足够大了，我记得理查德·尼克松，尼克松被指控，被弹劾，显然他感到羞耻，在那一刻他决定下台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不确定今天的政治领导人有什么感觉耻辱。如果他们没有这样的感觉，那么你就会为谎言、相反的真理、没有责任感和道德感打开大门。我担心这个。我担心这对于一些政治领导人来说是一个成功的模式，并且可能会激励其他人尝试效仿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我我认为这是一个非常严重的担忧。当你提到尼克松总统时，当他说“我不是骗子”时，他不想让我们认为他是骗子，无论他是否是骗子，他都在庆祝这个常态，“我们不要是骗子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信我们现在生活在一个有罪不罚的时代，一些当权者不仅行为不端，而且还逍遥法外。有罪不罚现象破坏并侵蚀了常态。我们不仅受到高层人士通过他们的行为或邪恶行为造成的伤害，而且你这样做也不受惩罚，说：“我的话很完美，我会再这样做。”或者它们让我们其他人觉得我们在某种程度上是失败者，因为我们想要达到高标准和行为规范。你侵蚀了规范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这就是为什么我们需要道德领袖的一个论点，因为道德领袖维护规范，他们帮助创建真正忠于高规范的组织和社区。&lt;/​​p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;坎耶·韦斯特 (Kanye West) 在与阿迪达斯离婚之前，在网上说了一些可怕的事情和可恨的事情。不管他是不是故意的，我们都可以争论，但他说了。但随后他又说了一件事：阿迪达斯对我无能为力。这是有罪不罚的声明。阿迪达斯通过与之抗争，通过断绝这种关系，最终遭受了数十亿美元的损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们看到的这场战斗不仅涉及不当行为，而且还看到有罪不罚的不当行为以及那些站出来的人&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当我想到道德领袖时，在某些方面我想到的是那些以身作则的人，他只是做正确的事情，你就会意识到这个人是值得信赖的、正直的、鼓舞人心的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在是领导力的新世界。我们在之前的节目中已经讨论过这一点，对于领导者和首席执行官来说，不可避免地需要对与公司不利的社会甚至政治问题做出回应，或者有时与公司无关，但员工和客户要求知道这些问题在哪里领导者站起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顺便说一句，如果没有公开的声明，员工和客户会为您假设并填写这句话。你不妨表明立场。这是一个棘手的领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导者是否有一个框架来管理这个充满永久社会问题的新世界，他们被要求以某种方式声明这些问题？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN ：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也许要和你约会。在电影&lt;em>;毕业生&lt;/em>;中，[一个角色对]达斯汀霍夫曼的角色说，“未来是塑料。”您刚才使用了“Adi”这个词，它是框架的未来。 All human judgment is framework-dependent. The prevailing framework in business is cost-benefit analysis. Now we need to create and scale new frameworks that are normative.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world is so interdependent where the hopes, dreams, plight of one person are showing up viscerally and visually on tiny screens in our hands. I mentioned Kanye West. After his divorce with Adidas, he showed up in the lobby of Sketchers, and before Sketchers knew it, they were involved in a social maelstrom of how to respond to his appearance there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One thing I know for sure that the world has been reshaped in ways to fuse it. Social, environmental, political, human issues, what just happened with the Supreme Court with abortion or how to respond to the invasion of Ukraine: these issues that were once deemed tangential to the business agenda are now inescapably part of it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Neutrality is over. There is an expectation to have a point of view, especially from employees and consumers and other stakeholders. We need a framework for that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pfizer has a great framework. Sally Susman has spoken about it publicly. Does it align with our purpose, given our values, what should our point of view be? How does it impact our constituents? What would be the price of our silence?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tom Wilson has done a great job at Allstate with his framework. There&#39;s a threshold question: “Is what&#39;s going on legal? But even if so, given our values, what should our point of view be? Then if not, let&#39;s continue to challenge these ideas.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think taking a stand is now something where you don&#39;t just get to say, “Hey, I just run a business. The business of business is business.” I think the business of business is society, it&#39;s community, and how we relate to whatever comes our way, and how thoughtfully and principled we are is now the new expectation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanksgiving dinner is coming in a few months and employees are going to sit there and run into their cousins that they haven&#39;t seen in a long time. At the end of the day, a CEO has to ask herself this question, “Are my colleagues going to be proud of Thanksgiving dinner to brag to their cousins about how their company handled this issue and that issue and this issue and that issue that is now part of their business agenda?” We have to pass that Thanksgiving dinner test.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I love that. I also love the future is in frameworks. I want to go to an audience question now, and this is from Srinivas in India. In an era now where artificial intelligence may be better at making decisions based on data than humans are, can we say that the time has come for conscience-based management or leadership?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five hundred years ago we had the scientific revolution, and that was a true revolution. Uber putting yellow taxi cabs in or out of business, LinkedIn maybe making it harder for recruiters, those are disruptions. True revolutions happen about every 500 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the technological revolution and the revolution that&#39;s being accelerated through AI is an every-500-year revolution. 500 years ago, we looked around and we wanted to be in charge of our surroundings and we said, “We&#39;re the smartest.” Descartes said, “I think, therefore I am.” It was 500 years of revenge of the nerds, and we called it the era of enlightenment and reason. We pretty much organized our affairs by being the smartest. It&#39;s incredible what we achieved: modern capitalism, we proliferated individual rights, biodiversity. It&#39;s incredible what was achieved in the last 500 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s interesting about AI is it is challenging our monopoly on intelligence. We&#39;re no longer the smartest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s the one thing a machine will never have? A heart. I actually think the technological revolution is putting into stark relief and focus the imperative to scale that which comes from the heart. There&#39;s an adage of moral leadership that only that which comes from the heart enters the heart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an economic standpoint in the industrial age, we hired hands and we hired strong hands. Then we went into the knowledge or information economy and we hired heads and we favored knowledge and expertise and specialization. I think we&#39;re going into a more human age where the qualities that emanate from the heart, like the ones you mentioned, empathy and the ability to do the right thing in our capacity for ethics and morality and conscience is now something we&#39;re going to have to scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What worries me, Adi, is that when social networks were first launched, we had some utopian thinking, anything that connects the world is going to be great. We will have richer human experiences. Individuals will be empowered. In the first innings we saw pictures of dogs and cats and our acquaintances became close friends again.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But then we started to see that technology is a force for good and bad. Good things can happen and harmful things can happen, including democratic elections being hacked. We saw that we are not just organically divided, but the profit motive has been &amp;nbsp;behind division and people are now pitted against each other and we&#39;re being actively divided through technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those in charge back then often said, “We&#39;re just technology. We&#39;re just a platform.” They proclaimed their moral neutrality. I think, Adi, more important than anything now, we cannot afford with ChatGPT and generative AI to say, “It&#39;s just technology.” We know that good and harmful things are going to happen.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people are talking about the possible end of humanity. The need for Spider-Man ethics, that with great power comes responsibility, has never been more important. I think those who are purveying these new technologies have unprecedented power, and they&#39;re going to need to scale conscience and Spider-Man ethics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;ve been talking mostly about morality and leadership at the highest level, that good leaders have it and people who are selecting good leaders should look for that. This is a question from Shabana from Islamabad in Pakistan. What role do you think leadership development can play in ensuring that individuals throughout an organization embody the same moral values?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s a great question. Moral leadership, there&#39;s an opportunity to build capacities, not skills, but qualities and capacities. And I think organizations can do that. There are some practices we need to scale of moral leadership and I&#39;m happy to mention a few.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to start with the most counterintuitive practice and piece of advice. I think everybody on this gathering would agree that the world&#39;s accelerating, it&#39;s always on. We&#39;re being digitally assaulted. We all experience FOMO, fear of missing out. Fair enough, Adi?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far so good.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The faster the world gets, and the more that comes at us, the more we need to pause. The hallmark of moral leadership is the pause. [Ralph Waldo] Emerson said that, “In each pause, I hear the call,” because only when we pause can we even ask ourselves important questions that a moral leader would ask. “How would I feel like if I were treated this way?” “What&#39;s the consequences of doing it this way or that way?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I like to talk about the four Rs, because in the pause, we can reflect on the challenge, the situation of the world in which we&#39;re operating. We can reconnect with our deeper sense of purpose and our values and conscience. We can rethink some of our assumptions of how we&#39;re operating, how we&#39;re making money, how we&#39;re making decisions. And only then can we reimagine a better solution, or a better path, or a better future. The hallmark of moral leadership is the pause.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral leaders also eschew philosophical mistakes. People think, “Oh, moral leaders must be about empowerment.” Well, that&#39;s true spiritually, but often empowerment, you know what happens? This is how a nonmoral leader might sound, “I push decisions to the front lines. I delegate authority.” And they think they&#39;re leading, and then five years later, everybody has all these rights, “I can spend $1,000 without asking my boss for permission.” “I can get on an airplane to a trade association meeting and spend money without asking for permission.” And you&#39;ve built a culture where everybody knows what rights they have. They&#39;re empowered in that way. But you haven&#39;t built a gym where they know the ethos. “What is the way here?”, where they know what is right.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;[Airbnb CEO] Brian Chesky recently came out against this form of empowerment, and said that he wants to be an orchestrator. Moral leaders don&#39;t just get out of the way and delegate. They show up, and they sit at the back of the room sometimes. They don&#39;t provide the answer. They ask the right questions. So there really are opportunities to be incisive and rigorous about what it is and what it&#39;s not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You&#39;ve identified the hallmarks of moral leadership. I&#39;m curious, as you look out at US companies, global companies, are many of them or most of them run by people you would consider moral leaders?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two things: I think what matters is not to look for beacons. I&#39;ve never seen a unicorn, but I&#39;ve seen a horse. I&#39;ve seen a horn. I&#39;ve seen white. I look for who&#39;s engendering trust by extending it. Who&#39;s creating such a high-trust environment where people feel that they can lean and take risks in order to innovate?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most innovation programs fail because trust is so low that people won&#39;t take the risk in order to innovate. I look not for perfection, and I think what matters most, Adi, is not who&#39;s a beacon and an icon of moral leadership, but who is authentically and deliberately on the journey. Who&#39;s taking risk in that regard? Who&#39;s being courageous in that regard? It&#39;s not about perfection in that way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And maybe I should end with the following: linearity is over in this world. We&#39;re in an up-and-down world, and the leaders who frame the future as a journey really elevate others, because nothing elevates a human beings more than being on a journey of progress, where we go up and down, but we stick together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Increasingly, I&#39;m seeing people have the confidence and the courage to frame that path ahead as a journey, develop an ethos for being on a journey together. I really think that nothing elevates somebody else more than framing the path ahead as a journey and creating an ethos where together, we can journey together, because to journey is to do something human.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s fantastic. Your words are inspiring.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can I say one last thing? Did you ever hear in business, “Hope is not a strategy?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through budgeting, planning, and control, we&#39;re going to superimpose the future, and that&#39;s kind of, “Hope is not a strategy.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Well, I&#39;m also here to say that without hope, there is no strategy. Moral leaders purvey hope, and they inspire hope in others by really helping them see possibility, helping them embrace the commonality in the other, so that we can do things together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral leaders really fight against the non-adage that hope is not a strategy, because they know that without hope, there is no strategy, and they&#39;re prepared to paint a picture of a distant future, but with rigor to go that way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to apologize for not answering your question before about metrics. I&#39;m just going to say the following. Metrics are moral choices. When we measure something, we&#39;re saying it matters. When we don&#39;t measure something, we say it doesn&#39;t matter. Moral leaders pause, and they pick the right metrics that move them on the journey, because they know that metrics don&#39;t come from on high. In and of themselves, they reflect our values.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dov Seidman, thank you for being on “The New World of Work”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adi, great to be with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Web3 Could Change the Business Model of Creative Work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_skizzomat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Skizzomat&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Web3 &amp;#8212; the read-write-own web &amp;#8212; could offer a new model for creative work. By offering new tools to earn and own assets, build wealth, and wrestle back control from powerful platforms and intermediaries, it has the potential to simplify how creators fund their ventures and new ways to earn a living, not just on the first sale of a work of art but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/nfts/earnings&quot;>;perpetuity&lt;/a>; thanks to programmatic royalty streams paid via smart contracts, self-executing code that can move and store money. If Web1 and Web2 democratized access to information and made it easier to collaborate online, Web3 equips creators with a new toolkit to build real wealth from their work, on a globally level playing field.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;For most of the industrial age, technology has acted as a tailwind for creators, powering an age of mass culture that supported a professional class of working artists. However, more recently, the rise of &lt;em>;digital &lt;/em>;technology — specifically, the internet and AI — has become a source of economic dislocation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web1, the so-called “read web,” was a digital printing press that democratized access to information, but it also commoditized art and music and undermined creators&#39; rights as their IP got laundered in the web&#39;s swirling washing machine of content.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web2, the “read-write web,” made it easier to publish content, share ideas and access a broader audience (ie, “write” to the internet) but it also confined creators to tightly run platforms they did not trust or control and where they lacked transparency into the economic impact of their work. Either that or risk the wilderness of the web where their creations could be copied without recourse. Digital artists had no easy way to monetize their creations and could not benefit when works were resold.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platforms that control content distribution have grown richer and more powerful, with precious little of that windfall trickling down to creators. Consider the strikes of the Writers Guild of America (WGA) and the Screen Actors Guild–American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG–AFTRA). Streaming has already shortened television seasons, shrunk writers&#39; rooms, and eroded artists&#39; traditional residual revenues; and generative AI and 3D modeling give companies more tools for further minimizing their use of writers and actors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/05/what-is-web3&quot;>;Web3&lt;/a>; — the read-write-own web — offers new tools to earn and own assets, build wealth, and wrestle back control from powerful platforms and intermediaries. Web3 could simplify how creators fund their ventures by crowdsourcing new titles directly from their fans. It could offer new ways to earn a living, not just on the first sale of a work of art but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/nfts/earnings&quot;>;perpetuity&lt;/a>; thanks to programmatic royalty streams paid via smart contracts, self-executing code that can move and store money. In other words, it might offer a new model for creative work.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;AI: Risk or Opportunity?&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Now, new technologies — namely, generative AI — pose new challenges for composers, screenwriters, visual artists, and other creative workers. It is too early to say whether AI will be all bad for all of them; it may expanding the ranks of professional artists or grow the market for culture and creating opportunities for humans to co-create or collaborate with AI on an equal footing. But it could also starkly devalue the work of copywriters, composers, and artists, and relegate these workers to supporting roles, such as polishing scripts or adding some depth of feeling to digitally rendered art. Cezanne said, “A work of art which did not begin in emotion is not art,” but plenty of studio executives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/disney-creates-task-force-explore-ai-cut-costs-sources-2023-08-08/&quot;>;see AI as a way to cut costs&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By analyzing hundreds of thousands of scripts against their viewership patterns over time, AI will get better at mimicking the stickiest and most bingeworthy of screenwriters&#39; styles, characters, and plots, not just to extend the arcs of existing stories but to synthesize all-new series and recommend the optimal cast or mix of character types. Ditto on the virtual replication of actors, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/indiana-jones-and-the-dial-of-destiny-de-aging-tech/&quot;>;tools like FaceSwap already in use&lt;/a>; to de-age stars like Harrison Ford for his latest portrayal of Indiana Jones. But such big names likely consent to such innovations on their own terms. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/money/2023/8/22/23840473/writers-strike-actors-wga-sag-workers-economy-impact&quot;>;As &lt;em>;Vox&lt;/em>; put it&lt;/a>;, “If people don&#39;t lock down control of their digital twins, then nothing else matters.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oscar winning director Stephen Soderbergh &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/steven-soderbergh-streaming-data-transparency-1235551409/&quot;>;told the &lt;em>;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; that, more than AI or visual effects, what keeps him up at night is the opacity of streaming data: He speculates that the studios are doing really well and don&#39;t want to share the wealth, or else really poorly and don&#39;t want their stocks to tank.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Artists hoped that the internet would help to disintermediate gatekeepers and middlemen, and change power dynamics in creative industries, but instead it added new intermediaries like streamers and platforms that distanced artists from their fans and obfuscated their economic impact. We need something different.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Culture Needs a New Business Model&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If technology is upending the longstanding business model of creative industries, it&#39;s also offering opportunities to establish a new one that can work better for creative workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web3 technologies can simplify how creators track the usage of their IP and to monetize it, ensuring they get paid promptly and fairly for their work. For instance, Web3 technologies could allow artists to grow and perhaps even thrive along with AI, rather than suffer at its expense. For example, smart contracts can create avenues for artists to be compensated when their work is used to train AI like a large language model.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web3 adds an &lt;em>;economic layer&lt;/em>; and a &lt;em>;rights layer&lt;/em>; to the Internet stack, where users can not only track the provenance of information and intellectual property but also protect, manage, and monetize these digital assets themselves with transparency peer to peer. These innovations can also change how creative ventures are funded, removing industry gatekeepers and amplifying underrepresented voices. In the Philippines, independent game studios are selling NFTs of in-game assets to gamers directly to fund new titles, disintermediating big studios and traditional financial backers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Jules Urbach, CEO of cloud graphics company OTOY, Web3 is fit for this purpose. OTOY&#39;s flagship product, OctaneRender, is what&#39;s known as an “unbiased, spatially correct graphics processing unit (GPU) render engine,” which is the industry&#39;s way of describing powerful software that can render more lifelike images and video than what came before. Marvel Studios used OctaneRender in the opening of &lt;em>;Ant-Man and the Wasp&lt;/em>;, according to Urbach.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using the cloud, OTOY is able to harness dozens — and sometimes hundreds — of GPUs at a time in its network to break down projects into smaller parts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By breaking up tasks, OTOY helps democratize the compute-intensive process of rendering, allowing artists to render in a couple of minutes what used to take hours on expensive hardware setups. Most important, anything created in the render network creates a hash on a blockchain, for the verifiable provenance essential to managing artists&#39; IP rights and moving digital goods from platform to platform. With such capabilities, artist guilds could create a set of smart contract templates for their members to use in managing such life-like renderings of themselves — their digital twins — and collect privatized data on industry usage that would give them bargaining power in future negotiations. The contracts could represent the artist guilds&#39; negotiated terms, plus whatever the individual artists or their agents have negotiated.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;From Hollywood to Everywhere&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This technology also offers artists ways to flip the traditional top-down model where studios and streamers try to control everything from IP to distribution. Hollywood screenwriter Jessie Nickson-Lopez has brought some of modern TV&#39;s most indelible characters to life. As a founding member of the writing team on &lt;em>;Stranger Things&lt;/em>;, she developed the story line for the character Eleven. Recently, as cofounder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mv3.io/&quot;>;Web3 startup MV3&lt;/a>;, she launched a collection of 6,500 non-fungible tokens (NFTs) of different characters, the building blocks for what will be a richly rendered narrative “universe,” originally created by Nickson-Lopez and her team. Set in the “dystopian cyberpunk society” of 2081, after the “climate has gone to hell,” MV3 focuses on “a ragtag group of idealistic” rebels struggling to “take power from the corporation that owns the city.” NFT owners will participate in the IP, have a say in their character&#39;s arc, and even co-create the story with the MV3 team. These different character assets could ultimately appear in film, TV, and other storytelling media. They could be playable characters in videogames or avatars in the metaverse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing that fans will support a project is key for firing up the Hollywood machine to spend $100 million or more on a film or TV show. Nickson-Lopez said, “So we reverse-engineered it, and I created the world of Eluna City and the characters that reside in it.” Though Nickson-Lopez architected this world and crafted story lines for main characters, MV3 will not decide the direction of the story. “For me, what&#39;s been most exciting is seeing how much creativity we&#39;re inspiring in people who have never created before but are consumers of dystopian worlds and of fiction. There&#39;s this hunger to play. Our fans are our community and our co-creators. Because they&#39;re invested in the world and in the characters, they&#39;re really excited to build it up with us.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MV3 inverts the Hollywood model. “As my lawyers say, &#39;It&#39;s like you&#39;re ripping off pieces of value and just giving it to people.&#39; And we&#39;re like, &#39;Exactly! That&#39;s exactly what we&#39;re doing.&#39;” Recently, the founders handed control day-to-day control of the MV3 universe to the community.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Ultimately, projects like OctaneRender and MV3 will work because they engage their communities not only in the economic upside but also in the governance. Handing over control and economics to fans is antithetical to the Hollywood model, and Nickson-Lopez recognizes that. Engaging people in the creative process, for love of the experience and not just for money, is what clearly drives these creators and gives their projects purpose and meaning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology tools and human capital are more distributed than ever. If Web1 and Web2 democratized access to information and made it easier to collaborate online, Web3 equips creators with a new toolkit to build real wealth from their work, on a globally level playing field. As the saying goes, the future is not to be predicted; it is to be achieved. For cultural industries and much else, Web3 can help us do it.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Software Companies Can Avoid the Trap of Product-Led Growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-software-companies-can-avoid-the-trap-of-product-led-growth]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_1603508378.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;designer491/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Companies like Slack and Dropbox have pioneered the use of Product-Led Growth (PLG). They start by building a product that&amp;#8217;s indispensable for small teams, then count on low friction and customer advocates to expand throughout the organization. PLG works, at least at first. But it can create challenges for growing companies. The answer isn&amp;#8217;t to reject PLG. It&amp;#8217;s to embrace it &amp;#8212; but to plan ahead. Eventually, even the best PLG company will need an enterprise sales strategy which takes years to develop. Don&amp;#8217;t wait until product-led growth stalls to plan for a multi-pronged sales strategy.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-software-companies-can-avoid-the-trap-of-product-led-growth?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-software-companies-can-avoid-the-trap-of-product-led-growth?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Enterprise tech companies usually grow by investing in a costly sales and marketing operation, suffering through long, expensive sales cycles. Eventually, if it works, their software is adopted “top down” throughout an enterprise. That approach is tried-and-true, but it&#39;s not the one that Dropbox or Slack followed. Over the last decade, those companies and many others have pioneered a disruptive new business model that is taking over the $250 billion software-as-a-service market. It&#39;s called Product-Led Growth (PLG).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The PLG playbook is elegant in its simplicity: First, build a compelling product that is indispensable to end-users. Then, encourage widespread internal usage with zero friction and increasingly add value for those individual end-users. Finally, leverage internal champions and their case studies to approach corporate buyers in IT to purchase the product for company-wide use. One of us, Oliver, executed this strategy successfully as a sales leader at both Dropbox and Asana.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to building initial traction, the merits of the PLG model are clear. A recent Bain &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bain.com/insights/what-it-really-takes-to-develop-product-led-growth/&quot;>;study&lt;/a>; showed that PLG companies in the past few years had generally experienced higher revenue and market share growth compared to non-PLG companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is a catch. Companies that follow the PLG playbook risk getting stuck in what we call the PLG trap. Although the PLG approach yields rapid initial adoption and growth, scaling a PLG company is a different story. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomtunguz.com/plg-less-profitable/&quot;>;A recent analysis&lt;/a>; showed that public companies that initially pursued a PLG model are actually 5–10% less profitable compared to their sales-led counterparts — implying that many PLG companies, despite initially benefiting from superior unit economics, actually lose efficiency as they scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ambitious managers of software companies, the lesson is not to avoid taking a PLG approach. Instead, embrace PLG as an initial strategy, but commit to winning the enterprise over the long term. Plan ahead and you can avoid the PLG Trap.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Understanding the PLG Trap&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Eventually, scaling an enterprise tech company will require classic enterprise sales. But adding enterprise sales as part of a multi-pronged approach to growth isn&#39;t like flipping a switch. It takes years to craft and execute an enterprise product roadmap and go-to-market strategy. PLG companies that neglect this approach early on will, unfortunately, find themselves stuck once they&#39;ve tapped the pool of initial bottoms-up users. Very few companies have demonstrated an ability to escape the PLG Trap once they become stuck.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The PLG Trap creates a common and natural dilemma for SaaS executives and boards, for several reasons:&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;In building a great product that is appealing to end-users, companies optimize their product and support organizations for small teams.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;When expansion opportunities emerge, companies add the bare minimum feature set (such as additional security, reporting, and administrative features) to drive initial adoption from classic early adopter customers.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Success with these early adopters inspires the company to quickly scale up an outbound enterprise sales and marketing team to execute this top-down, sales-led motion.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;The company then realizes they&#39;re trapped in a chasm: the early adopters found the minimum feature set adequate, but the majority of the market does not. Meanwhile, the customer support team is not accustomed to servicing large enterprises and the marketing team has been targeting small end users, not senior IT executives. The PLG company is not truly “enterprise ready” on a product or organizational level. Sales stall.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p>;A PLG company makes each decision logically along the way — but each decision may be a step deeper into the PLG Trap. Many companies find themselves trapped around the Series C stage — about 200-400 employees — but the principles apply to larger, public companies as well. For example, Dropbox has seen steadily declining year-over-year revenue growth from 25% in 2018 to only 8% in 2023 due to a failure to make this transition. Seamlessly transitioning from a PLG to an enterprise company, by avoiding the PLG Trap, requires deliberate planning from an early stage.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Avoiding the PLG trap&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To become fully enterprise-ready, a PLG company must simultaneously provide bottom-up value and be prepared to eventually deliver value at enterprise-scale. Here are three activities a PLG company must do to seamlessly evolve from a PLG-only to a PLG + enterprise company that can avoid the trap:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Create communities of champions across multiple levels in the customer organization.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The most successful PLG companies take inspiration from successful open-sourced companies and nurture community-building as a long-term, must-win, competitive advantage. Building an advocacy program becomes a core competency from an early stage, even before investing in monetization. It&#39;s important to note that PLG companies need to build multi-tiered community programs to appeal to multiple stakeholders, unlike sales-led companies that can primarily focus on developing executive champions. PLG companies must develop champions on the end-user, IT, and executive levels, with each level likely requiring a different approach to community building.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Build a go-to-market plan (GTM) that incorporates multiple sales motions.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Successful PLG companies may start with one GTM motion, but eventually they build multiple GTM motions to capture different types of customer opportunities. Unlike sales-led organizations, which are often segmented by customer size (ie, SMB vs. Enterprise), PLG companies are often segmented by selling motions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most popular motions PLG companies build include:&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;self-service&lt;/em>;: an e-commerce experience that generates demand and captures end-users to land in organizations&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;high-velocity sales&lt;/em>;: a data-driven sales motion that uses modern customer relationship management (CRM) tools, automated workflows, and analytical segmentation to identify and convert organizations with higher willingness to pay,&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;expansion sales: &lt;/em>;a capability focusing on transitioning organizations with strong product usage to adopt the product company-wide, and&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;outbound sales: &lt;/em>;an outbound motion targeting senior executives at prospects that may not have as much organic product adoption.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;h3>;Deliver product value across multiple levels, including at enterprise scale.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;PLG companies often begin by providing value to end-users or small teams. The bottoms-up adoption fuels viral adoption of the product in organizations. As PLG companies scale, they must also deliver product value to centralized buying personas like IT and executives. To address IT, many PLG companies develop an enterprise version with greater administration and security capabilities. To appeal to executives, some PLG companies, like the database software company MongoDB, naturally deliver enterprise-scale value due to the nature of the product. Other PLG companies, especially those on the application layer, may need to build, acquire or package adjacent products that deliver value on an enterprise scale. HubSpot has done this very effectively, graduating from a lightweight and narrow blogging tool to a fulsome CRM useful for larger enterprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Case Study: MongoDB&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The database software company, MongoDB is an example of a company that successfully avoided the PLG Trap, despite starting with a bottoms-up sales motion. (One of us, Jeff, is a partner at a venture capital firm that invested in MongoDB.) With over $1 billion in sales, the company has nearly 2,000 customers spending over $100,000 per year on its software. Yet the company&#39;s origins are as an open-source tool that end users could download for free.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Released in 2009, the company&#39;s initial product — an open source, document-based database tuned for the rise of Internet applications and the era of big data — attracted millions of downloads. As the company grew in popularity among large enterprise customers such as Goldman Sachs and Thermo, it built advanced security features and invested in dramatic scalability in order to earn its way into the enterprise. In parallel, MongoDB created an enterprise-ready sales force, marketing team, and customer success function.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whereas in early 2015, the company had just over 100 customers with over $100,000 per year, by late 2023 that figure had grown 20x. At the same time as it re-engineered the organization to be enterprise-ready, with multiple sales motions, a flexible product configuration, and a large investment in fostering its end-user community. By building both an enterprise-ready organization and a community-driven organization, MongoDB has scaled smoothly beyond the PLG trap to become one of the largest software companies in the world. As of this writing, the product has been downloaded more than 265 million times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By planning ahead, PLG companies can make the necessary strategic decisions to build a team and product platform that is truly enterprise-ready. The PLG model is seductively simple. Winning software companies need to be willing to embrace complexity — expanding beyond the typical managerial advice to “do one thing and do it well” and instead succeed in chewing gum and walking at the same time.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Types of Stories Leaders Need to Tell]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/5-types-of-stories-leaders-need-to-tell]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_1417699431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;horstgerlach/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Storytelling is an important leadership skill, and executives who want to succeed should master five types of narrative: Vision stories, which inspire a shared one; values stories that model the way; action stories that spark progress and change; teaching stories that transmit knowledge and skills to others; and trust stories that help people understand, connect with, and believe in you.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/5-types-of-stories-leaders-need-to-tell?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/5-types-of-stories-leaders-need-to-tell?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The historian Doris Kearns Goodwin was once asked what questions she would put to Abraham Lincoln if given the chance. “I feel like a bad historian,” she answered, “but I&#39;d probably ask him to tell me a story.” As she herself has documented, the 16&lt;sup>;th&lt;/sup>; US president was not just a great political leader but also a masterful raconteur, who used stories to entertain, educate, and inspire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Storytelling is an important leadership skill. As psychologists Gordon H. Bower and Michal C. Clark of Stanford first observed in 1969, we&#39;re 7 times more likely to remember a fact when it&#39;s wrapped in story. Telling stories can also help with all five of the effective leadership practices that Santa Clara University professors James M. Kouzes and Barry Z. Posner lay out in their book &lt;em>;The Leadership Challenge&lt;/em>;: 1) model the way, 2) inspire a shared vision, 3) challenge the process, 4) enable others to act, and 5) encourage the heart&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>; But it&#39;s important to learn which types of stories lead to which outcomes. Here&#39;s a primer.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Trust Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;As noted in The Moth book, &lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://themoth.org/how-to-tell-a-story&quot;>;How to Tell a Story&lt;/a>;, &lt;/em>;“When you choose to share your story, you share a piece of yourself.”&amp;nbsp;In so doing, you start to build trust and connect in new ways with your listeners. Trust stories humanize you as a leader and allow you to &lt;em>;encourage the heart&lt;/em>; of your team.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thasunda Brown Duckett, president and CEO of TIAA, &lt;a href=&quot;https://luvvie.org/podcast/thasunda-brown-duckett/&quot;>;connects her memories&lt;/a>; of being the only Black girl on the soccer team not invited to a teammate&#39;s birthday party to often being the only woman and person of color in a meeting. When you demonstrate vulnerability by sharing a personal story, others will be inspired to reciprocate, creating a virtuous circle of trust.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Teaching Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Brené Brown defines a leader as “anyone who sees potential in people and has the courage to develop that potential.” Great leaders need to be great teachers. Stories allow you to simplify complex topics by providing easy-to-follow models for behavior and skills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As chairman, president, and CEO of Lowe&#39;s, Marvin Ellison uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/03/08/1085285796/lowes-marvin-ellison&quot;>;stories from his life to teach&lt;/a>; his team. Early in his career, when he worked at Target, a senior leader from corporate visited his store and asked employees for feedback. When no one spoke up, Ellison volunteered that a new system wasn&#39;t working as intended. In the end, the system was fixed and Ellison was recognized for speaking up. Now, he tells this story when visiting Lowe&#39;s locations as a way of &lt;em>;enabling others to act &lt;/em>;with candor and promoting a feedback-driven culture.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While a trust story is built around you, a teaching story and the other three types can also be an indirect narrative — using someone else&#39;s story, a fictional one, or a parable to deliver your message. Just make sure your audience can identify and empathize with the protagonist so they want the same thing for themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Action Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A big part of a leader&#39;s job is to inspire action — and one of the best ways to do that is through an story that leaves the audience thinking, “If we do this (insert your desired action here), then we will get that (the desired result).”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entrepreneurs can use action stories to launch new business ideas. Canva founder and CEO Melanie Perkins dreamed of making graphic design accessible. To do this, she needed to create a new story for investors. “People are scared of designing,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2021/02/26/971813519/canva-melanie-perkins-2019&quot;>;Perkins&lt;/a>;. “They&#39;re conditioned their whole lives to think that they&#39;re not creative.” Early success stories included people completing simple design challenges and creating resumes that helped them land jobs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Action stories can also be used to inspire organizational change. Former CEO Indra Nooyi used story to &lt;em>;challenge the process &lt;/em>;at PepsiCo, shifting a product portfolio that was primarily sugar-based to something more health conscious. She wanted to maintain the sense of fun but ensure that it was also good for you. “Words that speak to people&#39;s hearts are more important than speaking to their minds,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/podcasts/worklife/taken-for-granted-indra-nooyi-says-its-time-for-leaders-to-care-part-2-transcript&quot;>;Nooyi shares&lt;/a>;. She developed an indirect narrative to get buy-in from her board, using story to illustrate emerging trends of evolving consumer tastes.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Values Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If you want your team to buy into your organizational values, tell a story that shows someone living into them as a means of &lt;em>;modeling the way&lt;/em>; for them to do so as well.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, to model the family-first mindset at Zoom, founder and CEO Eric Yuan often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/insights/eric-yuan-keeping-customers-employees-happy&quot;>;tells a story&lt;/a>; about being late to the company Christmas party because he was traveling with his son&#39;s basketball team. Chobani&#39;s CEO and founder Hamdi Ulukaya frequently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/podcasts/rethinking-with-adam-grant/anti-ceo-playbook-with-chobani-founder-hamdi-ulukaya-transcript&quot;>;shares tales&lt;/a>; of growing up amid corruption in Turkey and explains how it made him want to become a more ethical business leader. These stories communicate personal and organizational values and encourage values-driven behavior in others.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Vision Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;History is full of examples of leaders using vision stories. Following the evacuation at Dunkirk, Winston Churchill vividly described a Britain that would “fight on the seas and oceans” and “never surrender.” In his iconic “I Have a Dream” speech, Martin Luther King, Jr. used story to paint a picture of a world in which “man would not be judged by the color of his skin but the content of his character.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In business, GM CEO Mary Barra &lt;a href=&quot;/podcast/2021/05/ceo-series-mary-barra-of-general-motors-on-committing-to-an-eco-friendly-future&quot;>;uses story&lt;/a>; to illustrate a future with “zero crashes, zero emissions, and zero congestion.” In taking the reins as the first non-founder CEO at Microsoft, Satya Nadella needed to shift the culture internally from being “know-it-alls” to “learn-it-alls.” To promote the “learn-it-all” mindset, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/podcasts/satya-nadella-is-building-the-future-transcript&quot;>;Nadella shared a story about his dad&lt;/a>;. “He had this diary he would write in every day — people met, ideas generated to act on. It&#39;s a continuous system.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stories make the unseen future feel vivid and real, &lt;em>;inspiring a shared vision&lt;/em>; that listeners will commit to and make progress toward.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Kouzes and Posner&#39;s title implies, leadership is a challenge. But story can help with all five practices of effective leadership. Vision stories inspire a shared one. Values stories model the way. Action stories can spark change and, in turn, challenge the process. Teaching stories transmit knowledge and skills to others, enabling them to act. And when you share your own story you build trust and encourage the heart.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the Food Industry Is Using Cross-Training to Boost Service]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-the-food-industry-is-using-cross-training-to-boost-service]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_1137557948.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff; Mesut Ugurlu/Getty Images; Unsplash&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Cross-training employees on a variety of tasks can be a powerful tool for improving operations, as well as for attracting and retaining workers. When employees are cross-trained to perform a variety of both customer-facing and non-customer-facing tasks, they can adjust their work depending on demand and business needs. Of course, that&amp;#8217;s good for the business, but it also makes the job better for workers. For one thing, when employees are more productive and contribute more, companies can pay them more. Cross-training helps employees build capabilities that they can leverage in their career growth. It also enables more stable schedules. This article shows how several small food companies were able to use cross-training to improve service and job quality. Any industry can learn from these approaches to improve operations, customer experience, and employee experience.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-the-food-industry-is-using-cross-training-to-boost-service?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-the-food-industry-is-using-cross-training-to-boost-service?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;People are dining out again, but restaurants aren&#39;t always &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/30/dining/restaurant-prices-service.html?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Issue:%202023-05-30%20Restaurant%20Dive%20%5Bissue:50879%5D&amp;amp;utm_term=Restaurant%20Dive&quot;>;able to serve them well&lt;/a>;. Like many other service businesses, they face two operational challenges: attracting and retaining enough workers, and coping with highly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/chain-restaurant-local-restaurant-closing-11673616374&quot;>;variable demand&lt;/a>;. One lever for improving on both counts is cross-training — that is, training employees for a variety of tasks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cross-training is a powerful tool, but it is far from a new idea: One of us (Zeynep) first observed cross-training as part of a &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/11/the-case-for-good-jobs&quot;>;“good jobs system”&lt;/a>; that enabled low-cost retailers like Costco and Trader Joe&#39;s to pay more than their competitors while driving better value for customers. Beyond the service industry, manufacturers like Toyota have &lt;a href=&quot;/1999/09/decoding-the-dna-of-the-toyota-production-system&quot;>;long practiced&lt;/a>; cross-training to improve motivation and involve the frontlines in continuous improvement. And in their landmark &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/0030507376900167&quot;>;1976 study&lt;/a>;, J. Richard Hackman and Greg R. Oldham identified task variety as a driver of employee motivation across a variety of industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When employees are cross-trained to perform a variety of both customer-facing and non-customer-facing tasks, they can adjust their work depending on demand and business needs. Of course, that&#39;s good for the business, but it also makes the job a &lt;em>;better&lt;/em>; job for workers. For one thing, when employees are more productive and contribute more, companies can pay them more; higher productivity is what enables a typical Costco worker to earn &lt;a href=&quot;https://s201.q4cdn.com/287523651/files/doc_events/2023/Jan/19/costco-annual-shareholders&#39;-meeting-slide-deck-jan2023.pdf&quot;>;almost $10 an hour&lt;/a>; more than a typical retail worker. Cross-training helps employees build capabilities that they can leverage in their career growth and career paths. Cross-training also enables more stable schedules; instead of changing the number of workers throughout the day or week, companies can keep more consistent teams and just change &lt;em>;what&lt;/em>; they do, instead of changing &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>; is scheduled to work.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;But these benefits should be balanced with a possible downside: a lack of specialization and ownership. At the Good Jobs Institute, our work with a variety of small food businesses has shown us how they can make the best use of cross-training to improve service and job quality. Any industry can learn from these approaches to design flexibility into their job design and operations.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Approaches to Cross-Training at Three Small Food Businesses&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Employees don&#39;t have to be cross-trained to do everything, but a little bit of cross-training can go a long way. Three small food businesses we&#39;ve worked with have each found their own way to balance flexibility with specialization and ownership:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Counter service&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At two franchised locations of the Moe&#39;s Original BBQ chain, there was a strict boundary between front-of-house and kitchen teams, making it difficult to adjust to demand peaks. Owner Dewey Hasbrouck introduced cross-training between the two specialized teams so that they could cover each other on typical bottleneck tasks. For instance, when there were long lines at the counter, kitchen staff could now step in to answer the phones, bring food out to tables, and bag to-go orders. If it was the kitchen that was backlogged, the front-of-house team could fill sauce cups, restock the line, and prepare basic sides.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Bakery&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At She Wolf Bakery, the production team baked bread in the bakery and the sales team sold it at New York City Greenmarkets, seldom interacting. The teams were often busy at different times: the production team would be overwhelmed preparing bread on Fridays, while the sales team was busiest on Saturdays.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Head of operations Kim Vallejo realized there was an opportunity to better integrate the two teams. While bakers were already being trained on some of the packing duties, She Wolf also started offering a four-hour paid bakery orientation for new sales team members, during which they could take part in the bread-making process. They learned basic bakery side work like running the dish pit and oiling pans, which were very helpful to bakers during a rush, and the two teams also got to know each other better, which made them more motivated to help each other out.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Full service&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Tacombi, a Mexican restaurant chain with locations in New York City, introduced cross-training while navigating the city&#39;s strict tipping regulations, which don&#39;t allow employees in non-tipped roles to perform customer-facing tasks. The staff in their full-service concepts included many highly specialized roles, such as hosts, runners, bussers, and servers in the front, and dishwashers, prep cooks, quality control leaders (who manage the kitchen flow and check quality), and chefs in the back.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Operations leader Jose De La Campa noticed that scheduling these specialists was very complex and created service issues when someone called out sick. The work wasn&#39;t evenly distributed over time; at any given moment, the prep cooks might have nothing to do while the dish washers were swamped. But they were neither trained nor expected to help each other. De La Campa decided to reduce the number of specialist job codes; for example, in most restaurants, he combined the responsibilities of prep cooks and dishwashers, combined the roles of head chef and quality control leader, and removed the host role, redistributing that work to the other front-of-house positions, such as servers.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;The Impact of Cross-Training on Performance and Jobs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When employees can contribute to different parts of the business, it can improve service, increase production capacity, and make jobs better for the people doing them.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Better service&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At She Wolf, cross-training helped teams take more ownership to keep production running when faced with the unexpected variability of call outs, so they could always be there for their customers with quality bread. According to Vallejo, “If we are in the weeds and down three people and it&#39;s a Friday and all hands on deck, my delivery driver knows how to run the dish pit and they can jump back there and help us get ahead.” Training market team members on basic prep tasks also freed up bakers&#39; time to focus on higher-value tasks, ensuring bread quality didn&#39;t suffer due to unexpected variability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Tacombi relied on highly specialized roles, an absent dishwasher could paralyze operations. With fewer specialist roles and appropriate cross-training, an unexpected sick day could more easily be absorbed by the rest of the team. De La Campa also said that it improved the food and service: The head chef now had more ownership over quality control, motivating them to identify issues and provide proper feedback to the rest of the team.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Higher production capacity&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At Moe&#39;s Original BBQ, because team members could flex into different customer-facing and non-customer-facing tasks, they had enough slack to deal with demand peaks. This translated to higher-quality food and service. More significantly, the cross-trained team had the expertise to take on more catering orders. Catering sales increased by 60% in the first year, without Moe&#39;s having to significantly change its staffing levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Better jobs&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;All three businesses ended up raising pay. Their cross-trained employees were more productive and could contribute to more areas of the operation, making higher pay a good investment. Cross-training created a new talent pipeline for She Wolf: By allowing the market staff to get production experience, management could identify potential new bakers and help them make the transition onto the bakery team when they needed to hire. For those employees, this meant career growth and higher wages. Cross-training also helped these businesses give their people better — that is, more regular — schedules, since staffing didn&#39;t necessarily have to lurch up and down with the number of customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cross-training helped make the work more meaningful. At Moe&#39;s Original BBQ, cross-training contributed to better communication and a sense of belonging: The staff started insisting that they be referred to as “one team,” not “front-of-house” and “back-of-house.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The combination of higher pay, better schedules, and better work helped Moe&#39;s Original BBQ reduce employee turnover by 30%, which then helped them improve their performance even more.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Why Cross-Training Isn&#39;t More Common&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Many company leaders like the idea of cross-training, but aren&#39;t convinced it will work for them. Some think their employees can&#39;t handle — or aren&#39;t motivated to learn — a variety of roles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One genuine risk is that introducing cross-training &lt;em>;in isolation&lt;/em>; could create operational problems; if employees are already overloaded or have low tenure, or if the company can&#39;t set and enforce high expectations, introducing cross-training might lead to more errors and frustration. The key is creating &lt;em>;a system that enables cross-training. &lt;/em>;At the small food businesses, this involved some complementary choices:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Simplifying operations to remove non-value-add work so that employees only spend their time learning tasks that improve the customer experience.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Simplifying operations to reduce &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/give-service-workers-stable-schedules&quot;>;self-inflicted variability&lt;/a>;&amp;nbsp;— that is, to smooth the workload and make the peaks more manageable.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Setting clear standards to ensure that employees can be consistent in different roles.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Empowering employees to use their judgment to decide which tasks to do when.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Staffing with slack so that people have enough time to learn new tasks.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Investing in people to attract and retain great staff and hold teams accountable to high expectations.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Moe&#39;s Original BBQ had been trying to introduce cross-training for several years, but because of high turnover, it was a struggle just to get employees through basic training. So, in addition to cross-training, owner Hasbrouck made other operational changes to set his team up for success, such as simplifying the menu and smoothing the workload by moving specials from weekends to weekdays. He also made significant investments in his people, increasing full-time pay from $15 an hour to $20 an hour in Maine, plus tips. Higher pay came, however, with higher expectations: Hasbrouck changed the job description to state, “We want employees capable of doing it all.” Adding cross-training made the job worth more to the business and the higher pay made the additional responsibility and higher expectations worth it for employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Changes like these don&#39;t happen overnight, but a better system can drive operational excellence and let teams live up to their potential. Food businesses and other service industries are facing headwinds, but cross-training can ensure that they are up for the challenge, providing better service while also improving the lives of their employees and preserving vibrant businesses in their communities.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Video Quick Take: SAP&rsquo;s Aaron Green on Building the Brightest Talent Pools in the Tightest Labor Market - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/video-quick-take-saps-aaron-green-on-building-the-brightest-talent-pools-in-the-tightest-labor-market]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div data-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;6337163366112&amp;quot;}&quot; js-target=&quot;video-player-page&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;Loading... &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Julie Devoll&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Welcome to today&#39;s HBR Quick Take. I&#39;m Julie Devoll, editor for special projects and webinars at HBR. Today we&#39;re speaking with Aaron Green, who is the chief marketing and solutions officer at SAP SuccessFactors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hey, Julie. Thanks for having me here.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Julie Devoll&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Hi, Aaron. Thank you so much for joining us today. Let&#39;s get started.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Organizations today are facing many challenges, whether it&#39;s shifting market dynamics or labor shortages. How can they set themselves up to succeed in today&#39;s environment, with an eye toward the future? What are some of the roadblocks? And how do they move forward?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah, absolutely. Julie, I think probably the number one thing or challenge that&#39;s facing organizations today is really around the skills gap itself. And it&#39;s something that all our customers are really concerned about. In fact, skills are the new and future currency of work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And what this fundamentally means is we need to rethink the way in which we both retain and attract talent and look for the right skills at the right times in the organization. In a recent survey, more than 75% of business leaders said that hiring and retaining talent is the number one most critical factor for achieving growth. And we know that our people are the most valuable asset that any organization has. And our people are what allow us to innovate, compete, and grow.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So what this means for an organization is that we have to be able to understand the skills that we have today, but also understand the skills that are needed in the future. And build plans to upskill, cross-skill, reskill, and, in some cases, bring in those skills from the outside market. This is really the way that any company, but especially a growth or scale-up company, needs to be thinking about how they look at talent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Julie Devoll&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I want to switch a little bit to tools and processes. When an organization commits to using different tools to share insights and intelligence across all its practices, how do employees experience that change?&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah. So we know that in order to deliver an extraordinary customer experience or a customer outcome, you really have to have an extraordinary employee experience—an employer and employee value proposition—because when you do this, and when you really focus on your people, your people end up having more meaningful work experiences. And these translate into higher productivity and a better customer experience in whatever industry or geography you&#39;re in.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this really means that you have to have real-time insights into your total workforce across all worker types, including your contingent labor, because these insights allow you to really unlock the understanding of the skills that your workforce has, their aspirations, their work preferences, and how they&#39;re performing. And it really allows an organization to match that up to the workforce of the future and ensure that your people understand the path to whatever the future growth plans are for the organization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Julie Devoll&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I want to look ahead to the future. How do you envision artificial intelligence and automation helping organizations boost these insights and efficiencies in ways they can&#39;t really do right now?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah. So there&#39;s definitely no question that AI is a super-hot topic at the moment. And we&#39;re really privileged at SAP SuccessFactors, with over 9,600 customers and working with over 250 million unique users every day. And our customers are talking to us about AI all the time. And in fact, in a recent research study that we did, we found that recruiting and learning are two of the highest-priority areas for organizations to think about how they invest in AI to really automate many of the manual tasks that are required today.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there are emerging use cases, things like chatbots for more complex administrative tasks or HR self-service or ticketing, but also AI to drive some of that internal mobility that we&#39;ve talked about, looking at skills profiles and career paths, and using this to actually match people to opportunities inside the organization, whether they&#39;re short-term roles or gigs or longer-term roles. But fundamentally, what this means is that AI-powered talent intelligence platforms are going to become more critical than ever for all organizations, both for HR and for the broader employee base.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Julie Devoll&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Well, Aaron, this has been a great conversation. I want to thank you so much for joining us today.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks for having me.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.375509780;dc_trk_aid=566751408;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Learn More.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Aaron Green is SAP SuccessFactors&#39; chief marketing &amp;amp; solutions officer.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 04:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Growth-Focused Organizations Can Meet the Needs of a Shifting Workforce - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/how-growth-focused-organizations-can-meet-the-needs-of-a-shifting-workforce]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364386&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/HR_OPT1.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;By Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s competitive landscape, employees are what set organizations apart. Their unique skills, experiences, and contributions help companies innovate, compete, and grow.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the pace at which technology and innovation are introduced, though, the skills organizations need are constantly changing. In fact, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development estimates that technology will disrupt &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/06/build-a-strong-learning-culture-on-your-team#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20OECD%2C%201.1,do%20new%20types%20of%20work).&quot;>;1.1 billion jobs&lt;/a>; in the next five years—making the skills gap one of the biggest hurdles growth-focused organizations face today.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Addressing those gaps starts with figuring out what skills you need now and in the future and whether you should acquire them by hiring alone or by upskilling, cross-skilling, and reskilling your current employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a skills-based approach is how all organizations—especially growth-focused organizations—need to look at talent. But to make this possible, you need technology that&#39;s built for the job. Without it, HR and recruiting teams lack integrated, real-time data frameworks, meaning that they are making decisions based more on gut instinct than on data-driven evidence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering the many challenges growth-focused organizations face today—such as rapidly changing market conditions, the need to keep employees productive and engaged, and the race to attract top talent—having the right HR technology in place to meet the evolving needs of your business and your people can be a game changer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A connected cloud HR and enterprise resource planning (ERP) approach helps free that data from silos, so all departments can access the same people data in real time. This boosts efficiency and productivity, cuts operational costs and noncompliance risk, improves people&#39;s experiences at work, and helps organizations get people with the needed skills into the right roles.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Putting People at the Heart of Your Business Transformation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investing in this technology means investing in your people—and people are what drive business transformation. Today, people expect an employee experience (EX) where every interaction is as easy, seamless, and personalized as it is when they go shopping online. By using technology to enhance EX—from automating time-consuming processes to offering personalized learning recommendations—people have more meaningful work experiences, which translates into a more engaged workforce, higher productivity, and better business outcomes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/asset/dynamic/2022/08/ed4692e7-32d5-49e9-9240-a0a2dc2f8909.html&quot;>;MOD Pizza&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/07/cc941e1e-ee7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Growmark&lt;/a>;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/10/54f5d640-fd7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Sun Communities&lt;/a>; are great examples of how focusing on people by strengthening the connection between HR and business operations can help drive growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To eliminate friction in the hiring and onboarding process and enable new hires to become productive faster, the HR team at MOD Pizza determined that it needed to replace siloed people data and manual processes with scalable, cloud-based technology.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moving to a single cloud platform for both HR and ERP helped MOD Pizza automate the onboarding of 1,000 hires each month and 400 daily event changes related to new hires, promotions, and separations—resulting in 15 fewer hours of manual data entry each week.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company has also integrated survey touchpoints across the hiring and onboarding experience to gather feedback during this important stage of the employee life cycle. This connected approach is helping MOD Pizza gain efficiencies across the business while improving EX.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The agribusiness cooperative &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/07/cc941e1e-ee7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Growmark&lt;/a>; manages HR for an internal workforce of 3,600 and provides payroll support for an additional 4,200 employees at its member companies. Streamlining its HR and ERP operations by moving to a cloud-based solution helped Growmark integrate management processes, improve visibility across the business, and automate manual tasks. Analytics combining people and operational data helps ensure Growmark keeps its employees at the center of performance tracking, risk planning, and decision making.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/10/54f5d640-fd7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Sun Communities&lt;/a>;, a leading owner and operator of manufactured housing communities and recreational vehicle resorts, transformed its business processes by replacing a patchwork of legacy tools with an integrated cloud-based solution. This helps its HR staff streamline the management of processes and experiences across recruiting, onboarding, performance management, and payroll—without having to rely on internal IT resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Growth-focused organizations like these need to ensure their HR systems, experiences, and strategies are not operating in a disconnected state. The ideal platform brings together the talent, demographic, experience, and operational data an organization needs to inform its HR, finance, supply chain, and customer decisions. With this connectivity, organizations can also replace legacy and inefficient processes with end-to-end automated business processes and improved experiences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With real-time insight into your total workforce and an understanding of the resulting impacts on your business, you can unlock new opportunities for both your business and your people. You gain insights into your employees&#39; skills, aspirations, preferences, and performance. This view enables an unprecedented alignment of the needs of your business with the needs, wants, and competencies of your people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the right cloud technology, today&#39;s growth-focused organizations are strengthening the connection of HR across the business and scaling personalized EX across their entire workforce. These organizations are working smarter, hiring faster, and planning for what&#39;s ahead—and that makes their employees excited to be a part of their future.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.363679977;dc_trk_aid=554528446;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Learn More&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Aaron Green is SAP SuccessFactors&#39; chief marketing &amp;amp; solutions officer.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 03:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Smaller Manufacturers Can Upgrade Their Tech]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-smaller-manufacturers-can-upgrade-their-tech]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_21_1555842817.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Westend61/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;It is an opportune time for SME manufacturers to upgrade their operations by investing in new software and manufacturing innovations. The reasons include pressures on OEMs to build more resilient supply chains and to regionalize production and the falling cost and increasing ease of use of new technologies. This article describes six steps that SMEs can take to adopt these technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-smaller-manufacturers-can-upgrade-their-tech?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-smaller-manufacturers-can-upgrade-their-tech?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The post-pandemic push to make supply chains more regional and resilient is creating growth opportunities for many of the domestic small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) that large original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) rely on. These SMEs survived the waves of offshoring in the 2000s, often because they made lower-volume or costly-to-ship parts for automotive, aerospace, or industrial equipment sectors. But it was challenging for them to invest in new equipment or facilities when there wasn&#39;t much growth. Now some of the growth is coming back, and there is an opportunity for these SMEs to adopt new software and manufacturing innovations, and rethink how to improve the efficiency and productivity of their operations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the last three years we have talked to numerous SMEs, trade associations, and US government-supported &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/mep&quot;>;manufacturing extension partnerships (MEPs)&lt;/a>; across the midwestern United States. The MEPs were set up by the National Institute of Standards to help SME manufacturers and are in all 50 states and Puerto Rico. One of us (Ali Shakouri) has also worked extensively with SMEs across the state of Indiana, which at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nam.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MFG-GSP-FactSheet_201810.pdf&quot;>;28.6%&lt;/a>; has the highest share of gross state product devoted to manufacturing in the country. We have found that these firms are often quite conservative vis-à-vis the adoption of new technologies for several reasons:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;They are reluctant to change existing processes that work and that have served them well for years.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;They have a limited appetite to invest in the face of growing demand or constraints on their production capacity because of continuing cost pressures from their customers and foreign competition.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Or they find digital technologies daunting because of the need to learn new skills or develop new ways of working.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;This often means they have not kept up with technologies that are altering the competitive landscape. During the offshoring boom in the 2000s, many manufacturers moved much of their high-volume production overseas, and investments in the newest tools and technologies went there as well. This was evident, for example, in the metal castings industry, as new factories, equipped with the latest tools, were set up in low-cost countries. In the investment casting sector, new Chinese and Indian factories got the latest production tools, while US factories were left with older ones. It&#39;s easy to invest in the latest technologies when you are growing; when you are not, it&#39;s easier to stay with what you have.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s the wrong way to look at it now — these are actually moments to invest. Here are six ways to get started.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1. Leverage new simulation software tools.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Computer-aided design tools have been with us for decades, and they revolutionized all branches of engineering — the design and analysis of everything from mechanical parts and chemical processes to electronic products and semiconductors. What has been striking, though, has been both the increasing sophistication of these tools as well as the investments software developers have made in making them easier to use and more affordable. Yet adoption among SMEs has been slow.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;Simulation modeling tools can be a shortcut to improving operations. They allow firms to model and understand their process flows better, which can reveal bottlenecks and constraints, leading to new ways to operate. These tools have come a long way over last decade in terms of their ease of use, and many are cloud-based, have simple drag-and-drop interfaces, and provide building blocks that you can incorporate to make models easy to build. More sophisticated packages offer the opportunity to build a digital twin — a lifelike digital model of your operations that includes not only machines and material handling systems but even the people working there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A great example&amp;nbsp;of a company where simulation tools have made a difference&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pelcoinc.com/&quot;>;Pelco Products&lt;/a>;, an Edmond, Oklahoma-based manufacturer of traffic and utility products such as streetlights, poles, and pedestrian push buttons. As it grew over the years, its production processes had sprawled and slowed production. To improve them, Steve Parduhn, son of the founder, brought in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.okalliance.com/&quot;>;Oklahoma Manufacturing Alliance&lt;/a>; (OMA), the state&#39;s MEP. Parduhn got help in building a digital simulation model of parts of the production processes using software from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketchup.com/&quot;>;Sketchup&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simio.com/&quot;>;Simio&lt;/a>;. This allowed Pelco to test new scenarios virtually&amp;nbsp;before&amp;nbsp;it started moving equipment around. It was even able to simulate new technologies and equipment before bringing them on site. The increased capacity in the factory led to $1 million in cost savings and $5 million in new sales.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;2. Put data and new analysis technologies to work.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;SME manufacturers often collect a lot of data from their operations, but most haven&#39;t leveraged new artificial intelligence (AI), including machine learning (ML) tools, to gain fresh insights from the data. This can be intimidating to firms with no prior experience, so the key is to start simple and learn.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Working with Purdue University&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2134667&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&quot;>;AI-Commons team&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tmfcenter.com/history&quot;>;TMF Center&lt;/a>;, a company in Williamsport, Indiana, installed inexpensive power-consumption sensors to determine usage patterns across its complex parts-machining operations. This helped it start classifying activities and develop real-time dashboards of shop performance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kirbyrisk.com/mechanical-solutions/&quot;>;Kirby Risk Manufacturing&lt;/a>; in Lafayette, Indiana, is experimenting with sound sensors and ML to detect quality issues during operations, which would allow it to identify and fix problems much more quickly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://primient.com/about&quot;>;Primient&lt;/a>;, a food ingredient company based in Schaumburg, Illinois, was able to work with Purdue to develop a simple ML imaging application for its Lafayette corn-sweetener factory that helped its operators evaluate its production process for the size distribution of sugar crystals, a characteristic that determines how quickly the crystals dissolve in foods and therefore how sweet they taste. The new application provided measurement precision to a process that previous called for operator judgment — one that was prone to human error and wide variability. The ML application laid the groundwork for it to start using its extensive production data to improve yields and operational efficiency as well.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3. Learn how to implement simple automation.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;While many SMEs employ some degree of automation, it is often in the form of pre-set packages such as automated tool exchange systems or automated workpiece loaders purchased as part of expensive add-ons to machine tools. There are often many “dirty, dull, and dangerous” jobs that are still done manually, and automating them would not only improve product quality by reducing variability but also improve the jobs of workers by freeing them to do more productive and desirable work elsewhere in the process. But these are intimidating projects for SMEs who don&#39;t have prior experience. Again, the answer is to start with small projects and learn and get help from organizations such as the MEPs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kinnee Tilly, a vice president at&amp;nbsp;the Oklahoma Manufacturing Alliance,&amp;nbsp;described how it helped &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rise-manufacturing/about/&quot;>;Rise Manufacturing&lt;/a>;, a company in Broken Arrow, Oklahoma, that provides manufacturing and assembly services to aerospace, defense, and oil and gas customers. Rise had a surge in demand for its products during the pandemic, which led to bottlenecks in its manufacturing process. “They had a manual polishing process, and human variability was creeping in,” Tilly explained. “We had people who had never touched anything like a robot in their lives, who were very wary of it because they felt they were going to be replaced.” OMA lent it a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.automate.org/a3-content/what-are-collaborative-robots&quot;>;collaborative robot&lt;/a>; (“cobot”), a lightweight robotic arm that is simple to program and can safely share a space with workers, to help Rise get the process up and running. The workers saw the benefit. “Once we were done, not only did we not replace the people, we upskilled them [and] got them into a better job,” Tilly said.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;4. Get up to date on advances in production tools and methods.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;It is important for SMEs to get up to date on the tools and processes that are being used in their industry to speed up production cycles and improve quality. For example, digital casting technology, which encompasses simulation, printed prototypes, printed tooling, and laser metrology, can help lower costs and enable SME metal casters to compete more effectively with offshore production.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All operations, whether dedicated to production or services, will also benefit from better application of methods taught by Toyota. Almost every MEP teaches lean methods, pull systems, visual workplace concepts, and kaizen methods for process improvement. Yet many SMEs would benefit from a deeper understanding of the underlying concepts and a more conscientious application of these techniques. Toyota&#39;s production system is not static and continues to &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/what-really-makes-toyotas-production-system-resilient&quot;>;improve&lt;/a>;, and SMEs would benefit from doing the same.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;5. Leverage assistance programs from universities and outside resources.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The MEP programs are designed to help SMEs improve their capabilities and get started on the adoption of new technologies. Purdue, which manages Indiana&#39;s MEP and the state&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://tap.purdue.edu/&quot;>;Technical Assistance Program&lt;/a>;, offers a wide range of training and services in adopting new technologies. It even connects SMEs to university faculty and students for up to 40 hours of assistance per year in a wide range of fields, including advanced process control, materials, failure analysis, sensors use and applications, and engineering analysis.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;States can also provide direct assistance. Since 2020, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iedc.in.gov/&quot;>;Indiana Economic Development Corporation&lt;/a>; (IEDC), working with nonprofit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conexusindiana.com/&quot;>;Conexus Indiana&lt;/a>;, has been providing matching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conexusindiana.com/drive-industry-success/manufacturing-readiness-grants/&quot;>;manufacturing readiness grants&lt;/a>; to companies seeking to modernize their operations or integrating smart technologies and processes in order to increase capacity and speed and improve quality. SMEs can apply for up to $200,000, which they must match on a dollar-for-dollar basis. &lt;a href=&quot;https://photonautomation.com/&quot;>;Photon Automation&lt;/a>;, a 67-employee SME in Hancock County, Indiana, leveraged a $183,000 grant to employ a new laser welding technology for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conexusindiana.com/case-study/photon-automation/&quot;>;manufacture of battery products&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;6. Leverage peer relationships.&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Farm cooperatives played a big role in the adoption of agricultural technologies in the early and mid-20&lt;sup>;th&lt;/sup>; century through knowledge sharing. SME manufacturers can similarly benefit from informal networking and sharing of experiences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One example of such cooperation: The Purdue AI-Commons team has been working with a cohort of SMEs to share best practices to implement &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computersciencedegreehub.com/faq/what-is-edge-analytics/&quot;>;edge analytics devices&lt;/a>; and benefit from &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.mydatacan.org/&quot;>;privacy-preserving data sharing&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;An Opportune Time&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This is an opportune time for SME manufacturers to invest in their own transformation. The pressures to build more resilient supply chains and to regionalize production afford domestic manufacturers a rare growth opportunity during which they can update their operations and operating strategies. They should not miss the chance.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>