<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>哈佛商业评论</title><description>哈佛商业评论全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://hbr.org/ <item><title><![CDATA[What It Means to Be a Moral Leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;div js-target=&quot;video-player-page&quot; data-props=&quot;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;6337577423112&quot;}&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div >; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;加载中... &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption= &quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Dov Seidman 让人们认真思考，不仅思考他们做了什么，还思考他们如何做。他非常专注于“如何”做到这一点。他创建了 HOW 社会研究所，鼓励领导人走上道德领导之路。他甚至写了一本名为《如何：为什么我们做任何事意味着一切》的书。在我们每周直播系列节目“工作的新世界”的这一集中，塞德曼提供了关于当今良好的道德领导力的见解和灵感——在一个永远混乱的时代。他的中心思想是旧的领导方式不再有效。他向观众发起挑战，请他们选出一位近年来取得成功的指挥与控制型市长、大公司首席执行官或职业教练。他说得有道理。我们对领导者的要求的期望是：也许有一个明显的例子，那就是国家政治人物——现在包括同理心、脆弱性、正直和道德。 &lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader ?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/what-it-means-to-be-a-moral-leader?language=pt&quot;>;阅读葡萄牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;还记得领导人何时可以通过说“商业就是商业”来回避在敏感的政治或社会问题上采取立场吗？ HOW 社会研究所创始人兼主席多夫·塞德曼 (Dov Seidman) 表示，这种冷漠的中立态度已经不再有效。 “我认为商业的本质就是社会，”他说。 “这是社区，以及我们如何应对遇到的一切，以及我们的深思熟虑和原则性。”坚持正义的领导者是员工、客户和其他利益相关者的新期望。更不用说感恩节餐桌上的亲戚了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着人工智能的发展并挑战人类对智力的垄断，道德判断和同理心等纯粹的人类技能对于领导者来说变得更加重要。塞德曼说，虽然机器可以被教导做正确的事情，但只有人才能带领他人做正确的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于我们视频系列“工作新世界”的这一集，《哈佛商业评论》主编Adi Ignatius 与 Seidman 进行了座谈，Seidman 也是《How: Why How We》一书的作者做任何事情都意味着一切&lt;/a>;&lt;/em>;，讨论：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;如何让你的原则指导你作为领导者&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;暂停的重要性为了反思、重新联系、重新思考和重新构想你的使命&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;随着人工智能原始智能的增长，哪些人类特征和能力的价值将会增长&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;“&lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;工作新世界&lt;/a>;”探讨了高层管理人员如何看待未来以及他们的公司如何努力为成功做好准备。每周，Ignatius 都会在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/harvard-business-review/&quot;>;LinkedIn Live&lt;/a>; 上与一位高层领导交谈 - 之前的采访包括 &lt;a href=&quot; /2021/10/microsofts-satya-nadella-on-flexible-work-the-metaverse-and-the-power-of-empathy&quot;>;微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/11 /indra-nooyi-前百事可乐首席执行官谈动荡时期的人才培养&quot;>;前百事可乐首席执行官英德拉·努伊&lt;/a>;。他还在专门为《哈佛商业评论》订阅者提供的时事通讯中分享了对这些对话的内部看法，并为未来的讨论征求问题。如果您是订阅者，可以在&lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences?movetile=newworldofwork&quot;>;此处&lt;/a>;注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;工作新世界&quot; dek=&quot;前几集&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of -work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-world-of-work&quot; style=&quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合&lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;工作新世界&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 前几集 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt; p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dov，欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢谢，阿迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您对领导力的道德方面思考了很多。在这个感觉像是永久颠覆的时代，优秀的领导力是什么样的？&lt;/p>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;newsletter&quot; name=&quot;The New World of Work&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;follow-subscribe data -name=&quot;hbpnewworldofwork&quot; data-activity=&quot;newsletter&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div style=&quot;color: #000000&quot;>; &lt;svg>; &lt;use xlink:href=&quot;/resources/css/images/hbr- icon.svg#the-new-world-of-work&quot;>;&lt;/use>; &lt;/svg>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 订阅我们的每周通讯 &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;工作世界 &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; 关于人才、技术和商业未来的坦诚对话。为订阅者准备的特别电子邮件系列。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; js-target=&quot;subscribe-for-newsletter-tout&quot; data-method=&quot;subscribe&quot;>;注册&lt;/a>; &lt;/ div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/sign-in&quot; js-target=&quot;sign-in-this&quot;>;注册&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe&quot;>;签名向上&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 感谢您注册，&lt;span js-target=&quot;newsletter-success-firstname&quot;>; &lt;/span>;！ &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; 您可以查看我们的&lt;a href=&quot;/email-newsletters&quot;>;其他新闻通讯&lt;/a>;或通过管理您的&lt;a href=&quot;/my-library/preferences&quot;>;随时选择退出电子邮件首选项&lt;/a>;。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/follow-subscribe>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;优秀领导者要做的第一件事他们会退后一步，试图理解他们所领导的世界。领导力与头条新闻无关。我们都可以阅读这些内容，推文到推文，帖子到帖子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是关于趋势线的，世界将走向何方？哪些熟悉和陌生的力量正在重塑它？我们用什么框架来判断未来？我们将使用什么剧本来吸引人们踏上通往未来的旅程？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我还喜欢说，平静的大海从来不会造就伟大的水手，而外面的大海并不平静。 。因此，如果你想成为一名伟大的领导者，在波涛汹涌的大海上航行就是其中的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导力始终很重要，它始终具有重要意义。我们将通过一些例子来说明领导力可能比以前更重要，因为它会产生回响。但我们正处于一个一切都被扰乱的时代，包括领导力和权威本身。负责一个组织、一个团队或其他人的意义已经与过去不同了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想构建我认为最伟大的 21 世纪领导力挑战，然后我们可以讨论什么样的领导层应对它。我想你和你的观众都会同意，如果没有正式的授权，你就无法管理一家公司、一个团队、一个国家。人们需要负责。我无法想象一支没有主教练的足球队，一所没有校长的学校，一家没有首席执行官的公司，或者一个没有总统或总理的国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我们都知道，组织当具有道德权威的个人占据这些正式权威的职位时，人类和社会才能真正发挥作用。在不太透明、更不透明的世界里，我们经常将两者混为一谈：“他一定是一个伟人，否则他是怎么达到那么高的地位的？”或者，“除非他是一位出色的领导者，否则董事会不会把他放在那里。”但现在我们看到，正式权力可以被夺取，你可以在选举中赢得它，其他人可以将其授予你，“我特此任命你为副总统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但道德权威确实是取决于你是谁、你体现的价值观、你如何领导、你如何做出决定以及你如何与他人相处。在这个颠覆的时代，我们面临的挑战是，正式权威已被破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;硅谷企业家，即使拥有 20 比 1 的超级多数股权，也无法保住自己的工作，如果他们没有以开明的方式领导，甚至更糟糕的是，存在一些不当行为。我们看到社会各个领域的正式权威被推翻和破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;挑战在于我们如何培养和发展以道德权威领导的道德领袖文化？这是第一步。我们如何确保他们是发号施令、担任正式权力职位的人？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想补充一点，就领导力而言，这场流行病的遗产是，它已经揭示并阐明了道德领导的重要性。不仅仅是最高层，学校校长、星巴克的咖啡师、组织、部门和社会各个层面的商店经理：领导力都很重要。因为特别是在危机时期，当人们自然地感到不确定和害怕时，他们会求助于任何对他们有一定权威的人。他们对他们的期望是真理，一些智慧，一些无私，真正把对方放在第一位。他们期待道德领导力，阿迪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个很好的框架。你使用了“道德”这个词。在我们的世界里，为《哈佛商业评论》撰稿的人通常倾向于使用“良好的领导力”之类的术语。优秀的领导者除了拥有你需要的商业头脑之外，还具有同理心，他们很脆弱，但你使用“道德”这个词。你这是什么意思？为什么这是你的中心框架？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我所说的并不是说教、成为道德，或者成为如何应对道德困境的专家，或者如何在社会、政治、环境、宗教问题上采取立场的专家，即使它可能包括这些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道德领导实际上是关于如何。你如何领导、如何决策，是成本效益分析吗？还是有原则指导？你是否愿意做不方便、勇敢和困难的事情，因为这是原则或价值观对你的要求？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这实际上是关于你如何与他人相处和对话。是单向还是双向？这就是您结束会议的方式。你会说：“我们聊得很愉快吗？是谁的电话？哦，这是一个营销决定。谁有营销预算？”这是用权力来界定它，“这是谁的电话？”不如问：“什么是正确的选择？我们认为什么是公平的呼吁？什么是尊重并忠于我们价值观的召唤？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想了解一整套剧本，但现在我只想说，这不是道德说教。这实际上是关于如何做的。你如何运用权力，你如何做出决定，你如何行事，以及你在自己的价值观方面所体现的真正含义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许我们可以将这些纳入《哈佛商业评论》观众都在苦苦挣扎的问题中。阿迪，你在《哈佛商业评论》上写了很多关于我们在工作场所取得成功需要更多的行为和品质的文章。如果我能让你处于困境的话，你为什么不说出一些名字呢？为了赢得今天的胜利，我们希望我们的同事和队友有哪些行为？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好吧，相信。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;多夫·赛德曼：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信任。好吧，我要把这些写下来。信任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我之前谈到过诸如同理心、脆弱性、承诺之类的事情。我们不是在谈论个人贡献者，而是在谈论团队和公司，因此是共同的承诺和团队意识。请随意添加，这些只是一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些并不是可有可无的，这就是你所拥有的弄清楚今天很重要吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;您刚才没有提到的一些事情是效率、生产力和速度。你在呼唤人类品质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为道德领袖非常清楚改变行为和提升行为之间的区别。因为领导力是关于如何做的。我们如何让人们做事，我们如何在他们身上产生能量，我们如何让他们参与值得他们奉献和忠诚的旅程和任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我要出售产品，我可以获得你现在就买，而不是以后，或者更多而不是更少。如果我们制作一个很棒的政治攻击广告，我可以让你投票左派而不是右派，或者右派而不是左派。我们知道如何使用胡萝卜加大棒来改变或推动行为。如果你给我足够的胡萝卜和大棒，我可以让你更快地工作，也许更少的病假，工作 10 小时而不是 8 小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，阿迪，你所要求的行为，没有多少胡萝卜加大棒可以得到你，因为这是人类以最高尚的方式行事。你能想象对某人说，走进一个房间不要出来，否则如果你不能带着同理心和能力去建立对他人的信任，或者你在脆弱中找到更多的勇气，你就会被解雇。再多的胡萝卜也无法迫使人们做出这些行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我们试试奖金，再多的大棒也无济于事。我们来试试胡萝卜吧。如果你把每个人的工资增加两倍，阿迪，你会得到更多的同理心吗？你会得到更多信任吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你不会。可能不会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们可能会得到相反的结果。我们发现自己正处于领导力的一个不连续的时刻，我们想要从员工身上得到什么，无论有多少胡萝卜和大棒都无法实现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我并不反对大棒。应该有可解雇的罪行。但是，对被解雇的恐惧是否应该影响这个地方 2% 或 98% 的事情发生呢？我也真的很喜欢胡萝卜。我认为我们应该向同事支付尽可能多的工资，并希望比我们的竞争对手支付更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是道德领袖所理解的是，某些行为是不能强迫的。他们无法被激励，只能被激励。有道德的领导者是鼓舞人心的领导者，因为信任、同理心、脆弱性、协作、诚实、勇气，所有这些我们渴望在周围人身上看到的人类高尚品质必须而且只能受到启发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更多的领导者了解不同之处。回到办公室后，我们会看到这种情况的发生。更多的领导知道，如果你是我的下属阿迪，我可以坚持永远不骗我，永远告诉我真相，但我却永远不能坚持，永远忠于我。道德领袖知道，某些事情他们可以坚持，而另一些事情他们必须激发。我们实际上看到了这种情况，谁坚持让人们回到办公室，谁试图激励人们这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导范式确实发生了转变。过去是命令控制，“我是老大”。 “我说，你做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们现在所处的时代需要有同理心的领导者和脆弱的领导者。不久之后可能会出现另一次转变，并出现另一种领导范式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是否有科学依据，或者是否有指标表明这种领导方法不仅在大约 30,000 英尺的高空是正确的道德定义，但也包括机构的成果和绩效？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我们先了解科学和指标，但在我们之前这样做，这就是不会改变的事情。只有两种类型的行为。有什么可以做、什么不能做、什么应该做、什么不应该做。我相信最高法院法官波特·斯图尔特说过，做你有权做的事和做正确的事之间是有区别的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们曾经向人们说明，这就是你可以做的和可以做的不做。然后我们要求他们追求目标和战略，同时考虑到自己能做什么、不能做什么，并且要尽可能快、雄心勃勃，并且必须在此基础上赢得竞争。一位军事将领会说，在那个世界里，只有少数人占领了那座山。首席执行官会说：“这是我们的战略，这是我们的目标。”在那个世界里，每个人的工作就是把下一件事情做好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为当今世界的运作方式，我们希望越来越多的人不仅要做好下一件事情，而且还要做下一个正确的事情。我不认为这种转变会从要求人们做正确的下一件事情转变为激励他们做下一件正确的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;计算机可以通过编程来正确地做下一件事情。只有人类才能做下一件正确的事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为我们现在处于一个规范的环境中，规范就是规范中的，你应该做什么，不应该做什么。道德领袖起床去培育人们“应该有思想”的规范文化，这种文化将一直存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们对文化如此痴迷的原因是企业文化是被发明的，所有文化都是由企业文化创造出来的。发明，将规范从一代人传递到另一代人。规范是我们应该做什么和应该做什么。如果您只是要指定规则、政策和程序，则不需要文化，但如果您要规范化，则需要深思熟虑和有意识地扩展价值观、基于价值观的文化。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;我不认为这是一种时尚。我认为世界已经被重塑，使我们处于规范的环境中。我们在社会、社区和公司中看到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为这是事实。我认为也有一个反驳，也许这只是高层政治反驳，但我觉得历史学家会回顾这个时代，并将其定义为新的独裁统治之一，远离你所认为的一些理想。正在谈论。您认为这准确吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说过领导力与趋势线有关。让我们退后一步。您能说出一位在领导城市方面取得成功的独裁市长吗？你能想象一个专制的首席执行官管理着一家财富 500 强公司吗？你能想象一下在过去 10 年里，在篮球、棒球、足球、世界杯足球赛上赢得的冠军，说出这项运动的名字，通过命令和控制尖叫来运行，那个自上而下的教练吗？普京的独裁统治与泽连斯基的道德领导力之间存在着一场史诗般的战斗。但如果你退后一步，我会发现在许多其他地方的部门和我们生活的各个方面都存在一些关于道德领导力的奇妙趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我提出体育的原因是体育是为了获胜。这是关于成为冠军的事情，而谁在体育运动中获胜是令人难以置信的。我的意思是，金州勇士队的史蒂夫·科尔拥有出色的天赋，但他的竞争对手也是如此。有一年他的背部伤势严重，缺席了 43 场比赛。他甚至不在那里做教练，他们通过基于信任的文化做到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉尔·埃利斯（Jill Ellis），当她作为美国女子足球教练赢得冠军时，她知道她每一位球员的狗和猫。这只是她的教练开始时的个人化程度的象征。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你有&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/01/us-soccers-gregg-berhalter-on-rebuilding-trust-in-the-wake- of-controversy&quot;>;格雷格·伯哈尔特 (Gregg Berhalter) 在你的节目中&lt;/a>;，美国男队在上届世界杯​​上取得了令人难以置信的成功，并希望在下一届世界杯上超越这一点。但如果你听听球员们如何谈论他们在那里建造的东西，你会发现这是一种团结一致的身份。尽管他们是一支非常年轻的团队，但他们试图通过大胆和韧性等品质来超越竞争对手，从而在竞争中脱颖而出。我还有更多例子，但我对这里的一些大趋势非常乐观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;阿迪·伊格纳修斯：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当我问这是否是独裁时代时，部分原因是领导力，在某种程度上，至少是政治领导力，似乎不再感到羞耻。我已经足够大了，我记得理查德·尼克松，尼克松被指控，被弹劾，显然他感到羞耻，在那一刻他决定下台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不确定今天的政治领导人有什么感觉耻辱。如果他们没有这样的感觉，那么你就会为谎言、相反的真理、没有责任感和道德感打开大门。我担心这个。我担心这对于一些政治领导人来说是一个成功的模式，并且可能会激励其他人尝试效仿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我我认为这是一个非常严重的担忧。当你提到尼克松总统时，当他说“我不是骗子”时，他不想让我们认为他是骗子，无论他是否是骗子，他都在庆祝这个常态，“我们不要是骗子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信我们现在生活在一个有罪不罚的时代，一些当权者不仅行为不端，而且还逍遥法外。有罪不罚现象破坏并侵蚀了常态。我们不仅受到高层人士通过他们的行为或邪恶行为造成的伤害，而且你这样做也不受惩罚，说：“我的话很完美，我会再这样做。”或者它们让我们其他人觉得我们在某种程度上是失败者，因为我们想要达到高标准和行为规范。你侵蚀了规范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这就是为什么我们需要道德领袖的一个论点，因为道德领袖维护规范，他们帮助创建真正忠于高规范的组织和社区。&lt;/​​p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;坎耶·韦斯特 (Kanye West) 在与阿迪达斯离婚之前，在网上说了一些可怕的事情和可恨的事情。不管他是不是故意的，我们都可以争论，但他说了。但随后他又说了一件事：阿迪达斯对我无能为力。这是有罪不罚的声明。阿迪达斯通过与之抗争，通过断绝这种关系，最终遭受了数十亿美元的损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们看到的这场战斗不仅涉及不当行为，而且还看到有罪不罚的不当行为以及那些站出来的人&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当我想到道德领袖时，在某些方面我想到的是那些以身作则的人，他只是做正确的事情，你就会意识到这个人是值得信赖的、正直的、鼓舞人心的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在是领导力的新世界。我们在之前的节目中已经讨论过这一点，对于领导者和首席执行官来说，不可避免地需要对与公司不利的社会甚至政治问题做出回应，或者有时与公司无关，但员工和客户要求知道这些问题在哪里领导者站起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顺便说一句，如果没有公开的声明，员工和客户会为您假设并填写这句话。你不妨表明立场。这是一个棘手的领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;领导者是否有一个框架来管理这个充满永久社会问题的新世界，他们被要求以某种方式声明这些问题？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN ：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也许要和你约会。在电影&lt;em>;毕业生&lt;/em>;中，[一个角色对]达斯汀霍夫曼的角色说，“未来是塑料。”您刚才使用了“Adi”这个词，它是框架的未来。所有人类判断都依赖于框架。商业中流行的框架是成本效益分析。现在我们需要创建和扩展新的规范框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界是如此相互依存，一个人的希望、梦想和困境都在我们手中的小屏幕上直观地显现出来。我提到了坎耶·韦斯特。与阿迪达斯离婚后，他出现在 Sketchers 的大厅里，在 Sketchers 意识到之前，他们卷入了一场如何回应他出现在那里的社会漩涡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一件事我确信无疑：世界已经通过融合的方式被重塑。社会、环境、政治、人类问题，最高法院刚刚发生的堕胎问题或如何应对乌克兰的入侵：这些曾经被认为与商业议程无关的问题现在不可避免地成为其中的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中立已经结束。人们期望有观点，特别是来自员工、消费者和其他利益相关者的观点。我们需要一个框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辉瑞有一个很棒的框架。莎莉·萨斯曼 (Sally Susman) 曾公开谈论过此事。它是否符合我们的目的，考虑到我们的价值观，我们的观点应该是什么？它如何影响我们的选民？我们沉默的代价是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tom Wilson 在 Allstate 的框架中做得非常出色。有一个门槛问题：“正在发生的事情合法吗？但即便如此，鉴于我们的价值观，我们的观点应该是什么？如果没有，让我们继续挑战这些想法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为现在表明立场不再只是说，“嘿，我只是经营一家企业。生意就是生意。”我认为商业的本质是社会，是社区，我们如何对待遇到的一切，以及我们如何深思熟虑和有原则，现在是新的期望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几个月后感恩节晚餐即将到来员工们会坐在那里，遇到许久未见的表兄弟姐妹。在一天结束时，首席执行官必须问自己这个问题：“我的同事们是否会为感恩节晚餐感到自豪，向他们的表兄弟吹嘘他们的公司如何处理这个问题和那个问题以及这个问题和那个问题？现在是他们商业议程的一部分吗？”我们必须通过感恩节晚餐测试。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我喜欢这个。我也喜欢框架的未来。我现在想回答观众提问，这是来自印度的斯里尼瓦斯。在人工智能可能比人类更擅长基于数据做出决策的时代，我们是否可以说基于良心的管理或领导的时代已经到来？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五百年前，我们发生了科学革命，那是一场真正的革命。 Uber 让黄色出租车营业或停业，LinkedIn 可能让招聘人员更难，这些都是干扰。真正的革命大约每 500 年发生一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为技术革命和通过人工智能加速的革命是每 500 年一次的革命。 500 年前，我们环顾四周，想要掌控周围的环境，我们说：“我们是最聪明的。”笛卡尔说：“我思故我在”。这是书呆子复仇的500年，我们称之为启蒙和理性的时代。我们几乎通过成为最聪明的人来组织我们的事务。我们取得的成就令人难以置信：现代资本主义，我们激增了个人权利和生物多样性。过去 500 年取得的成就令人难以置信。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人工智能的有趣之处在于它正在挑战我们对智能的垄断。我们不再是最聪明的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;机器永远不会拥有的一件事是什么？一个心脏。事实上，我认为技术革命正在使人们更加清楚地认识到扩大发自内心的事物的必要性。有句道德领导的格言说，只有来自内心的东西才能进入内心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从工业时代的经济角度来看，我们雇佣了工人，而且我们雇佣了强有力的工人。然后我们进入了知识或信息经济，我们聘请了领导者，我们偏爱知识、专业知识和专业化。我认为我们正在进入一个更加人性化的时代，从内心发出的品质，就像你提到的那样，同理心以及以道德、道德和良心的能力做正确的事情的能力，现在已经成为我们所追求的东西。必须扩大规模。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我担心的是，阿迪，当社交网络首次推出时，我们有一些乌托邦式的想法，任何连接世界的东西都会很棒。我们将拥有更丰富的人类经验。个人将被赋予权力。在第一局中，我们看到了狗和猫的照片，我们的熟人又变成了亲密的朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但后来我们开始看到技术是一种善恶的力量。好事可能发生，坏事也可能发生，包括民主选举遭到黑客攻击。我们看到，我们不仅仅是有机地分裂，而且分裂背后的利润动机一直存在，人们现在相互竞争，我们正在通过技术积极分裂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时的负责人人们常说：“我们只是技术。我们只是一个平台。”他们宣称自己在道德上保持中立。我认为，阿迪，现在比任何事情都更重要的是，我们不能用 ChatGPT 和生成人工智能说：“这只是技术。”我们知道好事和坏事都会发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有些人正在谈论人类可能的终结。对蜘蛛侠道德的需求，即能力越大，责任越大，这一点从未如此重要。我认为那些提供这些新技术的人拥有前所未有的力量，他们需要扩大良知和蜘蛛侠道德。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们主要讨论的是最高层的道德和领导力，优秀的领导者拥有道德和领导力，而选择优秀领导者的人应该寻找这一点。这是来自巴基斯坦伊斯兰堡的沙巴纳提出的问题。您认为领导力发展在确保整个组织中的个人体现相同的道德价值观方面可以发挥什么作用？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个很好的问题。道德领导力，有机会培养能力，不是技能，而是素质和能力。我认为组织可以做到这一点。我们需要采取一些实践来衡量道德领导力，我很高兴提及其中一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想从最违反直觉的实践和建议开始。我想参加这次聚会的每个人都会同意世界正在加速发展，它永远在继续。我们正在遭受数字攻击。我们都会经历 FOMO，害怕错过。够公平吗，阿迪？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到目前为止一切顺利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN：&lt;/strong>; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界变得越快，我们遇到的事情就越多，我们就越需要停下来。道德领导的标志是停顿。 [拉尔夫·沃尔多]爱默生说，“在每次停顿中，我都听到了召唤”，因为只有当我们停顿时，我们才能问自己道德领袖会问的重要问题。 “如果我受到这样的对待，我会有什么感觉？” “What&#39;s the consequences of doing it this way or that way?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I like to talk about the four Rs, because in the pause, we can reflect on the challenge, the situation of the world in which we&#39;re operating. We can reconnect with our deeper sense of purpose and our values and conscience. We can rethink some of our assumptions of how we&#39;re operating, how we&#39;re making money, how we&#39;re making decisions. And only then can we reimagine a better solution, or a better path, or a better future. The hallmark of moral leadership is the pause.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral leaders also eschew philosophical mistakes. People think, “Oh, moral leaders must be about empowerment.” Well, that&#39;s true spiritually, but often empowerment, you know what happens? This is how a nonmoral leader might sound, “I push decisions to the front lines. I delegate authority.” And they think they&#39;re leading, and then five years later, everybody has all these rights, “I can spend $1,000 without asking my boss for permission.” “I can get on an airplane to a trade association meeting and spend money without asking for permission.” And you&#39;ve built a culture where everybody knows what rights they have. They&#39;re empowered in that way. But you haven&#39;t built a gym where they know the ethos. “What is the way here?”, where they know what is right.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;[Airbnb CEO] Brian Chesky recently came out against this form of empowerment, and said that he wants to be an orchestrator. Moral leaders don&#39;t just get out of the way and delegate. They show up, and they sit at the back of the room sometimes. They don&#39;t provide the answer. They ask the right questions. So there really are opportunities to be incisive and rigorous about what it is and what it&#39;s not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You&#39;ve identified the hallmarks of moral leadership. I&#39;m curious, as you look out at US companies, global companies, are many of them or most of them run by people you would consider moral leaders?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two things: I think what matters is not to look for beacons. I&#39;ve never seen a unicorn, but I&#39;ve seen a horse. I&#39;ve seen a horn. I&#39;ve seen white. I look for who&#39;s engendering trust by extending it. Who&#39;s creating such a high-trust environment where people feel that they can lean and take risks in order to innovate?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most innovation programs fail because trust is so low that people won&#39;t take the risk in order to innovate. I look not for perfection, and I think what matters most, Adi, is not who&#39;s a beacon and an icon of moral leadership, but who is authentically and deliberately on the journey. Who&#39;s taking risk in that regard? Who&#39;s being courageous in that regard? It&#39;s not about perfection in that way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And maybe I should end with the following: linearity is over in this world. We&#39;re in an up-and-down world, and the leaders who frame the future as a journey really elevate others, because nothing elevates a human beings more than being on a journey of progress, where we go up and down, but we stick together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Increasingly, I&#39;m seeing people have the confidence and the courage to frame that path ahead as a journey, develop an ethos for being on a journey together. I really think that nothing elevates somebody else more than framing the path ahead as a journey and creating an ethos where together, we can journey together, because to journey is to do something human.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s fantastic. Your words are inspiring.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can I say one last thing? Did you ever hear in business, “Hope is not a strategy?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through budgeting, planning, and control, we&#39;re going to superimpose the future, and that&#39;s kind of, “Hope is not a strategy.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yeah.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Well, I&#39;m also here to say that without hope, there is no strategy. Moral leaders purvey hope, and they inspire hope in others by really helping them see possibility, helping them embrace the commonality in the other, so that we can do things together.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral leaders really fight against the non-adage that hope is not a strategy, because they know that without hope, there is no strategy, and they&#39;re prepared to paint a picture of a distant future, but with rigor to go that way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to apologize for not answering your question before about metrics. I&#39;m just going to say the following. Metrics are moral choices. When we measure something, we&#39;re saying it matters. When we don&#39;t measure something, we say it doesn&#39;t matter. Moral leaders pause, and they pick the right metrics that move them on the journey, because they know that metrics don&#39;t come from on high. In and of themselves, they reflect our values.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;ADI IGNATIUS:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dov Seidman, thank you for being on “The New World of Work”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;DOV SEIDMAN:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adi, great to be with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Web3 Could Change the Business Model of Creative Work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_skizzomat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Illustration by Skizzomat&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Web3 &amp;#8212; the read-write-own web &amp;#8212; could offer a new model for creative work. By offering new tools to earn and own assets, build wealth, and wrestle back control from powerful platforms and intermediaries, it has the potential to simplify how creators fund their ventures and new ways to earn a living, not just on the first sale of a work of art but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/nfts/earnings&quot;>;perpetuity&lt;/a>; thanks to programmatic royalty streams paid via smart contracts, self-executing code that can move and store money. If Web1 and Web2 democratized access to information and made it easier to collaborate online, Web3 equips creators with a new toolkit to build real wealth from their work, on a globally level playing field.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/web3-could-change-the-business-model-of-creative-work?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;For most of the industrial age, technology has acted as a tailwind for creators, powering an age of mass culture that supported a professional class of working artists. However, more recently, the rise of &lt;em>;digital &lt;/em>;technology — specifically, the internet and AI — has become a source of economic dislocation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web1, the so-called “read web,” was a digital printing press that democratized access to information, but it also commoditized art and music and undermined creators&#39; rights as their IP got laundered in the web&#39;s swirling washing machine of content.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web2, the “read-write web,” made it easier to publish content, share ideas and access a broader audience (ie, “write” to the internet) but it also confined creators to tightly run platforms they did not trust or control and where they lacked transparency into the economic impact of their work. Either that or risk the wilderness of the web where their creations could be copied without recourse. Digital artists had no easy way to monetize their creations and could not benefit when works were resold.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platforms that control content distribution have grown richer and more powerful, with precious little of that windfall trickling down to creators. Consider the strikes of the Writers Guild of America (WGA) and the Screen Actors Guild–American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG–AFTRA). Streaming has already shortened television seasons, shrunk writers&#39; rooms, and eroded artists&#39; traditional residual revenues; and generative AI and 3D modeling give companies more tools for further minimizing their use of writers and actors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/05/what-is-web3&quot;>;Web3&lt;/a>; — the read-write-own web — offers new tools to earn and own assets, build wealth, and wrestle back control from powerful platforms and intermediaries. Web3 could simplify how creators fund their ventures by crowdsourcing new titles directly from their fans. It could offer new ways to earn a living, not just on the first sale of a work of art but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/nfts/earnings&quot;>;perpetuity&lt;/a>; thanks to programmatic royalty streams paid via smart contracts, self-executing code that can move and store money. In other words, it might offer a new model for creative work.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;AI: Risk or Opportunity?&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Now, new technologies — namely, generative AI — pose new challenges for composers, screenwriters, visual artists, and other creative workers. It is too early to say whether AI will be all bad for all of them; it may expanding the ranks of professional artists or grow the market for culture and creating opportunities for humans to co-create or collaborate with AI on an equal footing. But it could also starkly devalue the work of copywriters, composers, and artists, and relegate these workers to supporting roles, such as polishing scripts or adding some depth of feeling to digitally rendered art. Cezanne said, “A work of art which did not begin in emotion is not art,” but plenty of studio executives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/disney-creates-task-force-explore-ai-cut-costs-sources-2023-08-08/&quot;>;see AI as a way to cut costs&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By analyzing hundreds of thousands of scripts against their viewership patterns over time, AI will get better at mimicking the stickiest and most bingeworthy of screenwriters&#39; styles, characters, and plots, not just to extend the arcs of existing stories but to synthesize all-new series and recommend the optimal cast or mix of character types. Ditto on the virtual replication of actors, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/indiana-jones-and-the-dial-of-destiny-de-aging-tech/&quot;>;tools like FaceSwap already in use&lt;/a>; to de-age stars like Harrison Ford for his latest portrayal of Indiana Jones. But such big names likely consent to such innovations on their own terms. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/money/2023/8/22/23840473/writers-strike-actors-wga-sag-workers-economy-impact&quot;>;As &lt;em>;Vox&lt;/em>; put it&lt;/a>;, “If people don&#39;t lock down control of their digital twins, then nothing else matters.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oscar winning director Stephen Soderbergh &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/steven-soderbergh-streaming-data-transparency-1235551409/&quot;>;told the &lt;em>;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; that, more than AI or visual effects, what keeps him up at night is the opacity of streaming data: He speculates that the studios are doing really well and don&#39;t want to share the wealth, or else really poorly and don&#39;t want their stocks to tank.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Artists hoped that the internet would help to disintermediate gatekeepers and middlemen, and change power dynamics in creative industries, but instead it added new intermediaries like streamers and platforms that distanced artists from their fans and obfuscated their economic impact. We need something different.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Culture Needs a New Business Model&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If technology is upending the longstanding business model of creative industries, it&#39;s also offering opportunities to establish a new one that can work better for creative workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web3 technologies can simplify how creators track the usage of their IP and to monetize it, ensuring they get paid promptly and fairly for their work. For instance, Web3 technologies could allow artists to grow and perhaps even thrive along with AI, rather than suffer at its expense. For example, smart contracts can create avenues for artists to be compensated when their work is used to train AI like a large language model.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Web3 adds an &lt;em>;economic layer&lt;/em>; and a &lt;em>;rights layer&lt;/em>; to the Internet stack, where users can not only track the provenance of information and intellectual property but also protect, manage, and monetize these digital assets themselves with transparency peer to peer. These innovations can also change how creative ventures are funded, removing industry gatekeepers and amplifying underrepresented voices. In the Philippines, independent game studios are selling NFTs of in-game assets to gamers directly to fund new titles, disintermediating big studios and traditional financial backers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Jules Urbach, CEO of cloud graphics company OTOY, Web3 is fit for this purpose. OTOY&#39;s flagship product, OctaneRender, is what&#39;s known as an “unbiased, spatially correct graphics processing unit (GPU) render engine,” which is the industry&#39;s way of describing powerful software that can render more lifelike images and video than what came before. Marvel Studios used OctaneRender in the opening of &lt;em>;Ant-Man and the Wasp&lt;/em>;, according to Urbach.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using the cloud, OTOY is able to harness dozens — and sometimes hundreds — of GPUs at a time in its network to break down projects into smaller parts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By breaking up tasks, OTOY helps democratize the compute-intensive process of rendering, allowing artists to render in a couple of minutes what used to take hours on expensive hardware setups. Most important, anything created in the render network creates a hash on a blockchain, for the verifiable provenance essential to managing artists&#39; IP rights and moving digital goods from platform to platform. With such capabilities, artist guilds could create a set of smart contract templates for their members to use in managing such life-like renderings of themselves — their digital twins — and collect privatized data on industry usage that would give them bargaining power in future negotiations. The contracts could represent the artist guilds&#39; negotiated terms, plus whatever the individual artists or their agents have negotiated.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;From Hollywood to Everywhere&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This technology also offers artists ways to flip the traditional top-down model where studios and streamers try to control everything from IP to distribution. Hollywood screenwriter Jessie Nickson-Lopez has brought some of modern TV&#39;s most indelible characters to life. As a founding member of the writing team on &lt;em>;Stranger Things&lt;/em>;, she developed the story line for the character Eleven. Recently, as cofounder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mv3.io/&quot;>;Web3 startup MV3&lt;/a>;, she launched a collection of 6,500 non-fungible tokens (NFTs) of different characters, the building blocks for what will be a richly rendered narrative “universe,” originally created by Nickson-Lopez and her team. Set in the “dystopian cyberpunk society” of 2081, after the “climate has gone to hell,” MV3 focuses on “a ragtag group of idealistic” rebels struggling to “take power from the corporation that owns the city.” NFT owners will participate in the IP, have a say in their character&#39;s arc, and even co-create the story with the MV3 team. These different character assets could ultimately appear in film, TV, and other storytelling media. They could be playable characters in videogames or avatars in the metaverse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing that fans will support a project is key for firing up the Hollywood machine to spend $100 million or more on a film or TV show. Nickson-Lopez said, “So we reverse-engineered it, and I created the world of Eluna City and the characters that reside in it.” Though Nickson-Lopez architected this world and crafted story lines for main characters, MV3 will not decide the direction of the story. “For me, what&#39;s been most exciting is seeing how much creativity we&#39;re inspiring in people who have never created before but are consumers of dystopian worlds and of fiction. There&#39;s this hunger to play. Our fans are our community and our co-creators. Because they&#39;re invested in the world and in the characters, they&#39;re really excited to build it up with us.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MV3 inverts the Hollywood model. “As my lawyers say, &#39;It&#39;s like you&#39;re ripping off pieces of value and just giving it to people.&#39; And we&#39;re like, &#39;Exactly! That&#39;s exactly what we&#39;re doing.&#39;” Recently, the founders handed control day-to-day control of the MV3 universe to the community.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Ultimately, projects like OctaneRender and MV3 will work because they engage their communities not only in the economic upside but also in the governance. Handing over control and economics to fans is antithetical to the Hollywood model, and Nickson-Lopez recognizes that. Engaging people in the creative process, for love of the experience and not just for money, is what clearly drives these creators and gives their projects purpose and meaning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology tools and human capital are more distributed than ever. If Web1 and Web2 democratized access to information and made it easier to collaborate online, Web3 equips creators with a new toolkit to build real wealth from their work, on a globally level playing field. As the saying goes, the future is not to be predicted; it is to be achieved. For cultural industries and much else, Web3 can help us do it.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Software Companies Can Avoid the Trap of Product-Led Growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-software-companies-can-avoid-the-trap-of-product-led-growth]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_1603508378.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;designer491/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Companies like Slack and Dropbox have pioneered the use of Product-Led Growth (PLG). They start by building a product that&amp;#8217;s indispensable for small teams, then count on low friction and customer advocates to expand throughout the organization. PLG works, at least at first. But it can create challenges for growing companies. The answer isn&amp;#8217;t to reject PLG. It&amp;#8217;s to embrace it &amp;#8212; but to plan ahead. Eventually, even the best PLG company will need an enterprise sales strategy which takes years to develop. Don&amp;#8217;t wait until product-led growth stalls to plan for a multi-pronged sales strategy.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-software-companies-can-avoid-the-trap-of-product-led-growth?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-software-companies-can-avoid-the-trap-of-product-led-growth?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Enterprise tech companies usually grow by investing in a costly sales and marketing operation, suffering through long, expensive sales cycles. Eventually, if it works, their software is adopted “top down” throughout an enterprise. That approach is tried-and-true, but it&#39;s not the one that Dropbox or Slack followed. Over the last decade, those companies and many others have pioneered a disruptive new business model that is taking over the $250 billion software-as-a-service market. It&#39;s called Product-Led Growth (PLG).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The PLG playbook is elegant in its simplicity: First, build a compelling product that is indispensable to end-users. Then, encourage widespread internal usage with zero friction and increasingly add value for those individual end-users. Finally, leverage internal champions and their case studies to approach corporate buyers in IT to purchase the product for company-wide use. One of us, Oliver, executed this strategy successfully as a sales leader at both Dropbox and Asana.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to building initial traction, the merits of the PLG model are clear. A recent Bain &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bain.com/insights/what-it-really-takes-to-develop-product-led-growth/&quot;>;study&lt;/a>; showed that PLG companies in the past few years had generally experienced higher revenue and market share growth compared to non-PLG companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is a catch. Companies that follow the PLG playbook risk getting stuck in what we call the PLG trap. Although the PLG approach yields rapid initial adoption and growth, scaling a PLG company is a different story. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomtunguz.com/plg-less-profitable/&quot;>;A recent analysis&lt;/a>; showed that public companies that initially pursued a PLG model are actually 5–10% less profitable compared to their sales-led counterparts — implying that many PLG companies, despite initially benefiting from superior unit economics, actually lose efficiency as they scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ambitious managers of software companies, the lesson is not to avoid taking a PLG approach. Instead, embrace PLG as an initial strategy, but commit to winning the enterprise over the long term. Plan ahead and you can avoid the PLG Trap.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Understanding the PLG Trap&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Eventually, scaling an enterprise tech company will require classic enterprise sales. But adding enterprise sales as part of a multi-pronged approach to growth isn&#39;t like flipping a switch. It takes years to craft and execute an enterprise product roadmap and go-to-market strategy. PLG companies that neglect this approach early on will, unfortunately, find themselves stuck once they&#39;ve tapped the pool of initial bottoms-up users. Very few companies have demonstrated an ability to escape the PLG Trap once they become stuck.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The PLG Trap creates a common and natural dilemma for SaaS executives and boards, for several reasons:&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;In building a great product that is appealing to end-users, companies optimize their product and support organizations for small teams.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;When expansion opportunities emerge, companies add the bare minimum feature set (such as additional security, reporting, and administrative features) to drive initial adoption from classic early adopter customers.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Success with these early adopters inspires the company to quickly scale up an outbound enterprise sales and marketing team to execute this top-down, sales-led motion.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;The company then realizes they&#39;re trapped in a chasm: the early adopters found the minimum feature set adequate, but the majority of the market does not. Meanwhile, the customer support team is not accustomed to servicing large enterprises and the marketing team has been targeting small end users, not senior IT executives. The PLG company is not truly “enterprise ready” on a product or organizational level. Sales stall.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p>;A PLG company makes each decision logically along the way — but each decision may be a step deeper into the PLG Trap. Many companies find themselves trapped around the Series C stage — about 200-400 employees — but the principles apply to larger, public companies as well. For example, Dropbox has seen steadily declining year-over-year revenue growth from 25% in 2018 to only 8% in 2023 due to a failure to make this transition. Seamlessly transitioning from a PLG to an enterprise company, by avoiding the PLG Trap, requires deliberate planning from an early stage.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Avoiding the PLG trap&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To become fully enterprise-ready, a PLG company must simultaneously provide bottom-up value and be prepared to eventually deliver value at enterprise-scale. Here are three activities a PLG company must do to seamlessly evolve from a PLG-only to a PLG + enterprise company that can avoid the trap:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Create communities of champions across multiple levels in the customer organization.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The most successful PLG companies take inspiration from successful open-sourced companies and nurture community-building as a long-term, must-win, competitive advantage. Building an advocacy program becomes a core competency from an early stage, even before investing in monetization. It&#39;s important to note that PLG companies need to build multi-tiered community programs to appeal to multiple stakeholders, unlike sales-led companies that can primarily focus on developing executive champions. PLG companies must develop champions on the end-user, IT, and executive levels, with each level likely requiring a different approach to community building.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Build a go-to-market plan (GTM) that incorporates multiple sales motions.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Successful PLG companies may start with one GTM motion, but eventually they build multiple GTM motions to capture different types of customer opportunities. Unlike sales-led organizations, which are often segmented by customer size (ie, SMB vs. Enterprise), PLG companies are often segmented by selling motions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most popular motions PLG companies build include:&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;self-service&lt;/em>;: an e-commerce experience that generates demand and captures end-users to land in organizations&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;high-velocity sales&lt;/em>;: a data-driven sales motion that uses modern customer relationship management (CRM) tools, automated workflows, and analytical segmentation to identify and convert organizations with higher willingness to pay,&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;expansion sales: &lt;/em>;a capability focusing on transitioning organizations with strong product usage to adopt the product company-wide, and&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;&lt;em>;outbound sales: &lt;/em>;an outbound motion targeting senior executives at prospects that may not have as much organic product adoption.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;h3>;Deliver product value across multiple levels, including at enterprise scale.&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;PLG companies often begin by providing value to end-users or small teams. The bottoms-up adoption fuels viral adoption of the product in organizations. As PLG companies scale, they must also deliver product value to centralized buying personas like IT and executives. To address IT, many PLG companies develop an enterprise version with greater administration and security capabilities. To appeal to executives, some PLG companies, like the database software company MongoDB, naturally deliver enterprise-scale value due to the nature of the product. Other PLG companies, especially those on the application layer, may need to build, acquire or package adjacent products that deliver value on an enterprise scale. HubSpot has done this very effectively, graduating from a lightweight and narrow blogging tool to a fulsome CRM useful for larger enterprises.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Case Study: MongoDB&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The database software company, MongoDB is an example of a company that successfully avoided the PLG Trap, despite starting with a bottoms-up sales motion. (One of us, Jeff, is a partner at a venture capital firm that invested in MongoDB.) With over $1 billion in sales, the company has nearly 2,000 customers spending over $100,000 per year on its software. Yet the company&#39;s origins are as an open-source tool that end users could download for free.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Released in 2009, the company&#39;s initial product — an open source, document-based database tuned for the rise of Internet applications and the era of big data — attracted millions of downloads. As the company grew in popularity among large enterprise customers such as Goldman Sachs and Thermo, it built advanced security features and invested in dramatic scalability in order to earn its way into the enterprise. In parallel, MongoDB created an enterprise-ready sales force, marketing team, and customer success function.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whereas in early 2015, the company had just over 100 customers with over $100,000 per year, by late 2023 that figure had grown 20x. At the same time as it re-engineered the organization to be enterprise-ready, with multiple sales motions, a flexible product configuration, and a large investment in fostering its end-user community. By building both an enterprise-ready organization and a community-driven organization, MongoDB has scaled smoothly beyond the PLG trap to become one of the largest software companies in the world. As of this writing, the product has been downloaded more than 265 million times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By planning ahead, PLG companies can make the necessary strategic decisions to build a team and product platform that is truly enterprise-ready. The PLG model is seductively simple. Winning software companies need to be willing to embrace complexity — expanding beyond the typical managerial advice to “do one thing and do it well” and instead succeed in chewing gum and walking at the same time.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Types of Stories Leaders Need to Tell]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/5-types-of-stories-leaders-need-to-tell]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_1417699431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;horstgerlach/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Storytelling is an important leadership skill, and executives who want to succeed should master five types of narrative: Vision stories, which inspire a shared one; values stories that model the way; action stories that spark progress and change; teaching stories that transmit knowledge and skills to others; and trust stories that help people understand, connect with, and believe in you.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/5-types-of-stories-leaders-need-to-tell?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/5-types-of-stories-leaders-need-to-tell?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The historian Doris Kearns Goodwin was once asked what questions she would put to Abraham Lincoln if given the chance. “I feel like a bad historian,” she answered, “but I&#39;d probably ask him to tell me a story.” As she herself has documented, the 16&lt;sup>;th&lt;/sup>; US president was not just a great political leader but also a masterful raconteur, who used stories to entertain, educate, and inspire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Storytelling is an important leadership skill. As psychologists Gordon H. Bower and Michal C. Clark of Stanford first observed in 1969, we&#39;re 7 times more likely to remember a fact when it&#39;s wrapped in story. Telling stories can also help with all five of the effective leadership practices that Santa Clara University professors James M. Kouzes and Barry Z. Posner lay out in their book &lt;em>;The Leadership Challenge&lt;/em>;: 1) model the way, 2) inspire a shared vision, 3) challenge the process, 4) enable others to act, and 5) encourage the heart&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>; But it&#39;s important to learn which types of stories lead to which outcomes. Here&#39;s a primer.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Trust Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;As noted in The Moth book, &lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://themoth.org/how-to-tell-a-story&quot;>;How to Tell a Story&lt;/a>;, &lt;/em>;“When you choose to share your story, you share a piece of yourself.”&amp;nbsp;In so doing, you start to build trust and connect in new ways with your listeners. Trust stories humanize you as a leader and allow you to &lt;em>;encourage the heart&lt;/em>; of your team.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thasunda Brown Duckett, president and CEO of TIAA, &lt;a href=&quot;https://luvvie.org/podcast/thasunda-brown-duckett/&quot;>;connects her memories&lt;/a>; of being the only Black girl on the soccer team not invited to a teammate&#39;s birthday party to often being the only woman and person of color in a meeting. When you demonstrate vulnerability by sharing a personal story, others will be inspired to reciprocate, creating a virtuous circle of trust.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Teaching Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Brené Brown defines a leader as “anyone who sees potential in people and has the courage to develop that potential.” Great leaders need to be great teachers. Stories allow you to simplify complex topics by providing easy-to-follow models for behavior and skills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As chairman, president, and CEO of Lowe&#39;s, Marvin Ellison uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/03/08/1085285796/lowes-marvin-ellison&quot;>;stories from his life to teach&lt;/a>; his team. Early in his career, when he worked at Target, a senior leader from corporate visited his store and asked employees for feedback. When no one spoke up, Ellison volunteered that a new system wasn&#39;t working as intended. In the end, the system was fixed and Ellison was recognized for speaking up. Now, he tells this story when visiting Lowe&#39;s locations as a way of &lt;em>;enabling others to act &lt;/em>;with candor and promoting a feedback-driven culture.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While a trust story is built around you, a teaching story and the other three types can also be an indirect narrative — using someone else&#39;s story, a fictional one, or a parable to deliver your message. Just make sure your audience can identify and empathize with the protagonist so they want the same thing for themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Action Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A big part of a leader&#39;s job is to inspire action — and one of the best ways to do that is through an story that leaves the audience thinking, “If we do this (insert your desired action here), then we will get that (the desired result).”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entrepreneurs can use action stories to launch new business ideas. Canva founder and CEO Melanie Perkins dreamed of making graphic design accessible. To do this, she needed to create a new story for investors. “People are scared of designing,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2021/02/26/971813519/canva-melanie-perkins-2019&quot;>;Perkins&lt;/a>;. “They&#39;re conditioned their whole lives to think that they&#39;re not creative.” Early success stories included people completing simple design challenges and creating resumes that helped them land jobs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Action stories can also be used to inspire organizational change. Former CEO Indra Nooyi used story to &lt;em>;challenge the process &lt;/em>;at PepsiCo, shifting a product portfolio that was primarily sugar-based to something more health conscious. She wanted to maintain the sense of fun but ensure that it was also good for you. “Words that speak to people&#39;s hearts are more important than speaking to their minds,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/podcasts/worklife/taken-for-granted-indra-nooyi-says-its-time-for-leaders-to-care-part-2-transcript&quot;>;Nooyi shares&lt;/a>;. She developed an indirect narrative to get buy-in from her board, using story to illustrate emerging trends of evolving consumer tastes.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Values Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If you want your team to buy into your organizational values, tell a story that shows someone living into them as a means of &lt;em>;modeling the way&lt;/em>; for them to do so as well.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, to model the family-first mindset at Zoom, founder and CEO Eric Yuan often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/insights/eric-yuan-keeping-customers-employees-happy&quot;>;tells a story&lt;/a>; about being late to the company Christmas party because he was traveling with his son&#39;s basketball team. Chobani&#39;s CEO and founder Hamdi Ulukaya frequently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/podcasts/rethinking-with-adam-grant/anti-ceo-playbook-with-chobani-founder-hamdi-ulukaya-transcript&quot;>;shares tales&lt;/a>; of growing up amid corruption in Turkey and explains how it made him want to become a more ethical business leader. These stories communicate personal and organizational values and encourage values-driven behavior in others.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Vision Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;History is full of examples of leaders using vision stories. Following the evacuation at Dunkirk, Winston Churchill vividly described a Britain that would “fight on the seas and oceans” and “never surrender.” In his iconic “I Have a Dream” speech, Martin Luther King, Jr. used story to paint a picture of a world in which “man would not be judged by the color of his skin but the content of his character.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In business, GM CEO Mary Barra &lt;a href=&quot;/podcast/2021/05/ceo-series-mary-barra-of-general-motors-on-committing-to-an-eco-friendly-future&quot;>;uses story&lt;/a>; to illustrate a future with “zero crashes, zero emissions, and zero congestion.” In taking the reins as the first non-founder CEO at Microsoft, Satya Nadella needed to shift the culture internally from being “know-it-alls” to “learn-it-alls.” To promote the “learn-it-all” mindset, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/podcasts/satya-nadella-is-building-the-future-transcript&quot;>;Nadella shared a story about his dad&lt;/a>;. “He had this diary he would write in every day — people met, ideas generated to act on. It&#39;s a continuous system.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stories make the unseen future feel vivid and real, &lt;em>;inspiring a shared vision&lt;/em>; that listeners will commit to and make progress toward.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Kouzes and Posner&#39;s title implies, leadership is a challenge. But story can help with all five practices of effective leadership. Vision stories inspire a shared one. Values stories model the way. Action stories can spark change and, in turn, challenge the process. Teaching stories transmit knowledge and skills to others, enabling them to act. And when you share your own story you build trust and encourage the heart.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the Food Industry Is Using Cross-Training to Boost Service]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-the-food-industry-is-using-cross-training-to-boost-service]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_22_1137557948.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;HBR Staff; Mesut Ugurlu/Getty Images; Unsplash&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;Cross-training employees on a variety of tasks can be a powerful tool for improving operations, as well as for attracting and retaining workers. When employees are cross-trained to perform a variety of both customer-facing and non-customer-facing tasks, they can adjust their work depending on demand and business needs. Of course, that&amp;#8217;s good for the business, but it also makes the job better for workers. For one thing, when employees are more productive and contribute more, companies can pay them more. Cross-training helps employees build capabilities that they can leverage in their career growth. It also enables more stable schedules. This article shows how several small food companies were able to use cross-training to improve service and job quality. Any industry can learn from these approaches to improve operations, customer experience, and employee experience.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-the-food-industry-is-using-cross-training-to-boost-service?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-the-food-industry-is-using-cross-training-to-boost-service?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;People are dining out again, but restaurants aren&#39;t always &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/30/dining/restaurant-prices-service.html?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Issue:%202023-05-30%20Restaurant%20Dive%20%5Bissue:50879%5D&amp;amp;utm_term=Restaurant%20Dive&quot;>;able to serve them well&lt;/a>;. Like many other service businesses, they face two operational challenges: attracting and retaining enough workers, and coping with highly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/chain-restaurant-local-restaurant-closing-11673616374&quot;>;variable demand&lt;/a>;. One lever for improving on both counts is cross-training — that is, training employees for a variety of tasks.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cross-training is a powerful tool, but it is far from a new idea: One of us (Zeynep) first observed cross-training as part of a &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/11/the-case-for-good-jobs&quot;>;“good jobs system”&lt;/a>; that enabled low-cost retailers like Costco and Trader Joe&#39;s to pay more than their competitors while driving better value for customers. Beyond the service industry, manufacturers like Toyota have &lt;a href=&quot;/1999/09/decoding-the-dna-of-the-toyota-production-system&quot;>;long practiced&lt;/a>; cross-training to improve motivation and involve the frontlines in continuous improvement. And in their landmark &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/0030507376900167&quot;>;1976 study&lt;/a>;, J. Richard Hackman and Greg R. Oldham identified task variety as a driver of employee motivation across a variety of industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When employees are cross-trained to perform a variety of both customer-facing and non-customer-facing tasks, they can adjust their work depending on demand and business needs. Of course, that&#39;s good for the business, but it also makes the job a &lt;em>;better&lt;/em>; job for workers. For one thing, when employees are more productive and contribute more, companies can pay them more; higher productivity is what enables a typical Costco worker to earn &lt;a href=&quot;https://s201.q4cdn.com/287523651/files/doc_events/2023/Jan/19/costco-annual-shareholders&#39;-meeting-slide-deck-jan2023.pdf&quot;>;almost $10 an hour&lt;/a>; more than a typical retail worker. Cross-training helps employees build capabilities that they can leverage in their career growth and career paths. Cross-training also enables more stable schedules; instead of changing the number of workers throughout the day or week, companies can keep more consistent teams and just change &lt;em>;what&lt;/em>; they do, instead of changing &lt;em>;who&lt;/em>; is scheduled to work.&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;The New Age of Operations&quot; dek=&quot;Improving efficiency and increasing resilience.&quot; cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;But these benefits should be balanced with a possible downside: a lack of specialization and ownership. At the Good Jobs Institute, our work with a variety of small food businesses has shown us how they can make the best use of cross-training to improve service and job quality. Any industry can learn from these approaches to design flexibility into their job design and operations.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Approaches to Cross-Training at Three Small Food Businesses&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Employees don&#39;t have to be cross-trained to do everything, but a little bit of cross-training can go a long way. Three small food businesses we&#39;ve worked with have each found their own way to balance flexibility with specialization and ownership:&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Counter service&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At two franchised locations of the Moe&#39;s Original BBQ chain, there was a strict boundary between front-of-house and kitchen teams, making it difficult to adjust to demand peaks. Owner Dewey Hasbrouck introduced cross-training between the two specialized teams so that they could cover each other on typical bottleneck tasks. For instance, when there were long lines at the counter, kitchen staff could now step in to answer the phones, bring food out to tables, and bag to-go orders. If it was the kitchen that was backlogged, the front-of-house team could fill sauce cups, restock the line, and prepare basic sides.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Bakery&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At She Wolf Bakery, the production team baked bread in the bakery and the sales team sold it at New York City Greenmarkets, seldom interacting. The teams were often busy at different times: the production team would be overwhelmed preparing bread on Fridays, while the sales team was busiest on Saturdays.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Head of operations Kim Vallejo realized there was an opportunity to better integrate the two teams. While bakers were already being trained on some of the packing duties, She Wolf also started offering a four-hour paid bakery orientation for new sales team members, during which they could take part in the bread-making process. They learned basic bakery side work like running the dish pit and oiling pans, which were very helpful to bakers during a rush, and the two teams also got to know each other better, which made them more motivated to help each other out.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Full service&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Tacombi, a Mexican restaurant chain with locations in New York City, introduced cross-training while navigating the city&#39;s strict tipping regulations, which don&#39;t allow employees in non-tipped roles to perform customer-facing tasks. The staff in their full-service concepts included many highly specialized roles, such as hosts, runners, bussers, and servers in the front, and dishwashers, prep cooks, quality control leaders (who manage the kitchen flow and check quality), and chefs in the back.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Operations leader Jose De La Campa noticed that scheduling these specialists was very complex and created service issues when someone called out sick. The work wasn&#39;t evenly distributed over time; at any given moment, the prep cooks might have nothing to do while the dish washers were swamped. But they were neither trained nor expected to help each other. De La Campa decided to reduce the number of specialist job codes; for example, in most restaurants, he combined the responsibilities of prep cooks and dishwashers, combined the roles of head chef and quality control leader, and removed the host role, redistributing that work to the other front-of-house positions, such as servers.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;The Impact of Cross-Training on Performance and Jobs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When employees can contribute to different parts of the business, it can improve service, increase production capacity, and make jobs better for the people doing them.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Better service&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At She Wolf, cross-training helped teams take more ownership to keep production running when faced with the unexpected variability of call outs, so they could always be there for their customers with quality bread. According to Vallejo, “If we are in the weeds and down three people and it&#39;s a Friday and all hands on deck, my delivery driver knows how to run the dish pit and they can jump back there and help us get ahead.” Training market team members on basic prep tasks also freed up bakers&#39; time to focus on higher-value tasks, ensuring bread quality didn&#39;t suffer due to unexpected variability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Tacombi relied on highly specialized roles, an absent dishwasher could paralyze operations. With fewer specialist roles and appropriate cross-training, an unexpected sick day could more easily be absorbed by the rest of the team. De La Campa also said that it improved the food and service: The head chef now had more ownership over quality control, motivating them to identify issues and provide proper feedback to the rest of the team.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Higher production capacity&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;At Moe&#39;s Original BBQ, because team members could flex into different customer-facing and non-customer-facing tasks, they had enough slack to deal with demand peaks. This translated to higher-quality food and service. More significantly, the cross-trained team had the expertise to take on more catering orders. Catering sales increased by 60% in the first year, without Moe&#39;s having to significantly change its staffing levels.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Better jobs&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;All three businesses ended up raising pay. Their cross-trained employees were more productive and could contribute to more areas of the operation, making higher pay a good investment. Cross-training created a new talent pipeline for She Wolf: By allowing the market staff to get production experience, management could identify potential new bakers and help them make the transition onto the bakery team when they needed to hire. For those employees, this meant career growth and higher wages. Cross-training also helped these businesses give their people better — that is, more regular — schedules, since staffing didn&#39;t necessarily have to lurch up and down with the number of customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cross-training helped make the work more meaningful. At Moe&#39;s Original BBQ, cross-training contributed to better communication and a sense of belonging: The staff started insisting that they be referred to as “one team,” not “front-of-house” and “back-of-house.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The combination of higher pay, better schedules, and better work helped Moe&#39;s Original BBQ reduce employee turnover by 30%, which then helped them improve their performance even more.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;Why Cross-Training Isn&#39;t More Common&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Many company leaders like the idea of cross-training, but aren&#39;t convinced it will work for them. Some think their employees can&#39;t handle — or aren&#39;t motivated to learn — a variety of roles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One genuine risk is that introducing cross-training &lt;em>;in isolation&lt;/em>; could create operational problems; if employees are already overloaded or have low tenure, or if the company can&#39;t set and enforce high expectations, introducing cross-training might lead to more errors and frustration. The key is creating &lt;em>;a system that enables cross-training. &lt;/em>;At the small food businesses, this involved some complementary choices:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Simplifying operations to remove non-value-add work so that employees only spend their time learning tasks that improve the customer experience.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Simplifying operations to reduce &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/03/give-service-workers-stable-schedules&quot;>;self-inflicted variability&lt;/a>;&amp;nbsp;— that is, to smooth the workload and make the peaks more manageable.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Setting clear standards to ensure that employees can be consistent in different roles.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Empowering employees to use their judgment to decide which tasks to do when.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Staffing with slack so that people have enough time to learn new tasks.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Investing in people to attract and retain great staff and hold teams accountable to high expectations.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Moe&#39;s Original BBQ had been trying to introduce cross-training for several years, but because of high turnover, it was a struggle just to get employees through basic training. So, in addition to cross-training, owner Hasbrouck made other operational changes to set his team up for success, such as simplifying the menu and smoothing the workload by moving specials from weekends to weekdays. He also made significant investments in his people, increasing full-time pay from $15 an hour to $20 an hour in Maine, plus tips. Higher pay came, however, with higher expectations: Hasbrouck changed the job description to state, “We want employees capable of doing it all.” Adding cross-training made the job worth more to the business and the higher pay made the additional responsibility and higher expectations worth it for employees.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Changes like these don&#39;t happen overnight, but a better system can drive operational excellence and let teams live up to their potential. Food businesses and other service industries are facing headwinds, but cross-training can ensure that they are up for the challenge, providing better service while also improving the lives of their employees and preserving vibrant businesses in their communities.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Video Quick Take: SAP&rsquo;s Aaron Green on Building the Brightest Talent Pools in the Tightest Labor Market - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/video-quick-take-saps-aaron-green-on-building-the-brightest-talent-pools-in-the-tightest-labor-market]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;p>;&lt;b>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div data-props=&quot;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;6337163366112&quot;}&quot; js- target=&quot;video-player-page&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;span>;加载中.. . &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;script src=&quot;//players.brightcove.net/2071817190001/default_default/index.min.js&quot;>;&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;朱莉·德沃尔&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢迎收看今天的《哈佛商业评论》快速报道。 I&#39;m Julie Devoll, editor for special projects and webinars at HBR.今天我们采访的是 SAP SuccessFactors 的首席营销和解决方案官 Aaron Green。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;嘿，朱莉。感谢您邀请我来到这里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;朱莉·德沃尔&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>; if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;嗨，亚伦。非常感谢您今天加入我们。让我们开始吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当今的组织面临着许多挑战，无论是市场动态的变化还是劳动力短缺。他们如何才能在当今的环境中并着眼于未来取得成功？有哪些障碍？他们如何前进？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;亚伦·格林&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，绝对如此。朱莉，我认为当今组织面临的首要问题或挑战实际上可能是技能差距本身。这是我们所有客户真正关心的事情。事实上，技能是未来工作的新货币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这从根本上意味着我们需要重新思考留住和吸引人才以及在正确的时间寻找正确的技能的方式在组织中。在最近的一项调查中，超过 75% 的企业领导者表示，雇用和留住人才是实现增长的头号最关键因素。我们知道，我们的员工是任何组织所拥有的最宝贵的资产。我们的员工使我们能够创新、竞争和成长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这对组织来说意味着我们必须能够了解我们今天拥有的技能，但也了解这些技能未来需要的。并制定提升技能、交叉技能、重新技能的计划，并在某些情况下从外部市场引入这些技能。这确实是任何公司，尤其是成长型或规模化公司，都需要思考如何看待人才。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;朱莉·德沃尔&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我想稍微转向一下工具和流程。当组织致力于使用不同的工具在其所有实践中分享见解和情报时，员工如何体验这种变化？&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/ javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>;亚伦·格林&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的。因此，我们知道，为了提供非凡的客户体验或客户成果，您确实必须拥有非凡的员工体验（雇主和员工的价值主张），因为当您这样做时，当您真正关注员工时，您的人们最终会获得更有意义的工作经历。无论您身处哪个行业或地区，这些都会转化为更高的生产力和更好的客户体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这实际上意味着您必须实时了解所有员工类型的劳动力总数，包括您的临时劳动力，因为这些见解可以让您真正了解您的员工拥有的技能、他们的愿望、他们的工作偏好以及他们的表现。它确实可以让组织将其与未来的劳动力相匹配，并确保您的员工了解组织未来发展计划的路径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;朱莉·德沃尔&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我想展望未来。您如何看待人工智能和自动化帮助组织以目前无法真正做到的方式提高这些洞察力和效率？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;亚伦·格林&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的。因此，毫无疑问，人工智能是目前的超级热门话题。 SAP SuccessFactors 拥有超过 9,600 名客户，每天与超过 2.5 亿唯一用户合作，我们对此深感荣幸。我们的客户一直在与我们谈论人工智能。事实上，在我们最近所做的一项研究中，我们发现招聘和学习是组织考虑如何投资人工智能以真正实现当今所需的许多手动任务自动化的两个最优先领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是有一些新兴的用例，比如用于更复杂的管理任务的聊天机器人或人力资源自助服务或票务，还有人工智能来推动我们已经讨论过的一些内部流动性，着眼于技能个人资料和职业道路，并利用它来实际将人员与组织内部的机会相匹配，无论他们是短期角色、零工还是长期角色。但从根本上讲，这意味着人工智能驱动的人才情报平台对于所有组织（无论是人力资源还是更广泛的员工群体）都将变得比以往更加重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Julie Devoll&lt;/强>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;嗯，亚伦，这是一次很棒的谈话。非常感谢您今天加入我们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;亚伦·格林&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;感谢您邀请我。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.375509780;dc_trk_aid=566751408;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfu a=;ltd=; dc_tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;了解更多信息。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Aaron Green 是 SAP SuccessFactors 的首席营销和主管。解决方案官员。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 04:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Growth-Focused Organizations Can Meet the Needs of a Shifting Workforce - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM SAP]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/how-growth-focused-organizations-can-meet-the-needs-of-a-shifting-workforce]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/英雄图像>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img 咏叹调-scribedby=&quot;caption-attachment-364386&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/HR_OPT1.png&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;作者：Aaron Green&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在当今的竞争格局中，员工是组织脱颖而出的关键。他们独特的技能、经验和贡献帮助公司创新、竞争和成长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，由于技术和创新引入的速度，组织所需的技能在不断变化。事实上，经济合作与发展组织估计技术将颠覆&lt;a href=&quot;/2023/06/build-a-strong-learning-culture-on-your-team#:~:text=According% 20to%20the%20OECD%2C%201.1,do%20new%20types%20of%20work)。&quot;>;未来五年将创造 11 亿个就业岗位&lt;/a>; — 使技能差距成为以增长为重点的组织面临的最大障碍之一今天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决这些差距首先要弄清楚您现在和将来需要哪些技能，以及您是否应该通过单独招聘或通过提升现有员工的技能、交叉技能和再培训来获得这些技能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;所有组织（尤其是注重增长的组织）都需要采用基于技能的方法来看待人才。但要实现这一点，您需要专为这项工作而构建的技术。如果没有它，人力资源和招聘团队就缺乏集成的实时数据框架，这意味着他们更多地根据直觉而不是数据驱动的证据做出决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考虑到以增长为重点的组织面临的许多挑战如今，例如快速变化的市场条件、保持员工生产力和敬业度的需要，以及吸引顶尖人才的竞争，拥有合适的人力资源技术来满足您的业务和员工不断变化的需求可以改变游戏规则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;互联的云人力资源和企业资源规划 (ERP) 方法有助于将数据从孤岛中解放出来，以便所有部门都可以实时访问相同的人员数据。这可以提高效率和生产力，降低运营成本和违规风险，改善人们的工作体验，并帮助组织将具备所需技能的人员分配到合适的角色。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot; >; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div >; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;将人置于业务转型的核心&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;投资于这项技术意味着投资于您的员工——而人是推动业务转型的动力。如今，人们期望员工体验 (EX) 中的每次互动都像网上购物一样轻松、无缝且个性化。通过使用技术来增强 EX（从自动化耗时的流程到提供个性化的学习建议），人们可以获得更有意义的工作体验，从而转化为更积极的员工队伍、更高的生产力和更好的业务成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司例如 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/asset/dynamic/2022/08/ed4692e7-32d5-49e9-9240-a0a2dc2f8909.html&quot;>;MOD 披萨&lt;/a>;，&lt;a href= “https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/07/cc941e1e-ee7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Growmark&lt;/a>;，以及&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. sap.com/uk/documents/2021/10/54f5d640-fd7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Sun 社区&lt;/a>;是一个很好的例子，说明如何通过加强人力资源与业务运营之间的联系来关注以人为本推动增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了消除招聘和入职流程中的摩擦并使新员工更快地提高工作效率，MOD Pizza 的人力资源团队确定需要用可扩展的云来取代孤立的人员数据和手动流程基于技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迁移到 HR 和 ERP 的单一云平台帮助 MOD Pizza 每月自动化 1,000 名员工的入职，以及与新员工、晋升和离职相关的每日 400 项事件变更，从而实现每周手动数据输入时间减少 15 小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该公司还在招聘和入职体验中集成了调查接触点，以在员工生命周期的这一重要阶段收集反馈。这种互联方法正在帮助 MOD Pizza 提高整个业务的效率，同时改善 EX。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农业企业合作社 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/documents/2021/07/cc941e1e -ee7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Growmark&lt;/a>; 管理 3,600 名内部员工的人力资源，并为其成员公司的另外 4,200 名员工提供薪资支持。通过迁移到基于云的解决方案来简化 HR 和 ERP 运营，帮助 Growmark 集成管理流程、提高整个业务的可见性并实现手动任务的自动化。结合人员和运营数据的分析有助于确保 Growmark 将员工置于绩效跟踪、风险规划和决策的中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/uk/ Documents/2021/10/54f5d640-fd7d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&quot;>;Sun Communities&lt;/a>; 是一家领先的制造住房社区和休闲车度假村的所有者和运营商，通过更换遗留下来的拼凑物，改变了其业务流程具有基于云的集成解决方案的工具。这有助于人力资源人员简化招聘、入职、绩效管理和薪资等流程和经验的管理，而无需依赖内部 IT 资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;像这样以增长为中心的组织需要确保其人力资源系统、经验和战略不会在脱节的状态下运行。理想的平台汇集了组织所需的人才、人口统计、经验和运营数据，以为其人力资源、财务、供应链和客户决策提供信息。通过这种连接，组织还可以用端到端自动化业务流程和改进的体验来取代传统和低效的流程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实时洞察您的员工总数并了解由此对您的影响业务，您可以为您的企业和员工释放新的机会。您可以深入了解员工的技能、愿望、偏好和绩效。此视图使您的业务需求与员工的需求、愿望和能力前所未有地保持一致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;借助正确的云技术，当今以增长为重点的组织正在加强人力资源在整个行业中的联系。业务并在整个员工队伍中扩展个性化 EX。这些组织正在更智能地工作，更快地招聘，并为未来做好规划，这让他们的员工很高兴成为他们未来的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ad. doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N69702.124507HBRHARVARDBUSINESSR/B29173838.363679977;dc_trk_aid=554528446;dc_trk_cid=189409904;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=;dc _tdv=1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;了解更多&lt; /strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Aaron Green 是 SAP SuccessFactors 的首席营销和主管。解决方案官员。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 03:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Smaller Manufacturers Can Upgrade Their Tech]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/how-smaller-manufacturers-can-upgrade-their-tech]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_21_1555842817.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Westend61/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span >;摘要。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;对于中小企业制造商来说，现在正是通过投资新软件和制造创新来升级运营的好时机。原因包括原始设备制造商面临建立更具弹性的供应链和区域化生产的压力，以及成本下降和新技术易用性的提高。本文介绍了中小企业采用这些技术可以采取的六个步骤。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how -smaller-manufacturers-can-upgrade-their-tech?language=es&quot;>;阅读西班牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/how-smaller-manufacturers-can-upgrade-their- tech?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;疫情后推动供应链更具区域性和弹性，为许多国内中小企业创造了增长机会（大型原始设备制造商 (OEM) 所依赖的中小企业 (SME)。这些中小企业在 2000 年代的离岸外包浪潮中幸存下来，通常是因为它们为汽车、航空航天或工业设备行业生产产量较低或运输成本较高的零部件。但当增长不多时，投资新设备或设施对他们来说是一项挑战。现在，一些增长正在恢复，这些中小企业有机会采用新的软件和制造创新，并重新思考如何提高运营效率和生产力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去三年我们与美国中西部的众多中小企业、贸易协会和美国政府支持的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/mep&quot;>;制造推广合作伙伴关系 (MEP)&lt;/a>; 进行了交谈。 MEP 由国家标准研究院设立，旨在帮助中小企业制造商，遍布全美 50 个州和波多黎各。我们中的一位（Ali Shakouri）还与印第安纳州的中小企业进行了广泛的合作，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nam.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MFG-GSP- FactSheet_201810.pdf&quot;>;28.6%&lt;/a>; 用于制造业的州生产总值比例最高。我们发现，这些公司在采用新技术方面往往相当保守，原因如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;他们不愿意改变现有的有效流程，并且这些流程已经为他们提供了良好的服务。 &lt;/li>; &lt;li>;由于来自客户和外国竞争的持续成本压力，面对不断增长的需求或生产能力的限制，他们的投资兴趣有限。&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;或者他们发现数字技术令人畏惧，因为需要学习新技能或开发新的工作方式。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;这通常意味着他们没有跟上正在改变竞争格局的技术。在 2000 年代离岸外包热潮期间，许多制造商将大部分大批量生产转移到海外，对最新工具和技术的投资也转移到了海外。例如，在金属铸造行业，这一点很明显，因为在低成本国家建立了配备最新工具的新工厂。在熔模铸造领域，中国和印度的新工厂配备了最新的生产工具，而美国工厂则保留着旧的生产工具。当您成长时，投资最新技术是很容易的；当你没有的时候，更容易坚持你所拥有的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在这样看待它是错误的——这实际上是投资的时刻。以下是六种入门方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;1.利用新的仿真软件工具。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;计算机辅助设计工具已经陪伴我们数十年，它们彻底改变了工程的所有分支 - 从机械零件和化学工艺到电子产品和半导体的所有设计和分析。然而，引人注目的是这些工具的日益复杂性以及软件开发人员为使它们更易于使用且更便宜而进行的投资。然而，中小企业的采用进展缓慢。&lt;/p>; &lt;article-promo>; &lt;hbr-component type=&quot;promo&quot; is-insight=&quot;insight-center&quot; title=&quot;运营新时代&quot; dek=&quot;提高效率和增强韧性。” cta-text=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/insight-center/the-new-age-of-operations&quot; style= &quot;color:black;text-decoration:none&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; 洞察中心集合 &lt;/div>; &lt;h3>;运营新时代&lt;/h3>; &lt;div>; 提高效率并增强弹性。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hbr-component>; &lt;/article-promo>; &lt;p>;仿真建模工具可以成为改进操作的捷径。它们使公司能够更好地建模和理解其流程，这可以揭示瓶颈和约束，从而带来新的运营方式。这些工具在过去十年中在易用性方面取得了长足的进步，其中许多工具基于云，具有简单的拖放界面，并提供构建块，您可以合并这些构建块以使模型易于构建。更复杂的软件包提供了构建数字孪生的机会 - 一个逼真的运营数字模型，不仅包括机器和物料搬运系统，还包括在那里工作的人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一家公司的一个很好的例子，仿真工具发挥了重要作用&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pelcoinc.com/&quot;>;Pelco Products&lt;/a>;，一家位于俄克拉荷马州埃德蒙市的交通和公用事业产品（如路灯、电线杆）制造商和行人按钮。随着多年来的发展，其生产流程不断扩大并减慢了生产速度。为了改进它们，创始人的儿子 Steve Parduhn 引入了俄克拉荷马州制造联盟 (OMA)，即该州的 MEP。 Parduhn 在使用 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketchup.com/&quot;>;Sketchup&lt;/a>; 和 &lt;a href=&quot;https:// 的软件构建部分生产流程的数字仿真模型方面获得了帮助www.simio.com/&quot;>;Simio&lt;/a>;。这使得 Pelco 在开始移动设备之前可以虚拟地测试新场景。它甚至能够在将新技术和设备带到现场之前对其进行模拟。工厂产能的增加节省了 100 万美元的成本，并增加了 500 万美元的新销售额。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;2.将数据和新的分析技术投入使用。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;中小企业制造商经常从其运营中收集大量数据，但大多数没有利用新的人工智能 (AI)，包括机器学习 (ML) 工具来从数据中获得新的见解。对于没有经验的公司来说，这可能会令人生畏，因此关键是从简单开始并学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与普渡大学的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward 合作?AWD_ID=2134667&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&quot;>;AI-Commons 团队&lt;/a>;，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tmfcenter.com/history&quot;>;TMF Center&lt;/a>;，一家位于印第安纳州威廉斯波特的公司，安装了廉价的功耗传感器来确定复杂零件加工操作的使用模式。这帮助它开始对活动进行分类并开发商店绩效的实时仪表板。位于印第安纳州拉斐特的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kirbyrisk.com/mechanical-solutions/&quot;>;Kirby Risk Manufacturing&lt;/a>; 正在尝试使用声音传感器和机器学习来检测操作过程中的质量问题，这将允许它可以更快地识别和解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样，&lt;a href=&quot;https://primient.com/about&quot;>;Primient&lt;/a>;，一家位于伊利诺伊州绍姆堡的食品配料公司，能够与普渡大学合作，为其拉斐特玉米甜味剂工厂开发一个简单的机器学习成像应用程序，帮助其操作员评估糖晶体尺寸分布的生产过程，该特征决定了晶体在食品中溶解的速度，因此它们尝起来多么甜啊。新的应用程序为以前需要操作员判断的过程提供了测量精度，该过程容易出现人为错误和广泛的变化。机器学习应用程序为其开始使用其广泛的生产数据来提高产量和运营效率奠定了基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;3.了解如何实现简单的自动化。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;虽然许多中小企业采用了一定程度的自动化，但通常采用预设包的形式，例如作为昂贵附加组件的一部分购买的自动工具交换系统或自动工件装载机- 机床。通常有许多“肮脏、乏味和危险”的工作仍然由手工完成，而自动化不仅可以通过减少变异性来提高产品质量，而且可以通过让工人解放出来在其他地方从事更有生产力和更理想的工作来改善工人的工作。的过程。但对于没有经验的中小企业来说，这些项目都是令人生畏的。同样，答案是从小项目开始，向欧洲议会议员等组织学习并获得帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄克拉荷马州制造联盟副总裁 Kinnee Tilly 描述了该联盟如何帮助&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rise-manufacturing/about/&quot;>;Rise Manufacturing&lt;/a>; 是一家位于俄克拉荷马州布罗肯阿罗的公司，为航空航天、国防和工业领域提供制造和组装服务。石油和天然气客户。疫情期间，Rise 的产品需求激增，导致其制造流程出现瓶颈。 “他们有一个手动抛光过程，人为差异正在悄然蔓延，”蒂莉解释道。 “我们有些人一生中从未接触过机器人之类的东西，他们对此非常警惕，因为他们觉得自己将被取代。” OMA 借给它一个&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.automate.org/a3-content/what-are-collaborative-robots&quot;>;协作机器人&lt;/a>;（“cobot”），这是一种轻型机械臂，编程简单，可以安全地与工作人员共享空间，以帮助 Rise 启动并运行流程。工人们看到了好处。 “一旦我们完成了，我们不仅没有取代员工，还提高了他们的技能，并让他们找到了更好的工作，”蒂莉说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;4。了解生产工具和方法的最新进展。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;对于中小企业来说，了解其行业中使用的最新工具和流程对于加快生产周期和提高质量非常重要。例如，数字铸造技术涵盖模拟、打印原型、打印模具和激光计量，可以帮助降低成本，并使中小企业金属铸造厂能够更有效地与海上生产竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有操作，无论是专用的还是专用的生产或服务领域的企业也将受益于更好地应用丰田教授的方法。几乎每个 MEP 都会教授精益方法、拉动系统、可视化工作场所概念和流程改进的改善方法。然而，许多中小企业将从对基本概念的更深入理解和对这些技术的更认真应用中受益。丰田的生产系统并不是一成不变的，而是在不断&lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/what-really-makes-toyotas-product-system-resilient&quot;>;改进&lt;/a>;，中小企业也将从中受益。&lt; /p>; &lt;h2>;5。利用大学和外部资源的援助计划。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;MEP 计划旨在帮助中小企业提高能力并开始采用新技术。普渡大学负责管理印第安纳州的 MEP 和该州的&lt;a href=&quot;https://tap.purdue.edu/&quot;>;技术援助计划&lt;/a>;，在采用新技术方面提供广泛的培训和服务。它甚至将中小企业与大学教职员工和学生联系起来，每年在各个领域提供长达 40 小时的帮助，包括先进过程控制、材料、故障分析、传感器使用和应用以及工程分析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;各国也可以提供直接援助。自 2020 年起，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iedc.in.gov/&quot;>;印第安纳经济发展公司&lt;/a>; (IEDC) 与非营利组织&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conexusindiana .com/&quot;>;Conexus Indiana&lt;/a>;，一直在提供匹配的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conexusindiana.com/drive-industry-success/manufacturing-readiness-grants/&quot;>;制造准备补助金&lt;/ a>; 寻求实现运营现代化或集成智能技术和流程以提高产能和速度并提高质量的公司。中小企业最多可以申请 20 万美元，并且必须按等额匹配。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://photonautomation.com/&quot;>;Photon Automation&lt;/a>; 是印第安纳州汉考克县一家拥有 67 名员工的中小企业，利用 183,000 美元的赠款，为&lt;a href= “https://www.conexusindiana.com/case-study/photon-automation/&quot;>;电池产品制造&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;6.利用同行关系。&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;农业合作社通过知识共享在 20 世纪早期和中期农业技术的采用中发挥了重要作用。中小企业制造商同样可以从非正式的网络和经验分享中受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此类合作的一个例子：普渡大学 AI-Commons 团队一直在与一群中小企业合作，分享实施&lt;a href= “https://www.computerscience Degreehub.com/faq/what-is-edge-analytics/&quot;>;边缘分析设备&lt;/a>;并受益于&lt;a href=&quot;https://business.mydatacan.org/&quot;>;保护隐私的数据共享&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;时机&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;现在是中小企业制造商投资自身转型的时机。建立更具弹性的供应链和生产区域化的压力为国内制造商提供了难得的增长机会，在此期间他们可以更新其运营和运营策略。他们不应该错过这个机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- 引用 -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Research: Consumers Choose Shared Experiences Over Quality Ones]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/research-consumers-choose-shared-experiences-over-quality-ones]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;英雄图像 >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sept23_21_1399018466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label= &quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;塔拉·摩尔/盖蒂图片社&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt; span>;总结。&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;一些消费者在单独使用时体验是最好的。但新的研究表明，人们会为了与伴侣或亲人分享而放弃高质量的体验。结果，他们的日子可能会更糟，从而导致消费者不满意、销售额下降和商机被忽视。本文解释了为什么人们倾向于团结在一起，即使这不一定有益，并概述了营销人员可以鼓励人们分开（即使是短暂的）以提高他们的满意度的几种方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/research-consumers-choose-shared-experiences-over-quality-ones?language=es&quot;>;阅读en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/research-consumers-choose-shared-experiences-over-quality-ones?language=pt&quot;>;葡萄牙语&lt;/a>; &lt;/div >; &lt;p>;人们的生活通常是与他人共度美好时光和独处时间的结合。有些体验似乎是为了团聚 - 例如，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ama.org/shared-conspiration-experiences-2/&quot;>;最近的估计&lt;/a>;表明 90% 的电影院参观发生在电影院与其他人一起——而其他人则更适合独处时间，例如阅读或绘画。虽然人们经常自己决定如何度过自己的时间，但公司的选择也会影响这些决定。企业的设计或明或暗地旨在鼓励消费者与他人在一起或独处——例如每排有两个座位的游乐园游乐设施，或者提供吧台座位的餐厅，这样人们就不需要坐在空椅子旁的桌子旁在他们对面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些决策对客户体验有什么影响？特别是，当人们面临两难境地时会发生什么：选择是在朋友或伴侣旁边体验某些事情，即使它可能会降低质量，还是获得更高质量的服务，但分开做？例如，决定是否在音乐会上选择远离舞台的两个相邻座位或在场地前排选择两个不相邻的座位，或者等待更长的时间与全家人一起去游乐园游乐设施&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://myscp.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/jcpy.1352&quot;>;我们的研究最近发表在&lt;em>;期刊上消费者心理学&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;的研究表明，消费者经常选择质量较低的服务，以便在活动期间与同伴保持身体距离。 People will select these lower-quality options even in situations that offer little opportunity for interaction (like a yoga class), even when they know they&#39;ll have plenty of togetherness time later (like taking a flight on the way to a long vacation together) — and even when companies specifically tell them that services are designed to be experienced solo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumers so value togetherness that they will choose less-pleasing experiences or even skip high-quality experiences just because they cannot be physically next to someone they care about. This can result in unsatisfied consumers, lower sales, and neglected business opportunities. Luckily, our research has also identified some strategies marketers can implement to encourage consumers to be apart from a companion if needed.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Tradeoffs Between Togetherness and Quality&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To test the idea that people will choose social over solitary experiences, even when the latter may be more enjoyable, we first analyzed Tripadvisor reviews of the interactive play &lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g60763-d2631104-Reviews-Sleep_No_More-New_York_City_New_York.html&quot;>;Sleep No More&lt;/a>;&lt;/em>;. This is a unique experience in New York City: people who attend this play walk around several theatrically designed rooms reliving the classic Shakespearean tragedy &lt;em>;Macbeth&lt;/em>;. Importantly, this experience has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://lauraperuchi.nyc/sleep-no-more-the-intriguing-immersive-play-in-new-york-city/&quot;>;optimized for&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playbill.com/article/9-tips-for-attending-the-award-winning-sleep-no-more&quot;>;aloneness&lt;/a>;: the creators highlight that audience members should be silent, that people should walk at their own pace, and that staying with one&#39;s partner would create barriers between the audience and the actors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yet, we observe that some visitors (45 out of the 312 reviews we coded) explicitly ignored these instructions and chose to stay with their companion, even though everyone was informed that they would meet their companion at the bar inside for an after-party discussion. What&#39;s more, visitors who stayed with their companion rated the experience lower on Tripadvisor, about 25% below that of those who went through the experience apart from their companion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We then conducted a series of experiments in lab and online settings to understand &lt;em>;why&lt;/em>; consumers prioritize togetherness with a partner over the quality of experience, asking people to make choices about chocolate, seats for a show, or spots for a class. For example, in one study that we conducted at the behavioral lab of Mays Business School at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, we asked students to make a choice about how many chocolates they would like to share with another participant: they could either get two chocolates (one per person) and eat them together or they could get four chocolates (two per person) and eat them apart. We found that more people chose the option of eating fewer chocolates with another person when instructed that their companion would be a new friend as opposed to a stranger.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ultimately, and perhaps unsurprisingly, we concluded that people want to remember experiences as shared with people they know, and they believe that physical proximity facilitates the creation of special memories. Many people even recognize that getting an experience of lower quality is in fact less enjoyable even when shared with someone else — and yet they still choose less-pleasing experiences to remember the activity as shared. This can pose a problem: &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0956797614551162?casa_token=1snj7Bf_JVEAAAAA:UeUIT8XJKIkPgakpSoHGTfcdi_IQ4Ugm1F31dIy5BkZBMwM5k-uQ5wuPhSuZSqdoLHeLfO4JS74I6g&quot;>;research&lt;/a>; by Erica J. Boothby and colleagues demonstrates that sharing an experience with someone enhances the enjoyment &lt;em>;only&lt;/em>; if the experience is positive to start off. Their theory suggests that when people share a negative experience (eg, they watch a bad movie together), they will perceive it as even &lt;em>;more&lt;/em>; unpleasant when engaging in the experience with someone else as opposed to alone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This creates a dilemma for marketers and customer experience managers: many people will explicitly ignore your attempts to activity something solo, which may be fine if they enjoy the product or service. But if they don&#39;t, their reaction will be even more negative because they shared it with someone else.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Making Solo Experiences More Enjoyable&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;If the experiences your company provides would benefit from consumers being solo (at least during a part of the activity), there are a few ways to encourage people to choose higher-quality experiences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Given consumers&#39; reluctance to experience a perk without their partner enjoying the same perk, offering the same benefits to the companion of a recipient can be a way to increase people&#39;s uptake and satisfaction with any special treatment they are offered. This might look like offering an additional TSA Precheck pass to the spouse of a frequent traveler. However, it is not always possible for companies to treat their customers with free or discounted perks that will improve the overall experience because of monetary or space constraints. For example, an airline might not have two empty adjacent seats in first class. So, how should they communicate a free first-class upgrade to two people traveling together when the seats aren&#39;t next to each other?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these situations, framing an activity as functional is one way to spur people to be apart during experiences where physical proximity to one&#39;s partner would not necessarily maximize enjoyment. For example, a flight is one of many activities that people will share during a family vacation; thus, framing the flight as a utilitarian activity that serves the purpose of getting people to their final destination can be a way to encourage travelers to break apart to have a better experience. So instead of just saying, “Here&#39;s an upgrade on us!” when treating a couple with two first-class non-adjacent seats, our research suggests the airline should also mention, “Use the time during this flight to rest because your adventure starts the moment you step off the plane.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, businesses could provide guidance for consumers to be together for some parts of an experience but also to indulge their own interests for part of the time. Think of a couple visiting an art museum: partners might perceive it as awkward or inappropriate to suggest that they split up at some point to see different exhibits, even though this would make them happier. However, the museum could suggest paths for parties visiting with a group to “divide and conquer” the museum by exploring different aspects of the collection. When the parties meet back up, they can share photos or descriptions of what they saw — enabling visitors to create special memories together of the experience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our research can help marketers minimize complaints from customers whose shared experience is of lower quality by encouraging consumers to take advantage of more pleasant solo experiences — all while keeping some aspects of their social bond intact. These findings are especially relevant for activities where physical proximity does not always maximize enjoyment, like education or self-care. Recognizing that consumers often overvalue togetherness could result in better strategies for your organization and happier customers.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Is It So Hard to Leave a Bad Job?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/2023/09/why-is-it-so-hard-to-leave-a-bad-job]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/Sep23_21_1434151592.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;div>; &lt;span>;Anton Vierietin/Getty Images&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div more-caption=&quot;more&quot; close-caption=&quot;close&quot;>; &lt;span>;Summary.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&lt;p>;If you&amp;#8217;ve ever been in an unhealthy work situation, you probably know how hard it can be to leave. Leaving a bad job is never easy, and each person&amp;#8217;s breaking point is different, so beating yourself up over why you stayed so long in a traumatic situation won&amp;#8217;t help. But learning from each experience will empower you to own your career choices and leave earlier if you find yourself in a comparable situation again. The author presents five common reasons it&amp;#8217;s hard to leave a bad job and strategies for moving on.&lt;/p>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/why-is-it-so-hard-to-leave-a-bad-job?language=es&quot;>;Leer en español&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;/2023/09/why-is-it-so-hard-to-leave-a-bad-job?language=pt&quot;>;Ler em português&lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Have you ever been in a bad employment situation but couldn&#39;t bring yourself to leave? Nearly every client tells me about trauma they experienced at work, whether it&#39;s an unsupportive or deliberately cruel manager, a company implementing policies that are unfavorable to employees, continuous layoffs creating stress and anxiety, or politics that left them feeling devalued.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yet they stayed, some for years, even though they knew their work environment wasn&#39;t healthy. Here are five reasons it&#39;s hard to leave a bad job — and what to do about them.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Loyalty to your “work family”&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Working at a company for a long time can create a sense of loyalty to the organization and team members. My client, Beatrice (not her real name), worked for a law firm for more than 15 years and expected to be made a shareholder. But she learned she was rejected from partnership. “The lightbulb went off, and this was never going to be my company. I have given my life to these people, and they didn&#39;t value me that way. I had to decide, did I want to start over and try to become a shareholder somewhere else?” That was the breaking point for her, but even with an offer in hand from another firm where she would be a shareholder, she still struggled to depart. “I felt tremendous guilt leaving my old firm. I celebrated every major holiday with them. Two partners are my kids&#39; godparents. It was like my family.” In the end, Beatrice weighed her loyalty to the firm against the firm&#39;s loyalty to her, which helped her decide to accept another firm&#39;s offer.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;What to do about it&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Recognize that companies hire you to use your skills and capabilities to provide a service. If you&#39;re no longer providing the value the company expects or the company changes its goals and your skills are no longer needed, the company will let you go.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, reverse that logic. Look at how you&#39;re serving the company through the lens of what &lt;em>;you &lt;/em>;need to feel fulfilled and valued in your job. Determine if the company is still providing the value to your life that you need and deserve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some questions to ask yourself include:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Is the company providing me benefits and development opportunities that will enhance my career and life?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Are the company&#39;s policies inclusive of my specific needs?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Is the company recognizing the value I&#39;m bringing with more money, a promotion, partnership, or some other important recognition that matters to me?&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Every company-employee relationship is about loyalty and commitment on both sides, not just achieving goals and collecting a paycheck.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;A cult-like atmosphere&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When you join a company, everyone is working toward a common mission or goal. If the company has a righteous mission such as helping people be healthy, successful, happy, or helping to sustain the earth, then employees feel like they&#39;re contributing to the greater good of humanity or the world. Deciding to leave the company can feel selfish or even traitorous, like you&#39;ve “given up” on the collective mission.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the company isn&#39;t making big impacts on people or the world, the inside atmosphere is about collaborating to achieve a goal together. That feeling of being a critical part of a team or feeling “strong” because you can withstand any suffering to achieve the goals becomes addictive and diminishes the damaging aspects of the job.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I worked as a TV news reporter, when someone left the business to move into PR or another field, everyone talked about them as giving up or not being able to “cut it.” But the person who left knew they were escaping long hours, working weekends and holidays, low pay for extraordinary effort, and stressful daily deadlines. They were seeking more for their life in alignment with their values.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;What to do about it&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re feeling an intense camaraderie that prevents you from leaving what you know is an unhealthy work environment, take some time to define your what&#39;s important to you and determine whether those values are being fulfilled in the job — separate from the company&#39;s needs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are some questions to ask yourself to make that determination:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;What&#39;s important to me at work, and how do I define what that means?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Which values are being consistently honored or violated?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Is there anything I can do to ensure my values are honored?&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;For example, if being respected is a value and you define it as having your ideas heard and considered, but your manager consistently talks over you or ignores your ideas, your value is being violated. Can you discuss with your manager why this value is so important to you and influence it being honored? If not, you&#39;ll need to decide whether the company mission is more important than your values.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Nostalgia for what the company was&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When you join a company and have a great experience for months or even years, you&#39;re fully engaged in your job. Then change happens, whether that be a new leader, new structure, or a shift in strategic direction, and you may struggle to cope with it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These kinds of organizational changes can result in feelings of shock, denial, frustration, and depression. If you find yourself struggling to accept and adjust to the changes over time and find yourself saying, “I don&#39;t want to leave because I really love the company” instead of “I don&#39;t want to leave because I love my job,” then you may be stuck in the past, hoping the company will revert to what it once was.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;What to do about it&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Change is hard, so give yourself time to adjust and process what it means for your job. After you&#39;ve accepted the change, take an objective look at whether the present situation still fulfills your values and career goals. If you&#39;re still struggling in your job post-change, consider the following questions:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;What was the company like when I joined, and what is the company reality today?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;What would make the environment better for me?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Can I make any additional changes or requests to fulfill the values that are no longer being fulfilled?&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Companies, teams, and leaders all change — often especially as companies grow. It&#39;s up to you to determine whether you want to live in the present reality or a past that no longer exists.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Equity handcuffs&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Some employees receive equity grants in a company, such as RSUs or stock options. Stock grants vest over a period of time, usually years. Therefore, after suffering a distressing work environment, you may feel even more strongly that you deserve to wait out that vest for what you&#39;ve been through. But how much trauma are you willing to endure? Waiting for equity to vest could be detrimental to your health, so it&#39;s critical to understand whether it&#39;s worth it.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;What to do about it&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Determine exactly when and how much you will receive from each vest at the current stock prices and ask your broker or accountant these questions if you can&#39;t figure out the answers:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;After taxes and option strike price payments, how much will I receive?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;If I walk away from this money or wait until my stock vest, will this impact my retirement outlook?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;What net amount would I need to earn in compensation at another company to make up for the unvested stock value?&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Equity incentives are granted to keep you in the job, and many companies offer additional grants during your tenure through compensation programs. Therefore, there&#39;s never a “final” vesting date. But you can break the never-ending vest cycle if you have an exit date in mind based on how much you want vested before you depart and how much you&#39;re willing to forfeit.&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Fear&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s no shortage of things to fear when it comes to making a job change: Fear you&#39;ll jump into another tough situation, that you&#39;ll have to prove yourself all over again, that you won&#39;t be able to make as much money. Fear that you don&#39;t even know how to look for a job. If you&#39;re feeling beaten down from a bad work situation, fear can leave you with little confidence that making a change will lead to a better work environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;What to do about it&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;To help you bypass your fears, instead of just dreaming about what your life could look like in a positive work environment, deliberately visualize it. Close your eyes and consider the following when trying to combat negative thoughts and fears:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;If I weren&#39;t scared to leave, what would be possible?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;What does my new work environment look like, smell like, feel like?&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;What kind of support do I need to feel more confident in making a change?&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Finally, think about what advice you would give a close friend about a work situation that mirrors your own.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;. 。 .&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Leaving a bad job is never easy, and each person&#39;s breaking point is different, so beating yourself up over why you stayed so long in a traumatic situation won&#39;t help. But learning from each experience will empower you to own your career choices and leave earlier if you find yourself in a comparable situation again.&lt;/p>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Persona-Powered Onboarding for Better Employee Engagement and Retention - SPONSOR CONTENT FROM UNISYS]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://hbr.org/sponsored/2023/09/persona-powered-onboarding-for-better-employee-engagement-and-retention]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;hero-image >; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/hero-image>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;html>; &lt;head>;&lt;/head>; &lt;body>; &lt;figure>; &lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-0&quot; src=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2023/09/HeaderImage-1024x576.jpg&quot; >; &lt;/figure>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;By Joel Raper&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Imagine starting a new job where digital interfaces replace the comfort of friendly introductions and in-person guidance. Many who are now working in hybrid or remote roles have already experienced it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hybrid digital workplace is rewriting the rules of onboarding. While a hybrid model offers the flexibility to work from anywhere, it also brings the challenge of creating a cohesive and inclusive experience for new hires.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The essence of onboarding, once a straightforward process of on-site training sessions, device provisioning, and team lunches, now faces a transformative era. Without the nuances of face-to-face interactions, new employees can sometimes feel isolated, trying to make sense of the company&#39;s culture, human resources (HR) workflows, and technology tools all while working literally outside a traditional workplace environment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To address these challenges, organizations are transforming their onboarding strategies. HR and IT leaders emphasize creating robust digital onboarding platforms; integrating team-building activities suitable for remote settings; and ensuring that every new hire feels connected, valued, and equipped to thrive in their new role, even without a physical presence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Tailored Solutions for Diverse Needs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Onboarding today is more than just handing out new laptops. The process begins before an employee&#39;s first day, offering them the opportunity to select equipment and familiarize themselves with company culture, enabling immediate connections with other employees and new hires.&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos3&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Beyond an introduction to company values and processes, however, modern onboarding offers an entirely tailored—or persona-based—experience, often involving digital platforms customized for every new hire, directing them to vital resources and fostering connections. Simultaneously, a persona-based approach includes specialized technologies, trainings, and resources that align with distinct job roles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Examples of Persona-Based Onboarding&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remote software developer:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Preselected tech stack tutorials reinforcing standard coding procedures and access to code repositories.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Virtual coffee breaks with current team members.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;One-on-one virtual mentoring sessions with a team leader in order to establish alignment with the company&#39;s coding best practices.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Regional sales manager for a territory far from corporate headquarters:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Office tour and team meet-and-greets via augmented reality technology.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Immediate inclusion in hybrid sales meetings and client interaction simulations.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;An established on-site “buddy” to partner with during the first week.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Manufacturing associate on the factory floor:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;A mobile app that serves as a one-stop shop for all required HR workflows, accessible at any time.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Remotely deployed device provisioning to enable productivity from day one.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;A blend of live in-person trainings for complex tasks and safety policies, and virtual modules with evergreen information and resources.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; &lt;div id=&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;>; &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;>;if (isAdobeSync()) googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display(&quot;DFP_IC_pos4&quot;); });&lt;/script>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Global marketing team member based in the UK:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Tailored compliance training based on UK regulations.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Time-zone-adjusted virtual town halls.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Localized training content to help them understand market-specific sales strategies.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;US-based customer support representative:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Access to customer interaction simulations and CRM&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Virtual team-building exercises with US and global support teams.&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Cultural sensitivity training designed for a diverse customer base.&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;A successful onboarding process in this landscape recognizes the individuality of each new hire. While every employee requires a solid comprehension of company tools, culture, and objectives, the nuances of their experiences and expectations can vary widely by persona. These idiosyncrasies intersect to create custom onboarding experiences, designed as deep dives that align with individual learning styles, demographics, and company roles.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Importance of Dynamic Tools&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So how can HR and line-of-business managers begin to understand each relevant onboarding persona and their respective needs?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You don&#39;t need to start from scratch—digital experience management tools and their insights are pivotal in shaping personalized onboarding experiences during the first 90 days of employment. Organizations can craft journeys that resonate with each persona by aggregating device performance feedback with employee engagement and sentiment metrics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this environment, the goal is consistent: to ensure each newcomer feels seamlessly integrated and satisfied. Through iterative feedback loops and adaptive platforms, the onboarding experience becomes a journey that keeps refining itself.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a proactive stance doesn&#39;t only cater to immediate onboarding needs. It also positions companies at the cutting edge, crafting a digital workplace experience that&#39;s truly inclusive and primed for productivity in the long term.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A Balanced Approach &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yet amidst all this technology and data-driven personalization, organizations must not lose sight of the human essence of onboarding. The challenge—and indeed, the opportunity—lies in seamlessly weaving together the digital and the human (the “phygital”). Achieving this balance could involve virtual team-building activities, mentorship opportunities, or collaborative projects designed to foster a sense of community and connection.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hybrid digital workplace requires balancing digital solutions&#39; scalability and personal connections&#39; intimacy. By embracing persona-based onboarding solutions, you can help ensure that every employee begins their journey with a sense of purpose, belonging, and excitement, regardless of where they work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Future of Hybrid Onboarding&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hybrid workplace combines the best of both worlds: the opportunity for purposeful in-person collaboration and remote flexibility. The challenge lies in preserving the personal touch and ensuring that employees feel connected and valued, no matter where they are located. This blended model necessitates an evolved approach to onboarding, one that&#39;s persona-based, inclusive, and engaging.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Onboarding is no longer just about acclimating new hires to their roles or company tools. It&#39;s also about creating an inclusive experience that instills a sense of belonging. Through thoughtful strategies, innovative tools, and an emphasis on genuine human connections, you can deliver an onboarding experience that takes your hybrid workplace—and your business—to the next level.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Joel Raper is senior vice president and general manager, digital workplace solutions, at Unisys.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;Learn more about crafting a persona-powered hybrid workplace&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unisys.com/solutions/digital-workplace-solutions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;here&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/body>; &lt;/html>; &lt;!-- citation -->; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>