<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[教育部：对“预制菜进校园”持审慎态度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257458]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the topic of &quot;prepared dishes entering campus&quot; in some places has attracted widespread attention from society. Recently, reporters interviewed the heads of relevant departments and bureaus of the Ministry of Education regarding &quot;prepared dishes entering campuses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the person in charge, school food safety and nutritional health are related to the healthy growth of students. The Ministry of Education has long been working with relevant departments to effectively implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, and strictly implement the Food Safety Law and other laws regulations, and has successively formulated and implemented regulations such as the &quot;Regulations on the Management of Food Safety and Nutrition and Health in Schools&quot; and the &quot;Guidelines for the Construction of Nutrition and Healthy Schools&quot; to continuously strengthen the management of school food safety and nutrition and health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 57 of the Food Safety Law stipulates that canteens of schools and other centralized dining units must strictly abide by laws, regulations and food safety standards; those who order food from catering units must obtain food production and operation licenses from The enterprise orders and inspects the ordered food as required. Catering units should strictly abide by laws, regulations and food safety standards when processing meals to ensure food safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge pointed out that the party and the government attach great importance to school food safety and are very concerned about the healthy growth of students. Parents expect their children to eat green, safe, nutritious and healthy food in school. After research, given that there is currently no unified standard system, certification system, traceability system and other effective regulatory mechanisms for prepared dishes, a very cautious attitude should be taken when &quot;prepared dishes are brought to campus&quot; and it is not appropriate to promote them into campuses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成为全职儿女，是双向奔赴还是逃离社会？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/1JE8T6YwMwSf39ignBvAWz6wqusEAeMivHPOMl8t.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;930&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/1JE8T6YwMwSf39ignBvAWz6wqusEAeMivHP OMl8t. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Zhitong/Picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most effortless social identity a person can acquire from birth is &quot;son or daughter&quot;. As life progresses, a variety of new social identities will be acquired, including occupations, titles, Relationships, political identities, and more. When a person interrupts the process, deviates from the life trajectory preset by mainstream concepts, and retreats from society to the family, what words can he use to define himself? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, British society classified people who were not employed, enrolled in higher education, or furthered as NEET (Not in Employment, Education or Training). This term was adopted when it was introduced to Japan and Taiwan. The transliteration of &quot;Nite tribe&quot; is translated as &quot;gnawing old tribe&quot; in mainland China. But the &quot;elder-gnawing behavior&quot; is not limited to &quot;elder-gnawers.&quot; According to a China Family Tracking Survey by Peking University, the proportion of &quot;elder-gnawers&quot; among my country&#39;s working-age population jumped from less than 2% in 2010 to 40% in 2018. %above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japanese scholar Yamada Hiromasa proposed the term &quot;single parasites&quot; in 1999, which is more specific than NEET. It refers to those who have been delaying marriage and rely on their parents for daily life such as housing and food. People who use their income as &quot;pocket money&quot;. The male protagonist of the Japanese drama &quot;My Story is a Long Story&quot; is a &quot;single parasite&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is &quot;gnawing at the old&quot; or &quot;single parasitism&quot;, the words themselves have a certain derogatory color, and are only measured by social value. In the context of unavoidable stigma, some people who have returned to their families choose to define themselves as &quot;full-time children&quot;. Apart from all external social identities, they are at least the children of their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having full-time children is not a large number, nor is it an option that can be easily replicated, but it has caused a huge amount of discussion on the Internet. Rather than what a full-time son or daughter is or how to be a full-time son or daughter, we are more concerned about why they give up other identities. The reason why they have become full-time children is not only due to themselves, but also has a lot to do with the common difficulties they face in this era, but they have not been able to overcome it for the time being, or have given up the fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jv6s6VVx0pKS8P6lINgiWhE5nOKQqLExILl63Ng2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jv6s6VVx0pKS8P6lINgiWhE5nOKQqLExILl63Ng2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Zhitong/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Single sojourn&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In The popularity of exchanges in the Douban group &quot;Exchange Center for Full-time Children&#39;s Work&quot; has subsided. Old posts from the past are constantly being dug up by students and reporters in journalism and sociology, showing a strong sense of exploration into &quot;full-time children&quot;. Such inquiries sometimes arouse resentment. Some people couldn&#39;t help but post and ask, &quot;Why are people suddenly paying attention to full-time children?&quot; Most of the people who responded thought it was hype and hot-button pursuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most active period of the group is from January to April 2023. Many people who choose to describe themselves as &quot;full-time children&quot; share their stories publicly. In these stories, happiness and relaxation are rare, and anxiety and confusion are the main themes: &quot;I feel that my sense of worth is very low&quot; &quot;I am especially tired when facing relatives, and my parents sometimes show dissatisfaction&quot; &quot;I have already started to feel anxious in the third week&quot; &quot;...Some people also mentioned that some people who become full-time children are under peer pressure and are easily traumatized - they are out of touch with the mainstream development path of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The definition of full-time children in the group introduction is somewhat similar to the &quot;single parasitic family&quot;: single young people, living in their parents&#39; homes and enjoying financial assistance from their parents. The difference is that full-time children will work hard in exchange for financial assistance, and they do not give up employment, but keep studying, waiting for opportunities to return to the workplace, or take public postgraduate entrance examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This definition is consistent with most full-time children aged 20-30, although it is not applicable to those over 30 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xixi is 26 years old, and her situation fits the definition of a full-time child. After graduating from an overseas master&#39;s degree in December 2022, she went through various considerations of applying for a doctorate and finding a job, and finally chose to concentrate on preparing for the civil service exam at home. The background of her circle of friends is Russell&#39;s famous saying: &quot;Don&#39;t feel guilty for sleeping in, because you can&#39;t create much value when you get up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xixi believes that major has the greatest influence on her career choice. She majored in education. “Two of my classmates from the same school who studied accounting and marketing quickly joined the workforce. One joined PricewaterhouseCoopers and the other joined Mercedes-Benz. But these big companies don’t require education. student.&quot; Her original career plan was to enter a university after completing her Ph.D., but during the four months of applying in 2022, she felt tremendous pressure. Being infected with the new crown epidemic in December was the last straw that crushed her. The application was abandoned. Later, when she accidentally opened her mailbox, Xixi discovered that she had received an offer from the University of Birmingham in the UK, but by that time she had missed the deadline to apply for a scholarship. &quot;It is too low cost to spend millions to study for a doctorate in liberal arts at your own expense.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;A 985 master&#39;s degree in liberal arts is not as good as a bachelor&#39;s degree in computer science with three majors.&quot; Xixi felt this from the salary. A friend of hers joined an Internet company after graduating with a bachelor&#39;s degree in computer science. After a few years, his annual salary rose to 600,000 yuan. When she was applying for a master&#39;s degree, she briefly found a job with a monthly salary of only 3,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When taking the civil service exam this time, Xixi did not prepare for the exam while working as she did when applying for a master&#39;s degree. She found that the competition is too fierce now, and the number of people taking the civil service exam has increased significantly in recent years. Taking the National Civil Service Examination as an example, since 2021, the number of applicants has increased by about 500,000 every year, reaching 1.51 million in 2021 and exceeding 2.5 million in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xixi’s parents supported her decision to stay at home and find a job. Her father said to her: “Don’t worry, you can slowly find a job that you are more satisfied with.” One of her classmates was not so lucky. The family&#39;s financial situation is good, but his parents really wanted him to find a job as soon as possible after graduating from the master&#39;s degree. He could only find a job as a counselor in a local technical secondary school in a hurry, with a monthly salary of two to three thousand, and the work was very tiring. “He wanted to take the entrance examination for a certain position, but he had no energy to review after work, so he was caught in a dilemma: he was reluctant to give up his current job because he was afraid that he would not be able to find another job in the future; he was tired, unhappy and had little money if he didn’t give up. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the lessons learned from her classmates, Xixi prepares for the provincial exam with peace of mind at home. Her family&#39;s finances are jointly managed by her parents and her. She can freely use the fraction of her savings, which is enough to cover her living expenses, but she does not have to take on housework. &quot;I mainly want to be a companion.&quot; After going to college, Xixi rarely grew up like this. Spending time living with her parents, my mother cherishes her days at home. Every night, my parents watch TV in the living room, while Xixi does aerobics. One day when Xixi went to her room to exercise, her mother asked unaccustomedly, &quot;Why don&#39;t you dance outside today?&quot; Push her to work, but she still feels anxious, and she feels like her days at home are getting nowhere. &quot;We are in a result-oriented society. I cannot accept the view that life is not a track but a wilderness. I am still trapped by the mainstream values ​​of society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Professional Value&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Douban There is a question thread in the group, &quot;Why do children become full-time workers?&quot; Among the 16 answers, the reason &quot;doesn&#39;t want to work/can&#39;t find a job&quot; accounted for 11, including young people who are unemployed after graduation. In 2023, the youth unemployment rate continues to rise. According to the National Bureau of Statistics, the national urban survey of the population aged 16-24 years old, the unemployment rate exceeded 20% from April to June 2023. Since August, this data has been suspended release. When some young people who cannot find jobs return to their families, they become full-time children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lan Qi is one of the unemployed youth aged 16-24. She understands that having a full-time job is not a normal way of employment. &quot;I also get a salary at home, but it cannot be compared with going out to work outside. Any kind of job should communicate with the outside world.&quot; Lan Qi was forced to stay at home. She had a job after graduating from undergraduate school, but her father rejected it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;His worries are too conservative. Isn&#39;t it safe for a girl to go on a business trip for a few days? What&#39;s more, there are female colleagues traveling with her. His concept is that after I get married, I will have nothing to do with him. Before, we had to protect our daughter&#39;s reputation. The value of a virgin is better than anything else in her growth.&quot; Lan Qi did not try to persuade her father and resigned and returned home. She was pained by the absurd stubbornness of her parents and her own weakness, and had no courage to find a new job. &quot;I feel like I am useless. I am lagging behind my peers and out of touch with society. I am like Juexin in &quot;Home&quot; and Nora in &quot;A Doll&#39;s House&quot;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In me Among all the stories about stay-at-home children that I have read, Lanqi’s case is very special. I was not sure whether she belonged to this group, but she chose the word herself because she liked the professional attributes in it. &quot;As long as there is labor, it is a career. Some people think that children who work full-time are &#39;cheating on the old&#39;, but I don&#39;t agree. &#39;Cheating on the old&#39; means relying on their parents for food and clothing without putting in any work, which means losing one&#39;s own value. I want to do housework too. Valuable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lan Qi made me realize that in most descriptions of full-time children, the children should be the dominant one, asking their parents for financial assistance to provide for their own lives, but in fact Parents may also be the ones in control, and their attitudes and concepts shape the appearance of the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lanqi’s parents believe that doing housework is a better choice for women than working outside the home. Lan Qi said, &quot;They seem to be cultivating a housework machine. They do housework and cook for the future when they get married, and the skills they learn are for future generations. For example, my mother thinks that I learn swimming so that my children can learn it faster. .&quot; One time I was chatting with Lan Qi, and she said that she was cooking dinner that night, and her mother said to her, &quot;You took my place.&quot; She felt very sad, &quot;She could have worked hard in society, but she was doing heavy housework at home. , can the heart be willing and the emotion be willing?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of Lan Qi&#39;s parents comes from their ancestors, &quot;My grandfather &#39;protected&#39; his daughters very well, which was very rare in that era. They had a good reputation and were surrounded by neighbors. Quite recognized.&quot; Lanqi&#39;s parents hope that she will be a daughter who is waiting to be born, and she chooses to be a full-time child. Modern and traditional are integrated in this word, so it is both understandable and novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0HS9ni4yQzkUz8L7e5v5VxyjTfDi9SPGBnIha9zC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0HS9ni4yQzkUz8L7e5v5VxyjTfDi9SPGBnIha9zC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Zhitong/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Puppet on a String&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Among the reasons for becoming a full-time child, Yue Hang’s answers left a deep impression on me. She was the first person to accept my request for an interview. Before the interview, I didn’t realize how courageous she was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Hang’s narration drew me to Shenzhen, a hot and humid place with endless summers. In 2017, 25-year-old Yue Hang returned from studying abroad, and her father found her a job in Shenzhen. This job made her unhappy. At the end of 2020, she lost her sense of smell. After that, her skin problems worsened, her acne bleeds, and her attempts to resolve the unpleasantness all failed. In the spring of 2021, the second job her father found brought a turnaround in her life, but she was persuaded to quit after a three-month probation period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wait while I light a cigarette.&quot; Yue Hang said, but she didn&#39;t take a few puffs in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Hang’s first job was in a family business. The boss was from Chaoshan, Guangdong. There were less than 10 employees in the office, most of whom were relatives of the boss. Yue Hang couldn&#39;t even understand Chaoshan dialect, and she couldn&#39;t understand it until she left her job. She was like an outsider in the office and could only do things in silence. Salaries have basically never been increased. In 2020, the company&#39;s performance was not good and wages began to be owed. Other non-relative colleagues resigned, but Yue Hang persisted - she also submitted several resumes, but received no response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This company is not equipped with dormitories. When Yue Hang first arrived, he still had expectations for life. His salary was 5,000 yuan and he spent 3,500 yuan on renting a house. Later, her rental price dropped to 800 yuan. &quot;It&#39;s not a good house. It&#39;s cheap. I don&#39;t want to spend a dime on this job. I also struggled with myself. I endured hardship, but it didn&#39;t work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the company finally allocated dormitories, and Yue Hang moved in even though there was no air conditioning. She admitted that her mentality at the time was a bit stupid, &quot;Finally, the company provided free housing, and I had to live there to earn back my money.&quot; The highest temperature in Shenzhen in summer can exceed 40 degrees Celsius. Yue Hang was so hot that she was desperate while calculating her profits and losses. Only later did she realize I have suffered a great loss, and my health has been compromised. &quot;I hate that company, so I have to recover the psychological gap from the financial aspect. It&#39;s just that I feel it&#39;s unfair to get such a small salary.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second company made Yue Hang feel much better, until his boss He asked her: &quot;What did your parents teach you?&quot; He even criticized her in public and called her father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the four years of working in Shenzhen, Yue Hang was like a screw in a machine, always tense and unable to relax. The weekly working hours are from Monday to Saturday, with only one day off on Sunday. She will eat a lot of desserts and stuff them into her mouth until she feels like vomiting, just to get a little happiness. Although such happiness was short-lived, she didn&#39;t know where else to find it. When she had insomnia at night, she would masturbate to make herself fall asleep quickly, &quot;I need to have enough sleep to be able to serve my work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the night when she resigned from the second company, Yue Hang I have been lying in front of my desk, thinking about what happened in the week before leaving my job. Her whole body was frozen in place like a puppet. If she wanted to move, her body could move, but she had no will to drive her body. She fell into stupor for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2021, Yue Hang went out of town to attend a relative’s wedding on behalf of her family—both her parents worked, and she was the only one free. At the wedding, Yue Hang suddenly fell into a coma. Her parents came to take her home and sent her to a psychiatric ward the next day. She became a puppet again, conscious but unable to leave the darkness. She woke up only a few days later. Her depression was already severe. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The overdraft generation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In November 2021, Yue Hang was discharged from the hospital and began a life of recuperation at home. She almost shuts herself away and rarely communicates with her parents. They would get angry when they saw her sitting on the sofa &quot;doing nothing,&quot; so she always stayed in her room alone. Like a rebound from the regular life of commuting to and from work in the past, her sleeping time has become disorderly, and she will let herself suffer from insomnia. &quot;I just coax myself, not to be anxious, and I don&#39;t have to go to work anyway.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2022, after returning to her hometown as a child, Yue Hang resumed socializing, driving to meet friends, eat delicious food, and visit scenic spots... She likes to travel by car, but she has almost no chance to use a car in the past few years in Shenzhen. Her life includes many activities that were not available during her working life: trying to plant flowers and plants, going to the rooftop to dry clothes in the sunshine, and collecting express cartons to sell scrap products. She likes the process of collecting cartons. She first selects the largest carton, then unpacks and flattens other small cartons to stuff more things into a fixed space. Although the cartons collected for several months can only be sold for ten A few dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the small town in his hometown, apart from paying social security, Yue Hang’s other living expenses are about 1,000 yuan. Her parents gave her a living allowance, and she also earned pocket money through part-time work - she worked as a temporary assistant in a photography studio, earning 50 yuan for half a day. Since 2023, she has also worked as a temporary dishwasher in a hotel. These two jobs made her feel comfortable. The customers who came to take pictures wanted beautiful photos and were very polite to the staff. After the dishwashing work was over, she was able to share some dishes that had not been touched with chopsticks. &quot;This kind of physical work doesn&#39;t require using your brain and gives you a sense of accomplishment. As long as you finish the work in front of you, you don&#39;t have to work overtime after get off work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doing these two jobs is a rare independent decision-making for her. From a young age, Yue Hang&#39;s life has been arranged by her parents. When she graduated from junior high school, her parents suggested that she study abroad. She agreed. She completed high school and university abroad, and majored in economics, which is easier to find a job. Now, her parents&#39; investment in her education has become a burden and pressure on her. &quot;Even if your parents don&#39;t show their disappointment in front of you, it&#39;s difficult for children to not find this feeling if they have been raised for a long time and cannot find a job. They have not been able to make money for so long and it does not meet their expectations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Hang feels that his qualifications are average, especially not good at taking exams. After returning to China, her parents asked her to take the junior economist exam, but she failed and was unwilling to take other certificates. She was also not good at socializing, and only gradually became more open-minded after returning home. She is not used to fighting for anything. She didn&#39;t write her resume well when she wanted to change jobs. Recently, she changed it to a more formal version when she was looking for a job. She will also write down her experience as a dishwasher to enrich her resume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Yue Hang also has a sense of frustration in the face of the times, &quot;It is impossible for me to make more money than my parents. In their era, as long as you worked hard, you would have money, but I worked hard, and I I don’t have money to work overtime.” Yue Hang felt that many of the peers she saw in Shenzhen worked harder than her parents. Their generation worked harder but got less. &quot;We seem to have overdrawn our lives in advance. We have been busy attending cram schools since elementary school. We don&#39;t know what progress we are making. We can&#39;t catch up with a house or even a relaxing vacation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two years of being a full-time mother and daughter have been the happiest time for Yue Hang in recent years, and she has considered continuing to do so. In 2022, my grandma had an operation. During this period, Yue Hang proposed to his father that he wanted to be her caregiver. &quot;When I was hospitalized before, my parents hired me a caregiver, which paid me two to three hundred (remuneration) a day. I wanted to make this money. Of course, as long as they took care of my food, I wouldn&#39;t ask them to pay the price of a caregiver. Please ask me. But my father doesn&#39;t agree.&quot; Yue Hang feels that he can act as a nanny among relatives. In addition to his grandparents, his parents will also face care needs, because they all only have one child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Hang’s condition has stabilized a lot, and he is currently trying to find a new job, such as the food department or transportation department of IKEA. “It requires physical work, no overtime, plenty of exercise, and you don’t have to worry about so many interpersonal relationships. , taking into account physical health and mental health.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5pnGTNAYzfxYTyw3tMlHgbRtlytjPo5Ob5t5BLlp.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5pnGTNAYzfxYTyw3tMlHgbRtlytjPo5Ob5t5BLlp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251337&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Zhitong/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Crazy Work&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Yue Hang believes that the biggest constraint for children who work full time is financial resources. She does not want to rely on her parents all the time, so she can only continue to work. For Qingtian, a 37-year-old with 10 years of work experience, she does not have much financial burden, so she can calmly resign and withdraw from the labor market. She refers to herself as &quot;laying down trash&quot;. At the end of 2022, friends forwarded her a topical article about full-time children, with the sentence &quot;You are so typical.&quot; She rolled her eyes and approved of the new title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The stay-at-home children reminded Qingtian of a report he had read about Japanese people in their thirties and forties who nibbled on the elderly. One of the stories was that a 40-year-old daughter accompanied her 60-year-old mother on a trip abroad. , my daughter is very envious of her mother’s high pension. In &quot;The Choice of Being a Woman&quot;, she saw Chizuru Ueno having a similar discussion in 2003, &quot;&#39;60s generation&#39; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Refers to people aged 60-69&lt;/span>;) whose parents had retired before the economic downturn and widespread layoffs, and received generous pensions. It can be said that they are the first and last generation to fully enjoy the economy. People with high growth and good fortune. But the next generation does not have that kind of protection. It is precisely because this generation’s family has a strong financial background that it provides the possibility for their children to live in old age.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After resigning, his parents gave Qingtian a slap in the face. A large sum of money supported her life, and she put most of it into the stock market. Although she has lost a lot of money, she has confidence in the stock market. &quot;Our family started stock trading in the 1990s, and we have experienced several bull and bear markets. I believe we will always come back.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingtian was originally a middle-level cadre of a medium-sized Internet advertising company. What made her put down her career was her work. The futility and absurdity felt in it. In 2020, the company advocated cost reduction and efficiency improvement. Employees&#39; salaries were reduced by 15% and no bonuses were given. However, the company&#39;s performance that year was not bad. At the end of the year, the company&#39;s top executives went to Macau for the annual meeting. Qingtian&#39;s leader came back and showed off to her privately, &quot;The Rolex watch I just bought doesn&#39;t look good, and I want to change it.&quot; Qingtian thought of her employees, &quot;They are all good students of 985 and 211, diligent and diligent They worked diligently overtime, worried about losing their jobs, and didn’t complain when called by customers in the middle of the night, but they only paid several thousand yuan a month, what’s their fault?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, a colleague in Qingtian died of pancreatic cancer. , at the funeral, a former colleague who joined a leading Internet retail company vividly said that there was a row of AEDs hanging in their office. The first thing new employees did when they joined the company was to practice cardiopulmonary resuscitation. However, because of the high salary, many people inside wanted to change jobs. Go to their department. She lamented, &quot;The corporate culture is completely different from our previous company. We don&#39;t have to go through procedures or hold meetings. We just work! We are very motivated.&quot; Qingtian feels that the value has been impacted. &quot;Without people, there is nothing. Why are everyone so crazy? Why is this industry so crazy?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sense of value of &quot;hard work&quot; and &quot;self-realization&quot; that he always believed in in the past has gradually turned into &quot;self-exploitation&quot; and &quot;self-brainwashing&quot; in Qingtian&#39;s heart. . She has witnessed the success stories of the explosion of the Internet industry, and has also experienced anger and disappointment at the serious imbalance in the company&#39;s distribution of interests. She no longer seeks meaning in her work. &quot;The meaning of work to ordinary people is to earn money to support themselves and their families. If the family has a certain amount of accumulation, why not make some different choices so that both themselves and their families can live comfortably?&quot; Qingtian thought of the colleague who passed away. The last Douban broadcast complained about the relationship with her family, &quot;She never reconciled with her parents until her death.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because she was an only child, Qingtian had a close relationship with her parents, and because she had a failed marriage before, She does not plan to start a family anymore and wants to maintain the balance and happiness of living with her parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingtian lives in Guangzhou, and her parents live in the countryside of Huizhou. She often goes back to the village to stay. In the past, when I was working, I could only go home during the Mid-Autumn Festival and Spring Festival. What I saw was the golden rice and the remaining rice stubble. Now, she can fully witness the various stages of rice fields including irrigation, transplanting, heading, and harvesting. She would take her parents on trips, taking care of everything along the way and arranging visits to museums and natural scenery. Even if it was just a visit to the local vegetable market, the family would be very happy. She helped her parents take photos and edit videos, and discovered that they actually wanted to &quot;be seen.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her parents did not interfere with Qingtian&#39;s choices. She talked with her father about planting flowers and birds, calligraphy and painting, and told him that the richness of life now is five times that of the past. Occasionally, her mother would worry that Qingtian was getting further and further away from re-employment, but seeing that she was happy, she didn&#39;t say much and suggested that she study for a degree and experience more different experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only thing they worried about was that after they &quot;left&quot;, Qingtian would be left alone. This is also a problem Qingtian is worried about, but she has not found a solution yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O0LCKe0HfmalBlPeoiPfuD5lEnPky2BXcSD6JJJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O0LCKe0HfmalBlPeoiPfuD5lEnPky2BXcSD6JJJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Zhitong/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What is your function? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the Douban group, the living conditions of older children who work full-time are obviously more relaxed and self-consistent than that of young people. Among the anxious and confused headlines, &quot;37-year-old children who work full-time are happy every day&quot; is particularly eye-catching. . Qingtian replied to this post and expressed his agreement. However, Qingtian believes that children who work full-time have two things in common: first, their families have good economic conditions and their parents have high pensions, and second, they have harmonious family relationships. The situation of the poster, the gardener, is not entirely consistent with this. She does not believe that having children full-time is an option only for a well-to-do family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gardener is from Dalian, Liaoning. In mid-2022, the gardener&#39;s parents retired, and their pensions totaled more than 7,000 yuan. At the end of the year, they all found another job and had an additional income of four to five thousand yuan. The gardener said that although the money was not much, fortunately the family of three did not have high material desires. The gardener kept accounts and statistics of expenses. Every month, family living expenses are about 1,000 to 1,500 yuan. Her parents’ pocket money adds up to 1,000 yuan. Her pocket money is 1,500 yuan, a total of three to four thousand yuan. The income is enough to cover daily expenses. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On every working day, the gardener is responsible for buying vegetables and cooking. She would buy vegetables the afternoon before and cook at 9 or 10 a.m. As usual, she would prepare two green vegetables a day. The meat dishes would be prepared on Monday, such as braised pork, and she would eat a few pieces at a time and then cook them after eating. My mother would come home at 11:30 noon to pack rice to take away, my father would eat at work at noon, and my parents would eat the leftovers from lunch in the evening. In the afternoon, in addition to buying vegetables, the gardener will make bread and pastries and make snacks for his parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My mother doesn&#39;t know how to cook. She hasn&#39;t been able to cook since she was a child, so my father cooked when I was a child. However, my father only cooks the same old food, and the food he cooks is not very delicious. .” The gardener believed that her parents asked her to cook because they felt that she was more suitable for cooking at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gardener has a sense of identity with this &quot;job&quot;, &quot;I have many benefits from cooking at home. I will give them scientific combinations according to dietary guidelines, such as fruits, vegetables, carbohydrates, and milk. If I hadn&#39;t done it, Their health may not be as good as it is now.&quot; She believes that she is different from most full-time children, and she is really taking care of her parents. A netizen replied to her post, &quot;I am about the same age and status as Luzhu (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Owner&lt;/span>;), but my mother mainly cooks at home. It&#39;s time to get ready to improve your cooking skills.&quot; The gardener asked her, &quot;Then what is your function?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have to reflect your value. You can&#39;t just get express delivery as your function, right? Like me , I take care of the family&#39;s finances, make future plans for the family, save money, pay mortgages, and buy things. I don&#39;t work now, and I will try my best to spend less money and live a better life.&quot; Buy Before putting things in her hands, the gardener would think about alternatives in life. For example, she used baking soda instead of dish soap. If she really wants to buy, she will first go to second-hand websites to find brand-new products, or make careful use of coupons on e-commerce platforms. &quot;When you are making money, calculating these is a waste of time, but when you are not making money, calculation is making money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even at home, the gardener lives a very disciplined life. He goes to bed at 9 o&#39;clock every night and goes to bed in the morning. Get up at 6 o&#39;clock and spend most of the day busy. She has never been a lazy person. Before becoming a full-time child, she changed more than a dozen jobs. After each resignation, she would try to find another job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of her previous jobs were clerical, such as travel consulting, hotel reception, office administration, etc. The reason for her resignation was almost always &quot;disagreement with the leader.&quot; &quot;I lacked emotional intelligence and spoke directly. When I first graduated, I didn&#39;t understand anything about society. My father was a worker and my mother ran a small business. They couldn&#39;t teach me anything. Later, I gradually became able to understand eye expressions, but I still don’t understand the need to be diplomatic in situations like the wine table. But I don’t want to change it. Having a high emotional intelligence may mean lowering myself.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2019, the gardener resigned from his last job. , planning to open his own bakery. She taught herself baking in her spare time, can make Chinese and Western snacks, and can even make birthday cakes. In November 2019, she rented a store. It took two months to renovate and it was officially opened in January 2020. However, it was blocked by the COVID-19 epidemic only more than 20 days after opening. It opened again in May 2020. In 2022, Dalian has been under strict epidemic control since June. There was no business until November. The gardener no longer renewed his lease. &quot;I quit. After three years of business, I lost hundreds of thousands.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I asked the gardener, not long after the store was closed, the epidemic prevention and control ended. Do you regret it? Although she regretted the timing of closing the store, she remained calm, &quot;I knew I couldn&#39;t make money, and I couldn&#39;t do it big because I didn&#39;t want to hire people. From selecting raw materials to making it and handing it over to customers, I had to do it all myself. &quot;She closed the store not only because of the epidemic. She found it annoying to deal with customers. &quot;In the service industry, you will meet a lot of weird people. I haven&#39;t done enough work, but I am a little tired of dealing with people.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The shop is closed, but the gardener&#39;s business is still running. She will take orders from some old customers through the WeChat store and earn back her monthly social security fees. &quot;Earning more than a thousand yuan won&#39;t affect my mood in life, and it won&#39;t waste much of my time. If it&#39;s too much, it won&#39;t work and I&#39;ll start to get annoyed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;I don&#39;t want to follow the crowd. &quot;Son&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The gardener&#39;s parents are very supportive of her decision to go home without working. They think that the three members of the family should perform their own duties. The mother cannot cook, the father does not cook well, and the two We are all people who can&#39;t stay at home and like to work outside the house. We just leave things at home to the gardener. Sometimes the gardener reported to her mother how much pocket money she had spent this month, and her mother comforted her, &quot;Okay, this money is not enough to find a cook from outside.&quot; She said to her mother, &quot;I don&#39;t want to go to work, you Raise me.&quot; Mother said cheerfully, &quot;Fine, can&#39;t you raise me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the gardener&#39;s view, my father was simpler than my mother. Once she suggested, &quot;How about we take care of the whole house?&quot; Sold, the three of us will travel around the country together, and we will live wherever the place is good.&quot; My father said, &quot;Then you should act quickly.&quot; Sometimes the gardener feels that she is the person who thinks the most in the family, more like a Parents, &quot;The classic saying from both of them is, &#39;Don&#39;t think so much, just take it one step at a time.&#39; They have no plan for the next step. They support me in whatever I do and believe that what I do is right. Without my words, The two of them are still living in the town, and their lives are definitely not as good as they are now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gardener and her parents bought two small houses in the same community. She bought them first, and later saw that her father&#39;s provident fund was enough After collecting the down payment for a house, I suggested that my parents buy a house in the building next door. The parents do not know how to apply for loans or pay online, and the gardener is responsible for all procedures and loan repayment plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gardener is also concerned about the health management of her parents. She also arranges physical examinations for her parents every year. My mother was diagnosed with early-stage cervical cancer during a physical examination. During the surgery and hospitalization, the gardener accompanied her throughout the entire process.后来她还在个人公众号上写了一篇照顾住院病人的指南，“从头到尾非常详细，我是处女座，做事很细心，就算病人瘫床上我都不会让她长褥疮。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“上哪儿找第二个像我一样的孩子？把父母照顾得无微不至，而且我又不结婚生孩子，不让父母六十多岁还要为儿女操心，帮带孩子。”花匠没有结婚生子、组建家庭的打算，所以在生活上一直都与父母紧密相连。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;退回家庭后，花匠有更多时间回归到自己身上，闲暇时爱看电影和书籍，“我一个月能看60部电影。”她尤其喜欢杨德昌的《一一》和西恩·潘的《荒野生存》，最喜欢的小说则是毛姆的《刀锋》，她欣赏男主角拉里的特立独行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从“随大流”中抽离，摆脱了外界的声音和主流的观念，她能更清醒地认识自己，“原来我是一个不能处理亲密关系的人，我是一个不适合社交的人，我对朋友特别好、特别真诚，但我也想活得自我一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/AnfmnE77VwgCr3DKzeklQ7SH0wCHSQ2p80KkNGZC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/AnfmnE77VwgCr3DKzeklQ7SH0wCHSQ2p80KkNGZC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;候鸟归巢&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对全职儿女中的“全职”的另一重理解与“兼职”相对，重点是形容在承担“子女”这一角色上付出的时间，而非强调职业和经济属性。根据国家卫生健康委发布的数据，我国90%左右的老年人选择居家养老，仅有7%左右的老年人依托社区支持养老，3%的老年人入住机构养老。当居家养老的老年人有照料需求却无法被养老市场满足的时候，子女就要做出选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;减减今年42岁，北京人，多年在外地工作。 5年前的深圳，减减有一天上班时忽然接到父亲的电话，父亲那会儿在公园散步，走累了坐在路边，想儿子了。减减听到电话那头传来的“想你了”，眼泪一下流了出来。自打毕业后，他就没有和父母住在一起，即使在北京工作，和父母的联系也不多。后来他去天津、上海工作，又追着前妻来到深圳，婚姻没有挽回，离父母却更远了。 “我发现自己追求事业，追求爱情，却一直忽略了父母，我开始想回北京了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还没等减减完全下定决心，他就得知了父亲突发心肌梗塞住进CCU（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;心脏重症监护室&lt;/span>;）的消息，“我脑子&#39;嗡&#39;的一下，心乱如麻，缓了好一阵。”减减当即辞职，买了机票回北京，在病房见到了父亲。父亲心梗堵塞90%，且伴有严重的心衰，命悬一线，又因肺部有炎症不能立即做手术，整个人瘦到脱相。 “他看见我说，&#39;这回是不是我得把银行卡密码都告诉你了？&#39;我差点又哭出来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那段时间，减减每天变着花样做饭、熬鸡汤，给父亲送去医院，他明显感到父亲心情好多了，还发短信说病友们都羡慕他，其他人想吃饺子，跟儿女说了好几天才叫来一个外卖。一个月后，父亲做完手术出院，减减也想明白了对他来说什么是最重要的，“不是在事业上取得多大的成绩，因为事业总会有波峰波谷，不是和爱人卿卿我我，因为婚姻不过是利益的结合。只有父母才是真正一辈子对你好的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;减减毕业于北京大学广告学系，传播最广的广告作品是哈药六厂的新盖中盖高钙片。 2014年他尝试写剧本，但碰上资本寒冬，剧本写完拍不了，又进了企业工作。现在回家，他重新拾起了写剧本的活儿。 “虽然收入比起以前差很多，也极不稳定，但是我总算有时间陪伴家人了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;减减跟父亲一起生活，父亲退休工资五千多，家里日常开销都由父亲负责。他写剧本的平均收入是一个月5000元，负责缴纳社保、汽车保险、汽油费、物业费和取暖费等，一年大约3万元。他认为自己和父亲在经济支出上是互相帮助，并非啃老，而是全职儿女。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前工作时，他赚得多，但消费也多，离婚后基本没有剩下多少积蓄；现在，不稳定的收入降低了他的消费欲望，他不旅游、不逛街、不在外吃饭，省去不必要的社交，还学会了理发，很多原本需要花钱才能得到的服务全由自己做，反而存下了一些钱。 “我的养老金肯定没他们高，所以得努力攒钱为将来打算。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲不能完全接受减减的选择，也不支持他写剧本，有时候会对着他说教，“天天窝在家里不是个事。”减减考虑到父亲心脏不好，不想惹他生气，和导演打电话时都躲在房间避开他。有一次实在受不了，出去住了一个星期，回家后发现父亲说话嗓子很别扭，他意识到那是因为父亲一个星期没和人说话了，“我一下子体会到他的孤独，心又软了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“选择做全职儿女放弃了很多东西，我觉得值。”减减回想过去的生活，发现从上幼儿园开始，他就没有好好陪伴父母生活过，“上班的上班，上学的上学，回家后也就是一起吃个饭，然后又各干各的了；等工作了、结婚了就更不用说。”现在，他陪父亲一起散步、研究菜谱、看热播的电视剧、聊天南海北的新闻，最喜欢做的事是给父亲理发、修脚。他获得了一种前所未有的踏实感，“我在拉萨待过半年，心情远比现在浮躁。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他把这些感想化成剧本中的一段台词：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“有时候我真觉得咱们这些北漂挺可怕的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“怎么可怕了？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“哪个北漂不是为了自己的事业把年迈的父母丢在老家？春去秋来，回家看望父母的次数比候鸟还少。有媒体曾经统计过，一个25岁的北漂，按照一年回一次家的频率来计算，他这辈子还能陪伴父母的时间就剩下一个月。现在想想，咱们的心还真是够狠的！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为保护受访者隐私，西西、兰琪、岳杭、青田、花匠、减减均为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[盗用上亿公款打赏主播：“榜一大哥”的名头，何以如此引人入歧途？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257456]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，“月薪6000小伙为见女主播打赏9000万元”上了热搜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘明胜（化名）在江苏张家港一家私企做会计，下载某聊天软件后进入了女主播K宝的直播间，只看一眼便迷上了。根据平台游戏规则，只有成为“榜一大哥”才能取得会见主播的资格。他月薪不过6000元，遂利用职务便利，偷偷转公款打赏。成为K宝直播间“榜一大哥”之后，他如愿和K宝成为线下情人，并发生两性关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年初，集团公司对账时，发现刘明胜掌管的账目有大笔的资金亏空。据公安机关调查，他从公司的账上一共挪走公款约1.23亿元，先后打赏K宝9000万元，给另两名主播也分别打赏了几百万元。最终，被他挪用的约1.23亿元巨额资金大部分得以追回，共计追回1.2268亿元。刘明胜以职务侵占罪被判14年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这“过把瘾就死”的劲儿令人咋舌。其实，此类出纳挪用公款打赏主播的案例还不少，并且男女出纳都有。如银某为广西某房地产开发集团出纳，从2020年起，她爱慕抖音APP的某男主播，疯狂打赏，自己没钱了便动用公款。警方调查发现，她的抖音号2020年下半年充值500多万元，有430万余是用于打赏男主播，其中144万余系公司公款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又如，李某担任珠海某公司济南大区出纳，2018年12月至2020年4月，利用公司财务管理漏洞，将4826.4303万公款转至个人账户，用于打赏女主播、游戏充值、娱乐消费、谈女朋友等，其中直播打赏2000余万。事发后，这位“榜一大哥”被判12年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这类事件的一大共性是出纳收入不高，但过手的钱多，如果个人没有很好的品性与职业伦理，很容易陷入心态失衡，而出纳最明白公司的财务漏洞在哪里，所以他们一旦“有心算无心”，公司财务制度至少一段时间内都形同虚设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个值得思考的方向是：网络直播究竟是一个什么样的行业，主要满足了谁的什么方面的需求？那些人挥霍自己的钱、父母的钱甚至公司的钱，打赏异性主播，究竟是何种心态？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网络直播包含了若干种不同的业态，其中之一是至今方兴未艾的直播带货。如果将其仅仅看成一种新的分销渠道就错了，因为与线下渠道或其他“传统”电商渠道相比，主播卖的可不仅仅是货。尤其是那些做得比较成功的主播，同时贩卖“人设”、提供情绪价值，有类似明星-粉丝的关系存在，往往满足了异性粉丝对另一半的最好想象，甚至性幻想。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者，甚至可以这么说，那些红得发紫的主播，明明做好静好安暖或美美哒的“人设”就可以向粉丝收钱，竟然还额外附送一些还能用得上的商品，真是太“厚道”了。于是，沿着这条路径，“直播带货”的一部分会进化成“直播打赏”，既然不带货也能挣钱，那就不带货、不卖货，直接向粉丝卖“人设”就行了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，“直播打赏”也有多个不同的来源，受众与性质迥异，所以需要分开讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，其另一条进化路径是过去天桥杂耍、街头卖艺及卖惨乞讨从线下转到了线上，其主要受众或是草根阶层或是不特定公众，本文不再赘述。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一条进化路径是，分享欲与窥看欲的互联网化并进一步视频化。一些人把自己的工作、生活、爱好或技能通过视频与大家分享，有直播的，也有录播的，也不乏成功的案例，如钓鱼能手、套圈王、“手工耿”之类，让大家增加了对自己陌生领域的了解与知见，或让大家身临其境感受到自己向往的生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们这里重点讨论的“直播打赏”，有显著的主播-粉丝关系，并且一般是男主播-女粉丝、女主播-男粉丝关系，这就不可避免多少带有性意味&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“饮食男女，人之大欲存焉”“食色性也”，毋庸讳言，人的生命力很大一部分系于性能量或性欲望上。让无数中老年女性倾倒的“秀才”，让无数中老年男性倾倒的“一笑倾城”，让无数青年男女如痴如醉的明星，本质并无二致，说到是这些主播或明星的长相、气质与“人设”满足了异性对另一半最好的幻想，这才是这类“纯直播打赏”的发生学与动力学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鲁迅说，不满是向上的车轮。很少有人对自己目前的生活是完全满意的，对工作不满，对男女朋友或配偶不满，遂期望一种理想的生活，包括理想的配偶，也是人之常情。但是首先要明白自己的能力边界，明白自己在这个社会中是什么样的排序，这样就会对自己目前的生活是否“配得上自己”、人间是否“值得”有一个挤去水分的客观判断，自知者明。然后对于现状，该改变就改变，该接受就接受，这就是跟自己和解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而如果为了精神上的满足，把家中的大额财物甚至不是自己的财物打赏给异性主播，那实质上不是在提升而是在毁掉自己的生活。上述男女出纳挪用公款打赏异性主播正是此类情形。总之，每一个人应该把自己旺盛的生命力用在提升自己上，这样配得上的好东西就越来越多，这是正向利用自己生命能量的方法，而不是消耗自己的所有资源乃至生命力去满足自己的幻想。置个人的荣誉与前途不顾，只为“过把瘾就死”，枉费了人世间走一遭的好机缘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美成立经济领域工作组]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;为落实中美两国元首巴厘岛会晤重要共识，根据国务院副总理、中美经贸中方牵头人何立峰与美国财政部部长珍妮特·耶伦达成的共识，中美双方商定，成立经济领域工作组，包括“经济工作组”和“金融工作组”。 “经济工作组”由中美两国财政部副部长级官员牵头，“金融工作组”由中国人民银行和美国财政部副部长级官员牵头。两个工作组将定期、不定期举行会议，就经济、金融领域相关问题加强沟通和交流。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《红色天空》：在侯麦与王家卫之间]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256843]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qREaPt1m0u1fMC3ZO4Teszy6wrUZVg5tiIPhaaMY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qREaPt1m0u1fMC3ZO4Teszy6wrUZVg5tiIPhaaMY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250592&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;概念至上的佩措尔德&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在当代德国电影导演中，克里斯蒂安·佩措尔德可能是最受瞩目的一位。之前的“幽灵三部曲”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《心的居所》《幽灵》《耶拉》&lt;/span>;）和“移民三部曲”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《芭芭拉》《不死鸟》《过境》&lt;/span>;），让他在国际影坛收获了良好口碑。于是他趁热打铁，继续推出以“元素精灵”为主题的系列作品。以水女神为主题的《温蒂妮》（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020&lt;/span>;）是系列首作；在2023年柏林电影节斩获评审团大奖，以火之精灵沙罗曼达为主题的《红色天空》，则是这个系列的第二弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过梳理佩措尔德的创作轨迹，我们能发现一些明显的特点。他的作品知识分子气较重，会围绕某些特定主题，进行近乎论文式的阐释。同时他非常强调概念所占据的核心位置，在如此创作观念的引领下，古典神话角色的命运与现代德国人的处境相交叠（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《不死鸟》&lt;/span>;），二战时期犹太人的颠沛处境，也和当代欧洲阿拉伯裔难民的流离命运相互对撞（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《过境》&lt;/span>;），激荡出奇妙的化学反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我们也不得不指出，佩措尔德的电影虽然概念迷人，却在血肉与肌理上略显刻板，缺了些真实可感的生命力。这个问题在《温蒂妮》中暴露得尤为明显：将一位古典神话中的水精灵与一位当代德国工业潜水员的生活结合在一起的尝试，在纸面上非常有趣，却在转化为影像后很容易堕入在形而上与形而下两端疯狂摇摆、最终却两边都不靠的窘境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;佩措尔德一定是意识到了他在《温蒂妮》中的失策。于是在拍摄新作《红色天空》时，他寻求着一种更轻盈的笔触：形而上的神话元素被隐藏得更深，形而下的日常生活则被推向前台。剧情设定在一段夏日假期中，心事重重的年轻作家莱昂受邀来到朋友费利克斯的海滨度假屋，试图在安静环境中为小说收尾，同时等待出版商的裁决。但在这段本应令自己平静的时光里，他却被动结识了美丽活泼的女孩娜迪亚，和与她关系若即若离的情人德维。莱昂的内心被搅起涟漪，但逐渐临近的deadline（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;截稿日期&lt;/span>;）和知识分子的包袱，让他对娜迪亚的情愫变得纠结扭曲，这为4个人的生活制造出了一系列的喜剧和戏剧性。与此同时，一场山火则在内陆蔓延，成为整个故事令人不安的背景音，没有人知道，这段轻盈的假期，最终会不会结束于熊熊烈焰中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与佩措尔德诸多前作的片名一样，“红色天空”同样充满了潜能。它既在具象层面指代着被山火染红的天空，也在隐喻层面影射着几位主人公之间呼之欲出的性张力，以及在新约《圣经》“启示录”一卷中扑面而来的末世景象。但影片的故事，最终还是没能兑现其片名的全部潜能。山火的巨大破坏力，几乎是被一段野猪在森林中奔跑的镜头和两个辅助性角色的画外死亡一笔带过；而“Memento mori”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;终将死去&lt;/span>;）式的死亡警诫，也没能和人物的欲望互为表里地结合起来。归根到底，《红色天空》仍然讲述着一位以自我为中心的男性主人公追逐女主角，并在追逐过程中觉醒的故事。不论是他的好友、出版商，还是那场大火与死亡，甚至包括女主角本身，似乎都是引领他通往自我觉醒的工具。而在佩措尔德高超诱人的概念构建能力和他只能说是勉强高于平均水准的叙事表意能力之间，依然存在一道巨大鸿沟。 《红色天空》与其前作相比已有进步，但这道鸿沟仍需填补。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Zh1Vsz896cTN46UvPe0CjDwWeYJydBhnwEzqf2Qb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Zh1Vsz896cTN46UvPe0CjDwWeYJydBhnwEzqf2Qb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250590&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;隐而不发的情节剧大师&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与其在叙事和表意方面的温吞表现相比，佩措尔德对浪漫关系的书写和对情爱氛围的烘托能力，却堪称杰出。德国人向来以严肃著称，这容易让人忘记，不论是歌德和荷尔德林这样的浪漫派诗人，还是道格拉斯·瑟克和赖纳·维尔纳·法斯宾德这样的情节剧大师，都是在莱茵河的滋养中长大的。在某种程度上，佩措尔德也是前辈们浪漫衣钵的继承人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但佩措尔德的可贵之处在于，他对爱情关系的书写，不仅有着德国式的绝望浪漫，同时也带着一丝在欧美创作者中难得一见的含蓄气质。与占有爱慕对象的身体相比，佩措尔德的男主角们似乎总是对他们爱慕之人的灵魂更感兴趣，但他们在追求对方的过程中，又总是那么羞涩、笨拙，以至于幸福的终点看上去永远遥不可及。与之相对应的，佩措尔德的女主人公总像游移的精灵一般飘忽不定，无法被定义，无法被把捉。她们是自由的灵魂，毫不掩饰对倾心之人的情感，却又总是拒绝被定义为一成不变的符号，也永远拒绝成为客体。于是在佩措尔德的电影中，追逐与躲闪相交替的错位游戏一直进行着，这游戏仿佛自从男性女性诞生之时便一直在进行，也必将持续至世界的尽头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《红色天空》中，夏日假期、乡间度假屋的设定，与佩措尔德前作相比更为轻盈的调性，和角色们具有艺术家和知识分子气息的谈吐，都会或多或少让我们想起在埃里克·侯麦的电影中，那些对举棋不定的直男角色怀有善意的讽刺调侃，以及那些在喜剧基调之下，对情感百态不动声色的透视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在另一方面，佩措尔德制造浪漫情境的天赋，他对女性角色的浓烈爱意，以及他电影中男女角色因躲闪和克制而变得更加激烈的情感关系，都会让人想到另一个擅长制造浪漫氛围的电影大师——王家卫。或许，《过境》《温蒂妮》和《红色天空》的女主演葆拉·贝尔，已经悄然成为佩措尔德的张曼玉。这些电影的剧情，可能很快会从我们头脑中消逝，但葆拉·贝尔的明媚微笑和一袭红裙，却会久久留在我们的记忆里，透过男性导演那道无法彻底理解其所思所感，却依然（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;或者说——正因为如此而&lt;/span>;）充满倾慕的目光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[餐厅员工发顾客打娃视频后赔1万离职，警方如此调解令人费解]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据报道，9月19日，阻拦母亲殴打女儿、并将相关视频在网络发布的西餐厅员工江先生，在赔偿对方1万元后已辞职离开长沙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江先生之前在网上发布的监控视频显示，当事女子胡某一手提着购物袋，朝着小女孩不停地怒吼。随后，她带着孩子来到江先生所工作的西餐厅，要求孩子向她交代此前惹事的过程。而就在这时，胡某情绪失控，放下手中的购物袋，提起身边的椅子试图砸向女孩，江先生和同事上前阻拦。附近商户接受湖南电视台记者采访时透露，这对母女路过他家门店时，女孩突然摔倒，手里的冰激凌也洒落一地，导致衣服弄脏。随即，胡某情绪失控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江先生称，事发后胡某多次来到餐厅，称其不该把视频上网传播，并扬言要死在餐厅里。经当地派出所调解，江先生向对方赔偿精神损失费及医药费1万元后，主动向老板提出了辞职。网友们纷纷表示：“打人的人没事，阻止打人的人受到惩罚”，“看到这个视频真的是心疼这个娃娃”，还有网友说，“实在太让人寒心了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;餐厅员工阻止女子胡某当众殴打女儿，将视频上传网络，因此惹下麻烦，此事涉及多个方面，包括家庭暴力、公共监督、隐私权以及执法方面的是非。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先须明确的是，胡某当众殴打女儿的行为，属于典型的家庭暴力行为，不仅有违公序良俗，更触犯了相关法律。根据《中华人民共和国反家庭暴力法》第二条，家庭暴力是指家庭成员之间以殴打、捆绑、残害、限制人身自由以及经常性谩骂、恐吓等方式实施的身体、精神等侵害行为。第五条规定，未成年人、老年人、残疾人、孕期和哺乳期的妇女、重病患者遭受家庭暴力的，应当给予特殊保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对胡某的违法行为第一时间进行处理，乃派出所应尽职责。《中华人民共和国反家庭暴力法》第三十三条规定，加害人实施家庭暴力，构成违反治安管理行为的，依法给予治安管理处罚。可见，父母殴打子女，执法机关不能以“清官难断家务事”为由不闻不问。在此事件中，胡某公开殴打女儿，公众观感很是不好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于餐厅员工江先生公布视频的行为，从法律角度来看，他并没有侵犯胡某的肖像权。因为这是对公共场所违法行为的曝光，江先生是在行使公民的监督权。民法典第一千零二十条规定，合理实施下列行为的，可以不经肖像权人同意：为维护公共利益或者肖像权人合法权益，制作、使用、公开肖像权人的肖像的其他行为。江先生曝光其视频，显然是希望引发社会对于家庭暴力现象的关注，共同维护未成年人权益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;退一步而言，即使胡某认为自己的权益被侵犯，也应该通过合法的途径如诉讼等方式来维护自己的权益，而不是通过闹事等不正当手段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡某就此在餐厅多次闹事，然而派出所没有对其追责，反而以调解的方式，让江先生赔偿精神损失费及医药费1万元。此举不仅寒了江先生的心，也是释放出错误信号：如果违法行为可以通过调解来解决，甚至获得反向补偿，不就纵容了更多人任性而为？如此，法律也就失去了它的威严和公正。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为执法机关，应以法律为依据，注重保护未成年人的权益，以及公民见义勇为的行为，对违法行为零容忍，以此形成法律的威慑力，进而引导社会风气，通过普法教育来提高公民的素质。遗憾的是，派出所以当事人的情绪来左右处理结果，默认了当事女子“越闹越有理”的行为，如此调解与法理不符。网友们对此调解普遍质疑，表达了朴素的正义观。执法部门理应对此事重新调查，让违法者担责，而不是让见义勇为者因此赔钱又丢了工作，如此方能让人们对司法权威的信仰不致受损。毕竟，法律的威严与信用，往往就体现在执法者的日常之举中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如果你导弹打得不够准，是因为你人靠得不够近丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257374]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/gup4AaFCsszUqfElPfxsoCHZgB5ey11TUdvQehIu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/gup4AaFCsszUqfElPfxsoCHZgB5ey11TUdvQehIu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月13日，克里米亚地区塞瓦斯托波尔，烟雾从遇袭的造船厂滚滚而出&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，乌克兰方面消息称，乌克兰军方在2023年9月13日凌晨以10枚导弹和3艘无人艇对克里米亚半岛的塞瓦斯托波尔军事基地发动攻击，导致塞凡堡造船厂起火，正在维修的两艘舰船受损，分别为俄黑海舰队的罗普查级登陆舰“明斯克号”（Minsk），以及造价高达3亿美元、2014年才服役的基洛级柴油动力潜舰“顿河畔罗斯托夫号”（Rostov-on-Don）。现场的卫星图片显示，这两艘舰船损毁严重，要修复难度极大且花费不小，考虑到战时体系下这样的工程很难完成，因此基本只能报废。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯方面也承认遭到乌克兰导弹袭击，有舰艇受损，双方公布的情况基本证实了这次攻击的战果。这是俄乌开战后黑海舰队旗舰莫斯科号被击沉以来，该舰队遭遇的最大一次损失，也开创了有史以来潜艇第一次被导弹击中的纪录。更神奇的是，就在本次攻击两天之后，乌克兰又宣布，使用导弹和无人机攻击了克里米亚半岛上的S-400防空导弹系统，该系统一直被认为是俄罗斯最强的现役防空武器，土耳其甚至为了购买此系统跟美国和北约关系紧张，这次在实战中被乌克兰敌后斩首，让人大跌眼镜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一轮组合拳式的连续攻击，显然不是偶然为之的战果，而是乌克兰情报机关和国防部的一次联合军事行动，其中乌特种部队的行动可以说是功不可没。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在发动导弹袭击的前两天，也就是9月11日，乌情报部门宣布特种部队成功夺取黑海中的两座海上油气钻井平台，并成功移除该平台上的俄军事设施。地图显示，乌特种部队夺取的两个平台大约距离克里米亚海岸线五十多公里，俄军在上面设置了对空对海警戒雷达，以控制黑海地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次攻击并未引起国内舆论太多关注，甚至有一些媒体认为这是乌克兰反攻不利后的政治作秀，因为夺取那两个平台的战斗并不激烈，且没有太大的军事价值。然而在我看来，夺取海上平台的战斗才是这次攻击的序幕，因为乌克兰并没有隐形战机这种可以穿透敌防空网的装备，因此必须尽量压缩对方防空武器的反应时间，而这两座平台正好是俄罗斯的外围观测点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美军在2003伊拉克战争开始前，就用特种部队成功夺取了伊拉克在波斯湾的三个海上钻井平台，主要目的一方面是为了拔掉伊拉克在波斯湾的眼线，另一方面则为了避免伊拉克像海湾战争中那样对波斯湾倾倒石油污染环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当年的行动中，除了英美特种部队之外，波兰雷鸣特殊任务部队也承担了一个平台的进攻任务。这种夺取海上平台的战斗在特战领域被简称为VBSS（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;访问、登船、搜查和扣押&lt;/span>;），VBSS任务往往只有海上精锐特战单位才能胜任，此类行动之所以复杂，在于其涉及从水下到水面的战斗机动，并且还包括极近距离的室内作战。不仅需要大量的战前侦察，还需要行动单位进行大量的针对性实战训练才能下定决心实施。这种海上夺点行动一般不可能只是个政治表态性的任务，因为风险和成本都太大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从两天后导弹攻击可以看出，乌克兰夺取黑海钻井平台的行动只是其庞大行动计划的一部分，实际上后续的行动才是取得胜利的关键。在潜艇和登陆舰遭到导弹袭击后，乌克兰方面隔了一天才发动导弹攻击，战斗节奏似乎显得不够紧凑。但事实上，在夺取平台后乌特战人员并没有耽搁，另外一个攻击队在夜色掩护下悄悄在克里米亚半岛登陆，抵近侦察了造船厂中的潜艇和登陆舰，并使用热成像对其进行多角度的拍摄。在攻击发生后，这些潜伏的特战人员又对轰炸效果进行侦察和评估后才悄悄撤走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;空射导弹攻击因为涉及到入射角的问题，需要构建目标的三维图像，并察需要确认其雷达信息或热成像信息，这些都需要多角度的技术侦察。美国或许可以依靠其强大的卫星和侦察机平台进行侦察，对于缺乏技术侦察手段的乌克兰，使用特种部队或者秘密行动人员进行抵近侦察则是不错的替代方案。而且即便是美国这种技术侦察能力强大的国家，特种部队的抵近侦察仍是可选的手段之一，比如在海湾战争中美国为了寻找伊拉克的飞毛腿导弹，就派出多个特战小组进入伊拉克后方进行抵近侦察。除此之外，对于敌方防空武器信号特征的搜集，部署特战人员抵近检测也是非常可行的办法，因为只需要一套信号接收器，这些潜伏人员就可以长期获得周边警戒雷达的频谱信息，也可以获得更为全面的信号情报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有很多人认为无人机的出现可以替代特战人员，但实际上赢得战争的从来都是人而不是机器，只有人的素质匹配技术手段，才能战胜强大的对手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 20:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10人遇难，强龙卷风突袭江苏后，救灾与保险赔付正进行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/d0f40bac84.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/d0f40bac84.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251665&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月20日，宿迁市南蔡乡龙卷风受灾现场。视觉中国图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“几十秒的时间”“就几分钟”“十几分钟吧”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;龙卷风过境后，当地居民已记不清大风吹了多久。2023年9月19日这场突如其来的灾害，袭击了江苏省宿迁市、盐城市部分地区，据两地官方通报，共造成10人遇难、8人受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两天后，在宿迁市南蔡乡梨园路上，李鹏一直埋头收拾家里和超市的各种杂物，清理通道；在该市另一个乡镇大兴镇上北街，68岁的陈健强爬上了自家屋顶，收拾被龙卷风吹过的瓦片，准备重新盖顶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长达两公里的南蔡乡南大街已经大致恢复了往常的秩序，倒伏的树木、碎玻璃渣子被清理干净，临时货摊准备摆起来。在当地居民提供的20日照片中，唯有小货车上的梨，在龙卷风当天被掉下来的高压电缆烧得一半焦黑，还整齐地码着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这场龙卷风中，宿迁市宿豫区大兴镇、经开区南蔡乡发生的龙卷风为EF2级，盐城市阜宁县芦蒲镇、板湖镇的龙卷风为EF3级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据江苏省气象服务中心官微“江苏气象”介绍，龙卷强度分为EF0级至EF5级，EF2级及以上龙卷一般称为强龙卷，EF2级龙卷就会产生相当大的破坏，它可能连根拔起树木；EF3级龙卷甚至可能刮倒火车。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在宿迁，龙卷风不是常见的自然灾害，来得快去得也快。而在盐城，据盐城市阜宁县委宣传部介绍，江苏年均发生4.8次龙卷，其中有2.6次发生在盐城，盐城是发生频率最高的设市区。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“那一瞬间都吓蒙了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月19日傍晚5点多，龙卷风袭来的时候，罗琦正到学校接孩子，没注意到它的身影。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到家的时候，街上已经一片狼藉。罗琦看到，在南大街上，电线冒着火光，小汽车燃起熊熊大火。街上日常有个小集市，就在罗琦家的门口。她家门面的一个棚子被吹走了，不见踪影，另一个原来用绳子绑到了树上，结果砸在了冰柜上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗琦查看家里的监控视频发现，龙卷风来临前的3分钟异常平静，只是淅淅沥沥下着小雨。17时11分开始，监控录到一段较大的风声，门口的棚子被吹动。紧接着风声越来越大，路边飘过一顶红色的四角帐篷，大箱子被吹着跑，地上所有的小型物件开始四处飘飞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗琦说，孩子的奶奶当时正在门口洗菜，看情况不对想回屋里时，直接被风卷起的三轮车挤到了墙边。车上的车窗玻璃扎入她的手肘和脚，当晚到医院缝针了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗琦家旁边摊位的摊主则没那么幸运，他被风卷起来摔到了马路对面。那时街上手腕粗的主电缆突然掉落，燃起火光，大家都害怕触电。“那一瞬间都吓蒙了。”罗琦说，她三十多年来，第一次见到这么猛烈的龙卷风。那位摊主的妻子一直在寻求帮助，但没人敢施救。后来警察封锁了现场，人为断电后电缆还在冒火光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与南大街交叉的梨园路上，李鹏开了一家小型超市。在他的记忆中，龙卷风持续不过几分钟时间。但就在那几分钟里，龙卷风把街道两旁的屋顶几乎尽数掀翻，“那些石棉瓦和棚子都悬在天上，像飞机那么高，到处乱刮”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李鹏的家是16年的老瓦房，由于房屋之前一直没有出现过问题，李鹏也没有对房子做过加固和翻修。瓦房在这次龙卷风中损失惨重，房顶一直在漏水，里面的家具和门都砸坏了。“我没有算过损失了多少，只能等开始维修的时候才能具体统计。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;龙卷风一路移动至大兴镇时，已到了6点左右。14岁的女孩范特特刚从学校回家，她远远地看到一团黑色的东西慢慢往上卷起来，“它就好像连着天空一样，很长的”。吃晚饭时，家里的灯一闪一闪的，很快就停电了。一阵大风刮进了范特特的家里，奶奶前去堵两扇玻璃门，但是怎么也关不上。范特特跑去帮忙，“有股强大的吸力把我吸到门口，又吹到了树上”。范特特体重85斤，抱着门外的大树没敢动弹，直到风停了才顺着树干下来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“江苏气象”9月20日消息，9月19日，江苏受到两个龙卷风的影响。第一个龙卷是从17时到18时之间，在宿迁市经开区以及大兴镇；另外一个是从20时16分到35分，在盐城市阜宁县。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而据宿迁市应急管理局官方公众号消息，此次龙卷风灾情主要发生在乡镇镇区，人员稠密、建筑结构复杂，且发生时段恰逢下班时间。经初步统计，此次强龙卷风受灾人口5512人，1646户房屋一般受损，倒塌房屋137户，农作物受损41.8公顷，临时转移安置405人，2000余平米猪舍部分墙体倒塌、顶部塌陷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/9a3ba8adc3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/9a3ba8adc3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;南蔡乡的路边，电力工人在抢修线路。视觉中国图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;民房保险正在核查赔付&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;宿迁市蓝天救援队队长助理孙伟告诉南方周末记者，宿迁常见的灾害为暴雨水灾。相对而言，龙卷风在盐城市更频发，江苏沿海的民间救援队伍曾对雷暴天气、飓风天气做针对性的培训。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;19日傍晚6点多，蓝天救援队13名队员赶到经开区南蔡乡，当地消防救援队已抵达现场，蓝天队员协助配合清理倒伏的树木、散乱的杂物等，开辟出一条畅通的道路；同时排查供电线路，防止漏电等次生灾害，“我们一直作业至次日凌晨两点”。南蔡乡的道路清理于20日基本结束，宿迁蓝天救援队下午增援12人往大兴镇摸排受灾情况，主要协助乡镇工作人员核实有没有灾后失联的人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙伟说，龙卷风过境后还有一项工作是收拾建筑物外立面的杂物，比如屋檐边上的空调被吹到了支架外围，需要调整位置，受损严重的屋顶上有破碎的瓦片，要尽快清理。“防止龙卷风过后的暴雨，将原本歪斜的物品摔下来，造成次生灾害。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于大兴镇北街上的居民陈健强夫妇来说，主要问题是屋顶瓦片破碎后，晚上如何入睡。女儿陈果说，父母家的屋顶在几天前刚翻修完成，花三四千元换了新瓦片，没想到这次龙卷风掀开了大半，屋内的电器也淋了一夜的雨。幸好走廊是硬水泥板构造，两位老人就在走廊上铺上几层被子过了一晚。9月20日，七十多岁的姨夫赶来帮忙修房顶，不知什么时候能修好。村里来人登记了房屋损失，但是老人不清楚后续如何补助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月20日晚，宿迁市应急管理局发布微信文章称，已为宿迁市市区居民投保了公共安全城乡救助保险，将对宿迁市内的城乡住房由于洪涝、台风、山体塌崩、滑坡等自然灾害、火灾爆炸等造成的房屋损失进行赔付。赔付标准是城镇住房的房屋主体结构保险金额18万元/户，室内装潢保险金额12万元/户；农村住房的房屋主体结构保险金额18万元/户，室内装潢保险金额4万元/户。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该项目的承保方主要为中国人民财产保险股份有限公司宿迁市分公司，该公司联系人郑新波告诉南方周末记者，这一民房保险由政府统一购买，每户缴纳2元，已经连续购买多年。此次灾害发生后，他们于20日派出三十多位工作人员到乡镇核查定损，将在国庆假期前完成第一批赔付。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相对而言，盐城市应对龙卷风更有经验。公开资料显示，2012年6月23日，盐城&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: none;&quot;>;市&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;file://item/%E9%98%9C%E5%AE%81/871643%3ffromModule=lemma_inlink&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; text-decoration: none;&quot;>;阜宁&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; text-decoration: none;&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;file://item/%E5%B0%84%E9%98%B3/871862%3ffromModule=lemma_inlink&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; text-decoration: none;&quot;>;射阳&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;部分地区出现EF4级的龙卷风，风力超过17级，造成99人死亡，846人受伤。当地为此建造了盐城抗击“6.23”特大龙卷风纪念馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阜宁县委宣传部称，阜宁县对于发生频次较高的自然灾害也制定了相应的应急预案。此次龙卷风过后，第一时间在受灾镇成立“9.19”风灾抢险救援指挥部；安排专班到每一个受灾村摸清情况，第一时间掌握灾情并迅速上报。9月19日连夜开展4轮过筛式搜救行动。此外，通过投亲靠友、入住宾馆等方式，紧急转移安置受灾群众129人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江苏是全国龙卷风多发地区。据“江苏气象”消息，1956年至2015年，江苏共出现109个龙卷，其中发生在夏季的占比最高，达到79.8%，年平均1.5个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江苏易发生龙卷的原因是：全省地势平坦，河流湖泊密集，位于南北气候过渡带，冷暖气流频繁交汇，容易形成包括龙卷风在内的强对流天气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述文中的气象专家表示，通常在9月的中下旬，江苏已经不太容易发生龙卷，但近期由于气温较高，而且受江淮气旋的影响，带来了比较强的动力条件。在这样的背景下，9月19日江苏出现了比较罕见的龙卷事件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;21日，江苏省气象台副台长王啸华在接受央广网采访时表示，江苏省气象台经过2021—2023年强对流大风示范体系建设，具备了梅雨锋背景和台风背景下，龙卷的一些初步预报预警能力。下一步，气象部门将根据气候变化特点，应用多波段雷达协同观测等多源观测数据，改进优化龙卷预警技术和指标，进一步提高预报预警能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中当地居民为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[白切鸡寿司走红，年轻人流行的“中餐日作”是真香吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257296]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 17:30:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[钱锺书回避鲁迅？No，他开启了“悄悄关注”模式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257339]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/22/Al0NA8piZmtUhLaOo6f35jIRv7oOmF4B0asgnIe8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;732&quot; height=&quot;487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/Al0NA8piZmtUhLaOo6f35jIRv7oOmF4B 0asgnIe8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251595&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Lin Yutang, Lu Xun, Soong Ching Ling, Smedley, Li Peihua (Secretary of Soong Ching Ling) ). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Qian Zhongshu rarely talked about Lu Xun publicly, he could not &quot;avoid&quot; Lu Xun. Crystal once said in &quot;Miscellaneous Notes of Shi Qian&#39;s Throwing Books&quot; that at a symposium, Qian Zhongshu praised Lu Xun&#39;s short stories for being well written, but not suitable for long stories. The most well-known person is Qian Zhongshu&#39;s opening speech at the &quot;Lu Xun and Chinese and Foreign Culture&quot; academic seminar. This article was later published in &quot;Literary Journal&quot; on October 23, 1986, and collected in &quot;The Edge of Life&quot;. In his opening speech, Qian Zhongshu said a few words &quot;as usual&quot; based on people&#39;s &quot;public opinion&quot; of Lu Xun at that time: &quot;Lu Xun was a great man. The greater the figure, the more aspects can be observed; &#39;Chinese and foreign culture&#39; is a big The bigger the topic, the wider the scope of the problems that can occur.&quot; The main spirit of his speech was to hope that everyone can &quot;speak freely without bending the meaning to seek consensus&quot;, and could not see the true evaluation of Lu Xun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Qian Zhongshu and Lu Xun also had a period of time in the same city. In September 1927, Lu Xun left Guangzhou and lived in Shanghai until his death in October 1936. Qian Zhongshu graduated from Tsinghua University in the summer of 1933 and taught at Guanghua University. He began studying at Oxford in the autumn of 1935, so he spent more than two years in Shanghai. However, they were only from the same city, and the two of them had never been seen crossing paths. However, as a later scholar and because of Lu Xun&#39;s huge influence, Qian Zhongshu inevitably had to &quot;encounter&quot; Lu Xun intentionally or unintentionally when writing. &quot;On the Parallel Study of Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu&quot; written by Liu Yukai and &quot;On the Comparative Study of Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu Literature&quot; written by Sui Qing&#39;e have all made comparisons from an academic level. Scholars such as Xie Yong, Wang Peijun, Li Guotao and Qian Zhijun have made comparisons in their writings. There are also elucidations from time to time, and I would like to unearth several examples related to Lu Xun from Qian Zhongshu&#39;s writings, which may fill the gaps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Besieged City&quot;, Sun Roujia&#39;s uncle and aunt hold important positions in a large cotton factory and have always looked down upon Fang Hongjian. Once, Fang Hongjian and Sun Roujia quarreled again over the arrival of his aunt. When he learned that his aunt wanted to find a position for him in the factory, he jumped up and shouted: &quot;Who wants her to find trouble for me? I can&#39;t even beg for food.&quot; Don&#39;t ask her for it! Isn&#39;t it enough that she has two lackeys, Bobby and you, Sun Roujia? You tell her that Fang Hongjian &#39;has no skills but a very bad temper&#39;, and you won&#39;t be a lackey of a capitalist lackey.&quot; This paragraph of text , immediately reminds people of Lu Xun&#39;s famous article &quot;&quot;Bereaved&quot; and &quot;The Capitalist&#39;s Lacking Lackey&quot; published in 1930, which criticized Liang Shiqiu. Although Qian Zhongshu was studying in Tsinghua University at the time, he would not have missed the articles on the Lu-Liang debate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 84 of the first volume of the Commercial Press&#39;s &quot;Notes of Rong&#39;an Pavilion&quot;, reading the notes of Yue Ke&#39;s &quot;History&quot;, Qian Zhongshu excerpted the following paragraph in Volume 12 and added a note:&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the summer of the 10th year of the reign of Emperor Xizong (Wanyan) of the Jin Dynasty, Long Jian (present) in the Yuzhai Palace, there was a heavy thunderstorm Arrive, break the pillar and go away. Everyone was shocked, thinking it was ominous, and wanted to look at it in disgust. Some people thought that a general amnesty should be granted, so they called Zhang Jun, a bachelor, to draft the imperial edict. Among them are the words &quot;Gu Zi is ignorant&quot; and &quot;Looking at Yu Xiaozi&quot;. The translator did not know the meaning of Tuo Qianchong, so he said: &quot;Han&#39;er is strong in knowledge, and he relies on words to criticize my Lord&#39;s ears.&quot; When asked why, he translated and explained its meaning: &quot;The widowed is lonely and has no relatives; the ignorant is ignorant of human affairs; the eyes are blind; the brat is a child.&quot; He was furious and summoned Jun to question him, but he failed to answer him. , slash (cut) its mouth with a hand sword, and dig it with thorns. I didn&#39;t know that it was translated as &quot;foolishness&quot; or &quot;treachery&quot;. So... According to this, Lu Xun is also the ancestor of literal translation. &quot; (&quot;Notes of Rong&#39;an Pavilion&quot; page 146)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Xizong Wanyan Dan was the third emperor of the Jin Dynasty. It is said that he studied under Han Fang before he came to the throne and was able to write poems in Chinese. After he came to the throne, he was particularly diligent in studying Chinese classics. According to this article in the &quot;History of the Emperor&quot;, Wanyan Quan did not seem to be very proficient in Chinese, and the translator could only &quot;literally translate&quot;, taking out of context the commonly used imperial edicts. Formulas such as &quot;Gu Zi is ignorant&quot; and &quot;Xiao Yu Xiaozi&quot; can be &quot;directly interpreted&quot; as cursing the Lord, thus losing the original meaning of &quot;retreating, trusting, and rushing&quot;, and Zhang Jun was convicted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Zhongshu&#39;s note &quot;This is the ancestor of Lu Xun&#39;s literal translation&quot; naturally reminds people of the &quot;Lu-Liang Controversy&quot;. In September 1929, Liang Shiqiu published &quot;On Mr. Lu Xun&#39;s Life&quot; in &quot;Crescent&quot; &quot;Hard Translation&quot;&quot;, Lu Xun refuted it by publishing &quot;&quot;Hard Translation&quot; and &quot;The Class Nature of Literature&quot;&quot; in &quot;Jinya Monthly&quot; in March of the following year. The debate has exceeded the boundaries of translation. As far as translation is concerned, Lu Xun advocated &quot;literal translation&quot; (or &quot;hard translation&quot;), such as the translation of &quot;The Symbol of Depression&quot;, which &quot;is translated sentence by sentence, or even word for word according to the rules&quot;, and its purpose is to &quot;prefer to believe rather than obey.&quot; Qian Zhongshu is obviously familiar with translation However, his views were different from those of Lu Xun, so Qian Zhongshu went on to write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yu Reading &quot;Shuowen&quot; to the &quot;Kou&quot; part of the 26th word &quot;囮: 译也&quot;, Chang sighs Ji Chang (Editor&#39;s note: refers to Xu Shen), a true saint, foresees Tradutore, traditore! Wang Yuanzhi&#39;s &quot;Little Animals Collection&quot; Volume 14 &quot;Translation Dui&quot; says: &quot;Translation means Yi. It can change one&#39;s mind if it is big, but it can only change one&#39;s words if it is small. &quot;So on and so forth. After liberation, the trend of translating books became more and more popular. They did not know how to make mistakes, but they were eaten alive. Not only were they changed beyond recognition, but their hearts and minds were completely changed. They were the so-called &quot;great translators&quot; in Xun Yuan Dynasty. Gu Tangsheng&#39;s &quot;Records of Zhang Wenxiang&#39;s Shogunate&quot; Juan Xia said: &quot;Chen Lanbin envoy to the United States, one of his attendants, Xu, is not familiar with Western languages. One day, he suddenly picked up the Western Newspaper and seemed to be reading it with gusto. His colleagues asked him strangely. Xu said: I can&#39;t understand the Western Newspaper. I read Zhu Jun&#39;s translation. Also puzzled. If you still don&#39;t understand, it would be better to just read the Western newspaper. &quot;In this way, both this and Zhang Jun&#39;s incident can be used as the motto of today&#39;s translators. (ibid., pp. 146-147)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This note is related to the fact that &quot;after liberation&quot; the translation industry &quot;does not know what to do. Talking about &quot;eating alive&quot; is also a denial of &quot;literal translation&quot;. Regarding translation, what Qian Zhongshu pursues is the realm of &quot;translation&quot;, although &quot;thorough and complete &#39;translation&#39; is an unattainable ideal.&quot; Therefore, Qian Zhongshu pursues In the article, Zhongshu praised Xu Shen (Jianchang) as a &quot;true saint&quot; and said that he could predict that the translation would be &quot;囮&quot; (false) and that the translator (Tradutore) was a traitor (traditore). For details, see &quot;Lin Shu&#39;s Translation&quot; and There are several discussions in &quot;Guan Zhui Bian&quot;. The following part of this article is based on Gu Hongming&#39;s story of Xu reading a Western newspaper, and combined with Zhang Jun&#39;s view, he believes that &quot;all can be used as the motto of today&#39;s translators.&quot; It is humorous without losing irony, which is quite obvious. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s writing style is consistent. The most eye-catching part of the whole note is the note &quot;the ancestor of literal translation&quot; and so on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1920s and 1930s, Lin Yutang was trying to change the &quot;Chinese-style humor&quot; &quot;Joking attitude&quot; to reshape the virtues of gentlemen, so he advocated &quot;humorous literature&quot;. Unexpectedly, it backfired, as Qian Zhongshu criticized in his essay &quot;Joking&quot;: &quot;Since the promotion of humorous literature, joking has become a literati career. &quot;Lin Yutang helped the &quot;current ills&quot; by rescuing &quot;current ills.&quot; The actual effect of &quot;humorous literature&quot; ran counter to its original intention. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s &quot;Jokes&quot; was inspired by &quot;humorous literature.&quot; As for Lin Yutang&#39;s ideas, Lu Xun In &quot;One Thought and Action&quot;, he once criticized: &quot;Boom, there is no shortage of humor and sketches in the world. &quot; (&quot;The Complete Works of Lu Xun&quot;, Volume 5, page 473) also pointed out in &quot;Explanation of &quot;Funny&quot;&quot; that humorous literature just gives &quot;slick, frivolous and obscene&quot; the &quot;title of &#39;humor&#39;&quot; (&quot;The Complete Works of Lu Xun&quot;) &quot;Volume 5, page 342). Some people therefore believe that &quot;Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu really echo each other in their views on promoting humorous literature&quot; (Li Qinye, &quot;Reading &amp;lt;Writing on the Edge of Life&quot;), This statement is specious.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the history of modern literature, Lu Xun, Lin Yutang and Qian Zhongshu are all famous for their humor. Lu Xun&#39;s humor is like a dagger, with the edge of a scalpel to remove tumors, while Lin Yutang&#39;s humor is The breeze is like a purifier for the soul. At that time, Lin Yutang&#39;s humorous literature was naturally not as powerful as Lu Xun&#39;s essays, so it seemed out of date and was publicly criticized by Lu Xun. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s humor was like cold rain hitting his face, cold and thorny, like a pretender The embarrassment and uneasiness after his soul was exposed. However, although Qian Zhongshu also criticized Lin Yutang, if you compare his &quot;Laughing&quot; with Lin Yutang&#39;s &quot;On Humor&quot;, you will find how similar their views on humor are: Qian Zhongshu It is said that a person who is really humorous will have a &quot;knowing smile&quot; about humor. Lin Yutang said that a calm and distant bystander will give a &quot;knowing smile&quot; to humor; Qian Zhongshu said that humor is &quot;funny and wise&quot; , Lin Yutang said, &quot;wisdom has begun&quot; and &quot;there is humor&quot;; Qian Zhongshu said that humor is &quot;a breath of breath for the dull life&quot;, Lin Yutang said that humor is &quot;a part of life&quot;. Humor originates from wisdom, famous humorists It is not surprising that Qian Zhongshu and Lin Yutang have similar concepts but different expressions and effects. Because of this view of humor, Lin Yutang advocates humorous literature to cultivate the people&#39;s sense of humor and cultivate educated citizens, while Qian Zhongshu believes that true humor can &quot; &quot;Anti-bowing and laughing at oneself&quot; will become a laughing stock once advocated, so he said: &quot;Humor is at most a kind of temperament and can never be labeled as an idea, let alone a profession.&quot; ” It can be seen that although Qian Zhongshu and Lu Xun both criticized the “humorous literature” advocated by Lin Yutang, it cannot be said that their views on humor are of the same origin. On the contrary, Qian Zhongshu and Lin Yutang’s views on humor are “similar to each other.”&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As a witness and participant in the same literary and artistic trend, although Qian Zhongshu never had direct contact with Lu Xun, it even made people think that he sometimes deliberately &quot;looked sideways&quot; at Lu Xun, and followed the trend to find out the source. If we open the &quot;fog&quot;, we can still see their figures at the same time in major events in the history of modern literature, and then we can see Qian Zhongshu&#39;s consistent indifferent attitude towards Shi Xian, including Lu Xun, &quot;It&#39;s like seeing from flying sand, wheat waves, and ripples &quot;The posture of the wind&quot; (Qian Zhong&#39;s calligraphy). (The original title of this article was &quot;The posture of the wind&quot;, the current title was proposed by the editor)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“4.2千年事件”：地球大降温，华夏新生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257310]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the beginning of this century, with the advancement of molecular biology, we were able to explore the origin of rice through gene testing - detection The results show that cultivated rice was first domesticated in the Yangtze River Basin about 13,500 to 8.2 thousand years ago, and then spread to Southeast Asia and South Asia. After hybridizing with wild indica rice in South Asia, cultivated indica rice was produced and returned to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the process of studying the origin of rice, genetic testing has brought questions. Scholars suddenly discovered that there are many strange things about its spread time: after rice was domesticated, it stayed in China for thousands of years and did not spread outside. However, around 4.2 to 4,000 years ago, almost at the same time, rice suddenly appeared on the Japanese Islands, the Korean Peninsula, the Philippines, Indo-China Peninsula and the South Asian subcontinent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This makes people wonder: What happened more than four thousand years ago? ! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from ancient Chinese books, 4,000 years ago was around the time when the Xia Dynasty was established. It is said that after Emperor Yu controlled the floods, he sent envoys to measure &quot;the whole world&quot; and finally calculated that the distance from east to west and north to south of the earth was 233,500 miles and 75 steps. Although this is just a myth in the &quot;Book of Mountains and Seas&quot;, mythical stories often have prototypes: Maybe after Dayu established the Xia Dynasty, he sent envoys to explore the unknown world and spread rice to surrounding countries by the way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an archaeological perspective, the world between 4.2 and 4,000 years ago was suffering unprecedented disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you pay attention to Chinese archeology, you may have heard the saying &quot;a sky full of stars&quot;, which describes ancient civilizations before the Xia Dynasty: China between 5000 and 4300 years ago was full of archaeological sites. There are Hongshan in the western Liao River basin and Longshan in the Yellow River basin. These two are already city-state civilizations; in the Yangtze River basin there are Liangzhu and Shijiahe, both of which have entered dynastic politics. At that time, the earth was in the famous &quot;Holocene Warm Period&quot;. The humid and warm climate allowed civilizations all over the world to thrive. Even the deserts of Central Asia and the Sahara Desert of Africa were livable places with widespread forests and lakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by 4.2 to 4,000 years ago, the civilizations in the three major river basins all collapsed, and the entire land of China fell into chaos:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cities in Shijiahe and Liangzhu in the Yangtze River Basin collapsed one after another Destroyed and abandoned, the territory shrank sharply. By 3800 years ago, the original core area had almost become a no-man&#39;s land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many settlements in the Xiliao River Basin disappeared completely, and the population was directly replaced: genetic testing found that the Xiajiadian lower-class culture that later emerged in the local area had no genetic connection with the previous residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yellow River Basin is also full of victims: Archeology shows that the number of settlements in the middle and lower reaches of the Yellow River decreased by nearly 90% during this catastrophe, and the population may only be 1/10 of its original size. The exquisite and brilliant Longshan black pottery disappeared, and it was not until more than a hundred years later that a very rough gray pottery culture appeared - which means that the original civilization, the original knowledge and technology inheritance were also lost in this catastrophe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the origin of this catastrophe, the most common hypothesis is the Great Flood: Based on archaeological evidence, some scholars speculate that about 3920 years ago, a huge barrier lake formed in the upper reaches of the Yellow River, blocking the Yellow River. nearly 9 months. Afterwards, the barrier lake burst its banks, and about 16 billion cubic meters of lake water poured down instantly. The flood almost flattened the entire Yellow River Basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this hypothesis has some truth, it cannot explain the great collapse that also occurred in the Yangtze River Basin during the same period - in fact, not only the Yellow River and the Yangtze River, but also the whole world experienced a great collapse of civilization at that time. This was obviously a Climate disasters affecting the world:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The forests and Saharan lakes in Central Asia disappeared, and the great desert was born; in the Nile River Basin of North Africa, the early dynasty that had flourished for five hundred years came to an abrupt end, severe drought led to the collapse of agriculture, and Egypt fell into The century-long famine and civil strife is known to history as the &quot;First Intermediate Period&quot;; in the two river basins of West Asia, the Akkadian Empire completed its unification for the first time. A large amount of farmland was abandoned and was immediately attacked by foreign barbarians; in Central and Northern Europe, The cooling made the climate cold and humid, leading to the great migration of many ethnic groups...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This climate catastrophe is now called the &quot;4.2 Millennium Event&quot;, a catastrophe that can be called the end of civilization. . The superposition of turbulent ocean currents, super volcanic eruptions and El Niño may be the culprits of this natural disaster. The 4.2 millennium event manifested itself differently in different regions. Some places experienced severe droughts, while others experienced floods, but generally speaking, major cooling occurred. In fact, this event occurred from the end of the &quot;Younger Dryas Little Ice Age&quot; until the end of the Little Ice Age. Today, humanity has experienced the most severe cooling. The temperature in many places has never returned to the level of the Holocene Warm Period, and the good days of comfort and warmth are gone forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, it was the 4.2 Thousand Years Incident that exterminated the ancestors of the Western Liao River, severely damaged the ancient city-states of the Yellow River, and destroyed the two ancient dynasties in the Yangtze River Basin. Agriculture collapsed, famine was rampant, and mourning was widespread. In just a few decades or even a few years, 90% of the population has been lost. This is a doomsday scene that we today cannot imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The few survivors in South China, namely the ancient farmers of the Yangtze River and their descendants, had to take their rice seeds with them and flee in search of new land that could barely be cultivated. They crossed the sea to the east and reached the Korean Peninsula and Japan, becoming the ancestors of Koreans and Japanese immigrants; they reached the Philippines to the south and became the first stop for the Austronesian people to conquer the Pacific; they crossed the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau to the west and reached the Indochina Peninsula and India. , and the local hunter indigenous people, merged to form the Mon-Khmer language family (South Asian language family)...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, misfortunes and blessings depend on each other, and new life is also born in the doomsday disaster. After the catastrophe, China bid farewell to the &quot;starry sky&quot; and began to unite: the ancestors of South China (ancient farmers on the Yangtze River) who fled famine, and another group arrived in the northern Central Plains. Here they met the ancient farmers of the Yellow River who had also fled here. The two integrated and communicated to build a new home together - the north and south areas of Songshan Mountain where Erlitou in Henan is located were not prominent during the Holocene Warm Period, with only some scattered small settlements. However, hundreds of years after the Great Collapse, probably ancestors who had fled from various places gathered here, and the place rapidly revived and grew. About 3,800 years ago, Erlitou had developed into the largest settlement in the entire Yellow River Basin and became the undisputed master of the Central Plains. It immediately began to expand aggressively, and soon became an unrivaled and powerful dynasty in the entire East Asia - many scholars believe that it is the Xia Dynasty in ancient books, and the era of unification of China has arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>