<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中央气象台发布寒潮、暴雪、大风、强对流四预警]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 16:00:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 06:00 on November 5, the Central Meteorological Observatory issued four major warnings: cold wave, blizzard, strong wind, and strong convection! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue a cold wave blue warning at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by strong cold air, it is expected that at 08:00 on November 5 As of 20:00 on the 7th, the temperature in the eastern part of northwest China and most parts of central and eastern China will drop by 6 to 10 degrees Celsius. Among them, the temperature in central and eastern Inner Mongolia, the central and southern parts of Northeast China, and the central and eastern Jianghuai areas will drop by 12 to 14 degrees Celsius. ℃, the local cooling in southeastern Inner Mongolia, southwestern and eastern Jilin, central and northern Liaoning, and central and northern Jiangsu can reach more than 16℃; the lowest temperature occurred on the morning of the 7th, and the lowest temperature line of 0℃ will be located in northern Hebei and southern Beijing , southern Shanxi to the Guanzhong Plain of Shaanxi, southeastern Gansu, and most areas along the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River, the minimum temperature will drop to about 10°C. Areas north of the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River have northerly winds of magnitude 4 to 6, with gusts of magnitude 7 to 9, and locally up to magnitude 10; from the 5th to 6th, there are winds of magnitude 6 to 8 in the Bohai Sea, Yellow Sea, East China Sea and other sea areas, with the maximum gusts Level 9~10. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/88625308e4012be7a20db624fafd7401.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/88625308e4012be7a20db624fafd7401.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257118&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/abe6c2d110d5768a275edc42e989ecd7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/abe6c2d110d5768a275edc42e989ecd7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue an orange warning for heavy snowfall at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected that from 08:00 on November 5 to 08:00 on the 7th, the central and eastern parts of Inner Mongolia and the northeastern region will There were heavy to heavy snowfalls from west to east in the central and western regions and northern parts of the country. Some areas had heavy snowstorms, and local heavy snowstorms (30 to 38 mm). The new snow depth was 10 to 20 cm, and locally it could reach more than 25 cm. The main snowfall period is from the night of the 5th to the 6th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 08:00 on November 5 to 08:00 on November 6, there were heavy snowfalls in parts of central and eastern Inner Mongolia, northern Hebei, northwest Liaoning, and southeastern Heilongjiang. Among them, southeastern Inner Mongolia and southeastern Heilongjiang There were heavy local heavy snowfalls (20-22 mm) in parts of the country. The new snow depth in some of the above-mentioned areas is 5 to 10 centimeters, and it can reach more than 15 centimeters in some places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f3f35e9297889d60a2245f55010652bb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f3f35e9297889d60a2245f55010652bb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257117&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;From 08:00 on November 6 to 08:00 on November 7, there were heavy snowfalls in parts of southeastern Inner Mongolia, central and eastern Heilongjiang, central and western Jilin, and central and northern Liaoning, including southern and eastern Heilongjiang, Jilin, and other places. Local heavy snowfall (30-38 mm) occurred in northern and other places; there was local freezing rain in central and western Jilin, southern Heilongjiang and other places. The new snow depth in the above-mentioned areas is 10 to 20 centimeters, and it can reach more than 25 centimeters in some places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/38fdf7821954eb60b71e596258dbcc96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/38fdf7821954eb60b71e596258dbcc96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257120&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue a blue warning for strong winds at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected that from 08:00 on November 5 to 08:00 on the 6th, central Xinjiang Northern, central and southern Inner Mongolia and southeastern Inner Mongolia, eastern Qinghai, central Gansu, Ningxia, northern Shaanxi, Shanxi, central and western Hebei, Beijing, eastern Tianjin, northern Henan, eastern Shandong, western Liaoning, western Jilin, southern Heilongjiang, southeastern Hubei, There will be strong winds of magnitude 5 to 6 and gusts of magnitude 7 to 9 in northern Hunan and northern Jiangxi; there will be strong winds of magnitude 7 to 8 and gusts of magnitude 9 in the Bohai Sea, Bohai Strait, most of the Yellow Sea, and the northern waters of the East China Sea. Winds in parts of the Taiwan Strait and the northern and central parts of the Yellow Sea can reach level 9, with gusts of level 10 to 11. &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f4ef68884d0e0f3ed9c77ff1ed58606b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;899&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f4ef68884d0e0f3ed9c77ff1ed58606b.jpeg&quot; data-key =&quot;257116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From 08:00 on November 6 to 08:00 on November 7&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bohai Sea, Bohai Strait, and most of the Yellow Sea , the northern waters of the East China Sea, the Taiwan Strait, the Bashi Strait, the ocean east of Taiwan, and the northeastern waters of the South China Sea will have strong winds of magnitude 7 to 8 and gusts of magnitude 9 to 10. The wind force in some areas of the Bohai Strait, northern and central Yellow Sea can reach 9 Level, gust level 10~11&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;; northern and southern Xinjiang, northern Tibet, central Qinghai, western Gansu, most of Inner Mongolia, most of Heilongjiang, central and western Jilin, northwestern and southern Liaoning, and most of Hebei , central Beijing, eastern Tianjin, central and eastern Shandong&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and other places will have strong winds of magnitude 5 to 6 and gusts of magnitude 7 to 8&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/bd34849b91a8251e27248cfe28554b7e.jpeg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;899&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/bd34849b91a8251e27248cfe28554b7e.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;257119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue blue warnings for severe convective weather at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected to be in November From 08:00 on the 5th to 08:00 on the 6th, some areas in southern Anhui, central and northern Jiangxi, central and southern Hunan, southern Guizhou, and central and northern Guangxi will have thunderstorms or hail of magnitude 8-10; central and southern Anhui, central Jiangsu There will be short-term heavy rainfall in some areas of , western Zhejiang, central and northern Jiangxi, eastern Hubei, most of Hunan, southern Guizhou, most of Guangxi, Hainan Island and other places. The maximum hourly rainfall is 30-40 mm, and locally it can reach 50 mm or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected that the main impact period of strong convection will be from today to night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7209dba773e72e2e468f88cb09cb407d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7209dba773e72e2e468f88cb09cb407d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257121&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/cda050a7d669ad6d47ed62dd383dbe2b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/cda050a7d669ad6d47ed62dd383dbe2b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a >;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[9.4分科幻动画，每一帧都脑洞大开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259987]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;According to &quot;The Analysis of Dreams&quot;, people Can&#39;t imagine something I haven&#39;t seen before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But a recent American TV series has done it - &quot;Reign of the Scavengers&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Reign&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This science fiction drama is produced by HBO Max, and its Douban score is stable at 9.4 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/b57b65c9292582aa7c369266dea59443.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;770&quot; height= &quot;345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/b57b65c9292582aa7c369266dea59443.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257046&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other science fiction The works are all trying to explain something clearly, or making it unclear to make the audience feel mysterious, but &quot;Dominion&quot; focuses on one thing: don&#39;t talk, feel first. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;01&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dominion&quot; is adapted from the 2016 animated short &quot;Scavengers&quot; produced by Joe Bennett and Charles Huttner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This work has no dialogue throughout, and the storyline is almost non-existent: a spaceship breaks down and loses contact, and a pair of male and female scientists on board become the only survivors. Thus, the two people began a wonderful life on the alien planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8dccca93ed7fb627b2a1c40f6edc4470.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8dccca93ed7fb627b2a1c40f6edc4470.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257045&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s like The alien version of &quot;Pulse of the Earth&quot; leads humans to experience a gorgeous adventure of imagination in a spectacular way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, bugs that can be used as telescopes and gas masks;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04 /44B1E5F9EA121695CB5143575CD8414e.gif &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 351 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/Mes/image/23/11/000 4/44B1E5F9EA121695CB5143575CD8414e.gif &quot;Data -key=&quot;257048&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a flying fish that can be used as a bamboo dragonfly when put into a backpack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ef766eab154b4836f62f19add198ad01.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ef766eab154b4836f62f19add198ad01.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257054&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this planet The creatures are beautiful, weird and absurd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The drama series &quot;Dominion&quot; is an all-round expansion and extension of the short film &quot;Scavengers&quot;, developing the line of the spacecraft malfunctioning on the alien planet into three lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first line is the story of Sam and Ursula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of these two people, one is a classic white man and the other is an independent and strong woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/20d5feb2ff1476c25bd7a4129185e6c7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/20d5feb2ff1476c25bd7a4129185e6c7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257049&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two persons The creatures on this planet already have a certain level of understanding, and they can skillfully transform bugs into gas masks, and capture creatures to use as aircraft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process, we see that they still have a tendency to use living things as tools, but at the same time they have to be cautious, after all, they are surrounded by unknowns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6d849233303ff2b4acbb53a46aa9caa3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6d849233303ff2b4acbb53a46aa9caa3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257047&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 2 Thread is the story of a black girl, Archie, and an artificial intelligence, Levi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a robot, Levi originally simply received orders and performed tasks. But because a certain yellow creature on the planet gradually grew with its body, Levi seemed to have a will. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6965c165b005531d005ae4726ef3e578.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6965c165b005531d005ae4726ef3e578.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257052&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It will be in As you explore this planet at night, you will feel pain and begin to understand the lives of other creatures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/f6c628593669107293700d1de472e106.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/f6c628593669107293700d1de472e106.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 3 The thread is the story of Carmen, the unshaven uncle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carmen can hold up the entire line by himself because he has a connection with Blackie, a strange creature on the planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/9dc2d966dc300e71edecb4ac53cd7b3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/9dc2d966dc300e71edecb4ac53cd7b3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The card door is small Black hunts, and Black feeds Carmen by creating hallucinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carmen&#39;s wife died when the spacecraft landed, so he suffered from severe depression. Xiao Hei took advantage of Carmen&#39;s longing for his wife and mentally controlled Carmen, making her think that their symbiotic relationship was a normal couple&#39;s relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/01aaa88d5e918344d93bd783c8fd01da.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/01aaa88d5e918344d93bd783c8fd01da.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257056&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three lines The characters have a common purpose, which is to repair the damaged spacecraft and return to Earth. But those wonderful alien creatures brought them unspeakable shock. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;02&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The painting style of &quot;Dominion&quot; is weird and imaginative, and it seems to have an ethereal and lonely beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, plants that can turn corpses into landscapes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/1686a60eb1ef7a48d7c15d40f25df8c2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/1686a60eb1ef7a48d7c15d40f25df8c2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257053&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, mayfly A villain who lives and dies every day, from birth to death in just a short moment, just to bury new seeds, and then use his body as nourishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c547df2d44e986f19dc27b072d96085b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c547df2d44e986f19dc27b072d96085b.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, as White creatures that are as invisible as chameleons and moths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/67d599567acd1ca33dd38cf46e94da04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/67d599567acd1ca33dd38cf46e94da04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257055&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And those The densely packed and sturdy plants can be opened by a bird feather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/a8ba59b21e59bbffcefd44ab9b80a13d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/a8ba59b21e59bbffcefd44ab9b80a13d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257059&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flying The beasts are not running aimlessly, but have the same breathing and rhythm, so the seemingly bulky creatures instantly become extremely light and beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is difficult to say that there is any plot in this animation. The story here is secondary and the creature itself is the main thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plants and animals here have their own beauty and uniqueness. They share the ecosystem of the entire planet, are related to each other, and live in harmony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3aae2a2baad9b976b4cce35884b4e15e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3aae2a2baad9b976b4cce35884b4e15e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;03&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the animation, when the spacecraft lost contact, someone reported the situation to the relevant person in charge. The person in charge understands that the top management will not spend manpower and material resources to find a spaceship. Therefore, we can only pray that no one survives, &quot;otherwise they will live an even worse life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/25e1e044b37f0cdf7867e78abcc039ff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/25e1e044b37f0cdf7867e78abcc039ff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257058&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8654cdf95383461e160dfc912ad190a3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8654cdf95383461e160dfc912ad190a3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257057&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the tone that &quot;Reign&quot; wants to deny, life is like Grass mustard. The entire three lines actually emphasize that life itself is full of meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first line, the white uncle Sam has a nakedly hostile, repulsive and exploitative attitude toward alien creatures. He cannot accept unknown creatures and always looks at other creatures from a superior perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ursula was shocked by the beauty of the living and dying plant villain, Sam was very angry, feeling that Ursula had deviated from the mission and was irrational. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/dfee3c0c682bd74543d15335b9c3bf68.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/dfee3c0c682bd74543d15335b9c3bf68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in this On the planet, Sam seemed out of place. Ursula, on the other hand, seems to be gradually mastering the rhythm of the planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She put aside her own prejudices and tried to let perception take precedence, getting to know the planet step by step and discovering its beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for Archie in the second line. At first, she had no feelings for Levi, only command and control. But gradually, she realized the changes in Levi, and felt the pulse of the planet through Levi&#39;s guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, artificial intelligence has actually completed the connection with living things earlier than humans, thus guiding humans to return to a state of childlike curiosity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c6c5af4e6002655305e8d88c27af2919.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c6c5af4e6002655305e8d88c27af2919.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 3 The Carmen in this line is different from the first two lines. He reaches a connection with the alien creature Xiao Hei in a way that loses his humanity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Carmen&#39;s use of tools as a human made Xiao Hei quickly become the king of the species. On the other hand, Carmen&#39;s obsession with illusions makes Xiao Hei lose the ability to distinguish the truth in the process of using tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e3f3cac002d9d9fc55b4940a90d67aa0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e3f3cac002d9d9fc55b4940a90d67aa0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, Man has become a captive and a tool, in a lower position, while the little black who enslaved him has reached the top of the food chain. But on the other hand, perhaps in the eyes of other creatures, human beings are like that scary fat little black insect, with endless greed and desire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d9cfcf79dc8b1b7d90b4dc9fb25431b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d9cfcf79dc8b1b7d90b4dc9fb25431b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This drama Although it is a science fiction work, it uses the method of weakening the plot and enlarging the picture to break the anthropocentric thinking path, trying to bring the audience into an almost wild and equal environment, and use imagination to awaken human beings to The awe of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, the power of technology is hidden, but a kind of primitive vitality is filled with it. Here, no creature is superior to other creatures, and there is no large-scale plundering or killing. Everything is slow and orderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, don’t talk, don’t think, feel first, is the most correct way to open this animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[周涛　宿命狷狂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/05/98756b2c861e592ad4dfd9368f93a90b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/98756b2c861e592ad4dfd9368f93a90 b. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257100&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Zhou Tao&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Picture/Liu Xin&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Whether it is in the oral autobiography &quot;A Man and Xinjiang&quot; or the novel &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, Zhou Tao regarded himself as a specimen in that period of history. His unscrupulous self-exposure is due to his background in military life and his arrogant nature, just like his unbridled poetry and prose. At the same time, it also presents the true ecology of this special group of cadres&#39; children in the long river of history. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border -box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The beginning of chaos&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Kashgar in early October , next to Ustang Boyi Road, a thousand-year-old street in Id Kah, musical instrument shops and carpet shops selling hot wapu and tambourines are lined up, and the craftsmen making copper pots are clanging and banging, surrounded by black The vat where the stove is brewing&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sheep&lt;/span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The meat is sizzling. With the heat, the fragrance spreads far and wide. The tourists who flock here will definitely not let go of these antiques. They either raise their mobile phones to take pictures, or they want to eat two vats of meat, fresh and hot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Forty-six years ago, Zhou Tao, a college student in Xinjiang, never imagined that a place he thought was a &quot;purgatory&quot; would now become a place of fascination and curiosity for inland tourists. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;When I heard that I was assigned here, my legs were weak. It&#39;s over, I collapsed.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Before decentralization Although he had experienced the &quot;baptism&quot; of starving and carrying food on the Yili farm in the past 26 years, he always regarded himself as a son of cadres and his life was definitely going up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This earth-yellow town completely buried his blueprint with its loneliness and indifference. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The crowded Uyghur residential areas are all built with adobe and wood... The houses are like beehives, the roads are like spider webs, and the civil buildings are all yellow. You clearly walked in, but there were very few people around, you couldn&#39;t hear anyone&#39;s voice, and the doors facing the street were all closed, as if you had walked into an empty and silent mountain forest alone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It&#39;s like this every day. Ji Shuteng rides a bicycle from here to work at the prefectural committee and goes out under the city wall. From the gate of Daluo Dam, ride through the narrow dirt road on the side of the dam, pass through the road next to Abdul Kerim Street, then pass through the clanking streets of Ustangbuyi Street, and come to the cement-paved main street. On the spacious road, the car went straight down and arrived at the prefectural committee compound where he worked. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——&quot;Journey to the West&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;In the spring of 2018, 72-year-old Zhou Tao finally completed the autobiographical novel &quot;Journey to the West&quot; in his attic. He originally named it &quot;The Beginning of Chaos&quot; to refer to the confusion of young people during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; who could not see the way forward. One day before the publication of &quot;Contemporary&quot;, he suddenly realized that when he and his companions were sent to a remote place, they were on the way to the west: and &quot;the west is the place where the sun sets, the place where snow accumulates, and the way to the west.&quot; It is a road with dusk clouds hanging low like a curtain, and people&#39;s hearts are always curled up in their chests. No one knows what void they will step on next. Maybe, if you are not careful, you will fall from the edge of the earth.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/e041c1723aae44d699deeaaa33e04203.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 863&quot; height=&quot;1265&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/e041c1723aae44d699deeaaa33e04203.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257101&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the book, he wrote about the career of Qu Ming, a &quot;revolutionary scholar&quot; who had ideals before and led the city later. Cheng Zhimin, the &quot;perfect political loach&quot;, and decent Uyghur cadres like Simayi Ahematijiang have described the origins of power factions and the law of the jungle in Kashgar, a border area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The main character in the book, Ji Shuteng, is handsome, has poetry and books in his belly, is arrogant, conforms to the customs at heart, is strong on the outside but is incapable of fighting the outside world politically. His ability, eyesight and life are all dependent on his wife. It is difficult for readers who know a little about the author to think: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Is this Zhou Tao himself? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Literary critic and editor-in-chief of &quot;People&#39;s Liberation Army Literature and Art&quot; Yin Shi saw the manuscript for the first time and was shocked. It was so direct! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“There was a lot of scar literature in the 1980s that exposed the problems of the era. Most of them were complaints from victims. When writing about a character or event, there seemed to be hidden dissatisfaction and slightness. The protest carries a very subtle criticism, but it is not clear and does not describe specific political life, political tasks, or political beliefs. When writing about the so-called villain, do not go deep into his heart. It&#39;s just a symbol.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Yin Shi pointed out that in &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, Qu Ming, who went to Yan&#39;an to study Lu Yi as a teenager and received a red education, was in the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; During this period, he became a speculator and the strategist behind Cheng Qiang, hoping for the success of another &quot;revolution&quot; and a new distribution of interests. This was the main reason why Ji Shuteng gradually got rid of Qu Ming&#39;s influence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao also wrote about the inner thoughts of Cheng Qiang, a &quot;rebel&quot; from a peasant background, his judgment of the political trends at the top, and his heroic and loyal to his inner beliefs. Method of suicide. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ji Shuteng didn’t like Cheng Qiang, but when Cheng Qiang became a prisoner, he was not happy at all. Cheng Qiang almost committed suicide by jumping off a cliff, which made him even more upset. He was shocked. &quot;He can&#39;t see others in trouble, just like he can&#39;t tolerate anyone being domineering... He loves freedom and advocates equality. Ji Shuteng also gradually sees another side of his nature. One person or some people bully or insult another person or some people, and This is not an ordinary thing, this is the kind of very horrific behavior; once this kind of thing begins, persecution, abuse, killing and destruction will follow.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; During their eight years in Kashgar, Qu Ming and Cheng Qiang shaped Ji Shuteng in his conduct as a person, and he was eventually surpassed by him. However, Ji Shuteng did not escape the more terrifying mental terror and spiritual torture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ji Shuteng was reported because he expressed his inner thoughts about his leader in a casual chat. Ji Shuteng started to write a review, and he immediately felt like a deflated rubber ball. He wrote in the examination that he must be &quot;reborn&quot; and so on, but he didn&#39;t want to actually shed his skin like a snake. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t hurt, it doesn&#39;t hurt at all, just feel free to peel it off, it&#39;ll be fine!&quot; ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(wife) Zhuang Yan took off a piece and put it aside for him to see. He took off another large piece, &quot;Oh, it&#39;s such a big piece!&quot; He turned his face and saw that it was as big as half a tabloid. It was a piece of white paper with a tough texture. He said, &quot;Don&#39;t throw it away. It&#39;s better to put it in the paper.&quot; It says inspection directly on it. Human skin inspection is more profound than what’s on the manuscript paper!”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;—— &quot;Journey to the West&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to meet the distortion of history, people can even dehumanize themselves and cater to the atrocities of natural forces. Yin Shi believes that despite flaws in writing techniques and character creation, &quot;Journey to the West&quot; has the value of a &quot;scientific investigation report on human nature&quot; by unabashedly revealing the inner thoughts and showing the ups and downs and thoughts of cadres&#39; children. &quot;For a quasi-second-generation official like Zhou Tao, spiritual autobiography and documentary value are the first step, and self-examination is a further requirement.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7dc37dba640ff1da5d7f0082e3868018.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;564&quot; height=&quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7dc37dba640ff1da5d7f0082e3868018.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257105&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;If you combine &quot;Journey to the West&quot; with Zhou Tao&#39;s autobiographical oral record &quot;A Man and Xinjiang&quot; published a few years ago, you can better understand the extent of this &quot;self-exposure&quot;. Among the latter, he spoke freely, peeling away the ridiculousness and patheticness of his father and family, as well as his own embarrassment, ugliness, and the dark side of human nature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such an individual is undoubtedly far removed from the traditional Chinese gentleman and Confucian scholar. It seemed that he was determined to tear off those masks that he had to keep and care about before he reached his seventies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f37d4fae1864a9506df6526b7ff2e059.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 734&quot; height=&quot;984&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f37d4fae1864a9506df6526b7ff2e059.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257104&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The descendants of cadres in Xinjiang in the 1960s, the one from the right in the front row Zhou Tao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;A deep sense of superiority&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In After eight years in the ancient city of Kashgar, Zhou Tao finally had the opportunity to go to the Urumqi Military Region to engage in literary creation. After the troubled times, God gave him the most suitable arrangement for him who was both civil and military. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The rest of his life seems to prove that he has been on a smooth road since then. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao who left Kashgar, like Ji Shuteng in &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, had no nostalgia for the yellow land where he had lived for a long time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Why are you so unsympathetic? The answer is: This is not my place in the first place.&quot; He believes that wherever a person grows up before the age of 18, that place will become His eternal home. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Before the age of 9, Zhou Tao lived in Beijing. Before receiving re-education in Yili and being transferred to Kashgar, he lived with his parents in Urumqi - clearly &quot;higher&quot; than southern Xinjiang in his eyes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The sense of superiority is innate. The first is appearance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He has been born with white skin and big eyes since he was a child. Among the dolls with foreign children, he is also the most eye-catching one. The whole Zhou family has fair skin. He once asked his aunt, what is grandpa like? My aunt said, &quot;Your grandfather can&#39;t be compared to any of you. He&#39;s so handsome.&quot; Zhou Tao felt that his family&#39;s bloodline should be mixed, because his hometown in Yushe, Shanxi, is a mixed race area, &quot;where the Xiongnu, Qiang, and Jiedi gather.&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Xiao Qiao, a military writer who is nearly 10 years younger than him, said that Zhou Tao was born with a &quot;face and figure that make people doubt God&#39;s favoritism. Coupled with his humor, cunning, quick reactions and sharp words, This kind of person can easily make people jealous and at the same time create a desire for friendship.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Beyond the skin, family background is the foundation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao’s father, Zhou Wenjie, participated in the Shanxi Anti-Japanese Youth Death Team in his early years&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;The non-party groups at that time were actually anti-Japanese groups led by the Communist Party. They later became regular troops&lt;/span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, engaged in mass work, served as cultural teachers, and later became Chen Geng&#39;s subordinates. During the founding ceremony of the People&#39;s Republic of China, Zhou Wenjie, a battalion-level cadre, stood in the first row below the Tiananmen Gate. Later, he was admitted to the army as a diplomat and was assigned to the School of Foreign Languages. Before the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, he was a cadre at the fourteenth level. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao’s primary school classmates include many children of senior cadres. A sense of superiority was invisibly injected into Zhou Tao&#39;s mind during his childhood. He remembered that when his younger brother was born, the hospital made egg fried rice for his mother at noon. She refused to eat it and gave it to 4-year-old Zhou Tao. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the age of 4, Zhou Tao was standing on a hillside in Haidian District, just in time for work in the morning. He felt like a general. &quot;Looking at the gray, blue and black crowds of people under my feet, I suddenly felt a sense of superiority in my heart.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao will remember this idea throughout his life. Strange: &quot;How could such an idea come to mind at such a young age?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;That idea was the bud from the foundation of his thoughts throughout his life. The buds grow and are associated with him throughout his life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;His classmate Zhao Nan once saw a beggar on the street and said, what if we end up in this situation one day? Zhou Tao replied: &quot;Even if we are reduced to this point, others will look different when we stand.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Many revolutionary children have that sense of superiority. In fact, compared to this Judging from decades of history, it is very superficial. The concept of &#39;the world&#39; is also very decadent.&quot; Yin Shi said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao was not aware of it. He wrote about the pride and stubbornness of Ji Shuteng&#39;s class in &quot;Journey to the West&quot;:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; There is a little guy who is only in the third grade of elementary school and can memorize the names, positions, and military ranks of dozens of marshals, ten generals, and more than sixty generals. The man was surprised and asked: &quot;Then what kind of general can you be when you grow up?&quot; The answer was: &quot;At least a general.&quot; When he grew up to sixteen or seventeen years old, he became more and more handsome, talented in sports and arts, just like the revolutionary career of his father&#39;s generation. There really is some kind of blood inheritance. But after entering society, most of them cannot adapt. ...As for the spiritual legacy of the Chinese revolution: the pursuit of social equality and the new culture of advocating altruism, they have completely disappeared. There is no doubt that Ji Shuteng himself is one of these people. He knows very well that he was &quot;fed by strictly selected food.&quot; He is also convinced: &quot;This is exactly how our generation is full of ambitions.&quot; Faith grows like a stone, water cannot be poured into it, needles cannot penetrate it, and it is difficult for anything else to penetrate into our minds.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Among such a group of stubborn leaders with high vision, Zhou Tao&#39;s unruly attitude is even more prominent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As evidenced by his father’s memories: “When Tao was fourteen or fifteen years old, he loved horseback riding and bicycle riding. Once, he went to Nanshan with a party school cadre and rode a Kazakh horse alone. The horse galloped on the mountain road, and the witnesses were horrified. The leader yelled and cursed before stopping.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He has good physical fitness and once won the Xinjiang college men&#39;s table tennis singles championship. . But when I was in junior high school, I went to Beijing for a year of training, and I didn’t want to do it anymore. I deliberately trampled the ball and threw the racket on the wall. &quot;I felt particularly awkward after the head coach asked me to change the crossboard, because my personality is offensive rather than defensive. If I was asked to play defense, I wouldn&#39;t want to. If I didn&#39;t want to, I would destroy it and quit.&quot;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although he is unrestrained and youthful, he also has a way of assessing the situation that is different from his peers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the age of fourteen or fifteen, he already understood that playing table tennis would not accomplish anything. It&#39;s not about physical condition or mind, it&#39;s about starting too late. &quot;If I were to be in Beijing, I would definitely join the national team. The conditions are sufficient.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is another thing that he doesn&#39;t mind. Wu Guomei, a middle school Chinese teacher, gave Zhou Tao a score of 95 for his composition and gave him great encouragement. Other students regarded note-taking as a chore, but he was the only one who found joy in taking notes. &quot;Why did I win as soon as I wrote prose? Because I had written it a long time ago, and the ten notebooks are prose.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Literature is talent, and it is also Zhou Tao&#39;s upward path. The clearest one. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/73a2271d659b7a2e6a6d7fc959a3ccde.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;869&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/73a2271d659b7a2e6a6d7fc959a3ccde.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257103&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In 1965, Zhou Tao won the Xinjiang college student table tennis singles championship&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border- box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;An Inhuman Year&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《Twenty &quot;Four Ploughshares&quot; was often requested by Zhou Tao to be placed at the top of his collection of essays, which shows that he attached great importance to this article. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;That came from the year he received re-education at Yili 9901 Farm. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When we went there, everyone sat in a big sedan and sang along the way, such as &quot;Prairie Pastoral&quot; and &quot;Red Plum Blossoms on the Red Rocks&quot;. There was constant laughter and laughter, and everyone was full of joy. The feeling of starting a new life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When I got there, I found that I had become a &quot;prisoner&quot; overnight: I was not allowed to leave the company for 25 meters, I had to report when I went out, and strict military management was implemented every day. &quot;The grain puller saw it and said, &#39;How do you look like college students? What&#39;s the difference between you and labor reform prisoners? There are no distinctions between men and women, and all of them are in tatters. The horse pens are covered with straw, and rats are running overhead in the middle of the night, killing some people. My ear was bitten off.&quot; The arrogant and ruthless instructor refused to allow the sick students to see a doctor. Zhou Tao said that his biggest wish at that time was to &quot;capture the instructor and throw him into the Gongnaisi River.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How far have we cultivated the grassland? (Gestures with hands) This is a yurt. The area around the yurt is all plowed, and the cultivated land is only five meters away from the yurt. &quot;The white yurt has become an isolated island among the cultivated land.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The yurt in the yurt The dog barked, and an old woman came out. Without saying a word, she looked at our tractor coldly, &quot;That&#39;s not anger, that&#39;s contempt.&quot; That look condensed the coldness of more than seventy winters, and it made our souls look... broken into pieces.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now you see that my belly is big enough. At that time, my belly was like The huge hole dug by the excavator was completely sunken. I lost weight to 64 kilograms, and the bones on my face were all exposed. There are two bags of wheat weighing more than 80 kilograms. Two people hold the corners of the bag and lift it. You can dig it down and put it on your back. What did I do then? After I picked up the two bags by myself, I put them directly on my shoulders. I was so skinny but so strong (laughing). There are not many people who can do this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a triangular roof on the granary. A steel bar needs to be driven down from the top, and screws are required on both sides. fixed. There was a bold man who was swinging a hammer from above, and I was supporting him from below. Once, he almost hit his head with the hammer. Another time I jumped out of the air and grabbed the rope. As a result, after I grabbed it, the rope was coiled and there was a long section of it that was not tied. If there was no tie at the other end, I would have to die, or I would be disabled if I didn&#39;t die. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At an age when hormones are overwhelming, I suddenly fell from the sky into a mud pit. He began to wonder about the relationship between origin and destiny. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;There is not much difference between people. Unless they are particularly stupid or particularly smart, most people are the same. The differences between people are caused by society. . I had a saying at that time - if we are equal, do you dare? If we are on the same starting line, who are we afraid of? But at that time, you were suppressed everywhere, hit walls everywhere, and nothing could be accomplished.&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This kind of thinking and playing will accompany you throughout your life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/a9168589bca8721555e60a9bdea74826.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 984&quot; height=&quot;650&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/a9168589bca8721555e60a9bdea74826.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257102&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In the mid-1980s, three generations of Zhou Tao’s family took a group photo, front row The one holding the child on the left is Zhou Tao, the fourth from the left in the front row is Ma Wen, and besides the old man are Zhou Tao’s three younger brothers, his sister-in-law and their children&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border -box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px &quot;>;&lt;strong>;The father who &quot;sits on the slide&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao has always lamented that the 10 years between Yili and Kashgar were the most decadent years of his life. Looking back nearly fifty years later, he still laughs at his father&#39;s &quot;confusion&quot; and doesn&#39;t quite understand it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1941 and 1942, my father got sick and became a patient in the garrison hospital. Japanese prisoners. He was hung up and tortured, but his identity as a soldier was never revealed. There was a traitor who came in first. He wrote a note to the traitor at that time, saying that you are also Chinese and we are all Chinese. My father meant for him to help. During the Cultural Revolution, he was labeled a traitor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;My father’s thinking style belongs to a small landowner family, and is a bit idealistic, far away from reality. It’s too far away, so I’m not very good at dealing with people, I’m enthusiastic about everyone, and I don’t adapt to Chinese culture. When Marvin came to our house and had a little contact, she said, &quot;Why does your dad think like a foreigner?&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He is a very kind and honest person, but he is not a person with strong social ability. He has gone downhill in his life and is a slider. It&#39;s not that he doesn&#39;t want to follow, he wants to follow so much, but he can&#39;t. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1970, Zhou Wenjie, who had been expelled from the party, was sent to work as a farmer in the National Day Commune of Jimusar County, Changji. His mother also followed his father to the countryside. Two years later, the eldest son, Zhou Tao, completed his re-education at the Yili Farm and was assigned to Kashgar. He first took his wife to Jimsar to visit his family. His famous prose piece &quot;Chronicles of Jimusar&quot; was written about that experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d5fb99b945f2f7fbfac26d3fa269ca63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 335&quot; height=&quot;505&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d5fb99b945f2f7fbfac26d3fa269ca63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257107&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the entrance of the village, Zhou Tao took a cigarette and took a break, planning to ask for directions later. An old man wearing a black cotton-padded jacket walked around him holding a dung basket. Zhou Tao wondered what he was looking at and still smiled. Take a closer look, isn&#39;t this my dad? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The old man has completely become a rural old man. One is to dress in a rural style. One is the ruralization of his mental state, completely transforming him into a farmer. My mother stood waiting at the door. She looked very pitiful, her hair was gray and blown by the wind. My hair was not white when I went there, and I was already very old in my fifties. They feel that there is no possibility of coming back, and they will be like this for the rest of their lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;......&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking at the man carrying the basket in front of me, I remembered that when I was a boy, I had a fierce fight with a group of urchins in the courtyard of the institution, dancing with guns and sticks, and suddenly appeared in front of the building angrily. He calls me a &quot;mad dog&quot;; he thinks of forcing me to help him wash the endless laundry of the whole family on Sunday. The water is biting and his hands are red from the cold, but he will not give up until he rinses away the last bit of soap suds; he also thinks of the man who used to wear a military officer&#39;s uniform. People who wore uniforms, then Chinese tunic suits, cadre uniforms, and finally put on peasant black cotton-padded jackets; and thought of my father who was once graceful, then solemn, and finally became old and confused and became what he is now. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In prose, he blamed himself for always underestimating his father because of his failures in reality, ignoring his essential qualities as a person. of excellent quality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Paradoxically, from the way he speaks to the way he walks, from his body shape and facial features, to his habits and soul, no matter whether the social environment is favorable or unfavorable, he can never get rid of the influence his father injects into him. the genetics in one’s own body. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Later he realized that if his father did not suddenly appear, he would probably continue along the life trajectory of a Wuling prince, until one day he suddenly discovered I have been left far behind by the changes in society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The temperament has also been restrained. &quot;After his misfortune, I kept a low profile. I had a ghost and a weakness in my heart. I was much more honest and didn&#39;t dare to make it public anymore.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In that era, literature was a hobby and a Find a way out for yourself and your family. Marriage is different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;My wife Ma Wen’s father was the political commissar and major general of the Southern Xinjiang Military Region at the time. In &quot;A Man and Xinjiang&quot;, Zhou Tao admitted that his marriage was an obvious act of opportunism. For this reason, he abandoned his then lover and felt &quot;feeling guilty for the rest of his life.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ma Wen’s family originally did not agree to accept Zhou Tao, who was down and out at the time, but Ma Wen was devoted to being friendly with Zhou Tao and made it clear to his father, “It’s okay if you don’t let me be friendly with him. I listen to you, but I will never get married.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Less than ten days after the wedding, Zhou Tao and Ma Wen went to Yili Farm together. Looking back, half a century has passed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/fcbe7b129290d54f13e3d7743edf0137.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 984&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/fcbe7b129290d54f13e3d7743edf0137.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257106&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao and his wife&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Picture/Liu Xin&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Marvin in front of me has fair skin and speaks clearly and forcefully. Five or six years ago, Marvin had eye surgery and his vision was almost zero. He usually wears sunglasses at home. Whether communicating with Zhou Tao or outsiders, he has his own aura. Zhou Tao injured his ear when he was shot when he was young. Now he needs to wear a hearing aid to talk to people. The backbone of the family can be seen at a glance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sitting in the bright courtyard of the Urumqi Army Community, Zhou Tao cherishes his wife&#39;s kindness. &quot;She may have done it. She takes care of the inside and outside of the house. Don&#39;t look at her bad eyesight, she understands everything. She cut down all the trees in my yard and replaced them with crabapples and pomegranates. , dates, apricots, peaches, everything grows smoothly.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although Zhou Tao is crazy, he understands his shortcomings. He is outgoing and open-minded, but when encountering sudden setbacks, he easily becomes confused. The wife is not like that, she can always remain calm. &quot;I know how to look at myself, not others. Marvin is good at recognizing people, good and bad. She can see clearly. Her ability to do things is outstanding among women.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Marvin is also open to fame and fortune. Zhou Tao said that he had enough conditions to retire and move to Beijing, and the army could arrange a house for him. &quot;Mrs. Ma didn&#39;t go. She said she was staying in Xinjiang. She is determined and not easily swayed by vanity.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, after the autobiography was published, a lot of people A female military writer couldn&#39;t hold back her anger and wrote an article criticizing Zhou Tao for giving up love and choosing the &quot;most suitable&quot; one&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;the safest, The women who do not cause trouble&lt;/span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; become partners, using the rhetoric of &quot;Chinese men&#39;s traditional &#39;ugly wife and thin hot bed&#39;&quot;, and finally summarizes and utilitarianizes the two women. Sexual judgment is tantamount to denying one&#39;s own guilt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao did not respond at all. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Have you shown the description in the autobiography to Teacher Marvin?&quot; I asked him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;No.&quot; Zhou Tao smiled. There was an understanding in the smile that &quot;even if she saw it, she would just laugh it off&quot;, but also a trace of fear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border -box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;No more poetry after the age of 40&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;In the late 1970s, fortune befell Zhou Tao, who had an unappreciated talent. Relying on his literary talent and his relationship with his father, he successfully transferred to the Military Region Creative Office in Urumqi and concentrated on making a living through literature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When writers Cao Yu and Xu Chi went to Xinjiang in August 1978, after reading Zhou Tao&#39;s poem &quot;North and South of Tianshan&quot;, they praised at a symposium that &quot;it is sentimental and interesting. real poetry&quot;. Zhou Tao was caught off guard by this great news and thought of Liu Shaotang, the former &quot;prodigy writer&quot; who sparked his literary dream. &quot;The teacher in high school was telling his story &quot;The Green Mule&quot; on the podium. He&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(Liu Shaotang)&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Sitting in class with classmates and listening to lectures. What a feeling that must be!&quot; When I was 30 years old, I met an expert who appreciated me, and I felt happy in my heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The next two or three years became the explosive period of Zhou Tao&#39;s poetry. Xiao Qiao remembers that almost every two days in 1981, a new poem by Zhou Tao would gush out of magma from the ground. &quot;Look at their dates, they are as dense as the footprints left by poets when they go out every day!&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao once collaborated with Yang Mu and Zhang Deyi to create &quot;New Frontier Poetry&quot;, It is not about war, but about reflecting the unique features of the Xinjiang region. For a time, their names occupied the pages of &quot;Poetry Magazine&quot;, &quot;People&#39;s Literature&quot;, and &quot;Shanghai Literature&quot; one after another, and they were at the forefront of the literary trend. Liu Xiaowu, chairman of the Xinjiang Federation of Literary and Art Circles, objected to this on the grounds that &quot;frontier poems were originally about conquering the northwest, but now Xinjiang is part of the motherland, who are you going to conquer?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wait After starting to write hazy poetry, Zhou Tao once gave himself a direction - &quot;Guo Xiaochuan&#39;s voice, Wen Jie&#39;s color&quot;, but found that this combination &quot;doesn&#39;t work very well&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/0e32231c9649e4b49505957342ee2a0b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 984&quot; height=&quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/0e32231c9649e4b49505957342ee2a0b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257108&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In 1984, three military writers were at Kunming Airport, preparing to take a flight The helicopter flew to Laoshan. From left to right are Li Binkui, Zhou Tao, and Li Yanqing&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1984, he and two other writers were ordered to create on the Laoshan front line. At first, he even told writers who had not gone up the mountain about the dangers of going up the mountain to scare them; later, he witnessed with his own eyes soldiers who were blinded by Vietnamese army mines. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After getting used to it, the soldiers can sleep well at night. &quot;The helmets were lying beside the pillows, and their faces were sleeping like sculptures. They were all people who escaped from the hands of death.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Tiantian and Soldiers They ate and slept together and became familiar with each other. Zhou Tao did not hear any heroic words from their mouths. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;How does it feel to fight? The soldier said, &quot;It&#39;s so scary when the enemy&#39;s shells are covering it. I wish I could crawl under the ground and climb up quickly, regardless of my posture. There&#39;s no way to express the terror. It&#39;s absolutely irresistible to human will. If you can escape, That&#39;s pretty good.&quot; Zhou Tao imagined that it would be the same when our artillery fire covered the other side. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He wrote a long poem of 2,000 lines, &quot;Mountains, Mountains, Jungles.&quot; The poem not only contains the cruelty of war, but also a writing perspective that transcends victory, defeat and cause and effect: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;My poor and stubborn neighbor&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic, italic_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;My distant relative who has a melancholic temperament and is prone to disputes&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I fight you&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;My heart is actually angry and painful&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Almost crying while beating&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I beat another part of myself with tears &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Dongfang——is the name of our common grandmother&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot; >;Generation after generation of dead did not make the earth rot&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;but it was the living people who made it crowded and chaotic &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;All forms of death&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The purpose is to remind and explore the meaning of life&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;The dead are no longer afraid of death&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The living are fearful&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——&quot;Mountains, Mountains, Jungles, Jungles&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;This long poem has only been published in two not-so-famous frontier publications, and the single version has not been published due to the publishing company splitting the edition, so it has not entered the eyes of more readers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;It&#39;s a bit of a pity. It has been ignored for no reason. If this poem can be published in full in a publication like &quot;People&#39;s Literature&quot;, the impact will be great.&quot; Yin Shi et al. Many critics and friends expressed injustice for Zhou Tao. The author himself thought about it, &quot;It was too easy to write, very casual. I just started writing it in the notebook for fun, and then it became longer and longer without changing a word. No one else believed it.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao said that his only enemy is himself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Writing poems was very exciting, but his requirement for himself was: my poems should reach the national level&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(top)&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Level, I won’t write it down. Sure enough, when he won the National Award on his 40th birthday, he felt that his poetry career had come to an end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The next hill to attack? Prose. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao believes that his contribution and originality lies in &quot;liberation prose&quot;: &quot;What is important in prose writing is not testing and dismemberment, but feeling and embracing&quot;. He does not like &quot;research&quot; &quot;, preferring to indulge in endless daydreams, leisurely reflections, and tastes, so he doesn&#39;t care about the abruptness of the beginning, the transition and correspondence between the upper and lower paragraphs, and writes prose based on the logic, structure, and writing style of poetry. He even said arrogantly, &quot;Prose has no rules. I am the rules.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So in Zhou Tao&#39;s words, various memories, thoughts, emotions and imaginations rush together and cross paths. The river water on the embankment spreads in all directions on the endless grassland. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He is disgusted with the idea of ​​&quot;traveling in mountains and rivers&quot;, thinking that it is just &quot;treating mountains and waters as spiritual prostitutes.&quot; In the famous work &quot;Gonnas&#39;s Horse&quot;, he regards the appreciation of the horse&#39;s spirit and muscles as an artistic enjoyment; in &quot;Bird of Prey&quot;, he focuses on a horse that fought with an old wolf, its claws were dug into the bones of the old wolf and the trunk of the tree, and finally ran away. An eagle torn apart by wolves; in &quot;Crossing the River&quot;, I marvel that a thin old Kazakh woman over eighty years old subdued a fierce horse that refused to cross the river...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Whether it is a sacred mountain, a wild horse, or a human being, in Zhou Tao&#39;s passionate and bold expressions, there will always be a strong &quot;master&#39;s self-statement&quot; color, thinking that he is strong and sympathetic to the strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/869c4630e5db9b2e0e06a7b6a78217b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 498&quot; height=&quot;828&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/869c4630e5db9b2e0e06a7b6a78217b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257110&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;His prose is characterized by its length&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Several articles are more than 20,000 words&lt;/span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, famous for his strong expression and impulse to think. Zhou Tao once had a calm understanding of this: &quot;Speculation is a component in prose. If it is excessive, it will harm art. Therefore, I particularly value Jia Pingwa&#39;s prose. He does not focus on speculation but captures the hidden meaning of life. He pays more attention to the direct sensitivity to the original form of life. My recognition of him actually shows my recognition of some of my own shortcomings.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although it was over 20 years ago, Although he had the above understanding, his habit of eagerly expressing his thoughts has not changed since then. It can still be seen in &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Tao has the complacency of a proud man and the fear of &quot;losing what he has gained&quot; hanging over his head. He is obsessed with literature, thinking that it is free, fair and unfair. As complex as politics is. 20 years ago, he won the Lu Xun Literature Award for the first time for his collection of essays, but he did not go to accept the award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reason? &quot;The various literary awards are far from what I imagined. The awards must be fair. They must not be mixed up, and they must not be sprinkled with pepper. They must be awarded to those who are most worthy of the award. No matter who that person is, it may not be me.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He said that in the 1980s, the national goal was clear and everyone was full of hope. The entire era was the emotion exaggerated by &quot;The Toast Song&quot;. But in the early 1990s, he inevitably developed a feeling of nihilism, drifted away from society, and was no longer so direct. &quot;The Panic of Winter in Bortala&quot; was written in such a state - but only a few people understand it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/569f47056b7b988679b14a3928354a6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 984&quot; height=&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/569f47056b7b988679b14a3928354a6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257109&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In March 1986, Zhou Tao (first from right) won the first place in the country The second New Poetry (Collection of Poetry) Award, the first from the left is the famous poet Ai Qing, and the award recipient is Hu Qiaomu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px ;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Destined? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, which was completed more than 20 years later, Zhou Tao wrote that Ji Shuteng and other cadres went to the countryside and enjoyed a meal of grilled fish under the Populus euphratica forest by the Yarkant River. Feast: &quot;The ancient Maigaiti people used magic to catch big and lively fish from the river! ... The tray was presented, and the taste was really fragrant!&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;What is worth noting is not the delicious food, but the attitude of the food provider and the user: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The leaders of the inspection team sat cross-legged in the open space among the Populus euphratica trees, and the floor was covered with gorgeous Hotan carpets. The villagers held the trays, bowed their heads, and crouched like they were serving an emperor. Who taught them these great rituals? When did this tearful civilization develop? Ji Shuteng suddenly felt guilty, feeling that he was not worthy of such a feast and pious etiquette, and felt sorry for these desert people who danced the sword dance beside the campfire and painted peasant paintings in the orchard. What have we done for others to deserve such grand reception? ” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——&quot;Journey to the West&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This reminds me of Zhou Tao&#39;s long essay &quot;Essays on Halashal&quot; written in the 1980s. In that article, he associated the chapped lips of his fellow travelers with Ma Zhongying&#39;s Hui people more than half a century ago. The soldiers fought bloody battles with the Uyghurs of Hoja Niyazi, but now, the relics of the past are left by the thirsty lips of the north.&lt;/span>; &quot;>;Waterless ravines&lt;/span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ate up all.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He saw in the Hui people living in Yanqi A kind of &quot;hundred years of loneliness&quot; that not everyone can feel: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Forbearance and silence Behind the eyes of suspicion and sly distrust is the most sincere promise and life-saving friendship; the pain caused by the contradiction between the humiliating inferiority complex and the strong self-esteem deep in the heart; not being understood But they stubbornly want to preserve the barriers they have formed; the sadness and stubbornness caused by the great contrast between the backward lifestyle of remoteness and poverty and the self-confidence of the sky are the result of this kind of hundred years of loneliness.&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He pointed out, &quot;The history of the Chinese nation is not just the history of the Han people. There are countless emperors, famous ministers, and military generals who have served the country in the past generations who are from ethnic minorities. . &quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such ink and views are rare in his decades of rich writing.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;Yin Shi, who has been friends with him for many years, sharply pointed out his problem: &quot;He still doesn&#39;t express enough about the land of Xinjiang and the Uyghurs and other ethnic minorities. Zhou Tao also expressed the shrewdness of a Han man on this point. He did not learn from the language, classics, secular culture, or any other aspect - he did not go deep into Xinjiang. &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the analysis of &quot;Journey to the West&quot; just written, Yin Shi said bluntly: &quot;If each of them&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(protagonist)&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;&#39;s inner world can also be unfolded like Ji Shuteng&#39;s, especially if the personal spiritual world, cultural character and even national attributes of the Uyghur character Simayi Ahematijiang are deeply explored and presented. Then the many voices in this work, including the dialogue between different &#39;voices&#39;, will create great tension. &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Why can&#39;t it be expanded?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The language barrier is one, and the fear of being real is the other. It can only go so far. &quot;Zhou Tao answered me.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He has expressed his admiration for Zhang Chengzhi, but he also admitted that the latter has reached the extreme in his faith. In fact, Zhou Tao&#39;s major in university is Uyghur, but within half a year, the road to higher education was cut off by Yili&#39;s &quot;re-education&quot;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The angle from which he expressed his regrets and lamentations was: &quot;If I have completed four years of study, When I learn the Uyghur language, I can work as a secretary in a commune in southern Xinjiang, and then as a county-level cadre. I will learn more about ethnic relations and human affairs, and then go into historical research and ethnic investigation, and I will be able to organize a full-length novel. But I didn’t have much interest in learning Uyghur during that half year, and I couldn’t see it that far. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He is psychologically very close to grassland peoples like Kazakhs, and compares himself to “a semi-nomad who is used to yurts and mutton, and loves grasslands and riding horses.” As for Xinjiang, where he grew up, he considered this place his hometown, but he always observed and experienced it based on the roots of the Central Plains culture.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the literary critic Wei Qi In Hong&#39;s view, Zhou Tao rarely describes life in the market, nor does he take it as his duty to express the joys, sorrows, joys, and aesthetic tastes of the people. Instead, he tries his best to publicize his own personal life experience. Therefore, his writing also presents a kind of &quot;aristocratic&quot; style. tendency.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/97d629aae0ecf1617113532ed8d97452.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;479&quot; height=&quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/97d629aae0ecf1617113532ed8d97452.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257111&quot; data-mce- width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Looking back on most of his life, Zhou Tao said that he was somewhere between civil and military: Born in the army, it was martial; Background: studying literature and going to school; becoming an athlete and joining martial arts; coming back to school and liking literature and then following literature: after studying literature, he eventually went to the barracks to study literature. They are all nourishing you, and they are all restricting you; restriction is also nourishment. &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When he was old, he was considered to be the highest-ranking civilian cadre in the army and enjoyed military-level treatment. On the contrary, his mother, who had been caring for him all his life, heard his son Tao say, &quot;Mom, I&#39;m going to be a general.&quot; He replied, &quot;You haven&#39;t fought a day in a battle, how can you be a general? &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;What have the eight years in Kashgar taught you? &quot;I asked him.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He replied: &quot;It&#39;s not what you are born with. Your personal conditions must be displayed and expressed under the general trend of a society. Otherwise it&#39;s worthless. &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Are you a fatalist? &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He nodded. &quot;Everyone has his own destiny, and destiny is the possibility given to you by society. Those who are courageous but not ignorant are &quot;two poles&quot;, and those who are knowledgeable but not courageous are nerds. Only with courage and luck can you achieve great things. Me and Marvin? It&#39;s not luck, it&#39;s fate. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In an era when the whole family was torn apart by political movements, he questioned: “From being a free boy born in a family, to becoming a person who is influenced by society and his own conditions. Adults embedded in a certain profession, fate, how will you send us? Do you show special favor to us or are you particularly indifferent? Regarding the latter possibility, we were unwilling to consider and could not accept it at that time. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fifty years have passed, and the answer to the mystery has been completely revealed. What surprised him infinitely was that the answer to today’s mystery had been revealed to him one after another. He always believed that that By that time, everything is doomed.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;(Reference materials: &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, &quot;A Man and Xinjiang&quot;, &quot; &quot;Zhou Tao&#39;s self-selected poetry and prose volume&quot;, &quot;Zhou Tao is read by all eyes&quot;, &quot;A kind of writing of recognition&quot;, &quot;How to read &quot;Journey to the West&quot;&quot;, intern reporters Shi Jiayi, Wang Yuman and Zhang Miao also contributed to this article .Thanks to &quot;Contemporary&quot; magazine and Huacheng Press)&lt;/span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海南白沙：云端之上，蓝天之下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259994]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这款下饭剧，正在悄然流行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259899]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The new drama &quot;Tian Geng Ji&quot; has ended. The rating is not high, but the popularity is not low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is adapted from the farming novel &quot;The Rebirth of a Little Landlord&quot;: a modern girl, Lian Maner, wanders into the ancient countryside and becomes a peasant girl. Together with the mysterious man Shen Nuo, she battles wits and courage with her best relatives to seek justice for her cowardly &quot;parents&quot;. Under limited conditions, he worked hard to get rich and worked hard. He gained not only his farming career but also his love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The secret behind the popularity of &quot;Tian Geng Ji&quot; is just two words - farming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c7495f4ccca4d14862ab7149f37acf14.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c7495f4ccca4d14862ab7149f37acf14.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256834&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Among the online articles that emphasize fast pace and strong narrative, farming articles that focus on stable happiness appear to be somewhat unique. The development of farming literature is divided into three stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born out of SLG (strategy) games in the early days, the protagonist, like the player, recruits troops and horses in a different world, completes tasks, and develops the economy or agriculture with the purpose of &quot;building walls high, accumulating food widely, and becoming king slowly&quot; , and continue to expand its own power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The middle period focuses on the literal meaning, allowing the protagonist to make a fortune in feudal society, and the narrative style becomes warm and peaceful. In addition to &quot;Rebirth of a Little Landlord&quot;, the original work of &quot;Tian Geng Ji&quot;, popular novels such as &quot;Daily Life of Farming and Raising Children in Ancient Mountain Houses&quot; and &quot;I Sell Hotpot in the Song Dynasty&quot; also belong to the category of farming literature in this period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The style of farming literature and painting in the later period is clear&lt;/span>; Strange. It integrates infinite flow, fantasy, suspense and other factors based on the basic thinking of &quot;farming&quot; to achieve the fusion of genres. For example, &quot;After rebirth as the Dragon King, I make a fortune from seafood&quot;, &quot;I rely on farming to save mankind in the interstellar world&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we want to find &lt;span>; a source for farming literature in traditional literature, then the closest source is local literature. Both of them focus on the rural landscape, but the background of rural literature is thick and usually carries narratives of suffering, while farming literature is written in a light and soothing vacuum. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49e2fb8f4e551fbc1fb45b218c4791fe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49e2fb8f4e551fbc1fb45b218c4791fe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256831 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The road to film and television adaptation of Zhongtian novels has been relatively bumpy. Compared with other web novels with strong conflicts and many reversals, it is actually&lt;/span>; not that suitable for being adapted. onto the screen. What are now being adapted into &quot;farming dramas&quot; are generally medium-term farming dramas that are slow and steady, and are less difficult to shoot than early farming dramas and later farming dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chef Fang Holding a Pot in the Flower Room&quot; and &quot;&lt;span>;The Sparkling Chef in the World&quot; are relatively successful examples. There are no grudges or resentments, and they only revolve around women pursuing careers. The protagonist unfolds a small incision narrative. Both dramas weakened the farming attributes, amplified the food elements, and used delicious dishes to evoke the audience&#39;s empathetic experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/79d11908058c277cff63481c61f129db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/79d11908058c277cff63481c61f129db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256832 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The annual hit drama &quot;Do you know whether it should be green, fat, red and thin&quot; is adapted from the farming novel of the same name, which tells the story of Sheng Minglan, the concubine of the Sheng family, who uses her intelligence and talent to succeed in the big family. A story of surviving and overcoming the many challenges of life. The drama version deletes the time-travel elements in the original work, making the heroine&#39;s logic of acting according to the rules in a feudal society with strict hierarchies and distinctions between descendants and concubines more consistent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Do You Know&quot; while weakening the farming elements, highlights the family fighting and business elements, and enhances the dramatic conflicts. There was a discussion around the concubines of Da Niangzi, Lin Xiaoniang and Mo Lan. More than the heroine Sheng Minglan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/be81d57344a5d940a288c87483302cdc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/be81d57344a5d940a288c87483302cdc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256836 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Jade Face and Peach Blossom Always Encounter&quot; is adapted from &quot;The Butcher&#39;s Little Lady&quot;. It takes Hu Jiao&#39;s growth from assisting her husband to taking charge of her own role as the main line. It highlights the power of women in concept and presents the above story. But he was short of breath. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/948462ff5883bf8134990b1f861c86f1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/948462ff5883bf8134990b1f861c86f1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256833 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;To sum up, although &quot;Tian Geng Ji&quot; is not&lt;/span>; the first farming drama, it is undoubtedly the most relevant, showing the simplicity and leisure of farm life. , and depicts the discord among clan relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine Lian Maner’s career line (complete system tasks and earn 1,000 gold), love line (she and Shen Nuo change from firm allies to intimate lovers), and love line (help parents to be wise) Fighting with Wude relatives) with three hands, striving to be the winner of every track. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49d75a2346f3bfa7c78e7bbd3db59117.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49d75a2346f3bfa7c78e7bbd3db59117.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256835 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But judging from the feedback from the audience: the love line is too boring and lacks a sense of CP, the family line is too annoying and affects the audience&#39;s emotions, and what everyone loves most is the farming career line. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After all, love stories are rampant in contemporary online dramas. If you click on any idol drama, you can get handsome men and beautiful women falling in love in any era and any industry; it is so annoying. Relatives who will not pay for their lives have also watched a lot of costume dramas and urban dramas in recent years, so it is inevitable that they feel the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Therefore, it is not difficult to understand that &quot;Tian Geng Ji&quot; was ultimately popular for the seemingly insipid farming line, rather than anything else. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can&#39;t help but be reminiscent of &quot;Farming&quot;, a phenomenal variety show in the first half of this year. 10 young guests spent 190 days on 142 acres of land. of sowing and harvesting. Maybe even they themselves didn&#39;t expect that there would be so many viewers willing to watch them farming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/97ce23d7460c454ac135cfad19543d0e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/97ce23d7460c454ac135cfad19543d0e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256837 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nostalgia for farming is engraved in the DNA of the Chinese people. Ten years ago, the virtual vegetable growing game QQ Farm became very popular. Some people stayed up late at night and drove to see the sea. Some people got up early and went to bed early just to set the alarm clock and steal vegetables. Ten years later, people moved to WeChat farms, raising chickens, fish and pigeons in the status bar. Turn on your mobile phone, and all major e-commerce platforms have launched virtual services such as watering trees, planting trees, and operating orchards, and linked them to real benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chinese people, &quot;farming talent&quot; is an initial skill that can be obtained without &lt;span>; lighting it up. For thousands of years, Chinese society has been dominated by agricultural civilization, which has condensed the wisdom of the working people and given birth to a broad and profound Chinese culture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Tao Yuanming&#39;s poem &quot;Picking chrysanthemums under the eastern fence, leisurely seeing the Nanshan Mountain&quot; also symbolizes the Chinese people&#39;s pursuit and yearning for pastoral life. New. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Contemporary young people read Tao Yuanming and also pursue farming essays and farming dramas (comprehensive). If the utopian imagination constructed by the former is distant and ethereal, and somewhat unreal through the silk curtain of the times, then the comfort provided by the latter is within reach and approachable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/1f0b0900204242054072a0cdc952588e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/1f0b0900204242054072a0cdc952588e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256838 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the era of rapid development, everything&lt;/span>; is rushing forward like clockwork. Young people are rushing forward in the rapid current, but occasionally they also think about it. Take a breather after dinner and look for an emotional outlet. Therefore, slow-paced and beautiful farming dramas are an excellent way to relieve stress. And compared with radical entrepreneurial stories, farming also has a certain sense of security. Every time you work, you will gain, and the effort and reward are generally proportional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1960s, Taiwanese health realism films had a binary opposition of urban or rural narratives, with implicit praise and blame in the beautiful rural scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, sixty years later, the &quot;farming flow&quot; actually also hides a certain creative tendency. The countryside is often a healing utopia, while the city is a heterotopia that confused young people want to escape from. . Through a small screen, urbanites can also become farmers remotely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the farming literature and farming dramas have shortcomings such as outdated narratives, stereotyped characters, and a slightly dull rhythm, they accurately hit a spreading and popular public sentiment. We might as well give them more room for growth, and I believe there will be more hits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贵人鸟转型卖吃的，国产运动鞋三巨头正在分岔路口]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259989]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/04/eaa4eb85be65a96bdaa301cfe2d17880.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;631&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/04/eaa4eb85be65a96bdaa301cfe2d17880.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the most sought-after items in the fashion circle, the popularity of sneakers is receding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 22, Guirenniao issued an announcement stating that in view of the decline in revenue and continued losses of the sports shoes and apparel business since the judicial reorganization, and the increasingly fierce market competition, the company will end the sports shoes and apparel business that has been in business for 36 years. And the grain business will be the company&#39;s main business development direction in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guirenniao’s financial report shows that from January to June 2023, Guirenniao’s sports shoes and apparel business achieved operating income of 232 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 19.51%. From 2018 to 2022, ST Guiren’s annual net profit attributable to the parent company suffered 4 losses, with a cumulative loss of more than 2 billion yuan. The number of &quot;Guirenniao&quot; brand retail terminals has dropped from 2,358 in 2019 to 1,584 in the first half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/4e35dce86edf26ad3c2e59e5511f4fe6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/4e35dce86edf26ad3c2e59e5511f4fe6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257038&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Anta Sports, Li Ning, and Xtep International have successively released their financial reports for the first half of 2023. Facing the recovery in performance of Nike and Adidas in China, domestic products are still struggling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with last year’s report card where Anta’s revenue surpassed Nike China’s and Li-Ning’s revenue was ahead of Adidas China’s, there is still a certain decline in performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/93ba6b3e658359194e85bd53db909e2e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/93ba6b3e658359194e85bd53db909e2e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257039&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the first half of this year, among the three major domestic sports brands, only Xtep is still significantly expanding its stores. The current total number of stores is 8,256, ranking second. Li Ning has a net decrease of 155 main brand stores and is the only group that has no net increase in brand stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ea57ccb33ca4fc7db4141baa349f8f4e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ea57ccb33ca4fc7db4141baa349f8f4e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257040&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the past, due to the brand effect of several major fashion brands, Adidas and Nike had absolute advantages over domestic Anta, Li Ning, Xtep, and 361 Degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d2cbe8eccffe6128694adefe9d34b673.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d2cbe8eccffe6128694adefe9d34b673.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257041&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Today, the three giants of domestic products are deeply involved in their own core technologies - Anta&#39;s &quot;nitrogen technology&quot;, &quot;Li Ning&#39;s&quot; flick technology, and Xtep&#39;s &quot;XTEP ACE cushioning technology platform&quot;. They have fully blossomed with differentiated strategies. Anta and Li Ning have continued to Leading the domestic sports brand market for two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/57b049e6ef9c40de403b13c20b8132ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/57b049e6ef9c40de403b13c20b8132ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257042&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the future, if sports brands want to go further, they cannot just &quot;rest on their laurels&quot; or &quot;rest on their laurels&quot;. The addition of design languages ​​such as accessories, graffiti, and deconstructive splicing in shoe design has been squeezed out of the mainstream. The scope of the discussion was replaced by the proposition of &quot;how to make sneakers not like a pair of sneakers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e009a49268a310f5faf5ecea0da8dfb1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e009a49268a310f5faf5ecea0da8dfb1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257043&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;De-sneakerization and artificial intelligence are innovative paths worth exploring. At the same time, guided by audience thinking, sports brands must better understand the hearts of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3e9648a7aab0c4e2c59e37f9a8fe3a93.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3e9648a7aab0c4e2c59e37f9a8fe3a93.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257089&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;140&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the rise of DIY culture, more and more young people are creating secondary creations on sports shoes, transforming old shoes through graffiti, modification, and homemade methods. With the emergence of the national trend, the sales of Huai Li Guochao modified shoes have increased rapidly and are loved by many young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will discuss with you how domestic sports shoes can break through the bottleneck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子用16.8万彩礼钱环游中国：抽身离开也是一种觉醒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259967]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Do you agree with this kind of &quot;living yourself&quot;? A man in Shanxi broke off his engagement due to a temporary increase in the price of the bride&#39;s bride price, and used the bride price to resign and travel. On June 1 this year, Zhu set out with his luggage on his back. In five months, he visited more than 40 cities and spent more than 30,000 yuan. &quot;The main means of transportation are green trains, and it doesn&#39;t cost much to stay in a youth hostel.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu introduced that he and his girlfriend met through a blind date, &quot;We have been dating for almost eight or nine months, and I feel that When the time comes, we are ready to get married.” He said that a bride price of RMB 188,000 is the &quot;normal market&quot; in the local area. &quot;Ours is called a &#39;big package&#39;. This money includes wedding photos, three coins, etc. RMB 188,000. I have savings of RMB 168,000 and 2 I just borrowed it from a friend.&quot; Later, his girlfriend asked for an additional 30,000 yuan, &quot;I said I couldn&#39;t afford it, and I borrowed these from others,&quot; and they broke up after a quarrel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Frankly speaking, Zhu still hasn’t let go. Taking the green train and staying in a youth hostel, the five-month trip only cost more than 30,000 yuan, which is very economical. This is probably because this is the hard-earned money that I have saved and I don’t want to spend it lavishly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, he sympathizes with the hardships of his parents, saying: &quot;Every time I go on a blind date, I feel a little uncomfortable. I eat Haidilao with the girls, watch movies, etc., but my parents have never eaten Haidilao.&quot; &quot;Lao.&quot; His parents originally planned to help him pay the down payment for buying a house in Taiyuan. &quot;I also feel sorry for my parents. They have never been to many places and they are still thinking about buying me a house.&quot; I did not tell my parents about my resignation. &quot;I will tell you if I have the opportunity in the future, but I may not tell them for the time being. I am afraid that they will not accept it and say that I am not doing my job properly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that Zhu and his parents are both relatively traditional people in terms of values. They are down-to-earth, simple, have long-term considerations for life, and have a solemn attitude towards marriage and family. On the surface, 30,000 yuan was the straw that broke the camel&#39;s back; in fact, Zhu was probably worried that once this case was opened, it would be endless in the future. The reason why his girlfriend asked for 30,000 yuan was that &quot;her best friends all paid back.&quot; In addition, I asked for another 30,000 yuan.&quot; There is no end to the comparison, and your married life may not be comfortable and harmonious in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of evolutionary psychology, the origin of marriage or monogamy is: women have a 9-month pregnancy period, and there is a lactation period after the baby is born. It takes a long time for human children to reach adulthood, and It is necessary to acquire various survival skills, which requires a father&#39;s role to provide protection and survival resources for mother and child, and to teach his children through words and deeds; what men gain is to reduce the uncertainty of father and son (paternal uncertainty) through marriage, and to assume family responsibilities and social responsibility. The father in the sense is a product of cultural construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Chinese or Western, traditional marriage values ​​and underlying logic are the same. However, after entering modern society, this set of values ​​was first impacted by individualism and then deconstructed by progressivism/postmodernism, making it increasingly unsustainable. Raising your own children gives you a continuous sense of gain and happiness, but it is indeed hard work, consumes money and effort, and also requires a sense of responsibility and the ability to delay gratification vs. spending money immediately to enjoy the present and carpe diem. Which one will the chic &quot;modern people&quot; choose? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, when some women complain about what they get from marriage, some men will also reflect on why they got married. When some women talk about having a boy or a girl and the so-called right of surname, they say to the man, &quot;Does your family have a throne to inherit?&quot; Some men will suddenly realize and ask themselves: There is indeed no throne in my family to inherit, so I will spend a lot of money. Is it worth getting married and going through all the hard work of raising children? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When more and more men and women ask &quot;What is the meaning of getting married, starting a family, and having children?&quot; this in itself means the weakening of the reproductive instinct and the decline of marriage and family values, which in turn means the value of the benefits of childbearing. Write down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, betrothal gifts are not the same thing as betrothal gifts in traditional society. Bride price is the price paid by lower-class men to enter the marriage market, but it has been rising and becoming more general in recent years. The marriage market is a regional and multi-level composite structure. The bottom market may have more men and fewer women, but the top market may have more women and fewer men. According to the logic of supply and demand, when there are more men and fewer women, the man will pay the bride price, but when there are more women and fewer men, whether Will it be the other way around? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you get divorced a few days after getting married, it is almost impossible to get back all the bride price; one party will add the other party&#39;s name to the real estate certificate and lose half of the house. &quot;Talk about feelings and hurt money&quot;, investors are facing increasing risks. In the marriage market, the investor, as Party A, will consider reducing transactions when faced with excessive requirements and costs. This is squeezing marriage from the cost of childbearing. Zhu broke off the engagement due to a temporary increase in the price of the bride&#39;s bride price, which is another vivid case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In modern society, the self-awareness of men and women is constantly strengthening, which is the so-called &quot;self-awakening&quot;. Since there is a female awakening, there will be a male awakening, and the awakening must eventually be two-way. There may be a sequence of awakenings, but equality is the final outcome and stable equilibrium. In a system that evolves over time, the transient state solution is a temporary phenomenon, and the long-term steady solution is the final result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, a female teacher in Zhengzhou’s resignation letter, “The world is so big, I want to see it,” became popular on the Internet. Public opinion praised her for her self-awakening, courage to pursue personal freedom, and living her life. Zhu&#39;s decision to break off the engagement and then use his savings to travel around China based on the same motivation deserves the same evaluation. As an adult, regardless of gender, if you don’t want to live a routine and step-by-step life, if you want to chase your dreams and be responsible for your own decisions, there is nothing wrong with that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To what extent will men and women awaken in the future? What will be the shape of a stable marriage and family in the future? It’s hard to say, but one thing is certain: it must be based on the principle of equality between men and women, and a new stable balance will be formed based on equality between men and women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any worthwhile marriage must be based on love and morality. Only in this way can home be a haven where people can relax physically and mentally, rather than a place where the spirit is exhausted. This requires all kinds of reciprocity: reciprocity in love, reciprocity in family responsibility, reciprocity in giving, reciprocity in providing emotional value... A relationship in which one party always gives and the other party always extracts cannot go far. Therefore, when you find that you are entering such a relationship, you need to stop your losses in time; or, after you find that you have entered such a relationship, you need to get out. Who can deny that this is an awakening? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[索南才让：写最后一代游牧人的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259932]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/RaZv85deQGOVAoK0hsyPdiKIWKD5XbflDNetMbJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/RaZv85deQGOVAoK0hsyPdiKIWKD5XbflDNetMb JQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256518&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking off the maroon or indigo Mongolian clothes, taking off the top hat, and putting on a polo shirt is like opening a portal and stepping into another world. The 38-year-old writer Sonam Cairang&#39;s figure is not considered tall and majestic among herdsmen. After leaving the bright clothes and running pastures, walking in the crowded city, even the slightly laborious raised tongue reveals a reserved and bookish tone. He habitually put on a polite, courteous, and gentlemanly face, and sat down at the dining table, reminding himself that there wasn&#39;t much red wine in the glass, but he still had to take a sip first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having just left his hometown in his twenties, the outside world’s default behavior of standing at the wine table for a toast and saying a bunch of toast words made him at a loss. He followed the example in panic for a while, and then lied that he never drank. When he returned to the grassland, he relieved his psychological burden and started drinking. The rule in the pastoral area is that no matter how hospitable the other party is, no one will stand up and thank the host with a glass of wine and say that I will return the invitation next time; nor will the other party be offended just because he said the wrong thing. In no particular order, everyone started making fists after having two or three glasses of wine, &quot;It&#39;s much simpler, especially direct and rough.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People living in grasslands, especially in alpine areas, can&#39;t be said to be indifferent in their emotions. In short, they are not that Rich.&quot; When grazing, it is common to go two or three days without seeing anyone to communicate or talk. The longest time, judging from Suonan Cairang&#39;s personal record, this silence lasted forty or fifty days. He was talking to himself in a desolate and vast environment, and he had developed a distant and overlooking gaze, making it difficult for him to be sentimental. &quot;Man develops this kind of character in an interdependent relationship with the environment. His attitude towards living creatures is different and more ruthless.&quot; Livestock fed by hand can be a tool for herders to travel far, or a Food to go with alcohol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sonam Cairang’s short story collection &quot;Looking for Signals&quot; published in 2023, these animals have also become the real murderers that drive the plot. During a dialogue at the Shanghai Book Fair in August, guest Han Songluo deliberately counted the ways of death that appeared in the book in advance, and recited at the scene in a tone like a bill report, &quot;One death from freezing, one sudden death, two deaths from being run over by a cow.&quot; times, and once fell from a horse to death...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compare the &quot;modern ways&quot; of death in Alice Munro&#39;s writings about those who fled the town, such as plane and train crashes, cancer, shipwrecks and drowning, etc. , Han Songluo classified the passages in Suonan Cai&#39;s book in which he sacrificed his life to contend with nature or interact with animals as &quot;pre-modern&quot;. The author explained that this is indeed an environmental test that plateau herders face every day. &quot;There are often floods and lightning in Qinghai. People are struck to death by lightning, thrown to death by horses, and various accidents occur.&quot; Han Songluo With emotion, &quot;I thought we were very far away from pre-modern society, but Sonam&#39;s words bring us back to this scene, where the relationship between humans, animals, land, and death is still maintained by instinct.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes. The conversation took place in the Miguel de Cervantes Library, next door to the fashionable Julu Road. Some viewers in the audience did not buy it and raised questions, saying that in such an environment, &quot;it is completely impossible to think of the grassland.&quot; , and also didn’t understand, “What does it mean to tell stories about the past?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suonan Cairang still responded in a low voice, “There is a lag in writing. What you feel at the moment cannot immediately become a work. After Only through precipitation and fermentation can we write about the grazing experience passed down from our fathers.&quot; As for whether it can convey a strong sense of foreignness, this is actually an important clue for Suonan Cairang&#39;s writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His novel collection &quot;In the Wasteland&quot; published in 2021 was once spotted by director Wanma Caidan, and his new work &quot;Looking for Signal&quot; was also shortlisted for the 7th Pingyao International Film Festival in October 2023. &quot;Migration Plan·From Literature to Film and Television&quot; section - the story must exude a completely different temperament from the city, which is why directors have successively purchased the copyright and tried to adapt it; but this kind of northwest ranch style is not the focus of his text, as the final A generation of nomads, he shouldered personal experiences, the memories of his father&#39;s generation, and the collision of life when he went out to work as an adult. After a few years, he returned to his hometown with mixed eyes. Therefore, he was never satisfied with recording the strange scenery on the surface, but stood in the Explore the spiritual changes of herdsmen from a broader perspective - facing the expansion of urbanization undoubtedly reveals more and more consistent ways of living and thinking, making readers unable to feel the &quot;grassland&quot; coming towards them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2008, he came to Beijing with 300 yuan in his pocket and worked in a factory that made urban sculptures. Before entering the factory, he bought two volumes of the Nobel Prize in Literature collection, as well as a collection of works that cost more than 100 yuan. A biography of Faulkner that cost almost half of his net worth. One time I didn&#39;t go back to my hometown during the Spring Festival. I was watching fireworks alone in an empty factory. I suddenly felt a force, as if Qinghai Lake was close in front of me. I pushed open the invisible door of my home. My father, who had drunk too much the day before, was lying on the sofa with his hat on. sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My hometown is the bloodline of my writing. Later I started to doubt it, and the thread of pulling became weaker and weaker. Only after I leave can I write about my hometown and understand it.” Now there are no sheep left in his family, and there are about 80 of them. The cattle are usually taken care of by his younger brother, and he returns to the ranch once a month. In order to maintain his creative state, he lives in Haiyan County, not far from the ranch, and retains some urban living habits. When he gets up every day, he jogs, makes coffee, eats eggs, and then reads a book for a while. After 8 o&#39;clock, Go to the studio and start writing for the day. When I write seven to eight hundred words a day, I no longer want to write, so I go do something else. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The editor of the new book once concluded, &quot;Most of his novels are about stories about alpine grassland pastoral areas, but they do not make readers feel distant.&quot; The reason is Liu Xiaolin, vice chairman of the Qinghai Provincial Writers Association and a critic. After some analysis, &quot;he did not deliberately highlight the nationality and regional customs, lacked the quiet, simple and melodious pastoral mood of ordinary prairie novels, and did not examine the nationality in the binary opposition between the world and the local, tradition and modernity.&quot; The past and the future, and he has no intention of turning the novel into a national allegory. The usual thinking in the writing of these national literatures does not seem to affect him at all. He prefers to adopt a cold and calm narrative, focusing on the secular life of the grassland. , daily life such as grazing, drinking, and falling in love, showing the increasingly chaotic living conditions and life forms of the grasslands under the impact of modern civilization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/01/l2VGmDF1AHXwd1npPJEKUFA3j1fCJQZKAIjXoWV6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;546&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/01/l2VGmDF1AHXwd1npPJEKUFA3j1fCJQZKAIjXoWV6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256523&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Suonan Cairang’s own ranch&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The last generation of nomads in their hometown&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/ strong>;&lt;span>;I especially like watching movies. Hong Kong police and gangster movies and TVB costume martial arts movies have been with me growing up. Every year except winter, there is a mobile tent video hall on the grassland. It is very popular. At night, the speakers start playing videos to attract customers. Grasslands are different from cities. The sound penetration is particularly strong and can be heard within a radius of more than ten kilometers. When we heard it, we felt so itchy that we couldn&#39;t sit still at home. We immediately ran to a heavily trafficked three-way intersection a few kilometers away and got into a mobile tent set up on the roadside. The chairs take up space, so in order to seat as many people as possible, everyone sits cross-legged, not even able to stretch their legs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before going to school, my uncle was a movie projectionist on the grassland. I sat on his carriage and followed him to more than a dozen villages to enlarge the film. When I dropped out of school at the age of 12 and returned to the ranch, I started watching in mobile tents until I was in my twenties. At first it was VCD, then DVD, and the price rose from 50 cents to one dollar. The shows are different every day, not just Hong Kong films, but also some classic films from the Mainland, as well as foreign films like &quot;Gone with the Wind.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sounds like a wonderful teenage period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The only thing I have not regretted until now is leaving school. At that time, conditions did not allow (study). My family was in a pastoral area. If I wanted to study, I had to go to the county town. The winter pasture was 40 kilometers away, and the summer pasture was 70 or 80 kilometers away. There was no boarding school in the county, so I had to stay with relatives, and there was no one to take care of me. In addition, I couldn’t read it myself, and my family was very happy when I stopped reading, because I needed help. Looking back later, I probably gained more outside of school than in school. I didn’t study in school. I only studied after I came out. Going to school and studying are two different things. School is about learning, not reading. The first book I came into contact with was &quot;Dragon and the Eight Parts&quot;. I took that book to herd sheep. It was winter, and it was a day full of yellow sand, but I had no time to pay attention to other things all day long. I don’t even know where my flock is. That was the beginning of my real reading. As for movies, I probably watched thousands of them in those years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These movies will be helpful for you to write novels in the future Impact? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think a big part of my writing is film, whether it is narration or observing the dialogue of characters. Or in terms of demeanor, it will definitely have an impact in a subtle way. Because when I watch a movie, I will be particularly immersed in it. I will remember the lines in a good movie. I can even imitate the expression, intonation, and speed of each character when they say those lines. The scene environment will also be in my mind. vivid in my mind. I really long for that kind of ability right now. If I&#39;m watching a movie and you&#39;re talking to me next to me, I won&#39;t hear you at all. Although this habit has not been completely lost, I still cannot concentrate as before, including reading. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Watching a movie in a mobile tent saw Twenty How old were you? Did you have a TV at home at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Electricity was introduced to our home in 2008. I was 23 years old. I was already married by that time, and tent movies were slowly disappearing. The boom is booming. After the advent of solar energy, many herdsmen bought a small black and white TV, a VCD, two large solar chargers and a battery to watch at home, as did my family. I often see that the battery is depleted. The electricity is used for winter pastures and settlements. Where other nomadic sites have electricity, it is still powered. Anyway, the tent movie still managed to survive for seven or eight years before it was completely gone. Later, everyone had mobile phones. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think the current life in the pastoral areas is different from that in the city? Is the gap still big? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is basically no difference. There is actually no difference after having a mobile phone. There is no lag in the flow of information between cities and pastoral areas. When you get such important information, it will pop up on our mobile phones immediately, but the focus is different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A lot of things happened in the lives of the herdsmen. Big change? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, especially the impact on the younger generation is a complete transformation. Our parents have always been in a nomadic sequence. When they got older and were succeeded by our generation, their lifestyles changed like a fault. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearby farmers will come to the pastoral areas to build houses and do some temporary work during their spare time. Without exception, they will envy us. Because they saw that all the men, young and old, looked very leisurely. The older ones drank, rode horses, walked around, drove sheep back and forth all day long; the younger ones either played or played billiards every day. Watch movies and fall in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it still possible for teenagers to go herding now? No, they all went to study, and the perceptions of all the herdsmen changed. I used to not think that studying was the only way out, or the best prerequisite for the future of life, but now I do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But you didn&#39;t take that road either. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many of our group have not left, so our generation is the last nomad, and there will not be many in the next generation. Individuals will become truly nomadic, and nomadism is shrinking. This shrinkage is not only determined by ourselves, but also due to the adjustment of ecological policies. Qinghai is an important protected area. Everything is based on protecting the ecology and providing a good cycle, so grazing is not encouraged. There are many restrictions. For example, you cannot raise too many cattle and sheep. It depends on the carrying capacity of the pasture. If you have a thousand acres of pasture, you can only raise two to three hundred sheep. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yYMPeuFO6Ju7Wkz3NVTlS0taekLSKwGzQf6SdUMh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 683&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yYMPeuFO6Ju7Wkz3NVTlS0taekLSKwGzQf6SdUMh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256519&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Both roughness and delicacy are the truth on the grassland&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back now , do you think not going to school is a good choice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think my daughter can persist on this road for so long. That is unrealistic. It&#39;s an individual case and requires a little bit of talent. Sometimes I still can’t imagine it—how could I become a writer inexplicably? If I weren&#39;t a writer, I would definitely be in business or doing something else. I think it&#39;s boring to stay in the same environment all the time. I always want to change my way of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You now go to the county studio every day , the range of activity seems to be smaller. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Wouldn’t my own spiritual space be larger? I also often go to the pastoral area, which is very close. I usually just go for a walk and do nothing. Sometimes I go to see friends to have fun or help relatives. There are also houses over there, and sheep and cowsheds are ready-made. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Similar to &quot;Invite a Cow to Eat&quot; Is the story something you heard, or is it based on something that happened in your bullpen? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is a fictional story conceived from a very small point. There is a big pot at the door of our house, filled with various vegetable leaves and leftover rice. Every night when the yaks return to their pen, one or two will come to eat. The two of them occupied that place. When other cows came, they would attack with their horns. After a few times, the others stopped coming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electricity was already available at that time. The wires connected from the old house to the new house were too long, and a pole was erected in the middle. One day, the two of them stopped eating, and they were The lingering, vibrating sound burst out of the chest like a vent, breaking the pole. I was so angry that the power pole fell down. Although no one was hurt, it caused me a lot of losses. The wires were torn off on both sides and all the insurance was burned out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they are making trouble, they consciously know not to harm their owners, so they do not knock on the door or break in. Do you know what annoyed us most before? In summer and autumn, when it is almost dawn, at four or five o&#39;clock in the morning, the cows will eat slowly until they come to the tent. Because people move around and pour some water, there is salt in that area. You can&#39;t even drive them away. You can only take two or three steps outside. After a while, they come back and eat the tent&#39;s canvas edges, chewing them until you can sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bbhbALOhJpzgz4f89UXuCgxQvoW2yviZp3xM87IA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bbhbALOhJpzgz4f89UXuCgxQvoW2yviZp3xM87IA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256517&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will herdsmen become more patient as a result? Because you need to know how to adapt to this kind of interaction with animals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, they are all bad-tempered. The animals have not changed anything, but have only worsened. There are many who abuse cattle and sheep. Yes, the past two years have been slightly better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That kind of simple and crude language environment, you Do you think it’s good or bad for you to write novels? Do you think I might need to be more delicate? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t my novels just look simple and crude? Of course, of course, I am trying hard to make my text have a delicate element in the roughness. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did the change begin? It was because of others Evaluation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I realized it myself. When you reach a certain level, you will realize this. It&#39;s impossible to write two or three books and still be like this and still talk about it and think it&#39;s self-righteous. After reading too much and writing too much, &quot;Looking for Signals&quot; is the product of this awareness. You can see that the novella &quot;Portraits of Saints and Ivory Mahjong&quot; is different from &quot;In the Wasteland&quot;. I wrote it much more delicately. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first article in the new book &quot;Professor of Philosophy&quot; It is about a professor whose stepmother marries into the protagonist&#39;s family. I think the description of the psychology of the 18-year-old boy is quite detailed. How did you come up with that story? Does it have something to do with your experience when you were young, or was there a foreign professor like this in the local area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After thinking for a long time&lt; /span>;) I remember, it’s not the professor, it’s the Elvis Presley stereo! I wanted to buy a speaker at that time, and I was choosing it over and over again. Finally, I settled on a model made of Elvis Presley walnut wood, and I suddenly thought, if this speaker had a story, what would it be? In fact, that was just an introduction, and later in the novel the sound was completely forgotten. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now that I have a delicate awareness, I start writing Will it feel very different from before? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After having this awareness, I will be a little alert and a little anxious. But if I pursue one aspect too much, I will lose the other aspect. Writing still requires a balance. I can&#39;t throw too much here and too much there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You still cherish the benefits brought by your identity as a herdsman extensive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That style is a reality on the grassland. Its authenticity is particularly important, but it does not mean that there is no delicacy in the authenticity on the grassland. There is delicacy, but I have not fully learned it yet, so I will continue to learn, and when learning, I must balance the relationship between the two sides. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我国新增4处世界灌溉工程遗产]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259983]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Anhui Qimenyan Irrigation System, Jiangsu Hongze Ancient Irrigation District, Shanxi Huoquan Irrigation Project, Hubei Chong The Baini Ancient Weir in Yang County was successfully selected into the 2023 (tenth batch) World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List on the 4th. So far, my country&#39;s world irrigation engineering heritage has reached 34. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Ministry of Water Resources that the tenth batch of the World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List was announced at the 74th Executive Council of the International Commission on Irrigation and Drainage held in Visakhapatnam, India. Chen Mingzhong, chairman of China&#39;s National Irrigation and Drainage Commission and director of the Department of Rural Water Resources and Hydropower of the Ministry of Water Resources, said that my country&#39;s world irrigation engineering heritage covers almost all types of irrigation projects. It is the most abundant type of irrigation engineering heritage, the most widely distributed, and the most outstanding irrigation benefits. nation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qimenyan Irrigation System is located in Shucheng County, Anhui Province. It was first established in the Western Han Dynasty. It uses the form of wetlands to &quot;form canals and ponds for storage&quot; and has played an important role for more than two thousand years. It plays an important role in irrigation, flood control and drought prevention. It currently irrigates 200,000 acres of farmland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hongze Ancient Irrigation Area is located in Hongze District, Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province. It is a water storage irrigation area and consists of water storage, water intake, water transportation and drainage projects. Since the Eastern Han Dynasty, ancient people have diverted water for irrigation and farming. Water conservancy facilities have been built in the past dynasties, and the irrigation area continues to this day. Currently, the irrigation area controlled by the irrigation district is 481,300 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Huoquan Irrigation Project is located in Hongdong County, Shanxi Province. It has been clearly recorded since the Zhenguan period of the Tang Dynasty, and it still plays a role in irrigation, water supply, ecology, tourism and other functions. At present, the total irrigation area of ​​the project is 101,000 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Baini Ancient Weir is located in Chongyang County, Hubei Province, and includes two ancient weirs, Shijian Weir and Yuanpi Weir. According to literature, the ancient weir was first built in the Five Dynasties and the Later Tang Dynasty. It still plays a role in irrigation, flood control, drought resistance, water supply and other functions, with an irrigated area of ​​about 35,000 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List was established in 2014 to sort out the development of irrigation civilization in the world, promote the protection of irrigation engineering heritage, summarize the wisdom of traditional irrigation engineering water control, and provide historical experience and inspiration for sustainable irrigation development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that along with my country’s four heritage sites, there are 15 projects from India, Indonesia, Iraq, Japan, Thailand, Turkey and other countries that are included in the tenth batch of World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List. Currently, there are 159 irrigation engineering heritage items in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“海”中取粮]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259946]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/y4O4A33lBsLB3TRC9iI9iD6PgQUk9TK3l1GPwqIJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/y4O4A33lBsLB3TRC9iI9iD6Pg QUk9TK3l1GPwqIJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Researchers are building bird-proof nets for rice. During the grain-filling period of seawater rice, bird prevention is particularly important. Failure to take measures may result in no harvest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early morning As the sun just rose, Zhang Shuyin put on his sun hat, held a test record book in one hand, and a large-capacity water bag in the other, and got into the green rice waves, where he stayed all morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shuyin is a scientific researcher at the Qingdao Sea Rice Research and Development Center. He and six colleagues took root in the experimental field of about 100 acres at the National Southern Breeding Research and Breeding Base in Sanya. They stayed there for half a year. They were breeding in the experimental field. Nearly two thousand rice germplasm resources. For Zhang Shuyin and his colleagues, &quot;We touch and think about rice every day. Every variety in this field is like our child, and we cannot live without them for a day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hV72HFJ9duFfnIK5Or93SaqKjU5epYGrRWkGAosp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hV72HFJ9duFfnIK5Or93SaqKjU5epYGrRWkGAosp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Researchers Gu Xiaozhen (left) and Yin Huide (right) are taking field records, including rice growth, plant height, number of tillers, etc.&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;sea rice&quot;? Zhang Shuyin explained that literally, &quot;sea rice&quot; is rice related to sea water. It does not refer to rice that can grow in seawater, but to salt-alkali-tolerant rice that can be grown on coastal beaches and inland saline-alkali lands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CPxtRxs7AA4sFPt1oSQh8PRxf2sMpHtXFEDOE0Da.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CPxtRxs7AA4sFPt1oSQh8PRxf2sMpHtXFEDOE0Da.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scientific researcher Zhang Shuyin is replenishing water. The temperature in Sanya is high all year round, and scientific researchers have to carry large-capacity water bags every day &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Human beings have never stopped Challenge the dangerous natural environment. Planting &#39;sea rice&#39; on saline-alkali land is one of the ways.&quot; Zhang Shuyin introduced that the Qingdao Sea Rice Research and Development Center is headquartered in Qingdao. Since 2016, he and his colleagues have gone there every autumn. Sanya Nanfa will sow rice, and when the rice is mature and harvested in April or May of the following year, it will return to the headquarters with the high-quality salt-alkali tolerant rice varieties for further research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/JD0I9L3swqxxfMbqJNbRTh1jBivSrAYWsNMtRcAR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/JD0I9L3swqxxfMbqJNbRTh1jBivSrAYWsNMtRcAR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Nanfan Base, scientific researchers inspected rice fields, selected rice plants to conduct hybrid experiments, and manually threshed rice materials... day after day. &quot;Hainan can carry out experimental research on rice all year round, which can speed up the breeding process and shorten scientific research time by half.&quot; Zhang Shuyin said that when they cultivate a new rice variety, they need to undergo an average of eight updates to obtain a stable variety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/69zGhORE7gDfoStZOfXARtjxYxDd5xk88eaATqsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/69zGhORE7gDfoStZOfXARtjxYxDd5xk88eaATqsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yu Meng is walking in the muddy rice fields, one foot is deep and the other is shallow (&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Zhang Mao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Wan Jili, director of the Technology R&amp;D Department of Qingdao Sea Rice Research and Development Center, said, &quot;Currently, we have nearly 2,000 germplasm resources. The salt tolerance of the germplasm has also been continuously improved, from the initial 3‰. To the current 8‰.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DvLNQNmj2dlVcSV386QDR0ZE3wjAygAQa45iCEPb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DvLNQNmj2dlVcSV386QDR0ZE3wjAygAQa45iCEPb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256504&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Strong ears of hybrid rice. This shows that the hybridization test is successful and hybrids can be harvested from 2012 to 2022. The &quot;sea rice&quot; has developed from the scientific research and experimental stage to industrialization and large-scale promotion. As of the end of 2022, the planting area of ​​&quot;sea rice&quot; in my country has exceeded 1 million acres, and the varieties cover the four major types of typical saline-alkali lands across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Ry0MumwOXN7tZRQMN0ywoRbVvhXLh5sN5iThHsMu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Ry0MumwOXN7tZRQMN0ywoRbVvhXLh5sN5iThHsMu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Phoenix snails will cause harm almost throughout the entire growth period of rice&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;There are 1.5 billion acres of saline-alkali land in the country, of which 500 million acres are suitable for growing food, and the utilization potential is huge. In the near future, those saline-alkali lands that previously seemed “of little use” may become “regenerated fertile land.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/tHUXMLc8ErnYEhyMG4wPGyuPM7r3TUg8IJCxPVXn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/tHUXMLc8ErnYEhyMG4wPGyuPM7r3TUg8IJCxPVXn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256516&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rice breeding expert Yang Hanshu (right) leads scientific researchers to check the growth of rice and guides the breeding work&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/zor9FwWokvX43ONAFEcO9f2dpWiQwqz7sDgFL66d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/zor9FwWokvX43ONAFEcO9f2dpWiQwqz7sDgFL66d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scientific researchers are investigating rice seed production materials. The isolation film on the tree is to prevent pollen from secretly pollinating and &quot;exchanging&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2aTkg7ZtQzIGh0ZMjjDMTTNUqi3h2pUzPZtdjVL4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;546&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2aTkg7ZtQzIGh0ZMjjDMTTNUqi3h2pUzPZtdjVL4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scientific researcher Peng Nanxi Rice is being threshed. He uses a relatively primitive foot-operated thresher to facilitate cleaning and prevent seeds from being mixed &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Zhang Mao/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d8o2Pxve2K1vWdhNVZYHUm6gIJxmVkfozN8UTvng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d8o2Pxve2K1vWdhNVZYHUm6gIJxmVkfozN8UTvng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;Researchers turn on the adjusted proportion of seawater to irrigate rice&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DpftIXzh8QpHPXtENJBmdHBWuSHmR1nKKj26ZudD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DpftIXzh8QpHPXtENJBmdHBWuSHmR1nKKj26ZudD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Harvest for scientific researchers of different rice seeds. Every bag of seeds may hide good varieties &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/U0Lp7Nf0B8wssfiiGjCmLOVOQBRd00FYdYFvjuHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/01/U0Lp7Nf0B8wssfiiGjCmLOVOQBRd00FYdYFvjuHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yazhou, Sanya City, Hainan Province District National Salt-Alkali Tolerant Rice Technology Innovation Center Sea Rice Experimental Base&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[广东恩平4.3级地震，广东省地震局：已发生余震5次]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259985]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 21:47:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the official measurement of the China Seismological Network, at 19:24 on November 4, in Enping City, Jiangmen City, Guangdong Province (22.08 degrees north latitude, 112.25 degrees east longitude) A magnitude 4.3 earthquake occurred with a focal depth of 8 kilometers. The epicenter was located near Dahuai Town, Enping City, Jiangmen City, Guangdong Province, 3 kilometers away from the People&#39;s Government of Dahuai Town, Enping City, Jiangmen City, 13 kilometers away from the urban area of ​​Enping City, Jiangmen City, 37 kilometers away from the urban area of ​​Yangjiang City, and 156 kilometers away from Guangzhou City. As of 20:00, a total of 5 aftershocks had occurred, with the largest aftershock measuring 1.3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the earthquake was felt strongly in Enping City, Jiangmen City, and in Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Macau, Hong Kong, Dongguan, Foshan, Yangjiang, Zhanjiang, Maoming, Zhongshan, and Zhuhai. No reports of casualties or property damage have been received yet, and the mood of the local people is stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the earthquake, the Provincial Seismological Bureau launched a Level III emergency response and sent an earthquake field team (8 people) with the Guangzhou Earthquake Monitoring Center Station to Enping City to understand the earthquake situation and carry out intensive observations. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This earthquake is about 1 km away from the Cangcheng-Hailing Fault. Within 100 kilometers of the epicenter, there has been one earthquake of magnitude 5 or above. The largest earthquake occurred in Yangjiang, Guangdong on July 26, 1969. A magnitude 6.4 earthquake (63 kilometers away from the epicenter). Since 1970, the largest earthquake was the 4.0-magnitude earthquake in Enping City, Jiangmen City, Guangdong Province on September 18, 1989 (7 kilometers away from the epicenter). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the earthquake, the Provincial Seismological Bureau immediately launched a joint consultation with the China Seismological Network Center via video link. Based on the analysis of regional structure, historical seismic activity, and earthquake sequence types, it is believed that the original earthquake area of ​​this earthquake is unlikely to have a larger earthquake in recent days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>