<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[明月与乌皮靴：探寻“光影世界”之外的李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/28/a8b47c1659.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 28/a8b47c1659.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bright moon is a classic image in Li Bai&#39;s poems. The picture shows Li Bai under the moon in the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On the screen, Li Bai was pardoned and released, and he was walking on a pole on the Yangtze River. With his temples completely white, he finished chanting &quot;Apes on Both Sides of the Strait&quot; I can&#39;t stop crying, the boat has passed the Ten Thousand Mountains.&quot; When he was excited, he raised his hand and threw the long pole into the water. In the cinema, children happily recited the poems and adults shed tears. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2023, an animated film &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot; will follow the &quot;National Treasure Season 2&quot; and &quot;Chang&#39;an Ten Thousand Miles&quot; in previous years. Programs such as &quot;Two Hours&quot; once again put Li Bai&#39;s name on the hot search list. Different types of games such as &quot;Hundred Scenes of Jiangnan&quot;, &quot;Glory of Kings&quot; and &quot;Ink Soul&quot; have all invited Li Bai into their own world. Dramas, operas, dance dramas, musicals, and Cantonese operas all use Li Bai as the protagonist, summoning the soul of more than 1,300 years ago in the theater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1283&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bronze statue of Li Bai in Taibai Hall, Sichuan, by Li Xiangqun. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if he put on black leather boots and entered the court, Li Bai still could not unfold his arms throughout his life. He endlessly expressed in his poems Chanting, &quot;If I don&#39;t look toward the east mountain for a long time, the roses will bloom several times. The white clouds will disperse on their own, and who will the bright moon fall on?&quot; Xie An&#39;s seclusion in Dongshan after his achievements made Li Bai fall in love, and &quot;Ming Yue&quot; became the embodiment of the ideal that Li Bai pursued throughout his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Two years before his death, Li Bai met a Shu monk in Jiangxia, who was about to go to Chang&#39;an. Li Bai wrote, &quot;The moon of Mount Emei returns to you, and the wind blows west to Chang&#39;an. The Chang&#39;an Avenue spans nine days, and the moon of Mount Emei shines on Qinchuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai himself resumed his status as a commoner and never went to Chang&#39;an again, just like he left his hometown of Jiangyou, Sichuan when he was 24 years old and never returned in his life. In October 2023, Southern Weekend reporters revisited the two places to explore his wanderings between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9610ad4dd1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9610ad4dd1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259843&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Want to go up to the sky and embrace the bright moon&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was 20 years old, he and another writer Zhang Shuo were known as &quot; Su Ting, who was &quot;extremely generous&quot;, went to Chengdu to take up his post. Li Bai took the opportunity to visit him on the way with his poems. Su Ting admired the young man in front of him very much, and said to his staff: &quot;This young scholar has outstanding talent, and his writing style is like a flowing river. Although his current writing is not strong enough, he already has a unique style. If he continues to grow His knowledge will definitely be comparable to that of Sima Xiangru in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Perhaps Li Bai did not expect that this was already the most glorious visit in his life. In the next twenty-two years, he experienced various failures and setbacks in &quot;every prince&quot; and &quot;experienced ministers&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 730, Li Bai first came to Chang&#39;an. He lived in Princess Yuzhen&#39;s villa in Zhongnan Mountain, and also visited other princes and ministers, but to no avail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 734, he passed by Xiangyang, visited Han Chaozong and handed him the &quot;Book of Jingzhou with Han&quot;. Han Chaozong was known as a good scholar, but he was indifferent to Li Bai&#39;s request for recommendation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1120f704f1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1120f704f1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259844&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot;, the wandering Li Bai recited &quot;Quiet Night Thoughts&quot; under the moon. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Throughout his life, Li Bai never participated in the imperial examination, which was an extremely rare phenomenon among literati in the Tang Dynasty. One voice thinks that Li Bai disdains to participate, while the other is that Li Bai cannot participate. &lt;p>; qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Contemporary scholars such as Professor Lang Baoru of Inner Mongolia University interpret that even if it is not a &quot;family of industry and commerce&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s family &quot;hidden back to Guanghan in the early days of Shenlong&quot; and was not in the Ministry of Household Affairs Registration, no genealogy. Xiang Gong needs to provide documents that can prove his family background and identity, such as household registration and genealogy, for review by the Ministry of Household Affairs. People with &quot;unknown origins&quot; like Li Bai were naturally not eligible to be selected as tribute candidates by prefectures and counties and take part in the imperial examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai can only realize his ambition through other ways. &quot;Roaming in the mountains and rivers, living in seclusion to study Taoism, making friends with Taoist priests, paying homage to local governors and ministers of the government and the public, all with the purpose of raising one&#39;s worth and creating a sensational effect in becoming famous in the capital and the emperor, and only then was Tianbao summoned to the capital.&quot; Chongqing Xiong Du, a professor at Technology and Business University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taoism was respected in the Tang Dynasty, and the royal family regarded Laozi and Li Er as their ancestors. During the Xuanzong period, respect for Laozi and Taoism reached its peak. From the emperor to his relatives, nobles and bureaucrats, everyone believed in Taoism. Xuanzong&#39;s two younger sisters, Princess Jinxian and Princess Yuzhen, simply became female Taoists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the age of 5, Li Bai lived in Changlong County, Mianzhou, central Sichuan (now Jiangyou City, Sichuan Province) for 19 years. As the birthplace of the Five Pecks of Rice Taoism, Shu Taoism is very popular and there are caves and heavens all over it. According to legend, Zhang Daoling, the founder of the sect, once lived in seclusion in Heming Mountain and preached in Qingcheng Mountain. There is still a Jinguang Cave in Qianyuan Mountain in Jiangyou, which is said to be the place where Nezha became a disciple and practiced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai was immersed in the atmosphere of Taoism. He visited famous Taoist mountains such as Mount Emei, Daitian Mountain, and Ziyun Mountain, and made many unique friends. He once lived in seclusion in the south of Minshan Mountain with Dong Yanzi, raised many birds, and learned the art of calling birds to his palm. Yuan Danqiu later became his best Taoist friend throughout his life, and invited him to visit Taoism in Songshan Mountain several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have traveled to the gods for fifteen years, and they have never stopped traveling. ... The jade boy in Xishan made me refine gold bones.&quot; &quot;Alchemy bones&quot; means refining elixirs. It seems that Li Bai was deeply influenced by Taoism at the age of fifteen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In traditional Chinese philosophy, Taoism is the philosophical category with the deepest exploration of the universe.&quot; Both Ding Ying and her father had an indissoluble bond with Li Bai. The father and daughter successively served as the director of the Li Bai Memorial Hall. She analyzed to the Southern Weekend reporter that Li Bai and Su Shi were both from Sichuan, and their poems were full of elegant and romantic atmosphere. &quot;We are in a basin, and it is difficult to get out. The only exit is the sky. Sichuan people have developed the habit of using their own brains to make up for the reality, so they all have magnificent imaginations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Modern people are no longer sure of the specific locations of the fairy mountains in Li Bai&#39;s works, but they may as well pay tribute and commemorate his enthusiasm. Today, there are more than 20 scenic spots in Jiangyou related to Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/bbdf37ed70.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/bbdf37ed70.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of young Li Bai in front of Longfeng Hall. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown in Qinglian Town, also known as Longxi Courtyard, has a colorful sculpture mountain gate screen wall and a courtyard left over from the Qianlong period of the Qing Dynasty. Residential. The Longfeng Hall, built in 2003, enshrines Li Er, the founder of Taoism, Li Guang, the general of the Western Han Dynasty, and Li Hao, the king of Xiliang in the Northern Dynasty - the latter two are ancestors jointly recognized by Li Bai and the Li Tang family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ef7f9cab54.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ef7f9cab54.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259846&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house in Li Bai’s hometown was rebuilt in the 53rd year of Qianlong’s reign in the Qing Dynasty (1788). Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​kilometer away from Longxi Hospital, there is a Taibai Temple. Wen Zaiqiao, director of Li Bai’s hometown, works here. He likes the tranquility here. . He mentioned to Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, when worship was allowed, before the Mid-Autumn Festival every year, Guangdong businessmen would often come to the ancestral hall with their families and ask Taoist priests to perform rituals for three days. &quot;Li Bai likes the moon.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai never left Taoism throughout his life. However, there were many motivations for learning Taoism. Taoism&#39;s pursuit of freedom and eternity in individual life is exactly in line with Li Bai&#39;s pursuit of a spiritual state of indulgence and freedom. When he was politically frustrated, Li Bai often turned to mountains and rivers and wandering immortals. Taoism undoubtedly gave him spiritual comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The subtle relationship between studying Taoism and seeking official positions is much more secret. While the Tang Dynasty implemented the imperial examination system, it also recruited secluded wise men from time to time, asking them about political affairs, or asking them to come out to assist the king. Many of these people were Taoists. Xiong Du discovered that, compared with the strict scrutiny of family background in the imperial examination, talents specially ordered by the emperor could escape this rule. For example, Taoist celebrities such as Zhang Guo and Ye Fashan, who were rumored to have the secret of immortality, were recruited by the emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also speculated that the reason why Li Bai was good at immortal Taoism may be related to this, &quot;It is to create for Xuanzong that he not only has the talent of Wang Zuo who knows the world, but also is You really have the impression of being an &#39;immortal&#39; with an &#39;immortal spirit&#39;, so that you can avoid the trouble of tracing your family background and place of origin when you join the officialdom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spirit of taking off your boots is still in your sleeves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Night shrouds Xi&#39;an, and the lights of the &quot;Datang Everlasting City&quot; commercial street at the foot of the Big Wild Goose Pagoda come on. &quot;Prosperity of the Tang Dynasty&quot; performances are being performed all over the street. Amidst the loud drum music, &quot;Li Bai&quot; dressed in white clothes slowly rises from the rotating lanterns. Every night, this NPC (non-player character) will come here to exchange poems with tourists, &quot;Everyone, come and listen to this one again, the most difficult one among Taibai poems.&quot; What he throws out is &quot;Thoughts on a Quiet Night.&quot; There is also a &quot;Li Bai&quot; in Xi&#39;an. In the &quot;Twelve Hours of Chang&#39;an&quot; theme district, a certain liquor company has built a Taibai wine shop. He holds a wine bowl and invites tourists sitting at the table to drink with him while reciting &quot;The wine will come in&quot;. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Datang West Market Museum, a middle-aged lady who came with a group from Anhui told a Southern Weekend reporter that she observed that people traveling to Xi&#39;an pay attention to The most popular ones are the Terracotta Warriors and Horses, and the current recommendation is Li Yang’s Love.” Her tour guide, Xiao Liu, a native of Xi&#39;an, talked about Li Bai twice in the museum, &quot;casually&quot;. He admitted that he didn&#39;t know Li Bai at all before working, and he had relatively little contact with him after working. Except for a few tourists who like history, most of them People are similar to themselves, &quot;After watching &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, I understand a little bit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai actually did not have a fixed residence in the Tang Dynasty. He neither bought a house, nor was it found in relevant documents that he rented it. So like Bai Juyi, as his official position rose, his residence was from the south of the city to the imperial city, so the status level determines the level of wealth.&quot; Mao Jingru, education specialist of Xi&#39;an Museum, told Southern Weekend reporters that in history, &quot;Chang&#39;an It is not a place where he (Li Bai) has lived for a long time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 742, Li Bai received Xuanzong&#39;s order to enter Chang&#39;an. During the Sui and Tang Dynasties, some northern Hu people&#39;s clothing became popular in society, including the &quot;black leather Liuhe boots&quot; worn by the Hu people. Later, the official officially designated it as the standard wear for officials, which is quite similar to the black leather shoes commonly worn in modern formal occasions. When he first arrived in Chang&#39;an, Li Bai was still wearing the white linen clothes that symbolized the common people. This time, he changed into a round-neck robe and black leather boots and entered the capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai wrote &quot;Nanling Farewell Children Entering Beijing&quot; before leaving, &quot;It&#39;s not early to persuade the children to endure the hardships, and ride the whip on the horse for the long journey. ...Looking up to the sky and laughing out loud &quot;How can I be a Penghao person?&quot; Years of depression were relieved, and the ideal of displaying talents and strategies was given the opportunity to be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he had the ambition of &quot;lobbying thousands of people&quot;, and the position he was awarded was Hanlin enshrinement, or Hanlin waiting for the imperial edict. Unlike Hanlin scholars who are in charge of edicts and participate in political affairs, Hanlin ministers are a group of professionals in various fields who stay by the emperor&#39;s side to serve him. They had the opportunity to have real positions after being favored by the emperor. For example, Wang Shuwen, who was good at playing chess, and Wang Qian, who was proficient in calligraphy, waited for the imperial edict, were appreciated by Dezong, and served as attendant readers and calligraphers, and were promoted step by step. However, Li Bai entered the Imperial Academy with poetry and prose as his skills, and he always stayed in the position of a literary attendant and never entered the formal bureaucratic ranks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As time passed, Li Bai, who was living in the Hanlin Academy, found that his political ideals were becoming disillusioned. &quot;It&#39;s easy for blue flies to get together, but it&#39;s hard for white snow to harmonize with each other. It&#39;s meant to be dispersed,&quot; he said. People have repeatedly criticized others and promoted criticism.&quot; Not only could they not be reused, they were also slandered and ostracized by others. Opportunities that once seemed close at hand are actually out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/895515d194.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/895515d194.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259847&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai once lamented in a poem that &quot;the road is difficult and divergent&quot;, but then he wrote, &quot;There will be long winds and waves, and the clouds and sails will rise across the sea.&quot; &quot;. The picture shows a still from the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an 30,000 Miles&quot;. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yangbing&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Thatched Cottage Collection&quot; and Liu Quanbai&#39;s &quot;Li Junjie Ji&quot; both pointed out that there were more than one or two people who slandered Li Bai. Wei Hao&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; names the slanderers: Xuanzong once intended to appoint Li Bai as Zhongshu Sheren, but he was slandered by his consort, Zhang Shuo&#39;s son Zhang Bian, and it was not realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, Li Bai&#39;s own political limitations are gradually being valued and emphasized. Zeng Yueyu and Zhou Shi described Li Bai&#39;s incompetent official performance in the novel &quot;Li Bai Trilogy&quot;: &quot;Li Bai has drafted several official edicts, which are related to the recent personnel changes in the DPRK. Logically, before the official announcement, the content must be strict Keep it secret. Li Bai, who was drunk, didn&#39;t care about that at all. He took advantage of the drunkenness to use the internal information as oral news, spreading it around regardless of occasion or location.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;There is no way to verify whether Li Bai ever drafted official documents, and the degree of leakage may not be as exaggerated as described, but there is evidence for such writing. Fan Chuanzheng, who wrote the inscription for Li Bai, said that he &quot;went in and out of the province while drunk, and had to talk about the greenhouse trees.&quot; Wang Qi of the Qing Dynasty also suspected that he &quot;had leaked the secrets of the ban while drunk, and the Ming Emperor ignored it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Fangmin, a professor at Northwest University, researched based on Li Zhao&#39;s &quot;Hanlin Chronicles&quot; that the Hanlin Academy in the Tang Dynasty had particularly strict requirements on work style. Any carelessness in words or deeds would be punished. It may ruin the political future. He concluded that those who served in the Hanlin Academy would be more cautious than bureaucrats in other institutions. He also discovered that Xuanzong himself had personal experience of the harm of drunkenness and had abstained from alcohol for the rest of his life. Therefore, Li Bai&#39;s addiction to drinking could not help but make Xuanzong worry about appointing him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For Li Bai, returning from the political center frustrated, being slandered and alienated can be said to be his true feelings at that time. However, due to his personality and officialdom Political alienation and conflicts led to another reason for his political failure, which was also obscured to some extent. In the final analysis, Li Bai&#39;s frustration in waiting for imperial edicts was the political failure of a talented poet.&quot; Li Fangmin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xuanzong, who once &quot;gave food on a bed of seven treasures and a spoon in his hand&quot;, gave the poet a grand courtesy, but whether he would let Li Bai participate in politics must be marked by a question mark. In Duan Chengshi&#39;s &quot;Youyang Zazu&quot;, Xuanzong said to Gao Lishi, &quot;This man is really poor.&quot; Meng Qi&#39;s &quot;Benshi Shi&quot; records that Xuanzong &quot;used it as a non-corridor temple vessel, so he dismissed it with an imperial edict.&quot; Everyone is saying that Li Bai left an impression on Xuanzong, and that this person was not worthy of elegance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The discord between Li Bai&#39;s celebrity temperament and officialdom is concentrated in the matter of &quot;taking off his boots&quot;. Academic circles have different opinions on whether Li Bai ever asked Gao Lishi to take off his boots. Some scholars regard it as a novelist&#39;s statement and cannot be trusted. Zhou Xunchu, a professor at Nanjing University, believes that although Gao Lishi was the most favored eunuch by Xuanzong, under normal circumstances, Li Bai would not have ordered him to take off his boots. However, &quot;Li Bai was wild in nature and was drunk, so there was no clear reason to exclude this matter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The movie &quot;The Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; combines the two anecdotes of Lishi taking off his boots and writing &quot;Qing Ping Tiao&quot;. Gao Lishi asked Li Bai to compose a poem for Yang Yuhuan, and Li Bai took off his boots. After two rounds of fighting, Gao Lishi reluctantly took off a black leather boot for Li Bai. Li Bai was half drunk and half awake while writing &quot;Qing Ping Diao&quot;, which was praised by Yang Yuhuan, but Li Bai bluntly said that he did not write it specifically for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Tang Dynasty is really amazing if you have you.&quot; In the movie, Yang Yuhuan appreciates this sincerity. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The moon shines on Qinchuan on Mount Emei&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 744, on a spring night in Chang&#39;an City where flowers were blooming, Li Bai drank wine alone. There was no one around, but he was determined not to drink the contents of the cup quietly, so he sang and danced wildly, inviting the bright moon in the sky and the lonely shadow on the ground to drink together. He wants to get drunk, and then heaven, earth, and himself will cease to exist, and everything that is not going as he wants will be annihilated. At this time, it was less than two years since Li Bai was waiting for imperial edict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On an autumn night half a year ago&lt;/span>;, he was slandered and shunned in the officialdom, and his ambitions were difficult to realize. The frustrated Li Bai thought of the moon in his hometown: &quot; The dim clouds are falling, and the love of the past is dim. The green rose moon on the autumn mountain, who will see it tonight?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Finally, he left Chang&#39;an, leaving only Read such masterpieces as &quot;Drinking Alone Under the Moon&quot; and &quot;Wine to Ask the Moon&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, Li Bai had gone through two-thirds of his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;On the Nine Heavens of Chang&#39;an Palace, this place was once a close minister.&quot; Everything suddenly disappeared and became a memory. Li Bai&#39;s hope of finding a way out in the court was shattered, and he urgently needed to find spiritual sustenance. His deceased wife left behind a pair of children, but the time he spent with the children was far less than the amount of time he spent practicing Taoism in seclusion with the Taoist priests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Ziji Palace of the Taoist Temple in Jinan, Li Bai asked the Taoist priest Gao Rugui to teach him the Taoism and became a Taoist priest. From the time when Tianbao left Chang&#39;an in the late spring of the third year of Tianbao&#39;s reign, to when he traveled south to Wuyue in the fifth year of Tianbao&#39;s reign, this was the period when he was most worldly-minded. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Du Fu and Li Bai also met at this time. Du Fu experienced the blow of failing the imperial examination, and with a common depressing mood, he saw the depth and persistence behind Li Bai&#39;s wild and unrestrained attitude. &quot;We spend our days drinking and singing wildly, who is the hero of flying and domineering.&quot; This sympathy for each other continued in the lives of the two poets, even if they never met again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While wandering in the south, Li Bai kept witnessing the disappearance of old friends, and his mentality changed. When he arrived in Siming (now Shaoxing, Zhejiang), he paid homage to He Zhizhang, who died of illness here, and missed the years when they met in Chang&#39;an to exchange wine with each other. While in Jinling, another series of bad news came: his friend Cui Chengfu was demoted, Li Shizhi was forced to commit suicide, and Li Yong and Pei Dunfu were killed with a stick. Li Linfu, who was in power, was imprisoned many times, unjust cases appeared one after another, and the government and the public were filled with an atmosphere of terror. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai could no longer feel safe in seclusion. He often worried about the fate of the country, and his passion for serving the world deep in his heart burned again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He often expressed his longing to retire to the wild mountains and rivers, but whenever he had the opportunity, he always expressed his desire to return to the court immediately. He just couldn&#39;t get rid of going to the emperor&#39;s side. The ideal and desire to achieve great things,&quot; Ha Jin wrote in &quot;The Road to Heaven: The Biography of Li Bai.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After getting married for the second time in Liang Yuan, he went north to the land of Youyan, hoping to seek development by joining the army. In the poem presented to the judge He Changhao, Li Bai&#39;s intention is obvious. He is ashamed to be a scholar of Zhangju, and he is unwilling to be like Geng Yin. He actually wants to rise up with a sword and collect extraordinary achievements in the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On this trip north, Li Bai arrived at the jurisdiction of Anlu Mountain, and perhaps saw clearly the truth that the latter was preparing to rebel. Li Bai returned frustrated. He felt helpless against the internal and external troubles of the Li Tang Dynasty, so he could only seek seclusion in the south again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Besides studying Taoism, Li Bai, who has stars on his temples, is increasingly aware of the importance of one thing. &quot;Knowing what is wrong at fifty is what the ancients have done. If you make up for your mistakes with words, you will live forever.&quot; &quot;I am determined to delete the story and reflect it for thousands of years.&quot; He made it clear that there is no hope of meritorious service, and perhaps his destiny is to make words. It can also be said that Li Bai truly became aware of his identity as a poet when he was around fifty years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s first wandering ended with the scene of entering Chang&#39;an; the last wandering also had an event that brought it to an end, that is, joining the team of Yongwang Li Lin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, the Anshi Rebellion broke out, and people fled the war and were displaced. Wang Changling returned to his hometown, and when passing through Jianghuai, he was killed by the governor who hated him. Du Fu moved his family to Yanzhou for refuge. He heard that after Suzong ascended the throne in Lingwu, he went north to Lingwu and was captured by the rebels on the way and taken to Chang&#39;an. The poet Wang Wei was taken prisoner to Luoyang by the rebels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai and his wife Zong fled south to seek refuge and lived in seclusion in Lushan Mountain. He once planned to lobby the Li Tang clan in Jiangnan to raise troops to serve the king, and had dealings with both Xu Wang Yannian and Wu Wang Zhi. It happened that Yong Wang Li Lin raised his army and patrolled eastward to Xunyang. He repeatedly invited him to be an aide, and Li Bai finally agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is 56 years old and this is probably his last chance. This person with a complex of the Eastern Jin Dynasty feels that the old dream of the previous dynasty is right in front of him. At the end of the Jin Dynasty, the Five Husties disrupted China, and the Eastern Jin Dynasty established the country in Jinling, inheriting the lineage of the Central Plains. Will the Anshi Rebellion achieve Li Bai just like the Battle of Feishui in the previous dynasty achieved Xie An? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Fangmin understood that it was inevitable for Li Bai to join the Yongwang Li Lin. This move combined the objective situation and subjective wishes. He speculated that when Li Lin&#39;s lobbyist Wei Zichun was lobbying Li Bai, he hinted that Li Lin&#39;s actions in Jiangling and even on the eastward tour were in accordance with Xuanyuan&#39;s purpose and had the strategic purpose of managing Jiangnan. With these, he was able to impress Li Bai, who had an old love for Xuanzong as a monarch and a minister, and once again inspired his desire to help the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Lin was defeated, Li Bai was downgraded from a capital crime to a first-class crime, and was sentenced to Changliu Yelang. He set out from Xunyang, traveled to Dongting, and went up to the Three Gorges. When he first arrived in Wushan, he encountered a nationwide amnesty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, the counter-insurgency war was still going on. Not only was a large area of ​​land north of the Yellow River in Shi Siming&#39;s hands, but the rebels continued to invade the south. The situation was very serious. After wandering for thousands of miles, Li Bai once again had the idea of ​​​​serving the world. In Jiangxia, the political center of the south, while waiting for news about his friend Wei Liangzai in the capital, he went to visit some officials and waited for several months. , the imperial court showed no sign of conscription. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With no hope of meritorious service, Li Bai then thought of writing poems and speeches. &quot;Qu Ping&#39;s poems and poems hang over the sun and moon, and the Chu king&#39;s terrace is empty on the hills.&quot; He compared the two lives of Qu Yuan and the King of Chu: Qu Yuan was loyal and patriotic, but was exiled, but his poems and poems can compete with the sun and moon and are immortal through the ages; while the King of Chu The palaces, towers and pavilions built with extravagance and lust have long since disappeared, leaving nothing but desolate hills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai asked people to compile collections three times during his lifetime. Once he invited Duke Dongqian of the Han Dynasty, once he invited Wei Hao, and once he invited his clan uncle Li Yangbing. The end of Qian Gong&#39;s manuscript is unknown. Wei Hao followed Li Bai thousands of miles away, and the two became friends with each other. Li Bai gave him all the manuscripts at that time. Wei Hao was the editor chosen by Li Bai when he was in good health and thoughtful. However, the &quot;Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; he compiled for Li Bai were mostly fragments recovered from the Anshi Rebellion when &quot;all the chapters and sentences were exhausted&quot;. Li Bai was seriously ill in his later years and had no time to sort out the drafts. There was only one Li Yangbing around. Entrusting the poem manuscript to the pillow, there is no choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was 60 years old, he returned to Xunyang and climbed Mount Lu again, determined to spend the rest of his years traveling as an immortal and learning Taoism. However, he could not forget about the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he heard that Shi Chaoyi&#39;s power was back on the rise and Li Guangbi sent troops to suppress it, he resolutely asked Ying to participate, but he returned halfway due to illness. Li Bai is old. But the passion that had been ignited in him since his youth had never been extinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;His understanding of things, his political ideals and thinking have been like this throughout his life. He has established his ideas since he was young and implemented them. I think People like us would never know ourselves ten years ago, but from his youth to his old age, he maintained an innocent young heart.&quot; Ding Ying lamented to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 762, Emperor Daizong came to the throne, searched widely for talents, and granted Li Bai the official position of Zuo Shiyi. However, &quot;he was not born with a salary, but he was promoted to an official after he died.&quot; When the edict came, Li Bai had already passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are different opinions on the cause of Li Bai&#39;s death. &quot;Jumping into the river to catch the moon&quot; or &quot;riding a whale to catch the moon&quot; have always been talked about. Japanese sinologist Tomohisa Matsuura believes that these legends are sensitive to Li Bai&#39;s hobby. Li Bai unconditionally affirmed the existence of the moon and pursued the pursuit of becoming one with the bright moon. &lt;p>; There are earth-shattering articles.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A thousand years later, Gong Zizhen said in &quot;The Most Recorded Collection of Li Bai&quot;: &quot;Zhuang (Zhou) and Qu (Yuan) Shi cannot be combined. Combine it with your heart and start from the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d4e35e8ee3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d4e35e8ee3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 259848&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown Taibai Stele Forest contains mainly Li Bai&#39;s poems written by famous calligraphers and painters of past dynasties and couplets praising Li Bai. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Today&#39;s people don&#39;t see the ancient moon, but this month once illuminated the ancients.&quot; The moonlight of Mount Emei is spreading over Chang&#39;an Avenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探寻“光影世界”之外的李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261467]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 15:05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Animated movies, TV shows, games, dramas... various works have Li Bai as the protagonist, summoning more than 1,300 people The soul of years ago. Why do people talk about Li Bai in 2023?</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[滴滴“崩了”的12小时：损失千万订单量和超4亿成交额]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261466]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At around 10:30 a.m. on November 28, a Southern+ reporter discovered after testing Didi Travel App in Guangzhou , At present, Didi Chuxing&#39;s business, including online ride-hailing and shared bicycles, has returned to normal. However, this comprehensive functional paralysis lasted for nearly 12 hours, which is also the longest failure of Didi Chuxing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Didi Chuxing’s previously announced financial report for the third quarter of 2023, the total transaction volume of China’s travel business in a single quarter was 72.5 billion yuan, and the average daily order volume reached 31.3 million. With this “collapse” Calculating the duration of the failure, it is estimated that Didi will lose over 10 million orders and over 400 million transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As for the reason why Didi Chuxing App crashed for a long time, Didi Chuxing has not responded as of press time. However, judging from the system failure, some relevant people in the industry pointed out that the cause of the failure is likely to come from Didi’s own computer room network problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data shows that as a network service that requires extremely high response speed to data volume, the frequency of Didi Chuxing failures is not low. On September 22, 2022, users reported that Didi Chuxing could not be used normally. At that time, Didi Chuxing responded that &quot;due to a computer room network failure, some Didi services were affected.&quot; At that time, the failure had been repaired within half a year. On February 25, 2021, &quot;Didi crashed&quot; also appeared on the hot search. Didi Chuxing responded at the time that it was due to a &quot;system abnormality&quot; and the fault was quickly resolved. Earlier in October 2019, July 2016 and October 2015, Didi also experienced system failures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Didi Chuxing’s cloud services are mainly supported by Didi Cloud. According to Didi Cloud&#39;s official website, Didi Chuxing&#39;s cloud computing services are based on Didi Chuxing&#39;s business technology and experience accumulation. It adopts leading cloud computing architecture, high-specification server cluster construction, high-performance resource allocation mechanism, and refined operation model, and is committed to It provides developers with IT infrastructure cloud services that are simple, fast, efficient, stable, cost-effective, safe and reliable. According to Southern+ reporters, as early as March this year, Didi Cloud no longer provided public cloud services to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Have Didi ride-hailing and other services resumed? Reporter’s actual measurement: Still “paralyzed” in Guangzhou&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 28, according to Southern+ reporters’ experience in Guangzhou, relevant faults have not yet occurred. Completely solved, Didi Chuxing&#39;s online ride-hailing service still cannot accurately locate, and Qingju Bicycle cannot scan the QR code. &quot;The system is out of order, please try again later&quot; will be displayed in the App. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/634912d001c6227faf725b916fa85968.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1422&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/634912d001c6227faf725b916fa85968.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259865&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/739f6a430c50ca5b142bf1bef5b06fff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1422&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/739f6a430c50ca5b142bf1bef5b06fff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, Didi Chuxing told Southern+ reporters that it is &quot;very sorry&quot; for the inconvenience caused to users due to the failure of Didi Chuxing App, and is continuing to work hard to solve the problem. Please ask for travel during morning peak hours. Users pay attention to safety. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Didi Chuxing: Ride-hailing and other services have been restored, and cycling and other services are still being repaired&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 28, Didi Chuxing’s official Weibo posted that after the technical team repaired it overnight, Didi’s ride-hailing and other services have been restored. Cycling and other services are still being restored, and all Qingju vehicles that can be unlocked or unlocked can be ridden for free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8903bee1065a927825016b5e94b0bbff.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8903bee1065a927825016b5e94b0bbff.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259866&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[上班要不要强制穿工服，这是一个问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, &quot;Does your company require you to wear work clothes at work?&quot; Hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A netizen attended a class reunion. A total of ten people came. It turned out that three classmates who worked in different financial institutions were wearing almost identical work clothes. Nowadays, different units have different requirements for dress code. Some require employees to wear work clothes while others do not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This seems to be a small problem, but it is not. For example, in September, the U.S. Senate was in an uproar over whether members should wear formal attire when entering the Capitol. In the end, the U.S. Senate revised the dress code: allowing senators to wear casual attire such as hoodies and shorts. This move attracted criticism from mainstream media such as The New York Times and The Washington Post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Institutions, companies, and organizations around the world are faced with a multiple-choice question when it comes to employee attire: Should they uniformly dress? What are the considerations of whether to do it or not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/TQRExQi6pPp7lbrXzwLPQr6NFmeV6iqB9PvTA67a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/TQRExQi6pPp7lbrXzwLPQr6NFmeV6iqB9PvTA67a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Realistic Considerations of Uniform Dressing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;work clothes&quot; are actually people from the same institution or organization wearing uniform styles of clothing to identify them. identity, indicate their profession, and demonstrate their responsibilities. Generally speaking, work uniforms are uniform, rigorous, and depersonalized, and are distinguished from employees&#39; personal attire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From a company&#39;s perspective, employees often have practical considerations when wearing uniforms. First of all, this is a need to shape the corporate image. Employees are uniformly dressed and neatly organized, which will leave an initial impression that the company is rigorous, serious, and positive; uniform work uniforms generally have the company&#39;s logo on them, which can play a role in promoting the company&#39;s image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, for those positions that face customers directly and have more communication with customers, such as the financial industry and the lawyer industry, uniform attire of employees can bring customers A professional look and feel helps to dispel customers&#39; doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Furthermore, for workers, wearing uniform professional work clothes can play a role in psychological suggestion, help them enter the working state, and improve their work performance. execution ability. At the same time, wearing work clothes can also restrict the personal behavior of the staff, reminding him not only the personal image, but also the image of the unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are also some special occupations, uniformly pretending to reflect the authority and seriousness of the occupation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;比如我国对一些公权力机构提出了统一着装的要求，其中就包括公安部门、国家安全部门、司法部门、法院系统、检察院系统、 Customs systems, tax systems, national quality inspection departments, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In contrast, the reason why the US Senate relaxed the requirements for clothing was caused because public opinion was worried that this would harm the seriousness of Congress. The New York Times wrote like this: In the current division of the United States, one of the last harmonious signs of the Senate is the decoration specification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Although it cannot eliminate the profound differences under the surface, it does remind each senator that their goal is still the consensus of most people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are also some occupations unified dress, which is determined by the characteristics of the occupation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For example, the doctor&#39;s white coat is the earliest to promote the disinfection habits in surgery. The white coat also helps doctors to prevent static electricity during treatment. Many medical devices are very precise instruments. The effects of static electricity on equipment may mislead the results of diagnosis and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; When a doctor enters the operating room, he wore a blue or green surgical jacket, which has something to do with &quot;visual retention&quot;. During the surgery, when the doctor saw the patient&#39;s red blood, when he moved his eyes to the doctor&#39;s white robe, the phenomenon of &quot;color replenishment&quot; appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As long as the doctor looks at the red complementary color of the red-such as blue or green, it can immediately alleviate the role of &quot;color replenishment&quot; and slow visual fatigue, so surgery Most of the service will use blue -green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/28kkdyi9mv0KEF1GEF1GEF1Gen4exeibztev2.jpeg&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;720&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/28kkdyi9mv0KEF1GEF1GEF1GEF1Gen4exeibzxTev2.jpeg&quot; Data-Key = &quot;259824&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >; Relaxation requirements are not necessarily bad. &lt;/H4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some units and institutions require unified dress, with reasonable reasons, but this does not mean that uniform dressing is suitable for all all to all of all Units do not mean that uniform costumes are favorable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some people who have experienced the 1970s and 1980s may be impressed by the &quot;unified dress&quot; of that era. At that time, there was a name called &quot;law enforcement&quot;, and all a public unit would be uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the one hand, it reflects the sense of honor, &quot;there is a head&quot;; on the other hand, the work uniform is the &quot;invisible benefits&quot; of the unit, and some units take the staff The clothing all year round was packed, but the finances were paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So that some industries and personnel who did not have the functions of administrative management were also uniformly dressed, and they moved closer to the dressing of the law enforcement department. It has damaged the seriousness of the law enforcement department, wasted the finances, and also had a bad impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, starting from 1986, the State Council rectified the unified dress. In 1988, 1991, 1992, 2003, the State Council issued a unified dress issue. Related notices, criticizing those departments that uniformly uniform dressing, &quot;not only affect the seriousness of uniform dressing, but also lead to increasing fiscal expenditure.&quot; Later, the State Council also made clear stipulation on the unified dressing department and personnel. It can be seen that it is not uniform or good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unified dressing will bring constraints, stereotypes, and uncomfortable feelings to some professionals. Therefore, many employees opposed the unified dress. A British survey showed that 61%of the people looking for new jobs in 2017 said they would have a negative view of any company that executed the decoration specifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In order to fight monotonous uniform clothes, the Western workplace was born in the Western workplace. On the day, at least on this day, you can grasp the autonomy of dressing and be free to be yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another study shows that if the dressing requirements are easier, most British labor will feel higher efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Those big companies that pay attention to creative ideas often do not require employees&#39; dressing, such as Microsoft and Facebook. Although the employees may be different, such as the programmer loves a plaid shirt, Zuckerberg wore the same casual clothes every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; These technology companies not only do not require employees, they will also improve the work environment. Stimulate employees&#39; imagination and creativity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In short, it is difficult to generalize whether employees need to be unified. Some occupations emphasize seriousness, and some occupations value the perception that they bring to customers. Some occupations have special occupational attributes, and some occupations are more concerned about how to maximize the creativity ... Different demands are facing pretending to pretend to pretend to be pretending to be. There are different requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For the staff, the unified dressing problem is not so big, if the unit is free to send the work service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南开段峰：“拿着金饭碗讨饭”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261413]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In June 2022, Duan Feng’s team realized the interventional brain-computer interface in the sheep brain for the first time; a year later In May 2023, led by Duan Feng&#39;s team, the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army General Hospital (301 Hospital) and Shanghai Xinwei Medical Technology Co., Ltd. jointly completed the world&#39;s first &quot;non-human primate (monkey) interventional brain-machine&quot; &quot;Interface Test&quot; was a success. This research was considered by many media to have overcome the shortcomings of invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces and created the third new paradigm of brain-computer interfaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Feng, 46, is currently a professor, doctoral supervisor at Nankai University, and director of the Tianjin Key Laboratory of Interventional Brain-Computer and Intelligent Rehabilitation. Due to Duan Feng&#39;s outstanding achievements in the fields of brain-computer interfaces, artificial hibernation and intelligent aircraft, he was selected as Southern Weekend&#39;s 2023 Scientific and Technological Person of the Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the Southern Weekend Science and Technology Innovation Conference&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/298bbbf676.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/298bbbf676 .jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259781 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the southern weekend conference of science and technology innovation conferences &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of the China Academy of Communications, brain-computer interface (BCI) technology is a revolutionary human-computer interaction. Its mechanism of action is to bypass peripheral nerves and muscles and directly interact with the brain. Establish a new communication and control channel with external devices, which has the effect of monitoring, replacing, improving/restoring damaged or impaired natural central nervous system output and input. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a multidisciplinary cutting-edge technology that can not only assist in the diagnosis and treatment of some neurological diseases, partially or fully realize the compensation of certain human body functions, and is even expected to cure some mental diseases. Medical care is considered to be its most promising field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three main implementation methods of brain-computer interface, non-invasive, invasive and vascular intervention. The non-invasive brain-computer interface mainly refers to the collection of EEG signals in the cerebral cortex without surgery; the invasive type requires implanting electrodes deep into the brain, requiring surgeries such as craniotomy and bone drilling; the vascular interventional type mainly involves the electrode holder. Implanted into the corresponding inner wall of blood vessels to collect EEG signals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, most research on brain-computer interfaces is in the basic research stage, and some clinical results have also been achieved. In June 2022, researchers at Johns Hopkins University completed the world&#39;s first human trial of a bilaterally implanted brain-computer interface. A subject who had been paralyzed for 30 years successfully controlled machinery through EEG signals, completing Deliver cakes and eat independently; in China, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital launched brain-computer interface and deep brain stimulation methods in 2020 to treat refractory depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the participation of star companies such as Meta and Neuralink owned by &quot;Silicon Valley Iron Man&quot; Elon Musk, attention on brain-computer interfaces has been unprecedentedly high in recent years, and Duan Feng will also establish it in 2023 The company is trying to transform the results of brain-computer interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, since he returned to China after studying in Japan in 2009, he has been on the road of &quot;integration of industry, academia and research&quot; by focusing on teaching and research on one hand and entrepreneurship on the other. For this reason, he often stumbled. &quot;1 billion in 10 years, whether to do it or not&quot; has become his &quot;touchstone&quot; to test whether investors are sincere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Southern Weekend’s interview with Duan Feng:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Want to build an “industry-university-research integration” platform&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From an academic background, you received a bachelor&#39;s and master&#39;s degree from the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University, and studied precision mechanical engineering at the University of Tokyo, Japan, and received a master&#39;s and doctoral degree. degree, and chose medical rehabilitation equipment to start a business. Is it because you have always been interested in machinery? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>; When I took the college entrance examination in 1998, the major I wanted to study most was actually electronics. I filled out the application form and was transferred to the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University, where I majored in internal combustion engines and obtained postgraduate qualifications in my senior year. Studying in Japan is also an accidental choice. During my master&#39;s degree, my supervisor sent me to cooperate with two engine companies. At that time, the machinery industry was in recession, and one company went bankrupt. It was very embarrassing. At that time, I thought about changing careers and prepared to study abroad. It happened that the University of Tokyo in Japan not only waived the application fee, but also provided scholarships, round-trip air tickets and accommodation. The conditions were very good, so I chose precision manufacturing related to machinery among the majors they admitted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you later turn to brain-computer interface? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;I have studied intelligent service robots and unitized flexible production lines in Japan. My professional field has shifted from power machinery to robot control, and further Go to brain-computer interfaces. I first heard about the concept of brain-computer interface in a lecture at the University of Tokyo. I thought it was very interesting at the time, but I had limited energy and could not study it in depth. The biggest reason is that I want to copy Japan’s “industry-university-research” model in China. When I was studying in Japan, I encountered many companies that came to colleges and universities to invite students to dinner to identify talents, provide scholarships to students, and provide funds for scientific research projects to teachers to achieve the integration of &quot;industry, academia, and research.&quot; At that time, this model was relatively common in China. Rare. After graduation, I returned to China and entered Nankai University. After completing my teaching tasks, I could delve into the fields I was interested in, and then started to build a company to industrialize the research results. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you start your business at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;I learned about the market while teaching at the university. Specifically, it is to find companies to cooperate to develop things that are urgently needed by the market but there is still half a step in technology development. At that time, a friend introduced some assistive device products in cooperation with small medical device companies, which are types that rely on external force to move the limbs, but they are not independent movements. I hope to make devices that can be independently controlled by people to drive body movements, but I don’t want to sell products because it requires a series of issues such as device registration, quality inspection, and commercial promotion, so I anchored the technology research and development on the front end of the product. When I first returned to China, my monthly salary was only 3,800 yuan. After deducting 2,000 yuan for rent and 1,500 yuan for my children’s kindergarten tuition, I only had 300 yuan for living expenses every month. I think most entrepreneurs should have more money than me. Because I had no money, I had always pinned my hopes of raising money on finding partners or investors, so I took many detours and went through a process of company registration, cancellation, re-registration, and cancellation again. Many times it was dismantled. There was a difficult period when the east wall was repairing the west wall. At first, I considered making some small rehabilitation electrical stimulation equipment. A company talked to me about cooperation and asked me to do front-end research and development. It claimed that after the product was launched, the company would have its own sales channels. I believed it, but after finishing it, I found that this was not the case. Damn, there&#39;s nothing behind it. Some companies also asked me to invest in technology and promised equity. As a result, we advanced money, spent time, and invested a lot of energy. After the technology was formed, the &quot;partner&quot; ran away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to solve the entrepreneurial start-up fund? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;I earned it by selling technology. It is to help companies develop what they need and then sell it for money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Experiencing these things, the impact on you is What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;I am also reflecting and summarizing. Whether I am doing scientific research or doing industry, I just ask myself whether this is the case. If you really want to do what you want to do without anyone&#39;s help, then just do it. When I did not place my hopes on others and relied on my own efforts and persistence to do what I wanted to do, many people who helped me came to me on their own initiative. Some brought money, some brought resources, Others brought some new concepts and ideas, and gradually the matter became a success. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Among the people who took the initiative to find &quot; Liar&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When you have experienced some &quot;stepping into pitfalls&quot;, it will be easier to evaluate people&#39;s risks. Now come and talk to me. Yes, you can tell whether it is suitable or not in just a few minutes. I will not accept investment from others casually now. When someone comes to talk to me, I usually ask a question, &quot;1 billion in 10 years, do you want to do it?&quot; If you don&#39;t want to, then don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. In my case, if it works, it works, if it doesn’t work, it doesn’t work. There is no middle ground. This 1 billion is not just a thought, it is a scientific estimate. I do vascular interventional brain-computer interface experiments. Each electrode is ground out bit by bit by hand. It takes 10 days of grinding 24 hours a day to make one. The cost of consumables, labor costs, etc. in these 10 days add up. The total cost is at least 100,000 yuan; another example is the large animal monkey used for experiments. It costs 200,000 yuan to buy a monkey and 300 yuan to raise it for a day. This cost is very high. &quot;1 billion in 10 years&quot; is only used to test whether investors have the patience and sincerity to accompany the product&#39;s growth. It does not mean that someone must spend 1 billion. If the other party does not have a basic understanding of how much time it will take, how much money it will cost, and the possible return on investment, and they come and say that they are familiar with people from a certain local government and have connections in a certain park, they will talk about it with boastful words, or they will start talking about equity without saying anything. , we need to do due diligence, these are not the partners we would choose. We prefer to cooperate with people who have feelings and ideals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;No matter whether it is intrusive or non-intrusive, I am not optimistic about it&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Research on brain-computer interfaces has been very hot in recent years. What are the pros and cons of invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Non-invasive brain-computer interface is relatively safe because it is non-invasive. It mainly collects nerve discharge signals gathered on the surface of the scalp. Because this signal collection must be through the skull and layer of tissue cells, and there are more interference signals of the scalp, so the collected brain electrical signals are not very stable, collect some large large large, collect some large large large, collect some large large, and collect some large large. The action EEG signal is okay, but over time, or when it recognizes finer movements, it won&#39;t work. Invasive brain-computer interfaces implant electrodes into the brain by opening the skull. If you want to collect a certain signal, you need to implant electrodes into the corresponding brain area. Usually, within half a year, the signals collected through the invasive brain-computer interface are more accurate, and the effect of human-computer interaction is also better, such as controlling the robotic arm to grab objects, and the degree of completion is also relatively high. But it’s hard to tell after half a year, because the electrodes are harmful to the brain, may lead to rejection and suppuration, scar tissue can easily accumulate around the electrodes, and the circuits will also generate a certain amount of heat, which can easily cause inflammation, which is harmful to the human body. The damage is also relatively large. Therefore, its sustainability is very poor, and the EEG signals collected later will become weaker, or even no signals can be collected. This is also a fatal shortcoming of invasive brain-computer interfaces. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In September 2023, Neuralink’s invasive brain The machine interface has begun recruiting human clinical trial subjects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The intrusive approach will cause great harm, but there are still many companies to deal with. What is a person? Are they silicon-based organisms or carbon-based organisms? What are these electrode materials? People and these materials are fundamentally incompatible. I did an invasive brain-computer interface on mice, and all the mice died. The monkeys in Musk&#39;s previous experiments also died. This direction is problematic in terms of long-term safety. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why are you doing this &quot;world&#39;s first African &quot;Human primate (monkey) interventional brain-computer interface trial&quot;? How were the animal types selected and what was the testing process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;The trial&lt;span>; will be carried out starting in June 2022. It was originally to verify the feasibility of the interventional brain-computer interface. Although there have been some relevant reports internationally, whether they are true or false cannot be known until verification. In terms of details, such as verifying whether the sensor works and whether it can last for more than half a year in the animal&#39;s brain. For vascular interventional brain-computer interfaces, the blood vessels of animals that are too small, such as mice, are too thin for electrode wires to enter. Although the blood vessels of sheep are thinner than humans, they are relatively thick, and the price is also cheap. Basic movements can be distinguished. Come out; after the experiment is successful, we will test the monkey again, and let the monkey&#39;s active intention control the mechanical arm to grab food. Because monkeys are a species similar to humans, there will be no problem with it. Then we will feel more at ease when we do human experiments. . The overall process is rather tortuous. Finding partners and venues such as hospitals and laboratories is not a problem, because everyone knows that this is a very new research, and it will be easy to publish papers and get projects later, and it also has certain market prospects. The difficulty is that the early stage of this experiment was during the epidemic. Many engineers and students were often blocked and needed to find various ways to coordinate personnel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In January this year, the American Synchron company announced its The &quot;vascular interventional&quot; brain-computer interface clinical trial successfully allowed four paralyzed subjects to control external devices and complete operations such as texting and emailing, personal finance, and online shopping. How do you understand some media describing your research as &quot;creating the third new paradigm of brain-computer interface&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is recommended not to interpret it out of context. This &quot;pioneering&quot; and &quot;world&#39;s first&quot; should be viewed together. When I conduct experiments on sheep, I actually mean to create the third new paradigm of brain-computer interface in China, because no one in China has done relevant research; the world&#39;s first case means that I am the first person in the world to conduct experiments on monkey species. People who do this type of experiment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the success of this experiment, we will bring you What are the impacts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a mental point of view, it has no impact at all. I think it is very dull. According to our plan, this trial will soon enter the clinical stage, that is, it will be tested on humans, but it is still in the ethical review stage of the hospital. But I do get some emails from volunteers. What impressed me deeply was that there was a woman who wanted to save her husband who was lying in the ICU and hoped that her husband could participate in the clinical trial of brain-computer interface; there was also a grandson who wanted to save his grandmother, and the child wanted to be a volunteer; there was also a blind person Ask me to regain my sight... These letters are very touching, but our experimental ethics have not yet passed and we cannot recruit any subjects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some scholars believe that &quot;the development of brain-computer interface We are currently in a bottleneck period, and there is an urgent need for new principles and new technologies to drive research in related fields into the next period of rapid development.&quot; What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The current research on brain-computer interface technology is indeed in a bottleneck period. There are many problems about brain-computer interface. Global problems are not unique to China. Whether it is a non-invasive or invasive track, there are too many players. If they could achieve results, they would have been done long ago. There are too many smart people and many wealthy capital parties. At present, everyone is in a state of relative stagnation. To some extent, it shows that there is a problem with this road, and I suggest you consider changing the track. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Change track? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether it is invasive or non-invasive, I am not optimistic about it, because I have done it, and there are many domestic companies or institutions. Did. In China, the current focus of the industry is still non-invasive. Everyone is crowded onto this track and there is a traffic jam. But I don’t follow any industry. I am currently focusing on vascular interventional brain-computer interface technology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I hope more people can do research in a down-to-earth manner&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people are currently focusing on the industrialization of brain-computer interfaces in rehabilitation medicine. Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is a huge demand for patients in this field and the number of patients is also large. With some auxiliary equipment, partial or complete disablement of limbs can be achieved. Sports, so the market potential is relatively large. In addition, the technical process is not difficult, and some low-threshold products are relatively easy to make. As long as companies can raise funds and obtain corresponding certifications and licenses, they can quickly realize cash. If product prices drop further in the future, for example, a product worth 100,000 yuan becomes 20,000 yuan, then the demand will be even higher. There are two main chains in rehabilitation medicine, one is the innovation chain, and the other is the industrial chain. The industrial chain is to make high-end technologies low-end and turn them into products that are sinking. After sinking, they can be universally applicable to more people. After they are universally applicable to more people, there will be more data in scientific research, and there will be more After the data is collected, it is fed back to the innovation chain to form better technology and better products. What I am currently building is such a double-chain circulation platform. Therefore, we did not rush to make specific products, but calmed down and started working on the electrodes. After the electrode automation is completed, it can serve many products. My entrepreneurship was a relatively stupid situation, equivalent to begging for food with a golden rice bowl. The position I give myself is not to do specific, low-end, repetitive things, but to make the company a platform and a core system for brain-computer interface applications in rehabilitation medicine. This platform will also be open in the future. , allowing more people, companies, and institutions to do things together on this platform. As long as they don&#39;t fool me and want to do things down-to-earth, they are all welcome. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The current overall ecology of China&#39;s brain-computer interface industrialization What is it like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the concept of brain-computer interface is overheated at this stage, and some irresponsible media use gimmicks to gain attention. Change the concept. For example, the flashing pictures are actually brain electrical signals induced by vision, which is a conditioned response. However, in media reports, it is described as controlled by &quot;thoughts&quot;. It seems very fantasy, but it is actually very simple. As far as brain-computer interface companies are concerned, there are actually not many people who can really endure loneliness and do low-level R&amp;D, because low-level R&amp;D is too expensive and there is no cash return in the short term. I sincerely hope that more people in the industry are willing to do basic research in a down-to-earth manner. Today’s investors don’t blindly follow investments because they don’t have much money. Maybe because there are so many people speculating on concepts, there are not many people who really have the patience to accompany the growth of innovative companies. I am not willing to accept investment from such investors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, the domestic brain-computer interface corresponds to In product development, what are the urgent problems that need to be solved? What type of talent is most in short supply? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the ideal brain-computer interface product in the future should be realized through vascular intervention. In order to achieve this goal, it is urgently needed Solve the problem of electrode stability. After the stability is guaranteed, we can then find ways to realize automated production to reduce the cost of the product. Judging from the professional fields involved in talents, more cross-field and compound talents are needed. For example, there is overlap in at least two or more fields in materials, processing, machinery, circuits, medicine and other fields. The most important thing is that these people can calm down and do things in a down-to-earth manner. They will not go to this company where the salary is high today, or to make money in that field tomorrow. People without feelings cannot do good things. Under this premise, you must have good understanding and the ability to think independently and explore. Both are important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to brain-computer interface, you have other research Simultaneously? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We are currently also developing intelligent aircraft that can take off vertically and artificial hibernation of rats. In the future, we hope that artificial hibernation experiments can be combined with interventional brain-computer interfaces to use special stimulation signals through electrodes in blood vessels to affect the entire brain, or to modify the brain in this way to make people hibernate. This technology can be used in the future It is used in some medical treatment fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[风波过后，脱口秀行业复苏在望？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant -east-asian: normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-spie: normal; font-family: -apple-syster-font, blinkmacsyStyStmFont, &amp; quot; helvetica Next &amp;. quot ;, pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text -align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data-style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 18px;&quot;>;Open mic performance Sharp decline&amp;nbsp;Actors are looking for other opportunities&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; In May of this year, the talk show industry went through a series of rectifications. Among all cities, Shanghai has been most affected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Informed sources revealed to reporters that since the inventory operation in May , the cultural tourism department of Huangpu District, where most of Shanghai&#39;s talk show clubs are located, has strengthened supervision of performance content, and has become more rigorous in spot checks of performance videos every week. Actors must perform performances strictly in accordance with the approved content. If the performance video is inconsistent with the content submitted for approval, the performance organization will be fined 50,000-100,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This has led to two changes in Shanghai talk show performances. First, there are fewer individual performances or flagship shows for actors, because such performances require high content integrity and it is difficult for actors to delete passages; second, most clubs no longer hold &quot;open mic&quot; performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Open Mic&quot; is designed for new actors to practice as well as experienced actors Actors trial to talk about a new paragraph and open a talk show. Due to the unstable quality of the performance content, the open mic tickets in most clubs are relatively low, such as 19 yuan, 39 yuan, etc. Actors are not paid for speaking on the open mic. The main purpose is to polish the content and practice skills. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to the reporter’s understanding, the registration form for most open microphones is Actors submit their manuscripts in advance to the agency for approval, and then sign up one to two days before the performance based on their actual situation. Due to factors such as actors&#39; personal creative habits and time, the content and lineup of open mic performances are somewhat uncontrollable. It is common for actors to temporarily revise and adjust new jokes before going on stage or to be unable to go on stage due to unexpected circumstances and need to be replaced by other actors. Therefore, under the current cautious environment, most talk show clubs in Shanghai no longer hold such forms of talk show performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shanghai open mic performances dropped sharply, resulting in no new actors on stage Chances are, veteran actors are unable to update their creative content. Some full-time actors will choose to go to open mics in other cities to try out new jokes, and Hangzhou has become their first choice. &quot;Xie Haihan&quot;, the manager of Ersansan Talk Show Club, told reporters that four or five contracted actors in his club have chosen to develop in Hangzhou. Currently, there are at least 10 talk show clubs in Hangzhou. But this does not mean that actors can make money in Hangzhou, but that they are more &quot;famous&quot; in Hangzhou. &quot;Everyone is willing to go to Hangzhou, mostly because of the open mic. It is difficult to earn performance fees because the market is not that big now, which leads to oversupply.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259815&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space : normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;233 Talk Show Club host &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data -style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot; , Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;From increment to stock&amp;nbsp;Downside and up of the market&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans -serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;During interviews with reporters, many talk show practitioners mentioned Yes, in fact, the talk show market had been quietly declining even before the public controversy in May this year. The manager of a Shanghai talk show club told reporters that the current box office level of his club has returned to the state of 2017 and 2018. The number of weekly performances has been reduced to about 1/3 (when the performances were at its peak), and the attendance rate is almost the same. Cut in half. And this situation seems not only due to the industry earthquake half a year ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;233 manager &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot; told reporters , in the past two years, the club&#39;s box office has not shown an upward trend, so it began to expand its business to second- and third-tier cities such as Nanjing and Fuzhou. &quot;The size of the entire Shanghai (market) has actually reached its limit. If we want to increase our performance, we must either expand the city or increase the unit price. But now everyone&#39;s ticket prices are falling overall, so it is not particularly easy to raise (tickets). price), you can only expand the city.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He mentioned , the current number of performances in the club has not changed much, but the attendance rate has dropped significantly. &quot;An attendance rate of 60 to 70 percent is considered relatively high. Our theater used to be able to accommodate about 300 people, but now it is basically about 100 people, and there are 60 or 70 people. It is better on weekends. There may be 200 people.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; compared to Next, the box office situation of 233 Club in Fuzhou is relatively stable: &quot;Because the competition is not that big, there are only two (clubs) in the local area.&quot; Che Hongjun, the manager of Gao Xiao Comedy, told reporters, &quot;For some second and third tier For the city, they are not as many forms of entertainment as Shanghai and Beijing. The talk show is relatively fresh to over there. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline : 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMERIC: NORMAL; FONT-VARIANT-ASIAN: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-SPACE: Normal;-Apple-System-FONT , BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; quot; &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot; microsoft yah ei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; In the strong observation of the talk show actor, the golden period of the talk show market began in 2019:&quot; After the talk show variety show was broadcast, The talk show takes off online. &quot;In 2020, during the prevention and control of the new crown epidemic, all the performance industries were affected, and the talk show with a relatively small volume&quot; entered &quot;, seizing the share of other types of performance markets, plus the talk show variety show show The phenomenon -level explosion has helped the rapid growth of the offline performance. &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/27/6voahmxiiiu9rwaimcfxtNauyhgcsuwgkg2d9nmx.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 797 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.cms/med IAS/IMAGE/23/11/27 /6voahmxiui9rwaimcfxtNauyhgcsuwgkg2d9nmx.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259814 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; in: 16px; Outline: 0px; Font-Variant -NUMERIC: NORMAL; FONT-VARIANT-EAST-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-SPACE: NORMAL; FONT-FAMILY:-!! t, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; pingfang Sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Talking Show Actor strong. &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font- Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quotica N EUE &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans Gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; 1; 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In 2022, with the saturation of the market and the consumption of resources, the slump of talk show performance has begun to appear, and the industry has begun to usher in the bottleneck period. Hercules wrote in Xiaohongshu: &quot;Every year online program broadcasts, offline performance box office will have a significant rise, but this phenomenon is gone in 2022. It has not improved. It is not that the online program is not helpful for the box office. In fact, there are also, but at this time (talk show performance) The natural traffic of the box office is declining. The power is hedged. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; Laughing Comedy Manager Car In an interview with reporters, Hong Jun said that the current talk show market has almost no increase, and everyone is &quot;curling.&quot; Some clubs may start a &quot;price war&quot;, &quot;some brand prices have begun to explore 50, or even lower.&quot; But on the other hand, he still believes that &quot;this industry is upward&quot;, because &quot;everyone is also rolling quality, especially now more popular performances. The quality of the performance is very high. The tide is back, and everyone starts to fight the real knife. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; FONT-Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -apple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; The talk show actor also wrote in his little red book:&quot; In the future, the actor can no longer rely on the 15 -minute commercial performance paragraph. To a certain extent, this is a good thing. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; During the rapid growth of the industry, a large number of clubs and performers who only wanted to make fast money, eat dividends but did not pay attention to content, and saved a few actors to sell tickets to sell tickets. After seeing the online program, I didn&#39;t know the comedy itself. But in the cold environment today, with the withdrawal of this part of the people, after the industry experienced shuffling, it slowly entered a precipitation period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; A number of club the principals said in an interview with reporters. Because the overall box office is not good, they are more willing to leave the performance opportunities to actors with better content and stronger ticket ability. &quot;There may be a commercial performance opportunity when a actor&#39;s paragraph can reach thirty or forty. Now if you are less than sixty or seventy, your performance will be very small. Many people can no longer accept the performance. In the past two years, everyone At the wind, there will be no survival of the fittest. Now it is really difficult, but I think this is a way to go by a single (comedy). &quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data -style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot; , Arial, Sans-Serif; Letter-Spacing: normal; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); &quot;>; Where is the future? The necessary online traffic and healthy industry ecology &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font -Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family:-Apple-System-Font, BlinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; quot ;, pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino Sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-service: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible ; &quot;>; &lt;span>;&quot; I didn&#39;t take off six this year, but I once dreamed of myself, and the result was not very good. &quot;On November 3, Zhou Qimo, who had won the championship of a variety show of a part of the stall, posted such a Weibo. He imagined a period of his own experience of participating in the show and then being eliminated, and finally summarized: &quot;The root of the talk show is still offline.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; absent from online shows, completely returned to the next offline program. Is the talk show better? In the visits of reporters, almost every practitioner affirmed a point of view: the traffic of online programs is still necessary for the talk show industry, although online programs and offline performances are very different in creative creation. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Che Hongjun mentioned in an interview,&quot; The form of the form will be very internal consumption of actors. The 5 -minute volume is too small, and you need to rejoice with the audience quickly. The topic will be very limited. Traffic to help break the circle, because with the increasingly rich form of offline performances and entertainment, the art of talk show is facing more intense competition. &quot;Our competitors are not compete with talk shows. Our competitors are all popular entertainment methods: watching movies, KTV, short videos ... Everything is your competitors.&quot; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p Data -Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; Font-Variant-Numeric: Normal; Font-Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: normal; Fon T-Family: -padle- System-font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microS OFT YAHEI UI &amp; Quot ;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px ; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>;&quot; still requires the promotion of online traffic. &quot; Also agree with this view. Online programs can make the offline market do not drop too fast. If there is no traffic to promote it, it will be more bleak in the offline performance market of talk show. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-spie: n Oremal; FONT -Family:-Apple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica NEUE &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei UI &amp; Quot ;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, Sans-Serif; LINE-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In fact, many clubs and actors are trying to create online IP. The &quot;Smile Comedy&quot; club, initiated and established by Fudan University&#39;s &quot;Dankou Comedy Society&quot;, made its own variety show &quot;Dankou Comedy Comedy&quot; and was broadcast on station B in October; many clubs insist on making podcast programs to perform product publicity And maintain the stickiness of fans, such as &quot;No jokes&quot; of owl comedy, &quot;Hey Talk&quot; of the comedy box country, and &quot;Three words&quot; of Ji San San; more actors are trying to use self -media to create personal IPs and help Offline tickets. But most people have not been able to achieve stable commercial conversion online. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/no32MZOTGMH9SPBSPBSPBSNOPC5DP.jpg&quot; Border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1066 &quot;height =&quot; 1442 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/no32mzotgmh9sap3x4dspbsouuP.jpg &quot;Data-key = &quot;259817&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Smile Comedy&quot; Club self -made Variety Show &quot;Dankou Comedy Comedy&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/qcmadcyt2b6lehhinnxjclb8fjsvtwq1eg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 606 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/qcmadcyt2b6lehhinnxjclb8fjsvtwq1eg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259813 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Comedy Union Box Country&quot; actor Offline performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; From the perspective of the industry ecology, the domestic talk show The industry has risen and developed with the popularization and development of related variety shows such as &quot;Tonight Tonight Talk Show&quot;, &quot;Tucao Conference&quot;, and &quot;talk show conference&quot;. When a industry system, the rising channel of the practitioners, the deep binding of a company, a program, there will inevitably be a great risk -the fact has also proved this. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aqfcdtjrki4imcojvi6cax5hxjemyqruueb.jpg&quot; border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1620 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aqfcdtjrki4imcojvi6caxm5hxjemyqrtwcuueb.jpg &quot;data-key = &quot;259816&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Tonight Tonight Talk Show 》. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; A talk show actor said in an interview with reporters, Compared to the emergence of the next explosive program, she hopes that the industry can usher in a healthy ecology: &quot;Different companies can bloom all flowers, have mutual competition, and cooperate with each other. Either actors who have a hand or show (online IP), just like other industries. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武汉市卫健委：暂停武汉普仁医院出生医学证明签发资格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261446]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 11:13:23 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 28, the Wuhan Health and Health Committee of Hubei Province issued a notice, which is reflected in Wuhan Pure Hospital reflected by netizens. In the case of surrogacy and Wuhan Ruibo Xiang Judicial Appraisal, the Wuhan Health and Health Commission, in conjunction with the public security and judicial departments, and the appraisal agencies, the Wuhan Municipal Health and Health Committee conducted investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the qualifications for issuance of medical certification in Wuhan Puren Hospital have been suspended to conduct a special inspection of the hospital&#39;s maternity services and the application of birth medical certificates. The Wuhan Ruiboxiang Forensic Appraisal Institute has been instructed to stop its forensic appraisal business and accept investigation and handling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Next, the Wuhan Health and Health Committee will be held accountable seriously in accordance with laws and regulations in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在巴黎十年被抢近50次：移民导致社会治安恶化，法国社会治理失败]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261430]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recent Second-rate. Why bring a decimal number? Because she was robbed three times, she took it back, so it was only half a time, which means that it was actually 49 times. It&#39;s amazing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Relatives and friends in the diplomatic mouth, studied and worked in Paris in the mid -1990s. After retiring, I re -swimming in Europe. I feel that in 30 years, the changes in France can be regarded as people and not: Paris&#39;s urban appearance and infrastructure have not changed much. However, the composition of residents has changed a lot, and the social atmosphere and cultural customs are very different from 30 years ago. The personal feelings of relatives and friends and women&#39;s Internet celebrities are quite different: As immigration increases, France&#39;s law and order worsen significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reason for the high crime rate of immigration: There are many immigrants from Africa from France. Due to the different religious beliefs, cultural traditions, and customs, these immigrants and their descendants in education have made their social status and economy. The status is at a lower level. I long for the wealthy material life in Europe, but it is difficult to support in terms of economy, which will of course lead to an increase in illegal crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A large number of immigrants and illegal immigrants poured into France, which is the reverse sequelae of &quot;colonialism&quot;. It can be said that France is being reverse colonial. In the early 17th to 20th centuries, France occupied a large number of colonies in Africa, becoming the second largest colonial empire in the world after the United Kingdom. Two World War has caused the French population to lose huge losses. In order to make up for the lack of troops, France recruited hundreds of thousands of local young people from colonial French Africa to participate in the French army and fight against Germany. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the war, a large number of colonial soldiers remained in France and became early immigrants. The French film &quot;INDIGènes&quot; has a vivid description. Many black soldiers ask: We fight for France, why can&#39;t we stay here? Ask the French government and the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through these early immigrants, their relatives and friends in Africa learned the development and wealth of France. A large number of follow -up immigrants and illegal immigrants continued to influx. Official data: At present, there are more than 8 million blacks in France. Considering illegal immigrants, the actual number may reach 10 million, accounting for 15%of the 66 million total population in France. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The changes in the population structure have greatly changed the traditional French religious belief, cultural concepts, and living customs, intensified ideological conflicts, and brought increased crime rate, social turmoil, and both ethnic groups and classes. Street demonstrations protest, smashing and burning, becoming a commonplace for more than ten years, which can be called a wonderful landscape in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The turbulent social environment not only affects the economic development of France, but also affects the personal and property of each life in Paris. In this chaotic environment, throwing a wallet and a mobile phone is common, and such a high crime rate, the police are invincible and ordinary residents are invincible. In helplessness, the way they adopted was to raise the threshold for files: light crimes such as robbery and other serious crimes, regarded light crimes as illegal, and simply try to leave as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The United States also learned this set. In 2014, California passed the bill and stole the less than 1,000 US dollars as a minor crime, which can be guilty through community services. Use this method to avoid police conflicts and reduce the contradiction between police and blacks. This set of legal ideas and judicial practice has spawned the &quot;0 yuan purchase&quot; movement in Europe and the United States: the big group (mainly immigrants) rushed into the store together, took things to run, the store was unable to stop, and the police did not want to control it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to public security issues, there is also a seemingly irrelevant life detail change: French bread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the early years of retention in France, relatives and friends were impressed by French catering. Especially appreciation of French bread: In France, bread is not only a diet, but also a culture. In order to make Xiangsong&#39;s delicious bread, French bakers are very particular about the noodles and ingredients to fermentation and baking. It starts in the early morning to ensure that as the sun rises, the fragrant and hot -baking French bread is released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When he traveled to Paris after the new crown Class B tube, he was surprised to find that France not only was in society and public security, but even French bread became different from 30 years ago. Hardness, fatigue, poor taste, and severe slag ... Later, many ordinary breaders were new immigrants who lacked French culture and cooking traditions. For them, bread is no longer national glory, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage. Long custom and exquisite life taste, but just a job, no feelings, and not investing too much energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The relatives and friends who like to travel said: Now it is the former French colonies such as Laos and Vietnam in Southeast Asia. French bread is slightly authentic than Paris. There is also stricter labor discipline, there are certain requirements for employees, and they also follow the traditional French bread baking skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Corresponding to it: French people have a 150 -day rest day (116.5 days per year in the United States), and the average of 1490 hours per year (the American is 1791 hours). Probably because there are too many new immigrants, the grassroots work as much as possible from immigrants, and the French aborigines with higher income are getting easier and more reluctant The occupation is too lazy to do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is like: a company that is already going downhill is not a new technology and productive innovation, and trying to reverse the trend, but to reduce working hours, increase salary, weaken performance, give up management ... what will the consequences happen? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The problem of &quot;traditional loss and cultural ebb&quot; in France will not only be in public security nor catering. Those who have made the French proud of it, and have indeed achieved the culture and art of the world&#39;s peak, and they are also facing the same crisis. The former French film actor Dpadio tangled a group of people in the French performing arts industry, scolded Hollywood to engage in cultural aggression, and burned the American flag to vent their anger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Hollywood has neither forced force, nor does it &quot;cultural aggression&quot; against France through an unequal treaty, but people (including French) are unwilling to consume French movies, drama, and games. The French should really save themselves: they are in ideology, ideology, cultural concepts, artistic creations, as well as international political, economic and trade relations, social governance, and even baking bread ... What is going on in all aspects, what is going on? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The deterioration of social order brought by immigrants reflects the failure of the French government&#39;s social governance. The cultural impact and ideological collision caused by immigration issues reflect deeper hidden dangers. French social governance failure and ebb to ebb. The internal cause is that the spiritual power of the contemporary French is dissipated, the traditional values ​​are abandoned, and the national culture is lost. The French lived lazy, idle, and happy, and comfortably confirmed the ancient saying of &quot;from good as good as being as good as the evil&quot;. This state of life is worth pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, I also hope that everyone to think about the person, Elon Musk, who is still struggling in middle age: I don&#39;t want to make money with the power of human fall. For example, &quot;Jupiter Ascending&quot; interprets gravity: up is hard, down is easy The success of society and individuals requires a high spiritual core. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the personal point of view of the author, does not represent the position of this newspaper) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;&quot; https://feedx.net &quot;style =&quot; color: orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href =&quot; https://feedx.run &quot;style = &quot;COLOR: Orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一座湖南县城“利剑出鞘”：八百公职人员进退公租房]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261401]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;On the morning of November 14, 2023, a tenant in the middle and community of Run Middle and Community moves. Southern Weekend Weekend. Southern Weekend Weekend. Reporter Zheng Dan &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 736 &quot;data -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259769&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the morning of November 14, 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, a tenant in the middle and medium districts moved. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Supervise the whole people, make public rental housing more &#39;sunlight&#39;.&quot; A banner hangs on the main entrance of Runmi District, November 2023 Since then, the number of residents moved from the community has increased suddenly, and the &lt;span>; handling &lt;/span>; pickup trucks in and out of the furniture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Moving is common. Recently, Lianyuan, a county-level city in Loudi, Hunan. This stems from a centralized consolidation of public officials to occupy public rental housing. In addition to Run Mid -Mid -Community, the phenomenon of large -scale moving also appeared in the Runze Garden Community, Huimin Community, and Runyuan Community. According to locals, these four communities are public rental housing communities in Lianyuan City. Those who move are basically public officials and their relatives of Lianyuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A statistical table obtained by the reporter from the Southern Weekend shows that the above four public rental housing communities are investigated and exited 878 public officials, plus 4 households entering the units of public housing Public officials have a total of 882 households, including 28 public officials at the same level and above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Many public officials in Lianyuan said that people on this list must be retired before the end of November. &quot;This is the first time in the past decades, and the residents have been retreated in such a large area.&quot; A staff member of the Lianyuan Housing Security Service Center (hereinafter referred to as the Housing Insurance Center) told the Southern Weekend reporter that this operation was with the Hunan Provincial Inspection Team. Request rectification is related. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Do not replace the past conventions to the current rules and regulations, and must not compete with the people.&quot; On October 20, the secretary of the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee held a meeting and scheduled the scheduling Public rental housing operation management and service work. The &quot;Lianyuan Online&quot; public account released by the public account that the meeting emphasized that public rental housing is a affordable housing, and relevant departments must unify their thinking; to set up a leading group and work class to study, analyze, and find existing problem loopholes and weak links. , Establish a list of ledger in different categories to increase rectification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;In November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, the main entrance of Run Mid -Mid -Central District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/11/27/EDFD4A5F6F6F6F.JPEG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/ms/imedias/23/11/ 27/EDFD4A5F6F.JPEG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 259770 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, the main gate of Runzhongzhong District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;How can the residential insurance center have this ability&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; mid-November, the south On weekends, reporters visited public officials to stay in the middle and medium -sized districts and Runze Park Community. Many fences and walls were hung on the wall with red banners that combat illegal use of public rental housing and rented public rental houses. In the two communities, each building was posted with the announcement of the Lianyuan Housing Insurance Center: &quot;The Municipal Party Committee and the Municipal Government are carried out cleanup and rectification of the use of public rental housing in violation of regulations. Public leased housing situation (including actual staying in other methods such as transfers, rents, and resale). Once verified, the reporting units, organizations and individuals will reward 500 yuan/time. &quot;The announcement date of the announcement is October 31. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There are fewer people who have moved these two days, and many people have moved away a few days ago.&quot; On the afternoon of November 13, a resident in the middle and medium districts in Runzhong District Tell the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #000000;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; Public rental housing, full name public rental housing, refers to the limited construction standards and rental levels, Facing the middle -income housing difficulties, households in difficult housing, new employment employees, and affordable housing rented out of the town. According to the &quot;Administrative Measures for Public Rental Housing&quot; issued by the Ministry of Housing and Construction in 2012, the lease period of public rental housing generally does not exceed 5 years. If it does not meet the renewal conditions after the expiration, it shall retire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lianyuan City, this concentrated retreat, according to a number of public officials, it is the 11th inspection team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee to work in Lianyuan City 2 to work 2 During the month (September 7, 2023 -November 7, 2023), some masses reported that public officials reported illegally occupying public rental housing and rents and sold, resulting in poor households who really need houses to live without houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporter obtained a red head document sent by the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee to the municipal units- &quot;Regarding the founding of public officials leased public rental housing investigations The notice also mentioned that the 11th inspection team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee issued a letter to Lianyuan City on October 17, 2023, and feedback that there was a problem of public officials and the people in Lianyuan public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The notice requires all units to conduct investigations and foundation on public rental housing on the public rental housing of the unit, and on October 23, 2023 Before 17:00, the &quot;Statistics Form for Public Officials Leasing Public Rental Housing&quot; will be reported to the Municipal Housing Insurance Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Many ordinary people take this to the inspection team to reflect that the inspection team feels that this is a common problem. Rental). &quot;Lin Min (pseudonym) of the staff of the Housing Insurance Center told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Public officials illegally occupying public rental housing are not unique. According to public information, in May 2021, the Supervision and Inspection of Qingchuan County Discipline Inspection Commission of Guangyuan City, Sichuan Province found that local public officials used 412 units of public housing illegally, including 275 units of public rental housing in violation of regulations and 145 public officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2019, in 2019, the Anhua Discipline Inspection Commission of Yiyang City, Hunan Province also found such phenomena. Four public officers rented public rental housing, and 5 public officials were transferred to public rental housing. There were 28 public officials who did not withdraw the qualification conditions in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to the public information of Lianyuan City Rong Media Center, on the evening of October 25, 2023, the members of the Eleventh Inspection Team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee were at the Standing Committee of the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee Standing Committee The meeting again emphasized that the public rental housing issues that people reflect strong and highly concerned about the public must be realized and steadily promoted the rectification of the problem steadily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, before the inspection team arrived, Lianyuan City also tried to rectify the problem. According to a report from Hunan Daily in early 2023, the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center launched a special cleanup and rectification operation of public rental housing illegally from January 9th to 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;In January, reported more than ten public officials who were seriously inconsistent, and there were cars and houses in the name. Then After changing some people, a few households were cleared. &quot;Lin Min introduced that according to the practice of Lianyuan City, such special cleanup and rectifications will be organized every two or three years, but the rectification is small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Now so great to retreat, how can we have this ability to live in the insurance center? If it wasn&#39;t for the inspection team, who would move the municipal party secretary? According to Lin Min, the rectification of public rental housing involves a number of cadres, and the Municipal Housing Insurance Center is difficult to implement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a public official moved away from Run Mid -Mid -Central District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/ CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/27/8C9A7B4242.jpeg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/ 23/11/27/8c9a7b4242.jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259771 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, Public officials moved away from Run Middle District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Too many vacant placement and wasting waste? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Is public officials qualified to stay in public rental housing? Nie Chen, an associate professor at the School of Public Management of Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, who has long studied housing security, believes that some public officials who have low income and difficult housing &lt;/span>; meet the conditions to stay in public rental housing, which is normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;After the cancellation of the welfare housing system in 1998, most provinces and cities across the country will no longer be assigned to employees by the &lt;span>; units. Indeed, there are some civil servants&#39; salary and a heavy burden on the family. They can&#39;t afford a house, so he meets the conditions for applying for public rental housing. &quot;Wang Ciangliang, director of the China Construction Management and Real Estate Law Research Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But as far as the situation of Lianyuan, some people familiar with the matter told the Southern Weekend that public officials who stayed in public rental houses passed the number of people to check in, and a few were &quot; The batch &quot;gets the number of staying. &quot;Some people buy a house in Loudi, Lianyuan has no room; some have a house in Lianyuan, but he wants this house; some are batching friends or relatives.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: &quot;LEFT;&quot;>; &quot;The severe disaster area is moisturizing the middle and medium districts. Most public officials are there, near the city center, and the geographical location is more convenient.&quot; The person familiar with the matter said. Southern Weekend reporters compared the results of the three public rental housing computers of Run Mid -Central District, and the publicity list of public rental housing leased public rental housing in Lianyuan City found that the three -time number of Runmi Mid -Central Districts took place in 1826 households. There were 669 public officials in the community, accounting for residents in community. The total number is about 37%; of which 522 households are among the list of public announcements, and the remaining 147 households are not listed on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters obtained another &quot;Statistics Form for Renting the Public Rental Housing Housing Housing Rental Housing Housing Rental Housing&quot; of Lianyuan City 28 officials at the department -level cadres have been out at the end of October 2023, and the furniture is still cleaning up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Why are there such large-scale public officials living in the middle and medium-sized districts? The above -mentioned persons revealed that after the completion of the middle and medium -sized districts, when the number was released in 2017 and 2018, for some special reasons, &quot;as long as you participate in the lottery, you can be divided into the house.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Run Mid-Mid-Central District has built more than 2,300 houses at a time, no one lives, but it requires the occupancy rate to reach 90%. It is criticized. Because you want to build so many houses, it will definitely mean that there is such a large demand. &quot;The person familiar with the matter said that at the time of rent, the housing insurance department reported to the Lianyuan Municipal Government. The meeting was discussed to relax the conditions, and public officials who had no house in Lianyuan could apply for a lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 24, 2023, a reporter from the Southern Weekend called the relevant person in charge of the Lianyuan Resident Insurance Center to verify the statement. Refuse to be interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another staff member of Lianyuan City Resident Insurance Center told the Southern Weekend reporter that Runzhongzhong District is located in Jianzhong Village and Hujia Village in Lantian Street. Construction, including low -rent housing and public rental housing, at that time, it was called &quot;building a low -rent housing and a public rental housing project in Chengdong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The information of the official website of Lianyuan Municipal Government in 2013 shows that the construction of low-rent housing and Chengdong public rental housing project is the &quot;12th Five-Year Plan&quot; housing security in Lianyuan City One of the key projects for affordable housing construction implemented in the plan. The project covers an area of ​​188 acres, with a planned total construction area of ​​140,000 square meters and a total investment of 180 million yuan. It is planned to build a total of 276 houses. After completion, it will become the largest housing area in Lianyuan City. Jiaju District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 2021 A property bidding document in Runzhong District mentioned that the total construction area of ​​the community house is 140,000 square meters, a total of 30 buildings, including 2218 units, of which there are 2218 units. 742 non -residential (service houses). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; Lianyuan Online &quot;public account published by the Jianzhong -China rental housing panorama (above),&quot; Lianyuan Yearbook (2019) &quot;published in Run Mid -Mid -Central District: . Data chart &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;heart =&quot; 1223 &quot;data- src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259772&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text -rign: center; &quot;>;&quot; Lianyuan Online &quot;public account released by Jianzhong -China -Laurea rental housing (above),&quot; Lianyuan Yearbook (2019) &quot;published by Runmi Middle and Mid -District Panorama (below). Data Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Cowender housing refers to the government with rent subsidies or physical rents to provide society with low living security standards for urban residents and housing difficulties. Housing that guarantees nature. Nie Chen told the southern weekend reporter, &quot;In a sense, low -rent housing is a public rental housing. It faces lower -income people and lower rent than public rental housing. In 2014, low -rent housing and public rental housing are parallel. Called public rental housing. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Nie Chen analysis, from 2010 to 2015, the national large-scale public rental house and low-rent housing were promoted. The housing problems of families with low -income housing difficulties in 2015 should be guaranteed to reach 20%in 2015. &quot;At that time, there were targets to be completed in various places, and a large number of public rental housing was built.&quot; However, Nie &lt;span>; Chen &lt;/span>; found in the actual research process that some areas including Beijing, Shanghai, and Inner Mongolia appear. With remote or other factors, there are fewer people applying for lease, which leads to the vacancy of public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There is a trend now, that is, the public rental housing is gradually relaxing the conditions, and even the phenomenon of converting to affordable rental housing, expanding the scope of protection.&quot; Nie Nie. &quot;Nie Nie. &lt;span>; Chen &lt;/span>; said that the rent of affordable housing is generally not higher than 90%of the rental housing rent of housing in the same quality market in the same location. &quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is worth noting that in October 2020, the Lianyuan City Disciplinary Inspection Commission and the Lianyuan City Supervision Committee notified about Jianzhong Lianlian The bidding problem of rental construction. In November 2012, Liang Mou and Zhang Mouxian (active participants organized by Tan Mouping&#39;s underworld organizations led by Tan Mouping) were used as the active participants in the anti -corruption and bribery bureau. The engineering construction project of the 14th bid section of the Donggong Housing Community has contacted four companies including Lianyuan Xiangzhong Engineering Company, Hunan Province, to bid, and then won the project. Relevant judgment shows that Liang and Zhang Mouxian illegally obtained more than 1.29 million yuan in the project. In August 2020, Liang was expelled from the party and was expelled from public office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition to Runjun Mid-Mid-District, there are also many public officials in Huimin Community and Runze Park Community. A public official of a Huimin Community said that Huimin Community also gradually relaxed the conditions for public officials because of too many vacant houses. Another public official also said that the application conditions for the application of the public rental housing communities in Lianyuan were loose. As long as the migrant workers who had no house in Lianyuan could participate in the shaking number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The salary of public officials is not high, and many also meet the conditions of (shaking the number) conditions.&quot; ) It was said that there were less than 300,000 cities and towns in Lianyuan City, which made it difficult for poor households who had social security and houses without houses in their names. &quot;Go to take care of the low-income population first. If there are empty houses, you must relax the conditions, otherwise it is a waste of public resources.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft;&quot;>; Two ways to check in are viewed by the case of Lianyuan. &quot;Public rental housing is a affordable housing developed from the past economic affordable housing. It is mainly to solve a large number of working classes with low income and cannot afford market -oriented houses. . &quot;And for those who meet the application conditions and the residents of the shaking number, they are temporarily retreated or there are suspicion of breach of contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;In November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, a banner of combating the use of public rental houses in the Runze Garden Community. .infzm.com/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/cms/cms/cms /medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259773 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; November 2023, November 2023, November 2023, in November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, a banner of combating the use of public rental houses in the Runze Garden Community. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan, Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Patching&quot; and &quot;One Drive&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; November 1, 2023, &quot;Lianyuan Public Public Public Public Public Public Public Public Public City The new regulations of the Rental Housing Management Measures put forward more detailed requirements. Nie Chen told the southern weekend that the management regulations of public rental housing are generally formulated by local governments according to local economic conditions. However, the state has unified regulations that the lessee must meet the two conditions: &quot;low -income&quot; and &quot;housing poor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lianyuan&#39;s new regulations show: Lianyuan City&#39;s urban minimum guarantee, low-income, middle partial income household difficult families, new employment housing workers and urban and towns in cities and towns Stable employment migrant workers should be included in the scope of public rental housing security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Among them, families with medium-sized income housing in the town refer to the per capita disposable annual income of the family than the per capita disposable income of urban residents in the previous year, low family deposits, low family deposits. Families difficulty in housing in unscrupulous real estate at 180,000 yuan (including provident fund) and unrepided property in cities at or above or above; new employees who have no housing employees refer to employees who have worked within 5 years and have employed locally, and have no local housing in the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lin Min analyzed that the per capita disposable annual income restriction and work of the family per capita are enough to exclude most of the public officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There are more than 20 public officials who have been less than 5 years without issuing a notice, and the rest are all cut.&quot; Lin Min recalled that the Housing Insurance Center was in the internal meeting. The above request is that the public officials who have worked for 5 years will be cleared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lu Ke also told the southern weekend that the public officials who stayed in public rental houses, except for several university graduates who have been working for less than 5 years, all retired from all the rest. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A grass-roots business editor who has been required to retire from public rental houses due to the working period of more than 5 years, and wrote it on the official website of Lianyuan City Government: &quot; (I) Originally, there were no real estate in Lianyuan for no reason. Low -income personnel were fully eligible. They could not meet the people. I urged the leaders to consider foreign staff as appropriate. >; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Is there really no public office personnel to stay in public rental housing before the launch of the new regulations? Southern Weekend reporters randomly interviewed the residents of two households in the middle and medium -sized districts, both of which were non -public officials. One of them said that his brother and mother also applied for public rental housing like this, and he had not encountered a situation that he could not apply for public rental housing before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lin Min believes that the people who later reported that public rental housing could apply, it was a new problem that appeared in the new stage. &quot;Some people who did not need public rent at that time. Later, their children became family and needed a house. New public rental housing. Due to national policy adjustment, after 2016, public rental housing will not be built in principle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 8, 2023, Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center issued an announcement that the application for the waiting object of public rental housing from the day to November 20, Those who meet the new regulations can apply for public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a public official moved away from Run Mid -Mid -Central District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/ CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/27/63CD9E2856.jpeg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/ 23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259774 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; In the afternoon of November 13, 2023, Public officials moved away from Run Middle District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to a number of public officials, on November 9, 2023, on Thursday, when the inspection team is about to leave Lianyuan, urban management is about to leave, urban management A bureau&#39;s approaching public officials organized a number of people to go to the office office of the inspection team to reflect the demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Take the lead in the person (in the retired public rental house) to do some decoration to see if (the government) can pay some money.&quot; The public officials of the Urban Management Bureau said that there were dozens of people who went to find multiple units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A public official who stayed in Runze Garden told the southern weekend that his family also followed the situation. &quot;Originally, the first notice was moved before December 10th, but after they (reflected the situation), the notice was issued the next day, and they must be moved before November 30th.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;Text-Align: Left;&quot;>; A public official of the Lianyuan City Development and Reform Commission recalled that on the morning of Friday (November 10), the unit organized a meeting and asked to sign a commitment to move away from the public rental housing before November 30. Another public official who engaged in teaching also said that the school held an emergency meeting on the morning of the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Our unit meets more, it is opened on Saturday and Sunday.&quot; Reflect that &quot;most of our units&#39;s houses have been renovated, and their opinions are relatively large.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to Lin Min, the public officials who stayed in public rental houses spent more than 200,000 yuan for decoration. Regarding whether the decoration is given compensation, Lin Min introduced that the public rental housing contract clearly stipulates that &quot;come and throw away&quot;, and the decoration does not make compensation. &quot;Because it is not a rough room, the bathroom, kitchen, and lamps are all installed. You can basically move in when you meet the standard of delivery. &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition, many respondents told Southern Weekend reporters that the phenomenon of selling public rental houses in Lianyuan City is more common. &quot;I heard that a house of more than fifty square meters is sold for 50,000 to 60,000.&quot; Lin Min said that many people will decorate public rental housing and resale may be a local deep -rooted concept. To. &quot;There is a thought in our Lianyuan, that is, the government gave me the house, which means that the house is mine. I never worried that I would not be able to live in this house. I did not expect that the inspection team came to let us move. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; What follows is that the rent of Lianyuan&#39;s part near the public rental housing community has also increased. &quot;The two -bedroom and one -living house in the past two rooms rented less than 4,000 yuan a year, and now it has risen to 5,000 yuan.&quot; A public official who lives in the middle and medium districts of Runjun told the Southern Weekend reporter that according to public rental housing The price only needs to be paid in the early 200 yuan a year. The other two public officials also confirmed: &quot;Suddenly there are more than 800 households moved out, (nearby rental) housing is definitely nervous.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align : LEFT; &quot;>; On November 14th, the reporter from the Southern Weekend consulted with a staff member of the residential insurance center as&quot; tenants who did not check out &quot;. The other party claims that if you think you meet the conditions of staying in public rental housing, you can submit the materials and re -review. At 12 noon of the day of the application, 80 or ninety households were unwilling to check out the materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A public official who submitted the material said he received a notice on November 18 and still had to retreat. As far as he knows, only one of a paralyzed and family -difficult public personnel can continue to rent public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎是新冠的变异？张文宏等专家解读误区]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261440]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; At present, as the local area enters the winter, respiratory diseases have entered a high incidence. How should we prevent and treat it? What are the misunderstandings about respiratory diseases? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;Healthy China&quot; column invited Zhang Wenhonghong, a professor at Huashan Hospital affiliated to Fudan University, Liu Qingquan, Dean of Beijing Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital affiliated to the Capital Medical University, and Deputy Dean of Beijing Chaoyang Hospital affiliated to the Capital Medical University, Beijing Tong Zhaohui, director of the Institute of Highness Diseases, detailed explanations on the current common on the Internet about the misunderstanding of respiratory diseases on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Misunderstanding 1: This year&#39;s winter respiratory virus is complex. Is it terrible to superimposed infections? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Zhang Wenhong said that many people will be afraid of superimposed infection. In fact, sometimes multiple viruses or bacteria are detected because very sensitive detection methods are used, so don’t worry too much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tong Zhaohui said that despite the measurement of many diseases, it does not mean that every one is a disease. The doctor will comprehensively analyze which bacteria are the patient&#39;s pathogenic bacteria based on the patient&#39;s clinical condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Qingquan said that from the perspective of traditional Chinese medicine, superimposed infection is a synthetic or merger. &quot;For example, the fever is 7 days, and it is found that it is influenza. It has a fever again in about 10 days. This time it is mycoplasma. This is actually not superimposed, but not well -maintained. : Mycoplasma pneumonia is the mutation of the new crown? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Tong Zhaohui said that humans discovered the microorganisms of mycoplasma in the early 20th century. It was not determined that it was a pathogen in the late 20th century, and the new crown virus was known in the end of 2019. It doesn&#39;t matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Why are children particularly easy to infected mycoplasma? Tong Zhaohui said that children&#39;s immune systems are not fully developed and their resistance is not as good as adults&#39;, so they are more susceptible to infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Misunderstanding 3: Once you have a cold and fever, you have to quickly infusion? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Tong Zhaohui said, &quot;the cold and fever infusion is good&quot;, which is actually a misunderstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared with the flu, the temperature of the cold and fever is lower and the symptoms are lighter, which is often the symptoms of the upper respiratory tract. If you have a fever or cough after catching a cold, just take fever-reducing or cough-relieving medicine at home. Pay attention to getting more rest, drinking more water, and supplementing your nutrition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the flu, some flu can cause pneumonia and even severe pneumonia. At this time, you may be hospitalized, and the hospital doctor will determine whether you need infusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Wenhong also said that the infusion is limited to the severe patients in hospitalization, or some drugs cannot be taken orally, and can only pass the infusion. For the common cold, oral medications work better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Misunderstanding 4: Can Zhi Yuan body pneumonia be healed at home? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tong Zhaohui said that in most cases, whether it is a virus or mycoplasma, if it is limited to the upper respiratory tract, most of them can heal themselves, and a small part may develop to pneumonia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Wenhong said that in general, some symptomatic drugs of mycoplasma pneumonia can improve at home, but it is necessary to pay attention to whether there is any development in the direction of severe illnesses. For example, if your child&#39;s condition improves after taking medicine, you can observe it at home; if your child still has a high fever after taking antipyretics and is sluggish and unwilling to eat, you should seek medical attention as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Misunderstanding 5: Instant the swing of exercise in winter to improve immunity? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Liu Qingquan said that from the perspective of traditional Chinese medicine, excessive sweating will hurt the yang. During winter sports, your body will feel slightly warm and you may sweat a little. It&#39;s okay to work up a sweat, but it doesn&#39;t have to be every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Wenhong said that it is promoted to maintain a certain amount of exercise. &quot;Even if you are busy today, it is good to take 5000 steps.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Special reminder: Please pay attention to the weather in winter and wear a mask as appropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[OpenAI忙宫斗，AI大模型和应用忙上新丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/27/5c1572c356.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 27/5c1572c356.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-to-late November 2023, OpenAI experienced a constant reversal of personnel turmoil, and Sam Altman was re-appointed as OpenAI CEO It&#39;s over for now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plot is complicated and confusing, and it really attracted enough attention. Can a star company and a star CEO really influence the development process of AI in the human world? You might as well take a look at the efforts of more companies in upgrading and applying large AI models. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New large model&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 21, Anthropic, an AI start-up from San Francisco, California, launched &lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. anthropic.com/index/claude-2-1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Claude 2.1 AI model&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; supports the input of up to 200,000 Tokens, exceeding the OpenAI large-scale Model GPT-4 Turbo has 128,000 Tokens, which can handle longer text content, and also has a new system prompt word (System Prompt) function. Anthropic claims that the accuracy of Claude2.1 is twice that of Claude2.0, which enhances the ability to understand text content, especially when processing higher-accuracy documents such as legal documents, financial reports, and technical specifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as OpenAI cooperates with Microsoft, Anthropic and Google stand together. In early November 2023, Anthropic announced that it would use Google&#39;s chip Cloud TPU v5e to support its large models and use its cloud computing services. Google promised to invest US$2 billion in it in October 2023, with an initial investment of US$500 million. Dollar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Inflection AI, a company co-founded in March 2023 by Mustafa Suleyman, co-founder of Google’s DeepMind AI research group, Karén Simonyan, chief scientist of DeepMind AI, and Reid Hoffman, co-founder of LinkedIn, in November &lt;a href=&quot;https://inflection.ai/inflection-2&quot;>;&lt;strong>;A new generation of large model Inflection-2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>; was released on the 22nd, calling it the world’s second-generation large model. Language Model (LLM). Inflection-2 performs FP8 mixed-precision training on 5,000 Nvidia H100 GPUs, with approximately 10^25 FLOP computing capabilities. It is in the same training computing category as Google&#39;s PaLM 2 Large model, and has been tested on MMLU, TriviaQA, HellaSwag and GSM8k. In most AI benchmark tests, it is better than PaLM 2, and in some tests it is second only to OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone is benchmarking against OpenAI, and OpenAI is certainly not idle either. On November 6, OpenAI released customizable &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/introducing-gpts&quot;>;&lt;strong>;GPTs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>; at its first developer conference , allowing ChatGPT Plus users and OpenAI’s enterprise customers to create customized versions of ChatGPT. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Users do not need to master programming knowledge. They can build a GPT with exclusive functions in GPT Builder by relying only on dialogue and a specific knowledge base. This will be more in line with the user&#39;s specific needs and usage scenarios, and will greatly The application threshold is lowered. This service will bring new changes and opportunities in vertical industry artificial intelligence, software applications and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, this &quot;involution&quot; of computing power, data, and models belongs to enterprises. For users, the use value and application scenarios of large models are more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, in office, smart terminal, social media and other scenarios, users can easily get started directly through the built-in large model application, making commercialization faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;AI application implementation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since August 2023, various mobile phone brands have announced plans to access large models. On November 8, Samsung Electronics released a large AI model developed by Samsung Research Institute&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.samsung.com/kr/%ec%82%bc%ec%84%b1%ec%a0 %84%ec%9e%90-%ec%82%bc%ec%84%b1-ai-%ed%8f%ac%eb%9f%bc%ec%84%9c-%ec%9e%90% ec%b2%b4-%ea%b0%9c%eb%b0%9c-%ec%83%9d%ec%84%b1%ed%98%95-ai-%ec%82%bc%ec%84 %b1-%ea%b0%80&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Samsung Gauss&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;. It consists of Samsung Gaussian language, Samsung Gaussian code and Samsung Gaussian image, and is planned to be integrated into various products in stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, Elon Musk’s AI company xAI released a large model on November 4&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.ai/&quot;>;&lt;strong >;Grok-1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;, with real-time access to X (formerly Twitter), and Internet browsing and search capabilities to obtain more of the latest news on specific topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, the Google DeepMind team published a paper in Science titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adi2336&quot;>;Learning Skillful medium-range global weather forecasting&lt;/a>; paper introduces their new machine learning weather forecast model Graphcast, which can generate 10-day forecasts in one minute on a single Google Cloud TPU v4 device, and supports forecasts including tropical Cyclone tracks, atmospheric rivers and extreme temperatures. At present, the source code of this model has been made public. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The weather forecasting method (MLWP) is more accurate and efficient than the traditional &quot;Numerical Weather Prediction&quot; (NWP) method. In July 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06185-3&quot;>;Pangu meteorological model developed by Huawei Cloud&lt;/a>;, in the medium and long-term global weather forecast surpass traditional numerical prediction methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the MLWP model can also be extended to other geographical spatiotemporal predictions such as ecology, energy, and animal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, &quot;Nature Medicine&quot; published a paper on the research results of Alibaba Damo Academy and more than ten medical institutions around the world&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature .com/articles/s41591-023-02640-w&quot;>;Large-scale pancreatic cancer detection via non-contrast CT and deep learning&lt;/a>;, for the first time it has been proven that &quot;plain scan CT + AI&quot; technology can effectively detect early stage pancreatic cancer on a large scale Pancreatic cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pancreatic cancer is a digestive tract tumor with a very poor prognosis. It has the characteristics of difficulty in early diagnosis, low surgical resection rate, and easy recurrence and metastasis after surgery. It is also known as the &quot;King of Cancers&quot; because of its early diagnosis. Symptoms are vague, lack specificity, and are easily overlooked. CT is the most widely used and most sensitive examination method for detecting pancreatic cancer. However, the contrast of plain CT images commonly used in physical examinations and hospitals is low, making it difficult to identify early pancreatic lesions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team built a deep learning framework—Pancreatic cancer early detection model PANDA (Pancreatic cancer Detection with AI), which uses AI to amplify and identify subtle pathological features that are difficult to detect with the naked eye in plain CT images; internal Test evaluation shows that PANDA can achieve 90% pancreatic cancer lesion sensitivity and 99.9% lesion specificity in more than 20,000 clinical cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using AI to accelerate the popularization of early cancer screening, early detection and early treatment, the quality of patients’ lives can be guaranteed to the greatest extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attached are three recent major developments in the field of biomedicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New progress in biomedicine&lt;/h4>; &lt;h5>;Eli Lilly&#39;s weight loss therapy was approved by the US FDA&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 8, Eli Lilly announced that its glucose-dependent insulinotropic peptide ( GIP) and glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) receptor dual agonist Zepbound (tirzepatide) &lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.lilly.com/news-releases/news-release-details/ fda-approves-lillys-zepboundtm-tirzepatide-chronic-weight&quot;>;Approved by the US FDA&lt;/a>; for the treatment of patients with obesity or overweight and weight-related comorbidities (blood pressure, dyslipidemia, type 2 diabetes, obstructive sleep disorders apnea or cardiovascular disease) to lose weight and maintain weight stability. Zepbound is the first approved drug that simultaneously activates two intestinal hormone receptors (GIP and GLP-1), directly targeting the root cause of excess weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The obesity indication approved for Zepbound this time is mainly based on the results of two Phase III clinical trials, one of which targeted 2,539 adults with obesity or overweight and weight-related problems (excluding diabetes). Injecting Zepbound as a dietary and exercise aid, the highest dose group (15 mg/week) lost an average of 48 pounds (approximately 22 kg) in 72 weeks, while the lowest dose group (5 mg/week) lost an average of 34 pounds (approximately 15 kg) , the placebo group was 7 pounds (about 3 kilograms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comment: Zepbound is a GIP/GLP-1 receptor agonist injected once a week. Eli Lilly announced the first new Chinese evidence in the field of Zepbound obesity treatment on October 3, 2023. And has submitted a registration application for long-term weight management indications in adults in China. As of now, there are no GLP-1 drugs officially approved in China for the treatment of obesity or overweight. China has a huge weight loss market, and the market competition in the field of weight loss indications is fierce, which provides more information for individuals seeking effective weight loss treatments. multiple choice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;The world’s first CRISPR gene editing therapy was approved&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 16, the US biopharmaceutical company Vertex (VRTX.O) and the Swiss gene editing company CRISPR Therapeutics ( CRSP.O) announced that the UK Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has granted it &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vrtx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/vertex-and-crispr- therapeutics-announce-authorization-first&quot;>;CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing therapy Casgevy (Exa-cel) Conditional Marketing Authorization&lt;/a>; (CMA, applicable to drugs that meet significant unmet medical needs, valid for one year, updated annually Once), for the treatment of patients 12 years of age and older with sickle cell disease (SCD) with recurrent vaso-occlusive crises (VOCs) and transfusion-dependent beta-Mediterranean patients who are unable to obtain human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-matched hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Anemia (TDT) patients. This is the world’s first CRISPR gene editing therapy approved for marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Casgevy is an autologous, ex vivo CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing therapy that modifies the patient&#39;s hematopoietic stem cells in vitro so that red blood cells can produce high levels of fetal hemoglobin (HbF, a hemoglobin that carries oxygen ). Results from two global clinical trials of CASGEVY in SCD and TDT showed that treated patients had no serious VOCs or independent blood transfusions for at least 12 consecutive months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The above approvals open the door to further applications of CRISPR therapies in the future, with the potential to cure many genetic diseases. In addition, another American biotechnology company Verve&amp;nbsp;(Nasdaq: VERV)&amp;nbsp; announced its development of a single base editing therapy VERVE-101 based on the modification of the CRISPR system at the American Heart Association on November 12, confirming that gene editing therapy A single infusion of the drug significantly reduced LDL-C levels in people who were at high risk for early heart attacks due to inherited high cholesterol. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;Half natural, half synthetic yeast cells&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 9, &quot;Cell&quot; reported on the international cooperation project as a cover story &lt;a href = &quot;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/s0092-8674 (2)079-6?_returnurl=https%3a%2FLINKINHUB.elsevier.com%2FRETRIEVE%2FS0092886 7423010796%3fshowall%3dtrue &quot;&quot; >;The latest achievement of the &quot;Saccharomyces cerevisiae Genome Synthesis Project&quot;&lt;/a>; (Sc2.0 project): the design and synthesis of all 16 yeast chromosomes and a new chromosome of specially designed tRNA has been completed. The researchers crossed yeast cells containing different synthetic chromosomes and then looked for individuals carrying two synthetic chromosomes in the offspring. After a long hybridization process, the research team gradually integrated all the chromosomes they had previously synthesized (6 complete chromosomes and 1 chromosome arm) into the same cell. The resulting yeast strain accounted for more than 31% of the synthetic DNA and had a normal morphology. ; Later, a newly synthesized chromosome (chromosome 4, the largest of all synthetic chromosomes) was transferred using chromosome replacement, thus obtaining a yeast cell with 7.5 synthetic chromosomes, with the proportion of synthetic DNA accounting for more than 50%. The synthetic yeast cell Survival and replication capabilities are similar to wild yeast strains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/53090e4628.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/53090e4628.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;▲ VOLUME 186, ISSUE 24&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sc2.0 project initiated by the international scientific community aims to complete the design and chemical reconstruction of complete Saccharomyces cerevisiae The genome, and ultimately the yeast strain synthesized, will be a milestone in humanity&#39;s ability to use and understand eukaryotic genomes. On November 8, the results of the Sc2.0 project were published online in Cell (2 articles) and its sub-journals such as Molecular Cell (1 article) and Cell Genomics (7 articles). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Yeast is the first eukaryotic organism to have its entire genome sequenced. The large-scale design and reconstruction of its genome is a direct test of the authenticity, completeness and accuracy of the current knowledge base in the genome field. The above series of research results are not only a milestone for Sc2.0, but also a key step in the field of synthetic genomics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>