<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[离经叛道的“禁片之王”，终于迎来大结局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260850]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;This month, the biggest event in the animation industry&lt;/span>;, the non-animated version of &quot;Attack on The ending of &quot;Giant&quot; is none other than this. The long-awaited final work finally brings an end to this epic series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/ea5a811e3e55d28ca36b543387fd4f66.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;537&quot; height=&quot;416&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/ea5a811e3e55d28ca36b543387fd4f66.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258721&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Attack on Titan&quot; is the representative work of Japanese comic artist Isayama Hajime. It has a total of 139 chapters and was serialized in comic magazines for twelve years from 2009 to 2021. In 2013, the TV animation version of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; came out. After ten years of production, a total of four seasons were released (except for the theatrical version and special episodes). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Douban entry, the complete viewing order of the entire drama is: &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; (2013) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Season 2 (2017) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Season 3 (2018) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Season 3 Part.2 (2019) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Final Season Part.1 (2020) Part.2 (2022) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; The final season&amp;nbsp;the final part&amp;nbsp;the first part&amp;nbsp;the second part (2023). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/260482835e33291d29483186b6089ea3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/260482835e33291d29483186b6089ea3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258720 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The unique world view structure, bizarre background setting, incredible imagination, bloody battle scenes, and sensitive issues made this work popular as soon as it came out. attracted the attention of all walks of life. But while attracting countless viewers, it was also banned by many countries in the world due to its large scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, it still achieved a good rating on Douban, with Jiji scoring 9 points+, and even the least optimistic final chapter has a rating of 9.3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/4c766315fbedf871e47850543e220dc2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;483&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/4c766315fbedf871e47850543e220dc2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258723&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since the comic version has been completed in 2021, the audience already knows the ending of this work. It is worth noting that when the comic was completed, it caused huge controversy due to the plot that violated human ethics and was criticized by fans as a &quot;bad ending&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fundamental reason is that Allen, the protagonist of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;, is suspected of &quot;matricide&quot;. With his precognitive ability, he most likely manipulated the Immaculate Titan to eat his mother, leaving a huge psychological trauma on his young self. He then joined the Survey Corps, determined to get rid of the Titan. This setting is mainly to make the whole story logical and &lt;span>; form a closed loop of cause and effect. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But whether it is based on the emotions of the characters or the emotions of the audience, this setting is difficult to accept, and there is a sense of powerlessness in trying to justify it. To paraphrase netizens, this move is tantamount to “Harry Potter manipulating Voldemort to go back in time and kill his parents”, “Batman buying a thief to go back in time and kill his parents”, “Iron Man instructing the Winter Soldier to go back and kill him” One’s own parents”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the animated version, this &quot;matricide&quot; plot was brushed aside and explained in an extremely vague manner. Because of this, it wasn&#39;t as controversial as the comic version, but it just added a bit of tragedy to Allen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/fb44a83ea8c8765afcbe894da7e5f7fa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/fb44a83ea8c8765afcbe894da7e5f7fa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258722 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reason why &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; is hailed as&lt;/span>; a masterpiece is that it reflects reality and depicts an imaginary world with great conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story begins with an invasion of giants on Parady Island. Human beings were unable to resist the giants, so they built three high walls (Xina, Rose, and Maria) to resist the giants, in exchange for a hundred years of peace. But the terrifying giant still came. &quot;On that day, mankind finally recalled the fear of being dominated by giants, and the humiliation of being trapped in a birdcage&lt;span>;.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eren and his friends Mikasa and Armin suffered heavy blows during the Titan invasion, and were eventually admitted to the Survey Corps to fight against the Titans together. At first, the growth path of Allen and others followed the routine of traditional hot-blooded comics. But as the plot continues to advance, the audience soon discovers its anomaly - it does not stick to the binary opposition of good and evil, but digs deeper into the complexity of human nature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reversal in the plot drives the audience and the protagonist to constantly think together and break, rebuild, and break their own thinking. Allen&#39;s life was hanging by a thread during the battle, but he unexpectedly forced out his giant power. There are also many giants hidden in the Survey Corps. The three comrades who have been with Allen through life and death not only have the power of giants, but they are also &quot;spies.&quot; I originally thought that giants were inhuman monsters, but I didn&#39;t expect that giants are also human beings. Giants have also suffered from wars and are victims of racial antagonism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f9462227c0cb4cb5237e2357034e66a9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;693&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f9462227c0cb4cb5237e2357034e66a9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258724 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;All humans who can become giants&lt;/span>; are Eldians. They are regarded by ordinary people as &quot;descendants of demons.&quot; Two thousand years ago, the Eldians, who received the power of giants from their ancestor Ymir, became kings of the world. A hundred years ago, the Eldians were defeated by the Marais. The royal family led some people across the ocean to Parady Island and lived an isolated life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And those Eldians who stayed in other countries were reduced to slaves and lived like a concentration camp. For thousands of years, ordinary people have been deeply hostile to the Eldians and have always wanted to get rid of them. This kind of hostility led Allen to &quot;blackening&quot;, and he decided to use the sound of the earth to launch the &quot;Destruction Plan&quot; - hundreds of thousands of 60-meter-tall super-large &lt;span>; Innocent Titans ran rampant on the earth, indiscriminately Trampling all life, massacred 80% of the human population outside Parady Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The final chapter tells about the &quot;final battle&quot; after the earthquake started. At the end, Mikasa found Eren&#39;s true body under the cover of other members, then cut off Eren&#39;s head and gave him a passionate kiss. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/d6f86c8569a729a1ad946452176faf14.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/d6f86c8569a729a1ad946452176faf14.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258719 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the surface, &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;&lt;/span>; tells the story of &quot;a boy who slays dragons and eventually turns into a dragon.&quot; However, upon closer inspection, it is not that Simplicity is about sacrifice, but also about salvation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ellen&#39;s death has long been doomed. As early as the investiture ceremony, he had already predicted the future. He repeatedly tried to change his destiny, but all ended in failure. In order to break the reincarnation, let the giant&#39;s power disappear completely, and let the Eldians be treated as equals and even respected, he can only embark on an extremely lonely road. He started the roar of the earth, started the massacre, and then made his companions heroes, intending to use his own sacrifice to exchange for the peace of the Eldians. &lt;span>; As he himself said, &quot;This is to save Parady Island.&quot; The only way to win over everyone”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What Allen did was another way of ending sorrow with war. He weighed the difference between salvation and sacrifice, and finally chose to sacrifice the whole world to save those around him. This decision transformed him from a hero into a demon. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/adcd3b5f37cd9df03705d86e6529a58d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/adcd3b5f37cd9df03705d86e6529a58d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258725 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to exploring the complexity of human nature, &lt;/span>; &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; also involves many profound propositions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, freedom. Allen has always pursued freedom. Since he was a child, he has been curious about the sea outside the wall and the other side of the sea, thinking that it is an ideal world of freedom. But in the end, he discovered that &quot;there are enemies on the other side of the sea.&quot; So-called freedom, especially absolute freedom, does not exist at all. As a result, Allen finally became a free slave until death freed him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is the discussion on the meaning of survival. In the final chapter, Armin and Zeke have a philosophical conversation. Jike is a typical pessimist. He believes that the fate of human beings is to undergo an endless and painful reincarnation. The purpose of life is to reproduce, which is meaningless. Armin believes that the meaning of life lies in the moment and the feeling of living in the present: picking up shells at the beach, running with friends, reading at home on a rainy day, watching squirrels eating tree fruits... these may seem random. The sporadic fragments constitute a colorful chapter in human life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;These propositions give &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; a depth that ordinary hot-blooded comics do not have. Therefore, in a sense, in the past ten years, the audience has watched Allen and others grow and part ways, and at the same time, as their personal minds have matured, they have gained more perception and understanding of this work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The divisions and wars in the human world caused by issues such as wealth and poverty, race, ideology, etc., are always recurring and endless. Just like the current Israeli-Palestinian conflict, they always seem to verify the metaphors contained in Isayama Hajime&#39;s &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; again and again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the end of the story, Mikasa buried Eren under the tree where he liked to take a nap. In the future, even if the power of giants is lost, human wars will never stop. At this time, a man discovered the tree where Allen was buried. He walked in, and just like the ancestor Ymir thousands of years ago, he was about to gain the power of a giant...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This seems to tell us that as long as the fate of mankind changes over and over again, , then the tragedy will not be completely ended. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/daf3712a921d7eb60a4ae64d6f372410.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/daf3712a921d7eb60a4ae64d6f372410.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258726 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this case, is this world with constant conflicts still worth our efforts, struggle and life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This goes back to the conversation between Zeke and Armin. They are like the two sides of Sou Isayama. On the one hand, they reveal the nature of the world and point out its cruelty to us; on the other hand, they give us warmth, hope and strength, allowing us to base ourselves on the present, cherish precious moments, and live our lives well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Perhaps, in the final analysis, everything is just a matter of choice. Will you choose to be Zeke or Armin? Or do you have other options? No matter how you want to survive in the world, it all depends on you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当WeWork不再work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260848]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/18/JGRhwuRuCpQduncfyATYDZirEwUctBOQITGqN4gD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/JGRhwuRuCpQduncfyATYDZirEwUctBOQITGqN4gD . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258717&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;August 19, 2023, Beijing, WeWork joint shared office space&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 12th, Huang Wei, who was on his way to work, suddenly received a mass notice from the front desk - the office area will be closed from now on. Stop water supply. Soon after arriving at the company, he was told that the WeWork co-working space in Shanghai World Trade Center could no longer continue to operate, and tenants needed to move to other WeWork properties as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Wei’s start-up team has just settled in September 2023. The rent was lower than he expected, with the monthly quote for a single workstation being 1,200 yuan. When he first returned to China at the end of 2019, he learned about the market situation. The price of a WeWork near the Suzhou River for the same configuration of workstations was around 2,000 yuan. The salesman told him that if the high vacancy rate hadn&#39;t affected his business, he wouldn&#39;t have been able to sign for this location at this price. At that time, in this WeWork, the office areas with less than 5 people were quite saturated, while the offices with more than 10 people were completely vacant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;first come, first served&quot; reminder at the front desk did not allow him to hesitate. Huang Wei quickly selected an office space located one kilometer away by WeWork. When he saw the news that &quot;WeWork filed for bankruptcy protection&quot;, he had already moved into the WeWork office area in Shanghai Plaza for half a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, local time, in order to get rid of huge debts, WeWork filed for bankruptcy protection in New Jersey, USA. However, the bankruptcy filing is limited to WeWork&#39;s offices in the United States and Canada. The next day, WeWork China issued a statement stating that WeWork China had separated from WeWork at the end of 2020 and had independent operating and management capabilities as an independent brand. &quot;The major strategic restructuring decisions made by WeWork in the United States and Canada have no connection with WeWork China.&quot; .&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;WeWork, founded in New York, USA, is known as the &quot;originator of shared office.&quot; WeWork will lease commercial buildings for a long time at preferential prices, then divide them into shared office spaces after redesigning and renovating them. WeWork will provide flexible leasing contracts for freelancers, start-ups and large enterprises, etc., and earn rent differences and additional service fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, when it was first founded, the negative impact of the U.S. financial crisis was still continuing. Commercial buildings were widely idle due to the wave of business closures, a large number of companies laid off employees, and the unemployed became freelancers. WeWork, which emerged at that time, not only provided stylish decoration and flexible leasing options, but also provided free coffee drinks and organized a variety of community activities... WeWork co-founder Adam Neumann advocated &quot;space as a service&quot; and declared To create a &quot;physical social network&quot;, a &quot;world that allows people to live rather than just make a living.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/uDRbK6SD0u9ElpCRqVlC0VN5YV3jgatYqoXhjH1r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/uDRbK6SD0u9ElpCRqVlC0VN5YV3jgatYqoXhjH1r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258715&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 6, 2019, in Tokyo, Japan, SoftBank Group Chairman and President Masayoshi Son attended a press conference. SoftBank said the value of its investment in WeWork fell by nearly $4.6 billion &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;U.S. benchmark after financial crisis Interest rates have been at a low level for a long time, and capital is eager to enter the private equity market to seek higher returns. In an era when the concept of the sharing economy was highly popular, WeWork became the darling of capital and became a unicorn only four years after its establishment. In 2019, with the support of major shareholder SoftBank, WeWork&#39;s valuation soared to an astonishing US$47 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, SoftBank Group CEO Masayoshi Son called WeWork &quot;the next Alibaba.&quot; Alibaba is the most successful investment case of this &quot;unicorn hunter&quot;. In 2000, SoftBank invested US$20 million in Alibaba, which was only one year old. 14 years later, Alibaba went public, and the value of SoftBank’s shares increased approximately 2,900 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SoftBank was once the investment benchmark in the sharing economy track. Masayoshi Son advocates injecting massive amounts of capital into start-up companies to help them quickly crush competitors in scale and become a dominant brand in the market, hoping to achieve long-term profitability after gaining absolute advantages in users and the market. Uber and Didi are SoftBank’s investment cases in the sharing economy track during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, half a year after WeWork reached the peak of its valuation, it fell into a long and steep decline stage. In August 2019, as the initial public offering (IPO) application was exposed, WeWork&#39;s consecutive losses triggered market concerns about the company&#39;s profitability. Neumann&#39;s financial and leadership issues have also been exposed one after another. In the same month, Uber, which had just been listed for half a year, suffered its largest loss since announcing its financial report after falling below the issue price. For a time, there was a lot of discussion about the bursting of the unicorn bubble. WeWork’s plans to go public have been put on hold indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Neumann resigned as CEO and new management was brought in to help restructure the company&#39;s leasing business. It wasn&#39;t until October 2021 that WeWork finally went public with a valuation of US$9 billion. However, going public is not a panacea. Instead, it has become a magnifying glass that continues to expose problems. Although WeWork has always regarded itself as a technology company, it has never been able to achieve non-linear growth relying on its own profits, and its business model has not departed from the category of asset-heavy commercial real estate leasing. WeWork&#39;s customers are mainly small and entrepreneurial institutions with weak risk resistance and high liquidity. As competition in the industry becomes increasingly fierce, WeWork has to face the problem of price reductions and rising costs in order to retain these customers who are extremely cost-sensitive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The COVID-19 epidemic broke out around the world in 2020, and working from home became a common trend. The economic recession caused a large number of customers to close their businesses, and the office vacancy rate increased sharply. As a &quot;second landlord&quot;, WeWork still needs to pay rent to the landlord. WeWork, which emerged from the previous crisis, became a victim of the new crisis. Maturity mismatch may bring huge profits during economic booms, but it is a heavy burden during economic downturns, and the Federal Reserve&#39;s several rounds of interest rate hikes since the epidemic have exacerbated WeWork&#39;s debt burden. The long-standing systemic risks have ushered in a concentrated outbreak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/gjloiN0n5FG6LPE2jsj5YWdTUDrfDfeu0wMnJf7h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/gjloiN0n5FG6LPE2jsj5YWdTUDrfDfeu0wMnJf7h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258716&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On April 12, 2018, WeWork co-founder Neumann visited Shanghai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, WeWork pointed out in its second-quarter financial report that taking into account losses and expected cash needs, coupled with increased membership losses and current liquidity levels, the company&#39;s continued operations depend on management. Whether the company can improve its liquidity and profitability over the next 12 months. As of June 30, the company still had $2.9 billion in long-term debt and $13.3 billion in long-term lease debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;WeWork CEO David Tolley believes that &quot;unsustainable leases must be repriced&quot; due to a lack of &quot;the necessary financial flexibility to adapt to the rapidly changing commercial real estate market.&quot; Filing for bankruptcy protection is WeWork&#39;s attempt to survive in adversity. WeWork is seeking court approval to terminate 69 leases that are &quot;substantially unable to operate&quot; and negotiate with more than 400 landlords to modify existing leases. Analysts generally believe that WeWork’s exit will lead to a further increase in the already high office vacancy rate, which will have a negative impact on the cash flow and value of office buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a cycle. While the market is enthusiastically discussing the butterfly effect caused by the WeWork crisis, competitors are more willing to regard WeWork&#39;s &quot;big defeat&quot; as an &quot;episode&quot; in industry changes, or even as an opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The great irony of WeWork’s bankruptcy is that it happened at a time of record performance for the industry.” Jamie Hodari, CEO of Industrious, a New York-based shared office operator, told the Financial Times &quot;I made a metaphor during the interview, &quot;When a Marriott hotel is not doing well, it will become a Hyatt hotel.&quot; Mark Dixon, CEO of IWG Group, who is also a shared office operator, said in an interview with the BBC, IWG has now acquired and relaunched 40 office spaces that were once part of WeWork. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the lessons learned from WeWork, the shift from the asset-heavy model of &quot;direct leasing&quot; to the light-asset model of &quot;profit sharing&quot; has been a common effort in the industry in recent years, and now it is even more urgent. However, whether owners are willing to accept this adjustment still depends on their comprehensive assessment of the economic environment and operational value. A recent report released by IWG shows that 200 of the 204 new office spaces it signed in the third quarter of 2023 are asset-light operations, but overall, 60% are still operated by traditional leasing methods. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chinese market, WeWork China also hopes to become the traffic entrance in the stock era. &quot;The business model that only relies on rent difference is very difficult, but this is also our core competitiveness and advantage,&quot; Quan Bin, vice president of WeWork Greater China, said in a recent interview with &quot;Guandian New Media&quot; that companies must survive To achieve better and longer results, we must work faster and more resolutely in reducing costs and increasing efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/aXaJ158QLVgKsFL7LpYGSCNn5DIyBk8rsjRTmAeT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/aXaJ158QLVgKsFL7LpYGSCNn5DIyBk8rsjRTmAeT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258718&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai, WeWork joint shared office space&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Huang Weilai He said that while the decrease in rent costs is a good thing, it also reflects the downturn in the real estate industry. Huang Wei&#39;s entrepreneurial project involves architectural design, and the quality of his business is closely related to the ups and downs of the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2019, Huang Wei returned to China from the Netherlands and worked successively in a European and American architectural design company and a local design studio. &quot;Party A is not doing well, and it is even more difficult for those who provide design services downstream. The number of projects that can be received has shrunk severely, and the industry is seriously involved. If you want to survive, you must either sink or shrink. Even if you can get orders, The price/performance ratio is also very low. Many of my classmates and friends have changed careers.&quot; In early 2022, Huang Wei and two other partners co-founded Miaoqi Design Studio. Faced with uncertainty and the threshold of 30 years old, Huang Wei still persistently wants to try again in the industry he loves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After starting a business for more than a year, he has been sharing his entrepreneurial experience on social media. This small office relocation incident was also edited into a short video by him. At the end of the video, he talked about his views on this &quot;uncertain era.&quot; Unexpectedly, this became one of his most watched videos recently. Private messages poured in like snowflakes. Many comments expressed their empathy for such sudden changes. Of course, there are more &quot;advertisers&quot; selling his office space to him. According to CBRE&#39;s forecast, the new supply of Shanghai&#39;s office market in the second half of 2023 is expected to exceed 950,000 square meters, the highest level in the past decade. Demand is weak, supply is increasing, and the office market is still in a slow recovery period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Wei quickly crossed the message board. The sudden closure of offices pales in comparison to the pressure to continue operations. His lease is signed until September 2024. 2023 is about to pass, and the intensity of competition in the industry is far more intense than last year. At the bidding meeting, master-level firms competed for it, and it has become very common to choose one of two to three hundred proposals. How about next year? He still &quot;has hope.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 14:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[梁静茹演唱会“柱子票”案开庭：主办方是否应提前告知成焦点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260853]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In May this year, many viewers reported that they bought &quot;pillar tickets&quot; at Leung Jingru&#39;s Shanghai concert, and the view was It was obscured by the pillars surrounding the stage, causing heated discussions. On November 17, Ms. Li, who bought the &quot;pillar ticket&quot;, told Nandu reporters that a total of nine audience members filed lawsuits against the concert organizer, Shanghai Rubik&#39;s Cube Pan-Cultural Performing Arts Co., Ltd. On November 15, the first instance of the Meilong People&#39;s Court of the Minhang District People&#39;s Court of Shanghai opened in public to hear the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/67dacecd2e0c7f3166cf55332857d456.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/67dacecd2e0c7f3166cf55332857d456.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258728&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On-site picture of the &quot;pillar ticket&quot; provided by Ms. Li. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;9 viewers sued the concert organizer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On May 20th and 21st this year, the 2023 Leung Jingru World Tour Concert was held in Shanghai held, many audience members reported that after arriving, they found that their view was blocked by the pillars around the stage, and &quot;looking at the singers became like looking at the pillars.&quot; Some netizens posted on social platforms saying, &quot;I spent 1,599 to win the pillar position at Liang Jingru&#39;s concert&quot; and &quot;I spent 1,599 to buy something bad&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, Ms. Li, a concert attendee, told Nandu reporters that nine audience members, including herself, filed lawsuits against the concert organizer, Shanghai Rubik&#39;s Pan-Cultural Performing Arts Co., Ltd., demanding reasonable refunds. payment and compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 15, the first instance of the Meilong People’s Court of the Minhang District People’s Court of Shanghai opened in public to hear the case. Ms. Li said, &quot;The result of the court trial has not yet been announced. We are waiting for the organizer&#39;s mediation plan. If we still cannot accept the plan they propose, we will wait for the court&#39;s decision.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li introduced that this Among the 9 spectators who filed the lawsuit this time, 6 were spectators of the May 20th matinee and 3 were spectators of the May 21st matinee. The ticket prices included 1,299 yuan, 999 yuan, etc. &quot;We submitted materials to the court in early August to apply for filing a case, and received news of the court filing the case at the end of August. We all met through social media, and because the early negotiations with the organizer failed, we had no choice but to choose to sue. We wanted to We need to find out whether the organizer has violated our legitimate rights and interests.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li said that she purchased two tickets for the second-floor stand worth 1,299 yuan on May 20, and the attendance rate that day was quite high. The photo shows that in the middle of Ms. Li&#39;s field of vision is a hollow pillar, and the singer can be vaguely seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Nandu reporter searched for the seat distribution map and found that the two diagonal lines formed by the four corners were basically blocked by pillars, but this was not marked on the page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the organizer, Shanghai Rubik&#39;s Cube Pan-Cultural Performing Arts Co., Ltd., has responded that it is only responsible for the implementation of Liang Jingru&#39;s Shanghai concert, and the stage will not be built by the company. During the ticket sales stage, the company did not know that the stage design would have four pillars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li told Nandu reporters that the organizer had said that within the coverage area approved by it, a 200 yuan shopping card would be given as a token of appreciation. &quot;No matter what the price of the ticket, only 200 yuan will be compensated.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The focus of the dispute is whether the organizer should inform in advance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 15, during the court hearing of the case, the two sides focused on &quot;whether the organizer should notify Court investigations and debates were conducted on controversial issues such as informing in advance the existence of &#39;pillar tickets&#39; and whether these locations would affect the concert experience.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li introduced to Nandu reporters that the nine plaintiffs&#39; requests mainly include three aspects - requesting an order to order the defendant to return the plaintiff&#39;s concert ticket money; ordering the defendant to pay punitive damages to the plaintiff; ordering the defendant to pay punitive damages to the plaintiff; Bear the litigation costs of this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plaintiff’s attorney said that the focus of this case is whether the defendant informed all the plaintiffs in advance whether their views would be blocked. The plaintiff’s purpose for attending the concert was to “see” it, and having his view blocked was a very serious breach of contract. The plaintiff&#39;s right to know was violated, resulting in the loss of the right to choose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defendant’s attorney said that the reason why the performance used load-bearing columns was because the venue’s ceiling was not load-bearing enough. Without the load-bearing columns on the ground, the performance would not have been able to be held normally and would not have passed the safety approval. So the ground load-bearing columns were used. Columns are also common practice in the industry. &quot;It is common sense that certain positions in the auditorium will inevitably block the view. The defendant has never deliberately mentioned in the publicity that there are no pillars or obstructions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plaintiff believes that the design and layout of the scene It should have been completed earlier. Before the concert begins, the organizer should also fulfill its corresponding responsibilities, inform consumers whose vision will be blocked, and ask them whether they want a refund or other solutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defendant’s attorney stated that the defendant set up the stage mainly for safety reasons and did not intentionally deceive the audience. Moreover, this performance is the first stop of a series of tours, and they cannot be harshly criticized for considering so many things in advance. details. The response methods for other subsequent performances were improved after being affected by this performance. The first stop cannot be required based on the handling plan for subsequent performances; nor can it be considered that the defendant did not inform the defendant in advance just because the line of sight was blocked at some individual performances. There is an intention to deceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 3 pm on the 15th, the trial of this case ended, but the verdict was not pronounced in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The China Consumers Association has criticized the phenomenon of &quot;pillar tickets&quot; by name&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Concert organizers have dealt with &quot;pillar tickets&quot; differently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nandu previously reported that on August 14 this year, Shanxi Xingtai Lighting Culture and Entertainment Co., Ltd., the organizer of Jay Chou&#39;s 2023 Carnival World Tour Concert in Hohhot, issued an announcement saying that it would meet the needs of fans and allow more Fans can experience the joyful atmosphere of the concert live and reduce congestion outside the concert. After coordinating and fighting with all parties, the organizer will sell the seats with poor visibility in the area blocked by the sound console at a special discount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the organizer stated in the announcement that the viewing angle of the seats in this area is affected by the sound console and is blocked to varying degrees. It is impossible to fully see the entire stage. A large screen is set up behind the sound console for the convenience of the audience. Watch, special discounted tickets are non-refundable and non-exchangeable after purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 2, the China Consumers Association criticized the phenomenon of various &quot;pillar tickets&quot; and &quot;wall tickets&quot;, pointing out that consumers encountered &quot;blind selection&quot; of seats when purchasing performance tickets online, and some performance venues did not support consumption. The visitor chose his seat when purchasing the ticket, but when he arrived at the venue, he learned that what he had purchased was a &quot;pillar ticket&quot; or a &quot;wall ticket&quot; with blind spots, which caused a ticketing problem of &quot;only sounds but no people&quot; throughout the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Consumers Association said that relevant performance ticketing platforms and organizers should consider how to better protect the rights and interests of consumers and improve the consumer experience from the perspective of promoting the release of consumption potential. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 陈云生：宪法监督的研究任务依然任重道远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chen Yunsheng, the first Ph.D. in constitutional law in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1942 in Pinggu County, Beijing (now Pinggu District);&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1966, graduated from the Law Department of Beijing Institute of Political Science and Law (now China University of Political Science and Law); worked in Guangxi after graduation Served in judicial, education, and administrative work; in 1978, he was admitted to the Law Department of the Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences for further study. After graduating with a master&#39;s degree, Worked at the Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences; in 1983, he studied for a doctorate in constitutional law under the tutelage of the jurist Zhang Youyu; , STKaiti;&quot;>;Received a doctorate in law in 1987;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as a professor of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences Deputy director, professor and doctoral supervisor of the Constitutional Administrative Law Research Office of the Institute of Law, part-time professor and doctoral supervisor at 7 universities including Shanghai Jiao Tong University Law School and Beijing Normal University Law School, and honorary expert advisory member of the Expert Advisory Committee of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. Enjoy special allowances from the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yunsheng was in his study in the suburbs of Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Chen Yifan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/018fc437d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/16/018fc437d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258522&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yunsheng In a study in the suburbs of Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Chen Yifan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;81-year-old Chen Yunsheng seldom rests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;His days start at four or five in the morning, walking briskly, cooking, reading and writing in Pinggu District on the outskirts of Beijing, leading a regular old age life. He planted beans, sweet potatoes, pumpkins and corn on a piece of wasteland he &quot;claimed&quot;, and irrigated and cultivated it from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The interest in farming stems from his background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This rural boy, born in Pinggu in 1942, is the first high school student, the first college student, and the first doctor of law in the village. In 1966, after graduating from Beijing University of Political Science and Law (now China University of Political Science and Law), he was assigned to rural areas in Guangxi, where he ate and lived with farmers, waking up to the steaming heat of beef and feces every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the country resumed the postgraduate examination, he relied on a &quot;survived&quot; constitutional law tutorial and was admitted to the law school of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences with the first score in the reexamination. graduate School. Later, he studied for a doctorate and became the only student of the famous legal scholar Zhang Youyu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During this period, he read all the professional books in the law school and went from a &quot;minion&quot; in constitutional law to &quot;the first person in the country to supervise the constitution.&quot; In 1980, he participated in the formulation of the &quot;82nd Constitution&quot; amendment. He always believed that the true meaning of the Constitution did not lie in the constitutional document itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On his academic journey, he did not like to participate in administrative affairs and turned away many opportunities. He laughs at himself as &quot;a lonely ghost in academia&quot;, who only seeks to achieve the ultimate in knowledge and will never be swayed by trends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He advised students to endure loneliness. He always followed the third item of Descartes&#39; code of conduct: he always only sought to overcome himself, not to overcome fate, but only to change his own desires, not to change the order of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;God helps me&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After retirement, what is your daily life like now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I usually get up at four in the morning, have something to eat, and then go to the river. exercise. I used to run or walk. After I got seriously ill in May or June this year and was exhausted, I cycled for an hour to exercise. Then come back to research or write for an hour, then make breakfast and clean up. After breakfast, I go to work in the fields, usually for two hours, and then come back to continue my research. Two days ago, I was still harvesting vegetables grown in the fields. After lunch break, I worked at my desk again. Then I went to the fields to do some work, and then rode a bike for exercise in the evening. There are no weekends or holidays, and I don’t know what day of the week it is every day. It has been the same day for decades. For me, going out to give lectures and attend societies is also a rare way to rest. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; There are not many old people like you who are still farming in their eighties. Why do you live such a life as a farmer? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My family has been poor farmers for generations. There are five brothers in the family, and I am the second oldest. When I was a child, Confucius said, &quot;I am a young man, so I can do many despicable things.&quot; In addition to going to school, I had to help the family with work, planting fields, harvesting wild vegetables, chopping firewood, feeding pigs and cows, and I did all the work that rural children do. Pass. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I was about to enter middle school, a junior high school was established in a neighboring village. Children from the eastern, southern and northern areas of Pinggu could go to school. As a result, after we registered, Found that there was only an open space. The first thing we do when we go to school is dig the foundation and build the house. It took more than half a year to have a classroom and a canteen, and a simple basketball court was built. The students borrowed villagers&#39; houses as dormitories and kitchens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, the school funds were not enough, and there happened to be a shoe factory that made cloth shoes, so we contracted part of the factory&#39;s projects. My shoemaking skills were relatively good, so I was made a supervisor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the high school entrance examination, the whole county accepted more than a hundred high school students. I was the first in the village to pass the high school entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the college entrance examination, only three subjects: mathematics, Chinese and chemistry. In the summer, I lay on the field or on the hillside and looked at the clear sky. Meteors came one after another, and the Milky Way was clearly visible. So when I applied for my college application, my first choice was the astronomy department, but only a few people were recruited, so I failed. Beijing University of Political Science and Law was my last choice. My grades were up to standard and I was admitted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your time What is college like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I entered school in 1962. The schooling system was first 5 years and then changed to 4 years. , mainly studied political and legal subjects. In the first two years, he studied Marxism and criticized revisionism. During this period, he also organized a trip to Emei County, Sichuan (now Emeishan City) to carry out the &quot;Four Clean-ups&quot; movement. After graduating from college, I was assigned to Guangxi, but the receiving unit in Guangxi sent a telegram: &quot;Please postpone your registration.&quot; This was postponed for two years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; When you went to Guangxi two years later, what impressed you most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just arrived at my workplace in Guangxi. I haven’t settled in yet and haven’t unpacked my luggage yet. The leader organized employees to beat gongs and drums and send me to the countryside to receive education from poor and lower-middle peasants and undergo labor training. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I was assigned to a village on the China-Vietnam border, eating and living with farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I live on the lower floor of the building, with the soles of my feet facing the cowshed. The space under my bed is not wasted, and I have a litter of puppies, which are close to my ears. It&#39;s the chicken coop next door. At three or four o&#39;clock in the morning, a cow started to defecate. The smell of feces was steaming, and it immediately spread to the entire building. Then the dog under my bed also started to defecate. These are small things. I clean up dog excrement every morning. Cow dung smells bad, but it doesn’t touch my body. The most difficult thing is the rooster, which makes me unable to rest. &lt;p>; Like a decent and authentic farmer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;My biggest achievement in rural Guangxi is that I endured hunger and hardship, tempered my perseverance, and laid a solid foundation for my subsequent development in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did you decide to participate? Postgraduate examination? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After two years in the countryside, I returned to the county and later Go to rural areas and serve as a member of the basic humanities education team. Although I went to college, I had no room for improvement and felt that my personal future was bleak. On the other hand, I have a strong sense of ruralism and cannot leave my hometown, so I still want to return to the north for development. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​day in 1977, my wife suddenly asked someone to bring me a message from the county seat, saying that the country wanted to recruit graduate students. I learned about it and it was indeed an opportunity. But I didn’t study very well in college. I stayed in the countryside for another 10 years without reading newspapers or listening to the radio. I thought at that time that the number of undergraduates we graduated in 1962 was more than 400. If we add those who graduated two or three years ago, there would be more than 1,000. Many of these people have married and established businesses, and many have become leaders and have stable incomes and families. Therefore, there are definitely not many people who applied for the exam, probably only a hundred or so. I decided to give it a try and reported it to the county leader. He was very supportive and let me go back to the county to prepare for the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After all, put down the book for ten How many years have passed, how to prepare for the exam? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There was only two months of preparation time. The first problem was, I I can&#39;t find any books, especially no professional books to read. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another problem is English. The English I learned in college is basically wasted. I borrowed junior high school textbooks and started learning from ABCD. I was completely unsure. After studying for two or three months, I thought I had made some progress and was ready to take the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then how to deal with it in the end What about the exam? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The day before the exam, I was still memorizing textbooks, the 1975 Constitution and the Some newspaper articles. God helped me with the exam questions. I remember that the title of the essay at that time was &quot;Follow Chairman Hua on the New Long March&quot;, and the legal theory examination question only had five words - &quot;The French Civil War&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Leading the new Long March, the compositions are all relatively familiar political discourse. Naturally, whether it will be difficult for the candidates depends on their personal performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the preparation for the exam, I borrowed some Marxist-Leninist books. I have repeatedly read the articles about proletarian revolution and proletarian dictatorship in the book, such as &quot;Critique of the Gotha Program&quot; and &quot;The French Civil War&quot;, and have gained a lot of experience, so it is natural to answer the jurisprudence exam questions smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I was left with no knowledge of English, so I was happy as soon as I opened the test paper. It was an English report from the &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; about learning from Dazhai in agriculture. I don’t speak English well, but I am very familiar with the feats of Dazhai people in transforming the world and the professional terms involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, if you were asked to translate &quot;seven ditches and eight beams&quot;, I don&#39;t know the English words for &quot;gou&quot; and &quot;liang&quot;, but when I saw &quot;seven (seven)&quot; )&quot; and &quot;eight&quot;, I immediately knew that this must be Qigou Baliang, and I passed the English test at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After the adoption of the 1982 Constitution, &quot;little fame&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is life as a graduate student different from what you imagined? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Goed to school on September 1, 1978, and registered at the Law Institute of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences Later, I discovered that there was no school building for graduate students. The school leaders went to Beijing Normal University to borrow space. We built a simple classroom with linoleum in the open space between other people&#39;s buildings, and borrowed the building to use as a dormitory, with 8 people in one room. This is how study and life at the postgraduate level are settled. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than a year later, the Graduate School of the Academy of Social Sciences also found it inconvenient, so they asked us to move out and live in Beijing No. 11 School again. go. Usually, we go to the School of Law of the Academy of Social Sciences for classes and come back after class. I study for 12 hours a day, exercise for 2 hours in the morning and evening, and sleep for 6 hours. After studying hard for three years, my academic performance was quite good, and the school leaders were quite satisfied with it. After graduating with a master&#39;s degree in 1980, I stayed at the law school to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is related to undergraduate graduation Later I was assigned to work in rural areas of Guangxi, and my experience was completely different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s true, especially when I entered the work and formulated 82 Working on the Constitution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; What specific jobs have you been involved in? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The work of amending the Constitution was mainly led by the then Deputy Chairman of the Legislative Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. The director, Mr. Zhang Youyu, is in charge, and a secretariat is set up to be responsible for research and drafting work. At that time, Wang Shuwen, director of the Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, was a member of the Secretariat, so Zhang Youyu naturally handed over some of the academic research and data preparation work of the Secretariat directly to Wang Shuwen. Every time Wang Shuwen received a task, he hurried back to the law school and called all the staff to divide the work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The five of us are generally not allowed to leave the unit and stick to our jobs 24 hours a day. As soon as they come, we are instructed to conduct research immediately and write research day and night. Report, at that time we could only take a brief rest in the office. It was late at night, and we bought a bowl of instant noodles to eat by ourselves. At that time, it was difficult to find information, and the academic world was in a state of desolation. There were books transferred from Tsinghua University and Peking University in the law school. No one had read them for more than 20 years. The dust was an inch thick, so I dug through the dust to look for information. From the beginning of preparations in 1980 to the completion of the constitutional amendment in 1982, we persisted in this way for more than two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The process of constitution-making is complicated. We are only doing the most preliminary work. After the report is submitted, experts from the Secretariat will collect opinions from all parties and then bring it up to the leadership level. After the draft was passed, the People&#39;s Daily published a total of three solicitations for opinions. At that time, people were very enthusiastic about participation, and they may have hoped that through the formulation and implementation of the Constitution, the social disorder and national chaos like the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; could be ended forever. During the public participation in the discussion, more than 3,000 opinions were collected, and some people even suggested which words and punctuation should be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Participated in the formulation of the 1982 Constitution Has the related work had any impact on you personally? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; After the adoption of the 82 Constitution, the Constitution suddenly became a major event that attracted national attention. First of all, there was a lot of publicity. At that time, even &quot;little minions&quot; like me published hundreds of articles on tofu cubes in newspapers. Publishing houses have also requested manuscripts from us, from leaders to experts to little people like us. I was extensively involved in publishing dozens of pamphlets promoting the new constitution. In the process, I became &quot;a little famous&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Speaking of Mr. Zhang Youyu, what special impression do you have of him? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because of the amendment of the Constitution, I had contact with Mr. Zhang Youyu, who was eight years old at the time. When he was more than ten years old, he thought the articles I wrote were more interesting, so he liked to ask me to help him write manuscripts, and then he would revise them. I actually took on the job of his writing secretary. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 1982, leaders of the State Council advocated the cultivation of academic successors by several senior experts in the traditional &quot;master-apprentice&quot; format. Mr. Zhang Youyu chose me at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After more than a year of studying, the country changed the inherited master-apprentice model and officially changed it to a modern doctoral education system. I took the state-mandated doctoral examination, which included jurisprudence, constitutional law, English and politics. I was the only candidate and thus became his doctoral candidate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;As a scholar, we must maintain a &quot;normal mind&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt; strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You studied constitutional law with Mr. Zhang. How did you later pay specific attention to constitutional supervision? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because after the implementation of the 1982 Constitution, it is only a textual legal provision. However, whether the implementation process of government agencies is just and rational, and whether the implementation and supervision mechanism of the Constitution are scientific, all need to be continued to study. Naturally, I entered into the study of the theory of constitutional supervision. Judicialization of constitutional supervision has been my main focus for more than ten years. I have published three books, one of which is my revised and expanded doctoral thesis. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fate of constitutional law is to deal with the highest power of the country. At that time, I strongly advocated changing the Legal Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress into the Constitution and Law Committee. This was proposed by me, and was repeatedly demonstrated by generations of constitutional scholars. In 2018, the &quot;Constitution and Law Committee&quot; was finally established in the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think about academics? Relations with politics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Academics cannot be separated from society, nor can they be completely isolated from politics. There are quite a few scholars who place their main academic interests and attention on directly serving real-life politics and law. This is understandable. Of course, people need to study practical problems. This is also a university knowledge, and it is a more difficult knowledge. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;The problem is that people who do this kind of knowledge should adjust their mentality. You must be mentally prepared that not all research reports and suggestions for improvement that address practical issues should or may be accepted and adopted by the relevant political decision-making bodies. We have said that theoretical conclusions and political decisions do not always coincide. Theoretically, it is necessary to study physics carefully and observe the subtle details, while in politics, it is necessary to weigh the pros and cons, pursue advantages and avoid disadvantages. The two stand on different positions and pursue different value goals, so the conclusions and decisions will naturally be different. As a scholar, it is important to maintain a &quot;normal mind.&quot; It is naturally a happy and encouraging thing to have your opinions adopted. Even if your opinions are not adopted, you should not feel disappointed or discouraged. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; As far as you&#39;re concerned, what&#39;s the fun in learning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My book has been published. If someone reads it and experiences it, do you think it’s good? Just accept it, if it’s not good then reject it. However, we do not consider its impact when doing scholarship. That is a matter of whether contemporaries and future generations agree with it. It may be thirty or fifty years before anyone is interested in reading the book I wrote in depth. I know that at that time there was a scholar who had done such research and had such advanced ideological understanding. I don’t expect anyone of this generation to understand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Doing academic work is not only for gaining practical benefits, but also for learning. &quot;Liangzhizhi&quot; and a means to support my family. In addition to doing academic work, I also want to increase my knowledge. I groped forward according to my own research ideas, had the courage to explore, studied all my life, and was willing to be lonely. I would never be moved by the trend or follow the trend. So I laughed at myself at a certain society and said that I was a lonely ghost in the academic world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;I just want to learn this knowledge thoroughly and achieve what I think As mature as you are, you can enjoy it. My students said that 30 years later, they are still studying the topic of &quot;constitutional supervision&quot; that I studied at the time. Because the research task of constitutional supervision has a long way to go. In my academic career, I have gone through a meaningful and tortuous path. If I can achieve the ultimate in this aspect of knowledge, it will be a blessing to be able to masturbate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;For this reason I am&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nowadays, young people, whether they are looking for a job or taking postgraduate entrance examinations, are facing fierce competition, and they are also relatively confused. . What advice do you have for young people? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have taught at Beijing Normal University for seven or eight years, and I have a deep understanding of this situation. When a master&#39;s degree or doctorate is admitted, the first thing to do is to take exams, such as judicial qualification certificate, computer certificate, IELTS, etc. You have to take five or six certificates in three years, so how can you have time to study and read? Now that you&#39;ve almost passed the certification exam, it&#39;s time to send out your resume and look for a job. He waited until two weeks before the defense of his master&#39;s thesis before he hurriedly put together the paper, and its quality can be imagined. I always tell students that if they study well, they will not have to worry about finding a job in the future, and gold will shine. This society must always be supported by people with knowledge and vision. But secondly, the competition in society is so fierce that people will be unemployed immediately after graduation. Nowadays, many people deliver food after graduating from Ph.D., which is very realistic. If you set your starting point so low in the beginning and just find a job to support your family, how can our society progress? In the past, we talked about &quot;I think, therefore I am&quot;, but now I think it is &quot;I am, therefore I am&quot;. The reason why you are who you are is because of the things you have done. Personal self-realization and success always require a lot of effort or even a lifetime of effort. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the current master&#39;s and doctoral training system? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think our current training system is a kind of indoctrination education, and it is strict and strict. out. When I was studying for a Ph.D., the teachers only had one class every three to five weeks. They mainly relied on themselves to go out to listen to lectures and academic conferences, and tried their best to expand their knowledge. When I was studying in the United States, the school invited a professor from another school or our own school to give a keynote speech during lunch every day. Others listened while eating, or put down their knives and forks and raised their hands to ask questions, and no minute was wasted. Today’s students are also less active in participating in academic activities. Therefore, the main difference between the current and previous training models is that one is indoctrination and the other is heuristic; one is open and the other is closed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏205国道将收费引质疑：公共福利易涨难降，能否推进有待观察丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260825]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a toll station was built on the Huai&#39;an section of 205 National Highway in Suqian, Jiangsu, and the news that vehicle tolls will be collected soon has aroused social concern. great concern and doubt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to China Jiangsu Net, on October 20, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved that after the Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is completed and meets the traffic conditions, it will be managed as a government loan repayment road and jointly operated by Suqian and Huaian. Charges have been set and the charging standards for various types of vehicles have been determined, ranging from 10 yuan to 50 yuan. Media reports indicate that the toll station has been built. This means that tolls may be activated on this section of the national highway at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New toll stations on national highways! Many people believe that this is contrary to the country&#39;s policy of gradually canceling ordinary highway toll stations in recent years. However, the Jiangsu Provincial Transportation Department stated that the toll collection of first-class highways for which the government repays loans complies with the policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot;, roads constructed by the government using loans or paid funds raised from enterprises and individuals can collect tolls upon approval. The Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were built with government loans. According to the Jiangsu Transportation Department, this section still has nearly 1 billion yuan in debt to be repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the historical context of the Suhuai Toll Station on National Highway 205, we can find that the toll collection on this section is not a recent decision. In the early 2010s, the Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were successively renovated and expanded and upgraded to first-class highways. In 2014, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved in a document the establishment of a toll station at the junction of National Highway 205 Huai&#39;an and Suqian, and the two cities will jointly charge fees. In 2018, the Jiangsu Provincial Development and Reform Commission approved the feasibility report for the construction of the toll station. Today, the toll station is built and the provincial government issues documents approving the toll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the minds of many people, only expressways still charge tolls, and all other ordinary highway toll stations have been abolished. However, in fact, there are not only ordinary highway toll stations, but they have increased in the past two years. According to information released on the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial Department of Transportation, as of December 2022, there are still more than 10 national and provincial highway toll stations in Jiangsu Province. Also on National Highway 205, more than 90 kilometers north of Suhuai Toll Station, there is Xinyi Toll Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Toll Road Statistical Bulletin of the Ministry of Transport, at the end of 2021, there were 308 first-level highway main line toll stations and 115 second-level highway main line toll stations across the country. Compared with the end of the previous year, there were 308 second-level highway main line toll stations. The number of toll stations decreased by 7, but there were 8 more toll stations on first-class highways. The total mileage of tolled first-class highways was 17,600 kilometers, an increase of more than 200 kilometers over the previous year. Media reports show that since 2022, at least 7 new national highway toll stations have been added in various provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in recent years, it has become a trend to cancel tolls on ordinary highways. The central government has repeatedly proposed reducing road transportation costs and reducing road and bridge tolls. As early as 2009, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Transport and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued a document calling for the gradual and orderly elimination of tolls on secondary roads for government loan repayment. The revised draft of the &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot; released in 2018 stipulates that the construction of new first- and second-level toll roads and independent bridges and tunnels will be stopped, and only expressways can collect tolls. However, this revision has not yet been completed. In 2020, the General Office of the State Council forwarded the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Further Reducing Logistics Costs&quot; from the National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Transport, once again requesting to ensure that the overall burden of truck tolls is not increased. Under these policies, a large number of toll plazas have been eliminated across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, although Jiangsu’s new 205 National Highway Suhuai Toll Station collects fees, it is not impossible to rely on it. Although the project was established based on loans for road construction and toll repayment at the beginning of the reconstruction and expansion, the funds mainly came from banks. Loans, and there are still huge loans that have not been repaid, but this is now and then. In the early 2010s, the construction and reconstruction of first- and second-level toll roads was still allowed, but after a few years the policy has changed. Except for expressways, the central government has discouraged and even explicitly proposed to stop the construction of first- and second-level toll roads, and many places have also canceled them. A large number of toll stations on primary and secondary roads have been installed. Especially in the past year or two, due to the impact of the epidemic, the economy is struggling to recover. Under such circumstances, adding new toll stations and increasing public transportation costs will of course be questioned by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is no explicit regulation, &quot;national highways, provincial highways and other ordinary highways should be free of charge&quot; has become &quot;common sense&quot; in the public mind, just like highways are free on holidays. Once this kind of psychological expectation is formed, if you want to reverse it, you will certainly be questioned. It is easy to bring welfare from scratch, but it is difficult to bring it from existence to nothing. It is easy to go from paid to free, but difficult to go from free to paid. If the previously charged service is changed to free, the public will think they have benefited. But conversely, if it was free before and now it has to be charged, everyone will feel that their interests have been violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is true not only in public policy, but also in business. Since the birth of the Internet, various services have been almost free for ordinary users. Netizens are accustomed to enjoying free services. Once charges start to be charged, they will of course feel very unhappy if they have to pay to watch videos or use large-capacity, high-speed download network disks. Broadband and data traffic have been charged from the beginning, and no one thinks these should be free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a truly free lunch does not actually exist. If you want to watch free videos, you have to endure a lot of ads; if you want to use a free network disk, you can only endure the download speed of a small water pipe. Likewise, public benefits also need to be paid for by someone. There are no tolls on national highways, and construction and maintenance costs are indispensable. They can only come from fiscal revenue such as taxes, which means taxpayers must pay for them. If the local government&#39;s fiscal revenue is sufficient, then of course it won&#39;t be a problem. But if finances are tight, I&#39;m afraid we can only reduce spending on road construction and maintenance, or consider charging fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is preparing to collect fees at this time, which may be related to the local financial difficulties in recent years. But it remains to be seen whether it can move forward after attracting huge attention and opposition. Although Suqian and Huai&#39;an are in northern Jiangsu and are less economically developed than southern Jiangsu, they are still much more prosperous than many places in the west. There is still 1 billion in road construction loans, which may not be too big for local finances. of holes. What&#39;s more, Jiangsu, as the country&#39;s second largest economic province, should have enough financial resources to make transfer payments to local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if no tolls are allowed on national and provincial roads in the future, will the enthusiasm of local governments to build new roads be greatly reduced? This is also worth noting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[的里雅斯特：微型世界丨意长意短]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/gFlg06M7cgduE6nvUXaxWXkllUq2SXgeMB5ummeC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/gFlg06M7cgduE6nvUXaxWXkllUq2SXgeMB5um meC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258623&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Trieste in 1895. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time I pass through Trieste, I have to go and sit for a while in the ancient San Marco Cafe . This city has the best coffee in Italy, and the headquarters of Illy is here. Like many cities that were once glorious and then fell into silence, this city is half reality and half exists in words. Trieste was once the most important port of the Austro-Hungarian Empire and a blend of Slavic, Latin and Germanic cultures. More than a hundred kilometers away, Venice has kept the world&#39;s attention in a flashy way. Although every stone that built it came from elsewhere, and all the beauty is artificial, the first sight of Venice will make you wonder. One feels amazed and mesmerized. In comparison, Trieste is a sleepy city. She is located in the northeastern border of Italy, more than ten kilometers away in Slovenia. It faces the sea, backed by karst rocks, and under the mountains are checkerboard-like neighborhoods. There are many deep houses and compounds on the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;James Morris, an Englishman who served as a soldier here, later changed his gender and became Jane Morris. After World War II, she wrote full-time and became a reporter for The Guardian and a famous travel writer. In her book &quot;Trieste and the Meaning of Nowhere&quot; (Trieste and the Meaning of Nowhere), Trieste is an unforgettable city, but when she tried to remember it, she found that it was like an unforgettable city. Presented face. This city has no unforgettable scenery, no unique food, and it doesn’t even have an Italian flavor. In a 1999 survey, 70% of Italians didn’t even know that this city belongs to Italy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, Trieste also has her unique charm. This former free port chose to be included in Italy during the dispute between Yugoslavia and Italy in the last century. The chaotic past can stimulate people&#39;s imagination and reflection. She is more literary than any other city. At the beginning of the last century, Joyce lived in many places in this city. He worked as an English teacher and began to write &quot;Ulysses&quot; here. For him, Trieste was a particularly draining place for his liver. Joyce interacted with the melancholy Italo Svevo, encouraged the Jewish businessman to write, and highly praised his &quot;Zeno&#39;s Consciousness&quot;. Svevo&#39;s writing has a slowness that is rare in Italian. Most of the writing is about a businessman questioning his own conscience, which complements the thoughtfulness of a stream-of-consciousness novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a kind of continuity in the literature of this city. The writings of contemporary Trieste writer Claudio Magris also have the melancholy of Svevo, and his works are very similar to It was translated from German into Italian, which is not surprising since Magris is a professor of German literature at the university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a writer wants to present a city, it is actually difficult to capture its spirit and soul. Magris has been telling stories about the land. As the most important seaport in the Austro-Hungarian Empire, Trieste&#39;s once glorious history made her current situation look bleak, and the entire city was shrouded in a twilight. Magris&#39;s writing is, in a sense, a pursuit of Trieste&#39;s literary tradition and an attempt to get closer to reality. His &quot;Micro World&quot;, which won the &quot;Strega&quot; award but is difficult to classify, has many texts related to the space of the city and the literature of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult for a person with limited life experience to establish a deep connection with the vast world. Sociologist Xiang Biao proposed the concept of &quot;nearness&quot;. Magris is an example of practicing &quot;neighborhood&quot;. He lives in this city and uses the tenacity of a scholar to understand the place and penetrate deeply into the life here. His &quot;miniature world&quot; actually consists of cafes, parks and Sacré Coeur. After reading his &quot;Micro World&quot; and then seeing the San Marco Cafe, the park and the nearby Sacré Coeur, you will recognize everything and feel that the world is what he described. The San Marco Cafe, which opened in 1914, has a very high ceiling with leaves and coffee beans on the top. The ebony bar and the wine racks against the wall stand firmly there. You will recognize the mask behind the counter. There is a The golden coffee machine with the flying eagle logo and the lion-shaped table legs under the table are reminiscent of Saint Mark, the patron saint of Venice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The city’s ancient cafes resist the times in their own way. In the San Marco Cafe, the bar is still made of solemn dark wood, and the tables, chairs and wall decorations are still the same as a hundred years ago. One side of its &quot;L&quot;-shaped structure has been transformed into a bookstore, filled with nostalgic books. The most conspicuous place is Magris&#39;s &quot;Micro Worlds&quot;, which has dozens of pages describing the past and present of the San Marco Café. The café is the living room of the city, an open public space where some faces disappear and new ones appear. In this urban space, the history of literature here is recorded. Cafe San Marco is a place frequented by literary &quot;pilgrims&quot;. Everyone, in their own way, hopes that this cultural &quot;ark&quot; will continue to exist. In addition to drinking coffee, you can also eat exquisite pasta in this cafe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After coming out of the cafe, you can go for a walk in the nearby park to get some fresh air. There are towering plane trees in the park, and the sun shines through the leaves, and the golden light falls on a pool in the garden, which Magris also described. There are benches everywhere in the garden, where people read newspapers, books, or just sit around. There is a children&#39;s playground and an open-air cinema at the end of the park. Statues of city celebrities are scattered around, including a bust of Joyce wearing a hat and glasses, which was erected on the centenary of his birth in 1982, and a bust of local poet Saba, a second-hand bookseller of Jewish origin. , a neurotic patient and the cultural soul of Trieste, once wrote a poem titled &quot;Trieste&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I walked through the whole city,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;climbed a large Slope,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It was crowded at first, but then the road became empty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the end of the road is a low wall:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am sitting alone in this small corner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Where the low wall ends,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is also where the city ends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Trieste has an inaccessible beauty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you like, this city is like a rough, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Greedy wild child, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Having blue eyes and using a pair of overly large hands&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sent A flower;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Like a paragraph full of jealousy&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&#39;s love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On this hillside, I see the city (Trieste)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Every church, every street, even the crowded beach,&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;And the top of the mountain is full of rocks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The last house seems to be firmly rooted there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Everything around me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;all have a strange, tortured feeling,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is the smell of hometown (this is where I was born). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Every part of my city is full of life&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;She reserved a corner for me, suitable for me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A worried and lonely life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone lives in the corners of the city, including poets like Saba. The city has beaches, hills, and therefore a hint of countryside. Watching life from above, but not participating in it, while not feeling like an outsider, is exactly what this city offers Saba. Magris lives in this city in another way. He exists in a strict ritual, as cautious and solemn as the black and white marble floor of the Sacre Coeur. For him, everything was close by, a trip to the park was like traveling around the world, the clear cistern of the Sacre Coeur was like a spring in the glade, and the dim light of the church was as deep as the sea at night. Unfathomable. His life permeates the San Marco Cafe, the Park in the Street and the Sacred Heart Church two steps away. Magris even designed a reassuring ending for himself: with the comfort of his two sons, he lives in the Sacred Heart Church. In the golden sky painted by the church, jump through the ring of fire held by two angels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Trieste described by Magris is a city of twilight. In 2019, when he was 80 years old, he published &quot;The Bent Time of Krems&quot;. This is a book about twilight. There are five short stories in the book, telling the stories of five men in their twilight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Concierge&quot;, there is an old man who is reluctant to advance but to retreat, a president who once owned several companies. He enters an unknown field to get rid of the reality of facing enemies on all sides. He is a Czech who walked from the interior to Trieste for development. When he was young, the world was beautiful and big. He played his role successfully, building himself a strong armor with checks and profits. However, one day, his desire for success and inner panic left him. He became relaxed, sold his company, and became a concierge of an apartment with a calm mood. Once the sea has returned to the waterside safely. He tries to avoid roads where he can see the sea in the morning, takes the bus, and then walks to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist of &quot;Music Lesson&quot; is a Polish Jew who has entered his twilight years, a survivor with shame. He takes a car to go up the mountain to the home of his former student. The student, who became a musical master, showed him a piece of music he had composed as a tribute to the tragedy of the Jews, and he accepted the piece with embarrassment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist in &quot;Bent Time in Krems&quot; is the closest thing to Magris. He gives a lecture on Kafka and has dinner in a city called Krems. At the dinner party, someone mentioned Noni, the goddess of his youth, and by chance, he actually contacted her later. The &quot;now&quot; changes the &quot;before&quot;, time becomes curved, and all that is left is &quot;his&quot; longing for the god-like Noni. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Awarding&quot; is about an old writer attending a literary awards ceremony, feeling melancholy and relieved as time passes. In &quot;Outing Day&quot;, an old man went to the set to see the actor who played him in his youth. Everything was different from the previous story, and the old man got a kiss that he missed when he was a teenager. The five fragments of life are all based on the theme of &quot;old age&quot;, allowing people to see the scene of the city&#39;s twilight reflecting on life: the sunset fills the sky, and everything tends to be relieved. Magris uses short words to accurately outline some life fragments. The past and present coexist at the same time, and death becomes infinitely gentle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Magris, there is also a world-class best-selling female writer Susana Tamaro among the contemporary writers in Trieste. Most Italian families have her book &quot;Where the Heart Guidance&quot; 》. It was also a woman in her twilight years who was reckoning with the past through letters. There is also a writer recently introduced to the country - Gianfranco Kaligaric, who has certain connections with Trieste. He was born in Asmara, Eritrea, Africa. His family is a &quot;cosmopolitan&quot; family from Trieste, and he carries traces of the city&#39;s ethnic mix. He lived and worked in Milan and Rome. In 1974, he wrote the highly praised &quot;Waste of Summer&quot;. There is an indelible trace of youthful debauchery in his style, which still exudes endless charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又一中管干部被点名搞“七个有之” | 时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260846]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission announced that Chongqing Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of the city, violated discipline and law and was expelled from the party. (Internet data map)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/954c5c3e3c.png&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/954c5c3e3c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258712&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission announced that Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of Chongqing, violated disciplines and laws and was punished. Expelled from the party. (Internet data map)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission publicly announced the handling of disciplinary and law violations by Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of Chongqing. Situation: Expelled from the party and transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution. &lt;p>; Remain consistent and address many issues such as &quot;seven things&quot; and formalism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Seven principles&quot; was proposed at the Fourth Plenary Session of the 18th CPC Central Committee held in October 2014. The specific content is, &quot;Some people ignore the Party&#39;s For the sake of their so-called official career and their so-called influence, some engage in nepotism and exclude dissidents, some engage in gangs and cliques, and some engage in anonymous false accusations and rumors. In other words, there are those who try to win people&#39;s hearts and votes, there are those who appoint officials and make wishes and celebrate with others, there are those who do things on their own and act against the will, there are also those who try to make mistakes and make unreasonable comments about the central government, and so on.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before Xiong Xue was dismissed, many central management cadres had been characterized as &quot;seven qualities&quot;, such as Zhou Jiankun, former vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, and former chairman of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People&#39;s Congress. Deputy Director Gong Jianhua and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the second time this year that Xiong Xue’s name has appeared on the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Half a year ago, on May 11, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced on its website that Xiong Xue was suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and was undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. This also makes him the 19th central management cadre to be dismissed in 2023, and the &quot;second tiger&quot; to be dismissed from Chongqing after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before Xiong Xue fell, more signs had been revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Failed to pass the National People&#39;s Congress qualification review&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Born in Xiong Xue, who grew up in Chongqing, is a typical &quot;local cadre&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating from the Chinese major of Chongqing No. 1 Normal School in Sichuan Province in 1982, Xiong Xue entered the Chongqing Nan&#39;an District Committee and served successively as the mayor of Chongqing Jiangjin City and the Municipal Party Committee. He is the deputy director of the High-tech Zone Management Committee (director level) and director of the Chongqing Municipal Development and Reform Commission. He is in charge of education, science and technology, and was promoted to deputy mayor of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Government in May 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the beginning of 2023, Xiong Xue has suffered setbacks one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On January 17, 2023, the new Chongqing Municipal Government leadership team was made public. Xiong Xuewei was re-elected as deputy mayor, but continued to serve as a member of the municipal government party group . On the morning of the same day, at the third plenary session of the Sixth Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Congress, Xiong Xue was elected as a representative of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress. However, a month later, on February 24, the National People’s Congress website released a representative qualification review report, and Xiong Xue and other three people failed to pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before and after the National People&#39;s Congress confirmed his qualifications as a representative, Xiong Xue briefly continued to appear in public as a &quot;member of the Party Leadership Group of Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Government.&quot; On March 13, 2023, Xiong Xue also went to Wansheng Economic Development Zone to investigate the operation of industrial enterprises and energy supply guarantee work, and proposed to solve the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of enterprises and continue to optimize and improve the business environment. But this was also the last time Xiong Xue appeared in public reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s search found that they also failed to pass the National People&#39;s Congress qualification review. Except for Xiong Xue, who was notified of being investigated, the other two people were not reported to have been actually investigated. Impact and is still working normally today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking back at past public speeches, Xiong Xue has repeatedly emphasized the importance of &quot;party conduct and clean government&quot; and &quot;anti-corruption&quot; work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a survey conducted after he was appointed Secretary of the Chongqing Yongchuan District Party Committee in 2013, he emphasized the need to further enhance the people’s trust and satisfaction in the Party committee and government. We must do a good job in building a clean and honest government, strengthen education, supervision, and punishment to prevent corruption. In June 2020, when the Discipline Inspection Commission and Supervision Office of Chongqing High-tech Zone were officially unveiled, he also gave a speech, proposing to play the role of demonstration and leadership of leading cadres, take the lead in respecting the law and abiding by the law, and stand the test in small matters and details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, judging from the investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, Xiong Xue failed to complete the above requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The report mentioned that Xiong Xue accepted banquets and services that may affect the fair execution of official duties, accepted gifts and gifts in violation of regulations, obtained large returns through private loans, and was in conflict with Unscrupulous businessmen collude, engage in power-for-money transactions, take advantage of their positions to benefit others in project contracting, land approval, etc., illegally receive huge amounts of property, and fail to explain truthfully when organizing interviews and inquiries, among many other problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Seven Things&quot; is essentially a political issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;Xiong Xue is the third central management cadre to be clearly pointed out in the past two years for engaging in &quot;seven things&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Jiankun, the former vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, who was &quot;double-opened&quot; in June 2023, was accused of losing his ideals and beliefs, losing the people&#39;s position, abandoning his duties and mission, and implementing Ineffective implementation of the Party Central Committee’s major decisions and arrangements on poverty alleviation and the consolidation and expansion of poverty alleviation results, use of poverty alleviation projects for personal gain, serious damage to the interests of the Party and the people, failure to fulfill the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the Party, implementation of “seven things”, and confrontation Organizational review, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gong Jianhua, the former deputy director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People&#39;s Congress who was &quot;double fired&quot; in 2022, was accused of losing his ideals and beliefs, abandoning his duties and mission, and betraying the &quot;two &quot;Maintain&quot;, organize &quot;small circles&quot; and &quot;small gangs&quot;, engage in &quot;seven things&quot;, pollute the political ecology, fail to implement the Party Central Committee&#39;s decisions and arrangements on trade union work, secretly manipulate the selection of model workers, and privatize the honor of the party and the country. Give and receive, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the concept of &quot;seven things&quot; was proposed at the Fourth Plenary Session of the 18th CPC Central Committee, many central management cadres have been named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;News on the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission on September 16, 2020 stated: Former Deputy Chairman of the Internal Affairs and Judicial Committee of the Twelfth National People&#39;s Congress, Yunnan Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China Former Secretary Qin Guangrong &quot;publicly made remarks that were contrary to the requirements for comprehensive and strict governance of the party&quot;, and Meng Hongwei, former member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Public Security and former director of the China Coast Guard, &quot;refused to implement the decision of the Party Central Committee&quot;... In 2019, the Central Committee Without exception, all the central management cadres who have been investigated by the Discipline Inspection Commission and the National Supervisory Commission have &quot;seven problems&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the release of the &quot;Work Plan of the Central Anti-Corruption Coordination Group (2023-2027)&quot; in September 2023, the head of the Central Anti-Corruption Coordination Group Office once When answering questions from reporters, he pointed out that we must continue to focus on the &quot;seven problems&quot; and resolutely eradicate political groups that form cliques and parties for private gain. On November 10, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission also issued an article emphasizing that the &quot;seven things&quot; are essentially political issues, and they attempt to seize the power of the party and the state and undermine the centralization and unity of the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After more than a month of inter-provincial transfer, Wang Libo assumed the new vice governorship of Liaoning Province]&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;On November 14, 2023, &quot;Liaoning Daily&quot; released the news , after voting at the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Liaoning Provincial People&#39;s Congress, Wang Libo was elected deputy governor of the Liaoning Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Resume shows that Wang Libo was born in Dingzhou, Hebei Province in 1968. He has worked in Shanxi for a long time and served as the director of the National Economic Comprehensive Division of the Shanxi Provincial Development and Reform Commission and the deputy secretary of the Provincial Party Committee. long. In May 2016, Wang Libo was confirmed to be at the director level, and later served as deputy secretary-general of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee, director of the General Office of the Provincial Party Committee, secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Shanxi Provincial Department of Culture and Tourism, deputy secretary-general of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee in charge of daily work, and deputy secretary-general of the Provincial Party Committee in charge of daily work. Director of the Finance and Economics Office, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In January 2023, Wang Libo served as Secretary and Director of the Party Leadership Group of the Shanxi Provincial Development and Reform Commission, and was later transferred to Liaoning. A month ago, on October 10, Wang Libo appeared at a special study meeting held by the Theoretical Study Center Group of the Liaoning Provincial Government Party Group and spoke as a member of the Liaoning Provincial Government Party Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Sun Yeli is appointed as Party Secretary of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism]&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to an update on the official website of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, Sun Yeli has been appointed Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism. Hu Heping previously held this position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information shows that Sun Yeli, born in December 1964, is a graduate student in history at Peking University. After graduation, he entered the Central Document Research Office and worked as the Central Document Research Director. Deputy Secretary-General of the Office and Editor-in-Chief of &quot;Party Documentation&quot;, Member of the Office of the Central Documentation Research Office, Director of the Fifth Edition and Research Department, Director of the Sixth Edition and Research Department, Deputy Director of the Central Documentation Research Office, etc. He has long been engaged in party and state leaders. Book editing and ideological research, research on the history of the Party and modern Chinese history. In the past two years, Sun Yeli has also appeared publicly as deputy director of the Central Propaganda Department and spokesman for the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Heping is currently the deputy minister in charge of daily work of the Central Propaganda Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Intensive adjustments by leaders of more than ten universities including Peking University] &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the &quot;Current Leaders&quot; column of Peking University&#39;s official website shows that there have been many changes in the school&#39;s leadership. Among them, Jiang Guohua, currently deputy provost and executive vice dean of the Graduate School of Peking University, serves as deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Peking University. Fang Fang, currently director of the Personnel Department of Peking University, and Piao Shilong, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, serve as vice president of Peking University. Currently, he serves as director of the Propaganda Department of the Party Committee of Peking University. Ren Yuzhong serves as a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of Peking University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, on November 14, the Shaanxi Provincial People&#39;s Government website issued a cadre appointment and dismissal notice. Sun Qingwei, formerly a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee and Vice President of Peking University, became the Vice President of Northwest University. , preside over administrative work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to media reports, many universities in Shandong and Inner Mongolia have also recently welcomed &quot;new coaches.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, the Ministry of Education’s Personnel Department announced the appointment and removal decision of the Ministry of Education’s Party Group at Ocean University of China. Zhang Junfeng, former Vice President of Nanjing University, was appointed as President of Ocean University of China. , Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee. On the same day, the People&#39;s Government of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region released a batch of personnel appointments and dismissals, appointing Han Wei, member of the Party Committee of Inner Mongolia Normal University, as vice president; Meng Xianghong, deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Inner Mongolia University for Nationalities, as president; Han Yongquan, deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Chifeng University, and the Academic Affairs Office of Inner Mongolia University of Science and Technology. Chang Zhao Yongwang is the president and vice president of Inner Mongolia University of Science and Technology respectively; Liu Liqiang, director of the Academic Affairs Office of Inner Mongolia University of Technology, is the vice president; Zuo Hejun, dean of the Desert Management College of Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, is the vice president. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 14, three ordinary undergraduate colleges and universities in Jilin welcomed new secretaries or new presidents on the same day. They were the former presidents of Qilu University of Technology (Shandong Academy of Sciences) Wu Yantao, deputy secretary of the party committee, and Yang Jingbo, former deputy secretary of the party committee of Shandong Jianzhu University, were promoted to secretaries, and Kong Weijin, former vice president of Qingdao University, was transferred to deputy secretary of the party committee and dean of Shandong Jiaotong University. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[One year after his ouster, Deng Zhenxiao, the former mayor of Bozhou City, Anhui Province, was double-crossed]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;On November 14, 2023, the website of the Anhui Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision announced that Deng Zhenxiao, the former deputy secretary of the Bozhou Municipal Party Committee and former mayor of the Bozhou Municipal Government, seriously violated disciplines and laws and was expelled from the party and public office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;News shows that in November 2022, Deng Zhenxiao was fired on suspicion of serious violations of discipline and law. After investigation, Deng Zhenxiao engaged in collusion between officials and businessmen, accepted banquets in violation of regulations, used his authority or position influence to benefit his relatives&#39; business activities, allowed unscrupulous businessmen to interfere in cadre and personnel work, interfered in the use of fiscal funds, and caused heavy losses to state-owned property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After the Central Financial Work Conference, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced the investigation of The number of cadres reaches 9]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of November 15, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission reported that China Agriculture, which took the initiative to surrender in May this year, Lv Xiaodong, the former vice president of the bank’s Zhejiang Branch, was “double opened”. So far, after the Central Financial Work Conference at the end of October, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection has reported that nine financial officials have been investigated or punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 3, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission successively announced Wang Guizhi, former party committee member and chief supervisor of Guangfa Bank and former party committee member of Agricultural Bank of China Yunnan Branch , Vice President Shen Rui was expelled from the party. The next day, Zhang Hongli, former party committee member and vice president of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, was dismissed. On the 7th, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission reported that Zhu Congjiu, former vice chairman of the Zhejiang Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, was double-crossed. On the 10th, Chen Gongyan, the former party secretary and chairman of China Galaxy Securities Co., Ltd., was investigated; Yang Chunlei, the former full-time deputy director of the China Securities Regulatory Commission’s Party Committee Inspection Leading Group Office, was double fired. Four days later, An Qingsong, who had succeeded Chen Gongyan as president of the Securities Association of China, was dismissed; Li Dajun, former party secretary and president of Bank of Communications Yunnan Branch, was notified of his expulsion from the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Ministry information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Eight departments including the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology will launch the first batch of comprehensive electrification pilots for public sector vehicles in 15 cities]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, eight departments including the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology and the Ministry of Transport officially issued the &quot;Notice on Launching the First Batch of Pilot Zone Pilot Areas for Comprehensive Electrification of Public Sector Vehicles&quot;, identifying Beijing, Shenzhen, Fifteen cities including Chongqing, Chengdu, and Zhengzhou are the pilot areas for this pilot. According to the expected goals, the promotion of new energy vehicles will focus on official vehicles, city buses, sanitation vehicles, taxis, postal express vehicles, urban logistics distribution vehicles, airport vehicles, heavy trucks in specific scenarios, etc. The number of promotions is expected to exceed 600,000 vehicles; in terms of charging and swapping infrastructure, more than 700,000 charging piles and 7,800 battery swapping stations will be built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Public Security solicits disciplinary measures for electronic fraud and related crimes Opinion]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the Ministry of Public Security, together with relevant authorities, drafted the &quot;Joint Punishment Measures for Telecommunications Network Fraud and Related Illegal Crimes (Draft for Comments)&quot; ”, soliciting opinions from the general public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Disciplinary Methods (Draft for Comments)&quot; has a total of 19 articles, mainly including disciplinary principles, disciplinary objects, disciplinary measures, graded punishment, disciplinary procedures, and appeal verification 6 aspect content. For those who are held criminally responsible for committing telecommunications network fraud and related crimes, the penalty period is three years; for those who are identified as punishment targets by the public security organs at or above the districted municipal level, the penalty period is two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Since 2019, more than 7,500 public interest litigation cases in the field of barrier-free environment construction have been handled]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, and the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation jointly held a press conference. It was announced at the meeting that from 2019 to September 2023, procuratorial organs nationwide handled a total of public interest litigation cases in the field of barrier-free environment construction 7,526 cases, including 7,497 administrative public interest litigation cases and 29 civil public interest litigation cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Supreme Law issued new regulations to standardize comprehensive management of justice Recommendation work】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Supreme People&#39;s Court issued the &quot;Regulations on Several Issues Concerning Comprehensive Management of Judicial Recommendation Work&quot; on November 15. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judicial suggestions are constructive opinions issued by the People&#39;s Court to units or individuals on relevant issues during the hearing of civil, economic, and administrative dispute cases. According to the Supreme People&#39;s Court, since the current judicial proposal work still has problems such as insufficient deepening of traceability governance and insufficient standardization of handling procedures, this &quot;Regulations&quot; has been specially formulated to clearly follow the principles and document samples. The &quot;Regulations&quot; will come into effect on November 16, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Shanghai releases plan to create a &quot;Silk Road E-commerce&quot; cooperation pilot zone]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the morning of November 14, 2023, the Shanghai Municipal Government Information Office held a press conference. Zhang Xiong, Deputy Secretary-General of the Municipal Government, introduced the main contents of the &quot;Plan on Creating a &quot;Silk Road E-Commerce&quot; Cooperation Pilot Zone in Shanghai&quot;, which focused on creating a pioneering area. 19 tasks were proposed in three aspects, including establishing a test environment, vigorously promoting international and regional exchanges and cooperation, and expanding the opening up of the e-commerce field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the overall goals proposed in the plan, by 2025, Shanghai will have formed a number of institutional opening-up results with a demonstration and leading role, and gathered a number of internationally competitive enterprises. e-commerce business entities, create a number of regional carriers with unique characteristics, and build a number of public service platforms that promote the common development of the “Silk Road E-commerce” partner countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[24 municipal enterprises in Beijing are fully promoting 430 post-disaster projects Reconstruction Project]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;People&#39;s Daily Online reported on November 15 that 24 municipal enterprises in Beijing are making every effort to promote the construction of projects in Mentougou, Fangshan and Changping districts. There are 430 post-disaster reconstruction projects involving four aspects: infrastructure, public services, financial support, and people&#39;s livelihood services. The above three districts were severely damaged by heavy rains and floods in late July and early August this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to reports, the Beijing State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission is currently focusing on the overall idea of ​​&quot;basic recovery in one year, comprehensive improvement in three years, and long-term high-quality development&quot; to ensure safety and improving people&#39;s livelihood as the core, taking the actual needs of recovery and reconstruction in disaster areas as the entry point, guiding and urging municipal enterprises to be deeply involved in post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Science and Education News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The National Student Mental Health Advisory Committee was established]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;November 15, 2023 On the same day, the Ministry of Education issued a notice on the establishment of the National Student Mental Health Advisory Committee. The notice states that under the leadership of the Ministry of Education, the advisory committee will undertake the responsibilities of research, consultation, monitoring, evaluation, scientific popularization, and guidance on mental health work in universities, middle schools and primary schools across the country. Each work area will organize at least one major event covering the provinces in the area every school year through various appropriate methods such as surveys, popular science lectures, free clinics, etc. to assess the mental health status of primary, secondary school students in the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[China successfully launched a new generation of ocean water color observation satellite]&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation, at 11:55 on November 16, at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in my country, the Long March 2C/Expedition 1 The No. S carrier rocket carried a new generation of ocean water color observation satellites straight into the sky, and then the satellite successfully entered the predetermined orbit, and the launch mission was a complete success. This means that my country’s ocean water color series satellites have officially been upgraded to the second-generation observation system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;[&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liaoning will no longer approve new products for preschool children Training institutions]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A few days ago, seven departments including the Liaoning Provincial Department of Education jointly issued the &quot;Liaoning Province Management of Non-Subject Off-Campus Training Institutions for Primary and Secondary School Students&quot; Measures&quot; to make systematic arrangements for the management of non-disciplinary off-campus training. The &quot;Measures&quot; stipulate that training institutions that implement non-disciplinary training activities such as science and technology, culture and art, and sports must submit an application for establishment to the education administrative department. After verification by science and technology, culture and tourism, sports and other departments, if the establishment is approved, a school-running certificate may be issued. license. New training institutions for preschool children will no longer be approved, and online training for preschool children will not be allowed. The &quot;Measures&quot; will come into effect on December 1, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Sound&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Zhang Feng, Deputy Secretary of the Haixi Prefecture Committee of Qinghai Province: The ideological gap is the biggest gap, and the backwardness of concepts is the biggest backwardness]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From April 3 to 9, 2023, Gonghe County, Qinghai Province sent an 11-member party and government delegation to Changzhou City, Jiangsu Province, and Ankang City, Shaanxi Province for study and inspection. Member of the Standing Committee of the Hainan Prefecture Committee and Secretary of the Gonghe County Committee is one of the members of the delegation. The 10,000-word report he wrote after the inspection was recently published in &quot;Party Life&quot;, the official publication of the Qinghai Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the report, Zhang Feng mentioned that the ideological gap is the biggest gap, and the backwardness of concepts is the biggest backwardness. &quot;Many things, especially project construction and industrial development, We are still debating whether we can do it or not. When we are looking for policies and evidence, others have already taken the lead and achieved results.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;In October this year, Zhang Feng was promoted to deputy secretary of the Haixi Prefecture Committee of Qinghai Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive from The Paper, Daily Economic News, Caixin.com , Qilu Evening News, the official WeChat of the Inner Mongolia Government Office, the website of the Anhui Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision, China Business News, Xinhua News Agency, Shangguan News, People&#39;s Daily Online, Procuratorate Daily, etc.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[怕老的年轻人正被世界富豪们牢牢盯上]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260613]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, German tycoon Christian Angermaier &amp;nbsp;Angermayer) invested in the longevity biotechnology company Rejuveron, which hopes to achieve the purpose of extending life by solving age-related diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, big names in the technology industry such as Zuckerberg, Bill &lt;span>;·&lt;/span>; Gates, and the founder of Google have turned to anti-aging. Investing huge amounts of money in the field, these practices have triggered controversy from all walks of life. Capital has become a key force in the study of human &quot;immortality&quot; and has been criticized by ethics and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Capital is after all profit-seeking, and they are interested in the big cake behind anti-aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data shows that from 2015 to 2021, the global anti-aging market will grow by US$76.5 billion. Especially as China&#39;s consumption upgrades and health needs deepen, China&#39;s demand for anti-aging is growing day by day, and the anti-aging industry continues to expand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the anti-aging market gradually expands, anti-aging products and medical beauty projects emerge in endlessly, which are also subtly affecting people&#39;s understanding of aging. When it comes to getting older, most people worry about skin problems. For example, &quot;dull and yellowish complexion&quot;, &quot;enlarged pores&quot; and &quot;aging around the eyes&quot; are common problems for the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that aging is not just a problem for middle-aged and elderly people. The trend of anti-aging is blowing into the social circle of Generation Z. Under the discursive framework of advertising and the social media turmoil, more and more young people are also developing anti-aging anxiety. What provides emotional value to this group of mentally damaged young people are the various home beauty devices that are increasingly active on the grass-growing platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Bring the beauty effects of the theater home&quot;. From unique precision instruments in medical beauty institutions to miniaturized and convenient instruments for home use, home beauty instruments are deeply loved by consumers. Some brands have also launched a new concept of &quot;technological beauty&quot;, that is, using a combination of beauty instruments + skin care products to attract consumers. This has caused many young people to engage in consumer behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Research reports show that 42% of users spend more than 1,000 yuan on skin care every quarter. Under the dual consideration of economic strength and anti-aging needs, people aged 35-39 are the most willing to pay for their appearance, with 21% spending more than 3,000 yuan on skin care every quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, when faced with a home beauty device worth several thousand dollars, many people still hesitate to consider whether it is an IQ tax or what is an anti-aging product worth buying. Hot discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk with you about whether it is worth spending money on anti-aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8ae7276b4d.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8ae7276b4d.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258286&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/343de0e4ec.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/343de0e4ec.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5020a852e0.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5020a852e0.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/4929a36023.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/4929a36023.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258289&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/e9baa877a9.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/14/e9baa877a9.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258290&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/14/91b7312bdf.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 14/91b7312bdf.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 14/ddbff4839c.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/ddbff4839c.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 08:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[你家附近借书便利吗？期盼普及社区借阅服务]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260844]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After reading the limited collection of books at home, when I felt that there were no books to read and life was difficult, Xiao Xu called Called and said he wanted to send me a book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Xu is my former colleague. He knows that I like reading. I have given them away several times before, and each time they were several large copies. I was embarrassed to ask him to give it away again, so I politely declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have two major hobbies, one is walking and the other is reading. Walking refreshes me and reading makes my life fulfilling. If I don&#39;t take a walk for a day, I feel uncomfortable all over; if I don&#39;t read for a day, my life will be boring. Reading a few pages of books every day has long become a habit of life. If you don&#39;t touch a book on a certain day, you won&#39;t feel good even if you sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, most of the books I read were borrowed from the university library by my son. My son is studying in a local university. This has a great advantage for me, that is, I can use the university library as my own private library. This is all because of my son. Now that my son has graduated from college and is working, I have lost the convenience of studying. After my son left school, the source of books suddenly stopped. I had to rummage through boxes and cabinets at home and come up with the idea of ​​collecting books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the collection of books at home was too limited and could not meet my needs, so there was a book shortage. The days without books to read feel particularly long and endless. At this moment, Xiao Xu called and wanted to deliver a book. I was secretly happy, but at the same time, I felt that I couldn&#39;t always be in debt to others. Books are expensive nowadays, and Xiao Xu is just a working-class person, so how can he keep asking people to spend money? No matter how strong the relationship is, it must be measured. So I thought, it would be great if there was a place to borrow books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, it’s not that there is no borrowing office. You can borrow books from the city’s library, but it’s a pity that the place is not close to home. It’s more than ten miles away from home. In this way, it is natural to think, wouldn’t it be great if you could borrow books near your home? For example, community libraries, etc. But I couldn’t find such a place, and when I asked people, they said they had never heard of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My son joked that if we buy a house in the future, we will buy it near the library. Even if this kind of joke can come true, it will only be a long way away. They say we want to create a scholarly society, but even borrowing books is difficult. What can we do to create a better society? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I admit that fewer and fewer people read paper books now. But even so, the public services that should be provided must be provided and cannot be omitted. We often say that we need to provide all-inclusive assistance to needy groups, and we also need to provide all-inclusive assistance for reading, because there are always people who cannot afford to buy too many books, and there are always people who face the high price of books and have to give them up after considering them again and again. Even if you can&#39;t let go, you can only reluctantly give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let reading enter our daily life and become an important part of life, thereby improving individual quality and the population quality of the entire society. This is the fundamental essence of creating a scholarly society. Not to mention anything else, just for this reason, we also need a place where people can borrow books nearby. Such a place does not need to be big, it just needs to be convenient for people to borrow. At least one community committee must have such a place. In large communities, the number of places must be determined based on population distribution. In addition, in order to save costs, books can be regularly transferred between different places to maximize the use of books and satisfy the needs to the greatest extent. The needs of readers. I don&#39;t know if such a wish can be implemented in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a citizen of Anqing City, Anhui Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪国芭蕉——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（五）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260812]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/fXpujkHdDpeuAavi8nL2NRJEO5JawNmDWrcTl3NZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/fXpujkHdDpeuAavi8nL2NRJEO5JawNmDWrcTl 3NZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258619&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Matsuo Basho Monument at Inari Shrine in Niigata Prefecture, left picture taken in April 2023 month, the picture on the right was taken in September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After walking several points on Matsuo Basho’s “Oku no Homichi” in the fall of 2019, Then came three years of COVID. It&#39;s like a big dream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early April and early September 2023, in early spring and early autumn, I went to Niigata Prefecture in northern Japan twice, the Echigo country that often appears in ancient Japanese literature. Echigo Kingdom, one of the ancient &lt;span>;Reiji Kingdom&lt;/span>; in Japan, faces the &lt;span>;Sea of ​​Japan&lt;/span>; and is long and narrow from north to south. &lt;span>;Meiji&lt;/span>; Four years later, the feudal domain was abolished and a prefecture was established, named Niigata. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Niigata in April, the car was driving among the continuous farmland. The brown rice fields in early spring have just been plowed and are waiting for a new round of sowing. The September trip is already in my plan, so I started imagining the scene of autumn. For large areas of solid color scenes, yellow is the most suitable, and the combination with the blue sky is pure and gorgeous. In the Chengdu Plain where I live, there is a spectacular scene every day in March. The spread of rapeseed flowers is spectacular, and the atmosphere of early spring is quite exciting. Chengdu people who stay at home will basically go out for spring outings at this time, not to let down nature or themselves. Fortunately, I visited Niigata again in early September and enjoyed the sight of golden rice fields and blue sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many swans in Niigata’s deserted fields in April. They are pecking at the grain that falls in the soil. After being fed and fattened, they will fly back to Siberia. It migrates like this every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at these beautiful big white birds from a distance. Has Basho seen them? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Probably not. Matsuo Basho and his disciple Soryo Kawai arrived in Echigo in the summer of 1689. Echigo is a stop on the &quot;Oku no Hosomido&quot;. The entire &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot; journey is a total of 2,400 kilometers of hiking. Starting from Edo, go north, then turn west. It is said that the most magnificent journey is the monk Kukai’s tour of the eighty-eight temples in Shikoku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the trip to Japan in the spring of 2023, the excitement and yearning were mixed with a different state of mind from the trips in previous years. During the three years of the epidemic, except for a few short trips within the country, I have not traveled abroad. Three years of isolation has had a psychological effect on me, leaving me with a faint uneasiness, but I don’t know where this uneasiness comes from. When applied to the body, the hands and feet feel sluggish and sluggish. Having been separated from the same rhythm for three years, the effect is really powerful. The body is heavy and the state of mind is also sinking. I asked myself, what would happen if I never went out again? It seems to be possible. For middle-aged people, three years makes them look older. This is probably an important reason. By September, after a trip to Japan in April, a self-driving trip to Yunnan in May, and several short trips, I felt that my mind and body were beginning to adapt to the journey again, which was very gratifying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Ding Yuan settled in the village of &lt;span>;Niigata Prefecture&lt;/span>; and ran a B&amp;B called &quot;Four Seasons Inn&quot; with her husband, Mr. Nakamura Tatsuo. The couple also ran a local hotel. Various contents of travel. Regarding Basho, what Ding Yuan helped me find out is that Basho and Zeng Liang stayed in Murakami for two nights and three days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Basho accommodation in Murakami can be checked and determined based on local literature, but it has lost its former appearance and has become a salmon restaurant, so the curtain at the door is very interesting. This is a two-story Japanese-style house on Murakami Street. Three Japanese-style curtains are hung side by side at the door. They are written in black on a white background and in the middle are &quot;Izutsuya&quot;, which is the name of the restaurant. The one on the right is written &quot;Murakami&quot;. &quot;Salmon Cuisine&quot; and a book on the left reads &quot;Basho&#39;s Staying Place&quot;. There is a wooden sign at the door stating, &quot;In June of the second year of Genroku (1689), Basho and Zeng Liang arrived at Murakami during their journey on the &#39;Oku no Homichi&#39;. They stayed here for two nights and three days. , it was called &#39;Sukuzaemon&#39; at the time.&quot; In order to show that the brand was not the store&#39;s own words, the signature was &quot;Mura City Education Committee.&quot; Murakami&#39;s salmon industry is very famous. Every year, many salmon migrate here, and the output and quality are of high quality. Therefore, Murakami has a considerable number of salmon restaurants and processing workshops for curing and drying salmon. I asked Nakamura, is &quot;Izutsuya&quot; the most famous salmon shop in Murakami? Nakamura smiled and said, that&#39;s not necessarily true. It&#39;s because of the influence of bananas, but most people don&#39;t care about this, and only you cultural people care about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/MQzAIBoCpFBy1l4BFMplWcHVyGjQuJFUl4plJrQa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/MQzAIBoCpFBy1l4BFMplWcHVyGjQuJFUl4plJrQa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258620&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho and his disciple Kawai Sora went to the accommodation in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho wrote in &quot;The Thirty-Five Echigo Road&quot; in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot; , &quot;As soon as we passed the Mouse Pass, we entered the territory of Echigo from Dewa, and then we rushed to Shizhen Pass in Etchu. We walked for nine days in total. During this period, sometimes the heat was unbearable, and sometimes the cold rain poured down on us, which made us physically and mentally exhausted. Even getting sick was really miserable. So I didn’t record much of my journey.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because Basho was ill during Echigo, there are very few records about Echigo in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. Based on the results that Ding Yuan helped me check, I followed the traces in Murakami in early spring and early autumn. However, it is no longer possible to determine the location of this trace. We can only search for it based on the location of the Basho Sentence Monument. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jizo-do Hall in Kamikata Town has the Basho sentence monument &quot;けふはかり人も年よれ&amp;nbsp;First Time Rain&quot;. It can be translated as: Only today do you know that you are old, this is the first shower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inari Shrine has a Basho motto stone, &quot;Cloud folds 々人をやすむる月见かな&quot;. The general meaning I understand is that the shadow of the cloud covers the moon, and the shadow of the moon covers the person. The latter is a sentence from Basho&#39;s seven-part collection &quot;Spring Day&quot;, written in 1685. Basho visited Murakami in August 1689. He probably left no works due to poor health. Next to the Bajiao Monument Monument, there is a haiku poet Su Xian&#39;s Monument Stone. The handwriting is blurry. The general idea I read is: Under the moonlight, the shore of the water is covered with pine leaves like umbrellas (I don&#39;t know if it is correct or not). According to the introduction on the standing plaque next to it, these two stone sentences were erected in October 1843, during the 150th anniversary of Basho and the 17th anniversary of Susen. The introduction also specifically said that there are two important remains of Basho in Murakami, one is the Inari Shrine where this place is located, and the other is the Iwafune Shrine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Iwafune Shrine built on the seaside is much larger in scale and momentum than the Inari Shrine. It has a red torii gate and a white torii gate. In front of the red torii gate, there is a Basho sentence stone, which is engraved with the sentence &quot;On the seventh day of Hanasaki, Tsurumi will see Tsuruga&quot;, which can be understood as &quot;The cherry blossoms are in full bloom in seven days, and only Tsurumi can see such a beautiful scenery.&quot; The Basho stone in front of the white torii gate is engraved with &quot;Bunzuki や六日も长の夜には思ず&quot;, which means that the night of Bunzuki (July), when I am anxiously waiting for the letter, is also different from the ordinary night. The former Basho haiku has nothing to do with &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;, and the latter line is taken from a line written in the Hokuriku section of &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April, the day before Basho’s tour in &lt;span>;Niigata Prefecture&lt;/span>;, we went to Kameoka Monju-in, the Daishoji Temple in Yamagata Prefecture. In the drizzle, there was still residual snow on the mountain col in the distance and on the roofs nearby. When I was going down the mountain, I suddenly found a Basho sentence monument standing on the roadside, which read &quot;春の夜は桜に明けてしまひけり&quot; (Spring night, cherry blossoms are in full bloom). Tateishiji Temple (Mountain Temple) in Yamagata Prefecture is an important place to visit on the &quot;Oku no Hosōdo&quot; tour of Master Basho and his apprentice. I visited in 2019. I don’t know if they have been to the Great Holy Temple, and it is not mentioned in the book. Someone may have studied the details of these travels, and the results of these studies must be carefully explored to know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I used to read a lot of haiku in Chinese translation, but over the years I slowly started to read the original haiku. It is true that poetry cannot be translated. Because my Japanese foundation is still shallow, and it also involves issues of ancient and modern Japanese, I can only read these haiku at a loss. But maybe it was in this confusion, after leaking some clear information, that I finally understood the extremely concise and complex semantics of haiku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of Basho&#39;s activities in this area of ​​​​Murakami is Otohoji Temple. During my two trips to Murakami in early spring and early autumn, I went to Otohoji Temple twice. The cherry blossom scenery in early spring is obviously much more beautiful than the scenery in early autumn before the red leaves appear. It is said to be Murakami, but Otohoji Temple is actually located in Tainai City next to Murakami. This temple was built in the 8th century AD under the order of Emperor Shomu who was in office at the time. The temple covers a vast area of ​​more than 80,000 square meters. There is a &quot;three-story pagoda&quot; built in 1620 in the temple, which is designated as a national important cultural property of Japan. This temple is the only ancient temple in Shinji that is included in &quot;The Story of Konsai&quot;, and it is also the temple where Matsuo Basho once visited when he wandered the &quot;Oku no Hosho Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uYiV1rkOS05OOYFWHKCIRA8y6dKAOdlxPhPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uYiV1rkOS05OOYFWHKCIRA8y6dKAOdlxPhPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258621&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho Monument in Otohoji Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the topic, let me say a few words. It was almost noon after visiting Otohoji Temple in early autumn. Mr. Nakamura said that there was a steamed bun shop next to it that was very delicious and he hadn’t eaten there in a long time. We decided to leave it at that for lunch. When I arrived at the door, I looked at the description and found that it was founded in the first year of culture, which was 1804, and has a history of more than 200 years. The shop is really small, with a few stools and two or three tables. When the steamed buns arrived, they turned out to be red bean paste buns. Later, I looked up information and learned that in Japan, the so-called steamed buns are bean paste buns, and the outer shell can vary. There are white steamed buns made of commonly used flour, brown tea steamed buns made of wheat flour, and sweet potato flour, yam flour, and japonica rice flour. There are sweet potato steamed buns and wine steamed buns made from fermented rice flour, etc., but they are filled with red bean paste. Yiboji Steamed Buns are delicious, and I am even more impressed that such a snack shop has a history of more than 200 years. In Japan, I often come across various small shops that are hundreds of years old. I once ate at a ramen shop in Kyoto. When I came to the door after eating, I was shocked to see the signboard. It has a history of more than 400 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I posted photos of my visit to Yibao Temple in WeChat Moments, and a friend asked: Is it the Yibao Temple in &quot;The Story of the Past&quot;? It seems that its name first came from &quot;The Story of the Past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Story of the Past&quot; is a collection of folklore stories from the late Heian period in Japan, with a total of thirty-one volumes and more than a thousand stories. It is divided into Tianzhu (India) (volumes one to five), Cathay (China) (volumes six to ten), and Honchao (Japan) (volumes eleven to thirty-one). The current Chinese version of this Dynasty was edited by Zhou Zuoren. The stories in &quot;The Tale of the Past&quot; are all-encompassing, with Buddhist stories and secular stories mixed together. There are also many stories of gods and supernatural beings. Many creations of later generations come from this book, which is one of the source treasures of Japanese literature. It is similar to Chinese books such as San Yan Er Pai and Strange Stories from a Chinese Studio. Because each volume contains the word &quot;present and past&quot; at the beginning, it is called &quot;The Story of Present and Past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Japanese writers, Ryunosuke Akutagawa made full use of &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot;. It is said that about one-fifth of the material in the historical novels he created came from &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot;, including &quot;Rason&quot; Door&quot; and &quot;In the Jungle&quot;. Ryunosuke Akutagawa called &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot; a &quot;human comedy&quot; in ancient Japan. He said that &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot; is full of &quot;wild beauty&quot; and is &quot;a kind of beauty that has nothing to do with elegance and luxury.&quot; Many of the common Onmyodo and Onmyoji content in Japanese animations also come from &quot;Kanagi Monogatari&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spacious garden of Uhoji Temple, there is a Basho Sentence Monument, a round stone monument, the handwriting has been blurred. There is a wooden sign next to the stele, which records the content of the stele: &quot;In the second year of Genroku (1689), Matsuo Basho paid homage to the Ukiyo no Kita no Yamazakura Basho.&quot; I envy). Surrounding the Basho Sentence Monument are many echoing sentences from &lt;span>;Niigata&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;local&lt;/span>; haiku celebrities at that time. Otohoji Temple has been a famous place for cherry blossom viewing since ancient times. Basho admired the beauty of the northern cherry blossoms here, even though it was not during the cherry blossom season when he visited. Looking at Sakura Leaves, he also expressed his envious mood in his imagination. Two of the echoing haiku of other haiku writers were singled out and written in the description of the stele. They were probably the most famous haiku poets in the area at that time. One of them is not jade, &quot;Mitsukoshi Road や一の Temple の花ざかり&quot;, Mitsukoshi The road and Yi&#39;s Temple are filled with flowers. One song is by Yasuda Izabo, &quot;Different gods and Buddhas&quot;. Different gods and Buddhas all have the beauty of cherry blossoms. They are all sentences praising cherry blossoms. In Japan, the word flower, if not specifically mentioned, is cherry blossom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Niigata in early April, the cherry blossoms are in full bloom in previous years, but the spring of 2023 is coming fiercely, and when we arrived, the cherry blossoms were already a little overdue. In the garden of Otohoji Temple, on the round stone monument of Basho, there are several branches of cherry blossoms hanging down, on the eve of their withering. Behind the stele is a small hill, and on the steps are several red curtains from the temple, with the words &quot;Namo Guanyin Bodhisattva&quot; enshrined. The curtains fluttered gently in the sunshine and breeze. This sentiment and scene complement each other perfectly with the haikus tablet with unclear handwriting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Othoji Temple, like other Niigata landscapes, has very few tourists. I stood on the terrace outside the main hall, watching the yin and yang scene cut by the sun with the Buddha statues in the garden below. I have done this twice. Although the weather seems to be the same, there are obvious differences in the dividing lines between sunlight and shadow in early spring and early autumn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I visited Otohoji Temple again in September and suddenly discovered Kobo Daishi (Kukai) here. I didn’t notice it at all on that trip in April. There is a stone statue of Kobo Daishi Gozun here, which is a common standard shape of Kukai wearing a hat and leaning on a staff during his journey. This stone statue of Kukai is a bit cute, shaped into a pudgy little boy. I turned to the back of the base of the stone statue to read the description. The handwriting was a bit blurry, but I could clearly see the words &quot;Pursuing the eighty-eight sacred sites of Shikoku...to commemorate...&quot; and other words. It is estimated that someone went there before and erected a statue in Otohoji Temple after returning to Niigata. Benji was the monk Kukai&#39;s practice route. It later gradually became the most famous hiking route in the world, with a total length of more than 1,400 kilometers and 88 temples in Shikoku. Currently, more than half a million people from all over the world walk this road every year. This is also a strange fate for us. After seeing Kukai at Otohoji Temple, my friend Dr. Tan Weidong and I left Niigata the next day, flew to Osaka for a short stay, and then headed to Shikoku to start our plan Three years of preparation for the trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[格力电器：董明珠“绯闻”是造谣，已向公安机关报案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260839]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: &quot;Regarding the recent efforts of many self-media To obtain traffic, maliciously edit relevant videos, and use vulgar and filthy words to insult and slander company executives, Gree Electric has reported the case to the public security organs, which have accepted and filed the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanduwan Financial News reporter learned that recently There are rumors on social platforms that Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, is in love with Wang Ziru, the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; of Gree Electric Appliances. In a recent TV program, Dong Mingzhu responded, &quot;I don&#39;t even watch it. I don&#39;t think it matters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the same program, Wang Ziru said: &quot;I didn&#39;t watch it.&quot; &quot;I passed the salary slip issued to me by Gree&quot; and &quot;asked for an office close to the Dong Zong to facilitate reporting&quot;, etc., which have attracted much attention and controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Cheetah Mobile CEO Fu Sheng expressed his views on Wang Ziru in WeChat Moments. Fu Sheng said, &quot;I can only say that Wang Ziru is not only a freeloader, but also a gangster.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, Wang Ziru is the founder of ZEALER (ZEALER Network Technology). Tianyancha shows that ZEALAR was established in June 2012. It is a technology information website focusing on electronic product evaluation and Q&amp;A, and then expanded its mobile phone repair business, mobile device hardware laboratory, etc. Wang Ziru is not only the executive director and general manager of ZEALER, but also a digital review blogger with 1.97 million fans. He once became popular because of his public debate with Smartisan CEO Luo Yonghao over the review controversy of the Smartisan T1 mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258706&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from public information, Wang Ziru and Dong Mingzhu met in 2016. In an entrepreneurial program &quot;I Am the Founder&quot; broadcast that year, Dong Mingzhu served as the mentor of Wang Ziru&#39;s team. Afterwards, Wang Ziru posted a photo of herself and Dong Mingzhu on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258707&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Dong Mingzhu held a nationwide tour of live broadcast to bring goods. Wang Ziru appeared as the host many times, and together with Dong Mingzhu, they won 703 million yuan in sales. That year, Dong Mingzhu&#39;s 13 live broadcasts totaled 47.6 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 30% of Gree Electric&#39;s total revenue in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2021, Gree Electric confirmed the news of Wang Ziru joining Gree Electric. At that time, industry insiders said that Wang Ziru’s department was affiliated with Gree’s President Office and Cultural Training and Communication Center. During the same period, Wang Ziru resigned from his position at ZEALER, the media he founded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are rumors that Wang Ziru’s rank in Gree is equivalent to that of vice president, with an annual salary of more than 3 million yuan. However, judging from Gree Electric’s financial reports in the past two years, Wang Ziru has never appeared in the executive compensation table middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After joining Gree Electric, Wang Ziru rarely appeared on public platforms. Gree Electric did not disclose his specific work content. However, it is known from some public reports that he is currently in charge of the Gree channel reform project. In late May this year, Wang Ziru, who had been with Gree for two years but had not yet appeared, appeared publicly in Nanchang for the first time as the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; and spoke at the 2023 Gree Electric (Jiangxi) new marketing model presentation conference. In October and November, Gree Electric Shandong and Hebei Sales Companies also issued documents, and Wang Ziru gave a speech at a new marketing model conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that at the beginning of this year, news appeared on social platforms that Gree Electric Chairman and President Dong Mingzhu was in love with his company’s post-85s male executive. The news originated from the big V Gong A screenshot posted by Wen Xiang on the Internet. In February this year, Dong Mingzhu took the initiative to mention and denounced in an interview with reporters from Nanduwan Financial News and other media: &quot;Vulgar, obscene, and boring! It is not an exaggeration to use these words to describe it.&quot; She clearly denied the love scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, big V Gong Wenxiang apologized to Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, for his previous remarks in the Southern Metropolis Daily. Gong Wenxiang said in his apology statement that he made distorted remarks about Ms. Dong Mingzhu’s private life on Toutiao on February 26, which were widely disseminated and objectively damaged Ms. Dong’s reputation. &quot;I deeply regret and am deeply sorry to Ms. Dong. The special newspaper expresses my public apology and sincere remorse to Ms. Dong, and hopes to obtain Ms. Dong&#39;s forgiveness. I will use this as a lesson in the future to be a self-media person with three upright views.&quot; .&quot; Gong Wenxiang said in the statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: It is worth mentioning that the Internet is not a place outside the law. The company will take legal measures to resolutely safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the company and its employees. We maintain a zero-tolerance attitude towards any malicious slander and rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the TV program mentioned above, Wang Ziru said that no company is drowned in saliva. As a business operator and manager, you should spend more time focusing on what you should do. things to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>