<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[校领导被举报收实习回扣应调查，职校不能把学生当“猪仔”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260573]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, anti-counterfeiter Wang Hai publicly reported through the Internet that the leader of a vocational school in Jiangxi made huge profits from student internships. aroused great public concern. On November 13, Xinyu City, Jiangxi Province, where the vocational school involved is located, announced that a joint investigation team had been formed by the Municipal Education Bureau, Human Resources and Social Security Bureau, etc. to investigate and verify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Jimu News, Wang Hai posted on the Internet that Teacher Zhang from Jiangxi New Energy Technology Vocational College accidentally discovered that his ex-wife Yan Moumou, who was also responsible for student internships at the school, had a huge deposit of 6 million yuan. , and also discovered an account book involving tens of millions of yuan, recording the details and distribution ratios of funds transferred by multiple human resources agencies to multiple leaders of the school. One page shows that a four-month internship with 39 students received nearly 130,000 yuan in &quot;management fees&quot;. His ex-wife received more than 14,000 yuan, and another leader received more than 114,000 yuan. . The bank statements provided by the whistleblower also show that since 2017, multiple human resources companies have frequently transferred money to the account of a person related to Yan in the name of &quot;employing companies paying training fees&quot;, with amounts ranging from several thousand yuan to tens of thousands of yuan. No wait. The money finally went to Yan Moumou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The figure of more than 6 million is a bit shocking. From the article, it seems that this is only a small amount allocated to the assistant dean. Whether Wang Hai&#39;s report is true or not depends on the investigation results of relevant departments. However, it is no secret that in the name of organizing student internships, vocational schools actually engage in &quot;labor export&quot;, collect fees from internship companies, and even deduct students&#39; internship remuneration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, because some manufacturing companies had difficulty recruiting workers, vocational school students became the targets of some labor agency companies. Vocational schools then found a way to make money: they cooperated with labor agencies, organized students to work in companies in the name of internship, and collected management fees, training fees, etc. In a Jimu News report, a former vice president of Jiangxi New Energy Technology Vocational College admitted that when students go to companies for internships, the school does receive a management fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, companies will not spend this money in vain. In some places, in addition to schools collecting money, school leaders and intern teachers can also receive kickbacks. In this incident, a page of account books provided by the whistleblower showed that students from the school went to an internship in a company in Suzhou. For every hour they worked, the students were paid 15 yuan, the school could get 4 yuan, and the assistant to the dean could also receive it personally. 5 cents. Of course, the truth of the incident remains to be investigated. However, there have been precedents for similar incidents before. In 2021, it was revealed that Guizhou Aluminum Technician College arranged student internships through an intermediary company and collected fees ranging from 1,500 yuan to 2,000 yuan per student per month from the remuneration given to students by the internship unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vocational school students go to companies for &quot;internships&quot;, and the pay is low, but the labor intensity is not low. In 2021, Hunan Linwu County Vocational High School organized students to intern at a company in the county, where they had to work 11 hours a day. In the same year, some students from Hanjiang Science and Technology School in Danjiangkou City, Hubei Province were arranged by the school to intern at a technology company, working more than ten hours a day. And these &quot;internship&quot; jobs often have nothing to do with the majors they studied. Students majoring in computer science were assigned to &quot;move boxes&quot;, while those majoring in nursing were assigned to beauty salons and hair salons. These so-called internships are actually pure physical labor and have no effect on improving professional skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long hours and heavy labor are unbearable even for adults, let alone vocational school students who have just become adults or even minors. Many people have been severely damaged physically and mentally, and some have even become disabled due to work-related injuries due to fatigue at work and other reasons. Xiaopeng, a student from Linwu County Vocational High School, was pinched by a machine during his internship, resulting in the amputation of two fingers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In people’s minds, ordinary college students will also do internships before graduation, but the school usually does not organize arrangements. At most, it provides relevant information and requires students to contact the internship unit themselves. But vocational schools are different. Vocational education regulations require that students &quot;should&quot; participate in internship training, and internship experience has become a necessary condition for graduation of vocational school students. Some vocational schools use the precious sword of graduation certificates to force students to participate in &quot;internships&quot; organized by the school. &quot;If you don&#39;t go to the internship, you will not be given a diploma.&quot; The internship time is too short and cannot bring enough &quot;value&quot; to the school. No.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most vocational schools are at the technical secondary level and recruit junior high school graduates. Because of the &quot;50-50 split&quot; in the high school entrance examination, about half of junior high school graduates go to vocational schools. Most of these students are only 15 or 16 years old. At the age of 10, they have just finished the education stage that focuses more on discipline, and their minds are not fully mature. Compared with these immature students, schools and teachers are undoubtedly in an absolute advantageous position. These powers have become transformed in the hands of some schools and teachers. The sickle that cuts students&#39; leeks. These schools are not thinking about how to improve the quality of teaching and teach students real professional skills, but they are thinking hard about how to squeeze more money out of students.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a profession Education, no wonder parents and students abandon it like worn-out shoes. To do a good job in vocational education, we must first break this abnormal power structure and let vocational schools return to their role as education service providers. Students can come and go freely without being restricted by their student status. If you feel that a certain school or a certain major is not good, you can leave at any time and go to other schools or majors. As long as you study enough courses and learn enough skills, you can graduate. This will encourage vocational schools to compete in the education market. Win the favor of students and parents based on indicators such as teaching and employment quality, rather than treating students as cash cows and lambs to be cut.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS ：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 朱勇：历史研究联系现实要恰如其分，不能过于牵强]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260581]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhu Yong was born in 1955 in Wuwei, Anhui. The first Ph.D. in legal history in New China, the first Ph.D. in China University of Political Science and Law&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1974-1978, after graduating from high school, he joined the queue at Shushan Garden Farm in the suburbs of Hefei City, Anhui Province;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1982, studied in the Department of Philosophy, Anhui University;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1982-1985, studied for a master&#39;s degree in Chinese legal history at the Law Department of Anhui University;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985-1987, studied for a PhD in Chinese legal history at the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Graduated in 1987 and stayed at the school to teach;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Promoted to associate professor in 1990;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Promoted to professor in 1993;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1995, he served as the director of the Institute of Chinese Legal History;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as doctoral supervisor in legal history in 1996;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From September 2001 to May 2015, he served as Vice President and Dean of the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently, he is the vice-chairman of the Legal Culture Research Association of the China Law Society President of the China Legal History Society, President of the Chinese Legal History Professional Research Association, chief scientist of the &quot;Chinese Judicial Civilization Research Innovation Team&quot; of the Judicial Civilization Collaborative Innovation Center of the Ministry of Education, and enjoys special government allowances from the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 12, 2023, Zhu Yong was in the office of China University of Political Science and Law. (Southern Weekend reporter Du Hansan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/94ccde942a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/14/94ccde942a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258196&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 12, 2023 On the same day, Zhu Yong was in the office of China University of Political Science and Law. (Southern Weekend reporter Du Hansan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the first batch of independently trained PhDs in New China, 68-year-old Zhu Yong is considered young. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating from high school in 1974, Zhu Yong worked in the garden farm for four years. He originally thought he would deal with fruit trees for the rest of his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three years later, the college entrance examination resumed, and 23-year-old Zhu Yong entered the Department of Political Education of Anhui University to study. Nowadays, this age may have graduated with a bachelor&#39;s degree, but at that time, the eldest classmate in Zhu Yong&#39;s class was already 31 years old, and there were fathers and sons enrolled in other departments at the same time. In his own words, &quot;it was delayed for four years, but not too long.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The prelude of reform and opening up has been played, and the spring tide is surging in the economic field. At the end of 1978, Anhui University changed the 1977 Department of Political Education into the Department of Philosophy and Economics. Zhu Yong wanted to be transferred to the Department of Economics, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, he continued to study for a master&#39;s degree in Chinese legal history at Anhui University, and entered China University of Political Science and Law to study for a doctoral degree in Chinese legal history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 1987, the Degree Evaluation Committee of China University of Political Science and Law officially decided to award Zhu Yong a doctorate in law - the degree certificate number is &quot;Bo 87001&quot;. He is He is the first doctor of legal history in New China and the first doctor of law trained by China University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 12, 2023. On the campus of China University of Political Science and Law, pedestrians walk in a hurry. When I walked into Zhu Yong&#39;s office and saw a whole wall of books, time seemed to slow down again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the interview, he mentioned twice that his experience was relatively dull and he hoped to write in a &quot;low-key&quot; and &quot;plain&quot; style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Yong said that a few years ago, he accepted the task of compiling and organizing the &quot;(Newly Edited) General History of China&quot; and the &quot;History of Chinese Legal System&quot;. His current wish is to compile a special history that truly represents the evolution of Chinese law and to be recognized by both the legal and historical circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I vaguely feel that the direction of society is changing&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1974, you had just graduated from high school at the age of 18 and jumped in line at the Shushan Garden Farm in the suburbs of Hefei. . What kind of work did you do at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mainly working on fruit trees. This includes loosening soil and fertilizing fruit trees, weeding and pruning, spraying pesticides and drainage, picking and caring for fruit trees, etc. Fruit trees are highly seasonal and more tiring than farm work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Eating peaches feels good, but picking peaches in summer is particularly uncomfortable. If you wear too much clothes, you will feel hot; if you wear too little, the peach hairs will feel itchy if they stick to your body. In the peach orchard, the branches are low and the ground is full of ditches and bumps. I can only bend down and carry the baskets of peaches out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, hundreds of young people gather at the garden farm, and they can always find fun. When the fruit is ripe, it needs 24 hours of supervision. If you work the night shift, you won&#39;t be able to sleep for 8 hours at night. Someone came to steal the fruit, and everyone was very excited. They divided their troops to guard and try to catch the person. No one came to steal, but the night felt boring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Waiting in the garden It has been 4 years, do you have a chance to read a book? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Basically there are no books that we like to read. There are some learning materials that I generally don’t like to read. At that time, those who &quot;criticized Lin Biao and Confucius&quot; called Confucius &quot;the second son of Confucius&quot; and extracted his remarks for criticism. Everyone thinks what Confucius said is quite reasonable, but after listening to expert analysis, they feel that what the experts said is also reasonable. Only then will I be interested in reading it. After reading it, I can show it off by chatting with others. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also a few readings that are circulated privately, and people are eager to get the books. For example, &quot;Three Heroes and Five Righteousness&quot; is about Bao Gong and a group of heroes who travel the world. Too many people have read this book, and dozens of pages are either damaged or rolled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have thought about myself Any chance of going to college? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t think about this issue when I jumped in line. At that time, there were also university students from workers, peasants and soldiers, but the number of places was very small. This was almost impossible on our farm. My personality can be summed up in two words: casualness. I feel that since everyone can bear it, then work hard, and you will not be so tired when you enter management in the future, and there is still hope. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I didn’t expect it to be that far back then. If there had not been reform and opening up, I would have worked on the farm for the rest of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did you start Are you aware of a change in social trends? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the end of 1976, one day we were working together in the reservoir. The loudspeaker suddenly switched to another channel and played the song &quot;The Waves of Honghu Lake&quot;. Although the noise is extremely loud, the melody is melodious. Hundreds of people put down what they were doing and stood quietly listening. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, many songs before the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; could not be played. Everyone thought it was incredible, how could this song be played? I have a vague feeling that the direction of society is changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was at that time that Xinhua Bookstore began to sell classic novels such as &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, &quot;The Romance of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, &quot;Water Margin&quot; and &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, but there was a queue to buy the books Very long queue. I have a very good friend among the educated youth, whose family works in Xinhua Bookstore in Hefei City, so I asked her to buy a set. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you know Restore the college entrance examination news? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The summer of 1977 was the season when fruits were ripe, and there was no official announcement yet. The college entrance examination is to be resumed, but some people are already talking about it privately. If it is spread too much, everyone will believe it. In the orchard, the young man works the night shift. After getting off work at four or five in the morning, he takes a nap first and then reviews his books. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I have been hesitating for a while, feeling that I have lost so much time studying and I don’t want to take the college entrance examination. My mother was hospitalized in other places at the time, and she asked people to pass on the message through various channels. She said absolutely that if I didn&#39;t take the college entrance examination, she would not come home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the beginning, everyone was not very enthusiastic about reading the book. They just felt that others were reviewing and it would be inappropriate not to review themselves. In October 1977, &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; officially announced the resumption of the college entrance examination, and everyone went all out to change the status quo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many educated youths on our farm have signed up to take the college entrance examination. Later, many people asked for leave for various reasons. At first, the farm required that educated youths were not allowed to take leave and were not allowed to read during working hours. But the leaders at all levels of the farm are also relatively simple and kind-hearted. They also have children and understand our urgency for the college entrance examination, so they still have a certain degree of laxity in management. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Going to the Department of Philosophy for my undergraduate degree&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern China Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Professor Mo Lifeng from the School of Liberal Arts of Nanjing University has a similar experience to yours. They both joined the team in Anhui and were both admitted. Anhui University, where he later became the first doctor of literature. He once said that he was very ambitious before going to the countryside. He applied for Tsinghua University in his first three choices, but after staying in the countryside for 10 years, he only dared to apply for Anhui University. What impact do you think the four years of queue jumping had on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I applied for a volunteer, my vision was not broad enough and I did not think of going to another province to go to school. I applied for liberal arts. I felt that Anhui University was the best school within my knowledge, so I applied. Later I learned that with my scores, I could only get into Anhui University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 1977 College Entrance Examination in Anhui Province was held from December 10th to 11th. Shortly after the Spring Festival, I received the admission notice from Anhui University. Although I will report to the university soon, after the Spring Festival holiday, I still went back to work in the second farm team, thinking that I should stand on the last shift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, our second brigade had a walking tractor that collected feces from public toilets every day and fertilized the fruit trees. The body behind the tractor was broken, and the brigade secretary asked me to send it to a repair shop for repairs. It was so cold that the remaining feces on the truck bed was frozen. Before repairing, it had to be thawed with hot water and then wiped clean. At this time, I thought, I will leave the farm next week anyway, report to the university, and let this matter go. After that, I started my academic career of reading and teaching. However, my failure to get the tractor body repaired has long been a problem of mine. Later, I went back to the farm to visit the old secretary of the brigade, and I apologized to him specifically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I am lucky. Shushan Garden Farm, as my first foothold into society, allowed me to plan my life based on the principles of positivity and contentment, and to get along with others with a kind and optimistic attitude, which benefited me a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After arriving at Anhui University , why choose the Department of Philosophy? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I applied for my application, I applied for the Department of Political Education of Anhui University. Around the end of 1978, the school adjusted its majors and changed our ’77 students in the Department of Political Education into philosophy and economics respectively. At that time, the prelude to the country&#39;s reform and opening up had begun, and the economic field was booming. Most of the students hope to enter the Department of Economics, and I also want to adjust to the Department of Economics. But maybe it was because I did not do well in mathematics in the college entrance examination that I entered the philosophy department. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; How is everyone&#39;s enthusiasm for studying? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Everyone really valued their time at that time. There is a big age gap between the classmates in our class. The oldest was born in 1947 and the youngest was born in 1962. There is a 15-year age difference. In other departments, there are fathers and children admitted at the same time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The lights in the dormitory are turned off at 11 o&#39;clock in the evening, and many students go to read under the street lamps. At &lt;span>;four or five&lt;/span>; o&#39;clock in the morning, the street lights went out and the canteen lights came on. There is always a row of classmates holding books outside the cafeteria window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2000, Zhu Yong (middle), his master&#39;s tutor Chen Shengqing (first from left), and doctoral tutor Zhang Jinfan (first from right) attended an academic conference at Anhui University. (Interviewee/Picture) &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f6e62aad90.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1603&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f6e62aad90.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2000, Zhu Yong (middle) attended an academic conference with his master&#39;s tutor Chen Shengqing (first from left) and doctoral tutor Zhang Jinfan (first from right) at Anhui University. (Interviewee/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Why did you choose to continue studying for a master&#39;s degree in 1982, and why did you choose to study Chinese legal history after switching from the philosophy department to the law department? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In January 1982, I graduated from my undergraduate degree. At that time, the school distributed work uniformly, and they were all good units. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the early 1980s, the construction of the national legal system was initially launched. Everyone thinks that the legal system is an effective means of national governance, but no one can clearly explain the &quot;legal system&quot;. The more this happens, the more expectations they have for the legal system, and they believe that legal talents have great development prospects. My parents didn’t understand what legal history was, but they knew that I majored in law, so they fully supported my application for a master’s degree in Chinese legal history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I was in my third year of master&#39;s degree, I learned that Professor Zhang Jinfan of China University of Political Science and Law was recruiting doctoral students in Chinese legal history, so I decided to sign up for the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Cooking noodles and talking about academics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern China Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In February 1985, you went to China University of Political Science and Law to study for a PhD in Chinese legal history. What was your first impression of this school? What is it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first impression is the legal awareness of Fa Da people. When I first came here, the Third Ring Road was being built near the north gate of the school. Once while taking a bus, I saw a law student having a dispute with the driver over the parking issue of the bus. The driver thinks it&#39;s almost enough, don&#39;t take it seriously. But students said the driver did not follow the rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After experiencing the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, people at that time generally had little sense of rules. The awareness of rules among law students is refreshing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are Chinese political and legal Did the first batch of PhD students recruited by the university receive &quot;special preferential treatment&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The school gave me and my fellow seniors Zheng Qin and Huai Xiaofeng a scholarship. We bought a tape recorder and let us learn foreign languages. At that time, cassette recorders were very expensive, costing more than 400 yuan each. The second batch of doctoral students will not be issued. The management attaches great importance to us, but they use too much force. Maybe they don’t know what kind of learning conditions they should provide to doctoral students. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The language I study is English. The school thinks that a doctorate is a higher level than a master&#39;s degree. It is not appropriate to take classes with master&#39;s students, and it is difficult to be alone. Give us foreign language classes. So I was asked to attend a training class in Changchun to learn foreign languages, and the expenses were reimbursed. Training courses are very expensive, with foreign teachers attending classes and students staying in hotels. When you return to school, you don’t need to take another exam. A training certificate will count as passing the foreign language class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The 1980s , the doctoral training system is still in the exploratory stage. You are Mr. Zhang Jinfan’s “open disciple”. How did he guide the doctor? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, China University of Political Science and Law’s curriculum, teaching methods, and class hours for doctoral students There are no clear regulations on requirements, staged assessments, etc. The entire training process is basically the responsibility of the instructor himself. It is somewhat similar to the master-apprenticeship system in traditional Chinese society where a master leads an apprentice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When we were studying, Mr. Zhang was the vice president and dean of the graduate school. His schedule was very full, but lunch time was fixed. We proposed that we let him come to our dormitory at noon on weekdays, use an electric cup to cook a cup of noodles for him, beat an egg, and teach him while eating. The four masters and apprentices closed the door, whispered, cooked noodles, and talked about academics, having fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although I majored in legal history for my master&#39;s degree, I did not receive systematic legal training during my undergraduate period, and the basic theories of law are relatively lacking. Mr. Zhang taught students in accordance with their aptitude and believed that I should pay attention to the construction of the legal knowledge system and allowed me to audit civil law, criminal law, procedural law and other courses for master students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, everyone from our tutors to the graduate school encouraged us to take full advantage of the concentration of academic talents in Beijing. We went to Peking University, Renmin University, Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences and other institutions to take courses, participate in discussions, and visit famous teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zhu Yong&#39;s doctorate certificate, number is &quot;Bo 87001&quot;. (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/14/9216f69100.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /14/9216f69100.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhu Yong’s doctorate certificate, number is &quot;Bo 87001&quot; . (Interviewee/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;The title of your doctoral thesis is &quot;Research on Clan Law in the Qing Dynasty&quot;. At that time, there was no reference for doctoral thesis on legal history. Can you talk about the writing process of your doctoral thesis? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My doctoral thesis is a continuation of my master&#39;s thesis. At that time, basic research was relatively weak, many studies were not conducted, and the selected topics were not easy to repeat. In this case, it is not difficult to select the topic for my thesis. The key is to find first-hand information, and it will be easy to produce results. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While studying for a master&#39;s degree at Anhui University, the school gave the master&#39;s degree a thesis investigation fee of 300 yuan. It took me almost two months to travel to more than a dozen provinces. My main task was to check the family laws and regulations recorded in the genealogies of various places. At that time, in the southern provinces, genealogies were managed not primarily as books but as cultural relics. Therefore, genealogies are mostly stored in museums. Most of the genealogies from various places have been in existence for 100 to 300 years. The paper is yellowed and covered with insect holes. You have to read it carefully, and it will break easily if you are not careful. None of this raw material has been used before. In two months, I hand-copied thousands of cards about family laws and clan rules in museums in more than a dozen provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I was studying for my Ph.D., I spent a lot of time consulting in the ancient book library of the Beijing Library located in the Imperial College and the First Historical Archives of China located in the Xihua Gate of the Forbidden City. material. At that time, various academic institutions were very friendly to students looking for information. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Talk about academics&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before 1980, three international seminars on the history of Chinese legal system were held in the world, but mainland China was not invited in any of them. Scholars participate. What do you think about this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Once Mr. Zhang gave us a lecture and mentioned the Chinese legal system of scholars from other countries His historical academic achievements exceed those of local Chinese scholars, and even international academic seminars on related topics have not even been attended by Chinese scholars. From the perspective of academic responsibility, Mr. Wang hopes that we will work hard to change the status quo and firmly place the center of Chinese legal history research in China&#39;s local academic community. We were deeply touched by the words of Mr. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; There is a voice that believes that compared with departmental law, legal history has less say in reality. However, some scholars believe that true history must contribute to reality and history must participate in the social process. What are your thoughts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Concerning historical research, diversity in purposes and methods should be allowed. You can focus on connecting with reality, or you can focus on academics themselves. I have seen that some doctoral students always think about how to directly guide reality when deciding on a thesis topic. I encourage students’ innovation, but I also tell them that a scholar’s ​​task is to do academic work first and clarify academic issues. The formulation and implementation of ancient laws had specific background conditions in ancient society. The connection with reality must be appropriate and logical, and cannot be too far-fetched. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I have a similar experience myself. When a publication requests a manuscript, I send it in, and the editor sends back expert review comments. Experts suggested that I should base my article on the views I proposed and make some connections with contemporary social reality. I replied to the editor and said that my interest lies in talking about academics and history. The editor was very understanding and accepted my comments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Scholars may be able to distinguish There are two types of people, one is doing pure learning in an ivory tower, and the other is caring about reality. Should you be the former? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the value of a scholar lies in the academic itself. My research is generally not directly related to connected with reality. We can sort out the development process of legal systems and legal theories in Chinese history in detail, and put forward our own opinions on their laws, characteristics, and functions. If we can reproduce their true state and show their true role in the process of national management and social governance, our academic goal will be accomplished. As for whether this research result can play a role in contemporary national governance and rule of law construction, I believe readers are smart enough to sort through it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Research in the humanities is often related to scholars’ real-life encounters and life experiences, and is very personal. What impact do you think your past experiences have had on your scientific research work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My personality is conservative and lacks pioneering. Even if they join the queue for 4 years, the material conditions are poor and the labor intensity is high. But during those 4 years, there were no unpleasant feelings. In current terms, I am basically satisfied with the status quo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From 1977 to 1987, I studied continuously for 10 years and experienced three options: undergraduate, master&#39;s and doctoral examinations. These three road choices were not too difficult. If it was too difficult, you might have backed down at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Self-evaluation, my academic research is not very critical and not creative enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;From &quot;master-apprentice system&quot; to &quot;teacher-student system&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How has the current graduate education changed compared to the era when you were studying? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When we were studying, it was a more typical &quot;master-apprentice system&quot;. It is similar to the way a master leads an apprentice in a traditional social handicraft workshop. It is characterized by personalized guidance and comprehensive training. Mr. Zhang can give us personalized guidance and comprehensive training according to his own positioning and expectations for young scholars. The content of guidance varies from person to person and students are taught in accordance with their aptitude. At the same time, we pay attention to comprehensive training. Mr. Xiang gives us detailed guidance in all aspects of academic research, including reading lists, thesis topic selection, data screening, condensation of ideas, thesis structure, and written expression. It also covers many aspects of social interaction and dealing with people outside of academia. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;master-apprentice&quot; training method is more conducive to teaching students in accordance with their aptitude, but it cannot solve the problem of large-scale education. After the expansion of postgraduate enrollment, the &quot;teacher-student system&quot; in which teachers lead students was gradually developed and improved. Its characteristic is that it pays more attention to standardized training and digital management in the education process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;With Mr. Zhang You have similar experiences. Since 2001, you have served as the vice president and dean of the graduate school of China University of Political Science and Law for nearly 14 years. How did the &quot;teacher-student system&quot; of standardized training and digital management develop? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Yong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In these 14 years, we have indeed been committed to the standardization and digitization of graduate training. manage. For example, whether they are doctoral students or master&#39;s students, during the six-semester training process, there are unified regulations in the training plan on which books students should read, which classes they should listen to, and which teaching links they must complete.博士生要修满多少学分，听几门课，提交几篇读书报告、学期论文、学年论文，进行多少天社会实践，需要正式发表几篇何种级别刊物的学术论文，学位论文要达到几万字等等，都有明确的数字规定。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;标准化培养、数字化管理的优点在于，培养结果可评估，培养过程可监控，特别是能够有效适应研究生规模化教育的新形势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你会在博士培养过程中，保留“师徒制”的风格吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从1997年招收第一届博士生，我已指导培养八十余名博士生。在博士生培养过程中，一定程度上保留一些“师徒制”习惯。我招收的学生，其本科、硕士教育背景有法学，有历史，还有中文。对他们的培养，在完成数量化的规定动作之外，就需要补齐欠缺的知识结构。有些学生读书、研究能力较好，但社会交往有所欠缺。对这些学生，也需要有针对性地补齐短板。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在的学生很焦虑、很内卷，为找到一份理想的工作犯愁。你对大学生有什么建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在年轻人面对的竞争更加激烈，好的就业机会更加难得。个人的事业发展，既需要有良好的自我素质，也需要合适的外部机会。自我素质的培养与提升，无需多说。如何面对外部机会，基于我自己的经历和对人生的理解，我曾给我的学生提出建议：积极进取，随遇而安。在规划自己的事业蓝图时，如果面对多个机会，应该积极进取，设计最佳方案，力争最佳选择。在选择机会较少、改变现状难度很大时，则应珍惜当下，随遇而安。在不同岗位，把本职工作做好，也能展示才华，取得成就。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[预防糖尿病，摆脱“甜蜜负担”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260553]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;今天是一年一度的“世界糖尿病日”。据国际糖尿病联盟（IDF）发布的第10版《全球糖尿病地图》，中国糖尿病患者人数居全球首位，达1.41亿人，发病率高达12.8％。糖尿病是一种以高血糖为特征的代谢性疾病。任何年龄段的人，都可能患上糖尿病。</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 19:25:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在东京慢跑：痛楚难以避免，而磨难可以选择]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260548]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Experience the Imperial Palace Runner Service Station and try on new running shoes&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;While running on the streets of Tokyo in August, my short-sleeved shirt was completely soaked with sweat, and the sweat even exceeded the weight of the fabric itself. There is a word &quot;bitter summer&quot; in Japanese that specifically describes the scorching summer heat. Even if you cannot fully understand its original meaning, the single Chinese word &quot;bitter&quot; can already convey the meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/WsZh4SZI60RS60TPLMVRINpXpRxZuFCDHCT7edrx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/WsZh4SZI60RS60TPLMVRINpXpRxZuFCDHCT7edrx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the Tokyo Imperial Palace running route, there are facilities designed to cool down runners. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time I came to Japan was in 2019. If the epidemic has changed anything, I hate it the most. Runners have started running, and running on the streets of Tokyo is itself a mark of the epidemic. At the height of the epidemic, all sports venues in Beijing were closed. I couldn&#39;t hold it in anymore, so I ordered my first pair of running shoes online and started running along the empty streets. From barely finishing 3 kilometers, to the joy of running 5 kilometers for the first time, to completing 10 kilometers and half marathon, although it may not be worth mentioning among the huge running community, it is a small achievement for me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Running also gives me a new perspective on a place. Familiar places have new experiences because of running. In turn, this sense of strangeness also makes every small &quot;tribulation&quot; more enjoyable. Easier to get through. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/2ZPsf6DyySDGykcwiy80TWWk3Yxmn3x8xHSMee12.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/2ZPsf6DyySDGykcwiy80TWWk3Yxmn3x8xHSMee12.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258158&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scenery of the Imperial Palace Running Route&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been to Tokyo a lot times, but I did some homework before coming this time and knew that the running route around the Imperial Palace is the most famous; the writer Haruki Murakami prefers to practice around the Meiji Shrine Outer Garden. He wrote in &quot;What I Talk About When I Talk About Running&quot; &quot;Specially mentioned in the book; if you want to run at a higher pace, or complete interval running training Cross-intensity running exercises can help improve runners&#39; ability to resist lactic acid)&lt;/span>;, you can go to the Yoyogi Park track and field to try your skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While doing my homework, I also learned that Tokyo has complete supporting facilities for runners. Near the most popular route around the Imperial Palace, there are several hotels where runners can store bags, bathe, and change clothes. The service station only charges a fee equivalent to 30 to 40 yuan, and you can also rent sportswear, running shoes, running pockets and other equipment. You have decided to experience it before setting off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day after arriving in Tokyo, I woke up very early and took the subway to a runner service station I had found in advance. This service station is opened together with a restaurant. Since the charges are not high, runner service stations usually adopt a mixed operation method, allowing runners to stay for breakfast, or the service station is opened directly in the store of a famous sports brand. , increasing customer sources and boosting sales are all methods that service station operators have come up with after years of operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This service station has simple decoration, but it is clean and practical in Japanese style. The girl at the front desk is not good at English and does not have any English instructions at hand. It can be seen that the guests here are mainly Japanese locals and rarely receive tourists. After a few signs, it was not difficult to understand my purpose. I paid, received the keys and towels, and the rest was completely self-help. Later, the decoration of another service station I went to was obviously more upscale. The charges were similar, and both could apply for a monthly card. The price of the monthly card was basically the price of three single purchases, which was very cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second service station also cooperates with sports brands. There is a wall of Mizuno running shoes of different shoe sizes and a wall of Salomon racing road running shoes. Mizuno&#39;s running shoes are free to use, while Salomon&#39;s shoes are more expensive. The domestic price is 2,000 yuan, which only costs 100 yen. (About 5 yuan)&lt;/span>;You can try it out. Because of the good experience, I almost thought of buying a pair because of the 100 yen trial. It seems that this trial is indeed a clever sales method, and the sales scenario is very precise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/iGpztH37ua2aHx1xilIUbZz9bAhhYy153MCFgnXv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/iGpztH37ua2aHx1xilIUbZz9bAhhYy153MCFgnXv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Runner Service Station Locker Room&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Route around the Imperial Palace It is indeed very popular. There are many runners on weekend mornings, of all ages. You can tell the senior runners just by looking at their figures. Because Japan drives on the left and sidewalks are not very wide, everyone follows the rule of running counterclockwise to leave space for walkers. At first I thought it was out of consciousness, but later I learned that after the Imperial Palace route became very popular in 2004, more and more people were running. In order to regulate order, the government required that runners run counterclockwise in 2007. Others leave a certain way. If you violate the rules, you will probably be stopped by the guards around the Imperial Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only by experiencing this route yourself will you know why it is the number one running route in Tokyo. In fact, it is also a helpless move. As an international city with a dense population and a high price of land, running conditions in the core area of ​​Tokyo are really limited. The dense road network leads to many traffic lights. The streets are narrow and even the greening is quite restrained. It is difficult to see rows of big trees. Therefore, the moat and dense vegetation around the Imperial Palace, as well as the five-kilometer &quot;runway&quot; that goes around the city without interruption, have become the best choice for Tokyoites who love running. The Ring Imperial Palace Line also has the advantage of being relatively smooth and convenient for public transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/LoLsuTivS9Yr2bvvMsRNibl8gthFsXpuUN5nu5eZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/LoLsuTivS9Yr2bvvMsRNibl8gthFsXpuUN5nu5eZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258159&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Private running group on the route around the Imperial Palace&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And The second route I chose to run on the same day was the loop around the Meiji Shrine outer garden mentioned by Haruki Murakami. “I have been used to running on this track for many years, and even the details are engraved in my mind. There are pits and depressions everywhere.” I remember everything clearly.&quot; Meiji Jingu Shrine is not far from the Imperial Palace. The map at the runner service station indicates that you can connect the two routes for a run. The total length is almost 10 kilometers, which is the favorite distance for many advanced runners. The route of Meiji Jingu Outer Garden has tall trees, denser green shade and cleaner scenery. It was here that Haruki Murakami met famous marathon runners preparing for the Olympics, rising long-distance running stars who died in traffic accidents, and beautiful women who smiled and greeted each other every day but never talked to each other. He also complained that there were too many traffic lights on this route, but luckily he could touch them. It was a bit of a relief to see all kinds of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/8M8ZEgN3d5lrAn4OIXvgwW4UjVh9iglaWlJzM1nF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/8M8ZEgN3d5lrAn4OIXvgwW4UjVh9iglaWlJzM1nF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258157&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Writer Haruki Murakami’s favorite route to Meiji Jingu Gaien&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From historical opportunity to Hakone Ekiden&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;I am running along the path of a writer, but there is no inspiration. The writer is also very honest, saying that most of his thoughts are wandering while running, and he even treats himself as a running machine without emotions. There are many well-known writers in the world, and there are even more tenacious runners, but Haruki Murakami seems to be the only one who has both and is familiar to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a reason why Japan has such a well-known writer who loves running. Long-distance running is a national sport in Japan. The promotion and development of long-distance running for hundreds of years has allowed Japanese runners to cover all age groups, with a large base and high level. It can be compared to table tennis in China or basketball in the United States. Among the six major marathons in the world, the Tokyo Marathon is known as an event with more &quot;private subsidies&quot; than &quot;official subsidies&quot;. People spontaneously provide free supplies to the participants along the way. The number is actually more than the supply stations prepared by the event organizer. The enthusiasm of Tokyoites is also related to the superior strength of local athletes. Several local athletes often break the 2 hours and 10 minutes mark. This result is on par with the world&#39;s top East African athletes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of marathon events in China has been in full swing in the past ten years. If you often browse the event registration app, you can find places to participate every month. Sometimes you just feel overwhelmed. If there is any gap between domestic marathon events and the world&#39;s &quot;Big Six&quot;, it is actually more at the cultural level, and there is no other way to form a culture but time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Thomas Havens, an American Japanese scholar, Japan sent two runners to participate in the marathon event at the Stockholm Olympic Games in 1912, which can be called the starting point of the marathon in Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Japanese government at that time had limited financial resources and could only select two athletes to participate in the Olympics. The marathon is very similar to the long-distance running events that were held sporadically in the late Edo period. The purpose of these events was to &quot;improve the physical fitness of the people&quot; and to show that the Japanese could gain their own status in similar competitions in the West. This driving force, which combines national pride, proof of modernity, and an attitude of active participation in international competition, is the legacy of the Meiji Restoration of the same period. A famous example is a lively 12-hour running endurance race held in 1901 on the narrow track around Tokyo&#39;s Shinobazu Pond, which attracted more than a hundred competitors, 15 of whom completed 71 laps&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(103.6 kilometers)&lt;/span>;. Therefore, one of the last two Japanese athletes to participate in the 1912 Olympic Games was a marathon runner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the 1920s and 1930s, the Japanese were already among the fastest marathon runners in the world. After World War II, after decades of recuperation, from the 1960s to the 1980s, Japanese marathon runners returned to a dominant position in the world. In 1966, 15 of the top 17 results in the world rankings were created by Japanese male runners. By the 1990s, Japanese female marathon runners began to dominate the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/eGqKlFUPUY3mB92p0O1ho9fWKjEsLzTttbo2qd38.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/eGqKlFUPUY3mB92p0O1ho9fWKjEsLzTttbo2qd38.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258156&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Promotional materials about various events and clubs in the runner service station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;For a hundred years, Japan has been able to continue to dominate the world marathon field because of its large reserve of high-level private athletes. These high-level Japanese athletes have a more important platform for private events than the Olympic Games - Hakone Ekiden. The full name of Hakone Ekiden is &quot;Tokyo-Hakone Round-trip University Ekiden Race&quot;, which is a round trip between Tokyo and Hakone in the form of a half-marathon relay, with a total length of 217 kilometers and a total of ten stages. The units are based on each university. From the perspective of ratings, it is not an exaggeration to say that Hakone Ekiden is equivalent to the Japanese Spring Festival Gala. Since Nippon Television broadcast the entire Hakone Ekiden live in 1987, the ratings have remained at around 25%. You have to know that the entire game lasts for 12 hours. The ratings of China CCTV Spring Festival Gala in recent years have been just over 20%. Hakone Ekiden is arranged a few days before the New Year and is a great show that Japanese people can enjoy during the New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the TV series of the same name as the novel &quot;Strong Wind&quot; was released in Japan. This TV series is set in Hakone Ekiden and tells a passionate sports story about an unknown university long-distance running team that went through devilish training and counterattacked in the competition. , making more people aware of this Japanese sports event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The founder of Hakone Ekiden is the aforementioned Kanakuri Shizo, one of the marathon runners Japan sent to participate in the Stockholm Olympics. Kanakuri Shisan&#39;s first marathon Olympic trip was a tragedy. At that time, Japan used the whole country to send him and another sprinter to the Olympic Games. The travel expenses for each of the two athletes were equivalent to the thirty-six years of the prestigious Waseda University. tuition fees. However, the expectations of the people across the country and the fatigue of the journey overwhelmed him. The heat on the day of the competition was extremely hot. One Portuguese athlete even fell to the ground and died. Kanali No. 3 also lost consciousness during the journey and was carried home by local farmers. When he woke up, he was After the game the next day. He later participated in two Olympic Games, with his best result being 16th. Looking back now, the return on the cost of tuition fees at prestigious universities in the past thirty-six years has been too generous, and Kanakuri Shisan has become a leader in the development of marathons in Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1920, the first Hakone Ekiden was held between four universities including Waseda University and Meiji University. Except for the suspension during the two world wars, 99 sessions have been held so far. This competition will be the first in 2024 centenary event. Hakone Ekiden has provided a large number of world-class athletes for Japanese marathons. Among them, Osako Kei, the most familiar to Chinese running enthusiasts, has captured a large number of fans because of his handsome appearance and elegant running posture. He was once a student at Waseda University in Hakone Ekiden. An elite runner who still holds the domestic marathon record in Japan. Many of the current college runners are well-known celebrities. People take the train and rush to the viewing point in advance like chasing stars, waiting for several hours in the cold wind of the New Year. There will be tens of thousands of spectators waiting at the finish line, saying &quot;congratulations&quot; and &quot; &quot;Thank you for your hard work&quot; and &quot;You&#39;re already great&quot;. As the players passed the finish line one by one, such shouts came one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as you have a slight idea of ​​marathon results, browsing the Hakone Ekiden stage results every year is simply staggering, especially in 2023, when many long-standing records for stages were broken. Someone asked on &quot;Zhihu&quot; if the ten best amateur long-distance runners in China were selected to form a team, and it was not limited to college students, would they be able to enter the top ten of Hakone Ekiden? The answer is regrettable. After converting the same distance Afterwards, this team could only finish 15th in Hakone Ekiden that same year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, to quote a data, from November 23 to 25, 2012, a total of six full marathons were held across Japan. A total of 77,772 runners completed the race. The completion rate in five of the six races exceeded 90 %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/SncyVY9nj9L27yumGNuBesGoiIbrQ7FFHFrVsbGy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/SncyVY9nj9L27yumGNuBesGoiIbrQ7FFHFrVsbGy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258161&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;People preparing for activities in front of the runner service station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Chen Xi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;&lt;strong>;Government and Business&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Conspiracy”, Beginning with Yasuhiro Nakasone&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Long distance running is boring and grueling, 1990 The &quot;Ma Jiajun&quot;, which led the domestic middle and long-distance running events in the 1990s, recruited mostly team members from ordinary families in small and medium-sized cities. They relied on hard work, the ability to endure hardship, and won a place in society through sports performance. But marathon has been an elite sport in Japan since its beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hakone Ekiden first unfolded among four prestigious universities including Waseda University. As part of the rise of the nation and nationalism, these elite college students became the main force. This gene has been running through the development of Japanese marathon for nearly a hundred years. To this day, Japan&#39;s famous universities are still sending young people to the marathon. After graduation, these college students usually enter well-known Japanese companies and join professional runners sponsored by the companies. The team represents the company in various competitions at home and abroad to win glory for the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aforementioned Osako Jie joined the Nissin Industrial Running Group after graduating from Waseda University. However, joining a corporate running team means that corporate interests come first. Companies may even require athletes to sacrifice preparation time for international competitions such as the Olympics and give priority to domestic competitions in Japan. Therefore, many top athletes, including Osako Kei, ultimately chose to withdraw from corporate running groups in order to dominate their sports careers. After Kei Osako quit Nissin Industries and joined the Oregon Project sponsored by Nike, there were still many voices in Japanese society calling him a &quot;traitor&quot;. However, as he achieved excellent results in the international arena, these criticisms have become past tense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to the process of the Japanese marathon movement from state dominance to market dominance, one person cannot be avoided - former Japanese Prime Minister Yasuhiro Nakasone. Yasuhiro Nakasone is a highly controversial figure both for China and Japan. He once participated in the war of aggression against China as an officer. However, in the early days of China&#39;s reform and opening up, he strongly urged Japan to provide financial guarantees for China&#39;s export trade at that time. Without Japan guarantee, it would be even more difficult to obtain international loan financing given China&#39;s economic conditions at the time. He visited the Yasukuni Shrine and later apologized for Japan&#39;s war of aggression against China. But if you dig deeper into the core of his character, you will find that it all stems from his pragmatism. He once said: &quot;When asked what you did in post-war democracy, I can answer that I worked desperately to develop political methods in line with the era of mass democracy, and the patent for its secrets belongs to me.&quot; As a way to cater to public opinion He is a master of Japan. During his tenure as prime minister, he completed the &quot;division and nationalization of Japan&#39;s national railways&quot;. He dismantled Japan&#39;s national railways, which were once part of Japan&#39;s state monopoly, and operated them in a corporatized manner. Nowadays, you often see &quot;JR&quot; when traveling to Japan. &quot;East Japan&quot;, &quot;JR West&quot;, &quot;JR Hokkaido&quot;, etc. are all companies spun off from Japan National Railways. According to Nakasone Yasuhiro&#39;s pragmatism, these were all part of his efforts to cater to public opinion. As he said, Japan was already in an era of mass democracy at that time, and he pushed for this to happen faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this wave of privatization, the sports industry that was originally dominated by the Japanese state has gradually been handed over to the market. In the 1970s, the Japan Amateur Sports Association (JASA), which once believed that business would corrode the spirit of sports, began to allow Olympic athletes to appear in television advertisements, and the fees received were divided between the athletes&#39; companies and JASA. Advertising giant Dentsu organized a Japan Go campaign in 1979 to support the following year&#39;s Moscow Olympics. This kind of sponsorship of sports events by big companies became more popular in the 1980s, and athletes&#39; incomes also increased. After the Japanese real estate bubble burst in 1991, government finances were further tightened, and the marketization of sports was accelerated. To this end, the Japanese government also formulated a series of tax incentive policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Against this series of historical backgrounds, the marathon has been a sports event that Japan hopes to have an impact on the world since 1912. After a hundred years of development, it has gradually completed commercialization. This is also the trend and trend of world sports development: attracting the interest and social capital of the whole people through commercial methods, and selecting top talents on the basis of mass sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, the Tokyo Metropolitan Government defeated the business consortium with vested interests in the elite marathon event, and also calmed the Tokyo Police Department’s concerns that the marathon would greatly disrupt urban order. The first Tokyo Tokyo Olympics was funded by the government. Marathon. Now, the Tokyo Marathon is one of the six major international marathon events in the world. You must know that the Boston Marathon, one of the &quot;big six&quot;, started in 1897. The Tokyo Marathon has brought huge influence and commercial benefits to the city &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (more than 150 million U.S. dollars per year)&lt;/span>; and has become a competition for governments across Japan. The objects of imitation, Osaka Marathon, Kobe Marathon, Yokohama Marathon, and Hokkaido Marathon, have now become events with many domestic and foreign participants, and each time you need to draw lots to register. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/fiLBn71yrJJIKEVF2OVbgeeWHlXkdpxRdCc4gfza.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/fiLBn71yrJJIKEVF2OVbgeeWHlXkdpxRdCc4gfza.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258162&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Have an aerobic jog in Tokyo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course , a huge successful conspiracy between government and business must have provided some kind of social necessity. During the &quot;lost thirty years&quot; of Japan&#39;s economy, long-distance running became a way to inspire the national spirit and an antidote to spiritual dilemmas. This antidote not only acts on the body, producing pleasant dopamine and endorphins, building a healthy body that can cope with the high intensity of modern life, but it also acts on the mind, dealing with the emptiness that comes after the hardships of life with great material prosperity and lack. Just like Haruki Murakami&#39;s favorite saying: Pain is inevitable. Suffering is optional. He said, &quot;Really valuable things can often be obtained through very inefficient operations. Even if this is an illusory behavior, it is by no means a stupid behavior. I think so as a practical feeling as a rule of thumb.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In short, everyone who loves running can refer to the epitaph designed by Haruki Murakami for himself: &quot;He at least ran to the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[FF三季度卖车3辆，收入55.1万美元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260579]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 14, Faraday Futere (FF) released its third quarter financial report for 2023. During the reporting period, FF achieved revenue generation for the first time in the company&#39;s history, with total revenue of approximately US$551,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The financial report stated that FF&#39;s vehicle sales revenue includes revenue related to new car delivery, as well as revenue from certain other functions and services, including home chargers, charger installation, all-weather roadside assistance, software updates (&quot;OTA&quot;) ), Internet connection and destination fees (offset by certain co-creation fees). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the third quarter, FF delivered a total of 3 vehicles. That translates to roughly $183,600 in revenue per vehicle. The FF 91 2.0 Futurist Alliance previously disclosed by FF is priced at approximately US$309,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for FF, starting to generate revenue is already a new milestone. According to the financial report, as of the release of the financial report, FF has delivered 7 FF 91 2.0 Futurist Alliance to new users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to revenue, FF’s cost of sales in the third quarter was US$16.1 million. Of this amount, $10.4 million was depreciation on tools and equipment, and most of the remainder was manufacturing overhead, followed by labor and material costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FF explained that the higher cost of sales is due to the natural inefficiencies of early vehicle production - that is, the higher cost of parts caused by initial manufacturing inefficiencies and low output. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, FF was still in the red in the third quarter, with a net loss of approximately US$78 million, which was narrower than the net loss of US$119 million in the same period last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of cash flow, in the first three quarters of this year, FF&#39;s operating activities generated net cash outflows of US$240 million, compared with US$355 million in the same period last year; capital expenditures were US$10.8 million, compared with US$112 million in the same period last year; financing activities The net cash inflow generated was US$237.6 million, while the net cash outflow from financing activities in the same period last year was US$40.9 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the third quarter, FF raised a total of US$61.8 million through convertible notes, equity line of credit (ELOC) and ATM financing. As of September 30, 2023, FF&#39;s cash balance was $8.567 million, including $1.853 million in restricted cash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the future, FF said that the company plans to start the third phase of delivery at the end of the first quarter of 2024, that is, to fully deliver vehicles to users. According to the current factory improvement and ramp-up plan, FF&#39;s goal next year is to achieve a production of approximately 1,000 vehicles, but FF also admitted that this is subject to obtaining the required capital, the capacity and stability of the supply chain, and obtaining the necessary licenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[丢下铁饭碗，出走围城丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260559]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;November 11, 2023, Kunming, as the national examination and postgraduate entrance examination are approaching, candidates have a weekend Come to Yunnan Provincial Library for review. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f89400eabe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f89400eabe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 11, 2023, Kunming, as the national and postgraduate entrance examinations approached, candidates came to the Yunnan Provincial Library to review on the weekend. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260140?source=131&quot;>;&quot;When introduced highly educated talents decide to leave the county&quot;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, my mother came to Beijing to see me, and the topic naturally turned up that her colleague’s child had found a job this year. One works in a community in Beijing, with a monthly salary of more than 8,000 yuan, and has a Beijing household registration; the other stayed in Shandong and went to the CPPCC unit, which is also within the system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a former student from Shandong, in the first twenty years of my life, there was a saying that was repeatedly emphasized in my family, &quot;Knowledge changes destiny.&quot; How to understand? I think if there are simulation games for raising children, then my parents’ goal must be for their children to enter a good university and then choose one of the two good jobs of teachers and civil servants. Unfortunately, reality is biased. When he learned that I was not admitted to a major such as administration in the college entrance examination, my dad clearly expressed his disappointment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time, the pursuit of the system and the iron rice bowl has been one of the labels for us Shandong people. Until recent years, young people across the country have People also spontaneously fall in love with taking public exams and taking exams for editors. Stability is the most mentioned advantage of this job. The pseudonym in the report is Meng Cheng, a 35-year-old returnee man who joined the editor and then resigned to study for a PhD. This is how he was attracted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The starting point of the story is as usual. He was worried that the employment environment would require more and more academic qualifications. Between studying for a Ph.D. and finding a job, Meng Cheng chose the latter and went smoothly. Obtained a career establishment in a poor county in Guangxi. Unfortunately, this job that I started with great expectations was described as a &quot;siege&quot; when I left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When the Municipal Party Committee Organization Department wrote in the post, it was called Tourism Development Center. I was quite happy and thought I could participate in tourism projects.&quot; On the day of joining the job, Meng Cheng learned that &quot;separation of staff and staff&quot; was implemented in talent introduction, and he was actually assigned to the general office. &quot;Because when you are recruited, you must be assigned an establishment, so the Organization Department collected some empty establishments from the units.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the general office, one of Meng Cheng’s most feared tasks is organizing documents. “For example, if the municipal level publishes a document on the tourism market rectification plan, we will If you want to produce a county-level document, you can copy part of the city-level document, but you can&#39;t copy it all. You have to read it carefully.&quot; From writing to finalizing, it is common to spend a day and a half digging for a few words. What troubles him even more is that for things like writing documents, there is no clear operational process. “A lot of times it’s just casual remarks from the leader.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is still a lot of suffering in the besieged city. During the interview, we met a girl who had been working in the system for five years through talent introduction. The idea of ​​resigning had been lingering in her mind for more than three years, although she did not appear in the manuscript in the end. But I think her summary of the reasons for her resignation should represent the voice of the vast majority of people who want to leave the system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Recent master&#39;s degree graduates should be graded as a fourth-level chief clerk, but my unit assigned me a first-grade chief clerk until now. Join me in introducing Most of the students who came here were appointed as fourth-level chief clerks, and this year they were promoted to third-level chief clerks, which made me feel very unbalanced. On the other hand, the work in the system is more service-oriented and coordination-oriented, and the professional basics There is no use, no sense of gain, and no creativity. Just listen to your superiors and just be an obedient person. Over time, you will no longer be able to think independently. In addition, there is a serious age gap among employees, and the phenomenon of seniority is serious, and hard work is difficult. In the past two years, senior comrades have been considered first for promotions, and most of the energy has been spent on how to push out the work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent times, I have seen my close friends around me I couldn’t find a job everywhere, and I did a lot of job-related topics. I have been thinking that since childhood, the education we have received has cultivated individuals to become intellectually rich through a simple stimulus-reward mechanism. , but rarely teaches us how to grow into a complete self, and what to do next when the school education a person can receive comes to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, at the point of graduating from undergraduate or graduate school, some people throw themselves into society hastily, doing jobs they don’t understand or even dislike. Not getting affirmation, they repeatedly question their personal value; others turn around and hide in school, delaying the time to make a decision. These are all detours taken by talents who are introduced to the county and then leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Meng Cheng&#39;s view, leaving the system means leaving the siege, but is there a siege outside the siege? When can the layers of walls be demolished? Losing money may be a more complex social issue than personal choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孩子被欺负，该打回去吗？谈谈我对孩子的勇气教育]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260544]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My son, who is in fifth grade, got into a fight at school. When my wife told me, my first reaction was surprise. My son has been mild-mannered since he was a child, not competitive, and rarely conflicts with other children. Before the fifth grade, he had never had a fight. The most he had was an argument and a few angry words. My wife and I occasionally worry: We have been competitive for half our lives, and our children will not be bullied if they have such a bad temper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a naughty little boy in the class who loves to tease others. He is strong and full of energy, and other students cannot stop him. My son occasionally complains: This classmate is very annoying and always teases him and touches him. At first we couldn&#39;t hear the big problem, so we didn&#39;t take it seriously. It is normal for boys to collide with each other. If there is no fight or trouble, we as parents will not interfere deeply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My son complained several times. One day, my wife and I told him: &quot;If the teacher can&#39;t control things, you can solve them yourself. If it doesn&#39;t work, just call him back and don&#39;t let others bully you.&quot; The complaints stopped for a few days, and we almost forgot about this little incident. Unexpectedly, my son actually got into a fight. This was the first real fight between him and his classmates since he went to school, and he was the one who started the fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of the incident is very simple: a group of boys were playing in the dormitory, and the usually naughty boy was teased by a certain child and became irritated. The son was also present, and the boy threw an unknown anger at him, swearing and pushing him. The son angrily demanded an apology, but the other classmate refused, so the son punched the classmate in the face, and the two struggled, and then the teacher arrived and took the two away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We told him that if someone scolds you, just scold him back. How can you hit someone? My son’s answer was that he used to scold him, but that classmate was even better at scolding him. He scolded him again and again, and he was caught twice by the teacher. Not only was he scolded, but he was also made to stand in the classroom. It was so frustrating. &quot;What are you scolding each other?&quot; &quot;He called me stupid, and I called him stupid.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remembering it, the teacher did mention this matter, but he just downplayed it, and we didn&#39;t take it too seriously. pay attention to. When we reminded our son at that time, my wife and I secretly complained: The day has come when the child curses. It seems like this has been going on for two or three months. After a long period of patience and protest, the son finally broke out and rushed towards the strong classmate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After talking to our children, my wife and I were filled with shame and fear. We communicate a lot with our children. In order to give our children room to grow, we don’t pay attention to certain small snippets we hear, and ignore the children’s repeated calls for help. His character was originally gentle, but he endured restraint for a long time, leaving a &quot;weak&quot; impression on his classmates (who took it out on him when they were angered), and he was on the verge of being &quot;bullied&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, the son launched a timely counterattack and prevented the situation from getting worse. This incident also surprised the classmates around him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For his first fight, my wife and I did not blame him, but fell into self-reflection. Reflect on the negligence of parents and the key points of educating children. But one thing is very lucky: we always encourage him to have the courage to have conflicts with classmates, not to be submissive, timid, and have to compromise, but to dare to express anger. It can be seen that this kind of teaching has worked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We teach him this way largely because his character is too gentle and needs some &quot;blessing&quot;. A little boy can have no temper, but he must have strength. In order to protect our own rights and dignity, we do not object to children fighting among themselves. It is wrong to actively bully others. Hitting back when bullied is a form of defense and can also establish an effective deterrent. The child asked that time, what should I do if I can’t beat him? Wife&#39;s quick answer: If you can&#39;t beat him, you have to beat him, at least to make him think that you are not easy to mess with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through this incident, we revised a combat &quot;guideline&quot; for children: in the future, if a classmate uses swear words, laughs at you, or insults you, do not use swear words against him. Ask the other person to stop and apologize. If the other person repeatedly refuses to apologize, you can teach him a lesson. It doesn&#39;t matter if you can&#39;t win. If the teacher criticizes you, your parents will bear with you. Don&#39;t get into dirty talk with classmates, it&#39;s too ugly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There must be many people who disagree with this educational concept. Chinese people have always been gentle, courteous, thrifty and accommodating in their interactions. The rules and legal regulations for adults also say that &quot;a gentleman talks but does not use his hands&quot; and &quot;the one who strikes first is at fault.&quot; I don’t need to teach you these principles. Children will gradually understand them as they grow up. We value the education of courage, a quality that is more important than daily academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Courage is valuable because it allows children to build daily self-confidence and have the courage to explore and discover; it allows children to get rid of troubles, get rid of worries, and develop a sunny and cheerful personality. When children are in adversity, they can still think and make decisions instead of running away from difficulties, which is conducive to developing the quality of distinguishing right from wrong. It is no accident that a person with courage is often smart and upright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Courage education is certainly not about encouraging children to abuse violence or actively bully others with violence. Allowing children to fight should be limited to conflict resolution, not bullying of classmates. You need to express your anger and give a warning before taking action, rather than fighting randomly. A few simple rules can be understood by children. This kind of reasoning and exchange is far more conducive to improving children&#39;s understanding of the world than a crude prohibition of &quot;fighting is wrong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teaching children to develop courage is actually not easy. It is inevitable for adults to be submissive, but children are weak and often isolated. At this time, they need help from adults (especially parents). After understanding the reason for our son&#39;s fight, we stated the facts to the teacher and expressed our support for the child. The two parents met, apologized and understood, and the matter was resolved satisfactorily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Children fighting&quot; actually does not require much input from parents. The biggest pressure that children face every day comes from school. Teachers misunderstand punishments, cage management during breaks, and unnecessary extracurricular tasks... These need to be examined by parents and help their children withstand the pressure. My wife and I will help our child complete the assigned tasks and reassure him: It&#39;s not your fault that you didn&#39;t do it well, and it doesn&#39;t matter if the teacher asks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family is the most important place for children to grow, and parents are their best teachers. Courage, integrity, cheerfulness, optimism... these qualities are difficult to learn in school, and may even be erased. Parents need to take responsibility at this time and pass on values ​​to their children. This is not only character education for children, but also a process of constant reflection and re-growth for parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访世界银行原副行长祝宪：中国发展历程是不同于西方的现代化“药方”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As the largest source of funds for developing countries, the World Bank’s economic forecast reports and economic warnings have always attracted much attention . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1980, the third year of reform and opening up, China restored its representation and membership status in the World Bank, and received its first loan from the World Bank the following year. In the following thirty years, China became a protagonist on the world economic stage due to its reform and opening up. It transformed from a borrower of the World Bank to a major shareholder and played an important role in global economic cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China is also the third largest shareholder of the Asian Development Bank (&quot;ADB&quot;) and one of the initiators of the BRICS New Development Bank (&quot;New Development Bank&quot;). By participating in multiple international financial institutions, including the World Bank, China has integrated into the international economic order. After regaining its seat in the World Bank, what else did China get besides loans? As the status of the World Bank continues to improve, what has China contributed to the World Bank? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Xian, who is currently the Executive Vice Chairman and Secretary-General of the International Financial Forum (IFF), has served in the Ministry of Finance for a long time, and has successively served as China’s Executive Director of the World Bank, Vice President and Chief Ethics Officer of the World Bank He is the official, vice president and chief operating officer of the BRICS New Development Bank. He is a witness to my country’s long-term cooperation with international financial institutions such as the World Bank. He is also an experienced promoter of my country’s introduction of international funds to accelerate domestic innovation after reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the &quot;IFF 20th Anniversary Global Annual Conference&quot; held recently, Zhu Xian accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend and said that the World Bank plays an important role in China&#39;s reform and opening up process, not only providing loans, but also playing an important role in policy Suggestions, institutional innovation and talent cultivation play an important role, and their role cannot be ignored. At the same time, the World Bank began to promote China&#39;s successful experience in reform and opening up, because China&#39;s development process is different from the Western &quot;prescription&quot; for modernization. This is a very important reference for other developing countries. China also actively participates in global governance through international organizations and tells China&#39;s story to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Xian also emphasized that China’s reform and opening up must continue to move forward, relying on innovation and becoming an indispensable part of the world economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/CVbbOeohfYI9YrRiI9o7LXuesKxQ9Q4HWb43a4EE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;766&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/CVbbOeohfYI9YrRiI9o7LXuesKxQ9Q4HWb43a4EE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhu Xian: Former Vice President and Chief Ethics Officer of the World Bank, former Vice President and Chief Operating Officer of the New Development Bank; currently Executive Vice Chairman and Secretary-General of the International Financial Forum. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;First opening&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;International&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;Pioneering bidding system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1980, China resumed A legal seat at the World Bank (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;World Bank&quot;). Information shows that at the beginning of reform and opening up, the cooperative relationship between China and the World Bank was mainly about receiving aid. You were working in the Ministry of Finance at the time and served successively as deputy director of the World Bank Department, deputy director of the National Debt Department and director of the International Department, etc., so you became closely associated with the World Bank. What was the first project China received assistance from the World Bank? What is the historical background? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China is a founding member of the World Bank. In April 1980, Robert Strange McNamara, then President of the World Bank, was invited to visit China and was received by Deng Xiaoping. Deng Xiaoping said a very famous and courageous saying at that time, &quot;We have fallen behind these years, and we have to catch up. I hope the World Bank can help us, but even without this help, we are determined to catch up.&quot; This was Comrade Xiaoping&#39;s words. The original words are also a tone-setting speech. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, China resumed its legal seat in the World Bank. In July of the same year, the World Bank sent its first high-level delegation to China for inspection and subsequently submitted a detailed inspection report to the World Bank Board of Directors. This is the first step for the World Bank to launch a loan project in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lubuge&quot; Hydropower Station was China&#39;s first project using World Bank loans and implementing international bidding in the early 1980s. As a key national construction project of the year, the &quot;Lubuge&quot; Hydropower Station is known as the &quot;window&quot; for China&#39;s hydropower capital construction projects to open to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to obtaining a loan, what changes has this project brought? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the era of planned economy, China’s infrastructure construction projects were mainly established through mandatory plans. After receiving financial allocations or budget allocations, Construction of designated state-owned enterprises. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to the loan agreement signed with the World Bank, some projects in Lubuge must implement international bidding. This was a completely new thing at the time, and of course there was resistance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I happened to work in the Ministry of Finance in 1984. At that time, with the help of the World Bank, a total of engineering contractors from 8 countries, including state-owned enterprises, participated in the bidding. In the end, Japan&#39;s Dachen Company won the bid, and the winning price was 43% lower than the lowest bid price. After entering the company, it only sent a management team of more than 30 people and used the &quot;on-site recruitment&quot; model to form a construction team of more than 400 people. It managed the company according to a contract system and paid workers according to their work efficiency. This changed the “big pot” model of state-owned enterprises at that time. Workers are no longer paid the same amount, but are distributed according to their work. In the end, not only the construction cost was greatly reduced, but the construction efficiency was also greatly improved, and the project progress was significantly accelerated. The project was completed in 1986, five months ahead of schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the introduction of foreign advanced equipment, technology and management experience, the &quot;Lubuge&quot; hydropower station project has become a benchmark for my country&#39;s infrastructure construction to open to the outside world. In 1987, the State Council held a special meeting to require the comprehensive promotion of the &quot;Lu Buge Experience&quot; in the construction industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident later became known as the &quot;Lu Buge Shock&quot;. It is the first of its kind in China to launch global bidding, with price, efficiency and quality as its core assessments. It’s not just the World Bank loan we received, but more importantly these institutional changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Help China&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Promote market reform&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to being the first to launch a bidding system, what profound impact has the &quot;Lu Buge Experience&quot; had on China&#39;s reform and opening up? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From the perspective of project management and financing conditions, the &quot;Lubuge Experience&quot; has influenced China&#39;s infrastructure construction for more than 30 years since then. . The bidding system has since been gradually promoted in the country, and today almost all major infrastructure projects in the public budget must go through bidding. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the World Bank, the impact on China from the 1980s to the 1990s was not only the provision of loans, but also a lot of pioneering work in institutional innovation and talent training. It played an important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From my experience, this role is no less important than providing loan funds, especially during the transition from a planned economy to a market economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In what aspects is this importance mainly reflected? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time we didn’t quite know how to transform the socialist market economy. The World Bank conducted a comprehensive investigation of the Chinese economy and then wrote targeted recommendations and reports, some of which were praised by the top leadership at the time. The World Bank also recommended that governments at all levels, especially central ministries and commissions such as the Ministry of Finance, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the National Development and Reform Commission, carry out institutional innovation, which has had a relatively large impact. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, in the process of dealing with international organizations such as the World Bank, our country has also trained a group of market reform talents. For example, Zhou Xiaochuan, Lou Jiwei, etc. all gained their knowledge during exchanges with the World Bank and played an important role in market reform. I was still relatively young at the time, but I also got exercise during my exchanges with the World Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, not all World Bank recommendations are in line with China&#39;s national conditions, but many of the policy recommendations put forward at that time were based on economic surveys conducted in China, as well as exchanges with domestic officials and scholars, and after comparison with international experience. Feedback to China. So overall a lot of good advice was accepted and became reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;borrower&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;to&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;significant shareholder&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From an official of the Chinese Ministry of Finance working in conjunction with the World Bank, to serving as China&#39;s executive director in the World Bank, and even to the world Vice President of the Bank. With the reform and opening up, while your personal role is changing, China&#39;s status in the World Bank is also improving. During your tenure at the World Bank, if you looked at China from a different perspective, what would be the differences? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After the restoration of the legal seat of the World Bank, as a major country, China has obtained a seat on the executive director, joining the United Nations permanent members such as the United States and the United Kingdom. Like the Governing Council members, they have separate offices at the World Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a sense, the Executive Director of the World Bank is an official sent by China, not an official of the World Bank itself. Before and after I took office, many people held this position, such as Li Yong and Zhang Shengman before me, and Zhu Guangyao and Zou Jiayi after me. I feel very honored to be able to perform my duties at the World Bank on behalf of my motherland, and it is also a heavy responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the improvement of comprehensive national strength, China’s influence in the World Bank has gradually expanded. The World Bank began to promote China&#39;s successful experience in reform and opening up, firstly, to get rid of absolute poverty, and secondly, to promote the transformation of the planned economy into a socialist market economy through infrastructure construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very important reference for other developing countries. At the same time, China is also actively participating in global governance and telling China’s story to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What milestone events remain fresh in your memory? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;During my tenure at the World Bank, there were two milestone events that impressed me deeply: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;First, China’s loan scale from the World Bank reached US$3 billion per year for the first time. That was $3 billion more than thirty years ago. The World Bank&#39;s low-cost funds have become one of the most important channels for my country to introduce foreign investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using these funds, our country built a number of major infrastructure projects at that time. For example, the Beijing-Tianjin-Tangshan Expressway connecting Beijing and Tianjin was my country’s first inter-provincial and municipal expressway built with World Bank loans. This is the first project in China to introduce the construction of a supervisory system. The World Bank insists on giving priority to quality, strictly controls the progress and quality of the project, and will not sign for payment if it does not meet the standards, thus avoiding potential quality hazards caused by the rush period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, China has experienced a change in its role from a borrower to an important shareholder. In 1999, when I first joined the World Bank, China still ranked sixth in terms of voting rights. Now China has become the third largest shareholder of the World Bank. Although we still borrow money from the World Bank, as an important shareholder of the World Bank, our participation in the international financial market has gradually increased, and our influence on world economic development has gradually increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend: From a borrower to an important shareholder, how does China currently influence the world economy through the World Bank? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Xian: Compared with developed countries as shareholders, China’s role in the World Bank is different. For other developing countries, China&#39;s successful experience in reform and opening up has strong reference significance. Because China itself is a developing country, China&#39;s development process is different from the Western &quot;prescription&quot; for modernization, providing more practical experience in poverty alleviation and infrastructure construction. Therefore, China plays an increasingly important role in maintaining the international economic order and improving the global governance structure, and its influence in international organizations such as the World Bank is growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Compared with the World Bank, the New Development Bank has made breakthroughs and innovations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have successively held leadership positions in the World Bank, the Asian Development Bank (referred to as &quot;ADB&quot;) and the BRICS New Development Bank (referred to as &quot;New Development Bank&quot;). How does China exert its influence and role through different international financial organizations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are two reasons why I moved from the World Bank to the Asian Development Bank: First, we had fewer senior staff in international organizations at that time; And ADB happens to have a spot. Because I have experience working in the World Bank, the Ministry of Finance recommended me for an interview. Second, my professional ability in participating in promoting the World Bank&#39;s poverty alleviation project in western China has been recognized by all aspects of the World Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this is the general background that China has been highly recognized by international organizations such as the World Bank because of its reform and opening up. Without China&#39;s reform and opening up, there would be no experience for me and Chinese people like me in international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From my personal experience, working in the Ministry of Finance in the first half and working in multilateral international organizations in the second half are completely different experiences. I have witnessed China transform from a poor and backward country to the second largest in the world. the entire process of the economy. The experience of working in an international organization, especially promoting China&#39;s experience to other developing countries and promoting the development of poverty alleviation, is a very glorious career for me. In this process, the biggest challenge is how to balance maintaining Chinese characteristics and integrating with international standards. I hope this will attract the attention of young people currently working in international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The BRICS New Development Bank was officially established in Shanghai in 2015. China is one of the five largest shareholder countries and one of the initiators. Compared with the World Bank and AIIB, what innovations does it have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;According to the agreement between the five major shareholder countries at the beginning of the establishment of the New Development Bank, the first president will be an Indian, and the other four shareholders will Each country appoints a vice president. As the vice president in charge of business at that time, the first problem I faced was to clarify what kind of services the new bank would provide. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with multilateral international financial institutions such as the World Bank and the Asian Development Bank, the New Development Bank was entirely initiated and established by emerging market countries. However, the main business nature of the New Development Bank is different from that of multilateral financial institutions such as the World Bank. The institutions are relatively similar, and the clients are mainly developing countries. Therefore, we decided to learn from the good experiences and practices of the World Bank and ADB in related business fields, while avoiding the bureaucracy and efficiency problems common in international institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to be different from the World Bank&#39;s practice of attaching policy conditions when approving loan applications from developing countries, we proposed not to set loan conditions at the beginning of the establishment of the New Development Bank and respect the policies of different applicant countries. At the same time, in terms of &quot;environmental and social security policies&quot; and other aspects, the New Development Bank innovatively adopts a &quot;domestic system&quot; and implements it in accordance with the borrowing country&#39;s own lending policy. It is no longer like traditional multilateral financial institutions that impose a &quot;one size fits all&quot; policy on all borrowing countries. &quot;Acceptance effectively reduces the time and cost of borrowing countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another innovation is the adoption of &quot;local currency loans.&quot; Since the New Development Bank&#39;s funds mainly come from the local currencies of the five major shareholder countries rather than US dollars, the New Development Bank&#39;s loans are basically invested in the infrastructure of the host country. If these infrastructures generate income, its income will basically come from the host country and be in the form of It is reflected in the form of the country&#39;s local currency. Therefore, if the country borrows RMB and repays it in US dollars, it will create exchange rate risk. If you borrow local currency and repay local currency, there will be no exchange rate risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although compared with &quot;old banks&quot; such as the World Bank and Asia, the New Development Bank still needs to continue to work hard in many aspects, during my five-year term, the loan scale of the New Development Bank has increased from 0 to 0. $30 billion, pretty good. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;High-end service industry should have characteristics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(IFF) was initiated and established by leaders of more than 20 countries and regions including China, the United States, Britain, and Japan, as well as relevant international organizations and global financial institutions such as the United Nations, the European Union, the World Bank, and the International Monetary Fund. It is known as &quot;F20&quot;, its permanent venue is located in Nansha, Guangzhou. What role will IFF play in the integrated development and high-level opening up of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;IFF settling in Guangzhou is a mutual achievement. The Greater Bay Area has a developed economy and a high degree of marketization and internationalization, while IFF is globally representative and inclusive. This is also the significance of IFF settling in the Greater Bay Area and Guangzhou, to build a platform for non-governmental exchanges between scholars and enterprises. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nansha, Guangzhou, Hengqin, Zhuhai and Qianhai, Shenzhen Finance is at the forefront of China&#39;s reform and opening up. What are your expectations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a development perspective, Guangzhou should focus not only on investment in the real economy, but also on investment in the service industry, especially in areas such as finance. High-end service industry. In the past, manufacturing industry could attract foreign investment by demarcating a certain area with tax exemptions and other preferential treatment, but it is different now. The service industry needs to be opened up and needs institutional construction. The service industry differs from manufacturing in that services are more mobile. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, institutional openness means integrating with international standards. Now when local governments at all levels consider attracting foreign investment, they should not only focus on the manufacturing industry, but also the service industry, and need to explore new institutional opening-up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We also hope that the forum can make a contribution, at least to promote dialogue between the two parties. For example, the Nansha District government hopes to attract investment through us, but we suggest that manufacturing investment is no longer urgent for Nansha District, and what Guangdong needs now is not just manufacturing. While the manufacturing industry should be upgraded, investment in the service industry should have its own characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What special finance do you think should be developed in the Greater Bay Area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Greater Bay Area has huge demand for financial services. Greater Bay Area finance not only includes traditional bank loans and capital operations, but also digital finance and green financial services. In the process of continuous economic integration in the Greater Bay Area, we will provide enterprises with a full range of financial services, innovate in connectivity, and help the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area become a world-class bay area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area must become a world-class bay District, what do you suggest? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is still a long way to go for the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area to become a world-class bay area. First of all, compared with the Yangtze River Delta, the Greater Bay Area has institutional advantages, namely the three legal systems of &quot;one country, two systems&quot;. Secondly, dare to innovate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not just the Greater Bay Area. As China continues to move forward, it must rely on reform and opening up, rely on innovation, and become an indispensable part of the world economy. To correctly understand &quot;double circulation&quot;, &quot;inner circulation&quot; and &quot;external circulation&quot; are an organic whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, geographical factors cannot be ignored. The achievements China has made today are the direct result of reform and opening up. In other words, under the new situation, both cooperation and competition are needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国足球的“12岁退役”现象]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260557]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/14/7cca7c7bf41d87e4925b98a3d0ee722d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/14/7cca7c7bf41d87e4925b98a3d0ee722d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The phenomenon of &quot;retiring at the age of 12&quot; is something that Chinese football, which is full of opportunities, has to face painfully and deeply. A question of powerlessness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the U13 competition of the Key Cities Group of the Chinese Football Association Youth Football Championship (referred to as the &quot;Key City Group Competition&quot;) held in Qingdao at the end of October, tournament officials, coaches, and parents discussed this topic hotly and eagerly sought answers. A competition supervisor from Beijing told reporters that he deplored the changes in a youth team he had followed in the &quot;Hundred Teams Cup&quot; competition in Beijing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Those 10- and 11-year-old kids can play football better than we did when we were kids, but by the age of 12, half of the kids disappeared; by the time they were 13, they couldn’t play football anymore. He left. I went to ask the coach: &#39;Where are the people?&#39; He said that he spent four years training those children, and they just got a little bit in shape. When they entered junior high school, the team was disbanded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; &#39;Retiring at the age of 12&#39; is a phenomenon unique to us. If this problem is not solved, youth training will be cut in half and it will be difficult to achieve results,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since the widespread introduction of campus football, the number of players playing football has increased sharply in primary schools, but by the junior high school stage, that is, after the age of 12, there has been a sharp decline. &lt;/span>;This phenomenon appeared as early as 2018, when the organizers of the Beijing “100 Team Cup” announced a set of numbers about participating teams: there were 229 participating teams in the U8 and U9 primary school age groups, while U13 and U15 There are only 70 participating teams in the middle school age group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last year, reporters went to Xi&#39;an for research. The person in charge of the youth training of a local district and county football association said that among the echelons affiliated to their football association, there were more than 50 children in the U8 echelon; more than 20 in the U10 team; and only 10 in the U12 team. The left and right children cannot form a team alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A local youth training coach said that parents’ choice determines whether their children play football and also determines the quality of the youth training. He said: &quot;In the past, when we played football, our parents supported us, and the time spent playing football every day was longer than the time spent studying. Now it is just the opposite, and parents focus on studying. &lt;span>; There is no shortage of children with football talents in China. What is the support of parents? All are important. The future of Chinese football is in the hands of parents.&lt;/span>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Parents&#39; concerns&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen U13 women&#39;s football captain Lian Yutong every day Every time you go out to compete, one of your parents must accompany you. This time it was her father who accompanied her to Qingdao to participate in the key city group competition. He carried a projector from Shenzhen, not to play game videos, but to give his children online classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When the child comes out to compete, as long as conditions permit, her mother and I will definitely have someone accompany her, mainly to provide her with extra lessons.&quot; Lian Lian said, &quot;The child is only 13 years old and does not have that much self-discipline. She is strong, someone must supervise her to study during the competition. The pressure to study in junior high school is too great.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/14/0877d562f74bc96a41ede72c6915244c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;650&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/14/0877d562f74bc96a41ede72c6915244c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;April 15, 2023, Lian Yu Tong practices shooting at Shenzhen Baoan Stadium. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Mao Siqian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that Lian Yutong started playing football in the first grade of elementary school and spent a lot of time training and competing every week. For example, when I was in the sixth grade of elementary school, I was guaranteed at least four trainings and one game a week. &quot;It&#39;s absolutely fine to balance studying and playing football in elementary school.&quot; But in junior high school, the academic pressure suddenly increased. Lian Yutong was still able to train three times a week in the first grade of junior high school. After entering the second grade of junior high school this year, he really couldn&#39;t find the time. He could only put all the training on two days on the weekend and twice a week, leaving no training for the five days in between. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After children enter the second grade of junior high school, they only sleep 6 hours a day on average. Time is too precious. Sometimes they have to rush to train and have to eat in the car.&quot; Lian Lian said, &quot;In junior high school, if you want to If you play football, you will delay your studies; if you want to study, you will not be able to play well. You cannot have both.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that Lian Yutong&#39;s school has a high school entrance examination admission rate of only over 40%, which means that This means that she must be in the upper reaches of her class rankings to have any hope of being admitted to high school. This year Lian Yutong spent two months away training and competing, and his academic performance showed a downward trend. This made Lian Lian worried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now their father and daughter have two choices: focus on studying or focus on playing football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that focusing on study is a stable choice. Children can enter college and find a stable job in the future. But Lian Yutong likes to play football, and her parents respect her hobby. &quot;She really loves football, otherwise we wouldn&#39;t have to worry so much.&quot; But focusing on football is gambling with the child&#39;s future. There are too many uncertain factors in football and the success rate is too low, so learning cannot be lost. So, they can only do both. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/e51f43f59c69232015bc7fd34005c8c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/e51f43f59c69232015bc7fd34005c8c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258170&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 11, Lian Yutong (second from right) watched the game video with his parents and sister at home in Shenzhen. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Mao Siqian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But reality keeps reminding Lianlian: You can’t have your cake and eat it too. He was in a dilemma. “We can only walk and watch one day at a time,” he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that parents of children who play football often get together to discuss how to choose. Everyone is very anxious, and many choose to let their children give up football and study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The club Lian Yutong joined in elementary school had several teams for each age group, with the most teams from A to E5. The children went to play football after school in the afternoon. But in junior high school, there were no People play football, and it takes two age groups of children to form a team on weekends, and most children don’t play football anymore,” said Lian Lian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Yutong is still persisting, but the future is full of uncertainty. Lian Lian said that he now needs a kind of certainty to relieve his inner confusion, entanglement and anxiety about his child&#39;s future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b1ae2351a64afa5ec621c3122e4b072b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b1ae2351a64afa5ec621c3122e4b072b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258171&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 11, Lian Yutong (upper left) interacted with his teammates during a school team training match at the Shixia Junior High School of Hongling Middle School in Shenzhen Cheer up. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Mao Siqian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Suzhou Answer&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the key city group competitions, the Suzhou U13 women&#39;s football team is a standout, and it is guaranteed to win every game. , until finally winning the championship. Head coach Zhou Ying said that she has been taking her players to training and competitions since they were in the third or fourth grade of elementary school. As a team, they do not suffer from the &quot;12-year-old retirement&quot; phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This team receives training at Suzhou Sports School. The reporter asked Wang Jianjun, vice chairman of the Suzhou Football Association and vice president of Suzhou Sports School, about this. His written answer is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The phenomenon of &#39;retiring at the age of 12&#39; has not happened in Suzhou. The main reason is that when we select outstanding talents, we talk to the parents about their children&#39;s future. We will build A good platform allows parents to choose: 1. Help every child go to college, and focus on training, competition, and study. If you can&#39;t go to a professional club, you can find a respected job after graduation through college study. 2. Help particularly outstanding children enter the national team. 3. Can’t enter the national team but can be selected for the provincial team, represent the provincial team in the National Games and get the top three (Jiangsu Province has a policy that the top three in the National Games (can be placed in a job), and also solves the worries. 4. The requirement for coaches is not only to complete training and competition tasks, but more importantly, to cultivate each child to become a plastic talent with comprehensive development of morality, intelligence and physical fitness, so that every family Don’t worry. 5. At the high school stage, if children and parents are willing to go abroad to play football and study, we will also help them solve it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;So I think as long as the problem of children&#39;s future can be solved, there will be no problem. The &#39;retirement at 12&#39; phenomenon,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/97c4f2bf4f241214f1cd239406ac595f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/97c4f2bf4f241214f1cd239406ac595f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258172&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 15, 2022, the female football team members of Shengping Experimental Primary School in Suzhou City, Jiangsu Province were training. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Microphoto by Hang Xing)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The phenomenon of &quot;retiring at the age of 12&quot; is an unavoidable problem in Chinese football. The Chinese Football Association has begun to take measures to improve the youth training environment in the past two years, and recently established the policy of &quot;making youth training a top priority.&quot; &lt;/span>;The Qingdao venue of this key city group U13 competition specially organized a training class for women’s football coaches. Responsible departments in key football cities have held several similar coaching trainings, with the aim of comprehensively improving the capabilities of grassroots coaches. In addition, they also hope that key cities will open &quot;through trains&quot; for further studies to create conditions for football talents to further their studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U10 to U15 age group competitions in key city group events provide a key platform for the growth of players of the right age. Without this platform, Lian Yutong may not have the opportunity to participate in high-level national competitions. &quot;She has played a total of 12 11-a-side national matches so far, all of which are in key city groups this year.&quot; Lian Lian said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛U13女足主教练于铭磊在球队战胜武汉队后说：“孩子的成长需要这样的高水平比赛。这样的比赛要多举行。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使青训环境改善也不足以破除“12岁退役”现象。一位地方足球工作者无奈地说：“其实足协在这里办法不多，人家孩子去上学，你拦不住。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位教练说，家长需要孩子踢球未来有保障，“我们无法给他们保障，只能眼睁睁地看着一些很优秀的苗子离开了足球”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“12岁退役”导致大量足球人才流失，这一现象也并不仅限于12岁，只是在这一年龄段更为突出，有些孩子更早或稍晚放弃了足球。 &lt;span>;这是足球青训领域学训矛盾的反映，需要学训双管齐下解决。此现象不破，中国足球难兴。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[城市漫步丨洛城机密]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260542]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 12:05:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/gynCLkJT3JTZFvdKWSGUoMmLBVN4e1L8HuQkDoPc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/gynCLkJT3JTZFvdKWSGUoMmLBVN4e1L8HuQkDoPc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洛杉矶市中心。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1974年，当德国著名导演沃纳·赫尔佐格（Werner Herzog）听闻影评人、恩师洛特·艾斯纳（Lotte Eisner）病危，他没有登上下一班飞机或火车，而是执意从慕尼黑徒步去往巴黎。那是暴风雪肆虐的冬天，这一程至少需要好几周的时间，然而赫尔佐格却坚信：“只要我用双脚走过去，她就一定能活下来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以把赫尔佐格的行为看成是他私底下和命运之神打赌：如果我完成这一大胆的挑战，你必须兑现我的愿望。记录这段旅程的英译本《冰雪纪行》（Of Walking in Ice）在简介里把赫尔佐格的徒步之行称为“朝圣之旅”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也很喜欢长途漫步。然而，美国的城市很多是为汽车打造的，不适合步行。很多城市里都有类似的情况，从A地到B地看起来直线距离很近，但没有所谓的捷径，有的只是绕行的公路，十分钟的车程走路就要一个小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我仍选择走路，当然不是作为每天通勤的手段，而是周末“放空”的方式。在美国，或许除了东海岸的少数几座城市，大多数城市无法提供很好的“城市漫步”感受。但有时候我会反过来觉得，所谓良好的“城市漫步”体验是现代商业社会对消费者的规训。我们期待在地图上标出一个个重要的地标：街道提供“景致”，建筑提供“历史”，博物馆提供“浓缩的知识”，餐厅提供美食，咖啡店提供休憩，而后我们会逐个踩点，自以为对这个地方了然于胸。殊不知，我们不过在这些地方做着普通游客所做的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真正的步行是把肉身暴露在荒芜面前。来美国的第一年在爱荷华，那是被大片玉米地包围的大学城，因为好奇，明明可以坐校车回来的路，我用走的，经过的其实就是漫天飞长的野草，偶尔经过几栋大方盒子状的体育馆和学校建筑，路上没有人，只有我和几只彩色羽翅的小鸟。鸟儿似乎也觉得我很奇怪，停在枝条上瞅了我半晌才姗姗飞走。大自然没有善恶这种简单的二分法，我几次目睹遭到野猫袭击后的鸟雀尸体，有时候是我误闯“犯罪现场”，我看到野猫半掩在草丛中，用凶恶的眼神看我，生怕我抢走它的猎物。还有一次，我在河边与一条正在“穿马路”的小蛇狭路相逢，我浑身的汗毛都竖起来了，到底是继续往前走还是退回去？我犹豫着，这时候，我才发现，小蛇可能也在怕我，它蜷曲起来，也在想到底是前进还是倒退。这种彼此的害怕反而消解了我的恐惧，很快，它窜进对面的草丛，我也继续往前走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在城市里，尤其是美国的城市里，街道也颇有狂野自然的意味。开车的人可以把“荒芜”的时间压缩到最低限度，也可以用金属和车窗玻璃来建构自由和安全。步行则无法提供这种选项。在洛杉矶，虽然我从市中心回家有很便捷的公交和轻轨，但我还是常常花一个多小时走回来。城市的风貌会立即发生转变，前面还是高楼大厦以及沿街叫卖的墨西哥裔摊贩，隔一条马路就是绘满涂鸦的天桥以及衣衫褴褛、自言自语的流浪汉，因为走路，必须和他们擦身而过，鼻腔接受着尿骚臭的侵袭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我无意美化这种步行的行为，我这么做，一半是因为驾照仍没有考过，另一半则是幼年的习惯使然。不仅是洛杉矶，我在圣路易斯、底特律、芝加哥也是这样走，甚至走过几个需要稍加提防的街区。这样的行为在很多人看来无异于冒险，新闻上偶尔会有神志恍惚的流浪汉袭击路人的行为。但实际上，更多的是不适，而不是危险，倘若你像我一样，看起来就像个十足的穷人（只要看看我的手机和鞋子就没有行窃的欲望），而且总是走在光天化日之下的主路上（万一遭遇危机，可以往车道上寻求帮助）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也希望可以告诉你，我在这样的步行过程中收获了无数的故事，但事实远非如此，故事依靠更有目的的访谈、研究以及观察。我钟爱赫尔佐格的《冰雪纪行》也是因为他的坦诚，他写下了漫步时的荒芜以及或许毫无意义的遇见：“晦暗寂寥的森林包围了我，周遭一片死寂，只有风声在呼啸。西边的天空泛黄，空气很闷，像是要下冰雹了，高处的天空则是朦胧的灰黑色。忽然，眼前出现一座巨大的红色采石场：巨坑中积蓄着红色的水，一台挖土机停在水中，遍身生锈毫无用处。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但也不能说我一无所获。我在不同地方碰到的乞讨者打招呼的方式是不同的，底特律的乞讨者会夸耀你的衣着，芝加哥的乞讨者则会先给你施行一项帮助（有人帮我把行李箱直接拎下地铁站），洛杉矶的乞讨者会跟你诉苦。经历有限，对这些地域的观察不一定准确，然而底特律的朋友也告诉我，当地人非常重视时尚，连乞丐也会常常夸赞衣着，我忽然感到自己走在了这座城的真实场域之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;追根究底，关于行走，每个人都有各自的理由。十九世纪的美国作家梭罗在新英格兰地区徒步是为了在星辰的高度呼吸这颗星球的空气，用双脚获取大地的知识。而赫尔佐格在漫步三周之久，抵达巴黎，洛特·艾斯纳竟然奇迹般地好转了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我则想起了儿时的一段往事。当时我可能才五六岁，父亲特别喜欢伏趴在床上，要我光着脚在他的脊背上乱踩，说这是世上最舒服的按摩。我听了也特别高兴，就很认真地在他的背上“行走”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这之后，我和父亲从未如此亲密过，我也和母亲一样，嫌弃他“不求上进”“不负责任”，甚至夏天还散发出汗臭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或许，冥冥之中，只有在街道上乱走才让我感到和脚下的城市亲密无间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都崇州被狗咬伤女童已出院，身体各系统恢复顺利]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260555]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 11:12:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月14日，记者从四川大学华西医院了解到，成都崇州被狗咬伤女童经医院积极救治，已于11月13日出院。&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;目前肝肾功能正常，身体各系统恢复顺利，伤口愈合情况良好&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;，后续需根据医嘱定期复查。住院期间，四川大学华西医院人工缴费窗口收到预交金共计22万元，使用8万余元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>