<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[他们眼中的吴尊友：“疫”线三载，抗“艾”一生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259691]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/31/7438acad8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 31/7438acad8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256289&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After being diagnosed with pancreatic cancer, Wu Zunyou’s work did not decrease significantly. Just because of chemotherapy and surgery, the office location was changed from the new site of the China Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Changping, Beijing, to the old office building near the Temple of Heaven. Jia Tianyong/China News Service/Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For most people, they know Wu Zunyou from his repeated appearances at the new coronavirus pneumonia epidemic press conference started. Some netizens even put together a group picture of his photogenic scenes - from 2020 to 2022, he gradually lost weight, &quot;like green silk in the morning and snow in the evening.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Many people have much whiter hair than me. I just feel my work experience through media publicity.&quot; At the beginning of 2023, on CCTV News In the interview, he responded, &quot;Many people have paid more than me. They are working on the front line, and some have paid with their lives, so my investment is really nothing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He did pay the price with his life. At 12:56 on October 27, 2023, the chief epidemiologist of the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention and former director of the Center for STD and AIDS Prevention and Control, who had long worked on the front line of public health, died of illness in Beijing at the age of 60. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is less known is that he was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer two years ago. &quot;When we learned that Teacher Wu was ill, the first thing he said was that he was too tired.&quot; In Guo Wei&#39;s impression, Wu Zunyou rested for less than four hours a day. &quot;We sent him an email at two o&#39;clock in the morning, and at four o&#39;clock I received a reply.&quot; Guo Wei was a student of Wu Zunyou. He later worked at the China Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and became colleagues with Wu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;People who know Wu Zunyou well recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that although Wu was not tall, he was very energetic and always had a slight smile on his lips when he spoke. He usually likes sports, and a pair of running shoes is a frequent item in his luggage. When he travels on business, he always gets up early for a morning run. He also loves badminton. Wu Chang jokes that his right arm is stronger than his left arm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the National Two Sessions in 2023, he also prepared a proposal on strengthening the training of public health talents as a member of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference: &quot;We must train more Experts in the field of public health...should have successors in the field of infectious disease prevention and control, so cultivating talents and having a strong team is very important for the future of China&#39;s public health.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Requirements for makeup &quot;Block the haggard face&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Wei discovered that the teacher had changed. In December 2021, Wu Zunyou was awarded the &quot;Most Beautiful Technology Worker&quot; &quot;——Wu Zunyou on TV is much thinner than before. &quot;I asked him how much you weigh now, and he said it&#39;s only eighty pounds.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the operation, Wu Zunyou recovered well at first. His weight gradually increased from 80 kilograms to 90 kilograms, and his physical strength slowly recovered. However, a review a few months later found that Cancer lesions also appeared in other organs. Pancreatic cancer is known as the &quot;king of cancers&quot;, with a five-year survival rate of less than one-tenth. Wu Zunyou, a medical student, knows very well what kind of disease pancreatic cancer is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of 2022, Guo Wei went to Wu Zunyou’s home to pick him up to record a video for World AIDS Day on December 1, and found that his “hair was all white, and his clothes were He&#39;s going to be a whole lot bigger.&quot; When putting on makeup, he specifically asked to &quot;block the haggard face.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;His voice is completely different from before. It has no power at all. During the filming of the video, it took a lot of effort to speak out. He told Guo Wei that he did not dare to take off his clothes casually because he was too weak and he might catch a cold quickly if he took off his clothes. He had to hide away from air conditioners and fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After being diagnosed with pancreatic cancer, his work did not decrease significantly. He only changed his office location from the new site of the China Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Changping, Beijing, due to chemotherapy and surgery. An old office building near the Temple of Heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The website of the China Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shows that on February 27, 2023, Wu Zunyou also attended a high-level expert seminar on the prevention and treatment of AIDS and hepatitis C. His last Weibo Stay at 21:22 on April 2, 2023, and advocate &quot;scientific wearing of masks&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Wei recalled that on May 28, 2023, Wu Zunyou and some relevant leaders and experts met at the Oriental Hotel in Beijing to discuss the methadone maintenance treatment plan. Later Guo Wei realized When I arrived, the Oriental Hotel was near the Friendship Hospital where Wu Zunyou was hospitalized and the old CDC office, making it convenient for him to rush from the hospital to meetings. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fighting AIDS under pressure&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If the epidemic made the public aware of Wu Zunyou, the public health system knew about Wu Zunyou from AIDS prevention and treatment began. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 1994, the plasma of a 41-year-old woman in Anhui was tested positive for HIV. However, she lived in a remote rural area with little contact with the outside world and denied it. There is a history of drug abuse, extramarital sexual relations, etc., which almost cuts off all channels of transmission. When he was at a loss, the Anhui Provincial Center for Disease Control and Prevention called Wu Zunyou, who was studying for a PhD in epidemiology at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Wu Zunyou&#39;s research, a new route of AIDS transmission has surfaced - this woman often sells plasma, and 40% of samples from the local plasma bank are HIV positive , and the equipment is not disinfected, leaving a lot of opportunities for infection. His discovery prevented many people from contracting AIDS through apheresis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Zunyou’s research direction as a mentor at UCLA is the prevention and treatment of AIDS. After returning to China after graduating with a Ph.D. in 1995, he joined the Chinese Academy of Preventive Medicine (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;now the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/span>;) and became the then academic director of the Academy of Preventive Medicine. He is a postdoctoral fellow of Zeng Yi, the president and academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, focusing on behavioral intervention for HIV/AIDS. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;As for the epidemiology of AIDS, many people in China are already doing it, and they are doing it very well. And the prevention of the spread of AIDS for high-risk groups is Almost no one cares about behavioral intervention work.&quot; Wu Zunyou later explained his choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, most of the people at high risk of AIDS were hidden special groups, such as blood sellers, sex workers, drug addicts, etc. Intervention services were provided for special groups. , reducing their risky behaviors was beyond the acceptance of the general public at the time. &quot;I also faced a certain amount of pressure to deal with this difficult bone.&quot; Wu Zunyou once said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On a trip to Yunnan to investigate the spread of AIDS among female sex workers, Wu Zunyou hoped that the local epidemic prevention stationmaster would take them to the &quot;red light district.&quot; Wu Zunyou and his party visited hair salons one by one. &quot;A &#39;lady&#39; from the hair salon slammed the door and left after learning our true purpose.&quot; Later, they found another one and talked for 45 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At a seminar held on the beach in Beihai, Guangxi, Wu Zunyou and the organizers of the meeting gave each of the AIDS prevention and control personnel in each province 50 yuan to spend money Talk to the sex worker on the beach. &quot;They found it incredible that the conference organizers actually wanted to push them into the arms of sex workers. China has never had such training.&quot; Wu Zunyou later recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, these surveys have become the basis for distributing free condoms, promoting the correct use of condoms, providing clinic consultation services, and formulating AIDS intervention methods that are consistent with national conditions. They have also been It has been incorporated into the AIDS Prevention and Control Regulations and the Five-Year Action Plan for AIDS Control as a national strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another contribution of Wu Zunyou is the promotion of methadone maintenance therapy among drug addicts to control the AIDS epidemic. &quot;During this period, the health department had to deal with a lot of work with the public security and judicial departments, including national plans, drug collection, policy revision, on-site pilots and experimental work, all carried out by him and a small number of people.&quot; Guo Wei recalled. As of the end of 2015, there were 785 methadone clinics operating across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This approach has been recognized by the United Nations Program on HIV/AIDS, which has promoted it globally as a model for AIDS prevention and treatment. In 2022, the World Health Organization awarded Wu Zunyou the Mandela Health Promotion Award. The award citation stated: &quot;He is a pioneer in designing, piloting and expanding service promotion programs among sex workers. He established China&#39;s first needle exchange project and the first large-scale opioid substitution treatment program.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /31/45bc2dbd3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/45bc2dbd3e.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256290&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 1, 2021, an AIDS prevention and treatment propaganda was posted at a bus station in Fengtai District, Beijing advertise. Today is the 34th &quot;World AIDS Day&quot;. Yi Haifei/China News Service/Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Respond to asking for help and face doubts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Those who have dealt with Wu Zunyou In my impression, he not only promotes AIDS prevention and treatment with an open and scientific attitude, but is also &quot;friendly and personally present&quot; and is very willing to listen to the opinions of community workers and patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2012, Wu Zunyou posted his first Weibo post. He often interacts with netizens and responds to requests for help and questions. On June 4, 2014, he said, &quot;Yesterday, a netizen in Fuzhou reported that the first month of AIDS treatment in Fuzhou requires self-pay. Today I arranged for colleagues to contact the local area.&quot; Faced with a netizen&#39;s criticism of AIDS prevention propaganda, he responded modestly: &quot;Your criticism is true. AIDS propaganda and education need to be strengthened and more targeted. Many people will say this, but almost no one knows how to do it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He and I met at a meeting, and he knew all about Beijing&#39;s AIDS organizations in advance.&quot; Kong Lingkun still remembers the scene when they met more than ten years ago. . Kong Lingkun is the chairman of the Beijing Charity Without Borders Charity Foundation and has been committed to eliminating discrimination and supporting AIDS patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Kong Lingkun’s recollection, in 2015, the Beijing Charity Without Borders Charity Foundation settled in the Fifth Medical Center of the People’s Liberation Army General Hospital and set up a charity clinic. Wu Zunyou even made a special trip to the center Visit social workers and patients, and pay attention to the testing work of key groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For disease control personnel, the better you do your job, the less you can see your results. In clinical terms, the more patients you treat, the less likely they are to see your results. The more we do, the greater the sense of accomplishment. But if you look at us (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;CDC staff&lt;/span>;), when we do a better job, the patients The fewer there are; the fewer patients you have, the less you will be seen by society and invisible (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;invisible&lt;/span>;).&quot; 2022 In 2016, Wu Zunyou said this in an interview with &quot;Chinese Philanthropist&quot; magazine&#39;s Person of the Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s hard to say what his greatest contribution is. As long as it talks about all aspects and every field of AIDS in China, he has left a mark.&quot; Now at the United Nations Guo Wei, a strategic information consultant at the UNAIDS Representative Office in China, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the COVID-19 epidemic, Wu Zunyou posted on Weibo more frequently and with more words. Southern Weekend reporters found that since 2022, he has posted 23 original Weibo posts, covering the new crown, monkeypox, influenza epidemics, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The increase in exposure has also led to more controversy. In January 2022, Omicron virus first appeared in China and spread locally. Wu Zunyou said that Omicron virus is &quot;taking all&quot; and the vaccine has a very limited effect in preventing Omicron virus. People can be infected regardless of whether they have been vaccinated or not. . His remarks brought him controversy. On January 30, he apologized on Weibo for &quot;not fully telling the truth&quot;, emphasizing that &quot;although there have been a certain number of breakthrough cases among vaccine recipients, many people have been prevented from getting infected.&quot; Eleven months later, on December 7, he revised his view on Weibo: &quot;The new crown vaccine has a certain effect in preventing infection, and its effect is more significant in reducing the incidence of severe illness and reducing deaths.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Faced with doubts, in an interview with CCTV News in March 2023, he said, &quot;As a professional, sometimes you have to have the courage or courage to make such a decision. , such research and judgment can inform the people of the correct information in a timely manner.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/5c6b301bff.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/5c6b301bff. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2012, Wu Zunyou posted his first Weibo post. Web page screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Rigorous enough to even change the reference format&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Being a student of Wu Zunyou, tiredness is a common feeling. Guo Wei recalled that during his Ph.D. study, he needed to “negate and then deny” all the time - Wu Zunyou asked his students that papers can only be accepted if the conclusion cannot be denied. “Everyone who works with him can feel that he is right.” The job is very demanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is related to Wu&#39;s study when he was young. While studying for a doctoral degree in epidemiology at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), his thesis strived to simplify the complex and find the most effective data in the complex data. He used the simplest method to draw clear conclusions. A conclusion that can withstand scrutiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of students, Wu is sometimes rigorous to the point of harshness. &quot;Every punctuation point in the documents we sent to Teacher Wu must be considered, and he would never allow flaws to appear.&quot; Guo Wei recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In her acknowledgments for her thesis, Wu Peili, a master&#39;s student at Anhui Medical University, described Wu Zunyou this way: &quot;He always keeps the students&#39; affairs in mind, and never fails to study. He will personally guide you through topic selection, topic development, on-site investigation, data analysis, and article revision, and he will even go as far as to help you change the format of your references.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;This rigor also extends to epidemic prevention and control. Starting in 2020, Wu Zunyou rushed to many places to conduct epidemic investigations. According to statistics from the State Council website, Southern Weekend reporters have attended 25 press conferences since 2020, the last one on February 9, 2023. Wu Zunyou is responsible for the joint prevention and control data team. After 12 o&#39;clock every night, the data from each province are reported and compiled into a report, which is then submitted to Wu Zunyou for review and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 2020, during the epidemic in Xinfadi, Beijing, Wu Zunyou led multiple teams to conduct on-site investigations, and Guo Wei also participated. &quot;Which batch of goods and where they are placed, he always finds clues through these particularly small contents. This is the accumulation of long-term epidemiology.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At that time, although Wu Zunyou&#39;s spirit was as good as before, the signs of the disease had begun to appear. He felt stomach pain and often had a bad appetite. It was not until February 2021 that I was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer. Southern Weekend reporters discovered that from January 11 to February 4, 2021, he also went to Suihua City, Heilongjiang Province to carry out work on the new coronavirus pneumonia epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, Wu Zunyou came to the office of the United Nations Program on AIDS in China and brought his book &quot;HIV/AIDS in China&quot; ：Beyond the Numbers》. The book concludes by writing that HIV has taught China many lessons over the past 30 years, but as long as it responds to HIV in a pragmatic and flexible manner, works together to limit the number of new infections and improve the well-being of AIDS patients, China will continue to be in a We are well positioned to face the next decade with confidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Part of the content refers to the following books:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; &quot;>;&quot;HIV/AIDS in China: Beyond the Numbers&quot; Wu Zunyou/Editor, People&#39;s Medical Publishing House&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&quot;China&#39;s road to fighting AIDS: Says from those who have experienced it&quot; 》Zhang Wenkang/Author, People&#39;s Medical Publishing House&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突中的文学家，是不是妇人之仁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259657]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/4DiV8CP08EvSVrGViGjFEJqtNSR6F4Ha5aSyjAJI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;905&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/4DiV8CP08EvSVrGViGjFEJqtNSR6F4Ha5 aSyjAJI. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Colen McCain and his novel &quot;The Promise&quot; (translated by Fang Berlin , People&#39;s Literature Publishing House, 2021). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Colen McCain&#39;s novel &quot;Apeirogon&quot; is set against the backdrop of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict . The narrative method of the story is novel, unique and groundbreaking, and the author had high hopes for it. The winner of the National Book Award in the United States was also invited to give lectures all over the world. However, due to the epidemic, all these conferences were cancelled, and the book did not become as popular as expected. The rights to adapt this book were bought by the great director Spielberg, but there has been no movement so far. I wonder if these directors buying the adaptation rights are like real estate developers buying land, hoping to increase the value of the film. Sometimes when the market is not going well, I will be choked to death by covering myself up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this time the renewed war between Palestine and Israel has drawn attention to this book again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of McCain&#39;s novels combine fiction and non-fiction, and the combination of fiction and reality is effective. Sometimes he uses a real historical time and person as the main line, and the beads on it are fictitious. Sometimes the beads are real and the main line is fictitious; sometimes the main line and the beads are real and the color of the beads is fictitious. He is sometimes real and sometimes weak, and he is just playing with a heartbeat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the novel &quot;The Promise&quot;, the Israeli girl Smadar is killed by a Palestinian terrorist suicide bomb. Abel, a Palestinian girl, was hit in the back of the head by a rubber bullet fired by an 18-year-old Israeli soldier. These two events were ten years apart and both are true. Abir&#39;s father, Bassam, was a Fatah fighter who spent many years in an Israeli prison for attacking Israel with grenades. Smadar&#39;s father, Rami, is an Israeli graphic designer. The two fathers, who had lost their daughters in different ways, eventually came together through the Circle of Lost Parents to tell stories, preach peace and dialogue, and use stories as a means of healing. The magical thing is that before and after the novel was published, the father of the two girls also did some online activities with the author. There are not many novels in which the characters step out of the picture and join hands with the author to preach. This style is a bit sci-fi when I think about it, a bit like &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/YcGiCfgg7wiF4Zpm2eMIjFzG4uFP1zv9blUnWyiD.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1035&quot; height= &quot;578&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/YcGiCfgg7wiF4Zpm2eMIjFzG4uFP1zv9blUnWyiD.png&quot; data-key=&quot;256196&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A critical article written by Naftali Moshe on the blog of The Times of Israel after the publication of The Promise. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the new round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out, both protagonists said that they were deeply shocked. The development of the situation is obviously contrary to their vision of pursuing peace. In the novel, McCain seems to be more sympathetic to Palestine and opposes Israel&#39;s bullying of Palestine. Naftali Moses, author of The Times of Israel, wrote that McCain ostensibly wrote about an Arab and an Israeli, but subtly expressed his dislike of Israel. The author labeled McCain an &quot;anti-Semite.&quot; He quickly attributed this anti-Semitic accusation to the &quot;Jewish original sin theory&quot;, that is, the Jews were the murderers of Jesus - this was Hitler&#39;s accusation against the Jews back then. But World War II has been over for many years. Except for the notorious Ku Klux Klan, few people dare to openly express their dissatisfaction with Israel and the United States’ Israeli policies. Otherwise, the anti-Semitic label will be firmly slapped on your head. This trend of public opinion is obviously very scary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Hamas launched brutal attacks and kidnappings, most of the world&#39;s public opinion condemned Hamas. However, gradually, when Israel shifted from &quot;legitimate defense&quot; to &quot;excessive defense&quot;, millions of Palestinians were When there was no way out, causing an unprecedented humanitarian disaster, public opinion quietly reversed. Protests broke out across the United States in response to Israel&#39;s counterattack against Palestine. Not to mention places like Northeastern Schools and California Berkeley where student activities are active, the atmosphere at the University of Texas, which has always been very hands-off and close to my home, is very tense: students sympathetic to Palestine are handing out leaflets to promote the &quot;genocide&quot; facing Gaza. &quot; and &quot;blockade&quot;, there was a fierce argument with other students, and later the situation became tense and the police were dispatched. Several student groups at Harvard University expressed dissatisfaction with Israel&#39;s actions and were doxxed by multiple employers with Jewish backgrounds, saying they were permanently banned from hiring. The &quot;anti-Semitic&quot; label is so scary, why does McCain still write about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict? Of course, writers have feelings. If you don’t have feelings, what kind of writer can you be? Naturally, they hope to turn swords into plowshares and solve problems with pen and ink instead of swords and guns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lami in the book once participated in the Middle East war, but later became a pacifist, especially after the death of his daughter. His wife was Netanyahu’s classmate. After his daughter died, Netanyahu wanted to visit, but she flatly refused. When reporters came for an interview, she said: &quot;The killings were not the bomb&#39;s fault. The bomb was also a victim. Israel is guilty. It has blood on its hands. She is not immune to this. Everyone is complicit. Oppression. Tyranny. . Arrogant.&quot; The Israeli Ministry of Defense sent a glass bowl to the couple, with the name of their dead daughter engraved on it. The couple did not give Netanyahu any face, and felt that this was not a &quot;sorrow&quot; but a &quot;honor&quot;. Hammered the bowl to pieces, &quot;wrote a note and sent it to Netanyahu: Dear Bibi (Editor&#39;s note: Netanyahu&#39;s nickname), something is broken.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And in Bassam, who was on the other side of the conversation, also got out of his past thinking. He tried his best to study in England and studied the history of the Jewish Holocaust. After that, he also became a pacifist. It is not easy to take this step. His daughter could have been saved after being hit in the head by a rubber bullet. Unfortunately, due to the queues and long wait at the sentry post on the way to the hospital, Abir missed the opportunity for rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/ZJxXmoLBeGvgQGleVy40XRCPVY1NvB4P4SuvZH5p.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;914&quot; height= &quot;514&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/ZJxXmoLBeGvgQGleVy40XRCPVY1NvB4P4SuvZH5p.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256195&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the American TV series &quot;Billions&quot;, the actor and financial tycoon Bobby Axelrod is shown eating a banquet dinner. It is customary to cover your head with a towel. Some people say that this can ensure that the aroma does not escape. Others say that it is because the scene of spitting out bones is indecent, so it is necessary to cover up. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli-Palestinian conflict has accumulated thousands of years of retribution and is an endless cycle of oppression, resistance, and counterattack. . McCain cannot be said to be partial to Palestine. He was also wondering what was going on in this place. He has an overall reflection on human cruelty, which is not only cruel to each other, but also to the natural world. The book writes about the feast of buntings that Mitterrand ate before his death: &quot;The little birds will be fed for two weeks until they are about to burst. Then the chef picks up their feet and immerses them in a large vat of pure water. Boiled with Armagnac, soaked from scratch and left to drown. Next, the chef dehairs them, sprinkles them with salt and pepper and cooks them in their own fat for seven minutes before tossing them in just In the heated white stew pot.&quot; Finally, Mitterrand covered his head with a scarf and chewed the bird until the bones made a crisp sound. After reading this description, do you still have such high regard for &quot;French cuisine&quot;? Why write about Mitterrand eating birds? Later in the book, he writes: &quot;During François Mitterrand&#39;s tenure, France sold thousands of Milan missiles to Syria. They then entered the black market and were bought by Hezbollah guerrillas. .&quot; This kind of cruelty to birds is easily transferred to humans. After all, there is a terrible darkness in human beings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Birds are constantly written about in the book. &quot;Hoopoe, thrush, flycatcher, warbler, cuckoo, myna, warbler, shrike, sandpiper, boreal, plover, sunbird, swift, sparrow, nightjar, owl, gull, hawk, eagle , kite, crane, vulture, sandpiper, pelican, flamingo, stork, white-spotted blackbird, Eurasian vulture, blue-breasted Buddha, &lt;span>;Arabian thrush&lt;/span>;, bee-eater, turtle dove, white-throated, Yellow Wagtail, Black-capped Warbler, Red-throated Pipit, Lesser Reed Pipit.&quot; Why? Birds can migrate and are free. Israel and Palestine, on the other hand, are intertwined and difficult to access. “Area A is patrolled by multiple Palestinian security forces, but Israeli troops can march in at any time. Area B is under Palestinian civil jurisdiction, and Israel controls its security with the cooperation of the Palestinian security authority police. Palestinian security forces can only operate with Israel’s permission. … In addition, the H1 and H2 districts of the West Bank city of Hebron, 80% administered by the Palestinian Authority and 20% controlled by Israel, include so-called sterile streets open only to Israelis and those holding international passports .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the map, this area is so intricate that it looks like an improperly used, overly fragmented hard drive. The large and small sentry posts and high walls have turned the Gaza Strip into an open-air prison. It&#39;s also like being blocked all year round, with soldiers armed with live ammunition always blocking intersections, making it difficult to go out and look for opportunities to make a living. This kind of &quot;you in me&quot;, &quot;I in you&quot; situation, even if mother-in-law, daughter-in-law and brother are usually together, they can&#39;t deal with each other, not to mention the constant new and old hatreds between the two parties? The Israelis are still bulldozing their homes, shooting into their water tanks, and breaking the bones of children who throw stones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s social public opinion is very black and white. Many relatives and friends have conflicts because of whether they support Israel or Pakistan. In fact, have you ever considered that these divisions have entangled the two sides? Dividing it into so many areas, setting up sentries, and adopting different management methods seems very smart, but the human brain cannot handle such complexity. In the past, two sects were at loggerheads in India, but things got better after the partition of India and Pakistan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I admire McCain&#39;s moral courage, the courage to write about such a complex subject, and the courage to face the most difficult conflicts of mankind. Cangjie created characters, and ghosts and gods cried at night. There are a lot of troubles caused by words: Rushdie was sentenced to death in Iran and was recently stabbed blind in one eye. If you write about the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, you will easily be labeled as anti-Semitic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On such a complex issue as the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, there are now countless discussions from macro perspectives such as politics, religion, and geography. But don’t forget that for the Israelis and Palestinians involved, this is not just a national matter, but a family matter and a matter around us. The conflict is concrete rather than abstract, a man&#39;s child was killed by a bomb, a man&#39;s child was beaten to death by a guard. Such individual matters and family matters are so entangled and involve other backgrounds of history, culture, and war that it is difficult to write in one line and two lines. McCain then wrote 1,001 long and short chapters, just like &quot;One Thousand and One Nights&quot;, like a diary and a puzzle, making different themes and multiple narratives echo and set off each other. It seems to be a show of skill, but in fact it is a last resort to provide a literary treatment of this complicated situation. Writing this way also allows us readers to deeply understand the complexity of the Palestinian-Israeli issue from multiple dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But novels often describe problems. Where are the answers? McCain repeatedly mentioned the term &quot;extreme empathy&quot; and hoped that both parties in the conflict would understand each other&#39;s thoughts and stories. He believes that dialogue can solve problems. At the beginning of the novel, there is a sticker on the left front of the motorcycle that the Israeli Rami rides, which reads: &quot;If we don&#39;t start a dialogue, this will not end.&quot; So these two suffering fathers join hands to travel to various places to preach peace with sincerity. So can the kind of dialogue advocated by McCain really solve the problem, or is it just the wishful thinking of a litterateur and the benevolence of a woman? I don&#39;t know where the answer lies. What do you think? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[随国，从编钟出发]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Big Tomb&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Soft light spreads over, falling in men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man&#39;s face was slightly raised, and under his thick black eyebrows, his small eyes were deep and lively. The bridge of the nose is straight, the lips are pressed tightly, with a faint smile. The man&#39;s expression was three parts confident, three parts complacent, and four parts complacent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man stands in a corner of the Suizhou Museum, a bronze statue. The text under the statue states that it was reconstructed based on the skull of the tomb owner by the Institute of Vertebrate Paleontology and Ancient Anthropology, Chinese Academy of Sciences. In other words, it is highly similar to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The remains of the tomb owner have been sleeping on a small hill only a few hundred meters away from the Suizhou Museum since they were buried in the loess more than 2,000 years ago. I walked out of the museum and walked for 5 minutes along a quiet road behind the museum. I turned a corner in front of a unit called Ouyang Xiu Kindergarten, crossed a stone bridge, and entered the Leigudun Archaeological Site Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The green forest directly in front of the park is the lush city that men have dreamed of for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man’s name is Ji Yi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Ji Yi&#39;s name is not well known, then his other title is famous: Zeng Hou Yi. Zeng Hou is the king of Zeng State. Yi is his name. As for why it was asserted that his surname was Ji, there was a tortuous process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/Z6uN2lbCzmre7fP9VjTeOY6HJKemMDswziE55oxF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;619&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/Z6uN2lbCzmre7fP9VjTeOY6HJKemMDswziE55oxF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Statue of Zeng Houyi in Suizhou Museum&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Zuoping/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, beating drums A huge park has been built at the Dun site. According to the scenic spot information, its &quot;protection scope and construction control zone reaches 12 square kilometers.&quot; Around the park and outside the Suizhou Museum, there are also some residential buildings scattered here and there. However, judging from old photos, more than 40 years ago in the 1970s, there were still lush rice fields here. In the middle of the crop fields, there stood two isolated houses, which belonged to a radar repair station of the Air Force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, archaeological discoveries are like a saying: When a mouse pulls a shovel, the big head is behind. For example, the Terracotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shihuang and the Leigudun ruins were discovered due to the expansion of the radar repair shop&#39;s workshop. During the construction process, the workers discovered that there was some white plaster mud and a piece of artificially paved stone slab under the loess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said with certainty that although archaeologists have confirmed that there is a large ancient tomb under the wilderness, they were still deeply shocked when the details of the ancient tomb were revealed. I found an aerial panorama taken during the excavation. In the black and white photo, a large pit was dug out of the gray earth, showing that the tomb entrance was composed of three rectangles. Comparing the crowds around the pit as dense as ants, you can see how big and deep the entrance to the tomb is. Tan Weisi, the head of the archaeological team at that time, recalled, &quot;The entrance to the tomb is in the shape of an irregular polygon, with the widest point from east to west being 21 meters, and the widest point from north to south being 16.5 square meters, with a total area of ​​more than 200 square meters.&quot; As for the coffin that gradually revealed the true face of Lushan Mountain in the pit, It is 6 times larger than the Mawangdui Tomb and 8 times larger than the Wangshan No. 1 Chu Tomb where the sword of Yue King Goujian was unearthed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a conspicuous place in the exhibition hall of Hubei Provincial Museum, on the thick red carpet, two copper-wood structure brackets, one long and one short, are arranged in an L shape. One of them is more than 7 meters long, and the other is 3 meters long. Many, the height is more than 2.5 meters. On the top of the bracket, there are 64 chimes hanging in 8 groups on 3 levels. The total weight of the bronze chimes weighs 5,000 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This set of chimes, which can be called the treasure of the town hall, comes from Leigudun. Its owner is none other than Zeng Houyi. According to custom, it is named Zenghou Yi Chime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the shape, chime bells are divided into button bells, Yong bells and tungsten bells.镈钟最大，置于下层，其音浑厚辽远；甬钟次之，置于中层，其音圆润优美；钮钟最小，置于上层，其音清亮悠扬。令人称奇的是，每一口钟，都能敲出两个不同的音，称为双音钟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自1978年重见天日以来，几十年间，曾侯乙编钟曾经三次敲响。一次是出土当年，当地驻军礼堂里，编钟首次敲响，当代的耳朵有幸聆听穿越两千年时光而来的先秦雅乐。一次是1979年国庆，编钟被运往北京演奏。一次是1997年为迎接香港回归，编钟在湖北省博敲响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/MND1ZV7ty87AJFnQDS3S5uumhlpMKKangDVsfoZQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/MND1ZV7ty87AJFnQDS3S5uumhlpMKKangDVsfoZQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;湖北省博物馆镇馆之宝——曾侯乙编钟&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与本身的艺术价值和文物价值相比，编钟上的铭文或许更为珍贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;先秦时期的坟墓，不像后世那样有墓碑和墓志。要确定墓主为谁，只能依靠陪葬器物上的铭文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;擂鼓墩遗址出土的诸多文物，包括戈、殳等武器，以及青铜盘、豆等日用器物，都有“曾侯乙”三字出现。其中一件镈钟，上面有31字铭文，它不仅证明了该墓墓主为曾侯乙，还为曾侯乙生活的大体时代提供了坐标。这31个字乃是：隹王五十又六祀，返自西阳，楚王熊章，作曾侯乙宗彝，奠之于西阳，其永持用享。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大意是，楚王熊章五十六年，得知曾侯乙去世，特意制作了这套宗彝，送到西阳去祭奠他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熊章即楚惠王，是楚国惟一在位超过56年的君主。楚惠王56年，即公元前433年。另据棺木中的遗骨测定，墓主死时约42岁到45岁。以此推之，则曾侯乙生于前475年到前478年间。倘若生于前475的话，那一年，正是战国的开端。曾侯乙的一生，大体就是战国初期的将近半个世纪——其时，诸侯间虽然征战不断，但还不像战国中后期那样兼并剧烈，“率土地而食人肉”。作为一个小国之君，他在人间度过了安稳且幸福的一生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当考古工作者打开厚重的主棺时，他们看到了散落的骨架和众多精美的陪葬品。是的，两千多年后，曾侯乙的肉身已经腐烂，只有陪葬品留了下来。这些陪葬品，大多为玉器。古人认为，把玉器塞入死者的耳、鼻、口以及肛门，死者就能永恒，所谓“金玉在九窍，则死者为之不朽”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，所有渴望永恒的企图与努力，注定都是镜花水月。不仅尸首要腐朽，名字和事迹也要被遗忘。绝大多数人在这颗蓝色星球上生存过的痕迹，都将被忘川之水涤荡得无影无踪，就像从不曾来过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/gNZDmcannHVo1VFFjEPalgPWQHvMAiBi5j4GuD7o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/gNZDmcannHVo1VFFjEPalgPWQHvMAiBi5j4GuD7o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;擂鼓墩遗址一角&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（聂作平/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;青铜&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;曾侯乙墓的横空出世，让一个长久以来悬而未决的问题再次浮出水面：根据曾侯乙墓及之前的考古发现证实，在今天的随州一带，曾经存在过一个叫曾的国家。离奇的是，历史文献里，却找不到关于曾国的只言片语。尤其诡异的是，史料表明，同一时间段，该地区还存在过一个叫“随”的国家，而与有关“随”的文物，此前却从未发现。那么，曾与随到底是什么关系？有人认为，曾吞随；有人认为，随代曾；有人认为，楚灭随，在随地另建曾；还有人认为，曾随就是同一个国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，也就是曾侯乙墓被发掘35年后，在距曾侯乙墓只有四、五公里的文峰塔，发现了另一处春秋时期的墓群。墓群的坟墓多达50余座，出土文物上千件，其中青铜器占一半以上，且大多数都有铭文。铭文中的曾、曾子、曾公子、曾孙、曾大司马等字样表明，它是一处曾国高等级贵族公墓。编号为M21的坟墓，除了出土一批带有曾字铭文的青铜器外，更引人注目的是一件铜戈，铜戈上的铭文为：随大司马献有之行戈。这是多年来出土的第一件随国文物。并且，随国文物出现在曾国贵族墓中，为曾随一体提供了重要证据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最直接，或者说最具决定性意义的证据来自文峰塔墓群编号为M1的坟墓。该墓出土了一件编钟，编钟上的铭文，记载的是前506年的吴楚之战。楚国战败后，在曾国的帮助下复国。铭文将涉事的三方称为吴、楚、曾。 《左传》在记载此事时，将涉事的三方称为吴、楚、随。由此可见，曾与随就是同一个国家的不同称谓。 ——一个国家而有两个名字，先秦时并不少见，如魏因都于大梁而又称梁，韩因都于新郑而又称郑，州因都于淳于而又称淳于。具体到曾，它可能因都于随而又称随。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于曾国，或者说随国的源流，也在文峰塔墓群获得了答案——M1号墓地出土的两件编钟，其铭文，一件说，“曾侯與曰，&#39;余稷之后也&#39;”，稷即后稷，也就是周人始祖。这说明，曾国国君源自姬姓，是周王室后裔，所以，曾侯乙名姬乙。另一件记录得更为翔实，经专家释读为：“唯王正月吉日甲午，曾侯與曰：伯适上庸，佐佑文武，达殷之命，抚定天下，王遣命南公，营宅汭土，君比淮夷，临有江夏。”大意为，伯适上庸辅佐周文王和周武王，推翻殷商，平定天下。及后，周武王将他封到南方营建城池，建立国家，负责监视淮夷，防卫江夏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伯适上庸是谁呢？伯适，又作伯括，即南宫括。庸通容，上庸即上容，是南宫的名，伯适是他的字。史料记载，南宫适随武王伐纣后，武王曾命他拆掉纣王的鹿台，并开仓放粮，赈济百姓。按铭文所说，周初大分封时，作为功臣，南宫适被封到南方，也就是今天的随枣一带，建立曾国。曾国的职责是为防备东南边的淮夷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓淮夷，本是东夷的一支，商周时，生活在江淮地区并建有一批国家，如蓼、六、舒、舒庸和舒鸠等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;追根溯源，淮夷与商人有着亲近的血源关系，而周人是商朝的终结者。因此，为了防备淮夷，经营南方，周天子在今天的河南、湖北和安徽一带，分封了多个诸侯，这些诸侯大体地处汉水以北，称为汉阳诸姬，包括唐、应、息、鄂、邓、蒋、蔡、沈、随等国。这中间，随是首屈一指的大国，所谓“汉东诸侯，随为大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/SlSta4V8DgSE6wHmaQ4pe6eNraYMf1lg34RJxea5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/SlSta4V8DgSE6wHmaQ4pe6eNraYMf1lg34RJxea5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;湖北省博物馆曾侯乙铜建鼓座&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;淮夷的叛乱渐渐消弭后，汉阳诸姬的任务转为防备日益崛起的楚国，同时维护一条重要运输线的畅通。这条运输线就是铜锡之路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;先秦乃是青铜时代，青铜既是铸造兵器的原料，也是铸造礼器的原料。在“国之大事，在祀与戎”的背景下，青铜可以说是一个国家立国的根本。但是，定都关中的周天子直辖区域并不产铜，所需的大量铜料，只能由南方千里迢迢地输送——湖北大冶，以及距它只有100多公里的江西瑞昌，都有蕴量极为丰富的巨型铜矿。它们的开采，从2000多年前开始，一直持续到当代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方的铜要运到关中，路程超过1000公里。漫长的运输线，意味着更多的风险和更多的不确定性。以随国为首的汉阳诸姬，他们肩负的重任就是保障铜锡之路的畅通，保证采自南方的金属顺利抵达镐京。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国国家博物馆里，珍藏着一件名为曾伯簠的青铜器。簠，是祭祀或宴会时用来盛饭的器具，与簋并称，方的叫簠，圆的叫簋。曾伯簠即曾国国君所用，上面的铭文，有这么几句：“……克狄淮夷，抑燮繁汤，金道锡行，具既俾方。”意思是：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（曾伯）&lt;/span>;惩治淮夷，安定了交通枢纽繁汤，铜锡通道，都已恢复正常。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近水楼台先得月，既是汉阳诸姬的老大，又控制着铜锡之路上最重要的随枣走廊，随国比其它诸侯更容易获得大量的铜。从某种意义上讲，随这个小国——虽然汉阳诸姬中它最大，但与真正的大国相比，仍是小国——才是真正的青铜王国。曾侯乙墓出土的各种青铜器，计6239件，合在一起，总重量达10498.6公斤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/LNiEDBxEMDwAkGBduZHlMHEcVKecAt4EeE4WezfR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/LNiEDBxEMDwAkGBduZHlMHEcVKecAt4EeE4WezfR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;湖北省博物馆曾侯乙青铜尊盘局部&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在周朝，周公制礼作乐的大背景下，青铜器不仅具有实用功能，更具备精神价值，并与礼乐制度水乳交融。它是正音雅乐的乐器，是藏礼于器的礼器，是交通人神的法器。周公敬德保民的思想，通过物化的青铜器代代相承。发达的青铜文化，应该对随国产生了深远影响——可惜，由于史料阙如，我们无法获悉更多的细节。从关于随国的不多的记载来看，一个叫季梁的宗室，堪为代表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前706年，楚武王攻随，故意示弱，随国少师中计，请随侯倾力迎战。季梁提醒随侯，强大的楚国突然变弱，此乃“诱我也，君何急焉？”他进一步向随侯进谏，进谏内容，充分体现了季梁以人为本的思想。他说，小国要与大国对抗，在于有道；“所谓道，忠于民而信于神也。上思利民，忠也；祝史正辞，信也。”——有道，就是执政者要忠于民众，取信于神灵。君主时时想到如何有利于民众，这就是忠；代表君主祭祀的史官实事求是，这就是信。随侯不服，他称自己在祭祀神灵时，一直选用肥大且无杂色的牺牲，作祭品的黍稷也丰盛完备，对神灵足够有信了。季梁却告诉他，“夫民，神之主也。是以圣王先成民而后致力于神”——民众才是神灵的根本，所以历代圣明之君都是先团结民众，尔后才致力于祭神。季梁断言，随侯自以为给神献祭的牺牲肥大无杂色，黍稷丰盛完备，其实根本没用，不会获得神灵保佑。只有“务其三时，修其五教，亲其九族”——务其三时，指让民众专心进行春、夏、秋三季农事；修其五教，指倡导父义、母慈、兄友、弟恭、子孝的社会风气；亲其九族，指敦睦亲族之间关系，使其融洽——用这些行为来祭祀神灵，神灵才会降福，社会才会和谐，国家才会强大。所以，季梁毫不客气地要求随侯“君姑修政而亲兄弟之国，庶免于难。”——您如果修明政事，亲近兄弟国家，或许可以幸免于难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;季梁这番话，听得随侯心惊肉跳，不得不采纳了建议。楚国听说后，只得暂时放弃了侵随计划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随侯虽听从了季梁的劝谏，但他最宠信的其实还是那个没留下姓名的少师。当季梁渐渐失宠于随侯，楚国又看到了希望。楚武王第二次亲率大军，兵临楚随边境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楚强随弱，季梁建议与楚国议和。他说，如果楚国不愿议和，那将激怒我国将士而使敌军懈怠。少师却不愿议和。他认为，必须迅速出击才能彰显随国的强大。战前，季梁提醒随侯，楚人风俗以左为尊，左军一定是楚王所在的精锐。交战时，我们先攻打薄弱的楚国右军，右军一败，楚军就会崩溃。少师反对说，不与楚王正面交战，那等于说我们不敢和他硬杠，有损随国威严。于是，随侯下令攻打楚军左军。结果，随军大败，随侯逃走，随侯的战车也被楚军缴获。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ZPHmYjSkKJEzurgoS5Z1pmscMF07q5xTap5K3uEg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ZPHmYjSkKJEzurgoS5Z1pmscMF07q5xTap5K3uEg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;随州文化公园季梁雕像&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;附庸&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;曾侯乙墓出土了一批竹简，计240枚，有文字近7千。经专家释读，竹简是一份陪葬曾侯乙入土的车马兵甲清单。清单表明，曾侯乙死后，赠送车马的有楚王、楚太子、楚令尹，以及楚国的几位封君，如鲁阳公、阳城公、平夜君。总之，差不多所有楚国大人物，都对曾侯乙的死表示哀悼，并赠送车马或其它礼物。这分清单中随国人对楚王的称呼证实，此时的随国，已沦为楚国附庸——惟其如此，楚国君臣才对曾侯乙如此亲近，礼遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楚国崛起后，一直试图向东发展。向东发展有三个目标，第一个目标是占领宜于农耕的江汉平原；第二个目标是夺取大冶的铜矿；第三个目标是控制随枣走廊以及南襄隘道，进而北上争霸。当然，三个目标是循序渐进的，只有实现第一个目标才可能实现第二个目标以及第三个目标。而无论要实现哪一个目标，楚国必须做到的就是打败它的东邻随国。随国不仅肩负着周天子让它监视和防备楚国的任务，并且，地理位置十分重要，“北接黾厄，东蔽汉沔，介襄、郢、申、安之内，实为要地，义阳、南阳之锁钥，实为用之”。可以说，从楚国崛起的那一天起，楚国与随国之间就注定了你死我活的战争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;800年楚国历史上，楚武王熊通是一个铁腕人物，他踩着血泊中的侄儿的尸体，以弑君的方式登基为君。半个多世纪里，楚武王着意向东、向北发展。汉阳诸姬中的老大随国，是楚武王必欲灭之而后快的头号敌人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十多年间，楚武王三次伐随。前706年，随侯听从季梁进谏，楚军无功而返；前704年，随侯听从少师之言，随军大败；前690年，年过七旬的楚武王病死于伐随征途。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楚武王虽未能如愿将随国吞并，但大大削弱了随国力量，先后灭掉了权国、州国、蓼国、卢国和鄢国，几乎全部占有了肥沃的江汉平原，并将铜绿山控制在手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;50年后，楚武王的孙子楚成王，接连吞并了贰、谷、黄、英、蒋、房等十来个小国，进而实现了祖父多年的梦想——把随国变成楚国的附庸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前640年，随国联合汉水以东的一批小国，联合兴兵反楚。楚国令尹斗谷于菟率军进击，随国及联军大败，被迫与楚国订立城下之盟，从此沦为楚国附庸。此时，已是周惠王二十五年，原本强盛的西周早在100多年前就不得不迁都洛阳，周天子实力大减，至多相当于一个中等诸侯，对包括随国在内的汉阳诸姬，周天子早已自顾不暇。自此以后，随国“世服于楚，不通中国”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;附庸楚国后的随国，尽管疆域缩减，但与楚国之间的战争几乎绝迹，在大批诸侯亡国绝祀的吞并浪潮中，随国得以幸存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/uFxHxiBjqtNLcxgtCb5LCVA9YjrAYrvYBz4iwOQ3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/uFxHxiBjqtNLcxgtCb5LCVA9YjrAYrvYBz4iwOQ3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;随州位于江汉平原中部。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历史的戏剧性在于，无论对楚国还是对随国来说，两国君主及臣民都不曾想到的是，有一天，作为附庸的随国，居然将是宗主国楚国最后的拯救者——如果没有随国，楚国很可能在春秋末年就灭亡了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前506年，吴楚大战爆发。吴王阖闾亲率大军，溯淮河而上，在今河南潢川一带舍舟登陆，通过蔡国和唐国军队接引，吴军由楚国北方南下，直趋汉水。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴国本在楚国东部，楚国的防守重心一直在豫章，也就是今江西南昌一带。没想到吴军却避其主力，击其薄弱，打了楚军一个措手不及。吴楚两军在柏举&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今湖北麻城，另说湖北汉川）&lt;/span>;交战。吴军五战五捷，楚军大败。十天后，吴军攻占楚国首都郢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个春秋时期，吴军克郢是第一例也是惟一一例攻占大国首都的战事。消息传出，诸侯震惊，不由得对原本被视为蛮夷的吴国刮目相看。吴国之所以创造这样的奇迹，其主要功劳，应归功于伍子胥和孙武。正如《汉书》所说：阖闾举伍子胥、孙武为将，战胜攻取，兴霸名于诸侯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楚都被吴军攻占后，楚昭王逃到随国。此时，这个汉阳诸姬中几乎硕果仅存的蕞尔小国，成为楚国存亡续绝的最后希望。吴国派使者到随国，希望随侯交出楚昭王，并提醒随侯说，“周之子孙在汉川者，楚实尽之”——你们汉阳诸姬，都快被楚国吞并完了。现在，老天要惩罚楚国，你为什么把楚王藏起来？如果交出他的话，汉阳的土地，就归随国所有。对此，随侯拒绝了。他表示，随国与楚国世代有盟誓，他不能交出楚王。吴国大军深入，后方不稳，不愿再与随国交战，只好撤退。以后，才有了申包胥哭秦庭乞得秦师，楚昭王得以中兴的下文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鉴于随国对楚昭王的保护，楚昭王复国后，楚随关系开启了前所未有的蜜月期。原本，沦为楚国附庸后，尽管随国是周天子当初分封的诸侯，但已经“为楚私属，不通于诸侯，征伐盟会，不齿于列”。出于对随侯的感激，“楚人感其德，使随列于诸侯”。就是说，随国虽然仍是楚国附庸，但楚国让它像诸侯一样参与国际活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;襄阳博物馆珍藏的两件春秋时期的媵器，就是楚、随友好的见证。先秦时期，王公贵族嫁女，一般都会制作青铜器作为陪嫁，称为媵器。襄阳博物馆这两件媵器，一件称为曾侯作季汤芈鼎，一件称为曾孟芈谏铜盆。两件媵器上的铭文表明，一个叫羋汤和一个叫羋谏的楚国女子，先后嫁到随国。羋姓系楚国国君姓氏，为荆楚十八姓之祖，曾因电视据《羋月传》广为人知。所以说，楚随关系史上，有过一段相互通婚的秦晋之好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楚昭王奔随63年后，随国国君曾侯乙去世了。此时，楚国君主乃楚昭王的儿子楚惠王。同样出于对当年随国义举的感激，楚惠王特意制作了礼器来祭奠。追悼曾侯乙的，除了楚惠王，还有一大帮楚国王公重臣。原本默默无闻的小国之君，因祖先的一次政治站队，从而出人意料地得享哀荣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/D58Kf2X0gt938eSSt2wEeryVCtZ4tdS5SO6aAcuY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/D58Kf2X0gt938eSSt2wEeryVCtZ4tdS5SO6aAcuY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256127&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;夜空下的编钟，一个小国之君在机缘巧合下无意中留下的永恒。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时光是感情的敌人。如果说感情是酒的话，那么，时光就是不断往酒里渗入的水。时光愈久，渗入酒中的水越多，酒味就越淡，乃至于最后只有水的寡淡而无酒的甘醇。人与人的感情如此，国与国的感情亦如此。尤其在利益面前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;假如曾侯乙和楚惠王九泉下有知的话，他们一定会为子孙后代的选择感到遗憾：对楚国有再造之恩的随国，最终，还是被楚国吞并了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楚国何时灭随，史料无载，只能通过出土文物间接推断。在曾侯乙墓南侧数百米处，1983年，考古工作者发掘了30余座墓葬，这些墓葬被命名为随州擂鼓墩二号墓。考古工作者的结论是，墓中出土的器物，“不仅具有浓郁的曾文化特征，还有典型的楚文化因素”。因此，推断为“曾国即将灭亡或已被楚国灭亡后之曾人墓葬。”这些墓葬的时代，大致在战国早期偏晚至战国中期偏早，由是而言，随国的灭亡当在战国中期。这一点，也能从文献中找到佐证。如春申君在前272年劝秦国不要攻打楚国时，提到了“随水右壤”乃楚国领土。随水即广水，随水右壤即广水以西，即当年随国辖地。就是说，至迟在前272年，随国已并入楚国。此时，距曾侯乙与楚惠王的楚随蜜月期，已然远去一个半世纪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/TIe7DGLaYio4GfVpDTfq4zKoVn9Jexr648fKGk1g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/TIe7DGLaYio4GfVpDTfq4zKoVn9Jexr648fKGk1g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;随州广水丘陵地貌&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;漫长的随国历史，除了季梁等极少数人外，大多数王公贵族乃至君主都面目模糊，哪怕是因编钟而闻名的曾侯乙，后人对他的生平也知之甚少。考察擂鼓墩曾侯乙墓，最让我感慨的，既不是编钟，也不是玉器，而是21位永远不可能知道名字的年轻女子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在曾侯乙长眠的主棺周遭，有8具从棺。棺内，各有人骨架一具，均为19到26岁的女子。她们可能是曾侯乙的嫔妃或近侍。在主室附近的西室，另有13具从棺，棺内，也各有人骨架一具，系13岁到24岁的女子。同为殉葬品，却有不同的身份和称谓。前者称为人殉，人殉多是死者的妻妾和近侍，身份较高，人牲则是战俘或奴隶。人殉埋在死者墓中，身体完整，葬具较精，是为了让她们到另一个世界继续为死者服务。人牲则埋在专用的祭祀坑中，身体大多不完整，葬具粗糙，是为了将她们献祭给天地神灵和祖先。人殉中固然有被迫从死的，但也不乏自愿陪葬者；至于人牲，几乎可以断言，没有任何一个出于自愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个已经沦为附庸的小国之君，死后仍然要以21条年轻鲜活的生命作为陪葬，在编钟和玉器的灿烂辉煌之外，我依稀看到了那个远逝时代的血腥，蒙昧和野蛮。此种背景下，季梁“夫民，神之主也”的说法，尽管很难被君主们真正付诸实践，但仍然如同暗夜里闪烁于远方的萤火那样，微弱，却弥足珍贵。因了这萤火，冰凉的历史也才有了一丁点人性的温暖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;【主要参考书目：《左传》《读史方舆纪要》《湖北随县曾侯乙墓发掘简报》《随州志》《曾侯乙墓》《随州文化探源》《曾国与随国历史研究》《楚国灭国考》】&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[微信抖音等多家平台将引导“自媒体”账号对外实名丨滚动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 18:39:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年10月31日18:00&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;微信关于头部“自媒体”账号对外展示实名信息的公告&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为维护良好网络传播秩序，推动健康、有序的网络空间建设，增强头部“自媒体”账号可信度，便于公众为公共利益实施监督，微信将分批次分阶段引导“粉丝”量50万以上的“自媒体”账号对外展示实名信息，近期将首先引导100万“粉丝”以上的“自媒体”账号对外展示实名信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据微信公众号、视频号“粉丝”情况，平台100万“粉丝”以上的“自媒体”账号在用户确认同意展示后，账号注册主体为个人类型的将显示注册人真实姓名，机构类账号显示企业、机构名称，相关实名信息可在账号资料页进行查看。平台鼓励“自媒体”创作者真实表达，为用户提供更优质、可信赖的内容，未对外展示实名信息的100万“粉丝”以上“自媒体”账号，账号流量、收益等将受到限制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平台将持续优化产品功能，打造绿色健康的内容生态，为“自媒体”创作者提供更好的发展空间，也欢迎广大网友监督及建议，共同营造清朗的网络空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（微信珊瑚安全公众号）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年10月31日18:00&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;抖音关于“账号实名信息展示”的公告&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;2&quot;>;为增强“自媒体”账号可信度，保障用户的合法权益，维护清朗、健康的平台秩序，粉丝数量达到50万且发布涉及时政、社会、金融、教育、医疗卫生、司法等内容的“自媒体”账号需授权平台在账号主页展示通过认证的实名信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;3&quot;>;具体方式如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li data-track=&quot;4&quot;>;符合实名信息展示条件的“自媒体”账号将收到站内信通知，可以根据提示进行授权操作。实名信息应为账号认证的真实姓名或企业名称，应与提交的身份证件、营业执照等信息一致。&lt;/li>; &lt;li data-track=&quot;5&quot;>;平台获得授权后将在账号主页展示通过认证的实名信息。&lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;7&quot;>;需要授权展示账号实名信息的用户会收到站内信通知，授权展示具体上线时间以实际通知为准。若账号收到通知但未进行认证或授权，会对账号内容传播、商业收益等方面产生影响，直至完成认证及授权展示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot; data-track=&quot;25&quot;>;（抖音安全中心）&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;25&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年10月31日18:18&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;25&quot;>;&lt;strong>;微博发布关于“自媒体”账号实名信息展示的公告&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为营造安全、文明、和谐的网络生态环境，增强平台头部“自媒体”账号的可信度及权威性，站方将于近期引导头部“自媒体”账号进行前台实名展示，以此进一步规范“自媒体”账号运营管理，更便于公众为社会公共利益实施监督。具体说明如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. 站方将于近期引导社会时事、军事、财经、法律、医疗等专业领域100万粉丝以上的“自媒体”账号填写实名信息，后续将逐步扩大到相关领域50万粉丝以上的“自媒体”账号，经用户同意后进行前台实名展示。&lt;br>;2. 普通用户及以个人日常生活分享为主的领域账号不受前台实名展示的影响。&lt;br>;3. 用户填写实名信息后，将在个人资料页展示用户的真实姓名。对于未登录的游客用户、未通过真实身份信息验证的用户、行为异常用户以及近期因不友善行为被处置的用户，禁止查看其他用户前台实名信息。&lt;br>;4. 站方将通过私信告知需进行前台实名展示的用户，用户可通过私信链接引导进行前台实名信息填写。&lt;br>;5. 接收到私信引导但未进行前台实名信息填写的用户，其账号的流量和收入将受到部分限制，包括推荐流展示限制、热搜展示限制、广告分成限制、打赏收入限制等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各平台的头部“自媒体”大V因其拥有的社会影响力，在讨论社会时事热点时，具有远超普通用户的舆论引导作用，而前台实名的实施正是为了推动大V承担起与话语能量相匹配的责任，从而进一步推进网络舆论生态治理。后续，站方将不断优化并完善前台实名展示流程及规则，在压实平台主体责任的同时积极提升用户体验。同时，站方也感谢广大用户对前台实名的积极支持与配合，微博愿与各界力量携手，共同营造清朗的网络空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（@微博管理员）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[韩国酵母又火了！为何“发面馒头”是明星的颜值终点站？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 17:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第十届北京香山论坛，高端对话探讨全球安全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 16:37:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;第十届北京香山论坛于10月29日至31日在北京国际会议中心举行。 论坛以“共同安全持久和平”为主题，是历届北京香山论坛以来规模最大的一次，外方代表数量达到了历届之最。</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[神舟十六号航天员乘组平安抵京]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259673]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 15:44:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据中国载人航天工程办公室消息，圆满完成神舟十六号载人飞行任务的航天员乘组，于2023年10月31日乘坐任务飞机平安抵达北京。空间站应用与发展阶段飞行任务总指挥部领导到机场迎接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3名航天员抵京后将进入隔离恢复期，进行全面的医学检查和健康评估，并安排休养。之后，将在京与新闻媒体集体见面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:29:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[县文联有奖征文，获奖者多是内部人：如此吃相太难看丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259655]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一个县级文联主办的有奖征文，大半获奖者是文联旗下刊物的编辑部成员，其中主编获奖作品12篇，几近获奖作品的半数。这一文坛“盛事”日前引起了不小的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据华商报报道，实名认证为河南方城县文联的微信公众号“裕州心声”（裕州是方城县旧称）10月26日发布一篇题为《“清风方城”文学艺术作品有奖征文获奖名单揭晓》的文章，称由方城县纪监委、方城县文联联合主办的“清风方城”有奖征文活动圆满成功，25篇作品分获一二三等奖及鼓励奖（原文如此，但公布的获奖作品名单实际只有23篇）。令人大跌眼镜的是，在名单所示的23篇获奖作品中，有12篇的作者是同一个人“乔君笠”，其中一等奖1篇、二等奖1篇、三等奖4篇、鼓励奖6篇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一人独揽几乎近半奖项，如此实力，如此天纵英才，乔君笠何许人也？文章最后所附的《裕州心声》编委会名单显示，乔君笠正是这一刊物的主编。而方城县检察院官方社媒账号此前发布的文章显示，乔君笠还是方城县文联副主席。而方城县文联正是这次征文活动的主办方之一，《裕州心声》则是活动的承办方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再细看获奖名单，23篇获奖作品中，至少有18篇的作者是《裕州心声》编辑部成员，除了乔君笠的12篇之外，还有总编郭某栓（方城县文联主席）1篇作品获二等奖；副总编熊某祥2篇作品分别获二等奖、三等奖；副主编李某雁、编委会成员梁某锋、策划武某华也各有1篇文章获奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自己主办有奖征文活动，自己人获奖，还不止一人，还有人十多篇文章同时获奖，实在令人叹为观止。 “清风方城”，清风何在？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;众所周知，各种正规的公开比赛、评选等活动，为了保障公平公正，评委必须保持中立，不应与任何参赛者有利益关联，而且通常会规定一人只能获得一个奖项。就连不少商业企业主办的抽奖促销活动也规定，员工和家属不能参与，否则即使中奖了也要作废。更不用说文联作为一个社会团体，在中国是受公共财政支持的，属于公共机构。作为活动主办和承办方，方城县文联和下属刊物理应保持客观中立的立场，以保证奖项评选的公正性。结果，文联的领导和刊物编辑部成员亲自下场比赛，还获得了大多数奖项。既做裁判员，又做运动员，谈何比赛的公平公正？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2000年《读书》举办的首届长江读书奖，《读书》主编汪晖和作为评委的钱理群均有作品获奖，就曾经引起巨大争议。自评自奖当然是不符合公平原则的，不客气地说，某种意义上就是“分赃”。如果作者认为自己的作品足够优秀，有资格获奖，那也应该避嫌，不仅不应作为评委，甚至有必要辞去主办方的相关职务，否则就不应该参与评奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而方城县的这个征文比赛，还可能涉及私分公共资金的问题。单从奖金金额上看，这似乎不是一件大事。比赛一等奖奖金每篇也不过500元，二等奖每篇400元，三等奖每篇300元，鼓励奖每篇200元。乔主编12篇作品获奖，总奖金也不过才3300元。但是，方城县曾经是贫困县，2019年才摘帽。根据方城县2022年政府工作报告，2021年全县GDP293亿元，以该县2020年第七次人口普查时的87万余人计算，人均GDP3.3万元左右，城镇居民人均可支配收入33574元，农村居民人均可支配收入16315元。也就是说，乔主编在这次有奖活动中所得的奖金，相当于该县城镇年人均可支配收入的1/10，农民年人均可支配收入的1/5。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纪检委和文联联合主办的这一有奖征文比赛，奖金来源恐怕很大可能是财政资金。这样一场征文比赛，获奖者几乎都是自己人，而且一人独得近半奖项，让人不得不怀疑，这是巧立名目用公款为自己发钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，也有一种可能是征文比赛无人问津，文联的领导们才不得不亲自出马。根据上文所说，这一征文比赛自2022年11月20日开始，6月30日截稿。尽管“社会各界文学爱好者积极响应，广泛发动，潜心创作”，但半年多的时间里，也只征集到49部作品。可见，方城县的“文学爱好者”并不是很多，或者大家对这样的比赛不感兴趣，所以没什么人投稿，而且投稿的质量也欠佳。为了避免出现无人得奖的尴尬局面，乔主编才不得不把自己的作品拿来充数。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，如果是这种情况，文联的责任也不容推卸。作为当地的文学艺术工作者的组织，文联难道不应该了解自己县里有多少文学工作者、爱好者吗？征文能有多少响应，也是应该可以估计到的。对于明知可能无人问津的比赛，还要去策划去组织，最后自己人出面撑门面拿奖，那更坐实了“巧立名目为自己发钱”的嫌疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，类似的现象不仅仅存在于方城县这一件事上，其他更严重的也很多。比如云南某国企的一把手，就曾经以各种名目为自己发放了几千万元的“奖励”，终以贪污等罪名被处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一征文活动的主办方之一是县纪监委，却出现这样的丑闻，实在是讽刺。舆论关注之下，方城县文联已经删掉了获奖名单，并声称之前是“初评结果”，未经主办方同意就发布了，下一步将组织市里的专家重新评审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;方城县也为此成立了专门的调查组，在10月31日凌晨发布情况说明，初步调查认定评选环节存在问题，评选结果无效，至于后续调查处理情况，将“适时”发布。公众期待调查组的最终处理结果。或许，最合适的处理方案是取消这一征文活动，追回资金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:29:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[反向合资，中外车企探索合作新模式丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259659]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:02:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/PMAhFrUA6OTlsple6X7qVTgBVZcJhXr6oXIcl8wf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1408&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/PMAhFrUA6OTlsple6X7qVTgBVZcJhXr6oXIcl8wf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;256200&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月24日，广汽集团发布公告，董事会审议通过了《关于广汽三菱重组的关联交易公告》。广汽集团分别以1元对价受让三菱自动车工业株式会社、三菱商事株式会社持有的广汽三菱30%、20%股权，重组完成后，广汽三菱将成为广汽集团全资子公司，广汽埃安将利用广汽三菱工厂实现增产扩能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，不仅仅是三菱，随着近年中国本土汽车品牌的崛起，合资品牌如铃木、雷诺、讴歌、Jeep等陆续退出中国市场，部分车企会选择以另一种方式与国内企业合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月26日，全球第四大汽车制造商Stellantis集团和零跑汽车共同宣布，Stellantis集团计划投资约15亿欧元（约116亿元人民币）以获取零跑汽车约20%的股权，并在零跑汽车董事会获得2个席位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对比7月份大众汽车以约7亿美元获得小鹏汽车约4.99%股权，零跑与Stellantis的合作更加深入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stellantis不仅作为零跑的战略投资者参与中国市场，同时双方还将组建合资公司零跑国际（Leapmotor&amp;nbsp;International）共同开发国际市场，零跑汽车持股49%，Stellantis集团持股51%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1984年1月，首个中外合资车企北京吉普诞生，外资汽车品牌带着技术、品牌来到中国，中国现代汽车产业以“市场换技术”模式已走过近40年，而今面对中国新能源车市场的激烈竞争和技术进步，外资车企开始探索和中国车企合作的新模式，“反向合资”正成为新选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;【&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;】&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/frontier-risk-and-preparedness&quot;>;&lt;u>;OpenAI组建新团队以评估人工智能的“灾难性风险”&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月26日，人工智能研究公司OpenAI宣布组建新团队Preparedness，以评估和减轻与人工智能相关的“灾难性风险”。该团队主要任务是“跟踪、评估、预测和保护”人工智能造成的潜在重大问题，并致力于减轻“化学、生物和放射性威胁”，以及人工智能的“自主复制”行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：随着人工智能技术的发展和应用，人类社会也面临一系列超出传统经验的产业发展模式、监管模式的挑战。多国就人工智能起草和制定新的监管办法，但解铃还须系铃人，大模型厂商们积极参与和行动起来，更是帮助人工智能更好地往前发展的力量。（推荐人：唐家乐）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;【&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;】&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/cArAd1qxXVblfdwAAqTk5g&quot;>;&lt;u>;华为发布露天矿无人化解决方案&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月25日，华为联合中国华能集团、兴盛露天矿、酒钢集团和同力重工共同发布了“露天矿无人化解决方案”，其中重装远控、无人驾驶等无人化关键技术已规模商用，效率持平人工作业水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;露天矿重装远控可实现穿孔与铲装从人机互动到机机交互，穿孔作业从现场1人1钻到远程1人3钻，采装现场100%人工到远程80%自动化远控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：矿井开采条件恶劣，安全风险大等痛点长期制约着煤炭行业的发展。2020年3月国务院八部委发布《关于加快煤矿智能化发展的指导意见》，提出到2035年各类煤矿基本实现智能化，煤矿开采或成为传统产业智能化改造先锋。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;【&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;】&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/YWywXP_xGCpSUqkijrXv3A&quot;>;&lt;u>;中国电信研究院完成全球首次运营商NR&amp;nbsp;NTN现网试验&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月25日，中国电信研究院宣布与中国电信上海应急通信局、中国电信卫星公司紧密协同，联合北京捷蜂创智科技与北京邮电大学，基于同步轨道卫星，完成全球首次运营商NR&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;NTN（非地面网络）终端直连卫星现网环境测试验证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;试验结果表明，在5MHz低带宽频谱资源下，基于同步轨道卫星的NR&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;NTN网络仍可提供稳定的语音、短信及宽带数据服务，可作为国家应急通信服务体系、综合信息服务体系中重要的便携式解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：卫星通信是5G-Advanced和6G的重要组成部分，三大运营商都在积极进行探索。2023年9月，中国移动携手中兴通讯、是德科技共同完成国内首次运营商NR&amp;nbsp;NTN低轨卫星实验室模拟验证。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;【&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;04&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;】&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.excision.bio/_files/ugd/80a6fd_de98df6a38d042658595374af17d658a.pdf&quot;>;&lt;u>;全球首个HIV基因编辑疗法临床试验数据发布&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月25日，美国生物技术公司Excision公布，其在研CRISPR基因疗法EBT-101，在治疗HIV-1（艾滋病病毒的一种）感染的1/2期临床试验的积极中期数据。在前三名临床试验参与者中，使用EBT-101治疗没有导致严重的不良事件或剂量限制毒性，所有报告的不良事件都是轻微和可逆的；所有参与者的血液中&lt;span>;都&lt;/span>;检测到EBT-101，治疗产生了积极的生物分布；以上数据支持将该临床试验推进到下一个剂量水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;EBT-101是一款在患者体内进行CRISPR基因编辑的疗法，旨在通过单次静脉输注后治愈HIV感染，也是全球首个使用CRISPR基因编辑治疗艾滋病的人体临床试验。该疗法于2021年&lt;span>;底&lt;/span>;获得美国FDA批准进行人体临床试验，2023年获FDA的快速通道资格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：现有的艾滋病标准治疗方法是抗逆转录病毒疗法，可防止HIV病毒在体内的复制，但无法清除HIV病毒，患者需要长期持续接受治疗。CRISPR的发现是寻找潜在根治艾滋病（AIDS）治疗方法的突破，EBT-101是第一个针对人类整合病毒的CRISPR疗法。“治愈HIV感染”的目的地还很远，但已有人在路上并持续前进。（推荐人：罗仙仙）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“快枪手”邱礼涛的反驳：“我花的时间没有人们想象得那么短”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259633]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[依法查处，数百个非法涉外气象探测站向境外传输数据]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since this year, national security agencies, together with meteorological and security departments, have carried out special management of foreign-related meteorological detection nationwide in accordance with the law. , investigated more than 10 overseas meteorological equipment agents, inspected more than 3,000 foreign-related meteorological stations, and found that hundreds of illegal foreign-related meteorological detection stations transmit meteorological data overseas in real time, widely distributed in more than 20 provinces across the country, posing risks to our national security Hidden danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256145&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Illegal weather detection equipment installed by an overseas company&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256146&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Set Illegal meteorological detection equipment in our residential areas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of these illegal foreign-related meteorological detection sites are directly funded by overseas governments, and some observation points are set up around sensitive places such as military units and military industrial enterprises to conduct altitude measurements. Approval and GPS positioning; some are deployed in China&#39;s main grain-producing areas to correlate the growth of China&#39;s crops and grain yields; some are even transmitted to foreign official meteorological agencies in real-time at long-term, high-frequency, and multiple points to serve foreign homeland security and weather monitoring. The relevant equipment is small in size, easy to install, difficult to find, and can automatically collect and transmit over the network in real time. For relevant foreign-related meteorological detection activities, they failed to apply for an administrative license for foreign-related meteorological detection from our meteorological authorities, failed to submit meteorological data to our meteorological authorities, and transmitted meteorological data overseas without the approval of our meteorological authorities, violating the &quot;Foreign-related Meteorological Observations and Data&quot; &quot;Administrative Measures&quot;, &quot;Data Security Law&quot; and other relevant regulations. National security agencies, in conjunction with meteorological and confidentiality departments, investigate and deal with relevant illegal activities in accordance with the law, and promptly block illegal activities of exporting meteorological data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>