<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[百余家企业被“公开除名”，科学减碳有多难？ ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258230]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/QCLASjAcX5D3H6FtvhpuGOvsy1zfw8Tf7DDvzPyM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/QCLASjAcX5D3H6FtvhpuGOvsy1zfw8Tf7DD vzPyM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;July 24, 2023, Suichuan County, Ji&#39;an, Jiangxi Province, Zhufeng Peak, clouds and mist Swirling wind turbines. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If achieving carbon neutrality is regarded as a marathon, many companies are willing to stand on the starting line. But after the gun goes off, only half of the players actually take a step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to work together, there are many &quot;group chats&quot; around the world - various environmental initiatives attract companies to join and promise to achieve what goals by when. However, if the company fails to report progress to the &quot;group owner&quot; in a timely manner, it may be removed from the group chat or even have its name made public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, a group leader known for its strictness, &quot;The Science Based Targets Initiative (SBTi)&quot;, marked 121 companies and financial institutions around the world in August 2023. &quot;Commitment&amp;nbsp;removed&quot; tag, the list keeps growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SBTi was jointly launched in 2015 by the World Resources Institute (WRI), the Center for Global Information (CDP), the World Wildlife Fund (WWF) and the United Nations Global Compact (UNGC), in partnership with the Paris Agreement and global temperature control goals. Companies joining need to set goals and submit progress regularly. A total of 1,097 companies around the world will have their goals verified by SBTi in 2022. In February 2023, a report by the UNGC and Boston Consulting showed that companies that had made commitments in accordance with the Science-Based Carbon Target Initiative standards accounted for 35% of the total market value of global companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The companies removed this time include 100 foreign companies such as Amazon, Schneider, and Yahoo Japan, as well as 21 Chinese companies (including Hong Kong and Taiwan) such as Trina Solar, ZTO Express, and Qinhuai Data. This move was considered &quot;unkind&quot;. Amazon was once a core sponsor of SBTi, and the Earth Foundation established by Amazon CEO Bezos is still a core sponsor of SBTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An SBTi spokesperson told Southern Weekend reporters that the public removal of the list of companies is to increase the transparency and responsibility of corporate climate actions. SBTi has the responsibility to increase its ambitions based on the increasingly urgent situation of climate science. However, SBTi has not completely closed the door. Removed companies are welcome to resubmit their goals. After being successfully verified, they can rejoin the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is too difficult to clock in on time&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Committed to setting a Science-based target (SBT) within 24 months, and is the first person to join SBTi step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, this goal is in line with the Paris Agreement: to control global temperature rise within 2°C and strive to limit it to 1.5°C. For specific companies, it includes short-term and long-term goals. For example, a company can set a short-term goal of &quot;using 2021 as the base year to reduce emissions by 42% by 2030.&quot; The long-term goal must comply with SBTi&#39;s net zero standards. More than 90% carbon emission reduction needs to be achieved by 2050. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After submitting the letter of commitment, the company needs to submit its goals to SBTi for verification within 24 months. It is similar to preparing to run a marathon, planning when and where to run, and how to check in. In the past, companies that failed to submit targets on time, withdrew their commitments or made operational changes would be removed from the list by SBTi in the background, but the new policy is to make them public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 21 Chinese companies removed by SBTi (including 1 Hong Kong company and 3 Taiwanese companies) cover various industries such as logistics, photovoltaics, and information and communication technology (ICT). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted 17 companies registered in the mainland. Two companies admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that the current corporate carbon emission reduction work is insufficient; one company explained the progress of the company&#39;s carbon emission reduction work; Zhongtong Express, Hebei Chengxin Group, Guangzhou Yayao Electrical Appliances, Jiangsu Hongbang Chemical Technology Co., Ltd. and other companies declined Southern Weekend&#39;s interview request; 10 companies did not respond, and Southern Weekend reporters did not find any public statements from these companies regarding the removal. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enterprises also have difficulties in being removed from the list for failing to submit the &quot;punch in&quot; plan in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SBTi standards are constantly updated, and the latest version is version 5.1. In version 5.0 in July 2022, the minimum temperature rise for short-term targets is tightened from below 2°C to 1.5°C, and the target period that companies can set is shortened from 15 years to 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ray Atkinson, a spokesperson for Smithfield Foods, which was removed, said in an email that SBTi introduced new metrics and different reporting for the forest, land and agriculture industry in September 2022. requirements, which prevents pork producers and food processing companies from submitting science-based targets by the deadline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enterprise types and sizes vary, and the difficulty of setting goals also varies. After being removed, Amazon issued an announcement stating, “Developing appropriate carbon emission guidelines and practices for a large enterprise like Amazon is complex and takes time, making it difficult for us to submit meaningful and scientifically accurate carbon emissions within the required time. emissions targets”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, SBTi provides targeted goal setting guidance for 14 industries including aluminum, clothing and footwear, aviation, construction, and information and communications technology (ICT). The remaining industries need to follow unified standards set a goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that among the 121 companies that were removed, the top three industries were food and beverage processing, technical hardware and equipment, and the chemical industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ZkXhQqbUW3vIGTre0rLrbi2LpIIRglKAs0iIwxkL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1121&quot; height= &quot;1419&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ZkXhQqbUW3vIGTre0rLrbi2LpIIRglKAs0iIwxkL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Analysis of the list of companies removed by SBTi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Huang Siqi compiled Liang Shuyi&#39;s drawing/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The emissions of these three industries mainly come from scope 3, that is, the corporate value chain All other indirect emissions generated in. For large enterprises, Scope 3 is the biggest carbon reduction challenge. (According to SBTi requirements) linearly reducing absolute emissions by 2.5% per year is very difficult.&quot; Third-party carbon emissions management agency Yan Luhui, founder and CEO of Carbon Block, speculated that this may be the reason why these companies have difficulty submitting targets for verification on time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the Chinese companies whose commitments were removed by SBTi this time, a new energy manufacturing company that did not want to be named told Southern Weekend reporters that the company’s carbon emissions from the upstream supply chain accounted for less than 1% of the total carbon emissions. The proportion is relatively large. How to collaboratively promote carbon reduction across the entire industry chain is the biggest difficulty facing the new energy manufacturing industry in reducing carbon emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SBTi’s emission reduction requirement for scope 1 and scope 2 is to linearly reduce absolute emissions by 4.2% per year. Yan Luhui believes that this is for manufacturing industries where scope 2 emissions account for more than 80%, such as textiles or cosmetics. For suppliers, it is also very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun, founder of Climate Future and author of &quot;The Carbon Neutrality Era&quot;, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Submitting a letter of commitment to SBTi is very simple. You only need to fill in the basic company information to &#39;join&#39; SBTi, but the settings The conditions for the goal are very stringent. It is like a university that has basically no admission qualification requirements, but it is difficult to graduate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meeting the SBTi requirements is not easy around the world. According to data updated in real time by SBTi, as of October 3, 2023, a total of 6,249 companies around the world have made commitments, but only 3,540 companies have submitted their goals on time and passed verification, accounting for only 57%. The remaining companies that have not submitted their goals are still within the 24-month commitment period. If they fail to submit their goals after the deadline, they are also at risk of being removed from the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cBe9ohHdPpTd9f5cBEwGT6L21ziX19pey9x6JLSI.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1896&quot; height= &quot;844&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cBe9ohHdPpTd9f5cBEwGT6L21ziX19pey9x6JLSI.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253289&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of October 3, 2023, the situation of companies joining SBTi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(SBTi official website screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Change passive into active&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Join SBTi Many of the Chinese companies are not well-known to the public, and most of their businesses are to&amp;nbsp;B. Even joining SBTi may be driven by downstream brands. Many interviewees called it &quot;passive participation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ambitious companies often encourage suppliers to participate in carbon reduction actions. &quot;Dell&#39;s supplier management guidelines clearly require suppliers to fulfill their SBTi commitments, which is how many Chinese companies join SBTi.&quot; said Ma Yingying, climate and energy project director of the environmental organization Institute for Public and Environmental Affairs (IPE). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters counted information on 121 removed companies. The top three countries and regions are the United States, China (including Hong Kong and Taiwan companies) and the United Kingdom, with 23, 21 and 14 companies respectively; as of press time, In the total list of companies joining SBTi, the TOP3 countries and regions are also the United Kingdom, the United States and China (including 225 mainland companies and 242 companies from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun, founder of the Institute of Public and Environmental Affairs (IPE), said that a group of multinational companies have made net-zero emission commitments after the Paris Agreement. If local supplier companies cannot follow up on the climate commitments made by brand customers, they will It is possible to be at a disadvantage in global competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, while publicly removing its corporate commitments, SBTi also released the &quot;2022 SBTi Monitoring Report&quot;, which focused on the performance of Chinese companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An SBTi spokesperson responded to a reporter from Southern Weekend. The report shows that in 2022, the number of Asian companies that have set scientific carbon targets and commitments is growing rapidly, with China experiencing the largest increase - the number of companies submitting effective targets has increased by 194%. , “As the source of many global supply chains, China’s growing participation in SBTi could have a huge impact on global businesses’ Scope 3 emissions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carbon tariffs and other policies are forcing Chinese enterprises to turn from passive to active and integrate with international standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The EU&#39;s &quot;Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism&quot; (CBAM), known as carbon tariffs, requires countries or regions that strictly implement carbon emission reductions to pay (return) corresponding taxes when importing (exporting) high-carbon products. taxes or carbon quotas. A total of six categories of commodities, including steel, cement, aluminum, fertilizer, electricity and hydrogen, were included in the first batch and will enter the substantive implementation stage from 2026. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun said that if the carbon boundary adjustment mechanism cannot be effectively followed up, the transitional stage will have an impact on export companies. After formal implementation, the costs of export companies will increase due to carbon tariffs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the analysis of public financial reports and company official website introductions, Southern Weekend reporters found that &quot;operating international business&quot; or &quot;having plans to go overseas&quot; are also common features of removed Chinese companies. For example, Yingqu Technology carries out manufacturing activities in China, Southeast Asia and Europe; Narada Power&#39;s market covers 160 countries and regions around the world; Sichuan Yongxiang, a subsidiary of Tongwei Group, regards product exports and overseas investment as the future development direction of photovoltaic companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to following the requirements of multinational companies, there are also Chinese brand companies taking the initiative to implement scientific carbon targets. In November 2020, JD Logistics became the first domestic logistics company to complete the establishment of scientific carbon targets. In January 2023, Lenovo’s 2050 net-zero emissions target was officially approved by SBTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Large companies are willing to implement the initiative. On the one hand, it can drive domestic brands to improve their competitiveness and compete with world brands in supply. On the other hand, it can also drive small and medium-sized enterprises to realize their emission reduction responsibilities and public consumption behavior. Respond to the emission reduction initiative and jointly build my country&#39;s dual-carbon goals.&quot; said Guan Weijia, general manager of Guangzhou Jet Carbon Technology Co., Ltd., a domestic comprehensive dual-carbon service provider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The starting time is later, but the judging standards are the same&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For Chinese companies, the starting time is later, but the referee will not lower the judging standards. is the bigger challenge we face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Yingying also found that the carbon management level of many manufacturing enterprises in China is still in its infancy. On the one hand, they lack an in-depth understanding of proper terms such as carbon targets; on the other hand, they lack mastery of their own carbon emission data. Not enough, I blindly joined SBTi under the call, but it was difficult to achieve the goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For companies that are expanding rapidly, it is not easy to increase production while reducing carbon emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Weijia told Southern Weekend reporters that most of the early Chinese companies that actively responded to SBTi were industry leaders with high brand goals and keen business acumen. Why was it removed? Compared with terms such as &quot;broken trust&quot; and &quot;greenwashing&quot;, a more appropriate understanding should be that there is a deviation and incompatibility between the company&#39;s low-carbon goals and implementation path plans. &quot;From a subjective perspective, this group of companies is by no means just shouting slogans and doing nothing. It must be admitted that Chinese companies started their low-carbon actions later than international companies, and there is currently a certain gap. Therefore, under the same goals, domestic companies need to pay more Work harder.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun said that on the one hand, more digital solutions are needed to help Chinese companies achieve their goals. On the other hand, SBTi also needs to cooperate with stakeholders to develop scientific and reasonable emission reduction target setting methodologies based on different development stages and emission reduction responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will SBTi refer to the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities and set different goals for different development stages? An SBTi spokesperson responded to a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;All companies must abide by the same standards. Our standards currently do not distinguish between developed and developing countries, but we may review this carefully in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overview Join After all, among SBTi Chinese companies, only a few have had their commitments removed. Yan Luhui believes that SBTi&#39;s public removal of corporate commitments is also a positive signal, which can urge companies to propose goals in a more prudent and responsible manner and not to make blind promises. Regardless of whether they join SBTi or not, companies must have a clear “check-in” plan if they want to achieve any of their own carbon reduction goals. The first step is self-examination. Yan Luhui believes that only by understanding one&#39;s own carbon emissions can we find feasible and practical emission reduction methods that are in line with the company&#39;s experience and development. &quot;The core is to identify the hotspots of one&#39;s own emission reduction and promote emission reduction in a targeted manner.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After figuring out the situation, companies also need to plan a feasible emission reduction path for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, technology companies’ largest emissions come from data center electricity consumption, and data centers can be moved to western provinces such as Qinghai and Ningxia where green electricity is abundant; consumer goods companies have high raw material consumption, so they focus on finding In terms of alternative materials, some stationery brands use renewable recycled lunch boxes as raw materials for pen holders; the core of logistics companies is to reduce fuel emissions from transportation, and they can shorten the distance by changing transportation methods or optimizing routes through artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[总感觉自己被封印在床上？你不是一个人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/17e7725c5a6728bd21a29bd726d67530.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/17e7725c5a6728bd21a29bd726d67530.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the blink of an eye, the balance during the National Day holiday has been cleared. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The workers of this generation expressed their inseparability from the bed with jokes, &quot;I don&#39;t want to get up, I want to sleep until the sea is gone&quot; and &quot;The only thing I can afford now is The only thing I can&#39;t put down is the chopsticks, and the only thing I can&#39;t get out of is the bed.&quot; It seems that lying down all the time during holidays and having difficulty getting up during the workday is a post-holiday syndrome among young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the acceleration of the pace of life and the increase of social pressure, more and more people are sleeping poorly and unable to sleep. Poor sleep has become a modern urban disease, and sleeping at night Lack of time and poor sleep quality means staying in bed until the next day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Staying in bed has gradually become a disease of modern people. The sound of roosters, the system&#39;s built-in ringtones, songs you like or hate, mixed ringtones... Various songs with different styles will always sound at the same time at the same time every day, but none of these can wake you up from your sleep. of you. &quot;Give me two more minutes to freeze my memory.&quot; Jay Chou&#39;s lyrics may represent the voice of many seriously bedridden patients. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Where does bedridden syndrome come from? Is it a unique product of modern society or has it evolved from ancient times? Will staying in bed affect your life? How do we say goodbye to &quot;sleeping in bed&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Crowing of cocks doesn’t work, even the ancients also stayed in bed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s not just modern people who like to stay in bed Beds, our ancestors more than 2,000 years ago actually loved to sleep in. The situation and conversation between them lying in bed may seem familiar to people today. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are two sentences in &quot;The Book of Songs·Zheng Feng·The Woman Said Cockcrow&quot;, the woman said: &quot;Cockcrow&quot;, and the scholar said: &quot;Meudan. Zixing looks at the night , stars have bad days.&quot; Meaning, the heroine said: &quot;The rooster has crowed.&quot; The subtext is that it&#39;s time for you to get up. The male protagonist struggled in bed and said: &quot;It&#39;s not yet dawn. If you don&#39;t believe me, open the window and look at the sky, the stars are shining brightly.&quot; Does the male protagonist&#39;s answer sound like what modern people say, &quot;It&#39;s still early, let me sleep for five more days.&quot; Minutes&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reasons our ancestors had when getting up are the same as those of modern people. In &quot;The Book of Songs, Qifeng, Cockcrow&quot;, another bed-ridden lover&#39;s answer is believed to have touched the hearts of many modern people. He said: &quot;It is bright in the east, the light of the moonrise.&quot; Oh, it is not bright in the east, it is the light emitted by the moon. This justification for staying in bed is equally applicable to modern people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the common people who love to stay in bed, sometimes the emperor will stay in bed according to his temper. It is often said in the play: &quot;The courtiers are waiting for the cold weather at the fifth watch.&quot; The ministers have to go to court every morning at the fifth watch, waiting to see the emperor. But the emperor sometimes didn&#39;t want to get up early when he went to court so early to listen to politics. The most famous one is probably the sentence in Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;Song of Everlasting Sorrow&quot; describing Tang Xuanzong and Yang Guifei, &quot;The spring night is short and the sun is rising, and the king will not go to court early from now on.&quot; Tang Xuanzong was so obsessed with beauty that he stayed in bed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another emperor who was famous for staying in bed should be Ming Shenzong Zhu Yijun. During the middle and late periods of Zhu Yijun&#39;s reign, he rarely went to court. He did not attend the early dynasty for more than thirty years, becoming the emperor with the longest period of &quot;passive sabotage&quot; in the history of the Ming Dynasty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/49ed8865628d023fd418e64280c782f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/49ed8865628d023fd418e64280c782f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253245 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;There are a thousand reasons for those who stay in bed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Shu Guozhi wrote in &quot;Lying in Bed&quot;: &quot;Lying in bed, I have already woken up, but I have no intention of Get up. The body that lay flat for eight or nine hours the night before has rested enough, and the dream of traveling thousands of miles while sleeping the night before has also stopped. However, this lazy body is still willing to lie down, and the hairspring after the dream is still there. I want to float.&quot; I believe that seriously bedridden patients will sympathize with this statement. Everyone knows that staying in bed is a bad habit. But why can&#39;t I get up once I fall into bed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The imaginative person said: &quot;On the first day, my quilt was sick, and I had to take care of it in bed. On the second day, although the quilt&#39;s disease was cured, But the bed was infected, and I had to take care of it together with the quilt. On the third day, they all recovered, but I was sick, and my quilt and bed had to take care of me...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;At this time, the psychological school influenced by Freudian theory jumped out and said: &quot;No, no. This is the desire of the id. People have id, ego and superego. When lying in bed, the id It is believed that the body needs more adequate rest in bed, and the superego requires it to get up out of compliance with the rules. People are always contradictory when staying in bed, because the desires of the id conflict with the norms of the superego.&quot;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Scientists tell us that sleeping in bed is actually related to melatonin and light. A gland called the &quot;pineal gland&quot; at the bottom of the human brain secretes melatonin, a hormone that promotes sleep. Its secretion principle is related to sunlight: exposure to sunlight will inhibit the secretion of melatonin, making people in a state of wakefulness; when there is no exposure to sunlight, melatonin begins to be secreted, making people drowsy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Moreover, the time and body temperature when people enter deep sleep can also affect how quickly people get up. As shown in the figure, the higher the body temperature, the more awake the person is, and vice versa, so exercising more can ensure full energy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8a30c4137147207f636b4dc0fea4ef3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;245&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8a30c4137147207f636b4dc0fea4ef3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253247 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(Zhihu/Screenshot)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, Lai The relationship between bed and work efficiency is also very subtle. Milgram pointed out in his research that staying in bed is a unique type of procrastination behavior compared to other procrastination behaviors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Traditional research believes that the procrastination behavior of staying in bed will only have a negative impact on individuals. Research by domestic scholar Wang Lingzhi shows that students&#39; procrastination behavior will make them unable to complete academic tasks within the prescribed deadline, resulting in poor academic performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the traditional academic view is that procrastination will bring a series of negative impacts to individuals, some researchers have recently proposed that procrastination can also benefit individuals at some level. Bring about some positive behavioral consequences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Choi&amp;amp;Chu used a questionnaire method to divide procrastinators into active procrastinators and passive procrastinators in their research. They proposed that active procrastinators can do some things during procrastination. Make more thoughtful decisions and have higher arousal levels under stress levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t worry, staying in bed can be “cured” &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although, staying in bed is not a cure It&#39;s a disease, but if it happens while staying in bed, the consequences may be more serious than getting sick. So, how to “treat” this bad habit? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First of all, we must develop correct sleeping habits and develop correct waking procedures. For example, if the temperature in the bedroom is suitable, ideally the temperature in the bedroom should not be too low. Especially in winter, if the temperature difference between the inside and outside of the bed is too large, it will take a lot of courage to climb out of the warm bed. Don’t keep the room temperature too warm, as this will make it easier for people to fall asleep and feel groggy when they wake up. The ideal temperature is 16℃-21℃, and put a small basin of water in the room to prevent the air from being too dry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, the room should not be too dark. Research by Professor Maas of Cornell University in the United States has found that sunlight sends a signal to the biological clock, stops the secretion of melatonin that makes people sleep, and activates the awake neurons in the brain to help us wake up. Before going to bed, you can leave a small crack in the curtains, so that the morning sunlight can shine in through the window, telling the body that a new day has begun and it is time to get up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Be prepared and prepare an extra alarm clock. For some people, one alarm clock is not enough. If the alarm clock goes off, you will continue to sleep after it, and when you wake up, you will find that it is already late for work. Then prepare two alarm clocks. The set times should not be too close to each other, preferably 30 minutes apart. The second alarm clock should be set for a time when you must wake up. One is placed at the head of the bed, and the other is placed a little further away. You have to get out of bed to turn it off. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s no wonder that alarm clocks that deduct money if you don’t get up are so popular among young people. This alarm clock called Kello limits the number of &quot;naps&quot; the user is allowed to do after setting the alarm in a week. If the user does not get up and turn off the alarm after the preset time, Kello will deduct money from the subsidy in the APP. , are you still staying in bed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, you must regain consciousness as soon as possible and massage your face. When you have just woken up and haven&#39;t opened your eyes, you can use massage to increase blood circulation and help you wake up slowly. First, use the palms of both hands to press around the eye sockets from outside to inside, then the forehead, cheeks, and ears. Use your fingertips to gently tap with different intensity until the entire face is touched. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The most important thing is to adjust the sleep rhythm. Getting up at a regular time and sleeping for as long as you need is the most basic and effective way to get rid of bed rest. Try to get up on time every day for a few days, and you will find that the time you go to bed is quietly advancing every day. Slowly, your body will establish a new sleep and wake-up pattern. You will feel sleepy at the fixed time, and you will feel sleepy when you get up early in the morning. Much more awake. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, dear friends, don’t be reluctant to leave the bed. Start a new day by refusing to stay in bed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上交所、深交所：现阶段A股市场实行T+0交易的时机不成熟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258220]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange’s WeChat official account, some self-media said recently that A-share trading will be extended after the holiday. Time, and trial T+0 trading on some stocks. How do the exchanges comment on this? The Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange said that we are aware of the above rumors and the relevant content is not true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 18 this year, the relevant person in charge of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, when answering reporters’ questions about activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence, proposed to study the appropriate extension of the trading hours of the A-share market. This work involves a wide range of areas and has a large impact. The exchange is conducting in-depth research and demonstration in accordance with the unified deployment of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. In addition, the relevant person in charge made it clear in answering reporters’ questions in the early stage that the time for implementing T+0 trading in the A-share market is not mature at this stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3cea3d840728c32846d0f2b3128b670e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;699&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3cea3d840728c32846d0f2b3128b670e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253263&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a3dc335b53bd38baf6fe7c7138841cc9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;721&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a3dc335b53bd38baf6fe7c7138841cc9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大尺度、马赛克，十月新片要爆啊]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;Coincides with the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day At the end of the day, the movie theater also became lively. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Military films, suspense films, romance films, comedies, literary films...&lt;/span>; Various genres, you can choose from them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Let’s take a look at October’s theatrical films! &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(All new films released on National Day are included here)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Volunteers: Heroes Attack&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director: Chen Kaige&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Zhang Ke&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Tang Guoqiang/Wang Yanhui/Liu Jin/Xin Baiqing/Zhang Songwen/Huang Xiaoming/Zhang Ziyi, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09-28 (Mainland China) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/c28d601678bf06f8d10cfb28c1142f6c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/c28d601678bf06f8d10cfb28c1142f6c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253145 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;To commemorate the 70th anniversary of the victory in the War to Resist U.S. Aggression and Aid Korea, the film series &quot;Volunteer Army&quot; will be gradually released within a few years. &quot;Volunteer Army: Heroes Attack&quot; directed by Chen Kaige is the first in the series. It tells the first and second stages of the War to Resist US Aggression and Aid Korea. It comprehensively presents the battle of Liangshui Cave, the Battle of Sansuoli and the Songgu Peak Blockade from a grand and multi-dimensional perspective. war. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1b2f09e4376f33ab2c5233934434c083.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1b2f09e4376f33ab2c5233934434c083.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253141 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This is also the most difficult creation that Director Chen has encountered in his forty years of filmmaking. The film uses a 1:1 restored set and was filmed for more than 300 days. It was a star-studded film and the cast members underwent strict military management. The military images of Zhu Yilong, Zhang Zifeng, Chen Feiyu, Zhang Youhao, Ou Hao, Wei Chen, Yin Fang, Wei Daxun and other actors also raise expectations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a21b4613b57a8e548919228e1489d071.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a21b4613b57a8e548919228e1489d071.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253140 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;Director:&amp;nbsp;Zhang Yimou&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter:&amp;nbsp;Chen Yu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring:&amp;nbsp;Lei Jiayin&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp ;Zhang Guoli&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Yu Hewei&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Zhou Dongyu&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Sun Yizhou&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Li Naiwen&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Xu Yajun&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date : 2023-09-28 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e160e0b32e17fd75dccf30e271c38f17. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ e160e0b32e17fd75dccf30e271c38f17.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253142&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; was completed in 2019, the first trailer was released in 2020, and it was finally finalized three years later. &quot;In addition to money, there is money, and there is also officialdom&quot; implies that the film tells the story of cracking down on gangs and eliminating evil. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Su Jianming&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Lei Jiayin)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Li Huilin&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhou Dongyu)&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Work together to investigate a difficult criminal case, with countless overt or covert forces colluding behind it. Su Jianming ignored the dissuasion of his father Zheng Gang (played by Zhang Guoli), a high-ranking official, and rushed to Li Zhitian (played by Yu Hewei), a wealthy businessman involved in organized crime. >; Hongmen Banquet. But the closer you are to the truth, the closer you are to the abyss. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/25acfd48f6e17ba30bbcef85ad7c2cff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/25acfd48f6e17ba30bbcef85ad7c2cff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253143 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d7486b93a340448da8353db5b00dc7a6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d7486b93a340448da8353db5b00dc7a6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253144&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Due to the large scale of the crime-related content, including restricted scenes such as hands soaking in hot pot and corpses hiding in the wall, even the trailer is mosaic-ed in many places. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5fd5a6c3edae13490ef3d2969add2ade.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5fd5a6c3edae13490ef3d2969add2ade.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253146 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The movies of &quot;National Master&quot; Zhang Yimou have always been a must-see. The urban crime theme involved this time is very topical, gathering &quot;men seeking men&quot; and &quot;women seeking&quot; They are also all capable actors. Judging from the high-contrast tones of the trailer, Zhang Yimou is playing with a very new neon aesthetic, which is very suitable for presenting Steel Forest and Vice City. I believe that &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; will have good box office results during the National Day season. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/65b7d4ac6d31a57187a9bc13294176b4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/65b7d4ac6d31a57187a9bc13294176b4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253147 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Ex 4: Marry Young&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Director: Tian Yusheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Da Kuan/Da Guang/Tian Yusheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Han Geng / Zheng Kai/Liu Yase/Zeng Mengxue/Yu Wenwen/Zhang Tianai/Zhu Yan Manzi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09-28 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/590fcbd06d686fc86456a42ece892f3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/590fcbd06d686fc86456a42ece892f3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;Who would have thought that the &quot;Predecessor&quot; series would actually get a fourth installment. Although the ratings were basically below the passing mark, the box office of &quot;Exes 3&quot; unexpectedly soared to 1.9 billion, giving birth to &quot;Ex 4&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/628a1e9f5d40368b687090ad04439d49.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/628a1e9f5d40368b687090ad04439d49.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253148 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Exes 4&quot; tells the story of a new emotional problem for the brother who pursues love: Meng Yun who is experiencing the sequelae of a breakup&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(played by Han Geng)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Embarking on a journey to find true love; and Yu Fei (played by Zheng Kai) and his girlfriend began a cooling-off period rehearsal before getting married. The lovable thing about urban romantic comedies is that their connection with realistic emotions can easily attract the target audience, and the box office base is there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d21e67fec5c8c78d8ace10fb3ba7981e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d21e67fec5c8c78d8ace10fb3ba7981e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253150 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t seem that passionate&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;Director: Gao Hu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Xing Wenxiong&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Wei Xiang/ Wang Zhi/ Yue Liang/ Allen/Zi Yi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09- 28 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a6d02ac610771ec214e4cfd6e91b7ee5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1724&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a6d02ac610771ec214e4cfd6e91b7ee5.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;253152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film is adapted from the Spanish film &quot;Basketball Champions&quot; and tells the story of the basketball coach&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Wei Xiang)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The story of leading a basketball team composed of mentally retarded people to realize their dream of winning the championship. The original version scored 7.2 points on Douban, ranking among the top 10 Spanish comedy films. The Chinese version is produced by the Happy Twist Team. Original scripts are their weakness, but the lovable actors give it a wide audience base. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a99c6f209d0af950695c835e1e4aee2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;465&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a99c6f209d0af950695c835e1e4aee2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253151 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the comedians we are familiar with, the film also uses some amateur actors. They are all &quot;young men&quot; with mental disabilities. This actually brings more difficulties to the filming, but It is of great significance from the perspective of a public welfare film. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;93 International Train Robbery: Operation Moscow&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director: Qiu Litao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Chen Daming&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Zhang Hanyu/Andy Lau / Huang Xuan/ Wen Yongshan/ Gu Jiacheng&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Producing country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09-29 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a747b34e1648a3d415554da4b9df156.jpeg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1510&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a747b34e1648a3d415554da4b9df156 .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1993, on a train from Beijing to Moscow, four groups of robbers carried out serial robberies on passengers. Chinese police infiltrated the train and arrested gangsters disguised as international gangsters. This film is adapted from this shocking case and restores the cross-border manhunt drama of the 1990s. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e0850332c4a8fa4301a24100b1856425.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e0850332c4a8fa4301a24100b1856425.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253154 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This film is directed by Hong Kong&#39;s talented director Qiu Litao. He is not only good at cult movies such as &quot;Human Barbecued Pork Buns&quot;, but he can also control action blockbusters such as &quot;The Bomb Disposer 2&quot; and deal with detective themes. It’s also very handy, and the whole story is very well completed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another highlight of the film is: Andy Lau and Huang Xuan break through their &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; images, playing tough gangsters and challenging villain roles; while Zhang Hanyu plays the role of a plainclothes policeman , sparks fly in the male group drama. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/675e7deb9ee73e86c1a9e27257c33a3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/675e7deb9ee73e86c1a9e27257c33a3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253156 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f045cdb7b213f74670a132de9c58c2aa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f045cdb7b213f74670a132de9c58c2aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253155&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Best Encounter&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Director: Ha Zhichao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Qiu Yan/Lin Yongzhu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Jin Shijia/Qiu Ze/Junning Zhang/Jiang Peiyao &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-10-20 (China Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a9c1e4599b9b3a4b61ad4608c3b96103.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1547&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a9c1e4599b9b3a4b61ad4608c3b96103.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;253158&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the drama version of &quot;Detective Chinatown&quot;, Qiu Ze and Zhang Junning play a pair of equally matched high-IQ players. The combination of handsome men and beautiful women is very good-looking. In the movie &quot;The Best Encounter&quot;, they took off their fancy makeup and returned to simplicity, playing the role of a mentally retarded couple who want a child. The doctor played by Jin Shijia tried his best to persuade them to give up this unrealistic fantasy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ae56084ac971137609b18630672fe173.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ae56084ac971137609b18630672fe173.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253159 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/7b6c0d45f3ccb981dd5b9330b0907713.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/7b6c0d45f3ccb981dd5b9330b0907713.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253157&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Proving your acting skills through disfigurement is a path to transformation that is usually chosen by heroes and goddesses. But while paying attention to the differences between actors on and off the screen, we also need to realize the film&#39;s focus on social issues. According to the director, the inspiration for the film came from the welfare home he visited. He wanted to present his mixed feelings to the audience, so that more people can hear the forgotten voices of the disadvantaged groups in society. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Trapped Beast&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director: Peng Fa&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Deng Andong/Wang Qian/Peng Fa&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Starring: Chung Han-leung/Francis Ng Chun-yu/Cheung Siu-fai/Myolie Wu/Zhao Yanguo-zhang&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Producing country/region: Mainland China/Hong Kong, China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;Release date: 2023-10-27 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 07/92caa33d628e6b4b38d0d39d145e6101.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/92caa33d628e6b4b38d0d39d145e6101.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to restore order in Hucheng, the government launched a thunderous operation to eradicate underground industries. Fourth Master &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhang Siu-fai) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Director Zuo of the Commercial Investigation Department &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Wu Zhenyu) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; secretly muddied the water. Trying to fight for management rights. Police Officer Jiang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhong Hanliang)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; led a team and started a black and white showdown with them. Myolie Wu and Zhao Yanguo Zhang also play important roles in the film, and we can see a group of veteran actors performing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e45ec8dddacc2a1f214a370bf963e4ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e45ec8dddacc2a1f214a370bf963e4ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253161 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2d69730a24d1cc138e7bb7d2fd8e24be.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2d69730a24d1cc138e7bb7d2fd8e24be.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253162&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Trapped&quot; is the most common crime genre film in Hong Kong. It is easy to make a living but not easy to produce a high-quality film. I wonder if director Peng Fa&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(&quot;Hell&quot; and &quot;Ten Ways to See Hell&quot;) who is an editor can be meticulous in his script and make a &quot;loan to support&quot; movie. The scale and intensity of &quot;Gamble, profit and swallow bones&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Second Hand Masterpiece&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Director: Wang Zizhao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Xu Luyang/Liu Xiaodan/Zi Zhao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Yu Hewei/Guo Qilin/Ni Hongjie/Xu Enyi/Zhang Zixian&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-10-27 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/96fbf1663ba435465ccff8eb02a3b2ae.jpeg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/96fbf1663ba435465ccff8eb02a3b2ae .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253165&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film is adapted from the American movie &quot;The Greatest Father in the World&quot;. It is a warm comedy with a rather absurd style. High school Chinese teacher Lao Ma (played by Yu Hewei) has reached middle age, but his literary ambitions have not yet been fulfilled. His son Xiao Ma&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Guo Qilin)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; fell down a building and &quot;committed suicide&quot;. Unexpectedly, the suicide note Lao Ma wrote for him to save face became famous overnight. Lao Ma began to pursue his dream in the literary world, using Xiao Ma&#39;s name to realize his self-worth step by step, but Xiao Ma&#39;s sudden awakening made the whole thing get out of hand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1362bbbbf00003905f01af70b99fce60.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1362bbbbf00003905f01af70b99fce60.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253164 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film is produced by Ning Hao and Yu Hewei and produced by Bad Monkey Pictures. Yu Hewei and Guo Qilin&#39;s comedy partnership is more eye-catching. Yu Hewei has demonstrated his skillful acting skills in films such as &quot;Above the Cliff&quot; and &quot;I&#39;m Not Pan Jinlian&quot;, and has also made a mark in dramas such as &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; and &quot;The Age of Awakening&quot;. With his classic image, he can be regarded as a top actor in the entertainment industry; Guo Qilin has attracted countless fans in variety shows and dramas with his lovable image, but his screen shaping ability remains to be seen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Director: Zhang Lu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Zhang Lu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Xin Baiqing/Huang Yao/Tian Zhuangzhuang/ Li Qinqin/Wang Hongwei&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-10- 27 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cbba5fa45c8752e7d6890f745a246d32.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cbba5fa45c8752e7d6890f745a246d32.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;253167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; is a literary drama film written by director Zhang Lu and tells the story of Gu Wentong, a middle-aged man who lives alone&lt;/span>;&lt; The story of span>; (played by Xin Baiqing)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and the young female photographer Ouyang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Huang Yao)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; met and got to know each other. Ambiguous feelings surged between the two, and they also re-examined the relationship between gender and parent-child. The film inherits Zhang Lu&#39;s consistent roaming style. He is good at photographing flowing spaces and capturing flowing emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a01a67d6e67658a9a06cdda0d3d2b942.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a01a67d6e67658a9a06cdda0d3d2b942.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253163 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Here, Director Zhang chose to work with Xin Baiqing, who had stunning performances in &quot;The Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; and &quot;The Long Goodbye&quot;, and Huang Yao, who had a stunning appearance in &quot;Over the Spring&quot; . &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; was shortlisted for the main competition of the Berlin Film Festival and won numerous awards at the Beijing International Film Festival. Audiences who like literary style should not miss it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f6043ccb6ef92433ad90b5ccabbe897d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f6043ccb6ef92433ad90b5ccabbe897d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253166 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The above are the new films we have selected for theaters in October, hoping to take over the summer vacation and ignite the film market in the second half of the year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;And which movie do you most want to go to the cinema to watch? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[张镇麟突破暴扣，中国男篮夺亚运铜牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258196]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Chinese men&#39;s basketball player Zhang Zhenlin broke through and singled out in the game Hand dunk.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/51777940be.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/51777940be.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253232&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Zhang Zhenlin broke through and dunked with one hand during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 6, 2023, the Hangzhou Asian Games men’s basketball bronze medal match was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Gymnasium. The Chinese men’s basketball team trailed the Chinese Taipei team by 3 points in the first half and finally won. Completed the reversal at 101:73 and won the bronze medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, two Chinese male basketball players defended Chinese Taipei team player Atino under the basket.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a86bb3bb82.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/07/a86bb3bb82.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253233&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 6, 2023, two Chinese male basketball players defend Chinese Taipei player Atino at the basket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese men’s basketball team and the Chinese Taipei team had a match in the group stage on September 28. At that time, the Chinese men’s basketball team won 89:69. In that game, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team took the initiative almost throughout the game and did not give their opponents many chances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Zhang Zhenlin was passing the ball.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/e879f8dc10.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e879f8dc10. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253234&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Zhang Zhenlin was passing the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Wang Zhelin stole the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/07/2e5de377ce.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2e5de377ce .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253235&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Wang Zhelin stole the ball during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the Chinese Taipei team again on October 6, the Chinese men’s basketball team sent out a starting lineup of Zhao Rui, Zhu Junlong, Cui Yongxi, Du Runwang, and Hu Jinqiu. But throughout the first half, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team seemed out of shape. Although Zhao Rui hit two three-pointers at the beginning and scored a total of 8 points, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team did not quickly widen the point difference and fell behind 21:29 in the first quarter. In the second quarter, the Chinese Taipei team&#39;s offensive success rate dropped, while the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team gradually closed in on the score with the three-pointers of Hu Mingxuan, Du Runwang and Zhao Rui. At the end of the first half, it was still 3 points behind 46:49. In the third quarter, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team accelerated the pace of switching offenses, taking more shots from inside and outside. After a 34:10 attack wave in a single quarter, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team led the Chinese Taipei team 80:59. In the fourth quarter of the game, both sides&#39; offensive efficiency on the court was not high. Zhang Zhenlin scored consecutively and showed off dunks, leading the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team to further expand its lead. The final score was fixed at 101:73, and the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team successfully won the Asian Games bronze medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Chinese men&#39;s basketball player Zhao Rui made a layup during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/07/d7f8bf600a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07 /d7f8bf600a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253236&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Zhao Rui competed Mid-range layup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Chinese men&#39;s basketball captain Zhao Jiwei made a layup during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/925390d346.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ 925390d346.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253237&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, the Chinese men’s basketball team captain Zhao Jiwei played during the game basket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the performance of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team at the Asian Games did not meet expectations, especially in the semi-finals when it led by 18 points at halftime and collapsed in the final quarter, losing to the Philippines by 1 point. In this crucial battle, the failure to achieve the pre-match goal will have a huge impact on the entire Chinese basketball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, after the game, Chinese men&#39;s basketball players hugged Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2706b7987e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/07/2706b7987e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253238&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 6, 2023 After the game, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball players hugged Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese men’s basketball coach Djordjevic said after the semifinals: “What the Chinese team needs to do most now is to unite together, come out with heads held high in the next game, and strive for victory. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, after the awards ceremony, Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team, came to the men&#39;s basketball players and offered words of encouragement.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/30a055e785.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/30a055e785.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On October 6, 2023, after the awards ceremony, Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team, came to the men&#39;s basketball players and offered words of encouragement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, in the men&#39;s gold medal game of basketball at the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Philippine team defeated the Jordanian team 70-60 and won the championship. Players of the Philippine team at the award ceremony Wave.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8ff1697e5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8ff1697e5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, in the men&#39;s gold medal match of basketball at the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Philippines team defeated the Jordan team 70-60 and won the championship. Players of the Philippine team wave during the award ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics, from 1974 to 2018, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team participated in 12 Asian Games and won 8 golds, 2 silvers and 1 bronze. The worst result was fifth place in 2014. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, after the game, Chinese men&#39;s basketball players circled the court and high-fived the audience to thank them.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3f92f1a93c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/07/3f92f1a93c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 6, 2023 After the game, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball players circled the court and high-fived the audience to thank them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这两年，奢侈品销量为何逆势上升？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258122]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The global luxury goods market will further recover in 2022, achieving a year-on-year growth of 17%, with the market size reaching 2.545 billion yuan. In China, luxury goods sales reached 956 billion yuan, accounting for 38% of the global luxury goods market. Chinese people are still the most important force in global luxury goods consumption. According to the international consulting firm Bain &amp; Company, the personal luxury goods market is expected to grow by 5%-12% in 2023, which is another peak after the record growth in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why the global economy is slowing down, but the consumption of luxury goods is not affected at all, and even grows against the trend. This is an interesting question. Moreover, some luxury brands have bucked the trend and raised prices to maintain the competitiveness of their brands. For example, LVMH, Hermès, and Kering Group have all raised prices in the past three years. Among them, LVMH has raised prices more than five times from 2019 to March 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this phenomenon, American economist Veblen proposed a concept called &quot;conspicuous consumption.&quot; He believes that to obtain and maintain a lasting sense of glory, it is not enough to have money; you must also let others know that you have money. Therefore, the main purpose of conspicuous consumption is not the product itself, but to use this consumption to distinguish oneself from others. For example, if you want to wear a particularly expensive watch, it is obviously not just to tell the time, but also to show off to others and demonstrate your economic status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For luxury goods, it happens to have such a show-off function. Many times, luxury goods are the buyer’s proof of wealth. At the same time, rising prices make fewer people able to afford it, and those who can afford it feel more superior. This is a bit like the mentality we had when we were young: &quot;I can&#39;t live without what others have.&quot; But when we grow up, this mentality becomes &quot;I don&#39;t want what others have.&quot; I must maintain a certain sense of superiority and cannot let myself be reduced to The level of those people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So what we see is that the higher the price of some luxury goods, the more popular they become, because at this time the higher the functions they show off, the stronger the isolation effect. In 2022, Rolls-Royce only delivered a total of 6,021 cars in about 50 countries around the world. This is the first time in the 118-year history of the Rolls-Royce brand that sales have exceeded 6,000 vehicles. But with this sales volume, they have never worried about survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to conspicuousness, luxury goods have several other characteristics. It will place special emphasis on scarcity, such as emphasizing that it is a limited edition, emphasizing the use of precious and scarce materials, or emphasizing the complexity of craftsmanship such as pure handcrafting. In addition, luxury goods also have social attributes and are imitable. People who own the same luxury goods are more likely to recognize each other and form a circle. People are also happy to imitate the lifestyle of people of a higher class than themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consumption of luxury goods is not only an economic issue, but also a social issue. The so-called luxury brand is a modern concept, but luxury goods themselves are not exclusive to modern people. Even in primitive societies or today&#39;s primitive tribes in the Amazon rainforest, their leaders will be different from other people in their clothing. These clothing decorations are symbols of their status and power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time in human history, luxury goods were mainly linked to power rather than wealth. The &quot;etiquette&quot; of Confucianism is a direct reflection. There are clear regulations on what clothes, clothes and etiquette should be worn by monarchs and ministers, fathers and sons, and different social classes. All must follow the rules without chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only in modern times, with the process of industrialization and the prosperity of material production, the social form has generally shifted from a power society to a market society. The level of consumption is gradually decoupled from power and linked to the level of wealth. The role of luxury goods has gradually changed from a symbol of power to a symbol of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, luxury goods have always shown their top-down characteristics. It can be said that they have always been at the top of the aesthetic order, defined and spread by the upper class of society. In societies where the original power order was stronger, this power of definition came from the top of the hierarchy. In modern society, this aesthetic definition also comes from the top, but it is more reflected in the conceptual design of companies or designers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entrepreneurs continue to explore people&#39;s deeper, richer and more diverse needs, and then the market forms differentiation in the process of continuous stratification. At the top are today&#39;s many luxury brands. Luxury cars, watches, diamonds and jade, luxury brand clothes, shoes, cosmetics, everything is available. The difference in personality and identity is highlighted through the brand and tone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rich or powerful label themselves through luxury goods. They can neither escape from this circle nor allow others to enter it casually, so as to maintain their social status. Therefore, even if the price of luxury goods increases, as long as it is within their affordability, they will show no mercy or blink an eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the formation of this luxury culture has also satisfied the fantasies of some ordinary people, who mistakenly believe that owning a brand-name bag and high-end clothes will truly enter that class. At this time, luxury goods become a prop for one class to get closer to another class. Sometimes this prop is useful, but many times it has little effect and is just a deliberately guided high consumption demand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all know that to make a lie, you need to create a complete set, and one lie needs to be completed by another hundred lies. Similarly, if you are wearing a brand-name bag, the rest of your outfit should not be too shabby; and if you are wearing a brand-name outfit, your car should not be too ordinary. When these things are added up, if you don&#39;t really have a certain amount of financial resources, you may really be trying to make a fool of yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Young people need to be careful of this carefully constructed illusion and not be led by the luxury culture. Many times, just because you own a brand-name bag, others will definitely look up to you. These things may be helpful in establishing a first impression, but what is more important is the true strength of the person behind the bag. When masters compete with each other, they may be able to understand the depth of the opponent in just a few words, and they will not be easily confused by external things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, any individual, like any social and economic entity, must go through the stages of savings and investment if a society wants to develop its economy. If a young person wants to achieve himself and reach a higher platform, he often needs to save and invest in himself to prepare for success. As a luxury product, designer bags can be used as a means, but they should not be the ultimate goal and goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育的基础，在于如何理解“人”丨议教]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258210]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/AsoQGwZYVctwwR0mp5ZTs1EoJZsltI3cB1m4DK4e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;906&quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/AsoQGwZYVctwwR0mp5ZTs1EoJZs ltI3cB1m4DK4e. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 6, 2023, Lushan Township Central Primary School, Changxing County, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, Students are playing hide and seek. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of his work in educational media, he is an education scholar living in the United States and the Department of Asian/Asian-American Studies at the University of Miami. I read the article by former director Huang Quanyu from 2014 to 2023, and I still have different feelings from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Education&quot; actually has very complex dimensions. If you touch on education issues from different dimensions, you will have a completely different way of looking at education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The educational media I first worked on was a type of educational media that discussed educational topics for parents. My confusion or reflection on education at that time came entirely from a parent’s perspective: Why do children suffer in education? Why are parents so anxious? If education is about easing the panic of &quot;not being eliminated&quot; through self-repression and constant hard work in a long countercurrent, then when this road ends, what kind of people will our children grow into? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a position, Huang Quanyu&#39;s article opened a window for me: Maybe there is an educational paradigm that advocates children&#39;s freedom, happiness, and disorganization, but it also has good results, and this This relationship between freedom and achievement is not &quot;accidental&quot;, but has an educational connotation that is completely different from our understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first &quot;reading&quot; of his article for me: education has different perspectives. Then comes the second dimension - can we learn it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We did learn a lot of new concepts, such as STEM, PBL project-based learning, interdisciplinary, big concepts, metacognition, inquiry-based learning, etc. With the influx of these new concepts, I myself have also gone through some transformations, from media for parents to professional media for education policy research, school organization or strategic research, because I am really curious about the issues that parents complain and question. , what does the school think? Amid the vortex of concepts trying to “optimize” education, what exactly are schools doing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as I stepped into the professional field, I soon discovered that schools may be more helpless and innocent than parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Schools today are indeed in a dilemma. On the one hand, quality education has been promoted for decades, and in the past two or three years, it has evolved into &quot;literacy&quot; education: In April 2022, the country released new curriculum standards for compulsory education. The description and requirements for students&#39; literacy are basically in line with the world&#39;s most leading educational concepts. consistent. In other words, whether at the level of educational ideals or the implementation of educational policies, our education seems to be moving closer to the scene he described. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem is &quot;on the other hand&quot;. Our school education requires examinations at every node. The exam itself is not a problem, but the result of the exam is a ticket, which determines which door a child will enter next and which path he will take. Perhaps for the post-95s and post-00s, the meaning of &quot;doors and roads&quot; no longer has the fate-determining meaning of the post-70s and post-80s, but an inertial social mentality does not think so, but instead gives the exam a more important meaning. Stereotype meaning: educate in order to get high marks, study in order not to lose points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Are literacy and examination contradictory? This is actually a difficult question to figure out. Doesn’t the development of literacy require the evaluation of staged results or examinations? no. Huang Quanyu made it clear in his article that he was not against exams, but against &quot;examination-oriented thinking.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the exam is just an academic assessment, it is like a questionnaire sent out by the students themselves. Take it back to see where they still need to work hard and where they need help to solve problems. . Test-oriented thinking is actually a kind of judgmental thinking. It is issued by teachers, parents, schools, society... in short, everyone except the students themselves, and then decides whether you are a successful student or a failed student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an organization composed of education professionals, the school does not understand the contradiction between literacy learning and test-oriented thinking, but the problem is that the school must also do a test question that is not issued by itself, such as this A typical question: &quot;Can your project-based learning (or quality education, interdisciplinary learning, etc.) make students achieve better results?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This question seems quite reasonable, right? In fact, this problem is enough to knock down a school that has ideals and sentiments and hopes to make some educational reforms. Because once exams, scores, and grades become the criteria for &quot;literacy,&quot; the calm, patient, supportive, and accepting educational mentality that &quot;raises&quot; students will be wiped out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The test-oriented thinking that pursues results essentially requires some &quot;anti-human&quot; exercises, such as mechanized accuracy and high-density time management, all of which require this kind of exercise. Literacy requires an ecology that respects the rhythm of children&#39;s growth. It may seem like doing nothing for a long time, but growth will eventually move toward &quot;natural maturity.&quot; However, entrance exams can cut off the natural rhythm at any time. Countless examples tell us that in the search for certainty, the child&#39;s nature and will have become the most easily ignored link. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the matter of educational involution, the pros and cons are easy to see clearly, but the difficult part is the choice.对，孩子很苦，但孩子上了985；或是“你们都&#39;素质&#39;去吧，留我家孩子悄悄刷题”；学校也是一样，“家长只认升学率，所以升学率就是王道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育的症结，正如黄全愈在谈STEM教育的文章中提到的，“中国教育当前要解决的是素质教育的底色问题，而不是STEM 的具体课程问题”，更不是各种教育概念“加加减减”的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不断反思教育，最终就难免要接近一个终极问题：教育的意义到底是什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果教育是为了让少数孩子出人头地，那我们会迎来一个什么样的社会？如果教育是为了一种社会整体的向善与福祉，那么这样道德理想式的教育，对“我家的孩子”又有什么好处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为工作领域，我会看到各种各样的教育文章，看多了发现，教育本身存在一种个体与社会的张力。如果你只关注家长立场，看输赢，算得失，“制造焦虑”会是必然结局；而如果只站在专家、学者立场，看理论的推演、教学法的介绍，概念往往不接地气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《教育的基础》这本书中，有一句话让我特别有感触：“我们一方面说世界的未来属于孩子，但另一方面，世界却不属于孩子。”为什么这么说？因为我们的教育往往是凭着成年人的策略与计量、想象与设计，去规定孩子的动作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最近跟一些专家、校长聊到“拔尖创新人才培养”的话题，这也是接下来的国家人才战略。那么拔尖创新人才培养，会不会成为学校的任务、学生的试题？很有可能。会不会成为新一轮家长焦虑的靶点？也很有可能。那如何避免这种情况发生，而且能在一种积极的环境中实现拔尖创新人才培养呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄全愈写得明白：“创造性不是技能，而是潜伏在人的生理和心理层面的特质，教不出来，更遑论训练！”“只有当科学思维盘活科学知识时，知识才是力量。从这个意义上说，&#39;减负&#39;就是要培养科学思维，去减轻长辈的权威和人为的标准给孩子的负担，把死知识激活为青春洋溢的创新动力。”“孩子的智慧不是用来重复别人，而是用来创造自己的！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些金句散落在书中。创新本质上是一种破局，破除现有格局去探索未知世界，创新能力不可教，但可以培养，培养方式恰恰是创造环境，让老师“少教”，让孩子探索，然后“多悟”，从碎片化的多悟，变成系统化的认知，形成个性化的判断，最终是创造性的行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育不是非要逼自己的孩子站在某个不属于自己的潮头。这可以看作这本书的第三种“读法”——从教育中领悟人的价值。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作者系《看教育EnsightEdu》主编&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[让纳米技术拥有绚丽色彩——透视2023年诺贝尔化学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258218]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/FQYbemG8URIyG2yv7slZL84HQntDr Xd8lGABUf3o. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 4, 2023 local time, Stockholm, Sweden, announced the 2023 2023 When he won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry, he used flasks in the laboratory to explain. French-born Mongi Bavandi, American Louis Bruce and Russian-born Alexey Yerkimov were awarded the Nobel Prize in Chemistry on Wednesday for their research on tiny particles known as quantum dots . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 4, 2023, Beijing time, the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences announced that the 2023 Nobel Prize in Chemistry Awarded to Moungi G. Bawendi of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Louis E. Brus&amp;nbsp; of Columbia University, and Alexei Ikimo of the Nanocrystal Technology Company of the United States. Alexei I. Ekimov for their contributions to the discovery and synthesis of quantum dots. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What are quantum dots? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Quantum dots, also known as semiconductor nanocrystals, are semiconductor crystal particles composed of thousands of atoms that are generally less than 20 nanometers in size. Quantum dots have a specific three-dimensional structure, usually spherical or ellipsoidal. Generally, quantum dots are composed of a &quot;core&quot; made of semiconductor materials such as cadmium selenium or lead sulfide; sometimes the core of the quantum dot is wrapped by another material to form a &quot;shell&quot; ” to improve its optical and electronic properties. Quantum dots are one of the smallest building blocks in nanotechnology. Generally speaking, the properties of an element depend on how many electrons it has. Quantum phenomena appear when matter shrinks to the nanometer scale. This means that the properties of an element will be determined by the size of the substance, not by the number of electrons it possesses. Comprised of just a thousand atoms, a quantum dot is to a football what a football is to the Earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1937, physicist Herbert Froehlich predicted that once particles were small enough (so-called nanoparticles), they would be affected by the strange magic of quantum mechanics. . To explain this quantum phenomenon, Judith Giordan, president of the American Chemical Society, told AFP, &quot;Think of it as a small box. When the particle shrinks small enough, the electrons will hit the sides of the box. .&quot; In a larger box, electrons hit the sides less frequently, which means they have less energy. For quantum dots, the larger box emits red light, while the smaller box emits blue light. That means by controlling the size of the particles, scientists can turn their crystals into red, blue and any color in between. But it would be 40 years after Froelich predicted it before anyone could actually observe the phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The great discovery of ultra-small particles&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Quantum dots are a new type of material different from molecules. Due to the effect of quantum mechanics, as long as these nanoparticles are adjusted Their size can change their properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1937, physicists speculated that size-related quantum effects might occur in nanoparticles. At the time, however, it seemed impossible to recreate this effect in the real world. To do this, researchers need a perfect crystalline material, and they need to control the size of the nanomaterial very precisely, sculpting it layer by layer, so few believe this research is possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the early 1980s Ikimov and Bruce respectively proved that it could be done. Ikimov created a size-dependent quantum effect in colored glass. By changing the temperature and heating time of the molten glass, he found that he could change the size of the resulting particles. The smaller the particles, the bluer the light they emitted. This colorful experiment allowed Ikimov to successfully achieve size-dependent quantum effects in colored glass. His experimental results proved that the size of nanoparticles can control the properties of materials through quantum effects, laying the foundation for subsequent research and applications. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about the same time, Bruce became the first to discover this colorful quantum effect in liquid solutions, demonstrating the size and color of nanoparticles floating freely in solutions and gaseous compounds. the relationship between. These findings have sparked intense interest in how these tiny dots can be exploited for a variety of applications. Bruce also became the first scientist to demonstrate that free-floating nanoparticles have size-dependent quantum effects. His research provides important experimental evidence for understanding and exploiting the quantum properties of nanoparticles and advances the development of nanotechnology. His work has broad application prospects in fields such as electronics, optics and biomedicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for quantum dots to be truly useful, you need to be able to make them in solution and precisely control their size. In 1993, Bawendi revolutionized the chemical production of quantum dots in his lab at MIT. He developed a method to precisely control the rate at which crystals grow in solution and figured out how to stop the crystals when they reached the desired size. He first injected chemical reagents into the solution to instantly form tiny crystals, and then quickly adjusted the temperature of the solution to prevent their growth. Bawendi revolutionized the chemical production of quantum dots, which greatly improved their quality and paved the way for their use in a variety of applications. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Wide application prospects&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Quantum dots are a representative material of the &quot;size effect&quot; of nanomaterials. They are used in more and more fields. It has been applied more widely and deeply, from optoelectronic devices to photocatalysis to biological detection, almost covering people&#39;s current and future daily life needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quantum dots are now glowing in computer monitors and television screens based on quantum light-emitting diode technology. They also add nuance to the light of some LED lights, and are used by biochemists and doctors to map biological tissue. Quantum dots, for example, make it possible to change the color of LED lights very precisely and significantly increase their efficiency. The glowing fluorescent dots are injected into the body and attach to immune cells that aggregate into cancerous tissue, helping surgeons distinguish tumors that are even hard to see. Tuning the ability to absorb different wavelengths of light could also create customized solar cells that are highly efficient in different situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quantum dots have brought huge benefits to mankind. In the future, they could contribute to flexible electronics, tiny sensors, thinner solar cells and encrypted quantum communications, so we&#39;re just beginning to explore the potential of these tiny particles. Through the selection and issuance of the 2023 Nobel Prize in Chemistry, we can find that the Nobel Prize Committee not only pays attention to past contributions, but also pays attention to the possible impact of a discovery on the future. The ability to modulate nanoparticles by changing their size or surface properties could lead to a variety of as yet unexplored possibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原党组副书记、副主任殷美根被“双开”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258198]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission reviewed the former deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress , Deputy Director Yin Meigan conducted a case review and investigation on serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Yin Meigan lost her ideals and beliefs, deviated from party principles, had no sense of discipline and law, resisted organizational review, and engaged in superstitious activities; ignored the spirit of the eight central regulations, accepted gifts and money in violation of regulations, and entered and exited Private clubs; failing to report personal matters as required, failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing interviews and correspondence; borrowing money and housing from management and service recipients, being morally corrupt, and engaging in power, sex, and money transactions; violating regulations and intervening in market economic activities. and disciplinary and law enforcement activities; neglecting the education of spouses and children; forming a community of interests with unscrupulous businessmen, collaborating with relatives to engage in power and money transactions, taking advantage of the convenience of one&#39;s position to seek benefits for others in job promotions, project contracting, etc., and illegally accepting Huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yin Meigan seriously violated the party’s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and suspected of bribery crime, and did not restrain or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. , is serious in nature and has a bad impact, and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and submitted to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to give Yin Meigan the sanction of expulsion from the party; by The National Supervisory Commission dismissed him from public office; terminated his qualifications as a representative of the 15th Jiangxi Provincial Party Congress; confiscated his illegal income; and transferred his suspected criminal issues to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved was also transferred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[自由的健康的创作，很好丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/RobfInKocHxEIOn9ssnq6HH5c1iM3ScZWgn2EAlE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;176&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/RobfInKocHxEIOn9ssnq6HH5c1iM3ScZWgn2EAlE . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www. infzm.com/content/257431&quot; title=&quot;Director Wang Mu and his &quot;gentle shell&quot;&quot;>;Director Wang Mu and his &quot;gentle shell&quot;&lt;/a>;》)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interviewed young directors Wang Mushi repeatedly mentioned that he was not a professional screenwriter before - from the time he quit the drama circle in 2010 until he wanted to make his own movie in 2018, he was a film and TV screenwriter. He doesn&#39;t like revising drafts or attending meetings, and he doesn&#39;t endorse or talk about the discourse system that may be a mixture of film screenwriting reference book theory and Internet platform &quot;playing methods.&quot; He didn’t even meet the actors, go to the set, or compare the differences between his script and the final product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a writer, I really empathize with his approach: he only does what he wants to do, and doesn’t do anything he doesn’t want to do; at the same time, I feel that he can live in a small world with his own rules. , how difficult it is to make money, and how lucky it is at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While doing an interview with Director Li Xiaofeng for this topic (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;he has collaborated with Wang Mu several times&lt;/span>; ), I envy that kind of atmosphere even more. Everyone has a consensus on the concept of creation and trusts each other&#39;s personality and talents. This is the basis. On top of this, Li Xiaofeng gave a popular description, &quot;Whoever holds the knife eats the meat.&quot; Whoever writes this draft Write with your own characteristics. We don&#39;t need to be screwed together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng said that creative freedom is particularly important. It may be unstable, but it can ensure physical and mental health. I can understand what Li Xiaofeng means by &quot;unstable&quot;. &quot;Girl Nezha&quot; and &quot;Rebirth from the Ashes&quot;, which he directed and Wang Mu co-wrote, did not receive particularly high Douban ratings, but I liked them very much. Fully respect everyone&#39;s opinions and creative temperament. The effect may not be good enough, but the participants will definitely feel comfortable and some viewers will also enjoy watching it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Mu and Li Xiaofeng collaborated once more. The script &quot;Hypnotized by Water&quot; written by Wang Mu won a screenplay award at the Busan International Film Festival, but was not filmed due to lack of funds. But of course, success is not the most important, at least not the only valid criterion. At this point, I think their creations have returned to the essence of creation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interview with Wang Mu did not go as smoothly as I expected. He is not a cinephile director, and I am a layman in theater. When interviewing him himself, after several back and forths, I still couldn’t fully understand what it meant that drama held far more weight in his heart than movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peripheral interviews helped me. Li Xiaofeng said that Wang Mu is a serious creator. He likes Chekhov. His novel writing style is very static. There is a bust of Lu Xun in his home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng also talked about their first collaboration on the script for &quot;Rebirth from the Ashes&quot;. In this play, people in the 2010s have to look back to the 1990s, when ethical relationships changed dramatically and shocks occurred in people&#39;s hearts. The script was previously called &quot;Chasing&quot;, and there were already seven drafts when Wang Mu joined. Xu Feng and Li Xiaofeng, one of the protagonists, have imagined several identities, including repair shop workers, postmen, etc. Wang Mu changed Xu Feng&#39;s occupation to worker. Li Xiaofeng immediately felt that it was accurate, &quot;That movie actually contains a lot of thinking about social forms. Wang Mu wrote Xu Feng as a young man who was greatly affected by family and social changes, and he was also very innocent. He made Xu Feng&#39;s purity and ours The emotions for the working class are unified.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think of &quot;The Tender Shell&quot; again. Wang Mu looked for image references for the young male and female protagonists who were traumatized and redeemed each other. Dai Chun was Peter Sheff. Allen in &quot;Ikus&quot;, Juexiao is Antigone in the Greek myth written by Sophocles. Li Xiaofeng said that when he watched &quot;The Gentle Shell&quot;, he felt that &quot;there is a little bit of stagnation. The characters in Wang Mu&#39;s works have a relatively high quality and density of souls.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that I think about it, as the first work of a young director, it has no popular stars and does not have endless road shows like the movies in the past few months. It can get more than 12 million at the box office, which is pretty good. I hope that good works can be seen by more people, good directors can go further, and free creation can demonstrate its value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国银行原党委书记、董事长刘连舸严重违纪违法被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258200]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:21:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;830&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission investigated the former Party Secretary and Chairman of Bank of China Co., Ltd. Liu Liange&#39;s serious violations of discipline and law were investigated and investigated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, Liu Liange lost his ideals and convictions, abandoned his original mission, was not firm or compromised in implementing the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, abandoned his financial risk prevention and control responsibilities, and interfered in credit projects in violation of regulations. Illegal granting of loans, resulting in major financial risks, failure to fulfill the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, seriously damaging the political ecology of the unit, illegally bringing prohibited books and periodicals into the country, and deliberately trying to resist organizational censorship; ignoring the spirit of the eight central regulations, illegally accepting gifts, entering and exiting Private clubs, accepting skiing and travel arrangements, long-term borrowing of vehicles subject to management; failing to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing inquiries, hiring, adjusting and promoting cadres for personal gain; running businesses in violation of regulations; intervening in fund lending and illegally Keep confidential information; have bad morals, have bad family traditions, and neglect their relatives; have no bottom line in discipline and law, act arbitrarily, &quot;rely on finance to eat finance&quot;, and use their position to benefit others in terms of loan financing, project cooperation, etc. , and illegally received huge amounts of property. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu Liange seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of accepting bribes and illegally granting loans. They did not restrain themselves or hold back after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. They are serious in nature and have bad influence, and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishments of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and submitted to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Liu Liange from the party; according to It stipulates that the benefits he enjoys will be cancelled; his qualifications as a representative of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China will be terminated; his illegal gains that violate disciplines and laws will be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues will be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved will be transferred together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>