<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[澳门街坊的横琴生活：粤澳合作区两周年记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdw CKSbR0bN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251169&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn, accompanied by the crisp prompts when passengers cleared customs, the new passenger inspection building standing at Hengqin Port once again ushered in a busy moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every day, about 12,000 Hong Kong and Macao residents travel between Hengqin and Macao through the Hengqin Port. Macao resident Huang Huixia is one of them. Almost two years ago, she moved to the Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone in Hengqin and became a &quot;new Hengqin native&quot;; now, she lives in Hengqin and returns to Macau three or four times a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The transportation is more convenient, the house is more spacious, the living environment is more comfortable, the community services are better, and more and more Macao people come to the cooperation zone...” Talking about the two projects in Hengqin Huang Huixia has a treasure trove of her life experiences over the years. In the future, as the Macau light rail extension Hengqin Line project comes into use, the transportation from Hengqin to Macau will become more convenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 5, 2021, the &quot;Overall Plan for the Construction of the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot;) was issued, giving Hengqin &quot;a new platform to promote the moderately diversified development of Macao&#39;s economy&quot; It has four major strategic missions: &quot;a new space to facilitate the life and employment of Macao residents&quot;, &quot;a new demonstration to enrich the practice of &#39;one country, two systems&#39;&quot; and &quot;a new highland to promote the construction of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area&quot;. Twelve days later, the management agency of the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone was officially unveiled, and the construction of the cooperation zone has entered the &quot;fast lane&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the issuance of the &quot;Hengqin Master Development Plan&quot; in 2009, the country has successively introduced a series of innovative policies to draw a bright blueprint for the development of Hengqin.&quot; Dean of the Institute of Regional Opening and Cooperation at Sun Yat-sen University Mao Yanhua told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone has multiple advantages such as superior location conditions, solid cooperation foundation, and strong support. The current development momentum is strong, and the future will definitely be more promising.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;&lt;strong>;Macao Neighbors in Hengqin&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“My original house in Macao was very small, only about 60 square meters. After moving to Hengqin, the living area suddenly increased. 150 square meters.&quot; After two years of moving to Hengqin, Huang Huixia has the most vivid feelings about the changes in Hengqin&#39;s living environment, transportation conditions, community services, medical care, and customs clearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early autumn, the water of Tianmu River is shining, with green trees and lush vegetation on both sides. Strolling along the 7.2-kilometer-long ecological corridor along the river, rhythmic urban waterfront landscape belts such as ecological community areas and park-like communities gradually unfold, and across the water are the Macau Tower and the Grand Lisboa Tower. , MGM Hotel and other Macau landmark buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Huixia moved to Hengqin Shangcun from Macau two years ago, where 60% of the residents are Macau residents. Shangcun is only about ten minutes&#39; walk from Tianmu River. In her free time every day, she would go for a walk by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Huixia still clearly remembers the situation when she first moved to Hengqin. At that time, due to insufficient flow of people and few bus lines, it took a long time to go back to Macau. &quot;Now I travel to and from Macau three or four times a week. There are several buses to Hengqin Port after leaving the community.&quot; Huang Huixia told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hengqin Port is located on the west bank of the Cross Gate Waterway on Hengqin Island and is connected to the Macau Bridge. It is at the intersection of &quot;one country, two systems&quot; and the junction of &quot;internal and external radiation&quot;. At present, Hengqin Port has achieved &quot;cooperative inspection and one-time release&quot;. Entry-exit personnel only need to &quot;stand in the same hall, line up once, and undergo inspection once&quot; to complete the entry-exit procedures for both the mainland and Macao. The average customs clearance time per person is only 30 About seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customs clearance time has been greatly shortened and the process has been optimized, allowing Macao residents traveling between the two places to live a more comfortable life in the twin cities. Huang Huixia clearly feels that more and more Macao residents are passing through customs and entering the cooperation zone every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics, there are currently more than 7,000 Macao residents settling and working in Hengqin. The average daily passenger flow of Hong Kong and Macao residents entering and exiting through Hengqin Port will increase from more than 5,900 in 2022 to nearly 1.2 in 2023. Thousands of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to major improvements in the living environment, daily life and transportation conditions, the elderly care, medical and community services in the Hengqin Cooperation Zone are also constantly moving closer to Macau standards. In 2019, the Macau Federation of Neighborhood Associations set up a service center in Hengqin and formed a professional service team to provide Macau-standard home care home care services for seniors aged 60 and over in the cooperation zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As of the end of August 2023, we have provided services to more than 960,000 residents in Qinzhou and Macao.” A person in charge of the Macau Neighborhood Association told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to the continued advancement of the cross-border practice policy, there are currently a total of 67 short-term medical practitioners from Hong Kong and Macao practicing in Hengqin. &quot;New Hengqin residents&quot; including Huang Huixia can seek medical treatment from familiar Macao doctors without leaving the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We can participate in local insurance in Hengqin and enjoy the same medical insurance treatment as Zhuhai citizens. It is very convenient to buy medicines and see doctors, and the personal expenses are not high.” Huang Huixia said, “Follow-up’ Macao New After the completion of the Neighborhood project, a Macau medical team will be stationed and a large medical service center will be equipped, making life more convenient in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Macau New Neighborhood&quot; mentioned by Huang Huixia is a cooperation area The first comprehensive livelihood project for Macao residents, it will be equipped with various Macao standard public services and social welfare, and will create a high-quality and livable community for more than 10,000 Macao residents. Currently, the project has entered the acceptance stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Life in the cooperation zone will definitely get better and better in the future.” Huang Huixia told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Four New Industries&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Taking advantage of the rapid development of the Hengqin Cooperation Zone, Wang Ruiming came to Hengqin to seek development. In the past few months, he acquired an Australian-funded company and plans to establish a new company, mainly engaged in the financial and Internet industries, which is expected to be officially opened at the end of September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because he is engaged in the financial industry supported by the cooperation zone, his company can enjoy a 15% tax preferential policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ruiming is a &quot;third generation overseas Chinese&quot;. In recent years, attracted by the business policies and environment of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, he has been actively deploying in the Bay Area and has registered financial companies in Hong Kong and Shenzhen, focusing on funds, trusts, insurance and other businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Hengqin’s financial industry is highly open and cross-border capital flows freely. It is the most active area for cross-border RMB settlement. Many Fortune 500 companies have settled here. It is very promising to become China’s financial industry in the future. A new highland for opening up to the outside world.&quot; Wang Ruiming told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, the added value of the financial industry in the cooperation zone reached 8.8 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 40% of &lt;span>;GDP&lt;/span>;, with a year-on-year growth of 2.9%, showing a trend of accelerating agglomeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The cooperation zone has made solid progress around the &#39;Four New Industries&#39;. Not only has the industry positioning become clearer, but a system and mechanism for consultation, construction, management and sharing has also been initially established.&quot; Mao Yanhua pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Macao has a small land but a large population. There are more than 680,000 people living in less than 33 square kilometers of land, with an average of more than 20,000 people per square kilometer. It is one of the cities with the highest population density in the world. Problems such as insufficient land resources and a single industrial structure have always plagued Macao&#39;s development. Hengqin, across the water from Macau, covers an area of ​​106 square kilometers and has significant spatial advantages, providing sufficient space to support the diversified development of Macau&#39;s economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 2009, the State Council approved the implementation of the &quot;Hengqin Master Development Plan&quot;, clearly stating that Hengqin should be used as a carrier to jointly create a cross-border cooperation innovation zone, in order to gradually change the economic structure of Macao. Single questions provide new space. With the gradual advancement of high-quality development in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and the introduction of the &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot;, the integration of Hengqin and Macao has reached a new level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the beginning of development, Hengqin has been given the mission of serving the diversified economic development of Macao. In more than ten years of development and construction, this mission has not only remained unchanged, but has become more prominent.&quot; Mao Yanhua pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its inauguration and operation, the Hengqin Cooperation Zone has focused on the &quot;four new&quot; strategic positioning and vigorously developed the &quot;four major&quot; technological research and development and high-end manufacturing, Macao brand industries such as traditional Chinese medicine, culture, tourism, exhibition and trade, and modern financial industries. Industry&quot; and launched a series of new policies targeting the integrated circuit industry, financial industry, cultural tourism and exhibition industry, etc. In the past two years, a number of key projects have been accelerated, and the integrated development pattern of Macao and Macao has been initially established. The supporting role in promoting the moderately diversified development of Macao&#39;s economy is gradually emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023 alone, there will be more than 40 integrated circuit companies actually operating in the cooperation zone, initially forming an integrated circuit design industry ecosystem covering intellectual property (IP), third-generation semiconductors and other fields; Guangdong The Australian Cooperative Traditional Chinese Medicine Science and Technology Industrial Park contributed nearly 80 million yuan in corporate tax revenue in the first quarter, a year-on-year increase of 59%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With industrial agglomeration and policy dividends, the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone has become a new platform and new highland for Australian people and enterprises to invest and start businesses. Currently, there are more than 5,600 Australian-funded enterprises in the cooperation zone, an increase of 22.3% compared with before the cooperation zone was established, and the registered capital exceeds 148 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot; opens a new chapter in the construction of Guangdong-Macao in-depth cooperation zone.&quot; Mao Yanhua said, &quot;The construction of the future cooperation zone should continue to focus on the original intention of serving the diversified development of Macao industries, starting from building first-class industries Starting from the functional park, we will vigorously develop the real economy, make good use of the innovative system, and further attract the full flow and agglomeration of factors inside and outside the park, thereby creating a new growth pole for high-quality development on the west bank of the Pearl River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Italics , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Huang Huixia and Wang Ruiming are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[接连停运，有轨电车真的没“出路”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256990]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rS zHzGpQrZ3O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2019, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram in operation was nicknamed &quot; Dangdang car”. In June 2023, Zhangjiang trams will be suspended. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retro, good-looking, fresh... City trams once had such Internet celebrities label, but in the past few months, news of tram outages have appeared frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, an announcement circulated on the Internet stating that due to difficulties in operating funds, modern trams in Honghe Prefecture, Yunnan will cease operations on August 10, 2023. On August 11, the chairman of Honghe Prefecture Modern Tram Co., Ltd. responded that the announcement was false news. At present, the local tram has not been suspended and is operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the Tianjin Development Zone Guide Tram Line 1, which had been in operation for 16 years, announced that it would cease operation and started procurement of demolition projects. In June, Shanghai Zhangjiang Tram No. 1, which had been in operation for 13 years, was suspended and the tracks were quickly dismantled. Two years ago, in 2021, the trams in Zhuhai, Guangdong, were suspended and planned to be dismantled after more than three years of operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram was out of service, and workers were dismantling the track. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Shijun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, 3 of the 39 rail lines across the country have been suspended. According to the &quot;Urban Rail Transit 2022 Annual Statistics and Analysis Report&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Report&quot;) released by the China Urban Rail Transit Association, as of the end of 2022, a total of 39 tram lines in 23 cities across the country have been put into operation, with an operating mileage of 578.3 kilometers. , equivalent to half the distance from Beijing to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The primary reason for the suspension of operations is low passenger flow. This is not the first time such news has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2015, after the opening of the Chengdu Tram Chengdu Tram Line 2&#39;s first section, the line was not connected to the urban rail transit network and the passenger flow was low, which led to great pressure from public opinion and suffered &quot;some problems&quot;. &quot;Trams are useless&quot; controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are trams frequently suspended? How to avoid the &quot;chair transport&quot; situation? Compared with subways with large passenger flows, trams are &quot;urban rail transit low-capacity systems,&quot; Li Hongchun, an expert and deputy director of the academic committee of the China Urban Rail Transit Association and vice president of the Modern Tram Branch, told Southern Weekend that doing a good job Line network planning achieves a high degree of integration of multiple transportation modes, and low-capacity systems can develop systematically and healthily. There are also many successful cases in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Low passenger flow is the key to the suspension of trams&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Insufficient passenger flow and serious losses are the key reasons for the suspension of trams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jiemian News, before the suspension, the daily passenger volume of Shanghai Zhangjiang trams had dropped sharply to about 1,000 passengers. Wang Qingfeng (pseudonym), a bus enthusiast who works in Zhangjiang, recalled that sometimes “when we get on the bus from the starting station, there are almost no passengers on the bus along the way.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 25, 2022, at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on a working day, there were almost no passengers in the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram car, and there was only one conductor. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The operating pressure of the Honghe Prefecture tram, which denies rumors of suspension, is not optimistic either. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the tram passenger intensity in Honghe Prefecture was 0.01 (10,000 passengers/km·day), ranking at the bottom in the country. The passenger volume that month was only 26,000, with an average of less than 900 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 29, 2018, a tram was undergoing joint debugging and testing in Honghe, Yunnan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low operating frequency is an important reason that affects passenger flow. The longer the departure interval, the lower the attractiveness of passenger flow. Low passenger flow further affects the departure interval, forming a vicious circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval between Zhangjiang tram trains before they stop running is 15 to 20 minutes. For commuters, the waiting time is too long. &quot;Instead of waiting for the tram, it&#39;s better to buy a shared bicycle.&quot; Wang Qingfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only shared bicycles, but also the opening and operation of many subway lines such as the eastern extension of Shanghai Metro Line 2, Line 11, and Line 13, have dispersed the passenger flow of trams. Before the suspension, in February 2023, Zhangjiang trams reduced their operating hours from 17 hours a day to only 4 trips during the morning and evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pudong Modern Rail Transit Co., Ltd. stated in the announcement that in recent years, the public transportation system in Zhangjiang area has been continuously enriched and improved. Multiple urban rail lines have been put into operation, and ground bus lines have been optimized and adjusted many times. The passenger flow of Zhangjiang Tram 1 has been declining year by year, and ground buses will replace the connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Insufficient technical applicability and high maintenance costs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to low passenger flow and long departure intervals, the trams in Tianjin Development Zone and Shanghai Zhangjiang are subject to The vehicles are imported products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both use the Translohr system produced by the French company Raul, which has rubber wheels, single track and a small footprint. However, not many cities around the world use this system. With the gradual decline of Raul after its acquisition, the production of related parts has been greatly reduced, resulting in high vehicle maintenance costs and long maintenance cycles, and some parts are facing the risk of &quot;supply interruption&quot;. Difficulties in purchasing parts have also led to difficulties and high costs in maintaining trams in Shanghai Zhangjiang and Tianjin Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qingfeng recalled that when he was riding a tram in Zhangjiang, he discovered that there was a thick wooden pole in the driver&#39;s cab. The tracks are sometimes blocked by debris, and drivers need to get out of the car and use wooden poles to clear the debris, which greatly affects traffic efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Zhuhai tram, Li Hongchun mentioned in an interview that the TramWave ground power supply system it used lacked engineering practice, and the builders had insufficient understanding of the applicability of the technology, resulting in system problems after the line was opened. The failure rate is high and the operation service is unstable. At the same time, factors such as low passenger flow and high maintenance costs have directly affected the remaining section of Line 1 that was originally planned to be rebuilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being low in frequency, the out-of-service trams were also considered too slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Report&quot; shows that the average travel speed of subways in 2022 will be 36.47 kilometers/hour, the average travel speed of trams nationwide is only 22.3 kilometers/hour, and the travel speed of Zhangjiang trams is only 19 kilometers/hour Hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the maximum design speed of Zhangjiang trams is 70 kilometers per hour. The reason for the slow running speed is that trams do not have dedicated right of way - they share the road space with all vehicles and are still subject to traffic lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height= &quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Zhangjiang tram does not have a dedicated right of way. It shares the road space with all vehicles and is still subject to traffic lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long trams waiting for traffic lights exacerbate congestion. For example, the Zhangjiang tram passes by Pudong Foreign Languages ​​School Affiliated to Shanghai International Studies University. Parents will park their private cars on the roadside when picking up their children. When the tram comes in, it will occupy the entire road. One citizen said: &quot;You can either use the non-motorized lane next to it to overtake, or you can only follow the Dangdang tram.&quot; Dangdang tram is the nickname given to Zhangjiang trams by Shanghai residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Planning issues, not standard issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking around the world, trams are not a niche issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;China Tram Development Report (2020)&quot; released by the Modern Tramway Branch of the China Urban Rail Transit Association shows that subways and trams are the mainstream systems of urban rail transit in the world, of which subways account for 47 %, trams account for 42%, and light rail accounts for 11%. In Europe, trams are the mainstream public transportation mode in many cities. For example, in Berlin, Germany, trams account for as high as 55.6% of the rail transit mileage. In China, this proportion is only 5.71%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some voices pointed out that the tram was &quot;unacclimated&quot; after it came to China. But Li Hongchun reminded that many tram projects are operating well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In very large and megacities, trams can be used as extension lines and encrypted lines of large and medium-sized transportation systems such as subways. For example, Beijing&#39;s Xijiao Line, as an extension of Metro Line 10, starts from Bagou Station and connects tourist attractions such as Xiangshan Park, National Botanical Garden, Yuquan Country Park and the Summer Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Western Suburb Line is positioned to be “mainly for commuting, supplemented by tourism,” Li Hongchun added. The Xijiao Line is the first tramway in the country to be operated with multiple connections - two train sets are connected together to increase passenger flow. During the &quot;Xiangshan Red Leaf Festival&quot; in 2019, the maximum daily passenger flow reached 94,700, making it the first single tram in the country. The daily passenger flow is the highest recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the May Day holiday in 2022, in order to reduce the full load of the carriages, the Beijing Xijiao Line will adopt a multi-connection operation mode. A single train will change from 5 carriages to 10 carriages, with 8 groups per day. Heavy-duty trains are put into operation with a minimum departure interval of 5 minutes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(China News Service reporter Jia Tianyong Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Huai&#39;an, Jiangsu, trams even serve as the city&#39;s backbone public transportation, ensuring Passenger flow demand. Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is the first tram line in China that enters the core area of ​​the city, and its passenger flow has always been at the forefront of tram lines in the country. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the passenger flow in Huai&#39;an was 580,000, reaching nearly 20,000 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 16, 2020, in Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province, modern trams that were suspended due to the epidemic resumed operation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In tourist areas, trams can also play the role of special tourist buses, such as the Nanping Wuyi New District Line in Fujian , connecting Nanping City High-speed Railway Station to Wuyishan Station, seamlessly connecting with Wuyishan Scenic Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the experience of successfully operating trams, unlike large-capacity systems such as subways, trams, as low-capacity systems, are redeveloped on existing road resources, which is difficult and needs to be adapted to local conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that the suspension of some trams does not reflect problems with the tram system itself, but problems in planning and design. For example, the area near the first phase of the Zhuhai tram project is mostly high-end communities. Residents mainly travel by car. Moreover, the north side of the line is dominated by mountains. The development intensity along the line is low, there is little residential land, a lack of commercial facilities, and the line radiates from one side. , resulting in low passenger flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to plan rationally? Li Hongchun believes that trams are positioned as an environmentally friendly transportation system that fills the gap between large-capacity subways and conventional buses. First, we must ensure a clear level of public transportation planning and strengthen integration with comprehensive transportation. For the connection of hubs, the division of labor between trams and conventional bus systems must be properly handled, and the line network layout must consider the integration of large-capacity systems and medium- and low-capacity systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 26, 2020, the first tram in Wuyishan City, Nanping City, Fujian Province slowly drove out of the Xiandian depot and entered the trial operation stage. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Sanya tram is located closest to the entrance and exit of Sanya Railway Station, and the Jiaxing tram The station is directly connected to the newly developed campuses on both sides by pedestrian tunnels, making these designs more convenient for residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Site selection needs to be supported by a certain population density. Li Hongchun mentioned that it is necessary to accurately predict the passenger flow in the line corridor to avoid the situation where the actual passenger flow does not reach the estimated amount. In terms of construction timing, &quot;we must first consider what needs to be built most, not where it is easier to build.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the first section of Chengdu Rong Line 2 was opened, the low passenger flow was questioned because it had not yet been connected to the urban rail network. After the opening of the second section, it was connected to the subway, and the passenger flow reached nearly four. Ten thousand people, an increase of dozens of times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of operations, regarding the issue of tram rights of way, Li Hongchun believes that priority signals should be provided for trams to ensure the safety, speed and efficiency of tram operations. For example, Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is equipped with three major systems: tram signal priority control system, intersection red light electronic police and road section checkpoint system, and intersection video surveillance system, and arranges traffic coordinators to realize tram priority at intersections. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that under the dual influence of my country&#39;s rapid urbanization and the substantial increase in private car ownership leading to congestion, the development of public transportation is an inevitable trend in history. The construction cost of the subway is at least ten times higher than that of the tram. Compared with the bus, the tram has the advantages of large transportation capacity, high comfort and punctuality. Under the trend of carbon neutrality, tram It is an important option for public transportation construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[哈尔滨：黄昏缄默的时候，建筑在说话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 9:30 am on October 26, 1909, Congkuanchengzi (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changchun&lt;/span>;) Ito Hirobumi, who arrived in Harbin by special train, stepped off the train. A short man wearing a peaked cap and western clothes calmly touched his chest, ribs, and abdomen. He fired three shots and then fired four shots at the accompanying Japanese officials, shouting &quot;Ula Golia!&quot; in Russian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened suddenly, and everyone was still dreaming. Ito Hirobumi was put on a special train and died 30 minutes later. The man with a resolute face, An Zhonggen, was captured in an almost tragic manner; the seven gunshots fired over the Harbin Railway Station, which was built in 1899 and named in 1903, rapidly and profoundly changed the 20th century. The situation in Northeast Asia at the beginning - Although the train station was demolished and rebuilt in 1959, there are still vivid traces of this incident in the station, including the Ahn Jung-geun Memorial Hall and the platform where the incident occurred: the &quot;Δ&quot; and &quot;□&quot; on the ground , respectively, where Ahn Jung-geun and Ito Hirobumi are standing, about 5 meters apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old scene of Harbin Railway Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Ruo Ge As Li said, &quot;When poems and legends are silent, only buildings speak.&quot; - Around the train station, everything is completely different from what it was more than a hundred years ago. Only the Church of Saint-Iver still quietly &quot;leans&quot; on it. Stand aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Street: &quot;The Cross-Communication of Multiculturalism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Old Harbin&quot; without city walls is actually neither ancient nor modern - it is The &quot;modern city&quot; grew up amid the roar of trains. China&#39;s defeat in the Sino-Japanese War and many factors such as Tsarist Russia&#39;s use of alliance with Japan as bait to seize more interests in Northeast China gave birth to the construction of the Middle East Railway. In 1896, Russia obtained the right to build the Middle East Railway. In June of that year, Russia&#39;s Middle East Railway The General Administration of Construction moved from Vladivostok (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Vladivostok&lt;/span>;) to Harbin. At the same time, the railway was divided into The six ends of the east-west and south-west lines are being constructed in opposite directions at the same time. As the center of the 2,500-kilometer &quot;T&quot;-shaped railway that runs from Manzhouli in the west, Suifenhe in the east, and Lushun, Dalian in the south, it has quickly become an international city with &quot;sky-high buildings, merchants, soaring land prices, and every inch of land is precious.&quot; - &quot;The desolate wilderness turned into a prosperous port in an instant.&quot; Capitalism has become the &quot;power&quot; for Harbin&#39;s rapid growth and rise, but at the same time, foreign capital has inhibited and hindered the development of national capitalism, making it an &quot;alien&quot; between traditional Chinese cities and modern capitalist cities; a railway has even more influence on Harbin. The local architectural culture has had a huge impact, with a wave of compulsory and replacement architectural design trends - integration, addition, mutation... In the silent dusk more than a hundred years ago, in this city with wonderful characteristics, it began Continuously “cultivating”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Harbin Railway Station and St. Iver&#39;s Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Red Army Street, which shoots out straight from Harbin Railway Station, was originally named Horvat Street. It is the starting point and germination of Harbin&#39;s city construction. It spreads outwards with it as the axis, showing the annual rings of the city&#39;s growth. The original site of the Longmen VIP Building was built in 1907. At the other end, there were the Russian Consulate General in Harbin and the Officers Club of the Russian Trans-Amur Military District, as well as the &quot;famous&quot; Yamato Hotel in the Northeast; the Sino-Russian Daosheng Bank, built in 1920, is now It is the Heilongjiang Provincial Research Museum of Literature and History, still maintaining the original French Renaissance style; the Cheschakov Tea House’s mixed classicism, baroque and Renaissance style exterior bay windows, overhanging awnings, and open-air balconies are set among the Among the green trees, looking at the signboard of &quot;HSBC Camera Company&quot;, it is difficult to imagine that it was designed by Zhdanov, a Russian Jewish architect who has lived in Harbin for 37 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Red Army Street and the east-west Dazhi Street once intersected at the ancient Gothic wooden structure St. Nicholas Church. Nowadays, there is no trace of the Church of San Nicola. The International Hotel built in 1937 looks like a huge accordion. Opposite it is the former Italian Consulate, the Gibelosso building built in 1919, which is full of exquisite reliefs. The octagonal exterior walls are stacked upward layer by layer to form a lovely eclectic building dominated by Baroque style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another group of &quot;solemn vs. cute&quot; buildings is on Dazhi Street. The famous &quot;big stone house&quot; Harbin Railway Bureau Office Building was completed in February 1904 as the Middle East Railway Administration. Magnificent, majestic and dignified, it is like a &quot;huge castle&quot;; the Harbin Railway Museum, just across the street, has a simple interior decoration, while the exterior maintains the yellow and white colors from its days as the Middle East Railway Club, full of joy. breath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lama Terrace&quot; where St. Nicholas Church is located is the highest point in Harbin. It can be protected from floods when the Songhua River rises. Therefore, starting in 1899, Russia began to regulate the location of this place. The Qinjiagang area (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Nangang District&lt;/span>;) is undergoing large-scale urban construction. Within five years, the China Eastern Railway Administration Building and the Moscow Shopping Mall Building were built. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Heilongjiang Provincial Museum&lt;/span>;) and other European-style buildings were completed, and the east-west axis of Qinjiagang - Horvat Street, Dazhi Street and Main streets such as the New Business Street (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today&#39;s Guogol Street&lt;/span>;) were built. In the 1930s, the Qinjiagang area had &quot;grand buildings, neat streets&quot;, &quot;fresh air and fragrant flowers&quot;. Most foreign consulates were concentrated here, becoming Harbin&#39;s administrative center and a gathering place for foreigners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qiulin Company located in Nangang District today&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;East and West The various subsystems of Fang civilization collide, rub, infiltrate, and blend with each other here. The unprecedented integration of the architectural culture of various ethnic groups in the world presents a &quot;cross-communication of multiculturalism.&quot; The Middle East Railway brought a large number of overseas Chinese - according to statistics, in 1923, the total population of Harbin reached 400,000, with nearly 200,000 overseas Chinese and more than 180,000 Chinese. Twenty or thirty years after the Russo-Japanese War, Harbin has become an international city. It brought Russian culture, Jewish culture, Japanese culture, Tatar culture... and nearly 70 churches including St. Nicholas Church, St. Sophia Church, and the Church of the Annunciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhdanov is to Harbin what Hudec is to Shanghai. Among the three churches &quot;clustered&quot; on Dongdazhi Street, the Church of Our Lady of Saints and Saints designed by Zhdanov (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Church of Our Lady of Protection&lt;/span >;) is the most eye-catching. This Byzantine-style church is said to have preserved the 2,600-kilogram bell that was cast in Moscow in 1899, but it is not available to see now. What can be seen is the notice board erected next to the church: &quot;Please pay attention to your behavior, God is working.&quot; Watching you”. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Church: Bells Echoing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike the Virgin Mary Church, which is located on the busy main road of the city, the Tatar Church, also designed by Zhdanov The Tai Mosque is hidden among the residential buildings on Tongjiang Street. The red and white walls are full of Byzantine style of quiet and dignified temperament. It is like a &quot;mysterious little castle&quot;. Especially at dusk, it has a sense of simplicity. From 1899, when the first Russian Jew, S. I. Berzeri, came to Harbin to the 1940s, countless Jews came to this &quot;second home&quot; and built buildings here, including a hexagonal church with a dome holding up the Shield of David.星的犹太总会堂在内的众多犹太建筑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;鞑靼清真寺&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至少在百年前，雄浑的钟声曾回荡在哈尔滨上空，在钟声中，各国侨民、各色冒险家与流亡者都曾驻足聆听，在这个异乡找到故乡的片刻慰藉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈尔滨的象征——圣索菲亚教堂，在重要宗教节日奏响的悠扬钟声，可以说是老一辈哈尔滨人对城市深切的记忆。据说在冬天雪日中的教堂，拜占庭风格的外形能够让更多的雪留在建筑表面，风吹起雪花，纷纷扬扬，有如在水晶球中的极致浪漫；雪夜里，教堂又会化作金砖亮瓦的城堡，高耸的十字架犹如夜空中的繁星。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;圣索菲亚教堂雪夜，景致如水晶球般梦幻。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如若静观教堂细节，佳时则在黄昏。充满气势的饱满墨绿色穹顶被清水红砖的建筑主体托举得极高，金十字架熠熠生辉，呈现出次第升腾的动态美感；自侧面看，四个帐篷顶错落有致，斜照的光线在建筑细部投下神秘莫测的阴影，敦厚而古朴。步入教堂中，欣赏每日轮番上演的音乐会之余，还能品赏斑驳墙体与罗马风格的拱券窗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夕阳辉映在教堂顶部，让人联想到欧亚大陆那一端和它同名的姐妹，也让人重温城市过往的厚重历史。其实，这座教堂“出身卑微”，仅是沙俄东西伯利亚第四步兵师的随军教堂，1907年3月由俄商契斯恰科夫——他的家在红军街——出资翻新，1912年在原基础上包砌一层砖，1923年俄建筑师克亚西科夫在旧教堂东南角重新选址建造，1932年11月落成，遂成今日样貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;圣索菲亚教堂内的音乐会&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;圣索菲亚教堂的建筑样式与装饰风格借鉴了17世纪的俄罗斯砖雕艺术，而果戈里大街与士课街交角的圣阿列克谢耶夫教堂则把巨大的建筑体量与立面砖饰有机结合，赋予它浓厚的俄式乡音与独特情调。尽管这座原为东正教教堂、1980年改为天主堂的百年建筑亦有巍峨错落之美，甚至在东北响晴的蓝天下，堪称城市建筑的颜值担当，但少有索菲亚广场的那番热闹，日落之后绝少人迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;灯火&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：中华巴洛克&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;秋林格瓦斯打开瓶盖后沙沙作响，这种著名饮料看似啤酒，略呈红色，却只有1%的酒精量，极适合旅游徒步时“吹瓶”——比如从阿列克谢耶夫教堂，沿着果戈里大街一直走到1908年建成的L型淡绿色调的宏大建筑——秋林洋行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;果戈里大街有年头的建筑亦有不少，但在葆有当年荣光的同时，亦不可避免地没落破败了——一如道外区。从火车站向北，过江铁道之东，即是原称“傅家甸”的道外区，是山东、河北闯关东的移民聚居地。虽说亦是哈尔滨最早的市中心之一，但由于缺乏完备精细的规划，导致上世纪30年代的这里“街衢狭隘、参差错落”“一履其地，则令人作呕，掩鼻疾避矣”&amp;nbsp;——彼时民间俗谚曰“南岗是天堂，道里是人间，道外是地狱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里也曾生长出别具一格的“中华巴洛克”建筑。沿街一面沿用西方巴洛克式立面，同时融合了传统中式建筑富有吉祥寓意的装饰纹样，在凸出的挑台边缘设置铁艺栏杆或“观音瓶”式混凝土栏杆，步入内里，则纯然是北方四合院建筑形制，土洋结合，自有一番风韵。主要位于南二、三道街、已经修葺为景点的中华巴洛克街区却乏善可陈，青砖街道、宽阔院落，很多被改造成餐饮商铺，规整有余却少了当年的热闹繁华。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相形之下，还是街区以东靖宇街上的“中华巴洛克”最为原汁原味。始建于1890年的这条长街原名正阳街，亦是哈尔滨民族商业的发祥地：正阳楼、老鼎丰、世一堂、大罗新百货、亨得利、同记商场……寸土寸金的老街曾经商家鳞次栉比。在靖宇街与南头道街交口，1920年建成的四层砖木结构建筑纯化医院，前身为同义庆货店，是“中华巴洛克”的代表作之一：蔓花摇曳的浮雕从爱奥尼亚柱式和柯林斯柱式的建筑外墙一路蜿蜒而下，富丽奢华之风令人难忘，尽显当年民族工商业者对名望的希冀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;位于老道外的纯化医院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一切盛名、繁华与热闹都有终点。如今的老道外因大规模施工，人气不再，颓势尽显：沿街危楼举目可望，楼顶长满衰草，仿佛老建筑正在发出的叹息；街上游荡的小猫小狗看起来都充满沧桑感；在废墟边，偶尔可见打着“织补”招牌的小电动车，那是东北中老年妇女常做的营生——缝穷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在老哈尔滨，如果说“中”的窗口是“正阳街”，“西”的缩影就是中央大街——在萧红笔下，市街像一张“繁繁杂杂颜色不清晰的地图”，今日哈尔滨也具有类似特质——同样是商业街，道外的靖宇街成为大工地，而道里的中央大街，在早上七点，就有游人拎着格瓦斯瓶子四处闲逛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;老道外街景&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“夜，春夜，中央大街充满了音乐的夜。流浪人的音乐，日本舞场的音乐，外国饭店的音乐……7点钟以后，中央大街的中段，在一条横口，那个很响的扩音机哇哇地叫起来，这歌声差不多响彻全街。”萧红在《春意挂上了树梢》中曾经写到中央大街，不乏讽刺与戏谑；不过，她记录的“渐渐数不过来”的“像扯在太阳下的长串的黄色铜铃”一般的璀璨灯火，仿佛还挂在北起松花江防洪胜利纪念塔、南至经纬街、全长1450米的中央大街之上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在一些横的街上，是较为清静一些，路灯的光把树叶的影子印在路上，衰老的俄国人，正在絮絮地说着已经没有的好日子。……在日间也许以为是丑恶的，可是美丽的夜，把美丽的衣裳披在一切的上面，什么都像是很美好的了。”靳以笔下的那些短一些的街，和中央大街组成了类似鱼骨状的街道布局，撑起了1903年中东铁路贯通后，这条大街洋行云集、店铺棋布的“妖娆”样貌；特别是1924年俄国工程师科姆特·拉肖克负责设计并监工，铺设了长方形状如面包的花岗石路面后，面包石路代替了泥泞土路，大街容颜大改，富丽华贵起来，上世纪30年代，中央大街已成为建筑艺术长廊和万国建筑博览会，街道两侧多是巴洛克、哥特、文艺复兴诸式风格建筑，创造了优美的天际线；洋行商店、舞厅影院、餐馆酒吧林立……彼时的中央大街成为商品拜物教的朝圣之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;初具规模的中国大街（今中央大街）&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;方石铺就的街路上，维多利亚式马车发出的辚辚车声早已驶进历史的暮霭，只有一块块被流逝的岁月磨蚀得亮泽光洁的面包石，还在向今天步行街上的游人讲述长街的如烟往事——在夏日的傍晚，灿烂夕阳斜照在70余栋欧式、仿欧式建筑上，它们仿佛也拥有了自己独特的性格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;音乐：北国灵魂&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当然还有逛中央大街必不可少的马迭尔冰棍——在松浦洋行大楼改建的松浦1918西餐厅斜对面，即是马迭尔的冷饮厅。如今全国各地都能吃到价格不一的“马迭尔”，但据说都“欠点意思”，还是得在这里买5元一根、前店后厂制作出来、不带包装纸的最为正宗：在冬天这里日售一万根起步，元旦销量通常大爆发，一天能卖三至四万根——在哈尔滨的旅游旺季，“北风中的裸体马迭尔”是中央大街的特色之一，人人都想将自己“冷却到底”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;啃完冰棍，转身就能在马迭尔西餐厅品尝热乎乎的红菜汤、奶汁桂鱼和味道极美妙的罐虾——自从1898年俄国人在田家烧锅院开办铁路食堂，俄式西餐就在中国大地开始生根发芽，光中央大街区域就有塔道斯、华梅（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;原马尔斯西餐茶食店&lt;/span>;）与马迭尔等30余家西餐厅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美食佳肴令人回味无穷，特别是还有音乐相伴——不论在松浦、华梅，还是马迭尔自家一层的西餐厅，夏日里每每能听到马迭尔宾馆二楼阳台音乐秀的小提琴曲、萨克斯演奏或者美声独唱。轮番上阵的看似来自中东欧的艺人们卖力献艺，引得游人纷纷驻足，为中央大街平添许多热闹，更让人联想起他们的“前辈”，那些20世纪上半叶云集于此的外国音乐家：1936年，歌唱家亚历山大·威尔金斯基、费多尔·夏里亚宾来哈举办音乐会；1938年，10岁的赫尔穆特·斯特恩与父母来到中国，14岁在哈尔滨举办音乐会，后加盟成立于1908年、一度号称“远东第一交响乐团”的哈尔滨交响乐团，1948年远赴以色列后，他成为柏林爱乐首席小提琴家……上世纪20年代开始，在哈外侨先后创办了近30所音乐学校，百年未散的浓厚音乐氛围，成为哈尔滨被联合国授予“音乐之城”称号的重要基石。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;马迭尔宾馆旧景&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马迭尔的阳台音乐秀仅是“音乐之城”的一个小小音符。 “在马迭尔宾馆，就是那家有大舞台和豪华大厅的宾馆，在电影放映场次之间组织了剧目演出并开始加演舞蹈节目……我愉快地放下了剧团枯燥的排练，专门去他们那里了。”舞蹈家、诗人拉丽萨·安捷尔曾在中国生活了34年，常常在1906年由俄籍犹太人约瑟·卡斯普创立的马迭尔宾馆演出，她的倩影和夏里亚宾、威尔金斯基的照片，以及餐具、灯具、电器、饰物、马迭尔电影院的宣传海报，一起组成了宾馆内的“历史文化长廊”；在她活跃于哈尔滨的岁月里，这座中央大街极古老的建筑被目之为“拥有最豪华的舞厅及餐厅、最现代、最舒适的客房”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时马迭尔宾馆的风光一时无两，直到1933年震惊哈埠的“卡斯普绑架案”戛然而止。那年8月24日晚，在马迭尔西餐厅用餐后，老约瑟·卡斯普之子西蒙被哈伪警察厅督察长马丁诺夫和15名匪徒绑架；12月3日，西蒙的尸体在哈尔滨附近的小岭被发现，舆论大哗。转年，伤心的老约瑟带妻儿远走法国，不久于巴黎病逝，马迭尔亦从风光走向没落，往昔辉煌，只有卡斯普留在宾馆“历史文化长廊”里的皮包，可以聊作见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1948年11月25日，中共中央代表与在哈的沈钧儒、章伯钧等民主人士在马迭尔宾馆一号会议室达成《关于召开新的政治协商会议诸问题的协议》。那时73岁的“衡老”沈钧儒住在宾馆，常到松花江边散步，见到江水冰封后又重新解冻的罕景，遂作诗云：“江心冻后见奔湍，雪意连潮亦欠酣。地气也随人事转，从今北雁不须南。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;文化公园内的圣母安息教堂&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央大街走到尽头的松花江南岸，即是斯大林公园，一个既窄且长的“江沿儿”，自这里可以览尽时而湍急、时而平缓的江水景致、触摸到北国都会的灵魂，又可以在夏日感受已逾六十载的“哈尔滨之夏”音乐会的狂欢氛围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江水与歌声向远方流淌，百年岁月沉积，哈尔滨就像一块海绵，吸收所有的声音，而那些斑驳古旧的建筑，则成为城市历史变迁的见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原副主任龚建华一审被判有期徒刑15年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年9月19日，福建省漳州市中级人民法院公开宣判江西省人大常委会原党组成员、副主任龚建华受贿一案，以受贿罪判处被告人龚建华有期徒刑十五年，并处罚金人民币五百五十万元；对查封、扣押、冻结在案的龚建华受贿所得及其孳息依法予以追缴，上缴国库。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251237&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经审理查明：2004年至2020年，被告人龚建华利用担任中共南昌市委副书记、常务副市长、南昌市规划土地运作领导小组组长，中共宜春市委副书记、市长，中共抚州市委书记，中共江西省委常委、南昌市委书记，江西省人大常委会副主任等职务上的便利以及职权或者地位形成的便利条件，为有关个人在土地挂牌、工程承揽、项目开发、职务晋升等事项上提供帮助，非法收受财物共计折合人民币8361万余元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;漳州市中级人民法院认为，被告人龚建华的行为构成受贿罪，受贿数额特别巨大。鉴于龚建华主动投案后如实供述罪行，主动交代办案机关尚未掌握的部分受贿事实，具有自首情节，认罪悔罪，积极退赃，受贿所得及其孳息已全部查封、扣押、冻结到案，具有法定、酌定从轻处罚情节，对其依法可从轻处罚。法庭遂作出上述判决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次本不公开的学术不端自查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，石河子大学体育学院教授李伟（化名）在一场学术会议期间，随口答应同行朋友的论文挂名请求。那是一篇与游泳相关的论文。 2021年，第三方机构发现该论文涉嫌反向翻译软件合成，上报给教育部确认，教育部将情况反馈至石河子大学。学校启动调查，给对方学校发函，发现作为通讯作者的李伟此前并不知晓这篇文章的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李伟受到了处罚，三年内不能参加各类项目申报和评优评先。正在进行的本轮高校论文学术不端自查和挂名现象清理工作中，李伟被再次上报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月下旬开始，不少高校陆续通知开展论文学术不端自查和挂名现象清理工作，要求对2018年1月以来的学术论文进行自查清理。此前的2023年4月27日，科技部办公厅下发自查通知，要求高校和科研院所自查清理包括抄袭、剽窃、伪造同行评议、代写代投等较为常见的学术不端行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者注意到，自查最主要的目的是削减学术不端问题论文存量，着力遏制增量。 &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一次本不打算公开的自查行动。南方周末记者从接近科技部的人士处了解到，由于有两所高校将通知作为附件发布到网上，才被外界所知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;自查文件“本不公开&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据各学校发布的通知，此次自查清理对象主要是学校师生作为第一署名单位发表的所有学术论文。自查的重点范围基本一致，均是较为常见的学术不端行为。主要包括六类：抄袭、剽窃、重复发表；伪造通讯作者、伪造或操纵同行评议；伪造、编造、篡改实验数据和图片、一图多用、选择性使用；买卖、代写代投论文；购买实验研究数据；挂名现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照科技部通知，各省高校和科研院所都应开展自查和清理工作。不过，根据南方周末记者不完全统计，仅有石河子大学、青海大学、北京建筑大学等近三十所院校在官网发布了此份通知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从接近科技部的人士处了解到，前述科技部通知本是不公开文件，但有两所高校将其作为通知附件发布到网上，才被外界所知。事实上，江苏和安徽两省科技厅发布的通知文件末尾的确标注了“此件不予公开”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一场自上而下的学术不端清查运动。南方周末记者尝试联系前述公开发布通知的近三十所院校，其中，石河子大学、青海大学、西南科技大学和燕山大学接受了采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前看，不同高校在自查方式上略有不同。但都采取由老师自行填表报告的方式。表格内容主要包含自查老师的个人信息，例如职务、所在学院、研究方向等，以及论文信息，包括论文名称、DOI/PMID、发表时间、发表期刊、作者类别、学术违规情况等。要求学院统计科研人员在核查时间内发表的学术论文，对存在上述六种情况的学术论文进行甄别，提出整改意见，并形成自查工作总结报告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体到清查方式，可以大致分为重点抽查以及全面清查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石河子大学和燕山大学采取全面清查的方式。石河子大学科研处一位老师告诉南方周末记者，他们全面清查了期限内该校老师署名的8671篇论文。学校组织调查组，先由老师填报自查表，随后学院汇总上交，最后由校科研处上报兵团教育局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕山大学社会科学处一名负责人则表示，通知发布后，由二级学院组织老师自查，提交自查表和承诺书。学院根据自查情况出具自查报告，最后由社科处汇总上报。南方周末记者联系该校部分学院询问落实情况。其中，建筑工程与力学学院办公室一名工作人员确认了前述负责人的说法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青海大学和西南科技大学则采取重点抽查的方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青海大学一位负责老师表示，由校科技处牵头，采取两级制，先由学院的教授委员会组织自查，再由学校巡查办抽查。具体到不同学科，严格程度有所不同。例如，由于医学的学科特点，易出现学术不端问题，该校针对临床医学院的老师在2022年1月至2023年5月期间内所发的150多篇论文进行普查，而其他学科均为抽查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然通知中要求是2018年1月至2023年5月，但前述负责老师表示，青海大学每年都有两次检查，分别在期中和年终，因此此次将2022年至今的论文作为重点再查一遍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之所以采取重点抽查的方式，他解释，青海大学的强势学科主要是农林，“由于高原特异性，很多论文不做实验没有数据，没法从其他地方抄袭。所以，学术不端的概率相对会小一点”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;抽查是按比例进行。他举例，按照期限内学院发的论文总量，比如发了50篇论文，随机抽查10篇，包括科研的原始数据情况，以及论文的挂名人员是否为课题组成员等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而西南科技大学科学技术发展部一名老师表示，他们主要筛查重点论文，其他的主要依靠学校老师和其他工作人员的反馈和举报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;几乎没查出问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这种大规模自查，对不少高校来说是首次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西南科技大学和燕山大学的相关负责人均表示，此前未开展过类似的大范围系统自查工作。西南科技大学的负责人强调，学术不端和挂名现象等问题此前主要通过他人举报方式查处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，大部分通知中，留给老师的自查时间为一个月左右，目前学校层面基本完成了自查工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的自查窗口期较短。石家庄铁道大学科技处在2023年7月26日发布通知，要求各学院在7月30日前完成自查清理工作。发现存在问题的，及时填写汇总表，报送科技处，并采取勘误、撤稿等补救措施，且“逾期未反馈视为无学术不端论文”。他们留给各学院的自查时间仅有四天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而从接受采访的四所学校反馈来看，自查的结果是“几乎没什么问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕山大学的老师表示，自查工作在7月底就已完成，“没发现任何问题”，并强调，相关结果已经上报省教育厅。西南科技大学科学技术发展部的老师也表示，学校已完成初步筛查，没有发现相关违规现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于是否需要出具自查报告，燕山大学建筑工程与力学学院办公室的工作人员表示，“学校只要求我们填自查表，如果有问题的话要出具报告，但我们学院应该没有问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样，青海大学的负责老师表示，由于之前每年都组织两次清查，此次并没有查出严重的学术不端行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唯一例外的是石河子大学。他们自查出三篇违规文章，违规行为分别是不当挂名、购买数据、重复发表，分属体育学院、医学院和动物科技学院。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，不当挂名和购买数据均为此次清查之前就已被调查的违规文章。虽然多省科技厅的通知中表示，已完成查处的论文可不纳入本次自查清理范围。但石河子大学科研处的负责老师认为，“仍具警示作用”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;清查之后如何惩处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科技部办公厅表示，对自查清理发现存在问题的，科研人员要及时报告本单位并采取勘误、撤稿等补救措施。对符合《科研失信行为调查处理规则》第三十四条规定的从轻处理情节的可依规从轻处理；对隐瞒不报或虚假报告的，应按照《科研失信行为调查处理规则》第三十五条等有关规定严肃处理，公开通报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石河子大学科研处的老师解释，学校已对涉事老师进行批评教育，且要求他们三年内不可以申报项目，不允许评优选先和获得人才称号，也不能申报科技奖励。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石河子大学对此次自查中主动报告的采取从轻处理。动物科技学院张小千、李劼在2019年发表《培养温度对嗜热链球菌抑制法检测结果的影响》一文。涉事老师当时分别向《黑龙江畜牧兽医》和《中国奶牛》两家期刊投递论文，其中《黑龙江畜牧兽医》为核心期刊。 2019年5月，《中国奶牛》率先将论文发表，4个月后，《黑龙江畜牧兽医》刊出此文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发现重复发表后，论文作者曾反复与《中国奶牛》期刊负责人交涉，要求对方撤稿，但被拒。直到2023年7月，论文作者借由科技部的相关通知进行协商，对方最终同意撤稿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石河子大学科研处的老师表示，由于论文作者主动报告，且此前数次联系杂志社撤稿，因此处理方式上就从轻，仅批评教育。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;为何自查？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为何会有此次自上而下的大规模自查？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前述科技部通知中对此的解释为，压实各单位主体责任，削减学术不端论文存量，着力遏制增量，引导科研人员强化科研诚信意识等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;简而言之，自查的核心在于消除存量、遏制增量。前述接近科技部的人士解释，比如某位科研人员十年前买了一篇文章，要么已经发表用以申报职称获利，要么一直没用。如果没用的话，现在各种严打，只能憋着，一旦发表，没准哪天就会爆雷。不管怎样，他们都会忐忑不安。而自查清理是很好的机会，“就是给这些犯过错误的科研人员一个机会，不论当时是无知也好、侥幸也罢”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，也是给科研人员一个自查梳理的机会。 “梳理一下总归是好事，增强诚信意识，摸清家底，不至于出现被挂名却不自知的情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于遏制增量，“如果知道大家都在盯着这个事，他们以后也不会再干了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，前述接近科技部的人士提及，由于是自查，有从轻减轻情形，“如果没有从中获利，甚至可以不予追究，不过批评肯定是要的”。他认为，自查更多起到教育和震慑的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，这并非首次开展清查。南方周末记者了解到，2022年也曾在部委层面开展过这项工作，目的是让相关部门和地方层面了解到部委对科研诚信工作的重视，但当时“并未公开”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于可能存在瞒报情况，前述接近科技部的人士表示，如果自查时没问题，而将来查出问题，且处于2018年至今的时间段内，那一定会加重处理，“这相当于对抗诚信检查”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果拉长时间线看，自查背后，是近年逐渐多发的论文撤稿情况和趋严的科研诚信管理措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年4月20日，学术出版巨头施普林格发布声明称，107篇已发表于《肿瘤生物学》的论文因涉嫌同行评审造假而被撤稿。而这些涉事论文全部来自中国，发表时间为2012-2016年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国科协当时发表意见，希望施普林格出版集团能够尽快完善内控机制，加强对期刊的管理，把问题论文处理在发表前，而不是发表之后一撤了之，同时高度警惕以经济利益为目的、与“第三方”机构有勾结的“掠夺性期刊”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月15日，美国恒祥咨询（Healsan Consulting LLC）发布《2022年SCI论文撤稿简报》。简报显示，截至2022年12月31日，全球范围内总共有41642篇SCI撤稿，其中中国19421篇。具体到2022年1月1日至2022年12月31日期间，全球有5488篇SCI撤稿，其中中国的撤稿数量为2879篇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对科研诚信的重视程度也日益提高。 2018年5月，中共中央办公厅、国务院办公厅印发《关于进一步加强科研诚信建设的若干意见》。意见强调，要严厉打击严重违背科研诚信要求的行为，建立终身追究制度，一经发现，随时调查处理。这是首次以中央发文的形式，将科研诚信工作的重要性提到极高程度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，2020年，科技进步法修订，进一步明确了科研失信的相关惩戒措施。 2022年，科技部等22个部门对《科研诚信案件调查处理规则（试行）》进行修订，使得科研失信行为的调查处理工作有了更为具体的处理规则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，从2018年开始，科技部每年陆续公布科研失信行为调查处理结果，2017至2019年各有一批处理结果，2020年有两批，2021年和2022年则公布了四批。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此轮自查之后将有后续。前述接近科技部的人士表示，尤其是一点问题都没查出来的，恰恰在重点关注范围内。 “这次盖着单位的红章来，一篇有问题的文章都没有，但如果之后频繁撤稿，或者被调查出现问题，那单位的主体责任肯定落实不到位，到时一定严肃查处。”他表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医生频频被举报，“飞刀”为何难合规？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257002]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;目前，会诊和多点执业是让“飞刀”正规化的两条主要道路，但二者酬劳标准都要向着主要执业机构内的薪酬体系看齐。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;病没看好，手术费是否应该退还？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月底，河南杞县的一位患者家属马先生称，其父亲7月“脸上长了一个包”，于是来到杞县中医院治疗。医院告知需由开封的专家来做手术，并要支付3000元现金作为费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外院专家执刀、高于市场价的手术费用、现金支付等形式，都提示马先生父亲经历了一次“飞刀”手术。“飞刀”，顾名思义，“打着飞的去开刀”。医生们在闲暇时间离开所在医院前往外地出诊，多以执刀外科手术为主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有意思之处在于，患者的病没看好，马先生希望讨还执刀医生收取的3000元手术费，依据的是2005年原卫生部发布的《医师外出会诊管理暂行规定》中关于会诊费用应统一支付给会诊医疗机构的规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该事件经由河南都市频道报道后，旋即引发业内关注：“飞刀”手术是否应当存在？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有医生认为，“飞刀”手术当前缺乏制度保障，给患者和医生均带来了风险，应予以禁绝。也有医生持反对意见，认为“飞刀”手术帮助专家获得了收入，病人获得了便捷的治疗，基层医院获得技术经验，地方医保基金得以留在本地，应予以支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到今天，“飞刀”手术仍处于法律的灰色地带。能让“飞刀”合规的政策在医院内部管理以及制度流程上遭遇诸多障碍，在基层庞大的市场需求之下，私自开展的“飞刀”一直存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;收入问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对医生而言，“飞刀”长盛不衰的核心原因是“增收”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，会诊和多点执业是让“飞刀”正规化的两条主要道路，但二者酬劳标准都要向着主要执业机构内的薪酬体系看齐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年的《医师外出会诊管理暂行规定》中提到，会诊中涉及的会诊费用按照邀请医疗机构所在地的规定执行，可在当地规定的基础上酌情加收。加收幅度由省级价格主管部门会同同级卫生行政部门确定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“酌情”的幅度注定不会太高，北京市一家二级医院的科室主任成胜对南方周末记者表示，北京市内的院际会诊，专家到手费用大约是300至500元，“哪个专家愿意这样跑一趟浪费时间精力？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于多点执业的薪酬，原国家卫计委2014年发布的《关于印发推进和规范医师多点执业的若干意见的通知》中规定，多点执业医师的薪酬根据实际工作时间、工作量和工作业绩等因素，由执业地点医疗机构与医师协商确定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于操刀本院的日常手术，医生能获取的收入情况，上海一位呼吸科医生曾向南方周末记者透露，其每台手术的酬劳约为300元，勤劳的医生每天开展两三台手术，每月绩效奖金收入约3万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与之对应的是“飞刀”收入。从事“飞刀”中介工作的王贵向南方周末记者透露，患者接受一次“飞刀”手术的费用从3000元到9000元不等，中介抽成10%，剩下都归医生所有。决定费用高低的主要是医生等级、手术难度、执业距离，万元价位的手术可能需要多位医生跨省支援，手术时长7至8个小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中介往往会对专家分层。顶级专家一般是学科带头人、硕博导师、所在城市顶级医院的科室主任，这些医生是省会城市大医院外援的首选。普通专家的年资和知名度都较低，一般“飞刀”地点是县级医院。“普外、眼科、胃肠、肝胆、胸外、骨科的飞刀医生是比较多的。”王贵说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若没有王贵这样的中介牵线，“飞刀”则多发生在有私交的医生之间。邀请方的医生多来自区县医院，或曾在专家所在科室进修学习，或师出同门。“双方一定是知根知底的。”北京一家三甲医院的胸外科主任程磊表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，无论哪种形式，相较上述《规定》和《通知》，“飞刀”手术费用不菲。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;正规化努力从未停止&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在一些医生眼中，除了经济利益以外，“飞刀”还能展示自己的技术，提升“江湖地位”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程磊告诉南方周末记者，自己曾在手术器械厂商的组织下到外地医院展示技术，帮助一项肿瘤消融手术在全国范围内落地，“与其说是飞刀，更像是带教”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便是胸外科主任医师，程磊也得求助能应对高难度手术的同行“飞刀”。程磊的父亲在江苏一家医院检查出主动脉夹层，怀疑存在主动脉瘤。当地医院没有条件手术，而前往上海治疗有数百公里，一旦瘤体在路上破裂将危及生命。最后，“飞刀”医生解决了燃眉之急。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在医疗资源分布不均的现实之下，各级政府将“飞刀”带入正规轨道的努力从未停止。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年的《医师外出会诊管理暂行规定》提出了院际会诊制度，2009年的《卫生部关于医师多点执业有关问题的通知》则回应了社会各界关于允许多点执业的呼声。2020年以来，医联体建设加速，同一医联体内医院的会诊、培训、转诊制度也日渐成熟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以理解为，如果专家要长期在同一家医院做手术，一般会办一个多点执业备案。如果是一次性的就采用会诊的方式。”京衡律师事务所高级合伙人，曾当过6年医生的章李对南方周末记者如是解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多点执业制度诞生之初，曾有过“一名医生不得在三个以上医疗机构执业”的限制性规定，但2017年颁布的《医师执业注册管理办法》允许医生跨省多点执业。还规定医生在主要执业机构的同一省级行政区内多点执业，只需在这些执业机构备案即可。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从注册制改为备案制，意味着医生无需主要执业机构和当地卫生部门许可，即可多点执业。在这样的政策加持下，国家卫健委2020年10月公布的一组数据显示，国内多点执业医生的数量已达26万人，是2016年的4倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“医院不希望看到自己的医生到处飞”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前来看，多点执业推进依旧存在诸多障碍，这也为“飞刀”创造了现实土壤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位受访者提到了医院的软性管束。南方周末记者获得的西南某知名医院在院内实行的《医师多点执业管理规范》，其中要求医生完成多点执业备案之余，还要在当地所在区的卫生健康局备案，并向本院提交照片、医师资格证、执业医师执业证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;繁琐的院内审批流程并非孤例。据自媒体“看医界”公开报道，2020年，长沙市第一医院发布的《医师多点执业管理办法（试行）》规定，多点执业医生要求是中级及以上职称，所在科室须在上一年度科室年终KPI考核成绩位列中等以上水平等等。文件还表示，非指令性任务的外院医疗机构执业活动，必须经科室主任同意，并报备医务科、分管院领导，并经医院办公会批准后，方可办理注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述西南地区医院的《医师多点执业管理规范》中要求，多点执业医师应签订劳务协议，与多点执业机构就执业类别、执业范围、聘用期限、工作任务、医疗责任、时间安排、考核方式、薪酬、保险福利待遇等进行明确，并将该协议在本院医务部进行备案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京一家民营医院的外科医生庞梁对南方周末记者表示，一些医院明令禁止医生外出执业，理由之一是担心病人被分流到其他医院，影响收入。深圳市非公医疗机构协会名誉会长谢汝石则从单纯的管理者心理角度分析，“医院不希望看到自己的医生到处飞，这很正常”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;飞刀”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;纠纷不断，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“民不举官不究”？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;未经许可开展的“飞刀”手术，可能被定性为非法行医而遭到严惩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医疗事故技术鉴定认为构成医疗事故并且承担主要责任的，在行政层面上，“飞刀”医生可能会被暂停执业甚至吊销医师执业资格证；如果触犯刑法，医生还可能因涉嫌医疗事故罪而遭起诉。如果医疗事故是同等责任及以下，“飞刀”医生可能会承担行政责任。至于民事赔偿部分，法律规定赔偿主体是医疗机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很大程度上，“飞刀”相关纠纷仍属于“民不举官不究”，患者的意志对案件发展影响很大。章李代理过的一起案件中，“飞刀”专家在进行一场胸部结节手术时，患者出现大出血，“没能从手术台上下来”。事后医生上门道歉，家属也认为国家培养一个医生不容易，选择放弃行政投诉及刑事举报，所以“飞刀”医生没有涉及行政与刑事处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在另一起案件中，医生进行一场胸部整形手术，患者术中同样出现大出血，康复之后告到了专家所在医院的卫生主管部门。最后专家被行政撤职、调离工作岗位、被罚暂停执业三个月。这是章李所接触过的处罚结果最严重的一起“飞刀”案件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使不发生医疗事故，医生也可能被病人“闹”。一个广为人知的例子是，2019年，一山西患者请到了北京天坛医院医生对其进行神经外科支架植入手术。据中国青年报报道，事后患者家属在支付1万元现金“飞刀”费用时，偷偷录像并举报，导致涉事医生和该医院帮忙收钱转交的医生均被停职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个隐忧是，“飞刀”医生开完刀后拂袖离去，将术后护理留给基层医院，但后者可能缺乏相关知识，对病人福祉构成隐患。庞梁提到了2019年的一起医疗事故：一位男性患者在某医院进行了胃减容手术，由一位参加学术交流的外地医生执刀。术后5天，患者猝然离世。尸检报告显示，患者在术后继发胃漏、急性化脓性腹膜炎、腹腔脓血性积液，导致感染中毒性休克、多脏器功能衰竭而死亡。这可能是当地医院缺乏合适的术后护理的结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“病人觉得效果没到预期，要退钱，不退钱我就告你，一告一个准。”程磊表示，“飞刀”手术的灰色属性是医生们的天然软肋，高额的费用是上不得台面的。遇到纠纷，发出“飞刀”邀约的基层医院大多不会去找专家的麻烦，而是默默出钱“把事平了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;合法合规难题待解&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看似很美好的“飞刀”，仍未走出不合规的本质，这意味着身处其中的患者、医生的抗风险能力都极其脆弱。比如，一些医院会给医生投保医疗事故责任险，帮助减少发生事故后的经济损失，但未经备案的“飞刀”手术显然不在理赔范畴内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生们也逐渐摸索出一种“半合规”的院外会诊操作路径。出诊前先让基层医院出具邀请函，在自己院内完成备案。会诊完成后，再在正常收入的基础上加收一笔钱。后者不计入财务流程，也不会由病人直接付给专家，而是经由邀请方医院转手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目前日常中都是这么干的，需要有一定的补充收益这样才有人愿意去会诊。”谢汝石告诉南方周末记者，如此一来，“飞刀”行为本身是合规报备过的，属于合法的医疗行为，但收入的部分属于红包，仍然见不得光，可能面临院内纪检部门的查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于自我保护，医生们也会筛选“飞刀”病例，避免参与风险太高的“飞刀”手术。王贵表示，患者提出请院外专家执刀的要求后，管床医生会评估该患者家属是否“比较敏感”，容易挑刺，经济条件是否宽裕等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在庞梁的设想中，为了让“飞刀”收入走到阳光下，大医院应该建立一个公开的专家库，按照科室、级别对每位专家明码标价，供患者和基层医院选择。这一价格可以与日常执业的薪酬拉开差距。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是让“飞刀”真正获得名分。王贵所在的机构具备齐全的诊疗营业资质，控股民营医院。专家均在这家医院注册多点执业，再由该医院派遣出去提供咨询服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在章李看来，如此一来医生便能绕开公立属性的主执业地医疗机构，合法地进行外出会诊。在一篇教医生如何合法“飞刀”的文章中，他将这个做法称为“远程导弹”，而“洲际导弹”则是创建或加入医生集团、诊所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生集团主要是对接会诊供需双方，派遣集团医生前往基层医院提供服务。但医生集团不属于医疗机构，医生仍隶属于一个主执业医疗机构——或为医生的老东家，或为医生集团内的民营医院。本质上，医生集团只是中介平台，医生走的仍是多点执业或会诊道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾参与创办多个医生集团的谢汝石表示，医生集团可以与患者或派遣地医院签订告知协议，确定“飞刀”手术的价格，并且以医生集团名义收费。如此操作，使得处于灰色地带的“飞刀”费用合规。不过，医生集团面临的问题是，通过招投标形式与派遣地医院达成合作关系十分困难，而和患者一个个单独洽谈合作又不能形成商业模式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使资质齐全，王贵所在的机构依然十分谨慎。他们对外宣称的商业模式是提供医生的咨询服务，包含术前评估、术后康复方案制定等，但不包含手术执刀。“实际上是会执刀的，但不能这么说，因为没有文件允许我们这么做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中程磊、王贵、庞梁是化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新冠疫苗：每年秋天来一针？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些国家，新冠疫苗可能要像流感一样每年推荐接种了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月12日，美国疾病预防控制中心（CDC）发布建议，六个月以上的所有人都应该在今年秋冬季注射一针新版新冠疫苗。几天前，美国食品药品监督管理局（FDA）批准了莫德纳（Moderna）和辉瑞（Pfizer）的两种新版疫苗，新版疫苗针对的是名为XBB.1.5的奥密克戎病毒变体，这一毒株在全世界大部分国家广泛传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接种疫苗依然是预防新冠病毒住院和死亡的最佳措施。疫苗还可以减少长期的新冠影响。根据CDC发布的建议，近两个月没有接种过新冠疫苗的人，都可以接种这一新版疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们拥有了更多的工具来预防新冠病毒带来的严重后果。”美国CDC主任、医学博士、公共卫生硕士曼迪•科恩（Mandy Cohen）表示。发布这一建议的原因在于，新冠病毒仍在不断变异，新的亚型接连出现，而疫苗的保护作用随着时间急剧下降，接种新版疫苗能更好地保护大众健康。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CDC的独立咨询委员会以13∶1高票同意建议普遍接种这一疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赞成者之一、美国埃默里大学医学院副教授桑德拉·弗莱霍夫(Sandra Fryhoffer) 博士认为，新冠重症可能发生在所有年龄段包括没有基础疾病的人身上，加上很多人此前没有接种加强针，意味着对新冠病毒的整体免疫力都在下降，因此应该推荐全部人接种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;普通人打还是不打&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;鼓励接种新冠疫苗已逾三年，但疫苗策略正在悄然发生改变，大部分国家没有像美国一样，推荐所有人接种加强针。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，英国政府宣布，新版加强针免费提供的对象是65岁以上的老年人及一线医务人员和脆弱群体。法国不建议非脆弱群体接种加强针。德国压根没有秋季加强针计划，尽管它之前建议高危人群应该每年接种一剂新冠疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员普遍认为，由于新冠疫苗的主要作用是预防重症而非感染，因此高危人群接种受益最大。而低风险人群和未成年人要不要再接种，科学界仍存在争议。 “对于老年人、有基础疾病和免疫缺陷的人群接种加强针非常有意义。”约翰斯·霍普金斯大学健康安全中心传染病专家艾米什·阿戴尔贾（Amesh Adalja）表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;新冠病毒蔓延三年多来，不少人对病毒的感染逐渐麻木，选择接种疫苗的人数也逐渐下降。但事实上，无论在美国或是中国，反复感染新冠的人不在少数。美国CDC科学家报告称，自7 月中旬以来，因新冠住院的人数一直在增加，虽然其中大多数为幼儿和老年人，但住院的五岁以下儿童中有一半没有潜在的健康问题，这提醒人们即使其他方面健康的人也可能有罹患新冠重症的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在即将到来的秋冬病毒流行季，流感病毒、呼吸道合胞病毒和新冠病毒很可能交叉感染，这会对脆弱人群造成比较严重的后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;在冬季来临前做准备&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在我国，整体疫情处于局部零星散发状态，但新冠病毒并未消失，病毒在人群中的传播现象仍持续存在，身边不乏有人几个月前才经历“二阳”，现在又遭遇“三阳”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基于新冠的传染性极强，得过新冠后抗体自然衰减及没有绝对的保护性新冠疫苗，基本上多数人每年会感染1-3次。”深圳市第三人民医院院长卢洪洲教授解释，“对于免疫功能正常的人群，不会造成特别大的影响。”但对于高龄、糖尿病、肿瘤基础病等免疫功能低下人群，卢洪洲建议每年定期接种新冠疫苗。接种疫苗的策略，可以包括鼻喷疫苗和皮下注射疫苗联合免疫、多价新冠组合疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月25日，国务院联防联控机制综合组印发的《近期重点人群新冠病毒疫苗接种工作方案》提出，对老年人等重点人群实施针对性新冠病毒疫苗接种。明确在新冠病毒XBB变异株流行期间，重点是今年秋冬季，优先推荐接种含XBB变异株抗原成分的疫苗。专家呼吁已感染且未完成基础免疫的人群，应该在感染3个月后接种1剂次疫苗，这将有利于在后续可能发生的疫情中为重症、死亡高风险人群提供更好的保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有专家预计，9月开学后新冠病毒感染人数会增加。按照免疫力周期推测，下一波新冠流行可能出现在今秋11月左右。而此时也正逢流感季，新冠叠加流感，可能导致呼吸道感染相关重症增加，因此建议同时接种流感疫苗和新冠疫苗，这也是世卫组织的推荐——两种疫苗叠加可以最大限度地预防重症和减轻病毒交叉感染带来的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“住院和死亡人数增加表明，冠状病毒病将会长期存在，世界仍然需要预防、检测和治疗新冠的工具。”世卫组织总干事谭德塞博士在2023年9月6日的媒体通报会上强调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天降烟头烫伤女婴，DNA比对锁定嫌疑人：胜于住户连坐多矣！丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256968]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some time ago, a baby girl in Zhengzhou was burned by a cigarette butt falling from the sky in a community. The police collected blood from all the residents upstairs and compared the DNA on the cigarette butts, and successfully identified the suspect who threw the cigarette butts. This is another case of using high-tech means to identify the suspect of throwing objects from high altitude. It also reminds you again that throwing objects from high altitude is extremely harmful and the probability of police intervention to solve the case is greatly increased. Don’t take chances and try the law yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, at the end of August, Ms. Huang was taking her 4-month-old baby for a walk downstairs when an unextinguished cigarette butt fell from the sky and burned the child&#39;s shoulders and neck. Although the surveillance cameras in the community only cover one floor of the ground and there is no high-altitude surveillance, it is impossible to find out who threw the cigarette butt through the video. However, the police successfully found the suspect who threw the object at high altitude by collecting blood from all the residents upstairs to test DNA. Not only will this person be liable for civil torts, but he is also likely to be subject to criminal penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tall buildings provide us with more living and working space and have become a symbol of modernization. However, they also bring the risk of throwing and falling objects from high altitudes. Carrying high-speed kinetic energy converted from high-altitude potential energy, even an egg weighing tens of grams may cause serious injury, not to mention other dangerous items. In recent years, there have been constant news about vehicles being damaged by objects thrown and falling from heights, killing and injuring people. In 2016, an iron fitness ball fell from the sky in Suining, Sichuan, killing a baby girl under one year old; in 2020, another 14-month-old baby in Shaoxing, Zhejiang was hit in the head by a brick thrown from upstairs. Causing brain death...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is unlikely that an unextinguished cigarette butt will injure someone, the risk of causing a fire or scalding someone is not small. In addition to the recent case in Zhengzhou, a similar case occurred in a community in Luzhou, Sichuan in 2021. A cigarette butt dropped from a high altitude burned through the roof of a baby car and almost burned the baby. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, casualties or property losses caused by falling objects from high altitudes were usually dealt with as civil infringements, and the victims had to collect evidence on their own to prosecute. Unless the impact was extremely serious, the police generally would not intervene in the investigation. The individual&#39;s ability to collect evidence is naturally very weak, and in most cases the perpetrator cannot be found. What to do? The previous law stipulates that in this case, all &quot;possible perpetrators&quot; will be compensated. That is to say, once an incident involving a high-altitude object injuring someone occurs and the perpetrator cannot be found, all residents upstairs (except those who have evidence to prove their Those who are not the perpetrators (for example, if the building is vacant and no one lives in it, etc.) will be &quot;sitting together.&quot; Although this provision allows the victim to receive compensation, it is very unfair to those who did not throw things downstairs. It may even condone the perpetrators, because the consequences of the evil are shared by many people. This legal provision and related court decisions have caused great controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to solving the problem is to find the perpetrators and punish them severely. This aspect relies on technological progress, such as high-altitude video surveillance, DNA comparison and other technologies, which can help identify the perpetrators. On the other hand, there are changes in legal provisions. If you still let the victim collect evidence on his own, it will basically be impossible. Because individuals do not have the right to collect DNA from others for identification, there are no legal provisions, and properties have no incentive to install high-altitude surveillance systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Civil Code and Criminal Law Amendment (11), which will be implemented in 2021, has changed this rule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the civil side, although the &quot;simultaneous sitting&quot; provisions still exist, the Civil Code requires the police to investigate in a timely manner in accordance with the law and identify the person responsible. The &quot;continuous sitting&quot; rule applies only when the police are unable to find out. As a result, it has become the legal duty of the police to identify the person responsible for falling objects from heights. The police have greater power and ability to conduct investigations. For example, they can narrow the scope of investigation based on the mobile phone signal at the location of the incident, and can force &quot;possible perpetrators&quot; to provide biological samples for DNA comparison. Through these technical means, the police can basically make the perpetrators invisible. Especially the DNA comparison is extremely shocking. In the case of a cigarette butt falling from the sky in Luzhou, Sichuan, which almost scalded a baby, the perpetrator voluntarily surrendered after the police completed the DNA analysis on the cigarette butt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Civil Code also stipulates that property management companies and other building managers should take necessary safety measures to prevent infringement incidents of falling objects from high altitudes; otherwise, they will bear tort liability for failing to perform safety guarantee obligations. In this way, the property management company will have the motivation to do a good job in prevention, monitoring and other tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of criminal liability, the judicial interpretation issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court in 2019 stipulates that intentional throwing of objects from high altitude and negligent falling of objects from high altitude can be classified as &quot;crime of endangering public safety by dangerous means&quot; and &quot;negligence causing casualties.&quot; Convicted and punished for crimes such as &quot;serious accident crime&quot; and &quot;major liability accident crime&quot;. The Criminal Law Amendment (11), which took effect on March 1, 2021, has added the crime of &quot;throwing objects from high altitudes&quot;. Although the penalty for this crime is lighter than the penalty for &quot;crime of endangering public safety&quot;, the police must open a case to investigate the crime regardless of the severity. This also means that under the new criminal law, the threshold for criminal offenses for throwing objects from high altitudes has been lowered, and the police have greater legal responsibilities to conduct criminal investigations. In this way, the probability of the perpetrator being discovered will be greatly increased, the possibility and intensity of punishment will also be greatly increased, and the deterrence of high-altitude missiles will also be greatly increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Use technology to let the law grow teeth and form sufficient deterrence. Those who throw objects from high altitudes will be caught and severely punished. Those who throw objects from high altitudes will have nowhere to hide. With fewer people daring to test the law, the sky above our heads will be safer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[坚守大山十年，月薪不到三千：支教老师“中年危机”何解]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国铁集团：不可能给第三方平台“优先购票权”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 18:31:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Today, the railway department began to sell train tickets for October 3, with sufficient tickets left in all directions. From September 28th to October 2nd, there are still tickets left. For tickets sold during the pre-sale period on and before September 27, there are sufficient remaining tickets in all directions. Based on passenger flow demand, tickets for the more than 100 additional passenger trains that the railway department will open during the holidays have been on sale since September 18, which can increase the passenger capacity by more than 70,000 seats per day. From September 13 to 18, the railway department sold a total of 111 million train tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on passenger travel demand, the railway department has arranged to open more than 100 additional passenger trains during the National Day holiday. These trains will run on September 28, and tickets will go on sale on September 18. The main directions for adding trains are: Nanchang to Guangzhou, Wuhan to Guangzhou, Changsha to Nanchang, Nanchang to Shanghai, Xiamen to Shanghai, Shenzhen to Changsha, etc. Based on train ticket pre-sales, waitlist ticket purchase data and railway transportation capacity, the railway department will also open additional passenger trains in popular directions and hot time periods in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Passenger travel is highly concentrated during the holidays, and train tickets in some popular directions and hot periods are in short supply. Passengers can choose to buy tickets by waitlisting, transfer, etc., or according to the remaining tickets at different times and directions. , choose to travel during off-peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, EMU train fares have implemented a differentiated floating pricing mechanism, which is mainly based on market supply and demand and passenger flow patterns, with the published fare as the maximum price, and is implemented in time periods, seats, and sections. A multi-tier, high and low ticket price floating strategy. During this year&#39;s National Day holiday, high-speed rail still implements differentiated fares. For example, the fare for EMU trains between Beijing and Shanghai is as high as 667 yuan and as low as 404 yuan for second-class seats. Passengers can choose according to their needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Railway 12306 has never authorized any third-party platform to sell train tickets, and it is impossible to give third-party platforms the so-called &quot;priority to purchase tickets.&quot; Third-party platforms will retain user information during the ticket purchase process of passengers and friends. Not only do they have traps such as surcharges, acceleration packages, and bundled sales services, but they may also risk personal information leakage. Passengers please be sure to purchase tickets through official railway channels, look for the railway 12306 website (including the client), and pay attention to protecting legitimate rights and interests and the security of personal information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[治理矿山安全：实时监测八十余万名入井作业人员]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256970]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/SOkEroGpwkCPUDcHjKEN2TlsHU9Tjaruh9apHTj2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/SOkEroGpwkCPUDcHjKEN2TlsHU9Tjaruh9apHTj2. png&quot; data-key=&quot;251165&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the morning of September 18, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a meeting on further strengthening mine safety. Opinions on Production Work&quot; press conference. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Du Hansan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local regulatory and supervisory departments and national supervisory agencies have connected all normal production and construction coal mines to the Internet. Sensory data such as safety monitoring, personnel positioning, and video surveillance can monitor more than 600,000 sensors, more than 800,000 well workers, and 39,000 household operating video surveillance data across the country in real time, and develop a variety of risk analysis and early warning functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of September 18, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference on the &quot;Opinions on Further Strengthening Mine Safety Production Work&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Opinions&quot;). Deputy Director of the National Mine Safety Supervision Bureau Zhang Xin said that the opinions &quot;strive to fundamentally eliminate hidden dangers of accidents and fundamentally solve problems&quot; and further promote the transformation of the mine safety management model to pre-emptive prevention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions&quot; is the first programmatic document in the field of mine safety production issued with the approval of the Party Central Committee and the State Council since the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China. It proposes a series of measures around &quot;preventive transformation&quot;, which is the first time at the national level. It is clearly required that the headquarters of mining-related central enterprises and large and medium-sized mining-related enterprises be equipped with safety directors, and it is required to standardize the management of outsourced projects in non-coal mines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions&quot; require standardizing the management of outsourced projects in non-coal mines. The contracting unit dispatches project leaders, technical personnel and special operations personnel to the project department, and proposes to strive to establish the unit&#39;s own mining operations in production mines by the end of 2025. (Peel) the construction team or entrust an enterprise with corresponding conditions for overall management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Qingguo, director of the Safety Basics Department of the National Mine Safety Supervision Bureau, introduced that after the issuance of the &quot;Several Provisions on Strengthening the Safety Management of Metal and Non-Metal Underground Mine Outsourcing Projects&quot; in 2021, a total of 1,360 inspection teams were organized across the country. More than 6,800 people were dispatched, which lasted 7 months, to inspect 3,895 outsourced engineering mines, resource integration coal mines and managed coal mines, and 134 major hidden dangers were discovered, during which 461 outsourcing teams were dismissed or transferred to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Qingguo pointed out that through special rectification, the management of outsourced projects in non-coal mines has been further standardized and the management level has been greatly improved. “However, there are still inconsistent management of personnel teams, illegal contracting and subcontracting, and suspended safety responsibilities. , issues such as insufficient investment in safety.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions&quot; further requires the management of outsourced projects in non-coal mines, clarifies the safety responsibilities of non-coal mines, and regulates the number of contracting units for metal and non-metal underground mines, the staffing and academic qualifications of contracting units, and blasting operations. As well as establishing its own mining team, clear requirements have been put forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Without control of disasters, there will be no peace for mines. The management of major disasters is always the top priority in promoting advance prevention.&quot; Zhang Xin said that the next step will be to carry out regular and institutionalized surveys and management of hidden disaster factors in mines. To achieve the transformation from passive prevention to active management, from single treatment to comprehensive treatment, and from underground partial treatment to surface area treatment, &quot;anything that has not been identified, explored, and not treated in place shall be allowed to carry out mining operations, and we must not cooperate with it.&quot; Disasters are &#39;fighting with bayonets.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Feng, director of the Non-Coal Mine Safety Supervision Department, said that in the future, not only will the investigation and rectification of major hidden dangers not be in place, the companies and responsible persons responsible for the accident will be held accountable, and the investigation and rectification will not be in place. Enterprises that cause major hidden dangers to still exist must also be held accountable, &quot;reflecting the concept of transforming the mine safety management model to pre-emptive prevention.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>