<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[证监会：调整优化融券相关制度， 取消上市公司高管、核心员工融券出借]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258614]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to further strengthen the countercyclical adjustment of the securities lending business, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has fully demonstrated and evaluated that based on the current market According to the situation, the system for securities lending and the lending of allotment shares to strategic investors will be adjusted and optimized in a targeted manner, and on the premise of maintaining the relative stability of the system, the securities lending and the lending of allotment shares to strategic investors will be tightened in stages. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;On the securities lending side, the securities lending margin ratio will be increased from no less than 50% to 80%, and for private securities The margin ratio for investment funds participating in securities lending will be increased to 100%, giving full play to the countercyclical adjustment function of the system. At the same time, securities companies are urged to establish and improve the allocation mechanism of securities lending sources, the penetration verification mechanism and the access mechanism, and strengthen the management of securities lending transactions. On the lending side, according to relevant regulations, the lending of shares placed by strategic investors can be adjusted. In order to highlight the focus of listed company executives on their main business, the lending of special asset management plans established by listed company executives and core employees by participating in strategic placements can be canceled and moderately restricted. The lending methods and proportions of other strategic investors in the early stage of listing. At the same time, the China Securities Regulatory Commission will increase the supervision of various improper arbitrage behaviors, tighten the institutional fence, further strengthen supervision and law enforcement, and investigate and punish various violations every time they are discovered, and impose severe penalties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission will continue to strengthen the supervision of the securities lending business, timely summarize and evaluate the operating effects of the securities lending mechanism, and conduct The situation will be adjusted in a timely manner to better play the positive role of the securities lending mechanism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[停更、逃离、迷茫：原创画师与 AI 绘画的抗争]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/xtUjGvuxHNsnkgOYpk7RpZ4s3HZPCvCq1QYs2Wp8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xtUjGvuxHNsnkgOYpk7RpZ4s3 HZPCvCq1QYs2Wp8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253661&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fantasy cyberpunk style work&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Illustrator &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot;/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from August 2023, many illustrators have issued suspension notices. They questioned that Xiaohongshu&#39;s AI painting product TriK was used without permission , &quot;feeding&quot; his paintings to AI training, causing copyright disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident first started when illustrator Xueyu questioned whether the pictures released by Trik AI were very similar to his original works. A few days later, many illustrators discovered that their works were suspected of being fed and edited by AI. As the incident unfolded, some original artists announced that they would stop updating, and some users changed their avatars to a unified &quot;Resist AI&quot; pattern in protest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, ChatGPT has set off a carnival of large AI models in China. Generative AI has become unprecedentedly popular, and major Internet companies such as Baidu, Alibaba, and Byte have entered the game. Xiaohongshu is also preparing for an independent large model team and will launch &quot;Trik&quot; in April. The &quot;China Artificial Intelligence Large Model Map Research Report&quot; released at the end of May 2023 shows that 79 large models with parameters of more than 1 billion have been released nationwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The carnival brought about by generative AI continues, but many people are worried about whether AI will replace human jobs, and original painters are currently one of the professions most affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/o90KDT5Hk9wfM5y7p8knikhOeuXT3CPOHo19GSir.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/o90KDT5Hk9wfM5y7p8knikhOeuXT3CPOHo19GSir.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253662&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Original paintings under creation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Illustrator &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot;/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;The artist is wandering&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first reaction of illustrator Lin Meng was anger. She believed that everyone who devoted time and energy to the work and seriously created original works would not be able to accept it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Meng started painting at the age of 5 and has never stopped. When she was a child, her family conditions were average. She was sent to a painting preschool just because it was cheaper than kindergarten care at the time. It was this opportunity that paved the way for her future life. During her childhood, she was a quiet child who would not make any noise and could sit still. Drawing was a means of venting and expressing for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she had no beautiful clothes to wear and longed to have them, she drew them; she secretly bought expired magazines and copied character sketches in fashion magazines, feeling happy in the process. She knew about the existence of the Academy of Fine Arts at a very young age. , that is a &quot;longing for place&quot;. According to the art teacher, she is a child &quot;born for the Academy of Fine Arts&quot;, and she probably knows that she will definitely be admitted to the Academy of Fine Arts when she grows up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From graduating from Tianjin Academy of Fine Arts to becoming an illustrator, everything has followed the ideal pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as two years ago, she tried using AI painting. The technology at that time was limited, &quot;very childish and not very mature&quot;, but the birth of AI painting itself exceeded her imagination: cold electronic information could complete a painting through algorithm training. Later, these technological breakthroughs became more like a necessity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Meng does not reject AI, and science fiction themes have always been her preference in creation, just like she believes in the existence of aliens. &quot;Every field needs technological development, just like when we were children, everyone drew on paper, and later on electronic devices.&quot; From the current era to the era of artificial intelligence, how to live in harmony is a need during the transition period Something that everyone should deal with together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The contradiction is that it is difficult to live in harmony, &quot;because it does offend our interests, and it is also a matter of dignity. If someone steals your achievements, it is difficult for you to let them take it away generously.&quot; Lin Meng feels that the unfairness of AI is that, for a work that would take a creator a month or more to create, AI can produce almost the same effect in a few minutes. Although the details are insufficient, it can already achieve what outsiders would see at first glance. Pretty good effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an AI without emotions, it can achieve this effect because there are a large number of original works &quot;fed&quot;. For the original author, this is an unfair and difficult thing to solve. . Without rules and relevant legal constraints, virtuality and reality will conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Lin Meng settled in Xiaohongshu and successively released original works under the pseudonym &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot;. After the incident, she announced that she would stop updating and start again on other websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Lin Meng, the original artist Li Ke decided to stop updating and changed his avatar to a &quot;Reject AI&quot; pattern after learning about Xiaohongshu and TriK&#39;s practices. When talking about this topic, he was still angry. He felt that this approach was splicing, feeding, and training rather than creation. &quot;It just plagiarized the hard work of the predecessors and stitched together corpses, so I will not endorse AI, let alone AI.&quot; We will not regard AI as a tool, it is essentially plagiarism.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving the platform, going elsewhere seems to be just a temporary place to stay. It is common for unauthorized works to be used for AI training. . It seems that it is only a matter of time that the tide rolls to all corners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2022, illustrator Luo Qi also questioned on Weibo that the two-dimensional AI painting application Niji·journey was suspected of plagiarism. Many pictures generated by the application were similar to the original works of some artists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, NetEase’s LOFTERAI painting function was also questioned for using user works for AI training, causing many original painters to flee to other platforms. Subsequently, LOFTER removed related products from the shelves and issued an official apology letter. Nowadays, other platforms cannot guarantee that this group of &quot;wandering&quot; painters can find a shelter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, Station B was also on the hot search list for allegedly using AI painting to clean manuscripts and infringing the copyright of the NetEase game &quot;Yimengjianghu&quot;. At that time, netizens suspected that the &quot;Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day&quot; event promotion picture updated on the homepage of Bilibili was made using AI and incorporated the work of another original artist. It even had bugs in the details: recessed hands and only half-full shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the popular OpenAI and Microsoft received a 157-page class action lawsuit, accused of using the personal information of hundreds of millions of Internet users without permission. The plaintiff&#39;s lawyer cited a public statement by the head of OpenAI&#39;s security department, which stated that their AI product is &quot;a fairly immature technology&quot; and that without adequate security precautions, aggressive deployment of AI models would be very reckless. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like the painters stop editing, escape, or mark &quot;AI prohibited&quot; on their works, or learn ways to prevent being trained by AI, it is only temporary. They know very well that this will be a long process. challenge. The wave of AI is rolling forward, and all living beings are being swept up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lzioPAjx37uyIQOyBtFaU0Qe6BpzjiXEu7UQl4OC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lzioPAjx37uyIQOyBtFaU0Qe6BpzjiXEu7UQl4OC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Illustrator&#39;s &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot; workbench&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Illustrator &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot;/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;AI Impact: Some people embrace it, some people are laid off&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zela, a professional painter who has been in the industry for two years, is one of the earliest experimenters of AI painting - she did not recognize AI at first. But now AI has been used as a tool in painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her daily workflow is: learn from AI in composition, draw a sketch, and then color match according to some pictures of AI, using AI as a material library or tutor. The painting steps have not changed significantly, but Finding materials is faster. For her, the time-consuming step is not to refine, but to come up with a variety of plans for Party A to choose from in the early stage, and adjust the plans until they are finalized. This can save a lot of time on repeated work, but because she and AI are still in the running-in stage, overall Efficiency has not improved yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From early disapproval of AI to acceptance and embrace, the most critical reason is that Zela discovered that it can assist in painting, and half of the works generated by AI have merits, &quot;I can learn from them.&quot; , absorb.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, AI painting is still just a tool, but it will be a trend in painting in the future, &quot;because it is too cheap and convenient, especially the people at the bottom are most affected. Visual China , Artspace, and Pixiv have opened AI contribution channels, and AI graphics have also been used commercially, mainly in design work such as new media and event posters. The impact on animation and games remains to be seen.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The game industry Practitioner Lin Yuan told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that game original painters include original scene paintings, original character paintings, original art promotion paintings, etc. Many companies will outsource their game original painting design needs to specialized companies. Outsourcing pays according to the amount of each painting, which can save labor costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The game project I am working on has clearly used AI to do some character design. As far as I know, there are several other similar game companies that also use part of AI painting technology. The most intuitive The impact is that a need that we might have had to outsource or use internal personnel to solve can be solved directly with AI.&quot; He mentioned that some small and medium-sized factories and even large factories in the gaming field have used AI, but the degree of application is different. The degree of modification varies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Yuan gave an example. For example, to draw 100 original paintings, it would take 5 original painters to work for 3 months or more. Now you may only need one original artist to produce 100 pictures using AI, and he will make the modifications. This is a model that has been widely used commercially. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Yuan said that the current impact of AI is mainly on the lower market, and what it can replace is that part of the market that does not have high pursuit of quality and artistic attainments, such as game advertisements on web pages, many of which are drawn by AI. . Some game types that do not have high requirements for art packaging can also use AI, but for some more demanding needs, it will take time to design and polish, and currently AI is far from being able to achieve it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Meng’s observation is similar to this. Major manufacturers are also using AI, but most of it is only for auxiliary reference and not a complete replacement. Because the current technology cannot be replaced, but it will indeed replace some small companies that can quickly issue orders. &quot;Such market demand has always existed, but it used to take a while for painters to piece it together. AI can be very fast, in a few minutes Or a few seconds, so it threatens some companies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scope of the impact of AI is becoming more and more widespread. Many game companies have begun to lay off art design positions, and many companies have reduced their original paintings. Teacher position recruitment. An original artist at a game company in a second-tier city recalled that it was very popular to find a job a few years ago, but now the company has laid off a large number of people, leaving only three original artist positions, and all the others have been laid off. Large factories also have a sense of crisis. A painter from a large factory mentioned that the company has spent almost a year training AI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When original painters go for interviews, the salary can easily be reduced and the salary will not be too high. Some companies that deal with original painting outsourcing needs obviously feel that the demand has become less. They didn’t worry about orders a month ago, but now they may have one There are only a few orders per month. Because some requirements can already be completed using AI, this is the dilemma of the original painter.&quot; Lin Yuan&#39;s game project art director mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;AI will start by replacing labor force, just like robots replace workers in factories. Now AI is the robots in the creation factory. Those jobs that tend to be repetitive and have not so high technical content will be replaced. . Original painters will become more and more popular, and the entire industry will become more and more elite, and there will definitely be fewer positions. Unless the overall market size becomes larger.&quot; Lin Yuan believes that the emergence of AI is to meet market demand, and what can be used by existing If replaced by AI technology, it will naturally be replaced. With the improvement of AI technology in the future, the sense of crisis in the profession of painter will become stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even painters who have not been affected by AI have discovered that after the emergence of AI, customers are becoming more and more demanding on time. To a certain extent, this is a demand created by a fast-paced era, which has also pushed back changes in the entire production chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2A1UGazgFur6gR3HxRnNniCiwLt46JvYpk5KfjJj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2A1UGazgFur6gR3HxRnNniCiwLt46JvYpk5KfjJj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253660&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Comparison of the illustrator&#39;s &quot;It&#39;s a snow fish&quot; painting (left picture) and the image generated by Trik AI &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (the illustrator&#39;s &quot;It&#39;s a snow fish&quot; Fish&quot; social account/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is difficult to prove infringement&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The training database of generative AI is very large, which also makes the protection of intellectual property rights a difficult problem at this stage. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Yunting, a senior partner and intellectual property lawyer at Shanghai Dabang Law Firm, told Southern People Weekly that the main difficulty lies in providing evidence. The author has no way to prove that the platform used his own works for training. According to my country&#39;s copyright law, those who use other people&#39;s copyrighted works to train artificial intelligence must obtain the copyright owner&#39;s permission. However, the training process is not transparent, so it is difficult for authors to protect their rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also mentioned that even if the works generated by artificial intelligence are relatively similar to those of the original author, if they are included in the characteristic files (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Refers to inconsistencies in the unique elements of the work - for example, Tencent&#39;s logo is two penguins, and the penguins&#39; scarves or bows are the feature files. If the feature files are inconsistent, it is just a black and white penguin - no will be considered to constitute copyright infringement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Honglin, a lawyer at Shanghai Mankiw Law Firm, also pointed out that according to existing laws and principles, if a platform uses the author&#39;s original works for AI training and content generation without obtaining copyright or copyright-authorized works, there will be Risk of copyright infringement. The difficulty is that my country&#39;s Copyright Law does not protect abstract &quot;ideas&quot; such as styles or concepts, but only protects &quot;expressions of ideas&quot; such as specific elements in paintings. However, it is precisely &quot;ideas&quot; that can reflect the author&#39;s originality. . In this context, if the author discovers that the AI ​​painting has a similar style to his own work, it will be more difficult to defend his rights; only when the AI ​​painting is obviously plagiarized, he can claim infringement liability against him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Wp2LUMoUI8J3ToOdjJt3JaWKtIA7Mqt3dEpNSnP3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;493&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Wp2LUMoUI8J3ToOdjJt3JaWKtIA7Mqt3dEpNSnP3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Many original artists on Xiaohongshu have issued suspension notices&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to prove it Regarding AI infringement of original creators, Liu Honglin pointed out that current AI technology is developing rapidly, the selection of materials is highly random, and the calculation rules of algorithms are complex and diverse, making it easy to avoid traces of &quot;plagiarism&quot; in generative works from a technical perspective. Therefore, in order to prove that the AI ​​image generator infringes their copyright, it is necessary to prove which specific work was copied into the AI ​​algorithm system. However, the &quot;opacity&quot; of the algorithm makes this proof idea not easy to implement in practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the platform user agreement may also allow users to agree to the platform’s use for AI training without reading it carefully. One of the reasons why the Xiaohongshu incident triggered protests from painters is that according to Xiaohongshu’s user agreement, the platform has the right to directly use users’ works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Yunting believes that if a platform uses users&#39; works to train artificial intelligence, it should obtain separate consent from the original author, rather than obtaining authorization with just a user agreement. &quot;Even if this user agreement is signed by the platform, it may be deemed as a standard clause that excludes the other party&#39;s main rights because no consideration is provided, which is also commonly known as the overlord clause.&quot; Liu Honglin also pointed out that some have a significant impact on user rights and interests. According to the terms and conditions, the platform is obliged to remind users. Users have the right to claim that the contract is invalid if there is obvious inequality or clauses that exempt themselves from liability and increase the liability of the other party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Effective modifications can avoid heavy traces of AI, avoid infringement and avoid problems of too low quality.” Lin Yuan believes that the problem of infringement is difficult to solve. If you only use your own pictures or When commercial images are used to feed AI, the scope of learning is relatively narrow. To avoid infringement, the current practice is to make secondary modifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are also more cautious companies. A scene art practitioner at an overseas game company told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that this issue mainly depends on the company, and different companies have different attitudes towards tools. &quot;Our company prohibits AI drawing simply because we cannot control the source of materials for AI software. You may encounter potential copyright disputes. Rather than getting involved in such litigation, it is better to prohibit it in advance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Honglin pointed out that the intellectual property issues caused by artificial intelligence deep learning are more complicated than general copyright infringement. . The infringement determination principles applied in traditional copyright law cannot fully respond to the infringement issues of artificial intelligence deep learning, and relevant laws and regulations need to be gradually improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Honglin believes that the key to the conflict between AI and painters is that “there is currently a lack of a suitable profit distribution mechanism between the two parties. The AI ​​database uses the author’s works for data training, but there is no corresponding incentive mechanism. This is also something that the AI ​​industry needs to focus on in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Meng, who started learning painting at the age of 5, has a corner in his home dedicated to painting, where he stores several thick albums of paintings from childhood to adulthood. Sometimes, looking through past paintings, a certain scene from my growth will reappear like a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She remembered that one of the paintings was a still life gouache painting in high school, which was criticized by the teacher as having &quot;big problems&quot;. &quot;At the time, I felt like the sky was falling.&quot; But it was also the teacher&#39;s guidance. , also made her decide to focus on color and use color to express emotions. That painting was a key step in her growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The connection between painting and emotion is a part that AI cannot replace. Her current paintings are mainly in the cyberpunk style, but they are not mechanical in cold colors such as purple and blue. She chooses cheerful colors, mainly pink, a high-saturation cyberpunk. Lin Meng said, &quot;I hope that technology and machines will not be so cold, innocent and warm, and can be associated with cyberpunk. It is also an expectation for technology. I believe it can reach a balance point with human beings.&quot; &lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(To protect the privacy of the interviewees, Li Ke, Lin Meng, and Lin Yuan are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以新一轮冲突已造成双方超过3500人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258616]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Statistics released by the Palestinian health department show that as of 11:55 local time on the 14th, a new outbreak in Palestine and Israel Since the first round of conflict, 2,215 people have been killed and 8,714 injured in the Gaza Strip; 54 people have been killed and more than 1,100 injured in the West Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; In addition, according to a report by the Jerusalem Post on the evening of the 13th, data from the Israeli Ministry of Health showed that since the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the number of Israeli deaths has exceeded 1,300, and the number of injured has reached at least 3,484. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This round of conflict between Palestine and Israel has killed more than 3,500 people on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[诺贝尔文学奖得主格丽克逝世：她的诗有超越创伤与丧失的力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258626]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;738&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/20/10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;Picture/Katherine Wolkoff&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The word &#39;poet&#39; must be used with caution; it names a desire, not a profession.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Years ago, Louise Glick wrote in an autobiographical essay: The desire to make art produces an ongoing experience of longing, a restlessness that sometimes ends in a romantic or sexual way. There always seemed to be something ahead, the next poem or the next story, visible but out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To fully understand it is to let it haunt and torment; a certain sound, a stone, becomes a torment - the poem that symbolizes this sound seems to be somewhere, completed, It is like a lighthouse, but the difference is that when you swim towards it, it retreats.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his nearly 60 years of poetry career, he has accumulated 13 poetry collections, which are stacked in the corner of the room. Occasionally, Glick would deliberately suppress some &quot;sneaky&quot; complacency and lament that he &quot;didn&#39;t waste time.&quot; Now, a new stamen has been added to her crown - the Nobel Prize for Literature. The award citation praised her &quot;unpretentious poetic voice that universalizes individual existence.&quot; Her first reaction after winning the award was: Oops, I won’t have any friends! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps in response to the suffering and shadow of the current global epidemic, jury chairman Anders Olsen quoted &quot;Snowdrops&quot; in his speech, which was the novel that won Glick the Pulitzer Prize. Award-winning poetry collection &quot;Wild Iris&quot; (1992). It depicts the miraculous return of life after winter and seems to symbolize the poet&#39;s &quot;radical transformation and rebirth,&quot; who, despite being constantly troubled by life&#39;s mistakes and changing circumstances, is still able to &quot;make leaps from a profound sense of loss.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She saw a vision of death at the age of seven, and was choked by anorexia as a teenager. The precocious girl shouldered the destiny of the poet to &quot;witness&quot;. With the help of myths and religious fables, she traveled between the holy and the underworld, transcending the &quot;confessional poets&quot;. As predicted in the poem, she is indeed more like Lazarus than Joan of Arc - the person in the Bible who was saved and resurrected by Jesus, whom the poet Sylvia Plath wanted to &quot;imitate&quot; but ended up The lost road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In her poems, the self listens to its remaining dreams and fantasies, and no one is stronger than her in the face of its own fantasies.&quot; Olson said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Hungry is not for experience, but for understanding​&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I was born cautious, in Taurus under the sign./I grew up and thrived on an island,/in the second half of the twentieth century;/the shadow of the Holocaust/barely touched me.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1943 Glück was born in Long Island, New York, to a Hungarian-Jewish family. These few words are the &quot;autobiography&quot; she wrote for herself. As the title of her second collection of poems suggests, this &quot;house on the swamp&quot; is not stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her father is a successful businessman with a long-cherished wish to be a writer, and he often tells her legends and historical anecdotes such as Joan of Arc. My mother graduated from Wesleyan Women&#39;s College, where many ladies were born, and served as the &quot;arbiter&quot; of the family&#39;s art education. She also had a sister who would become a banker in Manhattan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Glick&#39;s writing is not Cold War-style politicization, but personal politics. Her writing returns to the identification of human identity. This is a key point. All the women in her works are Looking for my own voice.&quot; Fan Jinghua, the translator who first introduced Glick to China, pointed out that the rise of personal writing in the American poetry tradition, including the rise of Western feminism, is the reason why Glick has won many important awards over the years. background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Glick, family seems like her &quot;concentration camp&quot;. &quot;I have a strong desire to speak, but this desire is often thwarted: my sentences, if interrupted, are completely altered—transformed rather than interpreted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short , &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;She does not meet the definition of a child: full of hope for everything.&quot;&lt;/span>; As an adult, she wrote in her poem Wrote, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All the defense, spiritual stubbornness, persistence/taking off the mask of ordinary people and revealing the tragedy,/these are actually the The ignorance of the world./Means that which is partial, changeable, capricious -/everything that is excluded from the &#39;absolute&#39;.&quot; (&quot;Birthday&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the real The family trauma occurred 7 days before her birth, when her &quot;sister&quot; died unfortunately. &quot;Her death is not my experience, but her absence is; her death made me born.&quot; Glick later realized that she made such a dazzling declaration in her first collection of poems: &quot;Birth, not birth.&quot; Death is the unbearable loss.&quot; (&quot;Cottonmouth Snake Country&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tension between mother and daughter turns into a zero-sum game between the two sisters competing for maternal love in fantasy. In &quot;Ararat&quot;, the &quot;Book of Death&quot;, Glick wrote, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;When my sister dies,/my mother&#39;s heart changes Very cold, very hard, like a tiny iron pendant./ Later I felt that my sister’s body/ was a magnet. I could feel it sucking/ my mother’s heart into the earth,/ so that it would grow.” (“Loss” &quot;Love&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also rewrote the story of Solomon&#39;s verdict. When two mothers fight for one child, the mother is torn between the two daughters, and she is &quot;willing to destroy herself&quot; to prove who is the righteous child and cannot bear to split her mother apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mental symptom is related to the early realization of the &quot;destiny&quot; of writing. Not only out of the overwhelming will to get rid of her mother, but also the &quot;obsession with purity and control&quot;, when she was a teenager, Glick began to strictly implement a diet, from 85 pounds to 75 pounds, to some extent, she also imitated Zhen. De&#39;s asceticism eventually developed into anorexia, and he almost starved to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It quietly begins/in some girls/the fear of death, in the form/of devotion to hunger, / Because a woman’s body is a tomb; it will accept / anything. I remember / lying in bed at night / touching soft, discrete breasts, / touching, at 15 / the disturbing flesh / that I would have sacrificed / until Limbs no longer / blossom and escape: I feel / what I feel now, align these words - / the same need for perfection, / death just a by-product.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The need for perfection Linked to forms of resistance, body and mind are both unified and separated, leading to a &quot;metaphysical hunger&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Hunger is not for experience/ It is to understand as if it were available in the abstract.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years of psychoanalytic treatment saved Glick. After dropping out of high school, she interrupted her formal professional education and entered a poetry seminar at Columbia University, where she studied under two American poet laureates, Leonie Adams and Stanley Kunitz. Under the influence of the latter, she changed from being arrogant and arrogant to being humble and restrained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said frankly, &quot;Psychoanalysis taught me to think. It taught me to use my ideological tendencies to oppose the clearly expressed parts of my thoughts. It taught me to use doubt to check my own words and discover (self-expression It gave me the intellectual task of transforming paralysis—an extreme form of self-doubt—into insight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot; 656&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Some works by Louise Glick&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When I feel safe , I can love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Glick viewed this experience in a positive light, &quot;The feeling of hunger helped me control my greed, which was very helpful in gaining an independent self.&quot; And this seems to be It also established her own &quot;poetics of desire&quot;: in love, nothing is desired. She expresses her desire for someone or something in the world that she wants to possess by saying &quot;no&quot; instead of &quot;yes.&quot; What is undoubtedly revealed here is the finitude of human beings. Just like &quot;Ripe Peaches&quot;, from the door to the dining table, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Certainty, a dead thing/...accompanied by that obscene mouth/ Hungry for love -/it&#39;s like love&quot;&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, because love is as scary as death, this has been planted since childhood: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Fear, of loss The fear of disease; / the fear of disease wearing the bride’s white dress” (&quot;Joan of Arc&quot;)&lt;/span>;; and the mother who “knitted red scarves of various colors” also said to her grown-up son: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s not surprising that you are like this, / afraid of blood, your women / are like brick walls after brick walls.&quot; (&quot;Poetry of Love&quot; )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the representative work of his mature period, the collection of poems &quot;Averno&quot;, Glick reinterpreted the story of Persephone in Greek mythology: she accidentally ate Pluto&#39;s pomegranate, Kidnapped as a wife and returning home &quot;stained with red juice&quot;, she realizes that &quot;she has been a prisoner since she was born a daughter&quot;; Pluto wants to say, &quot;I love you and nothing can hurt you&quot;, But he thought it was a lie, and what he finally said was, &quot;You are dead, nothing can hurt you.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Burning Heart&quot; and Dante&#39;s &quot;Divine Comedy: Inferno&quot; The protagonist Franziska&#39;s dialogue explains the power of the &quot;male gaze&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Both fire and eternity/... even when I am touched Before, I already belonged to you;/You only need to look at me.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A more controversial poem is &quot;Mountain Plum Blossom&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I hate them./I hate them as much as I hate sex,/that man&#39;s mouth/it blocks my mouth, that man&#39;s body/it makes people limp&quot;&lt;/span>; , the upper and lower positions of the body during sex, are as conventional as choosing which flower to &quot;light up the yard,&quot; but are essentially rooted in forced silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Glick has always refused to be labeled as a &quot;hyphenated poet&quot;, and &quot;feminism&quot; is the most prominent prefix. Glick once emphasized that she and her sister were raised &quot;to reorganize, to achieve and to aspire to glorious achievements... We were never asked to believe that such achievements were impossible, either because of our gender Or our historical period.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is logically puzzled by the determination of some women today to write as women, since this appears to be an existing notion of ambition being constrained by gender differences. Rather than gendered distinctions, she cares about a &quot;bigger distinction&quot; between symmetry and asymmetry, harmony and homophony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we cannot forget that Glick calls herself an &quot;untrustworthy speaker&quot; in her poem. In her case, language is a medium that switches between frankness and disguise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《头生子》中患有产后抑郁症的母亲，《阿勒山》中为父亲哀悼的情感麻木而沉默的女儿，《草场》中面对出轨和婚姻破碎的愤怒而挑衅的妻子……这些形象或多或少，都与格丽克人生中不断遭遇的丧失和孤立相互映照：离过两次婚，一座房屋被大火焚烧殆尽。从此，她成了“梦中人和观看者”，一个“沉迷于丧失”的作者，“20年来等待着忍受无法逃避的丧失”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我想我的生活已经结束，我的心已经破碎。/于是我搬到了剑桥。”&lt;/span>;这段直白的口语，突兀地出现在整个诗集《新生》的结尾，留下一段具有余味的空白，亦不乏幽默和辛辣。 &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我曾告诉自己/从一无所有之中/没有什么能被拿去。/但你还能爱任何人吗？/当我感到安全，我就能爱”&lt;/span>;——这是《新生》给出的答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希腊神话中，狄多为埃涅阿斯的离去伤心自杀；在冥界重逢，他请求她的原谅，但她一言不发地走开。在格丽克笔下，她开口请求命运女神允许他回报她的激情，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; “哪怕时间短暂。短暂与一生/有什么区别：事实上，在这些时刻。/它们都一样，都是永恒。”（《迦太基女王》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这首诗曾收入一本《美国人最喜欢的诗》选集。学者丹尼尔·莫里斯在关于格丽克的导论著作中，饶有兴致地记下这桩轶事：一位密苏里州堪萨斯城的行政助理细致描述了这首诗如何与她对话，帮助她逐渐走出与一位科学家激烈的亲密关系，继续前行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“个人主义和普遍主义的，普通和神谕的，短暂和神话的，悲剧和喜剧的……” 丹尼尔·莫里斯指出，格丽克在当代文学中的“主体地位”具有足够的可塑空间，自毕肖普以来，很难再想到另一位美国诗人能吸引如此广泛的批评家、读者和同代诗人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格丽克早期的《花园》组诗，包含了“对出生的恐惧”、“对爱的恐惧”、“对埋葬的恐惧”几个部分，它们始终是格丽克的核心主题，然而夹杂在其中的一首《花园》，仍溢出对爱的真实渴望：&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“但仍然/有什么东西是你需要的，/你的身体这般柔软，充满活力，在石头的动物中间。/承认吧：像它们那样是可怕的，/超过了伤害。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;难怪诗人周琰会说：普拉斯之后，女性如何去爱？建议读格丽克。 “像她这样的诗人，如果你被表面的那种清冷、清高、拒人于千里之外，甚至时不时的不客气蒙骗，就傻了。这种诗人，不在表面上浪费精力。她关注的是人类的情感、精神和象征。所以内里必然是悲悯和暖的。不是那种内心冷酷或者麻木的诗人，这是根本区别。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个声音在《阿基里斯的胜利》中更为坚定：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“他已经是个死人，牺牲/因为会爱的那部分，会死的那部分。”&lt;/span>;译者柳向阳把格丽克的表达式总结为“爱大于等于死”。渴望超越了自我保护的生活表象，与美德和荣耀的认可相连。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;让更多声音掉落纸面&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;正是从《阿基里斯的胜利》开始，格丽克从神话人物中获取灵感，那些被抛弃的、被惩罚的、被背叛的声音，重新被置入现代社会的语境，成为她既个人又普世的“面具”。用诗歌评论家海伦·文德勒的话说，“给经验以永久的神话形式”，而不是像普拉斯、洛威尔等自白派诗人们那样，将自己的自传经历本身变为神话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格丽克把带有“自白派”印迹的第一本诗集视为“失败”。虽然诺贝尔奖委员会恭维她，“在她自己严厉和不愿接受简单的信仰原则方面，她比其他任何诗人都更像艾米莉·狄金森”，但格丽克说，狄金森只是她“早期的英雄之一”，后来就读不下去了，像黑板上粉笔或指甲划过，或是疯狂的小淑女的声音——小猫似的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《美国自恋主义》一文中，她尖锐地指出了里尔克式浪漫主义诱人的误导性，“在我们的诗歌中，自恋达到了最可怕的定义：它不是自我的延伸，而是自我的替代品，仿佛死气沉沉的镜子在某种程度上使幸存的男孩得以幸免。”最终导致的结果是：“他到达洞察力的尽头。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在格丽克心里有一种自动句式，以“诗人不应该……”开头，后面的空白可以用任何事物填补。原本，教学也在这个范畴内。但她意外地接受了教职，每年秋天在耶鲁开设诗歌课，还曾担任耶鲁青年诗人奖的评委。她对此抱有感激，认为激发了她的创作动力，其中一位年轻诗人的节奏和结构给了她很大的灵感，她还为此专门向他道歉，担心有任何“剽窃”之嫌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她对学生和自己一样严格，准备新诗的技巧就是彻底忘记上一首，每一本书就是对前一本书的抵制，“我对把里程碑擦亮这样的事没什么兴趣。”格丽克在采访中说，“我脑子里想的是怎么让诗活得更久一些。在这些不断扩展的诗里，他需要抵达出发点不同的目的地。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;典型的格丽克，有着“合金般质地”的语言风格，总是带着冷峻与克制。然而，有别于纸面上阴郁的形象，她会在朗读诗歌时模仿马叫，也喜欢放声大笑。幽默本身也成了她风格更新的武器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格丽克说，她总是尝试“让更多声音掉落到纸面上”，以便随时换挡。她喜欢这样的诗：你以为在读一首诗，其实在读另一首，又在读第三首，“每个句子本身都不是从前句推导而来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种音乐般的复调性早在《草场》便已登场，莫扎特的歌剧，成就诗行里的咏叹调。诗人尼古拉斯·克里斯托夫评论诗集《阿弗尔诺》称，18首诗丰富而和谐，“以相互关联的复杂形象、一再出现的角色、重叠的主题，形成一个统一的集合，但其中的每一部分都不失于为整体而言说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而她所有的作品集，何尝不是一个统一的集合？译者柳向阳2007年联系格丽克，讨论“诗选”中文版出版事宜时，格丽克一开始不愿意，希望一本本完整出版。在美国，2012年面世的《诗1962-2012》也没有用“全集”的名号，除了校对没有做任何修改，也没有个人介绍。 “诗是她留给世界唯一的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在十年前的诗集《村居生活》中，66岁的格丽克似乎宣告了某种不可能的休战：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“身体啊，想到我们不会再同行多久，我才/开始感到我对你产生了一种全新的柔情，很生涩、陌生，/犹如我所能记得的年轻时的爱情。”（《十字路口》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还在写，写得不慢。 2014年的诗集《忠实与美德之夜》，继续以非凡的优雅和轻盈接近死亡的主题。最新诗集预计明年也将在美国出版。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，“饥饿感”始终存在。这是西西弗斯一般的苦役，“艺术家说谎因为他为抵达所困扰，他感觉到了顶点就是他将永远栖居的地方，一个他的负担得到转换的地方：生命中的每一刻，我都站在这座山的山顶上。我两手空空。而那块石头却已增加了山的高度。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在很不一样——一点都不着急。” 格丽克在近年的采访中承认，她可以一边坐在露台上写冷知识，一边想，“这是生活当中最美好的事啊，最甜蜜的事情，就把句子换换位置，想想，哦，这样也行。那种愉悦感。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那是一个美好的夏天，花园里一切都在茁壮生长，没有任何义务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（参考文献：露易丝·格丽克《月光的合金》《直到世界反映了灵魂最深层的需要》（柳向阳、范静哗译）；Louise Glück,《American Originality》；Daniel Morris,《The Poetry of Louise Glück : A Thematic Introduction》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王毅同美国国务卿布林肯通电话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258628]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月14日，中共中央政治局委员、外交部长王毅应约同美国国务卿布林肯通电话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布林肯介绍了正在访问中东的情况以及美方对当前巴以冲突的立场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅表示，巴以冲突不断升级，面临失控风险。中方反对一切伤害平民的行为，谴责一切违反国际法的做法。中方认为，维护自身安全不能以伤害无辜平民为代价。军事手段没有出路，以暴易暴只会造成恶性循环。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅指出，当务之急是尽快停火降温，避免加剧人道主义灾难；遵守国际人道法，开辟人道救援通道；支持联合国凝聚国际共识、安理会发挥应有作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅强调，解决巴勒斯坦问题的根本出路在于落实“两国方案”，建立独立的巴勒斯坦国，实现巴以双方和平共处。没有阿拉伯和以色列两个民族的和解，就没有中东和平。中方呼吁尽快召开国际和会，推动达成广泛共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅表示，大国在处理国际地区热点问题时，应坚持客观公正，保持冷静克制，带头遵守国际法。中方将继续根据习近平主席提出的基本原则推进劝和促谈。美方应切实发挥建设性作用，推动问题尽快回到政治解决的轨道上来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布林肯表示，美方支持以“两国方案”解决巴以问题，支持联合国为缓解局势、提供人道救援发挥作用，愿同中方加强沟通协调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方还就中美关系简要交换了意见。王毅表示，近期中美陆续开展一系列高层接触，双边关系出现止跌企稳势头，受到两国人民和国际社会欢迎。希望美方同中方相向而行，落实两国元首巴厘岛会晤共识，克服干扰、排除障碍，拉长正面清单，缩短负面清单，切实尊重中方核心利益和重大关切，推动中美关系回到稳定发展轨道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布林肯表示，美方愿同中方一道，落实拜登总统和习近平主席巴厘岛会晤达成的重要共识，负责任地管理美中关系，推动美中关系保持稳定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原水下绝境，亚洲第一人陨命九顿天窗洞穴深处]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258618]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[154套新房雪藏12年后打折抛售，一个多月内近九成未成交]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258601]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《坚如磐石》编剧陈宇：在经典叙事中，做人性实验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258592]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KyKxXJnZBTyfvTFlRrv8TG4pP5T55r4tXATQia9k.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KyKxXJnZBTyfvTFlRrv8TG4pP5T55r4tXATQia9k.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253693&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年国庆档上映的电影《坚如磐石》，剧本由陈宇原创。陈宇是编剧、导演，也是北京大学艺术学院教授。几年前，他写完这个故事，觉得“写大发了”，想找一位强有力的导演合作，辗转给到张艺谋，张艺谋第二天就决定：拍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是有了陈宇和张艺谋的第一次合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月27日，电影正式上映前一天，北京万达CBD影城，首映礼上，张艺谋、陈宇和诸位主演在舞台台沿坐成一排。陈宇回顾，张艺谋当初看了剧本后，约他接下来的一周时间，聊剧本。要一周吗？陈宇疑惑。张艺谋说，就按一周打算吧，每天聊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一天后，正是《坚如磐石》上院线的那一晚，我在陈宇的工作室见到了他，聊起这个过程时他说，“我得理解他在想什么，知道他现在的艺术创作理念。反向，他对我也有好奇。”作为学者型创作者，陈宇不可避免地思考，他们即将做的这部电影，在电影史的坐标中会居于何处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聊了真有一周，两人在创作观和创作方式上达成共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观众在成片里看到的，是这样一个故事：金江市发生一起公交车爆炸案，嫌疑人当场死亡，后续牵连出金五集团董事长黎志田与副市长郑刚的明争暗斗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;片中有多段精彩群戏，几个主线人物也富有戏剧性：张国立演的副市长郑刚，娶了高官之女，一路走来，为了官位不择手段；于和伟饰演的黎志田是穷苦棒棒军出身，白手起家后做大，集团涉足地产、娱乐等多个行业，平素要处理复杂的人际关系，包括笼络官员、提防一起打天下的平辈、关心单纯的女儿、考察想扶上位的女婿。从那起爆炸案起，郑刚代表的官和黎志田代表的商勾结多年的事实逐步显露，他们的关系也逐渐破裂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷佳音饰演的警察、郑刚养子苏见明参与调查爆炸案，他高智商但人情迟钝，凭直觉和经验查案，一路被牵着走，最后才察觉养父背后可能有一个不堪的黑洞，其中还藏着自己隐秘的身世。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中秋国庆小长假结束，国庆档收官，《坚如磐石》以8.8亿元的票房成绩领跑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《坚如磐石》一拍即合之后，陈宇担任原著作者及编剧与张艺谋又合作了另外两部电影，已分别于过去两个春节档上映。 《狙击手》（2022）以小见大，聚焦抗美援朝战场上，五班班长、士兵与敌军进行的冷枪冷炮战。 《满江红》（2023）以悬疑类型为基底，辅以喜剧元素，讲抗金名将岳飞去世后，秦桧府中上下内乱的故事，以45.44亿元的成绩位列2023年春节档票房第一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈宇和张艺谋编导合作的三部影片呈现出一些共性，比如创作者对戏剧性的着迷，对经典叙事的追求。 《坚如磐石》剧情扎实，《满江红》和《狙击手》更是符合“三一律”原则，在一天里、一个空间内，讲服务于一个主题的故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tK4paBl06q4ikz59llIIfdapVcVBsY4rjGH9nYHI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tK4paBl06q4ikz59llIIfdapVcVBsY4rjGH9nYHI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253694&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《坚如磐石》主创人员合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;2&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;人可能会走向自己的反面，陈宇说。在执着于内容之前，他有过对形式的极度迷恋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他上大学是在西安，“一个极其质朴的环境”，别人在食堂都端着不锈钢盘子排队盛饭盛菜，他偏要夹两个青花瓷盘在腋下。他以此为例，形容过去自己身上那种艺术家式的自我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来进入北京电影学院读导演系研究生，第一次拍作业，题目是“爱情是什么？”陈宇的片子是这样的：两个相同颜色的茶杯（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;代表一对恋人&lt;/span>;）被放进一个托盘，“进入到某种约定或婚姻”——他饶有兴致地回忆：一个茶杯离开，和另外颜色的茶杯摆在一起；四个茶杯组成新的两对；最后它们又分离，每个托盘上只剩下一个茶杯。这是个全由静态图片组成的故事：爱情就是那几套托盘上的茶杯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你也可以说它很别致，我自己当年还挺得意的，但是今天看起来，是一种抖机灵式的创作态度。”陈宇说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;硕士毕业后，陈宇觉得自己在剧作原理、演员指导上仍有欠缺，决定到中央戏剧学院读博士。在采访里他回顾，那对他有“醍醐灌顶式的帮助”。他在博士论文中对戏剧和电影的本质进行比较。戏剧原理为他日后做电影剧本提供了方法论上的支点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流媒体上能看到的《蛋炒饭》（2011），是他编剧、导演的作品。从特殊年代到改革开放、市场大潮兴起，三个北京胡同里的孩子长大，有人留在原地，有人往南走，闯条路。在极小的人物关系的变化里，大历史的影像偶尔交错出现。此片入围第18届北京大学生电影节主竞赛单元，获得最佳电影处女作奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在创作观的转变与个人心智的成长相吻合。 “从相对极端的自我，成长、成熟，跟这个社会形成关联，我的自我跟其他人形成呼应、共振。”陈宇这样总结。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创作上，陈宇转向了经典叙事，他认同的原则包括：叙事要完整——有开端、发展、高潮、结局，每个部分充分完成相应的功能；有一套相对科学有效的方案在时间轴内披露、隐藏、传递信息；叙事应符合大多数人能欣赏的价值观，等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他想做一部“硬碰硬”的电影，从情节、结构到人物设计，都足够结实。这硬骨头，啃不啃？他问自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《坚如磐石》就是在此背景下创作出来的。思考和创作是艰难的。对着空白的word文档，看光标闪烁，枯坐、思索一连几个小时，是常态。最长的一次，连着三天，陈宇一个字没写出来，到点他就去吃饭、睡觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/B503aQQiAaFpH0MWrMopgpEoeZFpxaQeIlHaYSkD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/B503aQQiAaFpH0MWrMopgpEoeZFpxaQeIlHaYSkD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253695&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《狙击手》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2020年初，张艺谋给陈宇打电话，想做一个本子，三点要求：讲抗美援朝，不要宏大叙事，强化叙事魅力——这是《狙击手》的起点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《满江红》的题面则是山西的一处宅院，张艺谋带陈宇去参观，请他据此想一个故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三部电影合作下来，编剧和导演之间有分歧、争论，很正常。比如一个人物，在某处，张艺谋认为应该更强势，陈宇觉得应该藏。这样的时候很多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通常，陈宇会把争论生成一篇阐述，“我们开始是怎么想的？我们有几种方式，每种方式好处在哪，缺点在哪？综上，我推荐这种方式。发给他。这个问题我们就不讨论了，按照他最后做的决定，我实现就行了。我们赶紧去下一个问题。他作为我尊敬的人，作为导演，无论从哪个角度，我相信他最后做的那个决定，是最符合电影的决定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张艺谋给过陈宇这样的评价：“陈宇，你还是经常能想出一些好的故事，故事也讲得很跌宕起伏。”未来，他们还要合作第四部电影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从《坚如磐石》到《狙击手》到《满江红》，剧本都经得住分析，开头都有悬念：《狙击手》是在茫茫雪地里，美军想俘获神枪手，而五班受命要带回战俘；《满江红》的开端，是一个死亡的使者，一封丢失的密信，一个惊慌的小兵；《坚如磐石》带领观众进入的，是一桩凶手明显可见的车毁人亡的爆炸案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年刊发于核心期刊《当代电影》的学术文章《基于“叙事动力学”的类型片创作方法论——与电影&amp;lt;满江红&amp;gt;原著及编剧陈宇对谈》里，陈宇在分析《满江红》时使用了“升维”这个概念：在貌似倒霉的小兵张大身上，情节动作上的升维体现在“破案求生—刺杀复仇—逼出诗词、献身取义”的变化；同时完成人物的升维，“探子囧兵—机敏刺客—英雄义士”；从而实现主题的升维，从生存，到复仇，到“家国精神的彰显”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好的剧本要有精准的用途、结构和支点，但是，陈宇强调，叙事最终指向的是对人性本质的挖掘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是随着故事发展，观众发现，《狙击手》的五班班长在极为有限的客观条件下，和敌军对抗，完成几乎不可能的任务，人性之光彰显；《满江红》里，小兵被冤枉不是主线，几个小人物的刺杀失败不是结局，让所有人为之赴死的竟然是一首词；《坚如磐石》中，一个利益相关公司老板的死不是最终答案，因为钱外有钱，官上还有官。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KGq2LVKvpgX5gvCmiyXmz6zlc8yBpfH6u8AhDH0x.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KGq2LVKvpgX5gvCmiyXmz6zlc8yBpfH6u8AhDH0x.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253692&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《满江红》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;兽性和神性的糅合可能是人性的本质——对话陈宇&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;暗黑中的那一点点微光&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;和张艺谋讨论《坚如磐石》的那一周里，你们找到了怎样的理念共识？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他第一句话问我，觉得这大概是个什么样的电影？接近于现有的哪种影片？我会大概讲一下我对这个影片的未来样貌的预期。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得剧本阶段的《坚如磐石》接近什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我会用一些关键词：冷峻、凛冽、硬核、爆裂、人性的深度、人性之光。这是一个犯罪片，实际写的是人的欲望，当欲望让人异化后，会产生怎样的悲剧？这中间有反面人物的异化，但是在与黑暗事物交手的过程中，正面人物在异化下挣扎呈现出的人性之光，也是我特别期待去呈现的。我不迷恋于暗黑的美，而是暗黑中的那一点点微光。于是我把故事的主要视点放在苏见明身上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个大佬（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;郑刚和黎志田&lt;/span>;）之间那种暗黑的厮杀、博弈，呈现的是人性被异化后的奇观。苏见明这样一个正常的、让人同情的人，在这中间被绞杀，他呈现出了面对强大漩涡时人的力量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你写这个原创剧本时，是把你刚才说的那些关键词有意识地连接起来了？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那时我的创作理念和创作方法论开始相对成熟、稳定下来。我想写一个扎实的古典主义悲剧。因为每个人都有欲望，欲望在特定的时期、环境、行径下被扭曲，人就不可避免地被周围人群、包括自身形成的黑暗吞噬。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古典主义美学到今天形成一种经典叙事，classical——你可以说它是经典的、符合多数人审美的、带有古典意味的。我认为它是到目前为止最为有效、让多数人能接受的一种叙事方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影史上有很多阶段，我们都在探索新的电影语言，我一度非常迷恋这些。但真正进入行业以后，我发现，那些实验应该内化，为叙述服务，我会把真正讲好、讲清楚故事列为我的第一目标，而不是让特立独行、抖机灵成为我的抓手，我就开始走向对经典叙事的回归。写《坚如磐石》，第一是从这个角度出发，我想挑战经典叙事这个硬骨头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，我特别迷恋对人性的理解和认知。一个故事本质上最终会指向对人性的认知。我认为人性是个黑箱，研究自我是最困难的。我们只能不停地实验，看不同实验条件下人的行为，去找人性的特质是什么。挺难找的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好多作者写人性，人打着解放天性的旗号要实现自己欲望，本质上那是动物性，是兽性，这只是一头。另外一头是神性，有的人能为了某种崇高的价值牺牲自己的利益、性命。比如，为了救好伙伴献出了自己的生命，这跟兽性是完全背离的，兽性是我一定要保自己的命，甚至一口食物都从自己孩子嘴里抢过来吃掉。在兽性和神性的中间所呈现的面貌，或者说兽性和神性的糅合，可能是人性的本质。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尤其是受过经典戏剧作品的熏陶后，我回归到对我认为更为宏大、主流的叙事艺术的创作和探索，表现人性的命题成为我创作的目标和动力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;让你反复回看、思索的古典戏剧有哪些？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其他也看了很多，但索福克勒斯的《俄狄浦斯王》、莎士比亚的《麦克白》《李尔王》、阿瑟·米勒的《推销员之死》、田纳西·威廉斯的《欲望号街车》、曹禺的《雷雨》、老舍的《茶馆》这几个，是做到对一字一句都有分析和思考。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Kionwfx9oIFiU2PmbkSLsXBZWGUykDMMawv9IaG8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Kionwfx9oIFiU2PmbkSLsXBZWGUykDMMawv9IaG8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253696&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《坚如磐石》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一个优秀的剧本，以50万字到100万字的废稿为基础&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你说过编剧工作是非常务实、艰苦的，能不能结合你的创作经历具体讲讲？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我跟后辈、学生是这么说的，你想写出一个优秀的剧本，前面没有50万字到100万字的废稿为基础，不太可能。这些理论、你想清楚的这些事，最终应该形成你的本能、身体记忆。写出来，可能开始很烂，当你想了几十个这样的人物，就逐渐上道了。无论是走哪条路，用什么方法论，这些活你得干过。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;是不能避免的苦修。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，有这种苦修，才可能完成一个优秀的作品。我在《坚如磐石》之前是几十万、上百万字地写，我刚毕业那阵，中国电影产业化还没兴起，我什么活都干，广告片、宣传片、各种电视剧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不相信天才的出现，特别是对电影这种高度集成化、系统化、具有工艺要求的形式而言，像音乐家那样脑海里飘出来一段音乐，把灵感写下来就成为千古绝唱，这种情况非常罕见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;类似于这样——在电脑前对着空白文档——艰难思考的过程，实际上我就锻炼出了思考的复杂性。我一直认为人的思考是有维度的。大部分人的思维是一维的：我喜欢这个男孩，我跟他好；我不喜欢这个领导，我远离他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而日常生活中的烦恼可能是二维的：我虽然不喜欢这个领导，但是我得养家，于是我虽然很反感他，但我必须把我的工作调控好，让他重视我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在文艺作品中，可能再深一层：我不喜欢这个人的做派，又要去迎合他，但到最后我还是冲他拍桌子。就形成三个维度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建立多重维度的思考，寻找这些维度之间关系，我把它归结为进行复杂思考的能力。电影的创作，涉及的要素特别多，至少要想几千个思维的点，还要把它形成结构，非常复杂。说一个作者相对成熟，可能跟我刚才讲的这个有很大关系。随着训练、思考，逐渐具备了思考复杂问题的能力、组织复杂思考的方法，可能他能做的作品，深度、圆融度、自洽性，能够到一个更好的层次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种维度的思考也进入到我的方法论中。我经常会就自己的作品跟团队一起讨论。有三个维度是成为一个剧本的基础。我还必须要做到，在这三个维度再往上提升一个维度，非常难。它不是机械叠加，是维度的上升。看起来我写的是这样一个事，突破这个维度天花板，在新的维度里又进入一个全新的方向。但它们是相关联的，不是乱跑的。观众以为就这么着了，我还要再有新的、让你意想不到的东西，给观众这样的心理感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你和团队在创作时，会在视觉上把这个过程呈现出来吗，像画受力分析图？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从各种角度画思维脑图。内容创作是一个系统化的工程。编剧可以拆分成两个阶段，第一，策划和原创故事的阶段；第二，剧本的阶段。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;策划原创故事，意味着要明确我们要做一个什么样的电影，它的命题是什么，美学风格是什么？我们对应的是怎样的观众趣味？你要了解社会、当下中国的大众心理，以及电影的合作方、投资规模，等等。这些成为原创故事的一个切入点。我们都是团队在一起分析讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也会把局部工作分下去。比如说我们要弄个侦破片，会列出相关的文学和电影，相当于一篇论文。在这个基础上做侦破片，我们的当代性体现在什么地方？我们不可能再按柯南·道尔、阿加莎·克里斯蒂那样写，至少也得站在东野圭吾的肩膀上看问题。接着我们会进行故事的头脑风暴讨论，出来比如10个故事模型，分配给大家，先写成500字的（梗概）。往前走一走——圈出这片地，不知道哪里有水，我们挖坑，如果这条路是死路，那别走了；剩下三个坑看似是有潜力、有可能产生流水的，都往下写到3000字，再对比，找到那个对的坑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到第二个环节，开始写剧本初稿，就把它一次完成。后面才是针对这个初稿的修改，项目的各种具体要素进来。确定了演员，那我们结合演员的情况进行调整。比如《满江红》，我在剧本里可能会强化沈腾的长处，在台词上给他一种比较高级的幽默感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;业界对广义编剧的理解就是“你给我拿个本子来”。但这两块（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;上述两个阶段&lt;/span>;）区别非常大的，甚至前一块的重要性不亚于后一块。它不只关于编剧能力，实际上涉及对社会、对行业的认识，这些在前，才能产出一个好的项目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你以前说过，你们团队内部是采用非常科学化的创作方法。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是，好的作品是天衣无缝的，好像是个天然的有机体，你很难将部分从整体中间分离出来。一个作品越难拆，说明它的有机化程度越高。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你知道剧本的受力结构，只要能提取出来元件，这块可以拆出来，那就去提升它。比如我非常清楚这段对话叙事信息不够，那我们需要把这段对话的冲突性增强，在冲突中完成叙事信息的呈现。做类似这样的细节打磨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，创作是感性和理性的结合。驱使你写作品的一定是感性，愤怒、同情、感动、遗憾等等，创作者内心激发的情绪特别珍贵，在行业中工作时间越长，情感的冲动越难以激发，因为见得多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要保护这种情感，哪怕一篇小文章、一首歌让我心里一颤，我立刻就要想，是什么东西打动了我？这不能是一个泛泛的很好。我就很小心地呵护这个火苗，去分析、归纳它，把它放大成一团火焰，这团火焰就是激发我从事后面的理性创作的动力。要很清楚这个火焰是什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么能够确定你珍惜的火苗，同样也会打动大多数人，可以发展成一部经典叙事的电影？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;每个艺术家都有自己对世界的独有感受，但人需要一个逐渐理解他人、跟社会真正融合的过程。我并不认为艺术家就应该绝对特立独行，除非一辈子做实验性的、先锋的艺术，那很可贵，探索的是人类思想和情感的边界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但另一些优秀的作品，是不断寻找人类精神崇高的意义，要寻找共识，把它呈现出来，创作者的价值在于连接。我认为当你逐渐能淹没在人群之中，能理解跟大多数人共通的情感，才是真正成熟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么我觉得触动我的东西能触动其他人？首先我是一个人，第二当我是一个成熟的人，对世界的认知更广泛，自身能容纳更多的生活样态、情感运作方式，内心更加充盈，那我的呼吸、感受，和其他人的频率会更有可能趋向于一致。我极为个性的部分，逐渐能和其他人形成某种共振，这时候我就能够逐渐了解大众的心理脉搏。有这种情况：我看到这个故事很感动，它对其他人没那么重要；但也有些故事，我自然地能判断，它对更多的人有情绪价值，我可以去呈现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到今天，我期待自己做的作品能够跟更多人形成交流。好多文艺青年会觉得这是堕落，我并不觉得如此，我希望我的作品能够去影响、感动更多的人，给予更多的人以情感的慰藉。这个时刻是我觉得自己的创作最有价值的时刻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;艺术创作来源于限制&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《坚如磐石》是你自己写就的完整剧本，和张艺谋导演合作的后两部，《满江红》和《狙击手》，原初的点子都不是由你提出来的，接到邀约后，你怎么让它们成为从你心灵生发出来的、能够打动自己的作品。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我认为艺术来源于限制。当不准用语言、只准用肢体来传递信息和情感的时候，产生了舞蹈。当不准用正常方式说话，但是要传递复杂叙事信息的时候，才产生戏曲。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在别的采访里也提到，艺谋会有一些关键词，比如我们做一个抗美援朝的电影，讲一个狙击手故事。我是需要关键词、需要限制的。我就可以讲一个实时的故事，就从一个人的视点去看他卷入复杂的事情。虽然从多个视点讲故事自由度非常高，但是你会发现这种故事讲出来没有那么妙趣横生。很多时候，叙事的乐趣和叙事的价值就是来自于这种对视点的精准控制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就电影的情境来说，限制反而会让你更加自由，更加能呈现想象力。我有时候考试招学生，就直接扔给他们这样的题：现在你是一个手无缚鸡之力的人，被歹徒给逼到商场的厕所里，歹徒在外面砸门要冲进来。你想脱困，没有第二个门，怎么办？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本质上这是一个局部训练。观众就是想看，逼到绝路了，创作者有什么办法？当你真正想出了有价值的办法，意料之外、情理之中地完成了这件事，观众感到满足，你就完成了和观众的合谋。创作者也要把自己逼到墙角去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;比如刚才这个命题，大家会给出怎样的解法？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有各种各样的。比如声东击西，有的把他骗进来，拿个石头砸他；让水箱在那响，我走到另外一个隔间里。还有人想，通过什么方式和外界联系，把保安叫来……没有标准答案。这实际上是看你的创作力，同样一个场景，你有多少种传递信息、呈现信息的方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也会出另外一道题，比如说出玻璃杯的15种用途。一般人会说，我可以拿它养花、养金鱼，喝酒、喝水、喝果汁。这样的回答得不了分，它只使用了杯子的容器属性。有的人会往下答，拿它里面套上灯泡，晃动，在墙上产生光斑。可以拿五个玻璃杯，站在上面当梅花桩。可以打碎了用碎片自杀。可以拿它聚焦太阳光，当凸透镜。就开始得分了。能打破常规的思考，显然创作力会更强。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你之前说编剧是一个非常需要电影工业素养的职业，你同时身处学界和业界，是否会寻找一种通行的方法论，并进行推广？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈宇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我并不把它视为一个金科玉律，要推广到整个行业。每个人对电影可能都有不同的观念，甚至同一种观念里头也有不同的侧重，不同的作者有不同的表达方式。我现在只能做到，用我自己的方法和合作者一起完成一个我认为还OK的东西。在教学中，我把我的方法介绍给学生，他们找自己的创作方法。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如先做结构还是先做人物？有两种不同的创作：先想故事的结构，然后把人放在其中；或者我先建立这个人，让人自己动起来、去做事，形成结构。亚里士多德认为两者都行，只不过他更倾向于先结构。我自己也是，先做结构。但也有很多优秀的创作者，是让我脑子里这个人先出来，一颦一笑，他是怎么样做事，遇见人是什么样的反应，我让他这个人物去面对这些事。我觉得也很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[17岁少年抢劫杀害房东，浙江台州警方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258612]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/26IHYH9dV545IMyscP6p93AvxNM57h4MflEJToPi.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/26IHYH9dV545IMyscP6p93AvxNM57h4MflEJToPi.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254058&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亲友借债找我担保：给别人无限兜底，自己终将无法自拔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258565]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“多年不见的亲戚，要求我为其巨额个人债务提供担保，遭拒绝后恶毒辱骂我，还在亲戚群里骂我见死不救，怎么办？”网上的这个帖子，指向了人性的幽暗，也指向了一个内心柔软者的困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;把自己的财务问题放大为和亲戚相关的问题，一旦不能如愿，立马撕破脸，以道德大棒重击对方，不惜在家族范围内败坏其名声，可谓市侩、阴冷而残酷。对这样的做法，当然不能听之任之。亲戚关系建立在血脉基础之上，泛起特别温情，但这并不等于某个人对另一个人负有拯救财务危机的责任和义务。这是被骂后慌张无措的提问者首先应该明白的道理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事犹如一个楔子，引得众多网友的共鸣与吐槽。一位网友说的故事颇有典型意义，曾有一个多年未联系的同学，不知道从哪里要到的电话号码找到他，开口就是借几万块钱，答主当然委婉拒绝，于是对方降到1万，最后将借款的数额变成1000。答主面对这样的道德绑架，挂了电话，拉黑了对方。这种情况颇为常见，因为很多人都会面对一个不知道啥时冒出来、八竿子打不着的亲友向自己求援，若是你不应允，受到对方的揶揄那是大概率的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;借钱一事，若有能力是可以考虑的。就算不还，如果数目不大，大抵不会伤筋动骨。但是在种种关于私人的经济关系中，替人作保堪称最具迷惑性也最凶险的行为。一位答主讲述了这样一件事：他的表哥和表嫂和别人开了一家木材加工厂，让他拿出结婚证给哥嫂做担保，贷10万元。他没有答应，表哥不死心，通过各种方式死缠烂打，但最终他没有同意。而在无意中他得知，表哥根本没有和人合伙开厂这回事，而表哥已经穷得叮当响了。他感到后怕，要是头脑一热给答应了，这事就悬了，要是中间出点状况，压力还不是全给到了他自己身上？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;站在求援者的角度，除了个别肆意欺骗、给亲友“下套”者之外，亦有不少以窘迫实情相托者。因而也不必将所有的求援者列为不可信的“异类”。但纵是如此，我们也需要以一份理性和冷静来对待他人的求援。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这几年，创业的人多了，对于投资、资金、担保的需求自然也多了起来。有的人以“倾家荡产”般的决心上马某个项目，一旦资金跟不上，面临全局溃败之时，忧急之下，首先想到的是找亲友助力，或许之以利，或晓之以情，总之希望亲友伸出援手。这种心情可以理解，但具体回应之道，却值得商讨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位朋友告诉我，他就被堂弟请求，将自己的房产抵押，以换一笔救命钱来输血续命。但他考量再三，还是婉拒了，因为他仅有两套房，一套自住，一套出租补贴家用，既无多余之力帮助他人，也无实质的抗风险能力来“兜底”。堂弟自然是埋怨甚多。但他觉得自己并不是有能力不帮堂弟，也没有对堂弟利益造成任何损害，因而他无愧于心。何况，他后来得知，堂弟并不是只跟他一个人开过口，也并不只是他一个人拒绝了。这事的利害关系其实在于：房产之事系一个家庭的身家性命，丝毫经不起风浪，堂弟所提要求本身有点过分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广东俗语称，“不做中，不做保，不做媒，三代好”。古往今来，多少保人因为一次作保，受累甚大，肠子都悔青了，遂留下“古训”警示后人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作保看似签个字、画个押，云淡风轻，但真相并非如此。作保实在是牵连着严重法律后果的重大之事，其严峻程度往往超越了一个普通家庭的经济承受能力。无论是以何种方式为人作保，一旦被担保者跑路，相应法律后果就完全有可能转嫁给保人。这方面的例子举不胜举。几年前，江苏省常州市天宁区法院就强制执行了一起案件，由于借款人“跑路”，由担保人代偿25.5万元。至于因为被人连累，担保人被限制高消费、乘坐高铁和飞机的情况，亦很常见。而作保失败之后，夫妻不和、离婚的例子也颇多，实在划不来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法律界人士就此提示，为人担保，陷阱不少。例如，写借条时没有约定保证份额，担保人就承担了连带责任。一些保人之所以“失足”，一方面是因为抹不开面子，另一方面是因为对可能要承担的风险与责任一知半解，轻率同意。殊不知，你的“讲义气”，在让你难以“自保”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当一个人处于现实中的经济地位和家庭局面时，就不能意气用事，搬石头砸自己的脚，而是应该在不合理的求助面前果断说“不”。无疑，如果你连自己都保护不好，谈何“保”他人？要知道，当你因为一时之间的错误决定，而陷入重重麻烦时，那些当初找你作保的人，多数是不会出来救你的。相比之下，你因拒绝作保所担负的“见死不救”恶名，不过是最微小的代价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，因拒绝作保而被亲戚辱骂、排斥、败坏名声，你是有权维权的。大不了“骂”回去，以及干脆进行亲情断舍离。对付亲情绑架，最好的手段就是见招拆招。总之，不管何种情形之下，不能因为感情好，就打肿脸充胖子，卷入本来和你无关的别人的财务漩涡中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;围绕作保之争议，说到底，还是应该建立起边界意识。彼此是亲戚不假，是兄弟姐妹不假，理应谨慎界限，既不能强求别人、提出非分要求，也不能被别人强迫、答应非分要求。我所在南京本地素有“亲戚不共财，共财两不来”的说法，也是由诸多教训中提炼出来的。这话的要义就是，人际之间，过自己的生活，解自己的难，是本分。亲友之间确实可以有互助，以在能力范围之内又不影响自己的生活为限，这也是亲情的意义所在，但在处理重大财务问题时，绝不应越过界限和底线，轻率给别人无限兜底，最终令自己沉入无法自拔的泥沼，到这份上，不仅亲戚做不成了，自己的人生与家庭可能也完蛋了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重庆33层高楼底层挖出“四室一厅”，街道要求恢复原状]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>