<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[一方提分手，另一方都应同意：或体面结束，或不受要挟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is not uncommon for someone to break up when they are in a relationship. The question is, should I agree? My opinion is that when one party proposes a breakup, whether it is a real breakup or a breakup to coerce the other party into accepting their conditions, the other party should agree. 36Kr’s “2022 Chinese Couples Breakup Report” shows that more than 60% of girls break up first. We will use the woman to break up for analysis, but the opposite is true, and it also applies to the man to break up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some young netizens discovered an interesting phenomenon around them: when girls propose breaking up, boys basically agree. TA further said that because some girls like to use breakup as a means, but boys generally use breakup as the result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We will discuss it on a case-by-case basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first situation, a girl is serious about breaking up, but in the general perception of boys, breaking up is equivalent to announcing a breakup. You have informed me, so what if you don’t accept it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides, if you really want to break up, wouldn’t it be nice if the other party behaves decently and doesn’t keep pestering you? If one party wants to break up and the other party refuses to let go, it may lead to tragedy, which is what many people in love fear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I agree with the sentiment that &quot;breakups are serious.&quot; Breaking up is equivalent to the death of love. A person who cherishes life should naturally cherish feelings. He should not talk about &quot;breaking up&quot; unless it is no longer possible and must be said. In other words, if you don&#39;t say &quot;break up&quot;, don&#39;t leave any room for it - when you say &quot;break up&quot;, it means &quot;sealing the throat with a sword&quot; to the old relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second situation, the girl’s proposal to break up is false and the purpose is to make her boyfriend submit. On Himalaya, some netizens complained: My girlfriend often threatens to break up with me in order to get me to give her gifts. What kind of mentality is this? A group of netizens commented: This kind of girlfriend just wants something from you. If you are not in too deep, it is better to leave decisively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, it is often the case that girls who break up with them use the breakup as a game to force boys to compromise and satisfy their own needs. In this case, boys&#39; indiscriminate pleading is &quot;cooperating&quot; with the game&#39;s tactics, and it is also a meaningless sacrifice of self-rights and due stance. This can lead to various passive situations. From the perspective of human nature, if a girl unreasonably breaks up with her, she will get very good results - for example, her boyfriend will obey her words and not dare to violate them at all. For example, her boyfriend will buy things to compensate her to make her happy. Then it will be difficult for this girl not to gain a sense of accomplishment and deliberately make it a kind of inertia, making the other person keep flapping according to the owner&#39;s wishes like a bird locked in a cage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as a person is not a masochist, it is unlikely that he can endure all kinds of teasing and belittling by the other party without breaking down. To fully accept unfair demands is to dig a hole for yourself. It’s so easy to give in and compromise when you’re in love. After getting married, if the other party files for divorce if they don’t get along, what should you do? Someone has said it well: &quot;Breakups are mentioned frequently now, and divorce will definitely be mentioned frequently in the future.&quot; If this is the case, should we continue to compromise? If this is the case, how much happiness and trust can there be in a marriage? I&#39;m afraid it has long been overdrawn by one party&#39;s willfulness, tyranny and one party&#39;s weakness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that whether it is a true score or a false score, directly agreeing is the best choice. When a person is in front of someone who doesn&#39;t love him, or in front of someone who is always trying to &quot;test&quot; himself, there is no other way for him to do anything but be tough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, people’s hearts are made of flesh, and after being together for a long time, it is indeed difficult to make a break. Human nature is always complicated. Being &quot;kicked&quot; by the other party when you still love the other party deeply is indeed shocking and painful. Therefore, some people who have been broken up with want to stay out of nostalgia for the past relationship. This is not It&#39;s strange, but facts show that long-term pain is worse than short-term pain. It is wise to leave the person who &quot;mispaid&quot; the relationship as soon as possible. No matter how difficult the decision is, no matter how painful the heart is, it is better than letting yourself fall into an emotional quagmire and be unable to get out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You must know that hesitating and insisting on breaking up will not only make you and the other party extremely tired, but you are also more likely to be laughed at and affect your work and life because you cry and feel depressed all day long. future. After all, stalking itself means losing self-esteem and &quot;lowering to the dust&quot;. In addition, being indecisive and being weak can also bring about bad situations and even negative consequences. In life, some couples &quot;will get together if they are separated for a long time, and they will break up if they are together for a long time.&quot; After wasting their great youth, they eventually ended up breaking up, which is equivalent to a wasted effort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my hometown, some rural couples have been quarreling all their lives. Often one party wants to leave and the other refuses. As a result, the two people cannot reconcile until they grow old, which also affects the lives of their children. If they break up early, they can Is there such a thing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing these results, resolutely agreeing to break up will not only save a lot of unnecessary troubles, but also &quot;let go&quot; both parties. Isn&#39;t this the best result? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s more, the firm consent of the person being broken up is also a lesson to the other party. A psychology expert told a story that one of her friends was broken up in love and was in a very low mood. He thought she had been dumped, but when he asked, he found out that she was the one who initiated the breakup. The point is, she didn&#39;t want to break up, she just threatened her boyfriend again, but this time her boyfriend didn&#39;t keep her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Breaking up reveals one&#39;s character.&quot; As the saying goes, don’t do to others what you don’t want others to do to you. It’s not easy for two people who truly love each other to come together. They should manage their relationship well and jointly resist various risks encountered in the journey of life. How can you create risks and disturbances by yourself and let yourself fall into trouble? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that some people like to talk about breaking up casually and use breakup to control others. This is not only disrespectful to the other party, but also completing a kind of discipline. Some people just enjoy the sense of accomplishment of &quot;taming the other person under their feet and treating them like a dog.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the discipline does not set a time limit, this situation should make people vigilant. Resisting discipline is the responsibility of every person in the &quot;Emotional Castle&quot;. Getting together and staying together easily is the simplest and most practical love rule. Life is not long, and we can be prepared to spend this life with someone, or we can be prepared to let go when the opportunity arises. This is what we should do in order to avoid being troubled and constrained by a marriage that lacks quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[领航鲸“搬家”分几步？为啥要抹凡士林？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260907]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 17, two pilot whales more than 4 meters long and weighing about 800 kilograms arrived from Hangzhou Departing from a polar ocean park, &quot;relocated&quot; to an ocean park in Zhoushan more than 200 kilometers away, and moved into a more spacious &quot;new home&quot;. With a head weighing 800 kilograms, it is quite a battle to &quot;move&quot; such a big man over a long distance. It not only requires cranes and large trucks, but also requires more than 20 adults to carry it. So the question is, how many steps does it take to &quot;move&quot; a pilot whale? What is the greatest difficulty? What preparations have the staff made to protect the pilot whales? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What are the steps to “move” a pilot whale? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not an easy task to &quot;move&quot; a pilot whale weighing about 800 kilograms, and to move both animals together. So, what are the steps to &quot;move&quot; a pilot whale? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff said that there are five steps to &quot;moving&quot; the pilot whale this time. The first step: Capture and transportation, after capturing the pilot whale from the breeding tank, transport it to the box; The second step: Putting into the box and hoisting; The third step: Inspection before transportation, including the pilot whale’s breathing frequency, Check the mental state, etc.; Step 4: Monitoring during transportation, including monitoring of water temperature, air temperature, mental state, activity state, respiratory rate, etc. of animals during transportation; Step 5: After arriving at the destination, hoist into the water . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What are the living habits of pilot whales? Why did it get its name? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To successfully &quot;move&quot; a big guy like a pilot whale, you need to understand its physiological characteristics and living habits. Next, let’s get to know the large marine creature-pilot whale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pilot whales are mammals in the family Cetacea, Delphinidae, and are also called &quot;pilot whales&quot; because of their huge size. Pilot whales are divided into two types: long-limbed pilot whales and short-limbed pilot whales. Long-limbed pilot whales are mainly distributed in high-latitude waters, while short-limbed pilot whales are distributed in tropical and temperate waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/22f69f961e179bf7552d09428fac69b7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/22f69f961e179bf7552d09428fac69b7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258780&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sun Dong, associate researcher at the Second Institute of Oceanography of the Ministry of Natural Resources:&lt;/strong>;Pilot whales generally like to gather in large groups in the natural marine environment. The size of this group can usually reach 200 to 300. , this is a very large scale, which is rare among whales. Pilot whales are the liveliest among cetaceans. Pilot whales are often seen by sailors willing to accompany sailboats or ships when the ship is sailing on the sea. Their playful behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, due to the destruction of the marine environment, the number of pilot whales has been declining, and they have been included in the second level of my country&#39;s &quot;List of National Key Protected Wild Animals&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What are the difficulties for the &quot;big&quot; pilot whale to &quot;move&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to their large size and heavy weight, what are the difficulties in &quot;moving&quot; pilot whales? Come on and listen to the expert’s introduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sun Dong, associate researcher at the Second Institute of Oceanography of the Ministry of Natural Resources:&lt;/strong>;From the most professional perspective, the most important thing about the &quot;movement&quot; of whales is that we call this whale Cetaceans need to use their lungs to breathe, so the vent on its back, or in layman&#39;s terms, its nostrils must be exposed above the water to prevent it from drowning. Cetaceans can drown. But the water cannot be put in very little. If it is put in very little, one will cause its skin to become dry and dehydrated. Dehydration is a very serious event for cetaceans. The second is the huge body of cetaceans. , it needs the buoyancy of water to support its weight. Another factor is temperature. For cetaceans, especially when the temperature rises, it will cause them to suffer from overheating shock. This should be strictly avoided. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why do pilot whales need to apply Vaseline when they “go out”? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When it comes to &quot;moving&quot; a &quot;big guy&quot; like a pilot whale, every detail is important. There is such a detail in the transfer process that the reporter just photographed. After the pilot whale came out of the water, the staff smeared Vaseline on the pilot whale. Why did they do this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Quansheng, technical director of a polar marine park in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;The pilot whales apply Vaseline to prevent dehydration, because when the temperature is too high, cetaceans can easily dehydrate. After covering it with Vaseline, it will prevent moisture from dispersing. After applying Vaseline, we will cover it with a layer of wet towel. In this way, it has a water-retaining effect, that is, one is to prevent dehydration and the other is to moisturize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts told reporters that this time the two pilot whales &quot;moved&quot;, they were smeared with medical Vaseline which had almost no harm to their skin. The main area of ​​application was the back skin exposed to the air, but Avoid air vents when applying. Two pilot whales arrived at their &quot;new home&quot; in Zhoushan. Before entering the water, the staff used a towel to wipe off the Vaseline on the pilot whales. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to reduce the stress response of pilot whales during transportation? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Hangzhou to Zhoushan, it spans more than 200 kilometers. To ensure the safety of the animals, the vehicle must maintain a stable speed of 90 kilometers per hour during transportation. This extended the original drive of more than 2 hours to 5 hours. How can pilot whales reduce their stress response during long-distance transfers and reach their &quot;new home&quot; safely? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Quansheng, technical director of a polar marine park in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;We will stop eating 24 hours before transportation, and gradually reduce the amount of food in the first three days. This is the first ; Second, we will ensure appropriate water and air temperatures during transportation. This time we set the water temperature for the pilot whale at 23.5°C, which is a water temperature that is more suitable for raising it; third, we We need to ensure that the air in this transport vehicle circulates, that it cannot be too hot or too windy, and that it must be enclosed. Fourthly, we will have accompanying veterinarians and keepers who have raised it for a long time, who will caress and carry it out. An exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to allow the pilot whales to adapt to the new environment as quickly as possible, the room temperature, water temperature, lighting and other aspects of Zhoushan&#39;s &quot;new home&quot; are set according to the natural environment in which they live. However, in the first two days after arrival, the staff will feed a small amount of food, and then resume a normal diet after the pilot whales slowly adapt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[商务部清理歧视外资措施，废除“特斯拉禁入”是个好的开始丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260899]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A spokesman for the Ministry of Commerce recently stated at a regular press conference that the Ministry of Commerce has recently organized a special cleanup to further investigate Regulations and measures that may exist that discriminate against foreign-funded enterprises will create a fairer market competition environment for foreign-funded enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the website of the Ministry of Commerce, the Department of Foreign Investment of the Ministry of Commerce issued a document on November 8, requiring a special cleanup of regulations and measures containing unreasonable differential treatment of domestic and foreign capital. The scope of the cleanup includes laws, regulations, normative documents, and other policy measures issued by local governments and departments, as well as various measures related to business entities formulated by relevant departments. The document also lists a number of specific cleanup matters, including restrictions on foreign investment in access areas, discriminating or excluding foreign-invested enterprises and their products and services on the grounds of foreign brands, excluding or restricting foreign-invested enterprises from participating in government procurement, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Commerce’s special clean-up operation is targeted. In recent years, with the improvement of China&#39;s economic strength and external trade frictions such as &quot;decoupling and breaking links&quot;, there has been a domestic argument that &quot;it is strong enough and no longer needs foreign investment.&quot; There are also more and more comments on social media that are hostile to foreign brand products, and there are even restrictions on foreign brand products in some places. Some time ago, Hunan Yueyang Sanhe Airport banned Tesla electric vehicles from entering the airport on the grounds of &quot;confidential control.&quot; After attracting great attention, Yueyang Airport lifted this restriction, but similar phenomena still exist in many local departments. In addition to Tesla, Apple&#39;s mobile phones and other electronic products also receive special &quot;care&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of restriction on foreign brands has no legal basis. In September 2023, Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning stated at a press conference that China has not issued laws, regulations or policy documents prohibiting the purchase and use of foreign brand mobile phones such as Apple. The reason why some departments and companies ban Tesla cars, Apple mobile phones, etc. is that their cameras, microphones and other sensors may obtain surrounding environment information and upload it abroad, which involves &quot;state secrets&quot; and &quot;personal information security&quot;. However, according to Tesla&#39;s statement, the video captured by its car&#39;s &quot;Sentinel Mode&quot; is only stored in the vehicle&#39;s local storage device and will not be uploaded to the Internet. Other vehicle data will only be uploaded to the company&#39;s data center in China. The iCloud service used by Apple&#39;s domestic users is also operated by the domestic big data company &quot;Cloud Guizhou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Tesla and Apple are foreign brands, their products sold domestically are basically produced in factories in China. Their super factory in Shanghai has more than 10,000 employees. In addition, the localization rate of Tesla&#39;s auto parts has exceeded 95%, which has stimulated the development of many domestic companies in the upstream industrial chain, not only bringing income to the employees of these companies, but also improving the production level of the companies. The improvement of the production capacity of these enterprises has also provided energy for the development of other domestic automobile manufacturers. The same is true for Apple. Not only does its domestic foundries directly provide jobs for hundreds of thousands of people, but it also greatly improves the capabilities of the domestic industrial chain through strict management of domestic suppliers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Introducing foreign capital is not just about hundreds of millions or even billions of money, but more importantly, entrepreneurial spirit and talent, which is to discover or even &quot;create&quot; market opportunities and seize them. , the ability to create social wealth. During the process of reform and opening up, the introduction of foreign investment has played a huge role in promoting China&#39;s economic development. This impetus does not only come from money itself. China&#39;s goal of introducing foreign investment is not only to solve the problem of insufficient domestic development funds, but more importantly, to &quot;learn advanced Western technology and management experience.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it may be the competition, management and other concepts that come with foreign investment that play a greater role in promoting China&#39;s development. It is precisely because of the pressure of foreign capital that China&#39;s market-oriented reform has been accelerated, and domestic enterprises have also strengthened their bodies and developed in the competition with foreign capital. Even though China has now become the world&#39;s second largest economy, it still needs to introduce foreign investment. Because in many areas, China still needs foreign technology and entrepreneurial talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, the State Council issued the &quot;24 Policies and Measures for Attracting Foreign Investment,&quot; emphasizing the need to create a &quot;market-oriented, legal, and international first-class business environment.&quot; A market-oriented and legalized business environment requires that foreign-invested enterprises be treated equally and receive national treatment. As long as they are not within the scope of the negative list stipulated by the state, there cannot be any discrimination or restrictions on foreign investment. The products and services provided by domestic foreign-funded enterprises should also be treated equally with those of other domestic enterprises. Just like although the &quot;Government Procurement Law&quot; stipulates that under normal circumstances government procurement &quot;should purchase domestic goods, projects and services,&quot; the Ministry of Finance issued a special document in 2021 requiring that except for procurement projects involving national security and state secrets, government procurement must not distinguish Treat products produced in China by domestic and foreign-funded enterprises. As long as it is produced within China, regardless of whether its suppliers are domestic or foreign, their equal participation in government procurement should be guaranteed. This special clean-up operation by the Ministry of Commerce also includes the issue of restricting foreign-invested enterprises from participating in local bidding and government procurement as a clean-up matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Ministry of Commerce’s cleanup operation began, social media information showed that some local agencies’ “No Tesla Entry” signs had been removed. Prohibiting discrimination against foreign-owned enterprises is a good start. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人为什么变胖，问题可能没那么简单]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260883]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The global obesity and overweight problems have become increasingly apparent in recent decades. According to data from the World Health Organization, in 2016 Nearly 40% of adults worldwide are overweight, of which 13% are obese. There are approximately 2 billion overweight people. This increase continues despite public health measures to prevent and slow obesity in many countries. Along with the obesity epidemic comes a large disease burden. How to better manage weight has become an urgent problem in the field of health sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Balancing the quality and quantity of carbohydrates&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Carbohydrates, as a major source of dietary energy for people, have long been the focus of weight loss. Coping strategies such as the &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; of eating less or no staple food, or even strictly limiting carbohydrate intake have been derived. The &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; cuts off carbohydrates as an energy source and attempts to promote weight loss by burning fat to provide energy. Although this method has some short-term experimental support, what will happen if it is persisted in the long term is still a mystery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; requires maintaining a high level of fat intake while maximizing carbohydrate intake, which may increase the risk related to cardiovascular disease. In addition, it will also put pressure on the liver, kidneys and maintenance of nutritional balance, and there is a risk of a series of adverse reactions such as cognitive decline, constipation, fatigue, and nausea. Therefore, long-term adherence to such a diet for weight loss remains controversial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with the controversial &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; that strictly limits carbohydrate intake, a diet that reasonably controls carbohydrates has actually been widely recognized, including paying more attention to nutritional balance and simplicity. Processed “Mediterranean Diet” etc. Recently, scientists from Harvard School of Public Health and other institutions also found through long-term observational studies that instead of focusing generally on the total amount of carbohydrate intake, it is better to pay more attention to the quality and source of carbohydrates, so as to achieve better long-term weight management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because their research data shows that some carbohydrate-containing foods do make you fatter as you eat them, but there are also some carbohydrate-rich foods that may actually have a weight loss effect if you eat too much of them. Overall, higher glycemic index and glycemic load will lead to weight gain. Adding 100 grams of starch or added sugar per day increased weight gain by 1.5 kilograms and 0.9 kilograms respectively over four years. Relevant research was published in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) in September 2023. The main sources of daily starch are seeds and tubers such as wheat and rice, which are various staple foods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starchy vegetables such as potatoes and peas, and refined grains are also associated with weight gain. A 100-gram daily intake increase will increase weight gain by 2.6 kilograms and 0.8 kilograms respectively. But if it is non-starchy vegetables and whole grains, the increase in intake will actually reduce weight gain and help control weight. Increasing the intake of non-starchy vegetables by 100 grams per day will reduce weight gain by 3 kilograms, and the intake of 100 grams of whole grains will reduce weight gain by 0.4 kilograms. Similarly, consuming carbohydrates through fruits can also help reduce weight gain, with a daily intake increase of 100 grams corresponding to 1.6 kilograms less weight gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why these data are limited to four years to assess weight change is because some health data in the study are updated on a four-year cycle. Using data from more than 130,000 people in projects such as the Nurses&#39; Health Study, researchers analyzed the relationship between people&#39;s diet and weight changes over more than two decades and discovered these overall patterns of carbohydrates. Over the past two decades, people&#39;s average weight has increased by 8.8 kilograms, about 1.5 kilograms every four years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Highly processed carbohydrates have become a target&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If a person pays more attention to the management of carbohydrate quality and sources, use equal amounts of non-starchy vegetables, fruits and Substituting whole grains for foods like refined grains, starchy vegetables, and sugary drinks will result in less weight gain. In addition to foods such as vegetables and whole grains that are consumed in large amounts, an increase in dietary fiber intake also helps with weight management. Every 10 grams of increase per day corresponds to a reduction of 0.8 kilograms of weight gain. Considering that the age of the people in the study happens to span the middle-aged and elderly stages, including the critical period of weight gain in middle age, this large-sample long-term follow-up study has important reference significance for middle-aged people to strengthen weight management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, although the latest research data has the advantages of large volume and long follow-up time, and can capture more changes in diet and health, there are still some limitations, such as carbohydrate intake and Information such as weight is reported by the respondents themselves. There may be certain errors in these data, which will affect relevant conclusions and interpretations. To better understand the long-term health effects of carbohydrates, more randomized, controlled, long-term studies are needed to further confirm the conclusions in the latest findings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for why people become obese, the most popular explanation is energy imbalance, which is commonly known as &quot;eating more and moving less&quot;, but this is not the exact answer to the common obesity phenomenon in humans. As obesity rates remain high, some scientists think the problem may not be that simple. Two common explanations currently take into account more complex body system factors. For example, one view is that on the basis that energy intake exceeds consumption, because modern people eat too much ultra-processed food with high energy density, there may also be endocrine, metabolic and nervous system effects, making it more difficult for people to eat food. Self-control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another explanation related to insulin is that the hormonal response triggered by a large amount of ultra-processed carbohydrates causes the body to store more energy in fat, resulting in a lack of energy required for basic metabolism of the body. , after the brain recognizes this state, it will issue a hunger command, thus entering a vicious cycle of getting fatter and overeating. While the understanding of obesity remains controversial, these analyzes and a host of health studies have focused on carbohydrates in processed foods, including all types of so-called &quot;junk food&quot; that are high in sugar and fat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ultra-processed carbohydrates are classified as &quot;junk food&quot;, which is not unrelated to the current scientific community&#39;s understanding of the functions of carbohydrates. Carbohydrates are the only macronutrient for which there is no minimum intake requirement. In reality, in some places people eat a lot, but in other places people eat very little. What specific ranges of carbohydrate intake humans need to maintain in order to survive, be healthy, and even live longer are specific questions that need to be answered by scientific evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The risks and costs of eating out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From an evolutionary perspective, larger brain capacity is consistent with the evolutionary process of humans, and larger brain capacity is consistent with the evolutionary process of humans. The brain needs more energy support. After humans entered agricultural civilization, typical lifestyle changes included growing and eating grains, which are foods rich in carbohydrates. For this reason, the human digestive system has become more adapted to starch, but accordingly, new eating habits have also brought about a series of new health problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Latest research suggests that the mechanisms by which carbohydrates, glycemic index, and glycemic load may have negative health effects on weight may include enhanced responses to changes in insulin and other hormones that favor fat accumulation. . In recent years, some studies have shown that in addition to weight gain, the quality of carbohydrates may also increase a series of other health risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, a systematic analysis study published in The Lancet showed that compared with those who ate the least dietary fiber, people who ate the most dietary fiber had better health outcomes. The risks of a range of diseases are 15% to 30% lower, including lower cardiovascular disease mortality, coronary heart disease incidence, stroke incidence and mortality, and lower risks of type 2 diabetes and colorectal cancer. In addition, clinical trial data also shows that eating more dietary fiber will lower blood pressure and total cholesterol. The lowest risk dietary fiber intake is 25 to 29 grams per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, studies have found that whole grain intake may also help reduce overall disease risk. Increasing the intake of dietary fiber in the daily diet, replacing refined grains with whole grains, and eating more coarse grains will not only help with weight management, but also improve people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that with the epidemic of obesity in recent years, scientists have tried to verify a variety of weight loss and weight management strategies, most of which are related to &quot;eating&quot;, including the total energy of meals and the amount of food consumed. time. In 2022, a one-year intermittent fasting trial carried out in China found that while restricting food energy, arranging eating times from 8 am to 4 pm every day and not eating at other times, such a The weight loss effect of this dietary pattern is no better than that of energy restriction alone, indicating the importance of controlling energy intake for weight loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in April 2023, Australian researchers further narrowed the eating time window to 8 am to 12 noon every day, limiting the intake of 30% of the required energy to only these four hours. And you stick to this eating method for three non-consecutive days in a week, and you can eat whatever you want at other times. The experimental results found that under certain circumstances, intermittent fasting that limits meal times still has its own unique effect, not only can Lowering the weight of trial participants could also improve people&#39;s glucose tolerance and reduce their risk of type 2 diabetes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leonie Heilbronn, a professor at the University of Adelaide School of Medicine and others who have long studied fasting and meal times, explained to Southern Weekend reporters that human metabolism is governed by biological rhythms The brain operates downwards, alternating between day and night 24 hours a day. Improper eating time will cause the brain&#39;s light and dark rhythms to be out of sync with the biological clocks in other organs and tissues. Moving meals earlier and avoiding eating at night will help the body coordinate these rhythms. combine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, a randomized controlled trial in the UK also supported the conclusion of eating early, but it was not because of differences in metabolism at different times, but because the study at that time found that if you eat more in the morning, your overall health will be reduced throughout the day. If the meal time is moved forward, people will not feel too hungry that day, and appetite and total energy intake will be controlled. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Weight management should be a long-term plan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For weight control, no matter what the strategy is or how difficult it is, whether it can be persisted in the long term is the key to weight management. key. Otherwise, no matter how radical and rapid the weight loss method is, it will rebound when you can&#39;t persist, and destroy people&#39;s confidence in weight management during the continuous rebound. Some people whose obesity problem is particularly serious and whose weight loss through conventional methods has been ineffective can only reduce their health risks through extremely limited methods such as bariatric surgery. However, this method requires the removal of part of the stomach, which is extremely invasive and does not work. Not suitable for most people who have less severe weight problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, the latest research controls weight by managing the source of carbohydrates, which does not involve harsh food intake restrictions or long fasting times, and has positive implications for people&#39;s long-term weight management. significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the researchers also found that the relationship between carbohydrate sources and weight management was more obvious in overweight or obese people than in people of normal weight, indicating that these people may be more susceptible to weight changes. Sensitive, more fragile, but in turn suggests that those who pay more attention to the sources of carbohydrates in their diet may benefit more from this type of weight management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reflected in specific foods, it is necessary to limit sugary drinks and various types of steamed, fried, and baked refined rice noodles, and instead eat more roughly processed grains, fruits, and non-starchy foods. Vegetables etc. The &quot;Mediterranean diet&quot; widely praised by scientists is actually more scientific in managing carbohydrate sources and maintaining nutritional balance. In addition to consuming more vegetables, fruits, and whole grains, it also eats more beans and nuts, and more Fish and moderate amounts of poultry and dairy, but not a lot of red meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[拿电动汽车对比主战坦克：券商的“奇葩研报”为何层出不穷？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260891]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a screenshot of a research report comparing BYD’s U8 and T-90 main battle tanks was exposed. This screenshot of the research report comes from the special research report on BYD released by the Western Securities R&amp;D Center on October 24, 2023: &quot;BYD (002594.SZ) first coverage report: Cost is the shield, technology is the spear, and the sword points at the global automotive leader&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On page 26 of the research report, in order to present the output power of BYD&#39;s Yi Sifang four-wheel motor, Western Securities compared the output power, engine, and body of BYD&#39;s U8 and T-90 main battle tanks. , amphibious, on-site U-turn, lateral travel, zero-hundred acceleration and the number of driving wheels, and concluded: &quot;The technical indicators of Yi Sifang&#39;s four-wheel motor are comprehensively leading the industry.&quot; Looking up at the amphibious and lateral travel functions of U8, T -90 tanks are &quot;none&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Blue Whale Finance, a relevant person from Western Securities responded that the report was not written by an intern, and that the comparison of BYD’s U8 with main battle tanks was affected by relevant publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the impact of relevant publicity? Previously, many self-media compared BYD’s U8 with tanks. Regardless of whether the research report of Western Securities was influenced by self-media, but comparing electric vehicles with main battle tanks, and then claiming that its technical indicators are comprehensively leading the industry, whether the relevant arguments and conclusions are rigorous and reasonable will naturally be questioned by investors and public opinion. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in June this year, Western Securities and analysts were punished for research reports. According to the warning letter from the Shaanxi Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission: After investigation, the internal control mechanism for the securities research report publishing business of Western Securities is not sound, individual surveys did not fulfill the pre-approval procedures, sales staff participated in the assessment of research report analysts, and compliance management did not cover expert consulting services. The main business links; the quality control and review of research reports are not strict, and some research reports have unreasonable valuation forecasts and imprudent conclusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant securities research report produced by Luo Yamein, the signed analyst of BYD’s research report, has problems such as imprudent research methods, lack of reasonable justification for some assumptions, and insufficient basis for some conclusions. Not only was it shown The warning letter is also recorded in the securities and futures market integrity files. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than half a year later, Western Securities and the same analyst released another controversial research report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this was not done by a securities firm called Western Securities. In recent years, there have been numerous cases of securities companies being fined for &quot;weird research reports&quot;. On December 30, 2021, the Jiangxi Securities Regulatory Bureau issued two law enforcement documents to punish Guosheng Securities and its researchers in the research report on the research report on &quot;Tiangan and Earthly Branches in Time Selection&quot;. On October 18 of that year, Guosheng Securities&#39;s report called &quot;Tiangan Divine Branch&#39;s Application of Time Selection&quot; reported social attention. In the report, the time cycle of how the &quot;Sky and Earthly Branches&quot; dominate the market, and how to apply the &quot;Sky Stem Branch&quot; during the time selection. Liu Fubing, who has issued this research report for more than 12 years, has been on the list of 8 new wealth on the list, and 6 of them won the first place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If the above research report is &quot;not amazingly dead&quot;, it has become a talk. There is also a type of &quot;Strange Research Report&quot; that is more likely to mislead investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In July 2020, the Jiangsu Securities Regulatory Bureau posted a decision on administrative penalty, and the two analysts Ma Haobo, a signature of the two analysts signed by the &quot;Fucheng Deep Report 2: 3: 3: 3: Three 10 billion supporting market value&quot; Tang Weiliang fined a total of 200,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2016, a research report released by Soochow Securities has boldly predicted that the &quot;first share of A -share funeral&quot; Focheng (600965.SH) is the absolute leader of the funeral industry in the future. And give Facheng &quot;buy&quot; rating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, on October 25 of that year, Fucheng announced a &quot;clarification announcement&quot; to clarify the relevant content of the research report. Soochow Securities &quot;Fucheng Research Report&quot; stated that the number of tombs after the third phase of the Phase Three of the Pagoda Cemetery of Fucheng Co., Ltd. reached 400,000, and based on the data, Fusheng shares can get a net profit of 15.5 billion yuan. After investigation, the planning of the Pagoda Cemetery of Fucheng Co., Ltd. planned to build a tomb of about 125,000. The Forte Research Report also stated that the industrial M &amp; A fund jointly established by Fucheng and a investment company has a total size of 10 billion yuan. The scale of the current period is 1 billion yuan, and the size of the subsequent fund is still 9 billion yuan. After investigation, as of October 2016, the size of the above -mentioned mergers and acquisitions funds was only 1 billion yuan. The situation of the subsequent funds also needed to make a decision based on the progress of the first phase of the fund and the quality of the acquisition of assets. Third, the &quot;Fucheng Research Report&quot; stated that the company&#39;s major shareholders of the company were 10 billion in cash and had sufficient funds as the inferior back end of the above -mentioned mergers and acquisitions funds. After investigation, as of October 2016, the major shareholders did not make decisions on this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The research report released by Soochow Securities is very different from the actual data of Focheng&#39;s shares. The source of the letter and whether the data is investigated and verified, I am afraid that they are all confused. How can we afford the credibility of the market? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The so -called research report is an analysis report written by financial institutions such as securities companies, fund companies, banks, etc., which mainly include company analysis reports, industry analysis reports, investment strategy reports, etc. The purpose of the research report is to help investors better understand the market, the company, and the industry in order to be used as a reference. However, the content of the content is full of errors, pointing to Feng Shui, or a gimmick of the comparison of electric vehicles and the main battle tanks, reflecting that some brokers do not pay attention to the professionalism of the research report, and even use the research report as a kind of speculation tool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The motivation for the &quot;Strange Research Report&quot; of the securities firm cannot be simply attributed to the public. In the financial market, information publishing to some extent is a kind of power. Because of this, regulators have corresponding standard standards for financial institutions, listed companies, and media with various investment -oriented information. As a professional information provider, the research report of securities firms affects investors&#39; decisions to a fairly extent. However, in the process of pursuing the so -called market influence, some brokers created some shocking remarks to attract attention and attention. There will be traffic or interest considerations, and may even disturb or distort the market trend. Since the securities firms are also one of the important positions of the stock market, if there is a brokerage company publishing a research report from a listed company or a certain section in an exaggerated way, it is not typical to buy or sell the corresponding stocks secretly in the country. Manipulating the stock market behavior? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this regard, the regulatory has also issued many relevant management new policies in recent years. In May last year, the regulatory authorities sent the &quot;Notice on the&quot; Double Random &quot;on -site inspection of the&quot; Double Random &quot;inspection of securities research reporting business&quot; to various securities firms. The report shows that in 2022, the special “double random” on -site inspection work was conducted in the industry&#39;s research reporting business, covering a total of 45 securities companies and 300 research newspapers. In September of that year, China Securities Association reiterated the self -discipline management of securities securities research business, including more than 1%of the shares holding the research bid to disclose and the research report must not be operated within two trading days; The &quot;Qi Qi Research Report&quot; continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This shows that the punishment and regulatory efforts of the supervisory layers need to be strengthened for the strange research report. The warning letter, incorporated into the integrity file, etc., cannot touch the core interests of relevant personnel and securities firms, so that they would rather have a short -term market effect, and they are unwilling to adhere to the way of compliance. The regulatory authorities have made clear the responsibility of the production report and publishing of securities firms, and continue to increase the punishment of illegal acts. Fang may be able to stop the vicious cycle of the brokerage research newspaper&#39;s &quot;bad currency elimination of good coins&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; (&quot;>; ( This article is only the personal point of view of the author, does not represent the position of our newspaper) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[18亿元起拍，衡阳政务数据资源特许经营权转让为何暂停？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260897]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG ALT = &quot;Hengyang&#39;s transfer is considered to be the&quot; first shot &quot;of government data, which has attracted widespread attention. Visual China/Figure &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17a4e58168.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;heart =&quot; 810 &quot;data data -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/17a4e58168.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258771&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Hengyang&#39;s transfer is considered to be the&quot; first shot &quot;of government data, which has attracted widespread attention. Visual China/Picture &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 15, 2023, Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center issued a notice saying that according to the letter of letter from Fang Hengyang City Administrative Examination and Approval Service Bureau, the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Resources and Smart &quot;Transaction project&quot; trading activity of urban franchise operation rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past five days, the official website of the Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center only issued an announcement that it will use online bidding to transfer Hengyang Municipal Affairs Data Resources and Smart City Frank Management Rights with a starting price of 1.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There were no places to bid to transfer government data resources by franchising before. Therefore, this round of transfer is considered to be the &quot;first shot&quot; of government data and attracted widespread attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;After receiving a letter from the Hengyang City Administrative Examination and Approval Service Bureau, the transaction was suspended, but the letter did not explain the specific reason.&quot; The company has come to inquire about the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two staff members of the Hengyang City Administrative Examination and Approval Service Bureau confirmed to the reporters from the south weekend that because they received the notice of the higher authorities, they suspended the above -mentioned franchise transfer transfer project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The state is working on this (public data) work, they will give some guidance before doing it.&quot; A staff member of the Hengyang City Administrative Approval Service Bureau told the Southern Weekend that the project was a suspension state. The scheme also needs to be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; It does not involve national security, business secrets and personal privacy &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; According to the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center, the transfer was approved by the Hengyang Municipal Government. The subject matter was divided into two parts: government data data Resources and smart cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In December 2021, Hengyang, Hunan, released the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Opening and Open Administration of Government Data of Hengyang Municipal Affairs&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the management measures). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is clear that the government data refers to the government affairs department produced or obtained in the process of performing their duties. Resources, including information resources that are directly collected by various government affairs departments directly or through third -party, authorized management in accordance with the law, and information resources formed by the need to rely on the government information system due to their responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Encourage the use of information security, personal privacy, and information under corporate business secret conditions.&quot; Administrative measures stated that it is necessary Operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The management measures stated that it involves national security, business secrets, and personal privacy, or public data that cannot be opened in accordance with laws and regulations is not open. If national secrets, work secrets, business secrets, and personal privacy leaks, they will be handled in accordance with the State Confidential Law and relevant regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In June 2023, Guizhou issued a document requesting that the competent authorities at all levels of the big data authorities uniformly authorized the market entities with conditions to operate government data at the same level, and develop Data services and products, and trading through the Guiyang Big Data Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above management measures of Hengyang wrote that data ownership belongs to the government and authorizes Hengyang Development Investment Group Co., Ltd. to develop and operate with a franchise. The corporate warning channel shows that the company is the largest urban investment platform in Hengyang, with assets exceeding 140 billion yuan and 100%of the Hengyang SASAC. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; However, the effectiveness of the government data operation of Hengyang Development Investment Group was considered to be improved by Hengyang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On July 27, 2023, the official website of the Hengyang Discipline Inspection Commission issued the &quot;Notice of the Communist Party of Hengyang City Development Investment Group Co., Ltd. on the Inspection and Rectification Exhibition.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second notification question is &quot;the implementation of the municipal party committee and the municipal government&#39;s decision -making deployment.&quot; In this regard, the rectification situation wrote, &quot;Accelerating some of the asset resources that have been infused into the municipal party committee and municipal government ... Actively strive to complete the implementation plan for the implementation of government data resources (including Hengyang Mass APP) and smart cities.&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; What contents of smart cities are involved, and the official website and trading accessories of Hengyang City Public Resources Trading Center are not mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The pricing method of public data is not clear. &lt;/H4>; &lt;p>; On the official website of the Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center, this government data resources are transferred to a bidding method. The starting price is 1.8 billion yuan, each time The price increase is 10 million yuan. In the transaction attachment, the starting price is the evaluation price of the target, but the column of the evaluation agency and the evaluation benchmark date is blank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Why does the project evaluation price reach 1.8 billion yuan? The staff of Hengyang City Administrative Examination and Approval Service Bureau did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the pricing of data resources is a problem in the industry. In February 2023, Zhao Jingwu, an associate professor at the School of Law of Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, said that the data valuation index was not uniform and the data quality standards were difficult to conclude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He believes that even in general data trading activities, the so -called market pricing is just the result of self -negotiation between the two parties of the transaction. The market provides sufficient reference basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Government data is facing the same problem. On November 16, at the main forum of the China Data Element Industry Innovation Conference in 2023, Wang Jiandong, deputy director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission, said, &quot;At the end of this year or before the beginning of next year, the government guidance pricing method may be introduced to public data. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The official website of Hengyang City Public Resources Trading Center shows that the return mechanism for government data resources franchise management rights projects is&quot; users pay &quot;. During the franchise period, franchise operators can collect fees from users within the scope of the franchise as a return on project construction. However, the official website has not announced the specific period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A company where an interviewee is located is responsible for building a government data platform for a province in the south. He explained to the reporter from the southern weekend that users who pay for it mainly refer to enterprises with informatization business in various places, not individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before that, for public data, Hangzhou, Qingdao and other places also tried to authorize operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In September 2023, Hangzhou issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for Public Data Authorization Operation (Trial)&quot;. According to the document, it is necessary to determine the main body of the authorized operation platform operation, and with the consent of the municipal government, it should be responsible for the construction and operation, data management, operation and maintenance, and security guarantee of the authorized operation platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The plan of Hangzhou states that priority supports credit, transportation, medical, health, employment, social security, education, technology, finance, corporate registration supervision, housing construction, provident fund, public safety and other fields to carry out public data authorization operations It is led by the field competent authorities. Open open public data shall not be authorized to operate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 卞建林：刑诉法要保障个人权利]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260865]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 11:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Dr. File: &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p >; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Bian Jianlin, New China first litigation law law PhD. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1953 Born in Taixing, Jiangsu in October. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1960 -In 1965, Kaijiang Primary School, Taixing Town, Taixing County, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1965 -In 1971, Junior and High School, Taixing Middle School, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1972 -In 1979, workers of commercial refrigerated shipbuilding manufacturers in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1979 From September to July 1983, undergraduate students at the Department of Law, China University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; September 1983-7, 1986, 7 On the month, a graduate student at the Graduate School of Political Science and Law of China and obtained a master&#39;s degree in criminal litigation law. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; In August 1986, stayed in school and served as a full-time researcher of the Institute of Legalism. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; In September 1987, the Graduate School of Chinese University of Political Science and Law studied litigation law graduate students; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; July 1991, a doctorate degree in litigation law, the first litigation law in the country Professional PhD; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1992 associate professor, Professor in July 1997; &lt;/span in &lt;/span >; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; May 2000 as a doctoral tutor for criminal litigation law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; In 1991, he served as deputy director of the China Institute of Legal and Law of the Chinese University of Political Science and Law, and was appointed as the director in 1995; p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 2001 to 2006, as executive vice president of the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; August 1993-August 1994, a visiting scholar at New York University Law School; &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; August 1999-August 2000, high-level visit at Harvard University and Yale University Law School Scholars; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 2006-2022, served as the Criminal Procedure Law Research Association of the Chinese Law Society Director, president of the Chinese Criminal Procedure Law Research Association; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; 2006-2019, let him serve any Dean of the Institute of Law Law of China University of Political Science and Law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; 2003 to 2013, served as the State Council, served as the State Council Members of the 4th and Fifth Law Discipline Review Team of Degree Committee. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;The first PhD in lawsuit law in New China. /Image/23/11/18/728ed89d3b.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 745 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/dedias/image/23/111 /18/728ed89d3b.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 258737 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; The first PhD in litigation law in New China. (Photo of the respondents) &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 26-year-old admitted to college and graduated from a 38-year-old doctor. This year, Jian Jianlin was 70 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At 2 pm on October 18, 2023, Bian Jianlin appeared at the door of the office of the University of China and Law on time. Pants, a red paper bag in his hand, containing three -volume of &quot;governing the country and criminal litigation according to law -Jianlin Law Collection&quot;. For his 70th birthday this month, the publisher deliberately planned the collection of the paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1979, dragging the three-year-old tail. After 8 years of graduation of high school, Bian Jianlin left his hometown of Jiangsu and entered the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;. The college, which is the current University of Political Science and Law. Relying on the employees provided by the state, Jian Jianlin read the master all the way. &quot;A major event happened&quot; before life was about to move towards another fork. In 1986, the third batch of doctoral points in the country was determined that two doctoral tutors of the Law Professor of China University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1987, Professor Chen Guangzhong, a master of &quot;Criminal Procedure Law&quot;, recognized by Master Jianlin. Four years later, he became the first doctoral student in criminal litigation law independently trained in New China, and embarked on a career development path similar to his mentor. To this day, Bian Jianlin has trained 87 doctors and 11 post -doctoral post -doctors. He is a part -time professor at Jilin University, Wuhan University, Central South University of Finance and Law, East China University of Political Science and Law, Northwestern University of Political Science and Law, and the People&#39;s Public Security University of China, and National Prosecutor&#39;s College. In social media, he always actively participates in various seminars and academic lectures, and shares his understanding and suggestions on the construction of criminal proceedings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unwilling to advertise himself, Bian Jianlin has never talked about his past experience in public. Even for two hours of interviews, the topic could not get around his mentor. And he seemed to be an ordinary student who was &quot;older, late school&quot;, and he was lucky to go to the present in the mistake. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; accidentally becoming &quot;first&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong >; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot; collection, you seem to have mentioned your experience in school for the first time. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I don&#39;t like to talk about my resume, this collection has academics for me The meaning of career summary, so I said a few words in the preface. I am the first time I am early in the University of Political Science and Law. It is the first after the recurrence of the school, but compared with other earlier scholars, the age of enrollment is relatively older. Fortunately, my scholar blog is in one go, and it can be considered back for some time. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; Before being admitted to the Beijing School of Political Science and Law in 1979, what are you doing, and how do you think of law? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; After graduating from high school in 1971, I went to work in a provincial factory. Later, the college entrance examination was restored, but after all, it was not a required option. Of my high school classmates, few people later went to college. At that time, everyone had a job, and even married and had children. But I still have a little bit of my mind. I have such an aspiration to take the test. As for learning law, it is almost an inevitable choice. First of all, during the ten -year turmoil, our generation was abandoned. Mathematical chemicals were basically not studied. It was seriously partial. It was not easy to test science and engineering. Foreign languages, Chinese, history and laws are definitely the most attractive. Many of the books read in the past are solved cases. Disclosure, toilet grievances, punish evil and remove rape, and extend justice. Naturally, there is a legal feeling. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; Why study criminal litigation law? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I was a legal major in the school, and there was no more segmentation in the school. major. When I was close to graduation, I was determined to take the postgraduate entrance examination. According to my personality and interest, I did n’t like civil laws. I liked “criminal name”, so the professional choice should be criminal law. However, the choice of criminal lawsuit is accidental. In the school, there was only one subject in the school&#39;s criminal law law and the master&#39;s degree in the criminal law. In the postgraduate entrance examination, I went home for the Spring Festival, and I was going to take the exam after the Spring Festival. I think that the history of the legal system is to work hard to prepare for the exam, and the ancient Chinese is always a bit found, so it is the difference of thoughts. The choice of the test subjects determines the professional direction at once, so it is not that I realized the program from then on. The value and importance, because in fact, the physical law is still in front of the procedure method at that time. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; Law is a practical discipline. During the study, have you never thought of joining the practice? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The method of learning must be used. In addition, I was older when I was enrolled. I was able to study an undergraduate in that era. I also studied for a master&#39;s degree, so I was facing two choices at that time. One was to follow the wishes of my family to return to Jiangsu. Mature judges are more interested in me; if they stay in Beijing, they want to go through an old leader of the Ministry of Public Security to the International Criminal Police Organization of the China National Central Bureau. It really had thought, but in the end, these two options gave up, and did not implement the extent to the signing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; Why did you give up? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In 1986, before I graduated from my master&#39;s degree, the school was approved by two doctoral points. The two teachers were identified as Bo Zao, Professor Wang Yan and Professor Chen Guangzhong. Teacher Chen was responsible for litigation law. They are also the first doctoral supervisors of the University of Political Science and Law. After the doctor&#39;s point was approved, Mr. Chen talked to me once. First, I told me that there was a chance to continue his studies; the second was sure to me. Teacher Chen was looking for me, and I was more tempted, although I did not fully appreciate the school&#39;s superiority at that time. The most important point is that my nature is always uneasy. There is a spirit of upward, and there is always no thoughts such as Xiao Fu. In this way, I decided to continue reading the blog after graduation. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; In 1986, you obtained a master&#39;s degree, and the doctoral point was approved in the same year. How can you read Bo a year later? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Before and after graduation, I started preparing for Kaobo. However, although the doctoral point was approved at that time, the preparations for the publication and listing of the society were not sufficient. The reasons for all aspects caused the two doctoral points to have no enrollment. However, it was just that Mr. Chen was the deputy dean of the Graduate School at the time, and the school established a new research institution, namely the Chinese Institute of Legalism, and Mr. Chen also served as the director. So I stayed in the school to work in the Chinese Institute of Legalism, engaged in full -time research, do topics, and write articles. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; How many doctoral students studying with you under the door of Professor Chen? Why can you become the first doctoral student? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Frankly, in the first year of enrollment, there are candidates in the minds of the mentor. However, applying for the exam must follow the formal process. At that time, it was not like now that after the test was basically judged on the spot, and soon knew the results. In the end, Mr. Chen recruited me and also recruited one of our schools. He was a master&#39;s degree in criminal law in 1984. It was just a night. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is also a coincidence that if the school recruits a doctorate in 1986, then his master&#39;s degree has not graduated, we can not be a classmate . However, although the two of us are the first doctoral students, he is full -time, and I have stayed in school and belongs to the job. In accordance with the degree regulations of the country at that time, the study time was more appropriate than the full -time. As for how long it was extended, there was no clear regulation. So I extended a year and graduated in 4 years. If you are calculated at this time, you may graduate from me first, then I will not become the first doctoral degree in the criminal lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But the same school brother later went to study in the United States, and then he never returned, leaving me alone. Later, I joked and said that if he didn&#39;t leave, he would definitely graduate in front of me. The crown of the first doctor of lawsuit was him. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; &quot;Following Mr. Following&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; South China Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The first 18 doctoral doctors were born in 1983, but the first doctoral degree winner graduated in 1987. In a group of disciplines, law is not a niche, but the time to cultivate a doctorate in law is not too early. What do you think? &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I think the reason why the doctor of law is a little later is a little bit later, First, the gold content of the doctoral point at that time was very high. At that time, the approval of the doctoral point and the confirmation of the blog director needed the approval of the Degree Committee of the State Council, which was strictly controlled. The second reason is that from the perspective of teachers and the level of research, the law of law was also a scarce discipline at the time, and did not have the conditions for training doctors. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; In 1988, Professor Chen Guangzhong edited the book &quot;Comparative Research on Foreign Criminal Procedures&quot;. Three years later, your doctoral dissertation &quot;Research on Criminal Prosecution System Comparison&quot; passed. From the perspective of professional research, Professor Chen&#39;s impact on you is very big? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Mr. Chen has always attached importance to the understanding and reference of the foreign litigation system. When we were still studying for a master&#39;s degree, the textbook materials were very lacking. Basically, they were compiled by the textbooks of various schools and printed themselves. When Teacher Chen was a graduate dean, a subject brought from the Social Sciences Institute was a foreign criminal prosecution. Program comparative research. At that time, it has been reform and opening up. Encouraging the use of the world&#39;s vision to study China. Based on a group of experts in law, Mr. Chen absorbed some scholars in our school and other schools to do this work together to do this work together . A few of us who were still studying for a master&#39;s degree also participated in a part. I wrote a chapter, that is, for compulsory medical measures, but did not sign separately and completed it under the guidance of the mentor. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At that time, this book was the first domestic comparative system to study foreign criminal litigation procedures. If you have something abroad, you must read this book. For those who are involved in writing this book, because writing requires research on foreign information, only the University of Political Science and Law had this condition at that time, so it was the first step in my academic perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kaiti_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In the article, you call Professor Chen &quot;Thailand in New China Criminal Procedure Law&quot;. Do you have any observations of his studies and people? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Mr. Chen is a recognized master, the founder and leader of our discipline people. I feel that Mr. is learning. The biggest specialty is the head of the family. He has a lot of rivers, so he has a big deal, so he suddenly surpassed other teachers of his peers and let others be overwhelmed. The second is to use people to make good use of people. Every time he writes things and does project, he can always give the relevant content to the most suitable candidate; the third is to be able to pay attention to accepting new things, and to guide students to continuously improve himself. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition to learning, Mr.&#39;s sense of responsibility and mission is also very strong. He cares for current affairs, and is now 93 years old and is still paying attention to social phenomena and judicial practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Does personal characteristics affect you? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Started behind the sir. In addition to the teacher -apprentice relationship, the location also determines why my life is closer to life, knowledge, and gentleman. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>; You and Professor Chen have been promoting the localization of some extra -domain experience. In the process, does reform and opening up have a impact? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Mr. Chen is the iconic figure of the criminal proceedings law in my country, and the science of criminal litigation law The improvement of development and criminal proceedings can be said to have contributed greatly and well -contained. From the perspective of participation in legislation, when the Criminal Procedure Law was formulated in 1979, scholars participated less. At that time, Mr. Chen was still in Guangxi. I felt that this was his regret. The amendment of the Criminal Procedure Law in 1996 was an opportunity to make up. Mr. Chen played a great role in revision. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; I still remember that in the winter of 1992, after Mr. Chen became the principal of China University of Political Science and Law, the first lecture was at school. In the international student building that has been demolished now, the director of the Criminal Law Office of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress of the National People&#39;s Congress came with the director of the Criminal Law Office, and then he was brewing the law. In 1993, because he assisted Mr. Chen to promote the first amendment of the Criminal Procedure Law, I was sent to New York University as a core member of the research group. Later, the inspection delegation led by Mr. Chen went to several countries in Europe for inspection, and the director of the Criminal Law Office of the Law and Industry Commission also participated in the inspection. After returning to China, the Law Working Committee officially wrote a letter to the school, and commissioned Mr. Chen to bring the research team to the amendment of the law. One year later, Mr. Chen&#39;s research team submitted 350,000 words of &quot;Draft of the Criminal Procedure Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; to the Law and Industry Commission, of which 65%of the provisions were absorbed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition to domestic project projects, I assisted Mr. Chen for some international exchanges and cooperation to carry out some comparative research. For example, students are sent to study abroad, translated and published some criminal proceedings of representative countries, and promoted the implementation of the international human rights conventions and the implementation of the United Nations criminal justice standards in China, and so on. It should be said that it has done a lot of beneficial things to promote the development of my country&#39;s criminal proceedings system, and has also promoted the discipline construction and talent training of the litigation law of China University of Political Science and Law. These University of Political Science and Law were unique at that time. For other schools, there were neither the strength of this team, but also the necessary conditions and abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Modify the Constitution in 2004 At that time, Professor Chen proposed to write &quot;national respect and protection of human rights&quot; into the constitution; in 2012, when the second prosecution law was repaired for the second time, this one was written into the criminal lawsuit law. As his student, you have always advocated that the criminal lawsuit should protect personal rights. Why do you have always paid attention to this issue? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 卞 卞: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The relationship between human rights protection and criminal litigation is very close. The criminal lawsuit is a typical field of public power, and it is the heavy weapon for national governance. For a long time, due to the influence of ideas, institutions, and even ideology, we regard criminal lawsuits as a contest between the country and the crime, emphasizing the punishment of crimes, which leads to the power of the national special agencies in the lawsuit. Correspondingly, the rights and interests of criminal suspects, defendants, and other participants will not be fully protected. From the perspective of social development, the country&#39;s comprehensively promoting the governance of the country according to law and building a rule of law in accordance with the country must pass the rule of law and regulate public power through procedures, so as not to let power alienation and abuse. Through their own efforts, we strengthen human rights protection in justice, affect legislation, and improve judicial. Under the leadership of Mr. Chen, we also made our own efforts and contributions for this. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; &quot;The law of apprentices is not enough&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft: left; &quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; In the previous school lecture, you discussed the case of unjust and false cases. Judicial progress, from the perspective of past news reports, the agent lawyers of many cases are called &quot;dead lawyers&quot;. What do you think of this group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;卞建林：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;辩护制度和律师职业体现了一个国家的法治水平。 If the level of lawyers in a country is weak and the defense system is not sound, the progress of criminal prosecution is impossible. 1979年制定刑诉法时，基本上没有律师，1980年才有律师暂行条例，因此立法关于律师辩护的规定是比较落后的。但是从1996年开始几次刑诉法修订都对律师辩护制度作出完善，总体而言辩护制度的进步是有目共睹的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但同时也应看到，关于律师辩护的法律规定，特别是司法实践中律师辩护还是存在不少问题。我觉得其中一个重要原因就是没找到对律师职业和律师辩护的准确定位。在刑事诉讼中，辩护律师的职责是为被告人辩护，从事实、证据、法律适用、程序运作等各个角度挑毛病，发现问题，以促进案件的公正处理，从而提升法治水平。在性质上，律师不是行使公权力，不是办案机关的成员。而我们对律师的管理方式不一样，律师由司法行政机关管理，而司法行政机关又属于国家专门机关的组成部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在司法实践中，律师为了提供有效辩护，为了维护当事人合法权益，或者为了使法定程序得到遵守，需要在履行辩护职责时较真，有时会和办案机关办案人员产生冲突，因此有些律师被称作“死磕派律师”。但他们如果不较真，不死磕，就维护不了当事人利益，也不能正常进行辩护工作。最近又发生了一些极端的例子，如广西来宾一法院，强制律师进行安检，百般刁难，侵犯律师的正当权益，产生很坏的影响，受到全国人民的关注，也受到最高法院的点名。我想这样极端的事情发生后，整个法院系统都应引以为戒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;似乎这种矛盾在我们的很多法律制度中都会存在。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;卞建林：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;徒法不足以自行。纸面上的法要成为行动中的法，确实需要时间，在执行过程中也会出现各种问题。一定意义上说，我国目前司法实践中出现的一些问题，或者面临的困境，很多也是制度发展以后带来的。有些本来看起来很好的事情，但真正做起来却很难。可能会触动一些人的利益，甚至会激化矛盾。我认为发展中的问题还是要靠发展来解决，一方面在制度设计时要更多地了解情况，关注实践；另一方面法律一旦被修改，就必须维护法律的权威，办案机关要严格执法，带头守法，切实遵守法律规定的程序。 &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>;以前大家都说法学是人文社科，现在又说法学是人文社科里的工科，你怎么看这种观点？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;卞建林：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;毫无疑问，法学是人文社会科学，至少是门学问，或者说是科学，同时它也确实具有工科的一些属性，尤其是我们这个学科，应用性、操作性都很强。我们过去学习时，学的是“刑事诉讼法”，现在叫“刑事诉讼法学”，多了一个“学”字，其实是意识到这是个科学，是个知识体系。不仅仅是对法律作出表义的解释，而且用它来治理社会，达到良好的效果。以对案件事实的查明为例，不单单是认识论上的问题，还涉及价值论、方法论，要以正当程序来规制办案机关的权力行使。程序法总体而言是个操作规范，要有一套具体的原则规则、方法程序和制度规范，而且要细致缜密，具有可操作性，使诉讼活动有法可依。 &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>;>; &quot;>;从四十多年的求学、学术经历走过来，你有什么经验能向年轻学子们分享吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;卞建林：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;无论是做学问还是做老师，其实我都是跟陈先生学的，他为我们树立了榜样，教导我们要有爱国忧民之心，要有开放的视野，钻研的精神，这也是我做学问时努力遵循的。除此之外，我也经常提醒学生，要关心时事，关注当下。很多事情每天就发生在我们身边，或者每天都有与我们专业密切相关的事例，不要充耳不闻，漠不关心。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;至于怎么做学问、怎么写文章，这确实不是一个容易的事情。我觉得首先个人要努力，同时也需要机遇。像我们当年读书时，应该说机会还多一点，在我们前面由于断代而缺人，而社会又急需人才，这样才会有什么这个第一个，那个第一个。现在法学变成了显学，年轻人压力很大，但机会却不是很多，那就需要更加勤奋，倍加努力，要沉得下心，耐得住寂寞，莫辜负青春年华，真学有所成，会有用武之时和适当回报的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《等待戈多》作者最喜欢的戏剧来中国，观众看得很精神]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A black box stood on the stage. &quot;Endgame&quot; had not officially started, but the two characters were already inside. Extremely similar clips are repeated over and over again, as if the stage has turned into a machine that plays on a loop due to malfunction. The servant Clover wrung his fingers and walked the same route repeatedly with a strange gait. He stepped back from the door to the right of Master Ham&#39;s wheelchair, walked to the corner on the left, and then to the door on the right, taking fourteen precise steps, every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue has not changed either. &quot;Do you want me to leave you?&quot; &quot;Of course.&quot; &quot;Then I will leave you.&quot; &quot;You can&#39;t leave me.&quot; &quot;Then I won&#39;t leave you.&quot; The door was opened and closed again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1953, &quot;Waiting for Godot&quot; brought Beckett worldwide fame, but his favorite work was &quot;Endgame&quot; written four years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258749&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; will be performed at the 10th Wuzhen International Theater Festival in 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This play shows four deformed people in an empty house that is approaching the end of the world. : The master Ham is paralyzed from the lower body, blind, and has been sitting in a wheelchair; the servant Clover has a disease in his knees and cannot sit down. Ham&#39;s parents, Nag and Nell, have lost their lower limbs and live in two trash cans. The relationships between masters and servants, husbands and wives, and parents and children all show an extremely cruel side, but they are interdependent and inseparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the impression of Tobias Bianconi, Director General of the International Theater Association, in the past, the audience&#39;s reaction to Beckett and even absurdist plays was sometimes &quot;very frustrating and unhappy&quot;, but After he walked out of the theater, he found that after watching this version of the Vienna Volkstheater&#39;s performance, the Chinese audience was full of energy and had lively discussions. They all felt that the play was very fresh. &quot;Why is there such a reaction? What is the background that makes the audience like this play so much?&quot; he was curious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 20th century, which experienced the ravages of two world wars and was immersed in industrialization and the post-industrial era, the rationalism admired by Western civilization fell into crisis, belief in God collapsed, and self-doubt and self-denial became the themes of the times. This also brought profound conceptual changes to drama. What Beckett&#39;s drama expresses is the antagonistic relationship between human beings and nature, society, self and others who are completely alienated in social crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Absurd drama, which was born in Paris, France, in the early 1950s, was echoed again in Wuzhen, China, seventy years later. &quot;At the beginning, we thought the most exciting thing was this very unhealthy and toxic relationship. Later we discovered that it had some parts related to war. As it slowly developed, we found that it might be related to climate change. Recently, We found that it was combined with the COVID-19 epidemic.&quot; During the dialogue, theater director and German director Kai Vogels said that this version of &quot;Endgame&quot; has been performed for eleven years. &quot;The point of it being constantly performed is that it is always new. , what we see from this drama keeps changing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18 /yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.j pg&quot; data -key=&quot;258748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; was written in the late 1950s. The version that came to China has already been sold in Europe Acted for eleven years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vogels refined the four characters into two clown-like people, retaining the main theme A very tense contrast between servants: Ham is physically disabled, but has the power to control Clover; Clough is relatively able to move freely, but is always dominated by his master to do unnecessary trivial things, and his spirit tends to be paralyzed. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most eye-catching adaptation is Vogels’ emphasis on the sense of looping. The line, which was on an infinite loop before the show even started, only appeared once in the original script. Vogels uses this as the opening or closing line of every dialogue, repeating it a dozen times throughout the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new plot in the play brings an &quot;anti-climax&quot;: after Clover struggled, he shot Hamm, but the expected relief brought by death did not happen. After the monologue, Ham suddenly answered and got up from the ground, as if nothing had happened. Clover and he returned to their usual endless conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Beckett actually demonstrated a ritual cycle on the stage. The ending of this ritual cycle is satisfaction, nothingness, or the end of the world. Everyone can see it differently. Each point has its own interpretation, and what I present on the stage also has this meaning.&quot; At the beginning of the rehearsal, Voges hoped to show the inextricable cycle of repetition on the stage without making the audience feel bored. This balance Feeling is what he is looking for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1998 Vogels has been a theater and opera director in Austria and Germany. German drama is relatively lagging behind in digital innovation. From 2010 to 2020, while serving as the artistic director of the Dortmund Theater in Germany, Vogels began to try to combine digital media with drama and introduce digital thinking to the drama stage. He is a pioneer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among these works, digital techniques such as VR, real-time images, and on-site editing are emerging in endlessly. &quot;Endgame&quot; pursues Beckett&#39;s minimalist style. However, the artificially isolated cramped space, heavy metal-style amplified sound effects, The sudden switching of dazzling lights, the characters&#39; mechanically looping movements and lines, all give this picture of the human spiritual wasteland a cold science fiction color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more traditional images such as &quot;desert&quot; and &quot;dead branches&quot; in Beckett&#39;s original work are missing. In terms of stage design, the play chose a form that abstracted away from reality. Like the door, the few sets and props are all outlined with white chalk lines. Three-dimensional life seems to be locked in two-dimensional space. Machine guns and toy dogs are just thin wooden boards hanging on the wall when they are not picked out by actors and held in their hands. The clock has no hands and the flowers in the vase are out of proportion. The only real objects are the wooden chair with armrests in the center of the stage and the light bulb hanging in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors&#39; performances are consistent with German precision, and they achieve the ultimate in repetitive movements with slight changes. The actor who played Ham sat in a chair with his eyes closed throughout the performance, but still showed a strong sense of dominance and oppression in the relationship through his tone and gestures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The voice can be called the third &quot;starring&quot; of this drama, expanding the information and emotional density in the minimalist world. Clough&#39;s footsteps continued to echo in the space, powerful, but as flat as the scenery, with no specific sense of direction. Footsteps create a strong conflict with directionlessness. Every time Clover dropped something he was holding, there was a loud cracking sound, whether it was a telescope, a machine gun, or a toy dog. The laws of the physical world break down here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two people, who are both master and servant and father and son, are imprisoned in a lifeless atmosphere. The room they were in was, in a sense, like the final game board in a chess match. Ham is the general on the chessboard and needs to ensure that he is in the &quot;center&quot; of the room, controlling his pieces. The little soldier Clover could barely move a few steps, but under the command of blind Ham, the situation was certain to lose, but they could not and did not dare to leave the room, just like the chess pieces could not leave the chessboard. &quot;There is no nature anymore&quot; outside the house. Even when I opened the window, I saw &quot;ZERO&quot; written on the blackboard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They passed the time by teasing, controlling, and torturing each other, telling the old stories again, and looking at the window that they had looked at countless times, hoping that something would happen. What happened in front of my eyes was that other people passed by the window. However, their expectations were all in vain, and all their actions no longer made much sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the play, I realized that the beginning was the end. &quot;What time is it?&quot; &quot;Same as usual.&quot; They repeated the dialogue at the opening. Everything stopped suddenly, leaving silence and darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260877]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 08:59:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Miracle Doctor&quot; sells a bunch of titles to patients. Nongjian illustration&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;&quot;Miracle doctors&quot; sell a bunch of titles to their patients. Nongjian Illustration&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao’s “old Chinese medicine doctor” Hou Yuanxiang, who pretended to be an expert and professor and practiced medicine illegally for more than ten years, fell for his homemade “anti-cancer drug” - in February 2023, Hou Yuanxiang was arrested by Qingdao at first instance The Huangdao District People&#39;s Court of the city sentenced him to 12 years in prison and fined him 12 million yuan for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Hou Yuanxiang, his daughter, son, wife and former son-in-law were also sentenced for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 11 to 3 years respectively. In addition, the son of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s third sister was also involved in the case. He was sentenced to 11 years in prison for &quot;fraud&quot; and &quot;harboring&quot; in the first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total prison term for the above six people is 50 years, and the total fine is 29.8 million yuan. Southern Weekend reporters searched online for judgment documents and found that among counterfeit drug cases in recent years, the first-instance verdict in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case was extremely rare in terms of heavy sentencing and high fines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the case has not yet been settled. After the first-instance verdict, as Hou Yuanxiang and others filed an appeal, many self-media appeared on the Internet to &quot;cry out injustice&quot; for them. Some associated the case with the &quot;folk traditional Chinese medicine&quot; group, believing that &quot;if this lawsuit is lost, almost all folk Chinese medicine practitioners must close their doors.&quot; (For details, please see the report &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260879&quot;>;&quot;The Online Public Opinion War on the &quot;Miracle Cancer Doctor&quot;&lt;/a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s agent The lawyer questioned the characterization of the drugs involved in the case, arguing that after the revision of the Drug Administration Law in 2019, the threshold for identification of counterfeit drugs has been raised. Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is made of traditional Chinese medicinal materials and should not be identified as counterfeit drugs. Hou Yuanxiang does not constitute “production.” , the crime of selling counterfeit medicines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 30, 2023, the Qingdao Intermediate People’s Court ruled to revoke the original judgment and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the first-instance judgment “had unclear facts and insufficient evidence.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;old Chinese doctor&quot; who can&#39;t take the pulse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After being criminally detained on February 17, 2022, Hou Yuanxiang only stayed in the detention center for more than 20 days. After that, the police changed the enforcement measures to &quot;residential surveillance&quot; because of his illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Gang, the second-instance attorney, met Hou Yuanxiang after the National Day in 2023. According to him, two policemen worked in three shifts, watching him 24 hours a day, &quot;maybe because there are more patients coming to him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, 66-year-old Hou Yuanxiang is from Shandong A native of Yishui County, Linyi City, the province, he once worked as a teacher in the county, but later took a leave of absence without pay and became a doctor. After that, he moved his family to Weifang and settled down. Around 2019, after purchasing real estate in Qingdao, Hou Yuanxiang and his wife and their daughter Hou Jing and his wife both moved their household registrations to Qingdao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s confession cited in the first-instance verdict did not explain his medical experience. Some self-media said that Hou Yuanxiang studied under two &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot; Zhang Moumou and Lou Moumou, but Southern Weekend reporters did not find any information about the latter two as &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is certain that Hou Yuanxiang is not from a &quot;family of traditional Chinese medicine&quot; or &quot;six generations practicing medicine&quot; as some self-media said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to what Hou Yuanxiang’s wife and sister told China News Weekly, Hou Yuanxiang was originally a primary school teacher and started studying medicine when he was about 40 years old. He had “several teachers” but “all of them are gone.” This relative emphasized that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;excellent&quot; in taking his pulse - he could tell whether it was cancer or what kind of cancer it was by just touching it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a daughter-in-law, Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that she did not know how Hou Yuanxiang learned Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most patients call Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s WeChat signature is also &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. The &quot;Central Health&quot; website, which claims to provide communication, display, and promotion services for &quot;folk doctors,&quot; still has Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s personal introduction, calling him an &quot;international doctor of medicine&quot; and &quot;an authoritative international cancer expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, his online profiles, including “Professor of Chinese Medical College” and “Doctor of International Medicine”, “are all false” and “are intended to expand influence and make patients believe I&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Hou Yuanxiang did not even obtain a medical practicing certificate. Since the implementation of the Practicing Physician Law in 1999, regardless of whether it is traditional Chinese medicine or Western medicine, all practitioners must have a physician&#39;s practice certificate. Otherwise, it will be regarded as &quot;illegal practice of medicine&quot;, and they will be subject to administrative penalties in the lightest case and criminal liability in the worst case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A patient surnamed Xu testified that she began to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang in 2014. Since then, she has introduced many patients to Hou, and also asked Hou to attend a consultation at his winery. In 2019, she and Hou Yuanxiang co-organized When he went to the hospital, he found that Hou could not produce his medical license, so he doubted his identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only patients, but also some senior medical professionals had no doubts about Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s identity and ability. According to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang had been a doctor at Deyi Hall, a private traditional Chinese medicine hospital in Qingdao for a long time. Later, the person in charge of Deyi Hall asked Hou Yuanxiang to attach his medical qualification to the hospital. However, Hou Yuanxiang refused, and the two parties terminated the cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the testimony of Shen Yufa, director of Zibo Yiyuan Ruikang Hospital, around 2010, he met Hou Yuanxiang at a medical academic conference in Beijing. “Many people attending the conference at that time said that Professor Hou was a doctor of traditional Chinese medicine. He is famous for tumors, cancer, and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Shen Yufa’s wife got cancer and took Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade medicine. Shen Yufa also hired Hou as a &quot;part-time professor&quot; at Ruikang Hospital and sold Hou&#39;s medicine at the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, Shen Yufa once invited him to sit in Ruikang Hospital, but he refused because he did not have a medical license. The two parties only cooperated on selling medicines. However, Shen Yufa&#39;s son and another employee of the hospital confirmed that Hou Yuanxiang did not attend the hospital regularly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to private hospitals, Hou Yuanxiang has also worked with public hospitals. In 2016, Weifang Municipal Government Hospital, a public hospital, posted on its WeChat official account that Hou Yuanxiang was an &quot;authoritative expert in international cancer research&quot; and would conduct monthly consultations at the branch of traditional Chinese medicine. This article disappeared only recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Patients trust Hou Yuanxiang not only because of his impressive online resume, but also because of his “accurate” pulse numbering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Shijie is a relative of Hou Yuanxiang, a Jilin patient. According to him, Hou Yuanxiang once traveled to Changbai Mountain and hosted meals by himself. Hou Yuanxiang took his pulse on the spot. &quot;I have a friend who has high blood lipids and high blood pressure, and he can detect it,&quot; Dong Shijie told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang admitted to the investigators that he actually could not take a pulse. The reason for pretending to know the pulse is &quot;to put it bluntly, it is to let the patient buy medicine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang could not check the pulse, Dong Shijie was shocked: &quot;He is a traditional Chinese medicine doctor. What kind of disease would he treat if he could not check the pulse?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The whole family went into hiding&quot; after the incident&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, since 2011, Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Jing and others, without obtaining a drug production license, a drug business license, etc., posted Hou Yuanxiang’s false personal profile on the Internet to spread information in many places in Shandong Consulting and selling drugs claiming to be anti-cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hou Yuanxiang’s counterfeit drug case, the first person to be involved was his daughter Hou Jing—like her father, she did not have a medical certificate. On January 16, 2022, after receiving complaints and reports, multiple departments in Huangdao District, Qingdao City jointly conducted law enforcement and captured Hou Jing on the spot. Later, Hou Jing confessed to Hou Yuanxiang, his brother Hou Lei and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang was at his home in Weifang at the time. He didn’t seem to care at first. It wasn’t until Hou Jing was detained and he was interrogated by the police that he realized the seriousness of the situation and transferred the self-made medicine to Qingdao Clinic overnight. and production tools, but it was too late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court of first instance found that after Hou Jing was detained, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s wife went to the police station handling the case to inquire about information, and &quot;hidden the whole family&quot; after returning home for an excuse. The police then pursued the Hou family online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Lei’s confession, Hou Yuanxiang called him the day after Hou Jing was arrested. &quot;Two or three days later, my father said that this was a serious matter and asked me not to use my current mobile phone and to go out and hide. After hanging up the phone, I took out the phone card and threw it in the trash.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for how Hou Lei participated in these businesses, Hou Lei said that in the winter of 2019, Hou Yuanxiang &quot;asked me to apply for a bank card in the name of my wife Li Jianying... and asked me to pretend Director Li of the hospital, if a patient wants to buy medicine, call me and ask me to give the patient a bank card so that the patient can transfer money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, Hou Jing and Hou Lei had a bad relationship. After Hou Lei knew that Hou Jing was making money, he also wanted to sell medicine with his father. He asked him for the formula many times, but Hou Yuanxiang did not give it. He just asked Hou Lei to follow him and pay him a salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that Hou Lei helped Hou Yuanxiang deliver goods in Weifang, &quot;equivalent to a courier.&quot; In the first-instance verdict, Hou Lei was sentenced to &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; according to law, and was sentenced to 8 years in prison and fined 5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, after hiding for a few days, he received a call from Hou Yuanxiang from an unknown number, suggesting that he go to the third aunt&#39;s house in Qingdao to celebrate the New Year, and then the whole family went to the third aunt&#39;s house. According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, because he felt that &quot;the matter was quite serious&quot;, he once suggested that his father surrender. &quot;My father was very angry and said that I was not his biological child.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuai, the son of Hou Lei’s third aunt, told Hou Lei that he had the connections to settle the matter, but he would need 4 million yuan. After several communications, Hou Lei asked his ex-brother-in-law Fu Songjie to send 2 million yuan in cash to Li Shuai after he had already paid 500,000 yuan. Li Shuai confessed that when he saw Fu Songjie coming to the door with a sack of money, he was stunned: &quot;This is the first time I have seen so much money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Songjie was originally from a district in Weifang City In 2019, he resigned and went to Qingdao at the request of his ex-wife Hou Jing. Before resigning, Hou Yuanxiang approached him and asked him to serve as the legal representative of a private hospital in which Hou was a shareholder. After Fu Songjie arrived in Qingdao, he caught up with the epidemic and had no job, so he helped his father-in-law and his ex-wife, and ended up becoming an accomplice. Fu Songjie was sentenced to 3 years in prison and fined 500,000 yuan in the first instance. The sentence was the shortest among all those involved in the case, and Fu was the only one who did not appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Hou Lei was arrested, he confessed Li Shuai. In the next three days, Li Shuai, Fu Songjie and Hou Yuanxiang were arrested one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang, in addition to the above 2.5 million yuan, Li Shuai also defrauded him of more than 2 million yuan. The first-instance judgment confirmed the matter and stated that &quot;it will be separately investigated and handled by the public security organs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Hou Yuanxiang counterfeit drug case, the police seized a total of 8 houses in the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late February 2022, a week after Hou Yuanxiang was arrested, the Ministry of Public Security announced the first batch of eight major typical drug crime cases to be supervised, and Hou Yuanxiang’s fake drug case was among them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Secret Recipes&quot; of Unknown Origin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the Hou Yuanxiang case, the medicines that were classified as fake were four self-made medicines by Hou Yuanxiang and his daughter, two of which were named &quot; Anti-Cancer No. 1” and “Anti-Cancer No. 2”. According to Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s confession, these two medicines were made according to a &quot;secret recipe.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hou Yuanxiang has different opinions on the origin of this &quot;secret recipe&quot;. During the investigation stage of the case, he said that the secret recipe came from one of his &quot;second grandfathers.&quot; This recipe originally contained five kinds of medicine. On this basis, Hou Yuanxiang added shiitake mushrooms, ganoderma lucidum, and cordyceps. &quot;Even if this recipe is my own creation, I I have always wanted to promote this prescription and sell the medicine to make money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the trial stage of the case, Hou Yuanxiang’s statement about the “secret recipe” changed—he claimed that the recipe was given to him by his “teacher” at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s different statements about the source of the secret recipe puzzled a second-instance attorney: “Perhaps only he himself knows the truth.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment quoted an attorney of the Hou family According to the lawyer, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s anti-cancer &quot;secret recipe&quot; contains many Chinese medicinal materials such as shiitake mushrooms, cordyceps, Ganoderma lucidum, Prunella vulgaris, black dates, kelp, burdock root, dandelion root, ginseng, astragalus, angelica and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Chinese medicine practitioner who has been practicing for more than 40 years told Southern Weekend reporters that the Chinese medicinal materials in Hou Yuanxiang’s prescription include both “tonifying” and “attacking” ingredients, such as ginseng, Astragalus, when cancer patients reach the middle and late stages, most of them are relatively weak, so it is beneficial to use some tonics; &quot;attack&quot; medicines such as kelp, which has the effect of clearing away heat and dissipating stagnation, is only suitable for some early-stage cancer patients and is not suitable for late-stage cancer patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Hou Yuanxiang’s patients, there are many terminal cancer patients, and some came to Hou Yuanxiang because they were “sentenced to death by the hospital.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from traditional Chinese medicine (TCM), which treats patients according to prescriptions, Hou Yuanxiang’s anti-cancer drugs are prepared in advance, bagged and then sold to patients. According to his confession, around November 2020, Hou Jing purchased a decoction-making machine online. Since then, the father and daughter have taken turns using this machine to make decoctions, &quot;and can make about 80 bags a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; is 4,620 yuan per serving, and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot; is 1,920 yuan. One dose is taken for one course of treatment, and one course of treatment lasts for 12 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade anti-cancer drugs, Zhao Yin, a lawyer who graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and has worked in the clinical department of traditional Chinese medicine in the hospital for many years, believes that it is definitely illegal. According to her, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self-made medicines are similar to &quot;medical institution (TCM) preparations&quot; in hospitals, which refer to fixed prescription preparations prepared by medical institutions for their own use after approval based on the clinical needs of the unit. However, hospital preparations, like medicines, generally need to be approved by the drug regulatory department before they can be produced and sold. In principle, they can only be produced by the hospital for their own use and cannot be sold externally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin said that after the promulgation of the Traditional Chinese Medicine Law in 2017, the state has relaxed its management of traditional Chinese medicine preparations. Traditional Chinese medicine preparations that only use traditional techniques do not need to obtain a preparation approval number and only need to apply for a preparation approval number. It can be prepared after registration with the provincial drug regulatory department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine has also not been registered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Traditional Chinese Medicine Law stipulates that medical institutions that prepare traditional Chinese medicine preparations that should be registered but fail to do so will be punished as producing counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin also doubted whether Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade anti-cancer medicine really contained a sufficient amount of Chinese medicinal materials such as cordyceps claimed in the “secret recipe” because the medicine was made by Hou Yuanxiang and his daughter themselves and there was no formula. The production process standards lack proper supervision and supervision. However, quantitative detection of Cordyceps sinensis is very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Fu Songjie’s confession, Hou Jing would send Liuwei Dihuang Pills and other Chinese patent medicines to patients together with the boiled Chinese medicine liquid. In Zhao Yin&#39;s view, in this way, even if the patient feels effective after taking the medicine, it may be the effect of the proprietary Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid the characterization of &quot;fake medicine&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang once tried to defend himself by claiming that &quot;medicine and food have the same origin&quot;, which means that what he sells is food. However, due to the labeling of drug names such as &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot;, his defense is difficult to establish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin believes that the drug names &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot; are nondescript, because cancer is a concept of Western medicine, and traditional Chinese medicine generally does not have the term &quot;cancer&quot; or &quot;tumor&quot;. Instead, it is called &quot;accumulation of symptoms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Hou Yuanxiang’s practice of making homemade anti-cancer drugs, the above-mentioned traditional Chinese medicine doctors interviewed by Southern Weekend reporters called him “too courageous”. In his opinion, many Chinese medicine practitioners have secret recipes. In order not to reveal the secret recipes, they usually only sell the medicinal materials to patients. At most, they cook them for the patients. They certainly dare not make their own medicines and sell them to patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have any cancer patients been cured?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, supporters &quot;voted injustice&quot; against Hou Yuanxiang on the Internet because he cured many cancer patients. However, a Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s investigation found that it is questionable whether any cancer patients were actually cured by Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the first-instance verdict of the Hou Yuanxiang case, a list of cancer patients who claimed to be &quot;cured by Hou Yuanxiang&quot; leaked online. There were a total of 31 personal information of patients or patients&#39; family members on the list. This list is consistent with that provided to Southern Weekend reporters by Gong Feiyun, one of Hou Yuanxiang’s supporters. According to Gong Feiyun, at the end of June 2023, he went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, and it was Hou Yuanxiang himself who gave him this list. Gong Feiyun is a partner of a local traditional Chinese medicine clinic. A few years ago, he was involved in a controversy when self-made medicines were deemed to be counterfeit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters made all 31 calls on the list, of which 11 were not answered and 13 were refused. Of the 7 calls answered, 6 admitted that they were patients on the list or Family members, and another person denied that he was Che Moumou, the &quot;Director of the Provincial Environmental Protection Bureau&quot; written on the list, saying that he was &quot;running business.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 6 people, 3 people refused to be interviewed on the grounds of &quot;something happened&quot; and &quot;privacy involved&quot;, and only 3 people accepted the telephone interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The patient, Song Yuanjia, is from Qingdao, Shandong. He claimed that he was &quot;sentenced to death by the hospital.&quot; He approached Hou Yuanxiang with the mentality of giving it a try, and &quot;it was fine once he tried it.&quot; &quot;It has been 7 years now. Nothing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yuan’s family told Southern Weekend reporters that Hou Yuanxiang’s medicine was an “ancestral medicine” and he spent more than 200,000 yuan without giving a prescription, first taking “Anti-Cancer No. 1” and “in the end he became poor. Feel better, take &#39;Anti-Cancer No. 2&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, when Hou Yuanxiang moved his homemade medicine and production tools overnight, he asked the Song Yuan family for help, and the Song Yuan family found a warehouse for him to store the items Hou Yuanxiang moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yuanjia told Southern Weekend reporters that he had read Hou Yuanxiang’s first-instance verdict, but he was more willing to believe the “crying out injustice” video on the self-media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another interviewee, Wang Jingjiang, is a villager in a village in Zibo, Shandong, and the patient is his mother-in-law. He said that Hou Yuanxiang once planned to build a sanatorium in the village. He was driving for the village party secretary and got to know Hou. Later, his mother-in-law got cancer and there was no possibility of surgery. After undergoing chemotherapy for a period of time, he contacted &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jingjiang said that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was &quot;good&quot; and his mother-in-law felt &quot;strong&quot; after drinking it. However, she stopped drinking it because she couldn&#39;t stand the taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of lawyer Yang Fengzhu, one of the experts in drafting and demonstrating traditional Chinese medicine laws, Hou Yuanxiang’s “anti-cancer drugs” are several Chinese medicines mixed together. Although Chinese medicine treatments rarely have “immediate results”, they are not It has no effect. &quot;Once you take the (Chinese medicine) that replenishes qi, it will definitely have an effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jingjiang also emphasized that his mother-in-law was not &quot;cured&quot;, but &quot;has not (re) committed the crime or been transferred.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third interviewee, Li Cheng (pseudonym), is from Yanbian, Jilin. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the patient was his grandfather, and he had indeed seen Hou Yuanxiang for medical treatment and taken his homemade medicine. The old man passed away in September 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng said that his grandfather was diagnosed with rectal cancer in July 2019 and had spread to the lymph nodes. Relatives introduced him to Hou Yuanxiang. He has never met Hou Yuanxiang so far, and the two mainly communicate through WeChat. He said that after adding WeChat, Hou Yuanxiang once sent his personal profile, &quot;I also searched on Baidu about world cancer, committees, and cancer treatment experts, and I could indeed find this person. I thought this person was quite good.&quot; sharp&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When receiving a call from a Southern Weekend reporter, Li Cheng still called Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou.&quot; When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang was not a professor and did not even have a medical license, he was surprised and said that if he had known about this situation, he would &quot;definitely consider&quot; whether to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng said that in addition to drinking Hou Yuanxiang’s anti-cancer drugs, his grandfather also ate the “nutritious meals” recommended by Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;After about three courses of treatment, (grandpa) recovered very well.&quot; Li Cheng said, for this reason, he also introduced many patients to Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Cheng could not confirm whether his grandfather&#39;s condition improved for a time. &quot;Whether Professor Hou&#39;s medicine played a greater role or my grandfather&#39;s personal mentality played a greater role.&quot; Li Cheng said, &quot;We all say that (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine) is effective and easy to use, and it may have played a supporting role in grandpa&#39;s mental state.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Fengzhu has participated in many clinical trial demonstrations of drugs. . In his opinion, when patients undergo treatment, &quot;psychological effects are very important and can affect 30% of the (treatment) effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng also said that while his grandfather was taking Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine, he also underwent other treatments, including surgery, and &quot;Chinese and Western medicine worked simultaneously.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After &quot;slimming down&quot; with fake medicine&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Neither the attorney nor Hou Yuanxiang himself expected that the first instance would impose such a severe sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to relevant legal provisions and the amount of money involved ascertained by the driver’s agency, once Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is deemed to be counterfeit, the sentence will not be lenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the first trial, many attorneys representing the Hou family argued that Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine did not cause any harm to the patient. Hou Yuanxiang himself also stated that &quot;children can drink&quot; his medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the lack of any harm does not mean that Hou Yuanxiang does not commit the crime of &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot;, nor does it mean that he cannot be severely sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the criminal law before the 2011 revision, the crime of &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; requires &quot;serious harm to human health&quot; and causing death or serious injury in order to be sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin said that in order to increase the crackdown on counterfeit drugs, the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law in 2011 amended the &quot;crime of producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and no longer included &quot;seriously endangering human health&quot;. &quot;As a threshold for criminalization, as long as the production and sale of counterfeit medicines constitutes a crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law no longer requires death or serious injury as the only condition for a heavy sentence. It stipulates that &quot;other particularly serious circumstances&quot; can also be harshly sentenced. In 2014, the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate issued a judicial interpretation that as long as the production and sale of counterfeit drugs reaches 500,000 yuan, it constitutes &quot;other particularly serious circumstances&quot; under the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance court determined that Hou Yuanxiang’s production and sales of counterfeit drugs amounted to more than 14.36 million yuan, far exceeding 500,000 yuan. This means that once Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade medicine is determined to be counterfeit, he will be sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine can be recognized as counterfeit medicine must be based on the Drug Administration Law. Zhao Yin believes that before the law was revised in 2019, the identification of counterfeit drugs was relatively simple - as long as the drug did not obtain a batch number, it would be &quot;treated as a counterfeit drug&quot;, thus constituting a counterfeit drug in the sense of criminal law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Drug Administration Law revised in 2019 has made major changes to the definition of counterfeit drugs. Drugs without batch numbers are no longer automatically treated as counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industry generally believes that the above-mentioned modifications to the Drug Administration Law are related to the Hunan Lu Yong case. Lu Yong, a leukemia patient, purchased generic drugs from informal channels and helped his patients purchase the drugs. In 2018, the movie &quot;I&#39;m Not the God of Medicine&quot; based on it was released, triggering widespread public discussion on China&#39;s drug management system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The revised Drug Administration Law stipulates that counterfeit drugs can be classified as counterfeit drugs only under four circumstances (see the information link at the end of the article for details). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Cao Guoying, director of the Beijing Changjiang Pharmaceutical Development Foundation, who has long been engaged in anti-counterfeiting practice and research on drugs, after the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of counterfeit drug cases handled by the drug regulatory department showed a &quot;cliff-like decline.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the website of the State Food and Drug Administration, in 2019, the number of counterfeit drug cases investigated and dealt with by drug regulatory departments across the country was 14,041. In the following year after the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of such cases There were only 7,361 cases, a decrease of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend searched the Judgment Documents Network using the keyword &quot;counterfeit drugs&quot; and found that based on the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of judgments in criminal cases of counterfeit drugs dropped sharply from 5,044 in 2019 to 2020. Of the 2,361 pieces, more than half were missing. There was also a downward trend in the following years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2019 version of the Drug Administration Law has significantly increased fines while &quot;slimming down&quot; counterfeit drugs. &quot;The starting point of the fine is 15 times the production and sales amount, and if it is less than 100,000, it will be calculated as 100,000.&quot; Zhao Yin said, &quot;As long as you are producing and selling counterfeit drugs, you will be fined at least 1.5 million, and you will be punished to death (for production, sales, etc.) Selling counterfeit medicines).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Are Chinese medicinal materials medicines? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Cao Guoying&#39;s view, under the current overall environment of drug counterfeiting, it is &quot;very difficult&quot; for Qingdao to investigate the Hou Yuanxiang case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, whether Hou Yuanxiang should be held criminally responsible for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; has caused controversy in both the legal and traditional Chinese medicine circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hou family’s attorney cited the revised Drug Administration Law in 2019 as an excuse to believe that Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is made from traditional Chinese medicinal materials and should not be regarded as counterfeit medicine. Hou Yuanxiang and others do not constitute “production.” , the crime of selling counterfeit medicines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, according to the first-instance judgment of Hou Yuanxiang’s case, the public security organs initially opened a case against Hou Yuanxiang and others for “illegal business operations.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One month after the case was filed, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau issued a counterfeit drug identification certificate, identifying Hou Yuanxiang’s four self-made medicines as counterfeit drugs. According to the relevant judicial interpretations issued by the highest law and the highest detection in 2014, it is difficult to determine the &quot;fake drugs&quot; and &quot;inferior drugs&quot;, and the judicial organs can determine the determination opinions issued by the drug supervision and management departments above the city level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the above identification, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot;, &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot;, &quot;liver&quot; claiming to treat liver cancer, and &quot;wild heart brain soup&quot; used to treat heart disease The medicine is identified as a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the case entered the review and prosecution stage, at the request of the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Huangdao District, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau specially issued a supplementary explanation to explain why the products involved were identified as fake medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Instructions point out that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s four self -made products &quot;no drug registration certificate, no medical institution preparation filing, no drug production license, no medical institution preparation permit, no national standard, etc. Pharmaceuticals that promote the treatment of cancer, liver cancer, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, etc. are sold to patients to cure diseases. P>; &lt;p>; A second -instance agent lawyer pointed out that on the one hand, the above discussion said that the product involved in the case was &quot;in line with the definition of drugs&quot;, and on the other hand, it was &quot;non -drug&quot;. In its opinion, the reason why Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau discusses this is because according to the New Drug Management Law, &quot;the only thing that can be stuck is this one (non -pharmaceutical impersonation).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine identification issues, the reporter from the southern weekend contacted the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau. The bureau refused to interview on the grounds of the Hou Yuanxiang case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the first instance, almost all the acting lawyers of the Hou family questioned the false drug determination of the case. One of the lawyers pointed out that most of the medicinal materials used in &quot;Anti -Cancer 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; were in the 2020 version of &quot;Chinese Pharmacopoeia&quot;, which did not conform to &quot;impersonation of medicines with non -drug&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in Zhao Yin&#39;s view, Chinese medicinal materials are not of course considered medicines -Chinese medicinal materials are only raw materials for making drugs and can be sold in the medicinal material market. Sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Where is the medicinal materials used by Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s father and daughter&#39;s self -made medicine? There is no explanation in the relevant confession quoted in the first instance judgment, and Hou Jing cannot provide the purchase of the purchase and legal certification documents. According to Hou Jing&#39;s ex -husband Fu Songjie, Hou Jing&#39;s herbal medicines were sent through express delivery and logistics. The consignee generally used a pseudonym. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Gang, the acting lawyer of the second instance, questioned the fake drugs involved in the case involved in the case of the case, and questioned the fake drug identification letter based on the judgment of the first trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the newly introduced judicial interpretation of the highest law and the highest prosecution in 2022 (the old judicial interpretation of the old judicial interpretation in 2014), the situation of &quot;non -drug pretending to medicine&quot; can only be in the case where there is no controversy. Below, the municipal pharmaceutical regulatory department can be directly identified as fake medicine. For controversy, it is necessary to check or determine the pharmaceutical inspection agency set by the drug supervision and management department of the provincial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Li Gang&#39;s view, the identification of the fake drugs involved in the case of Hou Yuanxiang obviously controversial and should be tested. However, he believes that folk traditional Chinese medicine recipes lack national standards, and even if the results are tested, it lacks scientific and legitimacy. And Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was not tested at the time, and now it has been seized for more than a year. &quot;It has been deteriorated early, how to test it?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 5, 2023, another agent lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang told the Southern Weekend reporter that After the case was returned to the retrial, the procuratorial organs supplemented a lot of evidence to the court, including a inspection report on Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -pharmaceutical. According to this inspection report, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made drug detected the western medicine composition to treat diabetes. The Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau still determined that the product involved was a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s above -mentioned acting lawyer said that this shows that the pharmaceutical regulatory department may no longer determine the product involved in the case in accordance with the &quot;non -pharmaceutical impersonation medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s charges, Yang Zhiwei, a lawyer of Guangdong Fa Quan Law Firm, put forward another point of view to reporters from the south weekend: if Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; are clear and treating cancer &quot;Do not match the world&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang is entirely the purpose of selling medicines, so he may constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend found such a case on the referee document network: In 2019, Li Mouxiang, who did not qualify for medicine, was arrested for production and sales of fake drugs, but the Procuratorate arrested and arrested him with fraud. The court was sentenced to 14 years in prison for fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Is Hou Yuanxiang suspected of fraud? A reporter from the Southern Weekend asked about a first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang. After a few seconds of silence, the lawyer asked: Scam? Isn&#39;t that heavier? Later, he said that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;unlikely&quot; to constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang believes that Hou Yuanxiang constitutes &quot;the crime of obstructing drug management&quot;. The crime was newly established in the 11th Amendment of the Criminal Law issued in 2020. It pointed to the criminal behavior of drugs that did not obtain a batch number but not obtained by the production and sales. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer did not accept interviews with reporters from the Southern Weekend, but said such a sentence: &quot;If he is sentenced to being innocently guilty of his (Hou Yuanxiang) family, then we can do anything in the name of traditional Chinese medicine to do traditional Chinese medicine. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; Data link: Different definition of&quot; fake medicine &quot;before and after the revision of the Drug Management Law: &lt; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Before revision: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with the ingredients specified by national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to be medicine or pretending to be such medicines. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; A medicine with one of the following situations, according to fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The State Council&#39;s drug supervision and management department stipulates that it is prohibited; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) In accordance with this law, it must be approved without approved production and importing, or it must be tested in this law without testing without testing. ; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot; (3) deterioration; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (4) pollution; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body body body body , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (5) Use the raw material for the raw medicine of the approval number according to this law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (6) Indications or functions marked or functional beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the following situations: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to medicine or impersonating such medicines in other medicines; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (3) spoiled medicine; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font -Family: Kai, Kaidi_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (4) Indications or functions indicated by drugs or functions beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“抗癌神医”的网络舆论战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260879]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Hou Yuanxiang was investigated, a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for them on the Internet appeared on the Internet. Nongjian illustration &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 953 &quot;data- SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258747&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text -rign: center; &quot;>; During the investigation, Hou Yuanxiang appeared a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for him on the Internet. Nongjian Illustration &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang admits to the reporter from the southern weekend that for Hou Yuanxiang, who was sentenced to the first instance, the second trial was a &quot;backwater battle.&quot; The second trial of the case can be returned to retrial, &quot;the media has played a great role.&quot; (Report on the Hou Yuanxiang case for details, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260877&quot;>; &quot;For ten years of medical practitioners, relying on the secret recipe&#39;s self -made anti &lt;/a>;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer&#39;s media refers to the Internet self -media. In fact, the media reports of the mainstream institutions reported Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine cases after the second instance ruling was returned to retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the help of the media, Hou Yuanxiang, who was originally unknown, was described as a &quot;cure doctor&quot; sentenced by injustice. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Women with a public security background&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In mid -March 2023, the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine case was judged for more than a month later, and an article entitled &quot;Nine -year -old Xinxin for help: Mom Mom Articles of more than 3,000 cancer patients were sentenced to 11 years, and a fine of 30 million &quot;began to spread online. The article states that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter Hou Jing used the secret recipe of Chinese medicine to heal a lot of difficulty. , The whole family is implicated. There is also a photo of Hou Jing&#39;s 9 -year -old son asking for help: &quot;Why do you sin? Mom, do you have a sin? Let netizens from all over the country comment on you ...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This article has aroused heated discussion among netizens. The reporter from the Southern Weekend noticed that this article emphasizes that Hou Jing graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and was a Chinese medicine division, but he could not mention Hou Jing without a physician&#39;s practice certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter -in -law Li Jianying told the southern weekend reporter that after the judgment of the first instance, Hou Yuanxiang wanted to use the Internet to &quot;call unjust&quot;. At that time, she asked her children&#39;s photos. She was worried that the child would be affected and did not give it. Later, I used the photos of Hou Jing&#39;s son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2023, the media person Wu Pengfei began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. Wu Pengfei claims to be &quot;old journalists&quot; and &quot;well -known online writers&quot;. They have an account number on platforms such as Douyin, Kuaishou, and today&#39;s headlines. A reporter in the Southern Weekend found that Wu Pengfei worked in a media in Hubei Province in his early years and set up a planning marketing company after leaving the media. When he began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine, Wu Pengfei exposed a big news: a lady with a public security background had a price of 10 million. She wanted to buy Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s treatment secret recipe. Go to jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many self -media bloggers quoted Wu Pengfei&#39;s above statement, so that &quot;women with a public security background to buy medicines can not report to Hou Yuanxiang&quot; said that they became the mainstream online public opinion of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Li Gang, a second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, told reporters from the southern weekend that although he heard Hou Yuanxiang said this, he did not see relevant evidence. Control. As a lawyer, he &quot;does not comment&quot; on this statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Zining, the first instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, also told the southern weekend reporter that the above statement &quot;cannot be reflected in the (case) volume.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reporter of the Southern Weekend noticed that during the new crown epidemic in 2020, Wu Pengfei had picked up another &quot;divine doctor&quot; -Co Yuehua, who claimed that the injection phenol could cure the new crown, and released the news that Li Yuehua said Li Yuehua He was invited to resist with South Korea, but the news was denied by South Korea. Li Yuehua himself also told the media that he did not know the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend tried to contact Wu Pengfei, but as of press time, the other party did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;How much is the reliability of folk investigation?&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; After issuing the above article, Wu Pengfei has continuously released short videos entitled &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Injection Cases&quot; on multiple platforms. Now Episode 100 has been broadcast, of which the playback volume of the Douyin platform has exceeded 16 million. In these short videos, Wu Pengfei called Hou Yuanxiang as &quot;Hou Lao&quot;, saying that he was &quot;the first person in traditional Chinese medicine to treat cancer&quot;, with &quot;unique medical skills&quot; and &quot;shocking effect&quot;, &quot;a national treasure&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot; Each hair is gold. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, Wu Pengfei also quoted a set of data to show that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;cure cancer.&quot; He said that &quot;a national folk Chinese medicine organization&quot; investigated the efficacy of the top ten cancer names in China. Only 11 people were cured. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Jianying also told reporters from the south weekend that Hou Yuanxiang&quot; cured &quot;1166 cancer patients. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) has records.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei did not say which institution of &quot;National Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Organization&quot;. In fact, even Li Gang held a question about the data that Wu Pengfei said: &quot;How much is the reliability of private investigations?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In another short video, Wu Pengfei said that Hou Yuanxiang cured more than 3,000 cancers. patient. In the personal introduction of &quot;Yangtze Health&quot; (a website that provides communication, display, and promotion services), Hou Yuanxiang is &quot;cured more than 20,000 cancer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some media have questioned Hou Yuanxiang from the media, but the click volume is not the same as Wu Pengfei&#39;s short videos. Since the media &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; posted a video, saying that Hou Yuanxiang was a &quot;liar for sale of fake medicines&quot;, calling on the public to calm down the case: &quot;If the facts are ignored, it is not love Chinese medicine, but it is harming Chinese medicine.&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; After the video was released, &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; was siege by many supporters of Hou Yuanxiang. Wu Pengfei released 8 short videos to refute. It didn&#39;t take long for the video of &quot;Chinese medicine Chen Lei&quot; to get off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After seeing Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine on the Internet, Qian Hui, general manager of Nanjing Guishi Hall Traditional Chinese Medicine Museum, decided to support it. Qian Hui has experienced similar experiences to Hou Yuanxiang. According to media reports, Qian Hui did not have a physician&#39;s license. In order to avoid &quot;illegal medicine&quot;, his Chinese Medical Museum hired a regular doctor to prescribe prescriptions, and Qian Hui would &quot;guide&quot;. Self -making based on your own &quot;secret recipe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of 2017, Guishi Hall was reported. Because the batch number was not obtained, its homemade medicine was identified as a fake medicine by the Nanjing Pharmaceutical Bureau. The crime of medicine was once detained by the police, and Qian Hui was locked for 28 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Why do we support Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s innocence? The main reason is from the perspective of protecting traditional Chinese medicine, because once Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case is guilty, many traditional Chinese medicine can not do it anymore.&quot; To the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun, one of Guishitang&#39;s &quot;partner&quot;, traditional Chinese medicine is &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang is one of many &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;. He defines &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;: The collective name of Chinese medicine outside the system has not received formal Chinese medicine education in universities, and has no physician practicing certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2013, Gong Feiyun went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang. According to Gong Feiyun, although Hou Yuanxiang had been &quot;monitored and lived&quot; by the police at that time, he was not strict at that time. He tried to make an appointment and made a video. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun also participated in the mediation of the Guishitang fake medicine. According to him, during the handling of the case, Guishi Hall had a &quot;public opinion war&quot; with Nanjing police: first a media in Nanjing stood on the police stand and exposed the case. the sound of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, the case stayed in the public security investigation stage and failed to enter the procuratorate for review and prosecution. After this robbery, Guishi Hall has since maintained the Shanghai market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before Qian Hui and Gong Feiyun, another &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot; supporter Guan Le also supported Hou Yuanxiang online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guanle claims to be &quot;the first principal of the University of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Great Wall inscription character&quot; and &quot;Chairman of the World Chinese Medicine Hall&quot;. He described &quot;the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; as the &quot;Huangpu Military Academy&quot; of folk Chinese medicine. However, the university claimed to be established 3 years ago, but it has not been established so far. Guan Le once publicly said that after the university was established, he will select &quot;Academician of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Doctor of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; and &quot;Professor of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Related information shows that in June 2020, the slogan of the establishment of &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; just shouted, and Guan Le claimed to hold a establishment meeting of a branch of the university. The day after the meeting, Guan Le released an advertisement for a medical training course in multiple Chinese medicine groups, claiming that no medical foundation can learn on the spot, and the training fee is 18,000 yuan (preferential) for two days. Unexpectedly, this move with the &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; was publicly questioned by Gu Jingyu, a doctor of a three -section of Jiangsu family in Jiangsu, and Guan Le responded: &quot;Civil Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; is innovation: &quot;Since it is innovation, there must be no certificate. Without a certificate, it must be illegal ... &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After going to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, Gong Feiyun and Guan Le met in Shanghai. And ask him to speak up in the case of Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On September 9, 2023, the preparatory meeting of the Second Civil Medicine University planned by Guanle was held in Beijing. During the meeting, the Hou Yuanxiang case was discussed during the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;(Hou Yuanxiang case) is equivalent to uniting all folk Chinese medicine.&quot; Gong Feiyun told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the second trial of the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine, after the re -review was returned, the supporters of Hou Yuanxiang were jubilant, and they released the &quot;good news&quot; online, thinking that the case had a &quot;major turnaround&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Soon after that, there was another news from the media -Hou Yuanxiang was on a hunger strike, and the news was &quot;true.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei quickly posted a short video to clarify, saying that Hou Yuanxiang could not eat because he was weak, and his apprentice &quot;because he was afraid that someone would hurt Hou Lao and deliberately posted a hunger hunger strike in order to attract the attention of the whole society. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A few days later, Wu Pengfei posted a short video, saying that &quot;Hou Lao&quot; recovered, and began to &quot;drink a little wine&quot; every meal. … &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; According to Li Gang, a lawyer in the second instance, after the second trial retracement, because &quot;too many people who knew (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s original surveillance residential place)&quot;, the police replaced Hou Yuanxiang for a place to perform surveillance and residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;I no longer participate in this matter&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng (pseudonym) is the grandson of a patient with a Jilin cancer patient in Hou Yuanxiang. In the case, he also participated in the public opinion battle for Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 8, 2022, after Hou Yuanxiang filed a appeal, a WeChat person named &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; added Li Cheng&#39;s WeChat, claiming to be the daughter -in -law of &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Can you write a joint letter to Professor Hou for a love?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;What happened to Professor Hou?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I was reported by others , Now I still can&#39;t take my own medicine in the hospital. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng knew that Hou Yuanxiang had an accident. He told&quot; Meteor and sunset &quot;that he could help Hou Yuanxiang write a joint letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two months later, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; pulled Li Cheng into a WeChat group that supported Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng&#39;s mobile phone has a number marked as &quot;Director Li&#39;s anti -cancer&quot;, which was given by Hou Yuanxiang. He bought medicine for Grandpa to contact this &quot;Director Li&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before receiving a call from a reporter from the Southern Weekend, Li Cheng always thought that &quot;Director Li&quot; was called &quot;Li Jianying&quot; and was the person in charge of the medicine of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in fact, &quot;Director Li&quot; is Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s son Hou Lei, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; is Li Jianying. She is also the only one among all the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first trial, in the case of Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Yuanxiang said that &quot;Professor Hou&quot; was responsible for providing formula, diagnosis and treatment of cancer diseases, and selling medicines. Chinese herbal medicine, boiled Chinese medicine, etc., his son Hou Lei was pretending to be responsible for taking the medicine and returned medicine &quot;Director Li&quot;, which is Li Jianying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After more than a month of WeChat with &quot;Meteor and Santa&quot;, Li Cheng and Hou Yuanxiang also contacted. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) said that putting my information on the Internet, I said, as long as it is helpful to your case.&quot; Li Cheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng also suggested that Hou Yuanxiang talked about this on the self -media platform to increase attention. &quot;He said, let me let the family get it at home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, Hou Yuanxiang sent some case materials to Li Cheng to help him contact the media. There have been no news since then. Li Cheng failed to help Hou Yuanxiang contact the media. Until late 2023, he sent a message to Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;He gave me a sentence and said that (second instance) was about to open the trial, the problem was not big.&quot; This is Li Cheng&#39;s last contact with Hou Yuanxiang. Prior to this, the Hou family proposed that Li Cheng&#39;s personal information was put on the Internet as one of the cases of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;cure&quot; cancer patients, and he agreed. However, before the list was sent to the Internet, Li Cheng&#39;s grandfather died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After knowing the truth, Li Cheng realized that things were &quot;not so simple&quot; - &quot;I don&#39;t know these, I don&#39;t know at all. Let&#39;s help, but the premise must be within the framework of the law ... I no longer participate in this matter. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[床虱危机或已蔓延至香港：为何太阳晒不倒，杀虫剂无效？丨硬核唠科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260875]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>