<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[曹禺：现代话剧艺术的高峰丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256384]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蒙冤入狱29年获787万多元国家赔偿：“追责必须落到责任主体”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257505]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Tan Xiuyi, who was wrongfully raped and murdered and imprisoned for 29 years, recently received more than 7.87 million yuan in state compensation. Examining this case, which was selected for inclusion in the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate&#39;s work report to the National People&#39;s Congress, may help prevent unjust, false and wrong cases from recurring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Red Star News, what led to Tan Xiuyi’s injustice was a massacre that occurred in the summer of 1993: On the evening of July 16, 1993, Tan Hong, a villager in Qiantan Village, Tanzhuang Town, Shangshui County, Zhoukou, Henan Province ( A family of three (pseudonym) and his parents were murdered, and Tan Xiuyi, a 39-year-old fellow villager at the time, was identified as a suspect. At the end of 1999, the Zhoukou Intermediate Court made a first-instance verdict on the case and sentenced Tan Xiuyi to a suspended death sentence for intentional homicide. The first-instance verdict shows that the court found that: at about 22:00 on the evening of July 16, 1993, when Tan Xiuyi went home to relieve himself in the toilet, he saw Tan Hong, who was staying at his home that night, and became malicious and raped her. Fearing that the matter would be exposed, Tan Xiuyi had the idea of ​​killing Tan Hong&#39;s parents. At 1 a.m. on July 17, Tan Xiuyi sneaked into Tan Hong&#39;s home with the tools of the crime and killed his parents. Later, Tan Xiuyi was afraid that Tan Hong would doubt him after learning that his parents had been killed, so he killed Tan Hong after she got up and returned home, and hung her body from the beam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Tan Xiuyi appealed, in May 2000, the Henan High Court ruled to revoke the original verdict and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the facts were unclear. In January 2002, the Zhoukou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court made a retrial judgment. In addition to intentional homicide, Tan Xiuyi was also found guilty of rape, and his sentence was maintained with a suspended death penalty. Tan Xiuyi appealed again, but this time the Henan High Court rejected the appeal in 2003 and upheld the original verdict. Ten years later, this tragedy seems to have become an &quot;iron case&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Tan Xiuyi did not give up. He kept appealing and had his experience rejected: In December 2017, the Henan Provincial High Court ruled that &quot;the facts found in the original judgment were clear, the evidence was indeed sufficient, and the conviction and sentencing were not inappropriate.&quot; dismissed the complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until 2018, after the Henan Provincial Procuratorate filed the case for review, it believed that the facts determined in the original trial were unclear, the evidence was unreliable and insufficient, and the judgment was wrong. On June 18, 2020, it filed a protest with the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate lodged a protest with the Supreme People&#39;s Court on March 16, 2022. Four months later, the Supreme People&#39;s Court made a retrial decision and ordered the Henan High Court to retrial. This time, the Henan High Court changed the verdict of Tan Xiuyi to not guilty. At this time, Tan Xiuyi had been &quot;released&quot; two months ago and had been imprisoned for more than 29 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trial process of this case is full of doubts. The case occurred in 1993, but the first-instance verdict was issued more than six years later, and the second-instance verdict was found to be &quot;unclear.&quot; It can be inferred that the investigation process of the case was not smooth and the evidence based on which the case was decided was not sufficient. In this regard, the criminal protest letter of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate also stated: In this case, except for Tan Xiuyi&#39;s partial guilty confession, which is consistent with the investigation transcripts and autopsy reports, there is no objective evidence to prove that Tan Xiuyi committed the crime; for the crime of rape, the time of Tan Xiuyi&#39;s rape cannot be determined, and the rape behavior It is also impossible to prove; regarding the crime of intentional homicide, some of the crime tools are unclear and the conclusions of criminal technical appraisal are not unique. In addition, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate also found that Tan Xiuyi&#39;s several guilty confessions were inconsistent and contradicted other evidence. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate believes that the case also contains problems such as guilty confessions and interrogation transcripts that violate legal provisions and whose authenticity is questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the evidence in the case basically only consists of Tan Xiuyi’s confession, and there is no objective evidence. Even the authenticity of the confession is doubtful, and the confession may have been illegally coerced. During the second trial, the Henan High Court determined that the facts of the case were unclear and remanded the case for retrial. It can be seen that the second instance also believed that there were problems with the evidence. However, it took just over a year for the retrial to reach another verdict, which not only upheld the crime of intentional homicide, but also added the crime of rape (this is also a doubtful point: since Tan Xiuyi was found to have raped Tan Hong in the first trial in 1999, why was he not punished? Convicted of rape?), and the retrial second instance also upheld the first instance judgment of the retrial. It took six years to obtain enough evidence, but why did it take just over a year to add new evidence that was sufficient to establish the crime? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not to mention that homicide cases require sufficient evidence to be determined, rape cases only rely on oral confessions, which is difficult to understand. Regardless of whether it was forced, at least it must be proven that there was sexual intercourse between the victim and the suspect. Although the victim was dead, the rape and murder were only a few hours apart. At that time, the police also mastered DNA comparison technology. Through forensic identification, it was completely possible to find out whether the victim had had sex with the suspect before his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did the Henan Provincial High Court find that the facts were unclear in the initial second instance, but the second instance of the retrial, as well as the subsequent appeal, all believed that &quot;the facts were clearly found and the evidence was indeed sufficient&quot;? Are the judges who handle retrials, second trials and appeals under pressure from other parties? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case occurred in 1993, and many trials were held around 2000. Although the Internet was not very developed at that time, a major extermination case that killed a family of three still had a very large impact, and the public prosecutor and the law were bound to be under considerable pressure. What is particularly noteworthy is that Henan was one of the first provinces to propose &quot;murder cases must be solved&quot; at the beginning of this century. In 2004, it was recognized by the Ministry of Public Security as a national slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 National People’s Congress, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate stated in a report that in the past five years, 26 major criminal wrongful convictions, including the Wuzhou case and the Zhang Yuhuan case, had been corrected in accordance with the law; Protests or prosecutorial recommendations for retrials were made in 10 major unjust cases in which the original verdict lasted for more than ten years, and the court changed the verdict to not guilty in all cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these unjust, false and wrong cases, in addition to redressing the grievances and compensating the parties concerned, should the investigators at the time also bear responsibility? In 2013, the Central Political and Legal Affairs Commission issued guidance on effectively preventing unjust, false and wrongful convictions, requiring judges, prosecutors, and people&#39;s police to be lifelong responsible for the quality of case handling within the scope of their duties, and to establish and improve the accountability mechanism for unjust, false and wrongly convicted cases. In 2021, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, Zhang Jun, once stated that at the beginning of 2021, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate launched a comprehensive investigation into the cases of correction of wrongful convictions since 2018, and has listed and supervised 22 cases of wrongful convictions that were wrongly detained for more than 10 years, and all of them have proposed serious accountability. Opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate put forward, &quot;Correction cannot stop at state compensation, and accountability must fall on the responsible party.&quot; Correcting unjust, false and wrong cases cannot stop at overturned cases and compensation, so that there is a sense of justice in the investigation and trial process of the case. Only when responsible personnel take responsibility can judicial fairness and justice be demonstrated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[换个角度看大学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Why does school start on September 1st? What does an Olympic champion’s academic profile look like? Do you still need to make a resume when looking for roommates in college? There is another group of &quot;special&quot; freshmen this year, have you seen them? Come, look at university from a different perspective today.</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一个好演员的样子丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257370]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/OugasTfNJ5ML9yNbtsKg8Ese6jTVvmFQwr4ZgUOK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/OugasTfNJ5ML9yNbtsKg8Ese6jTVvmFQ wr4ZgUOK. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250583&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256835 &quot; title=&quot;Ka-Tung Lam: We must capture the soul and heart of the character&quot;>;Ka-Tung Lam: We must capture the soul and heart of the character&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kat-Tung Lam is one of my favorite Hong Kong actors . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 8 pm in early September 2023, I was waiting for the interview in the hotel suite and sat on the floor with the film’s publicity staff. A large &quot;The Eighth Suspect&quot; roll-up banner divided the space into two, and a media conducted an interview, asking Lin Jiadong about the cooperation between &quot;The Eighth Suspect&quot; and the director and starring actors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because the appointment took the longest, my interview was scheduled as the last one of the day. I&#39;m worried that he will be tired after the intensive announcements during the promotion period, or his desire to express will weaken (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is very normal&lt;/span>;). but no. When the staff and I walked around the roll-up banners, Lin Jiadong turned to look out the floor-to-ceiling window, looking very interested. Outside is the night view of Beijing&#39;s Third Ring Road. There are office buildings with lights on in the darkness, which may be very similar to Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He likes to observe other people&#39;s lives. He said that he likes to sit in a tea restaurant and listen to people gossiping - he imitates how guests and waiters shout in a tea restaurant where people are crowded around tables. He said that if others looked at him, he would look back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lin Jiadong, I saw what a good actor looks like. He is not particularly handsome, but the environment in which he lives allows for diverse creations. There is no need to have the appearance of an idol, and there is no need to expose a lot of private life. As a profession, the life of an actor can really be very long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that there is no age anxiety in him. When he played a supporting role in &quot;Infernal Affairs&quot; 21 years ago, he was already in his thirties (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;he was born in 1967&lt;/span>;), Abandoned the stable path of starring in TVB. Later, he said that it was unbearable to film so many TV series in a year. He has played golden supporting roles in many movies, such as two &quot;Underworld&quot; and &quot;Exile&quot;, &quot;Ip Man&quot;, and &quot;Chill&quot;. He has built a solid foundation step by step. In past interviews, he has always said that he is a boring and boring person. Apart from acting, he rarely talks about his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It would be better to end this article with a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the appointed time, the interview was coming to an end. After asking the last question, I couldn’t help but ask how they rehearsed the positioning of the long shot in &quot;Hand-Rolled Cigarettes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a work in which Jack Lam starred for free and supported new Hong Kong directors. He plays Guan Chao, a former Chinese-American British soldier who is completely unsuitable for the new era. There is a nearly 10-minute long shot at the end of &quot;Hand-Rolled Cigarettes&quot;, which is extremely exciting. The camera looks far away on the rooftop. The gangster Guan Chao worked for before discovered that his betrayal was not just about money, but also hiding the person who stole the gangster&#39;s goods worth tens of millions. Extreme violence occurs in this long shot, where Guan Chao is beaten by a group of thugs. Everyone&#39;s fight was not good-looking, using brute force and deadly strikes. Guan Chao got into a scuffle with someone and was beaten badly. He stumbled from one room to another and was beaten violently by two people from the other party he had offended. He was already dying (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The camera recorded Guan Chao&#39;s death in real time&lt;/span>;), Guan Chao used his last bit of strength to rush to the camera , and immersed the person who was lying on top of him to restrain him into the water tank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our action director arranged it first. His martial arts actor did it once. He filmed it and cut it out for me to see. He said, can you do it like this? I remember at that time I said, Director , I’m not young anymore.” Lin Jiadong smiled and repeated, and the director said, “You can do it, Jiadong!”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Okay. Lin Jiadong watched the long shot twice, and everyone rehearsed it twice more. The shooting started. When he shot the first shot, his eye was injured. He went to the hospital and came back to continue filming. He happily recalled the scene at the end of the long scene where Guan Chao dragged the person to the water tank and submerged him. It was very enjoyable. &quot;For this character, he only has these 10 seconds in his life (to fight back like this). That should be his response to life.&quot; Roaring.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我放弃改造“扫兴”父母：“人教人很难，事教人一次就会”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257398]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When we were young, our parents took us to know the world; when we grow up, we also hope to take our parents to see the world. But our parents’ response often disappoints us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I take them on a trip, they mumble along the way, saying, &quot;You spend money to find trouble.&quot; When you take them to enjoy delicious food, they say, &quot;It&#39;s not as good as the food at home.&quot; You buy them down jackets and furs. A coat, they say, is &quot;not as light and warm as a cotton-padded jacket&quot;... Every time I happily do this or that for my parents, I always get thrown cold water on it, which makes me feel annoyed. Sometimes I will show it out and quarrel with my parents, saying, &quot;The dog bites me.&quot; Lu Dongbin——I don’t know the good heart.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the discussion on the Internet about &quot;parents who are not a spoiler&quot; has attracted a lot of attention. The negative example is my parents. The positive teaching material is to happily accept the kindness of their children, and their children will take them to eat. Enjoy it and say &quot;It&#39;s delicious.&quot; When your children buy clothes for them, they put them on immediately and say &quot;It looks good.&quot; Your children order takeout and happily follow it to taste... Some people even pull their parents to &quot;swear&quot; before taking their parents shopping: &quot;I am determined not to waste money, I am determined not to spend money to find trouble, and I am determined not to eat junk food again...&quot; I feel very sad! So I forwarded these short videos to my mother to see, hoping that she would change. She immediately said, &quot;You have to pretend to like it even if you don&#39;t like it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I really had nothing to say. I have to admit that she is right. Rational analysis shows that these short videos, on the one hand, capture the emotions of adult children who are disappointed by their parents; on the other hand, for the sake of traffic, they create an image of &quot;parents who are not disappointed&quot; and please the adult children who occupy the mainstream of the Internet population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is indeed a generation gap between us and our parents. First of all, we have different growth backgrounds and different views on money. My parents’ generation experienced an era of insufficient material wealth, so they are very frugal. Although many people have pensions that exceed their adult children’s salary and have less expenses, they are still reluctant to spend money. As my mother’s famous saying “Saving money is the key to saving money” My greatest pleasure.” In this way, we can understand why uncles and aunts are willing to line up for two hours to receive 10 eggs, and why old people who live in high-end communities are keen to collect scraps and sell them, not only because they have free time, but also because they are used to being frugal. What&#39;s more, the characteristics of their generation have been accurately grasped by scammers, and they often succeed under the guise of &quot;free&quot;. I once advised my mother not to fill in personal information in order to receive the free small fans, small mirrors, and low-quality tissues, so as not to receive countless phone calls or even encounter telecom fraud. But she firmly believed: &quot;It&#39;s free, don&#39;t give it up!&quot; &quot;I just Without spending money, what can he deceive me about?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the behavior of our parents to discourage us is due to their different views on money. Our generation has become accustomed to buying houses with loans, spending with credit cards, and spending money on spending money. &quot;Baitiao&quot;, look for housekeeping and cleaning, and be more frugal, earn ten yuan and spend five yuan... As long as you are comfortable and happy, you should spend money. But they would rather walk five streets under the scorching sun than spend two yuan to take a bus. They can spend two hours taking a bus and wander slowly, so they won&#39;t spend 10 minutes taking a taxi to get there. Therefore, the essence of their disincentive to us is that they are afraid that we will spend money, because we are one family with them. They have experienced a period of material scarcity, have richer life experiences, and understand the ups and downs of life better. They often say that &quot;a penny can stump a hero&quot;, &quot;a long stream of water will keep you from worrying when encountering disasters&quot;, &quot;thinking ahead and looking ahead, you will always have food and clothing&quot; &quot;If you don&#39;t have enough food, you won&#39;t have enough clothes. If you don&#39;t calculate, you will be poor.&quot; &quot;Three years for the new, three years for the old, and three more years for mending.&quot; They save money not only out of habit, but also to fully support us when needed. , let us borrow less when buying a house, pay less every month, and have more money...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two generations have different views on money, and it is difficult to distinguish the pros and cons. Although my mother is also aware of the benefits brought by another consumption concept, it is still difficult to overcome the hurdle in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Think about the changes in our generation&#39;s consumption outlook. It has gone through almost twenty years. From college, we started accepting credit cards, mobile payments, and e-commerce. After working, we started to make rapid progress, buying, buying, buying, and now live broadcasting. After grabbing time, we began to reflect again, burst the consumption bubble, and became more rational... Now we force our parents&#39; generation to immediately keep up with our pace and support our consumption concept 100%. It is really unrealistic. The transformation of parents also needs to be done step by step. We have stepped on the consumption &quot;pits&quot; that we have stepped on before, bought a bunch of cheap and unused small items, been deceived several times, returned the goods several times, and been injured several times. Only then can the mind slowly become enlightened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother rented out the house and persuaded her to install new furniture. She was not willing to spend money, so she moved the &quot;old antiques&quot; that were no longer needed at home to the rental house. She was not fashionable at all. As a result, many tenants came and did not It looks like it has never been rented out. So, she asked someone to move the &quot;old antiques&quot; and install new furniture. Moving around, owing favors, and delaying renting, I indirectly lost a lot of money, which was far more than the money for new furniture. &quot;It&#39;s hard to teach others, but you can teach them everything once.&quot; She was convinced after he calculated the economic accounts for her through his words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, I saw in my circle of friends that they were going on a &quot;travel&quot;. The so-called &quot;travel&quot; meant visiting various towns and villages under the jurisdiction of our county. They happily told me that due to preferential policies, local residents over sixty years old can ride the bus for free. If they bring a bottle of boiled water and two boiled eggs, they can go out for a day without spending a penny. I suddenly realized that for us, Lijiang, Xinjiang, Tibet, Maldives, and Iceland are poetry and distance, but for them, the surrounding towns and villages are their poetry and distance, and this is a travel experience that is more suitable for their &quot;physical constitution.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our parents grew up with us and took the trouble to teach us to understand and experience small things one by one. As we grow older with our parents, we must also change our mentality, stop being harsh, and patiently accompany our parents to &quot;grow&quot; together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From then on, I gave up trying to reform my &quot;disappointing&quot; parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a middle school teacher in Tianjin)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders @163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[死亡失踪上万人的水灾和卡扎菲倒台后的利比亚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257425]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/o0ZuyjkGuA3rVspRSN5TLDaXB5H10ip7SjvqNBsG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/o0ZuyjkGuA3rVspRSN5TLDaXB5H10ip7S jvqNBsG. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 14, 2023, Derna, Libya, rescuers worked on the ruins of a building &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 10, 2023, the Mediterranean hurricane &quot;Daniel&quot; hit many cities in northeastern Libya. Heavy rains of 150 to 240 millimeters caused severe flooding in many cities. The port city of Derna was particularly severely affected. The wind waves in the city center were as high as 20 feet. Two old dams on the Wadi Derna river in the upper reaches collapsed. After the floods raged, almost no intact building could be found in the entire city, and some residents were swept into the Mediterranean Sea with their houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United Nations stated on September 16 that the local death toll has exceeded 11,300, and another 10,100 people are still alive and dead. 40,000 people are homeless. There are still dead bodies soaked in the sea and no one has salvaged them. The number is bound to rise again. Libyan state-run media stated on the 17th that it is currently known that 891 buildings in Derna were completely destroyed, 211 buildings were partially destroyed, and 398 houses were soaked in mud after being flooded. The mayor&#39;s office speculated that the death toll could eventually reach 20,000 - equivalent to a fifth of the city&#39;s population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 17th, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs cited data from the World Health Organization and published a report, revising the death toll caused by the Libyan floods to 3,958, with more than 9,000 people missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Derna is a city with a long history. &lt;/span>;) already exists. Amid the 2011 anti-government demonstrations in Libya, the city broke away from the control of Gaddafi&#39;s government on February 18. In 2014, the city was occupied by Islamic State militants, during which it was subjected to multiple air strikes by the Egyptian military. In 2015, the Derna Mujahideen Shura Council, a militia considered close to Al Qaeda, defeated the Islamic State and regained control of the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, General Khalifa Haftar, regarded as the main authority in eastern Libya, has led the siege of Derna, the last territory in eastern Libya that has resisted his rule, with intensive bombing and brutal The ground fighting inflicted heavy losses on the city. In 2018, Haftar finally captured Derna. Haftar did not order a large-scale reconstruction of Derna out of distrust of its residents. It was not until 2022 that the eastern Libyan government formulated a reconstruction plan for Derna. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to years of war, Derna City does not have unified central government management, its infrastructure is old, and its ability to prevent and control floods is very weak. In recent years, global warming has caused the waters of the Mediterranean to expand, and rising sea levels have eroded coastlines and caused flooding, especially in low-lying coastal areas like Derna. On September 10, 2023, Hurricane Daniel made landfall on the Mediterranean coast of eastern Libya. The hurricane had already caused serious damage in Greece, Turkey and Bulgaria along the Mediterranean coast, resulting in more than a dozen deaths. However, the Libyan authorities did not seriously formulate a monitoring plan. There was no plan to warn or evacuate residents of the dam situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Libyan National Meteorological Center said it had issued warnings through emails and media 72 hours before &quot;Daniel&quot; made landfall, urging local governments to take preventive measures. However, the National Meteorological Center of Libya is affiliated to the Government of National Accord in the west, and Derna is an area controlled by the eastern government. Local residents said that they did not receive warning before the flood hit, and the authorities did not have any evacuation plan. They only heard the loud noise of the dam breaking. Only then did everyone realize that the flood was coming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The World Meteorological Organization pointed out on September 14 that if the Libyan authorities had an early warning system for storms and floods, the vast majority of the victims could have been prevented from dying. In other words, this disaster appears to be a natural disaster, but is actually a man-made disaster. In the future, after floods wash away, landmines and unexploded bombs left over from years of war may surface, and secondary disasters may occur where people accidentally touch landmines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than ten years since the fall of former Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi, Libya has experienced one war after another and political crisis after another. To this day, it is still in a situation of confrontation between the eastern and western governments. . Many people have long forgotten this long dispute, but the floods that occurred in Derna, causing tens of thousands of deaths and missing people, once again drew people&#39;s attention back to this ill-fated place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/pviUluMz4LwOxQ6Ahu3w4waO28itNzjeEPzguqay.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/pviUluMz4LwOxQ6Ahu3w4waO28itNzjeEPzguqay.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 25, 2007, Tripoli, Libya, Libyan supreme leader Muammar Gaddafi (right) welcomed visiting French President Sarkozy&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A divided country&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Libya has an area of ​​1.76 million square kilometers and a population of 6.7 million. It is located in northern Africa and the southern coast of the Mediterranean. To the east is Cyrenaica, to the west is Tripolitania, and to the southwest is Fezzan. There is a desert barrier between the three, making communication inconvenient. They have been separated for a long time in history. Due to the separation of the natural geographical environment, the eastern and western regions of Libya are closely connected with the surrounding Egypt, Tunisia and Algeria, but have little contact with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Libya historically belonged to the Roman Empire, the Arab Empire and the Ottoman Turkish Empire, but these rulers regarded the above three regions as independent plates, so Libya has never been integrated into a unified entity in history. political community. Therefore, like most countries in the Middle East and North Africa, Libya is also a typical tribal country, and people identify with the tribe more than the country. During the period when it was ruled by the Arab Empire, it experienced the process of Islamization. Today, most people in Libya are Sunni believers in Islam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the 20th century, the unified Italy also joined the ranks of colonial expansion and began to look for its own territory in Africa. It took a fancy to Libya under the rule of the Ottoman Empire, so it brazenly launched a war of aggression. In 1912, Italy defeated the Ottoman Empire in the Italian-Turkish War, making Libya an Italian colony. At the same time, the Senussi Order in eastern Cyrenaica launched a large-scale resistance movement in the name of &quot;holy war&quot;. The secular forces in the western region also actively resisted Italian aggression and even established the Republic of Tripoli in 1918. It was later banned and disbanded by Mussolini. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the end of World War II, in July 1949, the leader of the Senussi Order, Idris, declared the independence of Cyrenaica and served as the emir. In December 1951, Idris won the support of nationalist forces and tribes in three regions and finally established the United Kingdom of Libya. The three regions of Cyrenaica, Tripolitania and Fezzan were each a state with autonomy. right. The three colors on the current Libyan flag represent these three federal states and are symbols of federalism. In 1963, Libya&#39;s new constitution abolished the federal system and divided the country into 10 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 1969, Gaddafi, the leader of the &quot;Free Officers Organization&quot;, launched a coup, overthrew the Idris dynasty and established the Libyan Arab Republic. Gaddafi, who was born in the Bedouin tribe of the Fezzan region, has ruled Libya for 42 years, relying mainly on strongman politics and centralization, coupled with distribution policies supported by oil revenue, to barely suppress tribalism and localism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Libya first discovered oil in 1958 and officially started production in 1961. Its oil reserves are approximately 47.1 billion barrels, ranking first in Africa and ninth in the world, accounting for 2.9% of the world&#39;s total. Crude oil has good quality and low sulfur content. It is a high-quality oil and is very popular in the international market. After 1973, with the sharp rise in international oil prices, the Gaddafi regime gained a lot of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid a recurrence of the tragedy of the fall of the Idris dynasty, and at the same time gain public support for his radical anti-imperialist stance, Gaddafi significantly increased investment in housing, health care, education and other fields, and increased workers&#39; wages. , and provide free public housing to the poor; the land originally belonging to the Senussi Order and Italian farmers will also be distributed to farmers, and farm tools and livestock will be provided at extremely low prices; new housing in rural areas can also be financed by government-controlled banks subsidy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But starting in the 1980s, due to the decline in international oil prices, Libyan oil revenue dropped sharply from US$21 billion in 1981 to US$5.4 billion in 1986. After the Lockerbie air crash in 1988, Libya was identified as the mastermind behind the crash and was subject to sanctions and embargoes by Western countries. In addition, oil field facilities are aging and oil production is ups and downs. There is no excess oil revenue to exchange for public support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, 95% of Libya’s export revenue, 75% of government revenue, and 25% of GDP came from oil. At the same time, Libya’s domestic unemployment rate was as high as 30%, and most important infrastructure construction projects and crude oil extraction Projects are completed through international tenders and are completed by foreign companies and technical personnel, while a large number of Libya&#39;s own young labor force is unemployed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2010, the &quot;Arab Spring&quot; broke out in the Middle East, and Libya was also affected. Anti-government demonstrations occurred, and the government responded with force to suppress them. On February 27, 2011, the opposition established the &quot;National Transitional Council&quot; in Benghazi, Libya&#39;s second largest city. On March 19, Britain and France launched air strikes in Libya in accordance with United Nations Security Council Resolution 1973. On September 16, the United Nations General Assembly passed a resolution to replace Libya&#39;s seat in the United Nations by the National Transitional Council. On October 20, Gaddafi was killed on his way to escape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2012, in protest against a movie that insulted Islam, the U.S. Consulate in Benghazi was attacked by an Islamic armed group. U.S. Ambassador Stevens was killed. The worst damage in years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/mzpx5TBpSLxfSfJJCWEvZMjsOtQwHjc2lgRNNRre.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;628&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/mzpx5TBpSLxfSfJJCWEvZMjsOtQwHjc2lgRNNRre.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251352&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 16, 2023, the disaster-stricken area of ​​Derna, Libya&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Post-Gaddafi era&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Libyan opposition is a group that includes defectors from the original Gaddafi regime, pro-Western liberals, eastern tribal leaders who are dissatisfied with Gaddafi and the dictatorship of western tribes, former Id A hodgepodge of supporters of the Reese royal family, the only thing they have in common is their dissatisfaction with Gaddafi. When the revolution has not yet succeeded, because the common enemy is still there, everyone has to seek common ground while reserving differences and work hard to cooperate. However, when the overall situation is determined, interests emerge, and the struggle for power is inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To avoid infighting and division when sharing the fruits of the revolution, a leader with high moral integrity and the ability to reconcile various factions is necessary. However, during the 42 years of Gaddafi&#39;s rule, Libya had no president, no prime minister, no parliament, no cabinet, only Colonel Gaddafi. The imagination and passion of a generation were limited by the ubiquitous &quot;Green Book&quot;. How could it be possible? Such a politician appeared in a short period of time? In addition, after Gaddafi&#39;s army was disbanded, Libya failed to form a new national army. The existing militia groups strengthened their own forces and expanded their territory, causing the country to fall into a state of disorder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During Gaddafi’s rule, Cyrenaica in the east was suppressed by him for a long time, and the locals were always very dissatisfied. After the &quot;Arab Spring&quot; took place, this was the first place where trouble broke out and started anew. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Libya was divided: the Government of National Accord and its armed forces recognized by the United Nations controlled most of western Libya, while the &quot;National Army&quot; led by Haftar controlled eastern and western Libya. Central Region. The two sides have clashed several times since 2014, and Libya has descended into civil war. The civil war continued until 2020, and the two sides finally reached a ceasefire. However, until now, the general election originally scheduled for 2021 has not been held, and sporadic fighting between the western armed forces and the eastern armed forces continues. Just last month, at least 45 people were killed in fighting between the two sides in Tripoli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An important reason why the situation in Libya cannot be stabilized is the intervention of external forces. The Western Government of National Accord recognized by the United Nations has Turkey, Qatar and Italy as its backers, as well as Egypt, Russia, Jordan, the United Arab Emirates, and France. It supports the Haftar regime that controls the center and east. Italy wants to maintain the &quot;face&quot; of its former colonial master, Turkey wants to restore the glory of the &quot;Ottoman Empire&quot;... Each &quot;player&quot; has different reasons for entering the game. However, they seem to have the same goal behind them, which is the oil and natural gas resources in the Eastern Mediterranean. In the past ten years, a large amount of natural gas and oil have been discovered in this sea area. Libya and even the entire Eastern Mediterranean region have once again become a &quot;powder keg&quot; for various countries to engage in energy competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consequences of disorder in Libya are not limited to the current out-of-control floods. After the fall of Gaddafi, the rebels looted the weapons arsenal of the government forces, and many weapons were transferred to other surrounding countries, especially extremist organizations. Chadian President Deby believes that the rise of extremist organizations such as the Nigerian terrorist organization &quot;Boko Haram&quot; , has a great relationship with the situation in Libya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[共赴亚运之约！杭州第19届亚洲运动会开幕式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257509]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 20:09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[水为串联、潮为意向 亚运会开幕式主题定名《潮起亚细亚》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257473]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou will open tonight. All parties will attend the Asian Games and look forward to showing the world Presenting an Asian Games event with &quot;Chinese characteristics, Asian style, and excitement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony performance of this Asian Games has also attracted attention. Come and listen to the interpretation of the opening ceremony by the chief director of the opening ceremony at the press conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021557728823&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Water is series, tide is The intended theme of the opening ceremony of the Asian Games is &quot;Tide Asia&quot; (3).mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/d8e9a4b35576678021557728823/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.j pg&quot; data-url=&quot; http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/d8e9a4b35576678021557728823/HOjpX1ZfB6wA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://12514 34507 .vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/d8e9a4b35576678021557728823/HOjpX1ZfB6wA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theme of the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou is named &quot;The Rise of Asia&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/fe8a003ef7ca83a47aaf866b6ea7a72f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/fe8a003ef7ca83a47aaf866b6ea7a72f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251701&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sha Xiaolan, Chief Director and Chief Producer of the Opening Ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;Simply put, tide is the most representative of Zhejiang’s regional characteristics. Everyone knows about the spring tides in the Qiantang River. When talking about tides, these are the first things that come to mind. Asia is the full name of our Asia, so this is the theme everyone finally decided on for &quot;Tide of Asia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f5de2de2068c6c27a25eb4523eb8c370.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f5de2de2068c6c27a25eb4523eb8c370.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251702&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Tide is the memory of Qiantang, the excitement of sports, the spirit of Zhejiang, and the pulse of the times. Because of its image of succession, it has a special meaning in Chinese culture. With &quot;Tide Asia&quot; as the general theme of the opening ceremony, it highlights the natural identity of the region, the unique charm of humanity, the vigorous power of sports and the development trend of the times. The first part of the entire opening ceremony is the &quot;tide of national style&quot;, the middle part is the &quot;tide of sports&quot;, and the second part is the &quot;tide of humanities&quot;, and the presentation method reflects the &quot;tide of science and technology&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/baddd5973c0ddaefa7de14439ad5bfc9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/baddd5973c0ddaefa7de14439ad5bfc9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251703&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sha Xiaolan, Chief Director and Chief Producer of the Opening Ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;When creating, we took Song Yun culture as the core expression of the previous chapter, which has 5,000 years of history. From Liangzhu, we have traveled to the Song Dynasty of Hangzhou that lasted nearly a thousand years, and then traveled to today&#39;s modern Hangzhou. We can also see a Hangzhou that connects ancient and modern times through Gongchen Bridge. And through the tide of sports in the second chapter, sports elements are fully displayed, including sports logos, sports symbols, and some ball games. In the next chapter, it is called the tide of humanities. Green waters and green mountains are mountains of gold and silver. A happy life, green water and green mountains are among them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/d31a261a4dee475746f7ff9eeb715355.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/d31a261a4dee475746f7ff9eeb715355.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251704&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The entire opening ceremony and performance used water as the connection and tide as the intention, showing the integration and excitement of China, Asia and the world in the new era through &quot;Tide Across Asia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;green&quot; concept will be throughout the opening ceremony performance&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, the director team also focused on introducing green, intelligent, and humanistic elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-1&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021562274795&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Water is in series, tide is The intended theme of the opening ceremony of the Asian Games is &quot;Tide Asia&quot; (1).mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/38f6c4535576678021562274795/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.j pg&quot; data-url=&quot; http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/38f6c4535576678021562274795/bFeOaHUOWJ8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434 507 .vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/38f6c4535576678021562274795/bFeOaHUOWJ8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of this Asian Games is &quot;green, smart, frugal, &quot;Civilized&quot;, the opening ceremony performance also carried out the &quot;green&quot; concept throughout. The first thing is not to set off fireworks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sha Xiaolan, chief director and chief producer of the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;Everyone knows that as long as fireworks are set off, there will be smoke, dust and other pollution in the air. We don’t set off fireworks to express our concepts, ideas, including environmental awareness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of the use of technology, Sha Xiaolan revealed that digital ignition was used for this ignition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f0091e63e7c73739527586697c6cd1c4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f0091e63e7c73739527586697c6cd1c4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251705&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sha Xiaolan, chief director and chief producer of the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;This time we want to return to the essence of sports. What is the essence of sports? Keeping fit and healthy is by no means a matter for a few people or a few groups of people, it is a matter for the whole people. I just want to say that if more people participate in ignition, millions, tens of millions, or hundreds of millions of people participate in ignition, one is the first in the world, the other is to maximize the participation of all people, and the third is It embodies the common destiny of the world and Asia, and finally it is the concrete practice of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家植物园将扩容，已有候选园“自宣”丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 18:59:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/23/PRrN12aHKcGG9UyEpq6I7vlxJeOFScwkEftCKhEh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/PRrN12aHKcGG9UyEpq6I7vlxJeOFScwk EftCKhEh. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251744&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 16, 2023, National Botanical Garden North Garden, Yingyinggou Metasequoia Forest Plank Road Spraying Turn on. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By 2035, China&#39;s national botanical gardens are expected to increase to about 10. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Forestry and Grassland Administration, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Natural Resources, and the Chinese Academy of Sciences jointly issued the &quot;National Botanical Garden System Layout Plan&quot; recently, determining that on the basis of the two national botanical gardens that have been established, the selection will be 14 National Botanical Garden candidate gardens are included in the national botanical garden system layout. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the national botanical garden system construction goals proposed in the plan, by 2035, we will strive to establish about 10 national botanical gardens, so that more than 80% of the national key protected wild plants and more than 70% of rare and endangered wild plants can be effectively relocated. land protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike ordinary botanical gardens, the National Botanical Garden is approved by the state. Its core functions include plant scientific research and ex-situ conservation, and is positioned as a national plant scientific research and exchange center, a strategic plant resource reserve, an ex-situ conservation base for endangered plants, and a plant science communication center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China currently has two national botanical gardens, namely the National Botanical Garden and the South China National Botanical Garden. The former was approved by the State Council on December 28, 2021, and was established relying on the Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Beijing Botanical Garden. The National Botanical Garden located in Xishan, Beijing, has an open area of ​​about 300 hectares and collects more than 17,000 species of plants. The latter was established based on the South China Botanical Garden of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and was approved by the State Council on May 30, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the criteria for selecting 14 National Botanical Garden candidates this time? What are the 14 candidate gardens? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the websites of the National Forestry and Grassland Administration, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Natural Resources, the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Central People&#39;s Government, but have not yet found the &quot;National Botanic Garden System Layout Plan&quot; full text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are still traces of action to speed up the construction of the national botanical garden system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, 2021, at the 15th Leaders’ Summit of the Conference of the Parties to the Convention on Biological Diversity, China proposed to launch the Construction of national botanical garden systems in Beijing, Guangzhou and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the International Biodiversity Day China’s home promotion event held on May 20, 2022, relevant leaders of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment and the State Forestry and Grassland Administration stated that they will accelerate the construction of the national park and national botanical garden system. At that time, efforts were made to establish a number of new national parks and to compile a plan for the construction of a national botanical garden system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the full text of the &quot;National Botanical Garden System Layout Plan&quot; has not yet been released, regarding the core elements and construction methods of the National Botanic Garden System, Xinhua News Agency reported that a combination of integration and new construction will be adopted to steadily Build a national botanical garden system with the national botanical garden representing the national image as the core and regional national botanical gardens representing typical climate zones and typical vegetation characteristics as the main body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhejiang Online, the official news website of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee and Provincial Government, the establishment of the National Botanical Garden will be based on the principle of &quot;one mature, one established&quot; to promote the construction of the national botanical garden system. Those that really fail to meet the requirements for establishment shall not be established as a national botanical garden; for those that fail to meet the evaluation standards, a yellow card mechanism will be activated, and through public announcements and rectification within a time limit, an exit mechanism will be adopted for those who fail to make rectifications and rectifications are not in place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the details of the selection of 14 more national botanical garden candidates have not been announced, the botanical gardens have &quot;self-declared&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of the Nanjing Zhongshan Botanical Garden of the Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences reported on September 21, 2023 that the garden has been included in the national botanical garden system layout as a candidate garden of the National Botanic Garden. The next step will be in accordance with the national botanical garden system layout plan and related requirements. , combined with the creation tasks and actual conditions, orderly promote the creation, establishment and construction of the &quot;Nanjing Zhongshan National Botanical Garden&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the botanical gardens’ self-declaration that they have been included in the candidate garden system, some regions have clearly proposed plans to build national botanical gardens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Shanghai proposed to create the Shanghai Chenshan National Botanical Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Hangzhou made it clear that the Hangzhou Second Botanical Garden will build a world-class botanical garden, with the ultimate goal of being included in the national botanical garden system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Cheng Kai was elected chairman of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation , Zhang Haidi stepped down]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency, the Eighth National Congress of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation concluded in Beijing on the morning of September 20, 2023, and Cheng Kai was elected as the first president of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation. Zhang Haidi, Chairman of the Eighth Presidium, resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Cheng Kai, male, Han nationality, born in November 1964, member of the Communist Party of China, graduate degree, doctorate in literature, physically disabled, previously served as a member of the Party Committee of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation and deputy chairman of the seventh presidium. Chairman, Vice Chairman of the Executive Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Adjustment of the leadership team of the National Health and Medical Commission]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;National Health and Medical Commission Updated information in the &quot;Commission Leaders&quot; section of the official website shows that Zeng Yixin and Lei Haichao have been appointed deputy secretaries of the Party Leadership Group of the National Health Commission, and Qu Xiaoli has been appointed as a member of the Party Leadership Group of the National Health Commission and a member of the National Supervisory Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at the National Health Commission&#39;s Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team. long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Yixin, male, born in October 1962, is from Loudi, Hunan. Zeng Yixin served as deputy director and member of the Party Leadership Group of the National Health Commission in March 2018, and deputy director of the Central Health Commission. In May 2022, he was designated as a minister-level cadre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lei Haichao was born in April 1968 in Dezhou, Shandong Province. He once served as director of the Beijing Municipal Health Commission and other positions. In October 2020, he was promoted to deputy director and party member of the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qu Xiaoli, female, born in September 1963, is from Changyi, Shandong Province. She was a member of the Standing Committee of the Henan Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Hainan Province adds a new vice governor]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hainan Province The sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the Seventh People&#39;s Congress passed the decision to appoint Battelle as deputy governor of the Hainan Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Battelle, male, Mongolian, born in February 1967, graduate student, master&#39;s degree in economics, member of the Communist Party of China. Battelle worked for the Ministry of Land and Resources for a long time in his early years. In 2015, he went to Hainan to take up a post. He served successively as a member of the Standing Committee of the Haikou Municipal Party Committee and deputy mayor, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the Hainan Provincial Department of Land and Resources, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Hainan Provincial Department of Land and Resources, and Director of the Hainan Provincial Emergency Department. Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Management Department, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Hainan Provincial Department of Transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2022, during the leadership change of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee, Battelle was elected as a member of the Standing Committee of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee, and later served as the Secretary-General of the Provincial Party Committee and Director of the General Office of the Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission of the Central Ministry of Social Work has been confirmed]&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;It was reported on September 18 that Liu Zhao has been appointed as the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission of the Central Ministry of Social Work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zhao, male, born in December 1963, is from Fufeng, Shaanxi. Liu Zhao once served as the director of the Traffic Management Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security. In 2018, he became a member of the Party Committee and Director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security. In July 2020, he was appointed as the Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Public Security. He recently resigned from the post of Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Public Security. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Anti-corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Former Xining Mayor Kong Lingdong was arrested Double opening]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight months after his dismissal, Kong Lingdong, former deputy secretary of the Xining Municipal Party Committee and mayor of Qinghai Province, was &quot;double opening&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Lingdong, male, born in December 1970, is from Wuwei, Gansu. Kong Lingdong has worked in Xining City, the capital of Qinghai Province, for a long time and was the director of the Xining Municipal Development and Reform Commission. In March 2021, Kong Lingdong was appointed as deputy secretary of the Xining Municipal Party Committee and candidate for mayor, and was elected mayor of Xining the following month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, Kong Lingdong was investigated. After investigation, it was found that Kong Lingdong did not perform his duties correctly, formulated and forced the completion of economic indicator tasks out of touch with reality, resulting in falsification of statistical data and adverse effects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Liu Wenxin, a Guizhou department official who engaged in prostitution and gambling, was &quot;double opened&quot; and was named as &quot;losing one&#39;s spirit in playing with things and obsessed with knives&quot;]&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission reported that Liu Wenxin, the former deputy secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Guizhou Provincial Party Committee who was investigated in October 2022, was &quot;double fired&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Wenxin, male, Han nationality, born in August 1967, is from Pingxiang, Jiangxi. He has been working in Guiyang City for a long time and has successively served as executive deputy mayor and mayor of Guiyang City. In 2017, he was appointed secretary of the Qianxinan Prefecture Committee. In 2022, he was transferred to deputy secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Guizhou Provincial Committee (director level). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Liu Wenxin has violated the bottom line of integrity, accepted gifts and money in violation of regulations, is morally corrupt, lives an extremely corrupt and decadent life, engages in power, sex, and money transactions, has long-term improper sexual relations with others, and engages in prostitution and gambling; He is obsessed with playing with things and is obsessed with knives. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ministry information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Natural Resources: &quot;Forest Park Management Measures and other four regulations are abolished]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the website of the Ministry of Natural Resources on September 20, Minister of Natural Resources Wang Guanghua signed Ministerial Order No. 10, announcing the &quot;Ministry of Natural Resources on the Fifth Decision to approve the abolition of departmental regulations. Four regulations including the &quot;Forest Park Management Measures&quot;, &quot;Forestry Standardization Management Measures&quot;, &quot;National Forest Park Management Measures for the Approval of the Establishment, Cancellation, Merger, Change of Business Scope or Change of Affiliation&quot; and &quot;National Forest Park Management Measures&quot; are abolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&quot;National Cultural Relics Crime Clues Reporting Platform&quot; is online]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 At the 13th Joint Conference of the Northwest Police Cooperation Zone and the Police Cooperation Conference on Combating and Preventing Cultural Relics Crime in the Yellow River Basin and Northwest Regions held on September 19, the &quot;National Cultural Relics Crime Clues Reporting Platform&quot; was officially launched from now on. The platform is a small program based on WeChat. The general public and netizens do not need to download the App software to report clues about crimes involving cultural relics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[8 ministerial-level cadres were hired Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate Advisory Committee]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, on September 18, 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate held an advisory committee working meeting and hired 8 new advisory members. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate newly appointed Sun Qian, Xu Xianming, Su Deliang, Wan Chun, Zhang Zhijie, Li Qilin, Liu Hua, and He Hengyang as advisory committee members of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Qian and Xu Xianming served as deputy prosecutors general of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. Su Deliang was a member of the Party Committee of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. Wanchun and Zhang Zhijie served as full-time members of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate at the deputy ministerial level. Li Qilin, Liu Hua, and He Hengyang served as prosecutors general of local provinces (autonomous regions). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&quot;Two Highs&quot; and the General Administration of Customs carry out criminal actions to punish the illegal introduction of invasive alien species]&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>; According to news from the website of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate on September 19, recently, the General Administration of Customs, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate decided to jointly carry out a one-year nationwide campaign to punish the illegal introduction of invasive alien species in accordance with the law. Resolutely prevent the entry and invasion of alien species through ports. The three departments will jointly carry out actions to investigate criminal responsibilities in accordance with the law, investigate and deal with a number of typical cases, and form a judicial deterrent; establish and improve case notification and case transfer mechanisms, and jointly carry out supervision and supervision of major cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Supreme Procuratorate, Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development: Standardize administrative public interest litigation for urban and rural historical and cultural protection and inheritance]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development jointly issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening Cooperation and Cooperation in Procuratorate Public Interest Litigation to Protect and Inherit Urban and Rural Historical Culture in accordance with the Law&quot; to strengthen law enforcement in the field of urban and rural historical and cultural protection and inheritance. Judicial connection. The &quot;Opinions&quot; focus on infringement of national interests or social public interests, especially illegal acts that are serious, have bad effects, and refuse to be rectified, focusing on the overall management and control of historical urban areas, the protection of historical and cultural blocks and historical areas, the protection of historical and cultural towns and villages, and Four key areas for the protection of historic buildings. The &quot;Opinions&quot; require that the handling of administrative public interest litigation for urban and rural historical and cultural protection and inheritance should be standardized. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Xiongan New District cancels commercial housing reservation For sale]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CCTV News Client reported that Xiongan New Area has canceled the pre-sale of commercial housing and implemented sales of existing houses to achieve &quot;what you see is what you get, and the certificate is handed over when you hand over the house.&quot; At the same time, Xiongan New Area supports willing talents to solve housing problems through renting, and provides &quot;equal rights for renting and selling&quot; in the fields of public services such as education, medical care, and employment. Xiongan also requires that in market-oriented projects in new areas, no less than 30% of the housing should be of the &quot;rent-only, not for sale&quot; type. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Hubei Xuanen Shiziguan Scenic Area has been declassified]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hubei Province According to the WeChat public account of the Department of Culture and Tourism, on September 19, the Hubei Provincial Department of Culture and Tourism released in the form of documents and other forms the review and processing of A-level tourist attractions in 2023 and the handling of travel agencies with many complaints. Among them, 6 A-level tourist attractions, including Xuanen County Shiziguan Tourist Area (4A), have been declassified. The report pointed out that the main body of Enshi Xuanen Shiziguan Tourist Area has a weak safety awareness, serious dereliction of safety management, improper emergency response, and has not paid attention to the safety hazards pointed out by multiple supervision and inspections of cultural and tourism departments at all levels, and has failed to make rectifications, resulting in 2023 On May 16, a commercial vehicle fell into the water from a pontoon, resulting in the death of five people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Shanghai Xuhui issued guidelines for the prevention and control of sexual harassment, four situations do not constitute sexual harassment]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Xuhui District, Shanghai held a press conference and jointly issued the &quot;Guidelines for Preventing and Controlling Sexual Harassment in Xuhui District, Shanghai&quot; together with seven units including the District Public Security Bureau. The &quot;Guide&quot; clarifies that sexual harassment mainly includes speech, text, images, body and other forms. Sexual harassment in the form of text is mainly manifested in multiple letters, mobile phone text messages, WeChat, emails, faxes, etc. with obscene and insulting content. Sexual harassment in the form of images is mainly manifested in sending or displaying pornographic pictures and items through emails, Weibo, WeChat, etc. many times. Four situations do not constitute sexual harassment: consensual interactions and dates; inadvertent physical contact; casual or isolated sexual language; and other socially and culturally acceptable words or behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Voice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Anhui Provincial Party Committee Secretary Han Jun: How No support for the University of Science and Technology of China can be overstated]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of September 20, 2023, the 2023 opening ceremony of the University of Science and Technology of China was held. Han Jun, Secretary of the Anhui Provincial Party Committee, attended the conference and delivered a speech: &quot;The Anhui Provincial Party Committee and the Provincial Government have always looked highly upon and loved the University of Science and Technology of China. We will, as always, uphold the concept of &#39;nothing is too much to support the University of Science and Technology of China&#39; and do our best to do a good job.&quot; The logistics director of the University of Science and Technology of China regards the affairs of the University of Science and Technology of China as a major matter of the Anhui Provincial Party Committee and the Provincial Government, and responds to the requests of the University of Science and Technology of China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会今晚8时开幕，广东运动员将担任旗手]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257507]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 18:30:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 20:00 on September 23, the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou will open at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Stadium. In international comprehensive competitions, the opening ceremony is often considered to be a cultural display that best reflects the characteristics of the host country. The Asian Games returned to China after 13 years, and Guangdong athlete Yang Liwei served as the flag bearer of the Chinese delegation. What will be the highlights at the opening ceremony? Let’s take a look in advance! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/63014c49eb08dc6a7a38c80ad41348f1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/63014c49eb08dc6a7a38c80ad41348f1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251747&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Stadium (right) and Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Tennis Center. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The scale of the event is the largest in history&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Hangzhou Asian Games will be held from September 23 to October 8, lasting 16 days. The scale and number of participants reached the highest level in the history of the Asian Games, with a total of 481 gold medals produced. All 45 members of the Olympic Council of Asia have signed up to participate, and many countries and regions have sent the largest delegations in history. According to statistics, more than 12,000 athletes have signed up to participate in this Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current Asian Games, there are not only Olympic sports such as track and field, swimming, but also special sports representing different regional sports cultures such as martial arts, sepak takraw, cricket, and Jiujitsu. The number of competition events such as break dancing, which has become an official event of the Asian Games, has reached the highest level in any previous Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the opening ceremony, the audience could see the six largest delegations from China, Thailand, Japan, South Korea, India, and Hong Kong, China. The number of athletes signing up for these six delegations each exceeded 600. people. Among them, the total number of Chinese sports delegation reached 1,329, including 886 athletes (437 female athletes and 449 male athletes). The average age of the athletes is 25 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/dabc9eb8a4ec345aa53abe588123905b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;516&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/dabc9eb8a4ec345aa53abe588123905b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251748&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Liwei (middle). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the opening ceremony, Chinese women&#39;s basketball players Yang Liwei and &quot;Frog King&quot; Qin Haiyang from Guangdong will serve as the flag bearers of the Chinese delegation. As the captain of the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team, Yang Liwei has helped the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team win the World Cup runner-up and Asian Cup championship for more than a year. The Guangdong Sports Legion spirit of &quot;dare to fight, be good at fighting, and have the courage to win&quot; inspires Yang Liwei to keep moving forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for serving as the flag bearer, Yang Liwei said that from a personal point of view, he is very happy to receive this honor, but &quot;this honor does not represent myself, but recognition of the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team. It is an honor that belongs to Chinese basketball.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Water elements run through the whole scene&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Hangzhou is a city that thrives and is born from water. Hangzhou’s business cards include the Qiantang River, the Grand Canal, West Lake and Xixi Wetland are closely related to water. Therefore, in terms of creative concept, the opening ceremony uses water as the core element throughout the entire venue. The overall theme of the opening ceremony is &quot;Tide Asia&quot;, which means that China in the new era is integrating with Asia and the world, rushing forward like a wave. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/97ae74e566e74fa893a8f8ace87d3203.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/97ae74e566e74fa893a8f8ace87d3203.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251745&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The Qiantang River flows through Hangzhou. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony will be divided into three chapters. Through the presentation of &quot;National Style and Elegance&quot;, &quot;Qiantang Tide&quot; and &quot;Hand in Hand&quot;, it will show the national style and national trend, the trend of nature and the trend of science and technology. , the collision of the tide of sports and the tide of the times. The embodiment of the &quot;water&quot; element is not only the source of the Liangzhu culture of Chinese civilization, but also the traceability of Zhejiang culture and Hangzhou culture. It is also the connection between the mountains and rivers of Asian countries and expresses the wish for a better China in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Technology and art go in both directions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the three major chapters, Hangzhou has more than 5,000 years of civilization history, a thousand years of Song Dynasty culture and the characteristics of the digital city Integrated display. The Liangzhu culture, which has a history of more than 5,000 years, allows the audience to appreciate the power of the light of civilization to illuminate the progress of history; the cultural spirit of the Southern Song Dynasty and modern civilized and intelligent Hangzhou are connected through a Gongchen Bridge, forming an ancient and modern world. Cultural dialogue and time travel; through 3D Dual Wire technology, the majestic Qiantang River tide will be presented to the audience in a new way...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, through the cooperation of ground screen, three-dimensional perspective screen, and naked-eye 3D The design of the visual effects and virtual images directly &quot;moves&quot; the thousands of miles of rivers and mountains, the mist and rain in the south of the Yangtze River, the tide of the Qiantang River, and the green waters and green mountains on the stage, creating a scene where people are walking in the painting and swimming in the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3f2db9212a4b5ea0998548e36ac08a8f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3f2db9212a4b5ea0998548e36ac08a8f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251750&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center stadium complex. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the last moment, you can see the scene of ancient Lin&#39;an and modern Hangzhou facing each other. The director team used virtual technology to present to the public a scene of thousands of lights of ancient and modern cities. . “We know each other no matter how far away we are, but we are still neighbors thousands of miles away.” Hangzhou will extend the most sincere invitation to all of Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Electronic fireworks are expected to be full&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to reflect the green, smart, frugal and civilized hosting concept of this Asian Games, no physical fireworks will be set off during the opening ceremony. fireworks. Although there is no grand fireworks display, the excitement of the opening ceremony will not be greatly reduced. The creative team innovates and uses the power of technology, 3D animation, AR technology, etc. to display fireworks in front of TV audiences and live audiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/522cc071258c7f54ec6dba0b4830ef76.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/522cc071258c7f54ec6dba0b4830ef76.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251749&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Tennis Center. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fireworks made with virtual technology are even more brilliant and beautiful than real fireworks. To this end, Sha Xiaolan, chief director and chief producer of the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games, also gave a viewing guide: everyone can watch the opening ceremony electronic fireworks show through TV, mobile phones and other ports, and the overall viewing effect is better than on-site. The creative team will use digital technology to present a 360-degree panoramic view of the electronic fireworks performances on both sides of the Qianjiang River, the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center venue complex, and the &quot;Big Lotus&quot; from angles such as upward, downward, and side views. This will be a highlight of the opening ceremony. time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The suspense of the lighting ceremony will be revealed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a traditional ceremony of modern large-scale sports events, the lighting ceremony conveys the spirit and concept of the games. The lighting ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games adheres to the concept of &quot;green, smart, frugal and civilized&quot; and follows the requirements of &quot;simple, safe and exciting&quot;. It is environmentally friendly without losing creativity and is full of technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Hangzhou Asian Games launched the Asian Games Digital Torch, pioneering the concept of &quot;Asian Games Digital Torchbearers&quot; and inviting netizens around the world to compete to be the Asian Games Digital Torchbearers and participate in online torch relay activities, so that the Asian Games flames can Delivery breaks through the limitations of time and space. At the opening ceremony on the evening of the 23rd, the creative team will complete the lighting of the main torch in the form of &quot;digital and real integration&quot;, creating the first digital ignition ceremony in the history of the Asian Games. Judging from current real-time statistics, more than 100 million digital torchbearers will participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/edb657b938fa64cb2f741b5ba6f49727.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/edb657b938fa64cb2f741b5ba6f49727.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251746&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Hangzhou Asian Games fire collection ceremony. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 23rd, each online and offline torchbearer was a small flame and a shining point, gathering on the Qiantang River to form a concrete &quot;digital person&quot; walking on the Qiantang River. The tide surged and the steps were determined, rushing to the sky above the &quot;Big Lotus&quot;, breaking the barriers of time and space, leaping into the 185-meter three-dimensional screen, meeting the sixth torchbearer, &quot;digital and real fusion&quot; lighting the main torch tower, completing the lighting ceremony. Who will be the last torchbearer to light the torch together with hundreds of millions of digital torchbearers? Let us look forward to it together! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一个自称丧失“特权”的北京人想要火成世界巨星]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257417]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/guhqxOKWY9QMsHGiTXOeQpzPUrvIS1FicqkIqi0A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/guhqxOKWY9QMsHGiTXOeQpzPUrvIS1Ficq kIqi0A. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I am still a loser. I am from Beijing but I don’t have a house because I used the money that could have been used to buy a house to study abroad. I thought my room for appreciation was higher than that in Beijing. House prices are high.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My major in the United States was economics. I used the money to buy a house to study economics, which is equivalent to spending a lot of money. I learned that I shouldn’t spend this money. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiu Gu put her own experience into a short video, with four big words “Losing Privileges” in white letters on a red background, which became the most popular content on Jiu Gu’s video account. She intentionally made this short video The video adds elements that bring traffic, &quot;privilege&quot;, which points to the imbalance of regional development and the gap between rich and poor; &quot;cannot afford a house&quot;, which resonates with the general anxiety caused by housing prices; &quot;study abroad&quot;, which is related to education involution and the aura of prestigious schools. . She also hugged cats and dogs in the video, and said this frankly: &quot;It&#39;s also for traffic. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jiu Gu’s narration, she played her “good cards” to pieces, but in fact, she did not feel that her choice was wrong. She believed that everything she did was in the direction of the country. She is moving towards a goal - to become a world superstar. This goal was set early, starting from the age of 4, without any feasibility assessment, all relying on self-confidence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She changed her online name to &quot;Jiu Gu Yao&quot; &quot;Fire&quot;, making no secret of his ambitions and desires.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, can a person who just wants to tell the truth, appear in photos without makeup, and has a moderate view really become popular on the current Internet?&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0eq17pfRpfExYoj6yLeFzpCsLV51ZCoWo5kh4tXw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0eq17pfRpfExYoj6yLeFzpCsLV51ZCoWo5kh4tXw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251343&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jiu Gu travels around the United States&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Average &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Finding that it was difficult for her to buy a house in Beijing as a Beijinger, Jiu Gu realized that she had missed the advantages of being a local. At that time, she returned from studying abroad and did not want to live with her parents all the time. , renting an apartment in Beijing, and encountered a second landlord who ran away with money, and her job was not going well, she fell into a low point in life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did she choose to study abroad? Jiu Gu believes that the main reason is that she was isolated in school. From elementary school to high school, Jiu Gu attended one of the top five public schools in Beijing. As grades went up, grades became more and more important. By high school, Jiu Gu felt that everyone cared about grades, and only top academics would be punished. Respect, people like her who like to participate in club activities are &quot;deviants&quot; who are not doing their job properly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The conflict broke out at a chorus festival. Jiu Gu was responsible for organizing rehearsals, but her classmates thought that rehearsals took up study time, and they were against The rejection of the chorus focused on Jiu Gu personally, and the cold violence spread throughout the class like a virus. Jiu Gu felt that she was not wrong. The liberal arts experimental class in the school often had the opportunity to rehearse dramas and participate in cultural and sports activities, while the students in the ordinary class could only当观众，她不过是也想参与一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑从小喜欢搞活动，北京话叫攒局，比如在家里办春节联欢晚会，让家里人出节目。她想出国留学，早些年北京许多文艺策划人都有留学背景，以便接触更多的文化资源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是2010年前后，家里原本准备拿积蓄去买房，因为玖姑突然的决定，这笔钱转而用作她留学的费用。 “当时觉得买房没有意义啊，何必把自己困在一个空间里面，外面广阔天地，大有作为。”在她的想象中，留学回来后，她会过上光鲜的、梦想的生活，每天攒局，出席活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑没能学喜欢的音乐剧，因为母亲觉得毕业后会找不到工作，于是她选了经济学，考入了美国加州大学戴维斯分校。选择经济学，是因为对营销感兴趣，她想知道，人们会因为什么而决定买一件东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来她发现，经济学学的不是这个，毕业后工作一样难找。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾自己的教育经历，尽管拥有优渥的教育资源，但玖姑觉得自己走了很多弯路。而有些人从小没有太多资源，却明确地知道自己想做什么，白手起家，例如乔小刀，“电焊工出身，在北京办艺术展，做民谣歌手，现在在大理做装置艺术。他是看书自学，一直朝着自己的方向走，不像我们，要先进学校，去考试，学会更多的为考试而学的东西，打压你真正想学的东西。出身在北京是我的特权，可这个环境只是在把我往平均值上拽。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毕业回国后，玖姑参与过做创新教育的教辅公司，设计项目制学习课程，启发学生的创造力。她没做太长时间，因为发现国内的创新教育偏向“极端”。 “一类是有钱人的特权，即使失败了，也有资源把孩子送到一个好的系统里去；一类是给底层辍学者或打工子弟提供再教育的学校。中间的人都在随大流。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jTMHHDwvhx13OLfolt3PXAd4y77UrZI3vvdkMurM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jTMHHDwvhx13OLfolt3PXAd4y77UrZI3vvdkMurM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;为了拍短视频，玖姑将妆容化成一颗心&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;主流之外&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在美国念大学时，玖姑从经济学转为心理学，并利用选修课机会学习大量感兴趣的语言学、音乐学的课程。学习之外，玖姑找到了更有趣的事情——在嬉皮士社区居住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪70年代，加州大学戴维斯分校为了探索可持续生活方式，发起了一次社区住房实验，建了一个独特的宿舍区。玖姑第一次看见那些白色半球体的小房子就觉得很酷，房子之间分布着花园、菜地、养鸡棚，她随后申请入住，一共住了三年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社区由居住者共同塑造，每周有一次社区会议，集体讨论公共决策，遵循共识原则，“所有人都同意要做一件事情，那件事情才能做”。每个工作日晚上大家在社区中心的毛毡房里聚餐，轮流做饭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;起初面对强烈的文化差异时，玖姑有疏离感，她用一段长而缓慢的过程来适应，并希望保持更加平等的文化交互，她会在社区里发起中国文化活动，用原创诗歌朗诵（slam poetry）和脱口秀的形式介绍“我是谁”、“中国是什么”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社区第一代居住者大多是参与过嬉皮士运动的青年，到玖姑入住时，社区仍然保留了对主权文化的批判精神，反性别歧视、种族歧视等，“不一样的是没有那么大的对抗性，没有那么激进，而更加持续。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回国后，玖姑保持着对公共事务和平权议题的关心。看到一则一人大笑引发全车厢都在笑的视频后，她发起在地铁上传播笑声的行动，体验过后，她的感受是，“在想要笑的时候不再压制，大方地笑出来，我相信一定会有人回应。”有感于女性摇滚歌手少，她采访从事“非典型”职业的女性，探究职业对性别设立的壁垒。还加入女权主义小组，参与创作并演出了团队根据伊娃·恩斯勒的《阴道独白》原创的话剧《阴道之道》，创作女权相关的说唱歌曲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但玖姑的事业并不顺利，她喜欢更有创意的工作，找的都是创业型公司，例如做创客教育、开发年轻人社交社群，失败率很高，“这些公司本身盈利也不好，最后都在走下坡路。”四年多的时间里，她换了六七份工作，2019年她又一次失业后，大半年没有找到工作，无论是创业型公司还是互联网大厂，她都没被录用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摆在眼前最直接的一份工作是留学中介，一单佣金高达几万，但玖姑无法从心里认同这份工作，觉得没有意义，“它是一个有钱人的捷径，你只要有钱，就可以找人帮你写材料，可以包装自我。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并且，留学归来做留学中介，“很难说明留学有前途”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年初，玖姑找到一份在上海的工作，母亲说她是北京的叛徒，“北京那么多工作你一个都找不着吗？”玖姑把这句话改成段子，“偌大的京城就容不下你了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份工作也没能持续很久，两个月后她又被开除了。她不再找工作，自己开营销工作室，打造个人账号展示创意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了提升热度，她决定成为一个网红。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O05PXWYwVL73B42xg3PqMdxE8guoB35VPgt4PLOR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O05PXWYwVL73B42xg3PqMdxE8guoB35VPgt4PLOR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玖姑在线下脱口秀的舞台&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;保持真实&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刚开始写文章、做视频时，玖姑发现很难吸引流量，一个视频只有几十个播放量。她转而在上海讲脱口秀，积累线下的人气。此前她一直在讲英文脱口秀，想出来的梗更贴合英语的语感和幽默，她要重新培养中文的语感，费了好一番功夫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一次玖姑在线下的开放麦讲砸了，下台碰上李诞，问他怎么克服语言困境。李诞建议她多听郭德纲，她于是把德云社的综艺节目看了一遍，练口音，练语感，学习脱口秀的技巧，研究文字结构。她的脱口秀商演从仅有8个人看，逐渐变成30人、60人、700人，收入开始超过本职工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她把自己的失业、脱单失败和所有世俗标准里的不成功写入脱口秀段子，通过自我消解来引发观众对负面情绪的共鸣。但她自称没有为过去后悔过，如她在视频中所说，“我说这些失败的经历并不意味着我不自信，我正是因为自信，才敢把这些失败的经历都拿出来当素材。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，以脱口秀演员的身份，玖姑参与拍摄一档线下相亲纪录片。或许是为了增加冲突感，节目组给28岁的玖姑安排了一位61岁的男相亲对象老邬，比她爸年纪还大一岁。节目播出后，玖姑的片段引发了大量争议和讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打招呼时，老邬故作幽默地说“好久不见”，问她“你觉得今天黄浦江美吗？”玖姑直接回，“在这看不见江。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老邬摆出一副说教的态度，“你觉得女性要独立吗？”玖姑反问，“什么叫独立？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老邬引经据典，“你看过西蒙·波伏娃的《第二性》吗？他们在实验，如何把女性从第二性变成女性为第一性。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑不接招，“我不觉得波伏娃在女权这个话题上比我更懂，我也不觉得我比她更懂。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;节目中的表现让玖姑小火了一把，她开始坚持每日更新视频，趁着时机做红账号。相亲时谈到的女权，成为她的第一个流量点。玖姑不谈理论，不讲学术，有出版社给她寄女性主义书籍，在拍短视频时，她直言自己没看，“对于女权的理解，我都是从我的生活经验中亲自提炼出来的，我也不觉得这些所谓社会地位比我高的权威，比我更懂我的女权诉求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管玖姑认为自己主张的是性别平权，甚至写过“男女平等的油腻”“爱干嘛干嘛，媚男也可以，媚女也可以”这样的段子，但是她的性别权利观点不断引来争议，有网友指责她是“女权”，也有网友骂她“媚男”。玖姑时不时地会“回击”这些评论。她发现“性别对立”的确是流量密码，有对立就会有争议，有争议评论数就会高，就容易被算法推荐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而当她使用“平权”时，却被视频平台认定为“不符合社区规范”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最吸引流量的还是追热点，“平台推流量跟热点直接相关，只要是热点，甭管你说得多差都有，有热点跟没热点是质的区别，流量至少相差10倍。”2023年9月份，玖姑所追的热点包括“秀才直播间被封”“茅台咖啡”“李佳琦直播间翻车”等等，虽然追热点，但她表示不说一句违背内心意愿的话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于中老年阿姨打赏秀才，玖姑说，“咱们女人操劳了半辈子，就应该花钱让自己爽。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拉踩他人也是引流的一种方式，“可以让他们粉丝来骂你，增加我的热度。”比如玖姑拉踩过另一个网红曲曲，“她还是不如我，因为她教你取悦别人，而我教你自洽……虽然我单身没钱皮肤还差，但我很自洽，我想说什么就说什么，而且还能火。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对蹭流量、拉踩的指责，玖姑非常坦然，“对啊，那就是一种营销手段，做营销人必须要做的事儿，我还摆在明面上呢。”拉踩曲曲的那则视频封面上就写着四个大字——“拉踩同行”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“保持真实吧，我发现大家都太不真实了。”玖姑说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/3van6XHDJ2rAF6FAJ3i56jKkLcrL9GsFYAI2T7v0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/3van6XHDJ2rAF6FAJ3i56jKkLcrL9GsFYAI2T7v0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;线下相亲纪录片《想要问问你敢不敢》&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;成为世界巨星&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;玖姑视频最大的特点之一是素颜出镜，并且不加滤镜。她的理由也很真实，“我可是日更啊，每天化妆30分钟多累啊，我又化不好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎每一期视频下方都有对她外貌指指点点的言论，“化上点什么吧，看不下去了。”几乎没有女性网红不化妆，这塑造了网络的审美和礼貌准则，有的网友即便不从美丑的角度去评判，也会指责玖姑对人不尊重，“公共场合，化好妆，收拾利索点，是对自己也是对别人的尊重。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑坚信这不是自己的问题，用短视频回击，“如果你觉得我不化妆就是不尊重你，那你根本就不值得被尊重，如果你看别人不顺眼还非得说出来，那是你眼睛有问题，喜欢评论别人外貌的人本身都没什么教养。”视频最后她又用自我调侃来消解严肃的气氛，“不像我，不化妆也超美丽，化完妆后还不如不化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;评论区或许还算得上是言语温和的地方，私信里的网络暴力泛滥成灾，玖姑收到过无数条带着脏话和黄色笑话的辱骂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;单从他们的名称、头像和账号内容上看，很难想象他们平时会对人如此不客气，有叫“温柔知进退”的人说“你爸妈怎么敢把你生出来啊”，有头像是学士服照片的人反复说她“丑逼”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑的自信让她没有感到受伤害，但也不想沉默，她几次发视频，主张用“网抱”抵制“网暴”，“我无法控制别人对我评论的恶意，我也可以选择不被他们影响，而是主动传播善意，把世界往我想要的样子推一把。”因为一个谈论女性主义的视频引起过评论区“性别对立”的争吵后，为了不制造对立，她用“平权”来替代“女权”，因为想做“解决问题的人”，她将视频整理出一个合集，名称是“解决男女对立”，解释关于性别和权利的偏见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑在网上的人气为她的营销工作室带来不少订单，也为她的生活增添了很多乐趣。 “我在现实里特别单调，我没有办公室，没有同事，如果不上网，我很少跟人聊天，就去朋友店里坐一坐。”即便在网上会收到大量的负面言论，但在现实里，人和人之间的交流全部被压在了平静之下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑觉得自己现在已经很火了，每天都有四五个人在路上认出她，每条视频的流量数据都不错。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但还不够，她的目标是火成世界巨星。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“成为巨星之后呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“影响世界，去做有价值的事，消除贫困，提倡环保，给女性赋能。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>