<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[宫鲁鸣：外教不是中国篮球的救命稻草]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256832]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/XovBvRKJkp0MMKw0YWuHZTlI7kYhKTy4v8e5uMQk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/XovBvRKJkp0MMKw0YWuHZTlI 7kYhKTy4v8e5uMQk. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250578&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;June 20, 2023, Taipan Village, Taijiang County, Guizhou, Chinese Basketball Association Vice Chairman Gong Luming watched the &quot;Village BA&quot; game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup fell on the evening of September 10 At the end of the day, the German team, which entered the final for the first time, continued to create miracles, defeating the Serbian team 83-77, and was finally crowned. Although the Serbian team failed to win the final victory in the decisive battle, in this World Cup they made it all the way to the final in the absence of several top stars, which once again proved the amazing strength of this veteran European team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some are happy and some are sad. The Chinese men’s basketball team ranked only 29th among the 32 participating teams. The coach is Alexander Djordje, the famous coach who holds the Lifetime Achievement Award of the Serbian Basketball Coaches Association. Vicky, for him and the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team, the trip to the Philippines World Cup was full of frustration and depression. The Chinese men&#39;s basketball team lost to Serbia 63-105 in the first game of the World Cup. This day happened to be Lao Qiao&#39;s 56th birthday. Before the game, many members of the Serbian team sent blessings to the legend, but after the game started, the birthday boy could only shake his head. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 16, 2022, the Chinese Basketball Association made adjustments to the head coach of the Chinese Men’s Basketball National Team and announced the selection of Djordjevic as the head coach of the Chinese Men’s Basketball National Team. His task is to lead the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team in the sixth window of the 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup qualifying period and the 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup, striving to lead the team to qualify for the 2024 Paris Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese men’s basketball team spent a lot of money to hire a world-class coach to lead the army, and naturalized NBA star Kyle Lee joined the team. The largest investment in the history of the Chinese men’s basketball team resulted in one win and four losses in this World Cup, setting the worst record in history. At the same time, he lost his Olympic ticket again and fell into the abyss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese men’s basketball team performed poorly in the last Olympic cycle and failed to qualify for the Tokyo Olympics. This time it failed to qualify for the Paris Olympics, which means that a generation of players cannot participate in the highest level during their golden period of competition. competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, when participating in the Olympic Games, the flag bearer of the Chinese delegation would be a tall and handsome Chinese men&#39;s basketball star. Now, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team, which has missed two consecutive Olympics, has even lost a standard-bearer who can guide the direction - veteran Yi Jianlian, who was unable to go with the team, announced his retirement before the last game of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball group stage. Fans lamented that since before the Olympics, Without being able to compete for eight to eight years, the glory of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team has completely faded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How should the Chinese men’s basketball team move forward? &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; conducted an exclusive interview with Gong Luming, the famous Chinese basketball coach. At the 1996 Atlanta Olympics, at the age of 39, he directed the Chinese team to reach the top eight in the Olympics for the first time. This is the best record that has not been broken so far. This group of players is also known as the &quot;96 Golden Generation&quot;. When the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team hit a trough in 2014, he was asked to come out. A year later, he once again brought the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team back to the top in Asia. This legendary guard, who is only 1.72 meters tall, is known as the &quot;fire-fighting master&quot; of Chinese basketball. In 1999, he became the head coach at the lowest point when the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team lost the qualification to compete in the Sydney Olympics. Through major changes and all-round team building, he created a young and brave golden generation of women&#39;s basketball, winning the 2001 Asian Women&#39;s Basketball Championship and the 2001 Women&#39;s Basketball Asian Championship. He won two titles at the 2002 Asian Games and finished sixth at the 2002 World Championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is the self-report of coach Gong Luming:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; I personally strongly agree with the strengthening of international exchanges in Chinese basketball. It is a good thing for the Chinese Basketball Association to hire foreign coaches, especially famous foreign coaches. They can bring us a lot of good experience in terms of confrontation, concepts, and methods. . However, some practical factors must be taken into consideration on how to properly coordinate the coaching team and how to give full play to the role of foreign teachers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The specialty of foreign coaches is high professionalism, concentration and seriousness, and their coaching level is also certain He was selected by the Chinese Basketball Association only after he has reached a certain height. There is no doubt about this. Most of them grew up in a highly professional basketball environment and believe that everyone in the team, including themselves, has sufficient professionalism. After assembling a national team, foreign teachers rarely think that the construction and management of the team and the improvement of athletes&#39; skills are also one of the priorities of the head coach. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;They are more accustomed to focusing on the court, such as the tactical system, lineup configuration, and opponents. Research, etc., and many other things, he will think that it is your athlete&#39;s own business, or that a mature professional athlete should have solved the problem long ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When foreign teachers serve as head coaches, although they will be equipped with excellent Chinese coaches as assistants, the basic Foreign head coaches rarely have in-depth and active communication with Chinese coaches. To be honest, they may not necessarily like our Chinese coaches, so we will see that the foreign head coaches are very dedicated and very courageous to carry out their work, but there are very few opportunities for Chinese and foreign coaches to formally exchange opinions or communicate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From our past experience, if a foreign teacher serves as an assistant coach, he will actively communicate with the head coach To communicate, he will actively communicate with the Chinese coaching staff the various information he has seen and collected, as well as how to deal with it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Over the years, whether it is the national team or local clubs, our basketball world has formed such a The coaching environment: Unless the Chinese coach is very proactive and actively cooperates with the foreign teacher and asks the foreign teacher for advice, he may talk more to the Chinese coach. If you don&#39;t do this and you just follow the foreign teacher, he will not actually give you any help. But if the Chinese side is the head coach, the foreign teacher will actively communicate with you about his experience, knowledge or methods. This is a very realistic thing. Such a coaching culture has been formed over the years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Another point is that even if there are no foreign teachers, the coaching staff is all local coaches. There is also an unwritten rule. I am used to following the arrangements of the head coach. To put it simply, if you don’t arrange things, I won’t do it. If the head coach has spoken and arranged for me, I will do it. If the head coach does not ask for it, then the assistant coach will not express his opinion easily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These are our &quot;basketball culture&quot;. When hiring foreign teachers, you must consider these practical factors. In fact, it is very difficult. There has been a consensus within the circle for a long time that foreign teachers can be used and the ball can be lost, but the initiative must be in our own hands. Even if we lose, we must let our own coaches know how to lose. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/O4yeTzwTaxr80Zv1c1vc6sHZGmgOxdACXvM7x0pw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/O4yeTzwTaxr80Zv1c1vc6sHZGmgOxdACXvM7x0pw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250580&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2015, in Changsha, Hunan, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team won the 2015 Asian Men&#39;s Basketball Championship. Gong Luming held the trophy high to celebrate&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;2&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;The most taboo thing about hiring foreign teachers is to treat foreign teachers as a life-saving straw and expect them to turn stones into gold and produce results in a short period of time. Can foreign teachers really save Chinese basketball? not necessarily! To this day, the best record in the history of China&#39;s men&#39;s and women&#39;s basketball teams is still led by our own local coaches. Group projects have their own particularity and complexity. It is not easy to achieve a breakthrough through a foreign teacher. This is something we must think about when building our team. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you invite foreign teachers in, you can&#39;t lose all your own things. Your own things have been accumulated over several generations and are suitable for your own personnel characteristics and specific environment. These experiences have been tested by specific practices. You can&#39;t just follow others and succeed. Making up for our shortcomings and developing our own strengths is fundamental. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some words may sound a bit outdated, but I still have to say that I always insist on paying attention to team building Ideological work. The so-called ideological work is not an empty long speech. It can be combined with many things in daily work requirements and business learning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Foreign teachers don’t care about team building, and they don’t know how to do this kind of ideological work. Before the competition, they Carrying a jersey to that station and saying that you must be worthy of the national flag on it is considered the ideological work he has done for the players. A person&#39;s mind is not that simple. Why do you play basketball? What basic quality requirements does this profession require of you? Going a step further, what is your specific understanding of the era you live in? What requirements does this specific background of the times place on yourself and the sports industry? You can&#39;t take the ball with nothing in mind. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not just the national team that lacks quality ideological work, our current professional league, there are people who can do it Is ideological education work? What social role should a professional basketball player play in today&#39;s environment? How many people can answer? We have engaged in professionalization, and players&#39; salaries have gone up, but their ideological understanding has not kept up. Athletes need guidance. Hearing people criticize the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team for &quot;male football&quot; brings disgrace to our work in basketball and football. As the old saying goes, &quot;A teacher once is a father forever&quot; and &quot;It is the fault of a son not to teach his father.&quot; From the club to the national team, have our coaches and team leaders fulfilled their responsibilities in influencing and educating young people? If a player has a problem, it must be related to management and education. No one educates him in the national team, and no one educates him when he returns home. He wanders around every day, even begging him and coaxing him, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/VGjynPqZDGsRtIwxJasuc8S7aHF3iszemchidAPX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/VGjynPqZDGsRtIwxJasuc8S7aHF3iszemchidAPX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250579&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 2, 2023, Manila, Philippines, in the 17-32nd group stage of the 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team lost to the Philippine men&#39;s basketball team 75-96. Head coach Djordjevic exited after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our own coaches must actively grow. We cannot just wait for high-level foreign coaches to be our assistants. This is unrealistic and impossible to win the true respect of our peers and team members. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Don&#39;t underestimate a team, its content is not just technical things. The head coach himself needs a kind of maturity, a subtle influence, and leading by example. What kind of atmosphere your words and deeds create is very important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The coach is actually an ascetic. If you want to be a good coach, you have to focus and give up many hobbies. You usually make a group of friends, train here, and arrange what to do in the evening there, so where can you go? When you are a player, you just have to take care of yourself. When you are the coach, you have to consider the affairs of the whole team. The affairs of the whole team are not one or two things. Team formation, communication between top and bottom, communication with parents, ideological issues, technical issues, the construction of the offensive and defensive system of the entire team, and opponent research, you are too busy working 24 hours a day, do you still have time to do other things? Failure to focus simply cannot solve these problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A person must respect his or her job, this is what you rely on for survival or for your food. . When I was coaching the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team, I always ate out of a porcelain bowl, just to remind myself that you have to take good care of your own job, don&#39;t fight, otherwise you won&#39;t have anything to eat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether you are a star athlete or a coach, you should abide by your duties and not sacrifice to show your personality. The core values ​​of sports are sunshine, health and positivity. In the past, before the national team completed training or competition tasks and before the players returned to the club, we had to set requirements for them. After returning, you must reflect the level and value of the national team members, lead by example, and take the lead in all aspects. , instead of going back to being a big name. Everyone in the league still has specific technical problems that need to be solved, and we will check them when we come back. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Chen, president of Peking Union Medical College and academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering, said in his 2023 opening speech, &quot;It is necessary to Take the world as your own responsibility, have real skills, and embody the nobility of life, the nobility of industry, and the nobility of health care in simple labor.&quot; Every industry must have its own professional beliefs, and the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team relies on the accumulation of generations of people If you gain a little bit of family wealth, the whole industry needs to cherish it and make practical contributions. If the family wealth is lost, the whole industry will suffer losses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[把美术课还给孩子？一所广东乡村学校的实验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256860]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;This is not a &#39;good&#39; school!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Zhongshan taxi driver He looked determined and made a judgment. On the way, he talked about Guinan School, which is located at the foot of Wugui Mountain in Zhongshan City. The implication is that this private primary and secondary school has an average admission rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have heard too many of the same stories. Designer and school art group teacher Zhang Yaoren could only smile helplessly. What is good and what is bad? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Achievements&quot; are always the only yardstick for most people. Zhang Yaoren didn’t think so. He is thin, in his fifties, and has been at Guinan School for more than five years. Old P, as people like to call him, is from Henan. He has been in Guangdong for more than thirty years. He settled in nearby Qixi Village a few years ago. He and Shi Lei, the principal of Guinan School, hit it off on this topic: &quot;Do children in rural areas need... Need aesthetic education?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vMCE1SIISojaA1pyEdXttSCFwmE6MrnjJsd4NQjL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vMCE1SIISojaA1pyEdXttSCFwmE6MrnjJsd4NQjL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Works by Guinan School students. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Independent artist and curator Guan Yong is in his forties, has a tall figure and likes to wear Straw sandals. He has been engaged in art education since he was nineteen years old, working in kindergartens, primary schools, and art galleries in Zhuhai, Guangzhou, Macau and other places. Later, he also participated in this miniature rural aesthetic education experiment as an art director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, Guinan School had more than 40 classes, more than 1,700 students, and 3 art teachers, but there was no art classroom. In July 2018, Guinan School converted six classrooms on the first floor into art classrooms. Now, the school has eight full-time art teachers, four studios and a reading room. The teaching content involves traditional Chinese painting, printmaking, pottery, paper-cutting, etc. Guinan&#39;s campus also has a miniature art gallery that displays students&#39; works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visiting this place, Southern Weekend reporters were surprised by the art works hidden on campus. These works are displayed all over the campus. A large number of clay sculptures are dried on the ground, prints are posted on the walls, installation art is hung in the corridors, and handmade works are posted under the eaves. These works are quite childish, and the largest number are clay sculptures, including cups, plates, bottles, jars, and various clay figures with strange shapes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Up3LZQx8CNfkgURkqUALPuYpCgqb4Tv173RGEIYA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Up3LZQx8CNfkgURkqUALPuYpCgqb4Tv173RGEIYA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Student art works in the corridor of the teaching building of Guinan School. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comprehensive studio, weaving, sewing, embroidery and other handicrafts are completed here; folk crafts The studio is for students; the folk art room is filled with students&#39; prints, paper-cuts, etc.; in the comprehensive painting studio, you can see Chinese paintings, watercolors, oil paintings and other works by students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/K4RhNWazPNxMQUDqRo9O4X3j0zIZBlSXxoWguIr8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/K4RhNWazPNxMQUDqRo9O4X3j0zIZBlSXxoWguIr8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250963&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Student prints from Guinan School. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you travel through the countryside, you can also see the works of students. &quot;Children&#39;s things are natural things.&quot; Zhang Yaoren pointed to the student works along the country road and said, &quot;(In the past) many paintings on the walls were relatively stiff.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, Guan Yong and others started a rural teacher program to provide teaching support to front-line teachers from rural areas and plan to complete the training of one thousand teachers within two years. Zhang Yaoren said: &quot;We do the Thousand Talents Plan precisely because we believe that (aesthetic education) is the most important thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;If you have never done carpentry, you will do carpentry; if you have never played in mud, you will play in mud.&quot;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;Local children mostly choose to go to public schools in towns. The students recruited by Guinan School are basically the children of migrant workers. Most of these students come from Sichuan, Hunan, Anhui and other places. Their parents left their hometown and came to the Pearl River Delta. While the students are in class, their parents sell things at nearby markets, work in factories, and do odd jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaoren recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that students would leave every semester. The fathers left the worksite, and the children flew away like birds. Academic performance has nothing to do with art. Zhang Yaoren said that they did not disclose the idea of ​​​​art courses to the parents of the students. He understands the parents’ thinking. Art is useless. It’s better to do more questions: “The parents must have said that my son only scored 85 points in math. Can you not let him attend the 90 minutes of art class? He might get 90 points in the exam. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Yong has a point of view. Regarding the curriculum, the art textbooks compiled by the state are always the basis, accounting for 70% of the curriculum. The remaining 30% is carried out by the teaching team for outreach and expansion. The content of the 18 textbooks for grades one to nine was broken up and reconnected with the four studios. As the grades increase, the content offered by each studio becomes deeper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/yPaKd9OGAQgZTSxdq2wI90zCjjZziTskqh66IZUd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/yPaKd9OGAQgZTSxdq2wI90zCjjZziTskqh66IZUd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gouache painting by Guinan School students. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All the teaching materials were smashed and placed in the studio... The textbooks are relatively thin ,&quot; Zhang Yaoren gave an example, &quot;One class (textbook) says that the mud will be gone, but we asked the first-grade children to work here for four consecutive weeks making mud, and (the students) wanted to make bowls after finishing the cups. I also want to make a vessel with a handle, so that the child will have an understanding of the properties of clay, the complexity of materials, and the complexity of creation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Improving teachers&#39; aesthetic and teaching abilities is the key . Five years ago, there were only two art teachers in Guinan School, and students would take out A4 paper to sketch in class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Rural Art Teachers) Their professionalism is not deep. How come teachers who graduated from the National Academy of Arts and Central America come to our place? When the professional level of the teachers is not that high, how can Can you improve their level?&quot; Zhang Yaoren told the Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Teach you how to work. If you have never done carpentry before, do carpentry, and if you have never played with mud, just play with mud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Yong et al. People prefer to refer to entering the classroom as entering the studio. They believe that art is the vocabulary of the adult world, while children&#39;s basic art education is &quot;enlightenment of students&#39; creativity and self-expression&quot; and is more like &quot;an artistic job&quot;. He rarely talks about art theory. When he encounters a problem, Guan Yong always says &quot;get moving&quot;. What should I do if I don’t have an art foundation? Guan Yong said, then work! As you dry it, you will feel it on your hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/1EySt6Joa4v1Qfj3z416218QnPl4KnxPxxZ1Z1UV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/1EySt6Joa4v1Qfj3z416218QnPl4KnxPxxZ1Z1UV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The art studio of Guinan School. Every time students finish class, they will clean up the studio as required. Zhang Yaoren believes that this is also part of aesthetic education. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guinan School does not add additional time for art classes, and of course does not allow preemption of art classes. time, students are required to complete a ninety-minute class once a week. Forty minutes of art class is simply not enough to keep children &quot;enjoyed.&quot; There is always an appreciation session at the beginning of the course. The teacher brings the pictures related to the curriculum to the children to “look at”. In nine years, students can look at tens of thousands of pictures, and these pictures become one of the sources of their aesthetic appreciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the second grade course &quot;Paper Cutting - Transformation&quot;, students need to learn origami, binding, cutting and collage heads, and watch the works of Huang Yongyu, Komatsu Miu, Han Meilin and others; fifth grade The ninety-minute class in the first semester is titled &quot;Color Blow Molding - Vase Flowers&quot;. The teaching content includes engraving outlines and patterns. The materials viewed include the works of Davids, Van Gogh, Matisse, etc.; In the ninth-grade course &quot;Comprehensive Printmaking - Mask&quot;, students have to learn how to engrave lightness and grayscale, and watch the works of Gu Kaizhi, Wu Daozi, and Zhang Xuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various equipment in the studio, including expensive printmaking machines, as well as various painting tools, glue guns, saws, etc. According to statistics, there are more than thirty kinds of paper. These materials come from Guinan School Expenditures. Zhang Yaoren said that the school has made great efforts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Q4vVA4zYwX0QyIXfpOnDVbYEIDsoi3KyR1mlocmq.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Q4vVA4zYwX0QyIXfpOnDVbYEIDsoi3KyR1mlocmq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250956&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the art studio of Guinan School, the drawers are filled with papers of various materials. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, not every school has enough funding for materials. Some materials also come from the land. The art teacher took the students to collect leaves, soil, discarded paper, old clothes, plastic bottles, etc. Every semester, children in Guinan consume tons of soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The art teacher became the leader of the main subject&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaoren once visited some rural schools in western Guangdong, and the proportion of left-behind children in these schools accounted for more than 60%. In a central primary school in a certain town, there are only 180 students. In the context of &quot;dismantling sites and merging schools&quot;, data from NetEase Digital shows that in the forty years from 1976 to 2016, 916,000 primary schools disappeared in China, and most of them were rural primary schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many art teachers who participated in the training confirmed this statement to Southern Weekend reporters. A rural teacher in Hengyang, Hunan told a Southern Weekend reporter with sadness that her rural primary school will be merged next semester. She came in a hurry from other places with great expectations in her heart, wanting to bring something new to the children in the village. After working for four years, she watched the number of students drop from more than one hundred to more than thirty. She is a little envious of physical education classes. Campus football education is a Hengyang specialty. Almost every primary school is equipped with a football field and guaranteed physical education class hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Xiaohong, the head of the Zhejiang Zhipu Charity Foundation, known as &quot;Huabu&quot;, has been paying attention to the life growth of rural children and the mental health of children in distress for many years. She told Southern Weekend reporters that six years ago, In a county in a mountainous area, there is only one full-time art teacher in all 20 rural primary schools in the countryside. There has been some improvement over the years, but there are still problems that need to be solved urgently. For example, there are 13 establishments in schools with less than 200 students. “Obviously, this (class arrangement) cannot be arranged no matter how you arrange it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In rural schools, &quot;one teacher uses many people to use it.&quot; &quot;I am now the class teacher in charge of the first grade, responsible for reading classes, labor and skill classes, and also responsible for the quality promotion of our school,&quot; a teacher told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visiting rural schools, Zhang Yaoren found that some teachers who graduated from normal art schools had been teaching their main subjects for more than ten years and no longer taught art, while the original teachers of Chinese, mathematics and other subjects taught part-time instead. Art, music and other courses. Some former art teachers have even become subject leaders of their main subjects, and they “always have some regrets in their hearts” when talking about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Comprehensively Strengthening and Improving School Aesthetic Education in the New Era.&quot; The opinions proposed that aesthetic education should be included in the entire process of talent training in schools of all levels and types, and should run through all stages of school education. A post-80s teacher from a public primary school in western Hunan is one of the second batch of local art students. I have been teaching for thirteen years and have taught foreign language and math all over the place. In the past two years, the school responded to the aesthetic education policy, and she was able to return to her profession and become a full-time art teacher, making up for her regret at the time: &quot;It&#39;s not that art has no threshold, it&#39;s because they think it doesn&#39;t matter if they don&#39;t teach well and there will be no consequences.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Art education has always been considered a &quot;minor subject&quot;. In many cases, the class hours of minor subjects are often &quot;occupied&quot; by the main subjects. Especially in primary schools with limited educational resources, it is more common for the main subject teachers to concurrently serve as the teachers of the minor subjects. The encroachment of the minor subject class hours is &quot;natural&quot;. &quot;Many documents on aesthetic education have been issued at the national level, and it cannot be said that they are not taken seriously. Art teachers like to take art classes, and students also fall in love with art classes, but in many cases they fail to take art classes.&quot; Luo Xiaohong felt heartbroken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another mystery in scheduling classes. According to the normal schedule, for example, a Chinese teacher has twelve classes and uses the original Chinese class hours; but in actual operation, a Chinese teacher is given six Chinese classes. The remaining six periods were replaced by art, physical education and other courses, and naturally all &quot;minor subjects&quot; were taken into Chinese language classes. According to Luo Xiaohong&#39;s observations in two counties in Zhejiang, the situation of &quot;two class schedules&quot; has been intensifying in the past two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A private primary school art teacher comes from a county in Dali, Yunnan, and teaches a village primary school with 250 students. She told Southern Weekend reporters that when she came to Guinan School, she seemed to find a companion all of a sudden. For example, both choose two classes to form one big class. Her school does not take up art time, but in the public elementary school next door, the situation is completely different. &quot;Now there are exams and there are not enough class hours. The teacher has no choice but to do this in order to achieve results.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“What I painted twenty years ago, you are still painting”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters saw at the teaching site that the art teachers who came for training experienced the Guinan experience in the studio The content of aesthetic education in the classroom: understanding materials-obtaining materials-production-teacher comments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The level of rural teachers obviously varies. The first practical class involved hand-made books, and most of the teachers successfully completed the work. In the second period of the ink painting class, the quality of the teacher&#39;s ink paintings showed a certain difference. While creating, some teachers told Southern Weekend reporters that, in fact, they had not really touched ink for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Guan Yong&#39;s request, an art teacher from Ankang, Shaanxi Province used three different kinds of paper to experience ink. He couldn&#39;t help but think of the students in class. Each student was given a brush, poured a little bit of ink, and asked them to apply it on the cardboard box and A4 paper. This was his best effort to let the students experience ink. If it is a handicraft class, paper cutting may be the simplest and most convenient. Many teachers told Southern Weekend reporters that the current main teaching format is drawing classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reality of rural resource constraints still exists. An art teacher in Huaihua, Hunan Province said that the school’s resources are scarce, and some art class materials even need to be purchased out of own pocket, costing almost 20,000 yuan. “It’s really impossible to do it. The classroom is empty, there is nothing, and the drawing board No, how to teach?&quot; Zhang Yaoren said that in the schools he contacted, students need to bring their own materials. If families cannot provide them, it will be difficult for the courses to continue. &quot;The pain of materials is a scar that has nowhere to hide in art courses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Hj47ESMSaP91n0rp7AvckUqLyRfBjsQmFyoeVrM1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Hj47ESMSaP91n0rp7AvckUqLyRfBjsQmFyoeVrM1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250960&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A fire hydrant at Guinan School decorated with student works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We cannot ensure that every student gets an art book to take home.&quot; The above-mentioned teacher from Hengyang told Southern Weekend reporters that where she lives, even art textbooks are not widely available, and they can only use teaching materials in turns.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned rural teacher from Yunnan said that some teaching content involves high-rise buildings Buildings, zebra crossings, etc. Some rural children have never left the village and have only seen them on TV. &quot;Since high-rise buildings are drawn with lines and squares, we will transform the content and consider how to return to the teaching objectives.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aq5KSZquk7pNJuHuzUjJUZccQX7cQXqiurpR8NNH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aq5KSZquk7pNJuHuzUjJUZccQX7cQXqiurpR8NNH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250961&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guinan School’s art studio decorates the walls with students’ paper-cutting work. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In rural schools, having an art classroom may be a luxury. An art teacher from Shaanxi recalled that when he first came to school, the principal said to him that you were the only art teacher in the school, &quot;just take whatever you want.&quot; He felt his shoulders sink, but soon he realized that this might mean staying away from various competitions and honors. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The training program does not reject urban art teachers. Maybe their schools have excellent resources, but they are still confused about teaching methods. A young teacher from Beijing&#39;s Haidian District asked that the textbook content requires innovation, for example, asking students to color in triangles, but teachers are limited in what they can do. Guan Yong asked, why don&#39;t you make the triangle bigger? Why not design a giant triangle and let students color it freely? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This teacher born in the 1990s suddenly understood. He was born in a normal school majoring in art education, and now teaches at a key primary school in Haidian, responsible for courses from fourth to sixth grade. According to him, there are plenty of classes and resources, and there are no problems with rural teachers taking on concurrent jobs. The school’s art teachers have all received very good professional art training. &quot;The pressure on art teachers comes from the normalization of &#39;listening to and evaluating lessons&#39;.&quot; The above-mentioned young teacher said that another problem is that the two classes a week are often separated by several days, and the content of the teaching materials is trivial, and students&#39; learning is not systematic enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reading the work, he commented that &quot;the children here (compared to the children in Beijing) are more active.&quot; Unlike many rural teachers who are surprised when they first see the campus, what he feels is not the art itself, but things other than art.现场，一位老师提问，是否应该为孩子进行示范，这是过往多年来的教学模式之一。关勇制止了她。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州天河区城中村的一位美术老师告诉南方周末记者，自己是美术专业出身，从来都是按照标准绘画，学习绘画的公式，画画的时候考虑最多的是公式，而非表达情感。她指着墙上学生的作品说，“第一感觉是非常自由，独一无二”。她想起自己的孩子在区前十的中学上学，参与学校的兴趣班，结果学习的内容和模式和自己小时候毫无差别，“我二十年前画的东西，你们还在画”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;美术是一把盐&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;桂南没有内部的评比活动，也很少参加外围的美术比赛。张耀仁解释说，美术作品的核心是自我表达，表达内心的感受，这怎么能够评分呢？而且观察那些比赛中的作品，往往能看到老师干预的痕迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，张耀仁要设计一个标识。在民间工作室，他看到一张猴子式样的版画。这张版画后来成为标识。按照收藏的标准，关勇特地制作了漂亮的收藏证书，上面有作者名字和作品名，在升国旗仪式时颁发证书给孩子，并给予奖金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/I1BvI5zZPXHpe53okfU9YdjzV0MHq6UiQ4mf1FVA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/I1BvI5zZPXHpe53okfU9YdjzV0MHq6UiQ4mf1FVA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250962&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桂南学校美术馆，这里存放创作材料和学生作品。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者张锐/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“作为平凡的他们，如果能得到美的滋养，我相信他们的生命会因此有所不同，”张耀仁说，“他可能会把自己的房舍收拾得干干净净，努力照顾好家人；她可能会从田间摘一把野花插在桌上，让平淡的一餐饭变得略有不同……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桂南学校举办乡村儿童艺术双年展时，美国宾夕法尼亚大学的一位学生，研究建立了一个数据模型，分析艺术教育对外来务工子女的影响。第一轮的效果分析出来后，得到一个正向性的结论。张耀仁不太愿意将结果功利化和数据化，用以论证美术和学习成绩之间的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他常说，美术就是一把盐，生活需要一点调味品。至于美育的势能和影响，张耀仁不考虑这些，也不在意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美术始终要落在教育，而非作品上。学校老师有学生作品观察,老师观察和记录学生课堂的行为、习惯、情绪等。比如一本《期末总结美术课堂观察日记》上，写于2020-2021学年第二学期的观察日记，每一位学生都以课堂表现、常规习惯、作品呈现来记录，一位学生表现不佳，一位老师如此写道：“往后课堂里，我会努力找到合适这类孩子的创作方式。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至少在一部分外界观点看来，挤占美术课，增加学习时间，提升升学率才是改变务工子女命运的关键。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桂南学校校长石磊从2017年便在想一个问题，究竟哪些人离我们最近？ “厨师、服务员、修理工、清洁工等，我们真实的生活中，感受源于他们。”石磊说，“我们的学生会有概率成为他们，这是很现实的问题。”据统计，学校仅有35%的学生会升入高中，而剩下的学生则会进入中专、职校等，如果他们对生活有不一样的感受呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石磊告诉南方周末记者，五年多的时间，学校陆续投了几百万元，改了教室、建了美术馆、买了材料等，减少了学校的招生规模，从2000多学生减少到了1200名左右，加上学费偏低，学校几乎每年都亏损。有同行跑来学校指着他骂，脑子有问题就去看病，“（他们不理解）这件事能帮我涨学费，还是帮我多招生？”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“复制”桂南式的美术教育存在难度。关勇在珠海接触过一些学校，几乎到了最后环节，却因老师反对而作罢。关勇回忆说，老师们不愿意干，认为增加了工作量却没带来额外的收入，自己主动要教，老师也不同意。 “太习以为常了，”关勇说，“不干就走了。”&amp;nbsp;骆筱红告诉南方周末记者，他们曾给一些乡村学校捐赠画笔、颜料等，结果几年过去，东西仍然囤在那里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你们了解我们的学生，你们只会做得更多。”石磊说，外来务工子弟的生活奔波、飘摇，在生活的压力下缺少机会去舒缓情绪。如果在很紧凑的生活中，多一个出口，生活会不会好一些？九年的时间，上万张作品看下来，生活的审美会不会提高一些？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石磊成长在工厂的子弟校，从小接触了很多好的美术老师、音乐老师，数年过去，语数外的知识忘却，却记得过去的美术课和音乐课，生活也得益于当时充盈的馈赠。 “别人看我们做了很多作品，画了很多画，这些在我们心里面反而是最不重要的，”石磊说，“我们不是为了这个东西去做这件事情，真正重要的是美育的过程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[癌症晚期旅客登机被拒：航空公司宁担非议背后的考量是什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256858]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一起民航新闻事件引发关注。 2023年9月12日，一位癌症晚期旅客在成都天府国际机场，预定了成都航空机票却被拒绝登机，引发舆论关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从视频中可见，一位老人坐在轮椅上，而另一位男子与老太太则坐在地上给航空公司客服打电话。这位男子哭诉说，“什么都有不让我走啊，我自己承诺书也签了，还带了护理工，怎么不让我走”，随后男子又说，“有癌症，四个月，之前你说没有心脏病、呼吸道疾病、外伤伤口，都可以。”家属最后跪在地上苦苦哀求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事后成都航空工作人员回应称，该名旅客确为癌症晚期患者，公司有明确规定，对于此类患者不予承运，以免旅客在飞行途中身体不适。该规定在官网“运输总条件”里有公示，如果是早期或者中期的癌症患者，则没有绝对限制旅客乘机。网友对其的意见也两极分化，有网友表示航空公司没有人情味，属于“霸王条款”“歧视旅客”；但也有网友表示理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起事件已经落幕，但仍有一些问题值得辨析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，航空公司拒绝癌症晚期旅客登机首先还是出于安全考量。成都航空官网上的《运输总条件》第6.1.3条写道，“有下列疾病的旅客，经成都航空同意进行特别安排外，不予承运”，其中第10款就是“癌症晚期患者”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，不仅成都航空存在“不予承运”的情况，国内各大航司也都有着相似或者相近的规定，比如国航在运输总条件里列明，“大纵膈肿瘤、特大疝肿及肠梗阻的患者”，除同意或者特殊安排之外，不提供航空运输服务；东航也在“患病旅客服务须知”里写明，对于“大纵膈肿瘤、特大疝肿及肠梗阻的患者”，建议不要选择乘坐飞机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此可见，成都航空并非唯一“针对”患病旅客的航司。说得准确一些，航空公司的类似规定，属于“拒绝运输与限制运输”的情况。尽管各大航司具体规定有所差异，背后依据的原则却是统一的：航空公司无法保证在承运过程中，可以有效保护与保障旅客的生命安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“敬畏规章，敬畏生命”在民航领域绝不是一句空话，每一条看起来奇怪的规章背后都存在大大小小的安全事故与血淋淋的生命作为警醒。对癌症晚期或是有特殊疾病的旅客而言，气压变化与氧气浓度变化都会构成对生命的极大威胁，存在突发疾病需要救护的潜在风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，不仅仅是患有特殊疾病的乘客不适合登机，怀孕32周乃至36周以上的孕妇也不适合登机，需要医疗许可与诊断证明书才能有限制地登机，这是考虑到了孕妇在飞行过程中的潜在健康风险。推而广之，罹患心脑血管疾病者不适合坐过山车，老弱病幼不适合参与潜水登山等极限运动，这并非“拒绝服务”或“歧视消费者”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这起事件中的旅客，更适合选择高铁或小汽车出行，这样既可以避免飞行中气压与氧气浓度变化带来的健康风险，在旅行途中也更容易得到及时的医疗服务。毕竟，从高铁或小汽车下车看医生，要比飞行途中找医生要容易多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，航空公司拒绝癌症晚期乘客登机，本身也体现了航司与旅客之间权责对等的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这起事件中，当事人提出的“承诺书”引发了比较多的注意。有网友认为，既然乘客已经“签字承诺一切后果自己承担”，那么航空公司仍然拒绝登机就显得不合适。这种说法虽然看起来入情入理，但却忽略了现行法律与民用航空的实际状况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从民事关系而言，航空公司只是提供运输服务的商业机构，合同义务是以航空器将乘客安全运送到目的地；乘客购买的则是符合票面价值的运输服务，并没有超越票面价值的医疗服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果允许癌症晚期旅客登机的话，航空公司恐怕无力承担相应的风险，需要付出的潜在成本也要远远大于做成这单机票生意的收益，包括但不限于旅客意外去世、旅客出现状况后飞机折返，等等。试问，一旦飞机被迫临时备降或者折返的话，其他旅客因此损失的权益又由谁来补偿？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;民航飞机并非具备特殊用途的“医疗机”，也没有“空中ICU”的条件。一旦患病旅客在飞行途中突发状况需要救治的话，那恐怕是航空公司无力处理也没有义务处理的额外任务。无论是旅客去世或是飞机被迫紧急折返，各方受损的总利益无疑都会大得多。一纸未必具备法律效力的“后果自担承诺书”，并不能说服航空公司无视可能发生的风险，承担堪称巨大的潜在成本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，航空公司拒绝癌症晚期乘客登机与其说是褒贬意味更浓的“歧视”，倒不如说是根据特定情况的“区别对待”。这种“区别对待”既展现出对乘客生命财产安全的尊重，也显示了“权责对等”的原则。航空公司与乘客同为民事主体，彼此的权利义务完全对等。航司有权拒绝服务超出自身义务与能力的旅客，旅客也完全可以选择愿意承担更大风险的其他航空服务商，或者是其他交通工具。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一块钱酸梅汤打败“入秋第一杯奶茶”，网红中药能刷医保吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256723]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[旧房换新房，能否激活淄博楼市？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256841]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/97064ca1ac.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1366&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/97064ca1ac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年4月10日，山东淄博，齐盛湖公园。 （视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这些天来，总有一些地方政府部门的工作人员打电话给李斌，向他咨询淄博买房“以旧换新”的模式和具体操作流程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月6日，淄博市房地产开发协会和市房地产经纪与评估协会联合发起购房“以旧换新”的签约仪式，首批12家房地产开发企业和房地产经纪机构代表签署合作协议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;按照《淄博日报》的说法，“以旧换新”即旧房换新房，房地产开发企业与房地产经纪机构联手，中介加速存量住房销售成交，房企优先提供优质房源，满足购房者置换需求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但市场对“以旧换新”的具体做法还存在不少猜测。在短视频平台，有人解读，淄博此次推出的购房“以旧换新”政策是让评估机构先“把旧房子评估后的钱给购房者，购房者再拿着这个钱去买新房。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“以旧换新”最早是贝壳找房尝试的一种住房销售模式。 9月13日，作为贝壳（山东）互联网有限公司的副总经理，李斌向南方周末记者作出澄清：原来客户置换时，如果之前住的二手房去化不掉，手上就没有资金给新房下定金。现在“以旧换新”的模式是让开发商、中介与客户三方签订协议，根据协议，客户交了定金后，开发商给客户留出90-180天不等的卖房时间，为客户保留心仪房源；中介同时在平台主推客户的二手房。如果协议期后，客户的房子依然没有卖出，定金可退还。 “&#39;以旧换新&#39;的核心是缩短新房、二手房之间的置换周期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/56104f158b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1434&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/56104f158b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250934&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;地方政府关心新房去化&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在山东，最早推出“以旧换新”政策的是济南市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年7月，山东省房地产业协会和济南市房地产业协会举办了一场有关“上半年房地产市场形势”的研讨会。除了山东省房地产协会和济南市房地产协会的会员单位，参会的还有山东省住建厅、省委财经办和济南市住建局和部分的金融机构。李斌记得，那场会议是“以旧换新”亮相的起点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“当时得到济南一些开发商的认可。”李斌说，8月下旬，“以旧换新”开始在济南一些项目做试点。以某房企的项目为例，由贝壳向购房者提供二手房房屋的评估、挂牌、带看和交易服务，满足交易标准的二手房屋，贝壳会帮助客户在30-90天内快速卖房；项目方给二手房的购房者提供1%-2%购房补贴，加速二手房出售速度。其间，一手房的购房者缴纳10万元即可锁定意向房源，待二手房售出后再缴纳新房房款，若二手房未售出，则可享受退房保障。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李斌记得，8月份淄博召开的一个房地产经纪研讨会上，淄博有关行政部门的工作人员也对这种“以旧换新”的房屋买卖模式很感兴趣，提出淄博的行业协会也能进行推广尝试。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“核心的手段是缩短新房和二房之间的交易时长，政府在其中起到支持和鼓励的作用。”李斌介绍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;诸葛找房数据显示，2023年1-7月，淄博新房价格持续爬升，由8272元/平方米上升至8425元/平方米，但8月价格下跌至8389元/平方米。与之相对，淄博的二手房价连月上涨，自2022年11月起开始呈现一、二手房价格倒挂的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李斌向南方周末记者解释，“以旧换新”要在加快二手房去化的同时，做好与置换新房的衔接。如果购房者手中的二手房卖不掉，就没有新房的首付钱，也就没法下决心买新房。 “数据显示，现在济南市二手房的平均成交周期达到175天，淄博甚至超过250天。”而在规模更小的城市、县城中，二手房的成交周期会更长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李斌介绍，买房“以旧换新”政策接下来还会相继在泰安、济宁等山东多个地市落地。除了山东，一些省外的城市也想了解相关的经验。李斌发现，前来交流的地方政府会更关心新房的去化，“毕竟新房的去化是城市激活房地产市场最重要的手段”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“观望的人比较多”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月8日，《淄博日报》公布了四十余个达成“以旧换新”协议的一手楼盘。但数位淄博当地的房产中介告诉南方周末记者，更多想要买房的人群还在观望。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;淄博市的房产中介张元（化名）告诉南方周末记者，“以旧换新”政策出台后，看房的人数明显增多，比之前多了三分之一，他每天的工作时间也从原来的12小时增加到了14小时。他表示，如果中介没能在协议规定的三个月内把旧房卖出去，客户就会把旧房及定金收回，“相当于白忙活三个月”。张元解释，政策会给中介带来更大工作量，但如果客户有把握把旧房卖出去，也就拥有了更多购入新房的底气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一位淄博房产中介孙宇（化名）9月8日就在短视频平台更新了他的政策解读。此外，他每天还能接到二三十个相关的咨询电话。有急着卖旧房买新房、一口气连问十几个问题的人，也有随意打听、持观望态度的人。孙宇告诉南方周末记者，大楼盘的开发商一般不收旧房，“他（开发商）想卖新房，还买二手房干嘛？”而对于中介来说，他们一般也愿意代理大产权住宅，即房主拥有房屋所有权、能出示房产证的房屋，“销售难度低，成交率更高”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;孙宇介绍，他手中待售的二手房主要位于淄博的主城区张店西区，也是中介口中的淄博的“黄金地段”。这里的最高房价超过两万元每平方米，而在房价最低的郊区，一平方米仅售五六千元，是中心城区房价的四分之一。 “参与&#39;以旧换新&#39;的一手楼盘都&#39;不太好卖&#39;”，孙宇介绍，它们大多分布在淄博市地段相对较差的郊区，学区房数量也相对较少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但已经有客户在孙宇这里成功“以旧换新”。这是一位35岁的客户，他要先卖出其位于张店区东部的旧房，才有足够的预算购入一套学区房。此前这套旧房在交易平台挂了近半年都无人问津。这几天孙宇以80万的价格把该客户的旧房卖出，客户又花费150多万购买了一套位于张店西南片区的学区房。在孙宇看来，这是参与“以旧换新”的一手楼盘里地段最好的房子之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;孙宇目前在淄博开设自己的房产中介公司，手下有十几个员工，业务集中在一手房和二手房的买卖。他说，目前政策还没有给公司带来销量上的明显变化，2023年，公司的房屋月销量主要集中在3至5套。新政使咨询的人变多，“但大家都很谨慎，观望的人比较多”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“知心闺蜜”恶语相向之前：李佳琦这样的“赛博货郎”何以逆势成功？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256854]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，“最强美妆带货博主”李佳琦怒怼直播间消费者的事件，让李佳琦本人陷入了舆论漩涡之中，即使在其本人含泪道歉之后，针对他的批评和指责仍未平息，这场风波除了将他推上舆论的风口浪尖之外，也让公众将注意力集中在“带货主播”这个行业上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在卷入这场口舌风波之前，李佳琦通过在美妆直播领域的多年耕耘，已经构建了一个令人咋舌的商业帝国，其短视频平台直播间一个月总销售额破10亿元、5分钟内卖出15000只口红等“惊天纪录”，甚至引发了传播学学者对其销售话语体系和传播策略的研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从主力消费者画像上来看，李佳琦主要针对的是女性受众，这一点从其直播时标志性的开场白“所有女生”就能看得出来。除了对“你们的魔鬼来咯”“Oh my god”“太好看了吧”“买它买它”等“闺蜜腔”熟练的符号化运用之外，李佳琦还非常善于使用层级对比的传播策略，通过“一抬一踩”为消费者营造“高人一等”的消费满足感。比如，在形容口红色号“土气”时，李佳琦会使用“二十年前妈妈涂的颜色”这样的修辞方式唤醒消费者的记忆。而在推荐自己的产品时，又会用“人间水蜜桃就是你”“涂上你就是贵妇”“限量版的XX色”等连捧带哄的修辞手段为女性消费者提供遐想空间，激发消费者下单一试的消费冲动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以女性为主的消费者愿意在李佳琦的直播间消费，并不完全是因为对其“口红一哥”专业能力的认可和肯定，更是对其“知心闺蜜”人设的信任和青睐。同样，女性消费者在李佳琦的直播间购买的不仅仅是口红和眉笔，还有情绪价值。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以“怼人事件”的起因和结果实际上都非常简单。对主播来说，在存量博弈与经济下行的压力之下，即使是李佳琦这样“闺蜜腔”精准熟练，“最懂女人心”的营销人设完美的头部主播，在调动消费者的消费冲动时也不如从前容易，由此产生的倦怠和烦躁情绪本身就是经济社会环境的一种自然折射。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而对消费者来说，过去对自己又捧又哄，无论是否消费都能提供满满情绪价值的“闺蜜”突然拉下脸来对自己恶言相向，在情感上是难以接受的。尽管李佳琦经常以“公主”“贵妇”“女王”称呼和形容消费者，但实际上其主要消费者群体仍以工薪阶层为主，他们被俗称为“打工人”，在职场压力下被卷到精疲力尽之余，试图在“闺蜜”的直播间寻找情绪价值时，却被对方指责“不努力”，勃然大怒也是正常的情绪反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以说，“怼人事件”实际上是李佳琦和消费者在压力下共同情绪的一次瞬时对冲。但并非只有李佳琦和消费者处于压力之下。在“大家赚钱都不容易”的当下，“李佳琦们”的生财之道又显得过容易，于是“怼人事件”也就成了那个压力的宣泄口。公众在借此事件宣泄压力和情绪之余，也开始思考“带货主播”究竟是怎样在我们这个社会中成为一个“很容易赚钱”的行业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上李佳琦在整个美妆产业链中扮演的角色，更类似于前现代社会走街串巷贩卖针头线脑和脂粉香盒的货郎。他既非商品的生产者，也非传统意义上开店做生意的商家，而是一种更特别的销售终端。旧社会因礼教禁锢，妇女既无法四处走动，也无法获得关于商品的信息，这些信息闭塞、见识有限的家庭妇女需要货郎这一媒介了解和购买商品。因此在古代社会，一个成功的货郎必然是一个熟悉妇女心理特点，掌握一定话术技巧，说话能往女性心里去的人精，一首旧社会的歌谣这样唱道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;货郎儿，卖花线，挑着担子走街面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;叮当摇动唤娇娘，引出娇娘门口见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;娇娘宜笑宜复嗔，价要便宜货要新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;侥幸货郎有艳福，生涯常与美人亲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见现代的“美妆主播”在洞悉消费者心理特点，制定针对化营销策略，搭配销售情绪价值这一点上，和古代贩卖针头线脑和脂粉香盒的货郎一脉相承。也正是因为这一特点，在旧社会对货郎这一职业也普遍存在偏见和歧视，认为他们行为不轨，一有机会就会勾引妇女，在明清话本小说中，多有货郎引诱、拐卖良家妇女的故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从商业发展形态理论来看，旧社会的货郎是封闭半封闭的“熟人社会”环境下商业信息差的产物。在信息时代，销售渠道和销售方式多种多样，开放的商品信息唾手可得，各种各样的商品广告铺天盖地，在这种环境之下，本身不应该存在“赛博货郎”的生存空间，至少其不应该在现代商业活动中占有如此重要的地位和比重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现实与理论恰恰相反，以李佳琦为代表的“赛博货郎”们不仅在现代信息社会中逆势猛进，大获成功，而且与其他一些国家的“网红”兼职带货的商业模式不同，在我国，“赛博货郎”发展成为了一个专门的职业，且形成了一个庞大的职业群体，成为了网络电商最主要也最有力的销售渠道和销售方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在全球第一制造业大国、全球第一信息化大国、全球第一网络零售大国，消费者的消费习惯却在某种程度上回归了前现代社会的“货郎模式”，这一反常识、反逻辑、反直觉的现实背后，实际上有着非常深刻的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，正是因为商品的极大丰富、商品信息爆炸式的增长、商品广告无缝式的覆盖，反而让身处商品和信息海洋之中的消费者感到迷茫和困惑。同时，“试错”的成本也呈现几何式上升，而那些不愿为了购买一件商品而钻研相关知识、比较同类商品优劣的消费者，也就自然而然地回归另一种意义上的“熟人社会”，也就是选择信任自己所青睐的“赛博货郎”们的“倾情推荐”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，信息化社会固然有其喧嚣热闹的一面，然而在资讯爆炸、舆论汹涌、全天候社交的背后，互联网上原子化个体的精神孤独也是一个严峻的问题。正如前文提到的，“赛博货郎”李佳琦提供的绝不仅仅是口红和眉笔，还有情绪价值，或许，后者比前者更决定了“货郎”这个古老的职业，在这个现代信息化商业社会中广阔而恒久的生存空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[林家栋：要把角色的灵魂、内心抓出来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256835]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/OugasTfNJ5ML9yNbtsKg8Ese6jTVvmFQwr4ZgUOK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/OugasTfNJ5ML9yNbtsKg8Ese6jTVvmFQwr4ZgUOK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250583&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，警察王守月在广东退休，同事为他庆祝，餐会上，他想起没破的案、没抓到的人，心情低落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王守月在手机上刷到云南某地火灾的新闻，路人面孔里有一张很熟悉，他确定那是二十多年前抢劫运钞车、杀害自己警察同事的主嫌犯陈信文。他穿便服，独自踏上旅程，拎着一袋水果去拜访陈信文，当时对方已经隐姓埋名地生活多年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jRRYqkC3rNmbY3a1KtAAEoIW1ZbU1J7s6unHPf1l.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jRRYqkC3rNmbY3a1KtAAEoIW1ZbU1J7s6unHPf1l.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250584&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《第八个嫌疑人》(2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月9日上映的电影《第八个嫌疑人》里，香港演员林家栋饰演退休警察王守月。片中只有一场枪战戏，也没有悬疑元素，观众早知道未落网的人是谁，看点在王守月和陈信文对峙的细节。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本片于2023年6月入围上海国际电影节主竞赛单元。对手戏演员大鹏（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;饰演陈信文&lt;/span>;）和孙阳受访时提到，拍戏前大家习惯排练一下，而林家栋和其他演员保持距离，“上来直给”，以此保护即时性的反应。林家栋很松弛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们说的是一场办公室群戏，王守月不堪工地施工声，到建筑公司反映情况，陈信文和其他几人在研究图纸。王守月以为他们在研究地产开发，实际上他们在密谋抢劫。那是20多年前惊天大案发生的几天之前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不晓得你下一步怎么做，你不晓得我下一步怎么做，所以在镜头以外，我们就保持距离感。”林家栋说。他觉得这是最符合角色需求的交流方式。饰演警队同事的张颂文喜欢在片场灵活发挥，林家栋也欣然接招。 “你突然改什么，我可以改。因为我的角色还在我手里，你的角色还在你手里。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林家栋做电影演员已经22年。 2002年，他第一次在电影里演警察，是《无间道》中的大B。天台上，陈永仁和刘建明举枪互指、亮明底牌的对决戏后，观众以为胜负已定，不料在电梯间，大B出现，干脆地杀了真警察陈永仁，亮出自己的黑社会卧底身份，让同为卧底、想要重新做人的假警察刘建明措手不及。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是全片的最后一场戏，在此之前，林家栋一直没看到完整剧本，真心认为大B是个好警察——导演有意为之。骤然得知身份反转，林家栋慌得不得了，怕自己演错。那时他还懵懂，需要听前辈安排。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早年的一期《鲁豫有约》里，刘建明的扮演者、曾为林家栋老板的刘德华提到，他那时要让林家栋去掉“电视剧的气息”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Xwtcx2vxeG6phdNkczSzs9mfN7KAhSHKekv8icwR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Xwtcx2vxeG6phdNkczSzs9mfN7KAhSHKekv8icwR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杀破狼·贪狼》(2017)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林家栋1987年进入TVB艺员训练班，第一次有戏拍是春节，原定的演员罢工，他才有机会顶上。 1990年代，他成为一名比较成功的电视剧演员，高强度的拍摄安排让他感觉脑筋闭塞，“想尽善尽美，又做不到”。他想换种生活，转去电影业，签约了刘德华的公司。 “哪怕是闲角、不起眼的小角色，镜头到你这里，你这一秒就是主角。别浪费这个机会，演好这个角色。”他受访时曾说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导演杜琪峰的《黑社会》（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2005&lt;/span>;）演技派云集，任达华、梁家辉、林雪、张家辉，没有盖掉林家栋的闪光处。在帮会和连胜交接之年，年轻一辈争夺权力。林家栋饰演的东莞仔效忠其中一派，听话、手狠，野心逐渐膨胀。影迷开始认可他。很快，《叶问》（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2008&lt;/span>;）里的汉奸李钊一角让林家栋拿到香港电影金像奖（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“以下简称金像奖”&lt;/span>;）最佳男配角提名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/sepyjFDz5nBfX5DhRUB7nlA43arTY2X1K4i8E3fg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/sepyjFDz5nBfX5DhRUB7nlA43arTY2X1K4i8E3fg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250589&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《叶问》(2008)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港盛产警匪片，林家栋演过警，演过匪。他演的警察有的斯文干练，有的城府甚深，“我做了很多次警察，每一次我都在找不同。因为我相信一个人生活那么多年，一定有不同的心理状态、想法、性格。我有这个机会放置不同的可能性。”林家栋说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/bgR83OjJYp2oQWymrd1m26vKCXFEnubavG0JtX1D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/bgR83OjJYp2oQWymrd1m26vKCXFEnubavG0JtX1D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250585&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《寒战》(2012)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，凭借《寒战》里的警务局高层Albert，他又获得金像奖最佳男配提名。片中，鹰派和文官势同水火，梁家辉和郭富城争执的对手戏十分出彩，彭于晏演的新警察是潜伏的反派，想要帮助父亲（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁家辉的角色&lt;/span>;）扫清升官路障，有大反转；相较之下，Albert的形象绝不是最饱满、最出彩的，但林家栋稳住了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林家栋也演过面慈但冷血的匪。凭借淡漠的贼王，他同时获得香港电影金像奖、香港电影评论学会、香港电影导演会影帝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/npjwyFz4FWkI6toJ9VmpUmau97eTgt5bT0KVEMQh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/npjwyFz4FWkI6toJ9VmpUmau97eTgt5bT0KVEMQh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250588&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《智齿》(2021)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，他凭《手卷烟》和《智齿》两部电影获得两个金像奖最佳男主角提名。其中《手卷烟》他以零片酬出演，饰演被社会遗弃的人：他的角色关超二十多年前是华裔英兵，退役后生活失意，欠高利贷，做黑社会两头吃的营生，收留了一个被追杀的落难印度人，最后自己身犯险境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林家栋今年56岁，他这几年的银幕形象，从关超到王守月，有郁郁衰老之态。但他本人保养得宜，身形瘦削。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月初的一个晚上，9点多，忙了一天的工作，林家栋讲起表演，兴致依然高涨，比如《命案》（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023&lt;/span>;）片尾天台戏他的自由发挥，让他饰演的命理大师在人格分裂后喃喃自语：“我是一支花，我是一支花。”比如《手卷烟》里关超对待印度人前后态度的微妙转变，是由于对方称呼的改变。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他记性极佳，能迅速回忆起《黑社会》最后一场戏，野心上身的东莞仔对台词气口的处理。他不时加上肢体动作，还原自己一个人关在房间苦苦琢磨的样子：在沙发上瘫下来，半个小时，再坐起身，做出翻看剧本状，找突破口。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王守月是个无聊的人，好容易退休了，生活还是过得像工作，这可能有点像林家栋。他上过许多次TVB或者其他电视访谈节目，都说自己这个人没意思，无聊得很。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他是勤奋的演员，哪怕拿了影帝，也说只能“嗨48小时”，然后会想工作。那年，握着奖杯，他在台上对自己说，冷静点。然后说，“这么多年我自己觉得，演戏真的是不分年纪的。也不计较颜值，最重要是自己用心。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是林家栋的讲述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;警察的感情&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我想王守月这个角色有点不一样，过去我看很多警匪片对警察的描述，没有太多表现感情，但这一次我觉得是很好的机会，这个角色是有情的人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;第一场在退休饭局，我其实有一些压抑、遗憾，二十多年，（嫌疑人）看不到，抓不住，怎么办？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;到后来我跟大鹏这个角色对冲，慢慢了解他，他是做错了一个决定的可怜人。看到他在火灾现场的新闻短片，不是太光鲜的，所以我要亲眼看看他现在什么样，应该过得不太好吧？能不能把他抓回来、用什么方法，我不知道。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;办公室那场戏，人物矛盾还没有出现。我的处理是随着身体语言，去给他们压力：返回来-停住-走，聊，再回头，巴拉巴拉，这样子。我觉得可以这样处理，已经足够，如果太多情感就假了，你根本不晓得他们是谁，他也不晓得你是谁，如果我想通过画面让观众感受压力，身体语言做这个反应就够了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;每次演出前，我习惯先看看这里的场景，适应我的身份、情绪，我跟里面其他人物的关系。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我必须要尊重导演跟摄影师的风格。有的导演、摄影师，是用镜头帮忙做了很多事，不需要我做太多，在拍摄现场我就配合你。但如果是定镜，你让我走，那么摄影机的镜头在这里，空间那么大，我在这个空间能做多少，尽量做。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;感性与清醒&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;演员在镜头之内很感性，镜头外我们应该很清醒。我每天都记住，我见过什么人、聊什么天，我会问不同理念的朋友，对新移民什么感觉？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;每个行业都有不同的人存在，我想感受他们的生命力在哪里。每一次放假，我都找一些圈外的朋友聊天，有做水产服务、开的士、卖钻石、做大品牌公关的，也有做老板的，在中环做金融的。我的朋友大部分很能说，多听，我就明白原来他们的生活圈、思维、共同态度是这个样子。他们的人生满足了我。我慢慢累积，内置我的经验，将来演出，我知道得很具体。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;比如很多大公司裁员，老是裁最一线的人，你经理一个月的人工费够10个人的，裁你一个就够了，但很多公司是将军多过兵，为什么那么奇怪呢？这就涉及到人性的问题，人一定是要保护自己的。但是将军少了10个兵，又怎么打仗？生活中真的有太多的问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《寒战》里本来我是反派。我跟导演说，我演反一号很开心，但是对你的电影是很大的破坏。现实里，一个大公司的管理层，要生存，不光是看能力有多强，忍耐最重要。不能够太过，要懂得收。 Albert是法律博士，学历特别高，不可能被彭于晏那个角色笼络的。两个礼拜后，导演真的改了，让我的角色最后死掉了，我反而开心。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我年少的时候很少说话的，家里全都是姐姐在说，姐姐也不明白男生的想法，我们很少交流。但是我每天看很多东西，脑袋里也在想，为什么这样？去喜宴，穿黑色的西装。朋友了，去殡仪馆，也是黑色的西装，那怎么分是红事还是白事？很多为什么。后来读训练班，老师也告诉我们，生活是体验，你们必须要记住这个感觉。就更加特意去想，看多一点，多想一点，为人物的性格找一个根源，将来创作就更有理有据。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我跟朋友很无聊的，夜里1点多肚子饿，问在哪里，吃夜宵好不好？茶餐厅最好，吃喝有中有西的。外带，不需要。进去坐，吃什么，看（这时候自己）胖不胖。不胖的话，我最喜欢吃番茄酱的粉，胖就不可以了，喝奶茶或者咖啡。我和朋友叫一个套餐，吃的给你，我喝这个就可以，不浪费。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;茶餐厅是一个很真实的地方，没有那么多的枷锁。在酒店，每个人都很静的，说什么不知道(模拟窃窃私语)，看不到情感。茶餐厅有很实在的生活在里面，人很愿意表露他们的情绪，可以了解到一点八卦。这个样子最舒服。我现在也去。要做山上的人不难，把自己封闭起来；但生活很重要，感受生活很重要，要不然怎么演出？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gyGjrnRLSWDVdFArYwioQoc7oOLyCVEKigrDKXXL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;543&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gyGjrnRLSWDVdFArYwioQoc7oOLyCVEKigrDKXXL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250587&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《无间道》(2002)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不甘&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我八几年到TVB根本不知道什么是演出，所以才读那个训练班，慢慢了解、喜欢，但不甘于只是演出，因为我觉得演出有些是演，很有技术性，但不够好，不投入。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《无间道》（最后那场戏）演之前我吓了一跳。刘德华刘伟强你们骗我，为什么我要开枪打陈永仁？ ok，给我一分钟。他们肯定很清楚这个剧本，我对角色只有那一点点认识，其他我都不知道，所以必须要相信他们。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;但必须承认，剪完之后，看成片我是可以接受的。人最多的是什么东西？面具，面对不同的场景、不同的人物，人会戴着不同的面具，这是我从那场戏领悟出来的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（至于表演上的质变）我想应该是在《黑社会》到《叶问》。观众之前看我就是一个斯文小子。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/aTINtflx8n06v4KPhj2AsJnuIePMQJ1XPKlWVwhq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/aTINtflx8n06v4KPhj2AsJnuIePMQJ1XPKlWVwhq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250582&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《黑社会》(2005)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《黑社会》导演是杜琪峰了，我不知道导演想什么。到现场，30分钟前才拿到剧本，知道对白，好，试试看了。跟着感觉走。导演说ok，我问，可不可以再来一条。导演说，我觉得ok就可以了。真的吗？我觉得好像是欠了一点点。杜导说我不需要，你不相信我吗？我回相信。 （笑）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们也不可以看playback（回放），只有导演能看。群戏只有一两场，其他时候没有对手，只有我自己一个人演。所以我真的没有太多的想法。在电影院看，我才想到，原来表演可以这个样子的吗？原来创作变化是那么大的，编剧跟导演很了解我们这些演员，能够把我们改到一个程度，让观众有很新、但是很实在的感觉。我觉得很厉害，影响我很深。那我应该还有机会，我不甘于就是现在这样子。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;到《叶问》是第一次，那个戏还没开拍，我到上海，躲在房间里头三天三夜，没有出房间吃饭，我的助理把饭拿来放门口，像住监狱一样。过三天就拍了，我想，应该怎么处理这个人物，就这点空间，能够表达李钊这个人物的无奈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;李钊是汉奸，做汉奸是不好的，但我跟导演说，我（指李钊）不在北京、不在南京，看不见权力问题，我在佛山，钱真的不多，要生存。有一场戏，演对手戏的角色死掉了，我根本没有想过人要为一包米死掉，打打无所谓，受伤也算了——那个时代没办法，但死好像是过分一点了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;拍的时候，因为导演没有喊cut，我做了一个很长的反应。我要求导演让我做长一点，哪怕后面剪掉也无所谓。那个时候我开始知道，要把角色的灵魂、内心抓出来。还好洪金宝导演说可以做。 Thanks. 《叶问》有机会、有镜头、有时间让我做。我再通过这个镜头告诉观众，李钊，你难过吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;先想一想&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一个戏拍完，我会让自己变空白。我带一个电脑到外地去，可以一整天不出去，在房间看、想，因为我已经进入另外一个角色里头，过去了的就不想了。如果老是想过去很容易卡住。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我不把它当作一个工作，这是我的兴趣。有的时候导演打电话问：你在公司里头吗？ “在。”“最近怎么样？我想到一个案子，你觉得怎么样？”“有趣啊。”“那我过两天带编剧过来找你谈谈。”“好。”就这样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;比如最近，有一个投资方，他不是找我演出的，他说现在香港的电影真的困难，他希望做有内容的限级片。我想一想，可以这样、那样。他说，“你帮我当监制可以吗？可以来跟导演聊聊。”接着投资方找我演出，我想应该很好玩的样子，就跟他合作了。现在项目还在创作阶段。大家觉得香港电影可能题材越来越少，我希望能够通过我自己的一点点努力，得到多一点空间，让观众看不同的题材。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/RG5lr3MtdiJIj0PKTqAtcYOrTRRINVk7VRLWrHsk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/RG5lr3MtdiJIj0PKTqAtcYOrTRRINVk7VRLWrHsk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250581&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《手卷烟》(2020)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《手卷烟》这部电影是香港政府支持的（作者注：《手卷烟》为香港“首部剧情电影计划”第四届大专组得奖作品，由香港电影发展局资助拍摄），花的是香港纳税人的钱，我说片酬我不要了，但必须要好好弄剧本。我跟电影发展局聊：我觉得这个题材是有潜质的，但是我觉得可以更好一点，你多给我三个月可以吗？对方说好，你演出就可以。我跟导演、监制不停聊，我觉得有改进空间，不要浪费了，先想一想。一个礼拜之后，我们重新再弄这个剧本。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《手卷烟》一整部电影是讲几个被社会遗弃的人，关超是英兵，他的南亚朋友文尼是新移民，好像不被主流接受。所以他们有句对白，文尼说，这个地方跟我想象的不一样。关超说，是你们傻，你们以为自己去了天堂吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《手卷烟》的大部分剧情发生在关超家，一个逼仄的小屋。我第一次看景，光很亮，尖沙咀在香港是很繁荣的地方，很多招牌灯很亮，很斑斓。我说导演你相信我，关超依赖外面的光打进来照着他的生命，其实他生活一点也不亮，要有黑暗的效果。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我还跟导演讲，90年代整个社会很投机，人贪心，没有身份要怎么弥补？赚钱。那个年头我在TVB拍电视剧，摄影师也是一路拍，一路看股票涨跌。所以电影里出现了一个人做股票买卖，输掉了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我用一点点人生经验告诉你，我觉得这个样子最能配合《手卷烟》这个内容。电影为什么那么饱满，因为我经历过。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中科院博士晒缅甸工资单？实为国内收入，每月四五千清单曝光]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256850]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月15日，从缅甸获救回国后的中科院博士首次发自述视频回应网上质疑，随后“中科院被骗博士晒出缅甸工资单”登上网络热搜。南都记者通过该视频和当事人张先生了解到，网络热搜存在误解，他晒出的实际是此前在国内每月四五千元的工资单。他介绍，当时因家人生病需要花很多钱，“全家只有我一个人工作，面临非常大的经济压力”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/cef13046a6736df6bef58695b92771b3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;475&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/cef13046a6736df6bef58695b92771b3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250944&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;张先生发自述视频回应网上质疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张先生在视频中称，“这段时间接受了很多媒体的采访，也接受了警察的调查，不过网上还是有一些质疑的声音。”因此，他希望进行回应来消除大家的疑惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/a1a8252b06ef51c1da2be2e718d4ee87.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/a1a8252b06ef51c1da2be2e718d4ee87.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;张先生被骗前在国内的工资单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于为什么选择去国外工作，他解释，当时他在国内中科院的一个研究所工作，每月的工资大概四五千元。 2022年，他的父母和女朋友都生病，需要花很多钱，“当时全家只有我一个人工作，面临非常大的经济压力”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是那时他求职很不顺利，前前后后投了一二十份简历，都没有收到回应。他坦言，“这个非常打击我的自信心，所以最后才会想到看看有没有国外的工作机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那份令他深陷缅甸诈骗园区的国外工作，是通过中介找的。张先生介绍，他看对方多年时间一直帮国内的人寻找国外的工作机会，所以比较信任对方。这个中介给他推荐了一份新加坡的工作，“薪资待遇比较合理，每月1.5万元加提成，每周工作六天，每天工作10小时，比国内的工作要辛苦，但是包吃包住，待遇比较合理，所以打算试一试。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前接受专访时，张先生曾告诉南都记者，原本希望出国谋求工作机会，却被诱骗至缅甸诈骗园区。 They worked 18 hours a day under strict supervision, were punished corporally if they failed to complete their performance, and were severely beaten if they were found to have &quot;leaked secrets&quot;.后来经多方营救，他于9月5日回国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，被骗与学历、阅历没有必然关系，“诈骗利用的是人性的弱点，任何人都有可能成为受害者”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月15日下午，中国科学院庐山植物园的工作人员告诉南都记者，张先生曾是该单位的正式入编人员，“薪资是按照省里的相关规定一直在走的”，属于公益一类事业单位的标准，除此之外还有博士津贴及其他费用，但对其具体的薪资表示并不清楚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[度数又涨了……近视怎么防，能手术吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256683]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[施工方举报大桥偷工减料：事件逐渐“失焦”，情况属实还是造谣生事必须搞清楚丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256667]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, an accusation of &quot;cutting corners on a highway bridge&quot; has attracted attention. On August 30, 2023, a netizen surnamed Liu with the online name &quot;Liu Shao&quot; reported in real name on the social media platform that there were construction quality problems in the Qinghai Tongsai Expressway Taohe Bridge built by China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau No. 5 Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu claimed to be the actual construction party and began to undertake the substructure project of the Taohe Bridge on April 6, 2022, which lasted more than eight months. He reported that the project leader of China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company &quot;did not use steel bars from the shortlisted manufacturers according to the design, privately used non-standard steel bars from non-shortlisted manufacturers, cut corners during construction, and used unqualified sand and gravel materials during winter construction, resulting in poor concrete quality.&quot; qualified&quot;. Among them, statements such as &quot;the pile inspection process changed the second-category piles to the first-category piles&quot;, &quot;80% of the pile foundation steel bars are unqualified&quot; and &quot;there are hidden safety and quality risks&quot; attracted the attention of the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 6, the Fifth Company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau issued a public statement stating that it had previously entrusted Qinghai Provincial Traffic Inspection Co., Ltd. as a third-party testing agency to conduct quality inspections on the bridge. The inspection report shows that &quot;the physical quality of the Taohe Bridge meets the design requirements and the quality is qualified.&quot; The steel bars and concrete used in the construction are all qualified, and the pile foundation tests are all Class I piles. Liu&#39;s reports have been refuted one by one. At present, the competent authority has entrusted a testing agency to &quot;conduct physical quality inspection and raw material sampling inspection&quot;, and the re-inspection results will be announced to the public in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu didn’t buy it. He showed evidence to &quot;Running News&quot; and said, &quot;The test report I got contains Class II piles.&quot; The pouring time was May 26, 2022. The test date is June 29, 2022. Liu admitted that he made the report because the Fifth Company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau not only refused to pay him for his labor services, but instead cleared him from the site, causing heavy losses to him. “Now I have to report the project quality issues even if I don’t need any money.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, Liu was sued by China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company to the People&#39;s Court of Ledu District, Haidong City, Qinghai Province for infringing the company&#39;s reputation rights because he reported that his labor fees had not been settled. The case will be heard in court on September 18. Liu also presented evidence, saying that he had received a message from the other party &quot;Look at the hardness of our China Railway No. 5 Bureau&quot; after reporting with his real name; the other party also proposed a &quot;compensation plan&quot;, but he did not agree if he was not satisfied. The Fifth Company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau responded that Liu’s main purpose was blackmail and “I will report it as soon as I don’t get the blackmail.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident has evolved to this point and has gradually become &quot;out of focus&quot;: the dispute between Liu and China Railway has become a new hot spot. A closer look at this incident reveals that there are actually two important aspects that deserve further analysis and questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the relationship between the civil dispute between Liu and the Fifth Company of China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau and his reporting behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Liu&#39;s self-report or the &quot;extortion of money&quot; accusation from China Railway No. 5 Bureau, it is shown that the report was due to Liu&#39;s financial demands and that the two parties had a civil dispute. But what is curious is why the case was initiated by China Railway No. 5 Engineering Co., Ltd. against Liu for &quot;infringement of reputation rights&quot; instead of Liu launching a civil lawsuit against China Railway No. 5 Engineering Co., Ltd. due to a labor contract dispute? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of this incident was an economic dispute over &quot;unpaid labor fees&quot;. Following this line of thought, Liu first reported the problem when he could not get the labor fee, but was sued for &quot;infringement of reputation rights&quot;. Then, instead of filing a civil lawsuit on the grounds of a labor contract dispute and demanding payment of the labor fee, he filed an online lawsuit He reported that the project was cutting corners and materials, saying &quot;I have to report project quality problems even if I don&#39;t get labor fees,&quot; and rejected China Railway&#39;s compensation plan. This shows that Liu escalated the incident at all costs, giving the outside world the impression that &quot;the fish is dead and the net is broken.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the evolution of the incident, there are still some questions hidden in the game between the two parties during this period: Has Liu&#39;s labor fee been settled? If it was indeed not settled, Liu initially went to China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau and the relevant departments in Qinghai to report this problem. I am afraid it was just a normal rights protection. Why was he sued by the Fifth Company of China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau for &quot;infringement of the company&#39;s reputation rights&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the chat records provided by Liu, the words of a person from the China Railway No. 5 Bureau after the real-name report, &quot;The more you cause trouble, the less afraid I am. Look at the hardness of our China Railway No. 5 Bureau&quot; to the outside world. It leaves more room for interpretation. This sentence can make people reasonably speculate that Liu chose to &quot;turn the table&quot; by exposing the quality problems of the project precisely because his demands for labor fees were repeatedly ignored by the other party. So, will the labor fees be settled on time, or will the compensation plan of China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company satisfy Liu after the report, and the matter will be settled smoothly? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Liu came out to expose the project quality problems just because the labor fees were not paid, and the project quality problems were true, then the whole incident would have the flavor of &quot;unevenly sharing the spoils, and turning the table over in anger&quot;. The problem behind it is undoubtedly more worrying; or, if the truth is as claimed by China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company, Liu intends to &quot;extort money&quot;, then whether the test results and the evidence he presented are forged, and how much his labor fees are? A clear answer should also be given as to why it was not settled and why it was not settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, whether the truth of the incident is that Liu extorted money or that the Fifth Company of the China Railway Fifth Bureau was in arrears of labor fees, it cannot conceal the most important focus of this incident: whether the construction of the Taohe Bridge on the Tongsai Expressway was completed. Through safety inspection, whether there are any project quality problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the Tongsai Expressway has a total length of 204 kilometers, and the total estimated investment of the project is 18.562 billion yuan. The main project will start on June 15, 2022, and is planned to be completed in October 2025. This expressway connects Qinghai Huangnan Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture and the Qinghai-Gansu border area. It is a section of the &quot;G0611 Zhangwen Expressway&quot;. The Taohe Bridge is located in Saierlong Township, with a total length of 824.5 meters and a total of 20 spans. On July 17, 2023, the first box girder of the bridge was successfully erected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Mou chose to report after the substructure project of the Taohe Bridge was completed and the first box girder was successfully erected. Judging from the current situation, it was because of the intensification of economic disputes. Which one is more convincing is the previous test results announced by the fifth company of China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau, the test results of the supervision company commissioned by Liu himself, and the evidence presented. This is something that the competent authorities should conduct an in-depth and serious investigation in the follow-up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, inconsistencies between actual construction and prior surveys are relatively common in the engineering community. If Liu&#39;s accusation is true and China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company chooses &quot;non-standard steel bars, unqualified sand and gravel materials and Class II piles&quot; in construction, its impact on the quality of the project will also need to be determined through professional evaluation. The key to the problem is whether changing construction materials will affect the quality of the project and thus endanger the safety of the Taohe Bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the focus of this matter should not be on the dispute between Liu and China Railway No. 5 Bureau. Relevant departments should adhere to the principle of safety first in the follow-up investigation, focus on the inspection of project quality, investigate whether the fifth company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau made normal changes in construction materials or cut corners, and fully demonstrate the impact of changes in construction materials on the traffic of the Taohe Bridge. impact on safety and fully disclose the findings to the public. If there is indeed a case of cutting corners and affecting the quality of the bridge, the relevant responsible persons should be severely dealt with and even held criminally responsible; if the whistleblower spreads rumors and causes trouble, he cannot go unpunished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“数字”间谍来自何处？有何招式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256665]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The current development of network technology is rapid, and new things such as 5G, Metaverse, ChatGPT and so on are emerging. It makes people exclaim &quot;the future is already here&quot;. Along with it, there are also a large number of hidden network security risks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a specialized agency for safeguarding national security and a department in charge of counter-espionage work, national security agencies continue to strengthen the tracking, monitoring and prevention of relevant activities, effectively safeguard our network security, and make &quot; &quot;Digital&quot; spies reveal their true colors and have nowhere to hide! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Where did the attack come from? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Spy shadows thousands of miles away&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Currently, cyberspace has become a target for overseas espionage and intelligence agencies. An important position for my country to carry out cyber espionage work, our country has become the main victim of high-level persistent threat (APT) attacks. In recent years, national security agencies have discovered that dozens of espionage and intelligence agencies from different countries and regions have carried out cyber attacks in our territory. They either set up specialized agencies, set up &quot;cover companies&quot;, and developed professional means to directly carry out cyberattacks and penetrations against me, or through &quot;behind-the-scenes control&quot; and &quot;service outsourcing&quot; methods, they instruct professional companies and hacker organizations to carry out the operations, or through &quot;purchasing&quot; &quot;Data, loopholes, tools and other methods are used to lure domestic institutions and personnel to implement it. Some countries also use the guise of &quot;hunting&quot; to lure other countries to implement it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Who are the potential targets? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The flash of swords and shadows within easy reach&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From the perspective of attack targets, in addition to the continued attacks on our national institutions and related In addition to carrying out cyber attacks on &quot;traditional targets&quot; such as confidential units, overseas espionage and intelligence agencies have also continued to strengthen attacks and penetrations on China&#39;s critical information infrastructure and major infrastructure network systems, and have further extended their black hands to China&#39;s universities, scientific research institutions, and large-scale infrastructure. Enterprises, high-tech companies and other institutions and business executives, experts and scholars and other groups. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Judging from the attacks, various software systems such as email, office automation, user management, and security protection are involved, as well as various hardware devices such as servers, computers, switches, and routers. , as well as mobile phones, WIFI, cameras and other civilian household equipment, it can be said to be &quot;pervasive&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;What are the tricks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;A highly threatening &quot;professional team&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Different from ordinary social hackers, overseas espionage and intelligence agencies It has many resources to mobilize, strong technical capabilities, rich experience in cyber attack activities, and more covert methods. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some of them collect and steal personal information, use social engineering, and accurately forge “phishing” emails and websites to conduct deception attacks on target objects; some use mining and purchasing key &quot;Zero-day vulnerabilities&quot; in software systems and hardware equipment directly attack and penetrate the company; some first intrude into the network of companies that control our supply chain or operation and maintenance service organizations, and then use this as a &quot;springboard&quot; to attack downstream user units; some on a large scale Penetrate and control China&#39;s civilian network and home network equipment, and establish &quot;positions&quot; to carry out cyber attacks against China and other countries. Behind extremely professional and covert attack methods, there are often more dangerous intentions! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0005c4c4635be7fb8fdab302f8671fc4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;488&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0005c4c4635be7fb8fdab302f8671fc4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250757 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Overseas cyber attacks against us&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Common&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Common techniques&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How much harm is caused? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Security issues that cannot be underestimated&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Cyberattacks by overseas espionage and intelligence agencies are large-scale and deep-seated , strong sustainability. Once the network systems of our country&#39;s state agencies, secret-related units and other important corporate institutions are attacked or invaded, the state secrets, important data, documents, etc. stored and processed may be &quot;caught in one sweep.&quot; Once our critical information infrastructure and major infrastructure network systems are invaded and controlled, they will face the risk of being disrupted and destroyed at any time. Overseas spy agencies conduct cyber attacks to steal trade secrets and intellectual property rights of our companies and institutions, and monitor the content of our citizens’ network communications for a long time. They also seriously infringe upon the legitimate rights and interests of our citizens and organizations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e45429180f71bb35c1ff1b37ee0e262.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e45429180f71bb35c1ff1b37ee0e262.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250756 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Environment&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Reduction of cyber attack and secret theft scenarios of foreign spy and intelligence agencies&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt; /a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>