<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中国银行原党委书记、董事长刘连舸严重违纪违法被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258200]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:21:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;830&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission investigated the former Party Secretary and Chairman of Bank of China Co., Ltd. Liu Liange&#39;s serious violations of discipline and law were investigated and investigated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, Liu Liange lost his ideals and convictions, abandoned his original mission, was not firm or compromised in implementing the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, abandoned his financial risk prevention and control responsibilities, and interfered in credit projects in violation of regulations. Illegal granting of loans, resulting in major financial risks, failure to fulfill the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, seriously damaging the political ecology of the unit, illegally bringing prohibited books and periodicals into the country, and deliberately trying to resist organizational censorship; ignoring the spirit of the eight central regulations, illegally accepting gifts, entering and exiting Private clubs, accepting skiing and travel arrangements, long-term borrowing of vehicles subject to management; failing to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing inquiries, hiring, adjusting and promoting cadres for personal gain; running businesses in violation of regulations; intervening in fund lending and illegally Keep confidential information; have bad morals, have bad family traditions, and neglect their relatives; have no bottom line in discipline and law, act arbitrarily, &quot;rely on finance to eat finance&quot;, and use their position to benefit others in terms of loan financing, project cooperation, etc. , and illegally received huge amounts of property. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu Liange seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of accepting bribes and illegally granting loans. They did not restrain themselves or hold back after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. They are serious in nature and have bad influence, and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishments of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and submitted to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Liu Liange from the party; according to It stipulates that the benefits he enjoys will be cancelled; his qualifications as a representative of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China will be terminated; his illegal gains that violate disciplines and laws will be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues will be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved will be transferred together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[救援队分析上海4岁女童走失情况：事发地系泥沙滩，沙质不好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258186]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 4, a 4-year-old girl disappeared on the beach of Nanhui New Town in Pudong, Shanghai. She has been missing for more than 10 years. 60 hours. The local police, firefighting and private rescue teams have been searching for days. On the 7th, Li Chenguang, the captain of the Shanghai Dandelion Rescue Team who participated in the search and rescue, told Nandu reporters that after the water receded on the evening of the 6th, the rescue team searched along the breakwater along the low-tide coastline. The girl was found but has not yet been found. According to the introduction, the beach where the girl was lost is a mud beach impacted by rip currents, and is not a scenic spot. &quot;We have always discouraged everyone from entering, but when the weather is good, people do play here every day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About Regarding the controversy over how far the girl was from the coast when she was lost, Li Chenguang analyzed it to Nandu reporters. If the girl was lost around 17:30, the girl’s father was not as far away from the shore as he said when he left. According to recent hydrology It is estimated that the location of the incident is about 100 meters from the shore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Pudong police report, the girl’s father said that when the incident occurred, he returned to the shore to get his mobile phone and left the girl alone on the beach. He returned more than ten minutes later but did not find his daughter. Surveillance footage showed that the girl waited in place for about 10 minutes, then walked towards the water, fell down at the water&#39;s edge and disappeared into the waves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fdedb3e1be01a5c599cb91d2793c8e42.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fdedb3e1be01a5c599cb91d2793c8e42.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253229&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The lost girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4-year-old girl disappeared in the waves&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 5, the girl’s parents posted a message for help on social platforms, saying that their daughter died in October. Lost on Nanhui New Town Beach at around 17:20 on the 4th, 4 and a half years old, 108cm tall, wearing a blue Elsa princess dress, no shoes or socks, with a bow on each side of her head and two small braids at the end of her hair. , wearing a yellow butterfly headband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the police information report issued by the Pudong Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau on the 6th, at about 18:40 on October 4, the girl’s parents went to the Lingang New City Police Station of the Pudong Public Security Bureau for help, saying that their 4-year-old daughter Lost while playing at the beach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl’s father said that he took his family to the beach that day, and he took his daughter Huang Moumou to the beach about 20 meters away from the sea to play. During the process, he went back to get his cell phone and left the girl alone on the beach. More than ten minutes later, he returned to the beach but could not find his daughter. Because it was dark and the search failed, he asked the police for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the report, the Pudong police immediately organized a large number of police forces to conduct a dragnet search along the coast. The fire department dispatched infrared sensor drones. Relevant personnel searched throughout the night, but no trace of the girl was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day, the Pudong police, together with the Fire Rescue Corps, organized nearly 200 people from 6 rescue teams including Lantian and Houtian to carry out a comprehensive search. At the same time, the organization personnel checked more than 20 surveillance probes around the beach one by one, and initially ruled out the possibility that the girl was taken away from the beach by others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the on-site probe is far away, people can only appear as blurry white dots in the image. It was not until evening that his father finally pointed out the exact location of the girl when he and the girl were separated on the surveillance. Based on this, the police found the suspected girl&#39;s figure among the nearly 100 people in the image. After waiting in place for about 10 minutes, she walked towards the water. Go, fall down by the water and disappear into the waves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report stated that at present, Pudong police have coordinated with hydrology experts from Shanghai Ocean University and Maritime University to analyze the flow direction to further carry out search work. If the general public has relevant clues, please contact the police in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The search and rescue team members said that the girl was about 100 meters away from the shore at the time of the incident&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 7, Li Chenguang, captain of the Shanghai Dandelion Rescue Team, told Nandu reporters, They received help from the morning of the 5th, and on two consecutive nights on the 5th and 6th, about 6 rescue teams with a total of more than 200 people participated in the search. &quot;Yesterday afternoon, the police confirmed that the child was swept away by the sea water, and our search outside the area stopped. The subsequent search work focused on searching in the breakwater along the low-tide coastline after the tide ebbed at around 6 p.m., because the girl might have been swept away. He rushed back and got stuck in the breakwater.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chenguang told Nandu reporters that local police and fire fighters had searched the girl on the night of the 4th, but the search on the nights of the 5th and 6th still did not find the girl. &quot;The Coast Guard also arrived at the scene yesterday. Maybe the government will have more power in the next step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Chenguang, the beach where the incident occurred is a mud beach impacted by rip currents, and the sand quality is not good. It&#39;s not a scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This tidal flat is not allowed to enter now. In fact, everyone has been discouraged from entering, including the victim. They also climbed over it. The coastline here is relatively long. When the weather is good, there are indeed people there every day. We play here, including ourselves sometimes, but the sea water is still quite dangerous. This time I also remind everyone to pay attention to safety, especially to watch the children.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About the distance when the girl was lost Regarding the controversy over how far the coast is, Li Chenguang analyzed to Nandu reporters that if the girl went missing around 17:30, the girl&#39;s father was not as far away from the shore as he said when he left. &quot;Because according to the recent hydrological conditions, the exposed beach surface during this period is only one or two hundred meters in total. (Where they are) is about 20 meters from the water and about 100 meters from the shore.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家体育总局原党组成员、副局长杜兆才严重违纪违法被开除党籍和公职]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258194]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:08:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission punished Du Zhaocai, a former member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the State Sports General Administration, for serious disciplinary violations Illegal issues were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Du Zhaocai lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original intention and mission, failed to perform the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, seriously damaged the political ecology of the football field, resisted organizational censorship, and engaged in superstitious activities; ignored the spirit of the eight central regulations , accepting gifts and money in violation of regulations, accepting banquets from others in violation of regulations; not reporting personal matters in accordance with regulations, and failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing correspondence; using public tools for personal use, &quot;relying on sports to eat sports&quot; and &quot;relying on football to eat football&quot;, and not only want to be an official He also wanted to get rich, engaged in power-for-money transactions, took advantage of his position to benefit others in business operations, employee recruitment, etc., and illegally received huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Zhaocai seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline and life discipline, which constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of bribery. He did not restrain himself or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, which was of a serious nature. , the impact is bad and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Du Zhaocai from the party; by The National Supervisory Commission dismissed him from public office; confiscated his illegal gains that violated disciplines; and transferred his suspected criminal issues to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved was also transferred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[世风日下或许只是错觉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258162]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/BayJvmt4lz9Q9EKVZLrfFKYFOwxjBwld21fViZHQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/BayJvmt4lz9Q9EKVZLrfFKYFOwxj Bwld21fViZHQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253098&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From &quot;the world is declining and people&#39;s hearts are not as old as they used to be&quot; to the endless emergence of &quot;the worst generation&quot; and the &quot;beat generation&quot;, research has found that people are increasingly concerned about moral decay and moral trends. The feeling of being worse spans time and geography and is a common social phenomenon that can even be traced back to more than 2,000 years ago. If such a feeling is real and accurate, it may mean that human moral standards have been steadily declining and reaching new lows for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there is also another possibility, that is, the general moral decay and declining social order are just people&#39;s illusions. There is a certain pattern behind it that causes people in different eras and different regions to always have such similar feelings. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, researchers from Columbia University and Harvard University used more than 12 million related scientific data to verify people&#39;s views on moral development trends. The results found that the subjective feeling of &quot;the world is declining&quot; is indeed not an individual time. , a phenomenon that occurs in individual places, but is extremely universal. However, through more objective comparisons of survey data over decades, researchers are also convinced that these subjective feelings of &quot;the present is not as good as it used to be&quot; are actually an illusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Universal and lasting feeling&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This study was published in the magazine &quot;Nature&quot; in June 2023 and relied on data from recent times around the world. Sixty countries and a time span of more than 70 years. Through these horizontal and vertical comparisons, the elders have a more scientific explanation for the criticism of young people that &quot;one generation is inferior to the other&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For most people, morality mainly refers to the way people treat other people in daily life, such as whether they are honest, polite or even willing to help others, etc. The researchers used a series of survey data dating back to the 1940s to understand people&#39;s attitudes toward moral changes. The surveys included direct questions about trends, such as “Do you feel our society’s integrity and ethical behavior have changed more, less, or the same over the past few decades?” “Now do you feel the moral values ​​of the country as a whole have changed?” Better or worse?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that in more than 80% of the survey items, most people believe that the moral level of the entire society is declining. Specifically, people are more likely to experience moral decline when the comparison period is longer. For example, when comparing the longer period of the past ten years to the past year, people are more likely to feel that the level of social morality is declining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some recent surveys, researchers have also found that age is also an important factor in how people feel. People will feel that people today are less friendly and less sincere than the people they saw when they were 20 years old. Similarly, they will also feel that the people they saw at 20 years old are not as moral as the people they were born in. And overall, older people feel more morally bankrupt than younger people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But has social morality really been declining? Some more concrete and objective investigation shows that this is not the case. In addition to asking people generally about their feelings about moral changes, decades of survey data include direct questions about a wide range of people&#39;s specific moral behaviors. For example, &quot;Were you respected by the people around you yesterday?&quot; &quot;In the past 12 months, how often did you give up your seat to strangers, give directions, look after things, or lend money to others?&quot; The results of a number of surveys on specific moral behaviors are clear. By comparing people&#39;s records of their own and their peers&#39; moral behaviors in different eras, the moral level is actually relatively stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even when evaluating some specific social and moral issues, people may feel moral improvement. For example, when the survey asked about how to treat people with disabilities and sexual minorities, many people believed that society was making progress. These data all show that although when people generally evaluate social moral changes, they will feel from the bottom of their hearts that morality has been declining or even getting worse. However, by comparing relatively more objective specific moral behaviors, the subjective judgment of moral decline cannot be held up. foot. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Happier and more ethical&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I do often hear people say that people are becoming more and more selfish and less generous. Etc. I hear this statement both from the public and other academics. However, I always point out that the data shows this is not true. This latest study is very convincing and I agree with the author, though Many people feel that this is the case, but there is no objective evidence that moral standards are actually declining.&quot; Abigail Marsh, a professor in the Department of Psychology at Georgetown University, told Southern Weekend reporters that some of her own research shows that , some forms of altruistic behavior are actually on the rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, she collaborated with researchers from the Department of Psychology at Harvard University and other institutions to conduct a summary analysis of survey data on altruistic behavior in a large number of countries. The results found that a country’s altruistic behavior is related to the subjective happiness of local people. There is a positive correlation. When the material resources and cultural value of a place support people from both objective and subjective conditions, and people feel happier, altruistic behavior will also increase. Moreover, the more individualistic values ​​prevail in places, the greater this effect will be. obvious. Relevant research was published in Psychological Science, and similar conclusions were also included in the latest edition of the 2023 World Happiness Report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some data suggest that altruistic behavior, especially toward distant strangers, generally increases over time. This may be because happiness increases, and as happiness increases Altruistic behavior appears to be increasing as well. These studies also show that around the world, where subjective well-being is higher, there are also higher levels of various altruistic and generous behaviors, such as being more likely to donate to charity and volunteer. Serve, help strangers, donate blood, donate organs and bone marrow, and treat animals humanely.&quot; Of course, ethics is more than selflessness and generosity, but these are important components of ethics, Abigail Marsh explains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The findings of the latest research highlight this paradox about morality. On the one hand, human society has been developing in terms of material and spiritual culture, and there is no reasonable explanation for the continued decline in morality. On the other hand, there are differences in the level of development, cultural traditions, and people&#39;s happiness in various places. Under such circumstances, the widespread moral decay is even more unreasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After analysis, Columbia University psychologist Adam M. Mastroianni and Harvard University psychology professor Daniel T. Gilbert, who participated in the latest study, believe , two common psychological laws may explain this strange social phenomenon. One is an attention bias and the other is a memory bias. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Psychological biases that are prone to occur&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A large number of psychological studies have found that humans are fascinated by negative information about others and always tend to search for and pay attention to negative information. It&#39;s such a good thing that negative information in the mass media has received more attention. This creates an attention bias. When recalling past events, people tend to forget those bad experiences and are more likely to remember some good memories, showing a memory bias. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, when people look at the current society, they may pay more attention to the dark side of society, including immoral people and things. When comparing the past, it is easier to remember the good people and good deeds and forget the immoral behavior, thus feeling that the world is deteriorating and people&#39;s hearts are not as old as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to verify the influence of these two psychological effects, the researchers also changed the participants&#39; attention through experiments, asking them to focus on familiar people such as family and friends in their social circle. The results were obvious. Double answer. People believe that the moral level of people in society as a whole is declining, but the moral level of their acquaintances and relatives has not only not declined, but has improved. Similarly, when people put aside the influence of memory bias and compared two eras that they had never experienced, the phenomenon of moral decline also disappeared. Generally speaking, people believe that the moral decay of society begins when they are born. These different answers are indeed intriguing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that there are still some limitations to the latest research, including inaccuracies in historical data measurements. The combined effect of attention and memory biases is only an explanation that the latest research attempts to give, and it is not enough to scientifically prove the reason behind the phenomenon of moral turpitude illusion. People all over the world, both ancient and modern, lament the deterioration of society. There may be other reasons behind this social phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, some scientists have indeed given slightly different explanations before. Researchers from the Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences at the University of California, Santa Barbara believe that personal characteristics play an important role in this phenomenon. In real life, a considerable part of the scenes of lamenting the deterioration of society and moral decline are caused by the elders blaming the younger ones. In the eyes of these elders, today&#39;s children are incomparable to them in the past and have lost many beautiful moral qualities. Research has found that in such accusations, elders can easily form a series of biased opinions based on personal characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, if you are good at something, you will be more likely to focus on other people&#39;s shortcomings in this aspect; if you have advantages or preferences in a certain aspect, you will assume that everyone was like this when you were a child. This self-centered attention bias and memory bias may have given rise to the impression that &quot;one generation is inferior to the other&quot;. In this impression, the shortcomings of young people are so glaring, and the qualities that everyone in the older generation has now been lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Difficulties in changing moral behavior&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;These discussions on moral changes also reflect the complexity of moral issues themselves. In 2019, Jenae M. Neiderhiser, a professor in the Department of Psychology at Pennsylvania State University, and others analyzed the moral development of children in a large number of families and found that moral quality is not entirely determined by the upbringing environment, but rather There are also genetic influences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study, which lasted for nearly ten years, focused on two moral indicators: social responsibility in adolescents and responsibility in early adulthood. Because it also included twins of all types and brothers and sisters in recombined families, it was possible to compare genetics and The role of environmental factors in moral development. Research shows that genetic factors and the upbringing environment provided by parents jointly shape children&#39;s moral character in the early stages of adolescent growth, but after adulthood, the role of parental upbringing weakens. Relevant research was published in Behavior Genetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Professor Abigail Marsh, who has long studied altruistic behavior, moral behavior also has a physiological basis. Compared with the law of survival of the fittest driven by selfishness, altruists are willing to help others even if their own interests are harmed. This is a unique problem from the perspective of evolutionary theory. Abigail Marsh and others have used magnetic resonance imaging to study the brains of a group of extraordinary altruists and found that these people who are willing to donate kidneys to strangers can be identified by characteristics such as an increase in the size of the right amygdala. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People often refer to these extraordinary altruists who are willing to risk themselves to help others as &#39;patron saints&#39; or &#39;saints.&#39; But our research suggests that biological phenomena may help explain why some People engage in extraordinary altruistic behavior. This may be because they have specific neurological and cognitive characteristics that make them more concerned about the well-being of others than the average person.&quot; Abigail, who is also a professor in the Interdisciplinary Program in Neuroscience at Georgetown University Marsh told Southern Weekend reporters that morality is fundamentally about weighing the consequences of oneself and others in behavior, and a series of studies have shown that there are biological differences behind some people choosing to value the happiness of others more. &quot;The brain is designed to learn and adapt. In general, I believe that people help others based on their true values ​​and that they genuinely care about the well-being of others. If people generally become more selfless over time, then It must be because we have learned to value the happiness of others more. What we don’t quite understand, however, is how to increase the importance one attaches to the happiness of others in some targeted way.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This It also means that understanding and changing moral behavior itself may be more difficult than the common delusion of moral decay. More importantly, for the real society, if people in a society have formed a consensus of moral decay and believe that the social moral level is declining, then both the direction of public policy and the development of interpersonal behavior will have a negative impact. produce a negative impact. After all, a society with a declining moral level contains the motivation to restore tradition and return to the past in the public arena, which may trigger a series of socially regressive behaviors. And once people believe that the world is in decline, the way of interpersonal communication may also develop in the direction of mutual distrust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many psychological surveys have found that because they underestimate the kindness of strangers, people are more hesitant to ask strangers for help, and they are less afraid to take the initiative to say hello to strangers. This interpersonal environment of mutual distrust has greatly affected people&#39;s happiness and sense of belonging to society. The illusion of a declining social moral level may be one of the reasons for this phenomenon. What’s even more frightening is that people are often very sensitive to changes in social norms and behavioral norms. Once they make a mistake in judgment, it may lead to truly unethical behavior in the subtle process. These highlight the significance of a correct understanding of this illusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[魏明毅：“像个男人”的要求如何伤害男人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/OPKkXxVazmd4ofE5r7XLw1SjL9BW1KszkfaehUff.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/OPKkXxVazmd4ofE5r7XLw1SjL9BW1 KszkfaehUff. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wei Mingyi, writer and psychological counselor, has been engaged in psychological counseling and supervision for decades. Author of &quot;Silent Worker: Days and Nights at the Dock&quot; and &quot;Reflections of Suffering: Field Notes of a Suffering Worker&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 At 11:20 in the morning at the end of August, 53-year-old Taiwanese psychological counselor Wei Mingyi appeared in the video, an hour later than the agreed time. She quickly apologized and explained that when she was helping colleagues at the placement agency in class in the morning, a child with visual limitations suddenly picked up a fruit knife, and she delayed the interview while dealing with this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I told the child that you must have encountered something. Please tell the teacher and we will discuss it together. Put down the knife first, and then we can talk about it.&quot; The crisis was quickly resolved. Every once in a while, Wei Mingyi will go to the resettlement agency to teach colleagues to help children who have been improperly disciplined by their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her new book &quot;Reflections of Suffering: Field Memos of a Suffering Worker&quot; published in March 2023 &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot;)&lt;/span>;Some chapters are also about this kind of children, &quot;They may not be very smart and have great difficulty solving problems. I don&#39;t look at them from the perspective of illness. Usually, People will interact with the outside world in a worse way after being treated inappropriately by the people around them. As long as they are treated in an appropriate way, they can return to their original appearance.&quot; Wei Mingyi sat in front of the screen and talked about this again Eyes red. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was probably the inertial outlet behind years of emotional labor. She was not surprised that she shed tears. In 2016, she completed her field record at the Keelung Pier, &quot;Silent Workers: Days and Nights at the Pier&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (the simplified Chinese version will be published in 2022) &lt;/span>;, she would cry when participating in new book sharing and interviews, &quot;I vaguely feel that I am suffering. I still like to work, but why is the heavy feeling still very big.&quot; When she repeatedly talks about the suffering of others, suffering also becomes Her own. The publishing house later simply prepared the paper for her in advance, &quot;because she knew Mingyi would cry in the next scene.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a last resort, she turned down all job offers and flew to a strange country to walk every day. &quot;At that time Only walking makes me comfortable.&quot; Day after day, she found that the suffering she witnessed in the anthropological field gradually became her flesh and blood, which happened to be an opportunity for her to write her second book &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot; is a collection of her more than 20 years of work experience in psychological counseling and social supervision. In it, she writes about her brother who killed his sister due to a dispute over a game, and how she gave birth to a son who had incest with his father and was killed by his family. She happily accepts underage girls, violent women, and men who kill their wives... It has been seven years since her last book was published. During this period, she was still working as a psychological counselor and was used to the continuous daily consultation. I hope that my busy work can alleviate some of the suffering in society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Wei Mingyi’s account:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Even though a large group of people want to do things well, the suffering has not been alleviated&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The so-called appropriate way to treat a child is to go back to the child himself and understand who he is, how he sees the world, and how he thinks. But in a place with high competition and little regard for children&#39;s human rights, this can easily be overlooked. Many inappropriate interactions and parenting stem from parents who do not view their children as human beings with free will, and such children are unlikely to be healthy. We need to know: Children are not extensions of adults. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because there are so many things worth reminding, I often say when I teach parents in Taiwan: If you remember Don&#39;t live too much, just remember not to do anything you regret. Don&#39;t use your words to say hurtful things. We look forward to changing others, but when our eyes look at others, it is easy to forget how we face others. If you want your children to respect you, you must first practice respecting your children. I often wonder, is what I am doing now the same as what I teach others? I remind myself in this way: I have to be a consistent person, otherwise I will be very conflicted internally. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Part of my current job is to provide regular training to parents and institutional colleagues. Reservations usually begin in October of the previous year and are then booked throughout the year. I work 25 days a month and go to two different places every day. When I encounter some special suicide cases, I will be added temporarily. The work is intensive, but I don&#39;t think it&#39;s self-exploitation. If I can do something, I will try to do it as much as possible. It was only in the past two or three years that I discovered that even though a large group of people seriously wanted to do things well, the suffering was not alleviated. The work of a psychological counselor is like doing back-end first aid. No matter how much time I give, the consultation can&#39;t be completed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What&#39;s the problem? If the social structure is relatively healthy and cares about life, suffering will not arise so quickly. In the past few years, I wonder if I can go to the frontier and do some primary prevention work, such as writing a book - to organize the things I have seen over the years into words, so that more people can start to have the opportunity before they get worse. Reflecting on the important role that individuals play in the social structure, the entire social structure and cultural situation may have the potential to change. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These ideas are certainly related to my anthropological training. &quot;The Silent Worker&quot; was a big turning point in my life. Like most people, I used to be quite individualistic and believed that destiny was in the hands of individuals. Facing the general environment, psychology emphasizes adapting through awareness and adjustment. However, from the perspective of anthropology and my field experience in Keelung, I discovered that many things cannot be conquered by man. People are not that great. The role played by the entire social structure and cultural situation is like air that appears around us and affects our lives, but we may not be aware of it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under the value of &quot;like a man&quot;, men are also victims&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;The Silent Worker&quot; was originally a very marginal piece of writing, but the response it aroused was beyond my expectation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2009, as a graduate student in anthropology, I went to Keelung Pier to do fieldwork. During my eight months in the field, I experienced culture shock. After working as a psychological counselor for more than ten years, I thought I knew a lot about Taiwanese workers and their situation. However, when I went to the field, I found that my knowledge was limited. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past, whether it was my work or living environment, &quot;like a man&quot; required men to behave tough. , showing their masculinity. In comparison, women seem to be devalued and in a relatively weak position. But in the field I discovered that this gender label has two sides. &quot;Like a Man&quot; frames a daily ideal, allowing men to act in it, think about how to shape themselves to become a &quot;valuable&quot; man, and constantly evaluate whether they are like an (ideal) man. They have to tread a line and if they fall outside of that line they are not recognized and respected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On the contrary, women seem not to be expected, but they also grow resilience from the trampling of life, This resilience is more evident in older women. For men who were recognized in their young adulthood, their lives almost plummeted when they failed to meet the mainstream value expectations of society. This is also the reason why the suicide rate of men in Keelung is much higher than that of women. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Keelung&#39;s suicide-seeking data ranks among the top two in Taiwan all year round. Suicide is a word that workers often mention in private, but they are reluctant to talk about it in the field. In addition to feeling shameful, the more common reason is: they have no way of understanding. I usually don’t ask my group of dock friends directly if they have any experience of cheating, but if they have heard of or encountered it. Almost everyone will tell me that they have experienced such a thing at some distance or near. Regarding the men around them who have experienced and heard about men who have died suddenly, the most common expression they express is &quot;I&#39;m just fine as usual, I don&#39;t see anything wrong with it.&quot; These responses reminded me of reporter Wang Jialong’s desire to “speak” and “be heard.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​afternoon in the field, Wang Jialong, as usual, said in a local voice that he would take me to try it Authentic snacks that only Keelung people know. But based on previous experiences, I knew he wanted to say something, and he always used food as the excuse. He first talked about how he was careful not to blurt out in front of his current girlfriend that his specialty was actually taught by his ex-girlfriend, and then said that he had some things that he never knew who he could tell:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;外面交的，刚开始是打电话听你的声音就好，接着要见到你的人，再来就要你留下来过夜；后来不是要你的钱，是要你的人。那时候我老婆和女朋友都闹自杀，割腕、吃安眠药，我自己也吃过。当时觉得事情全部搅在一起，像是码头民营化，我都不知道未来到底会怎么样，每天想每天头痛。结果有一天刑事组打电话给我，说我女朋友从我们一起住的大楼跳下来。人家一个好好的人在我们家变成这样，别人听起来也许会觉得我好像很行，可是我自己知道，是悲剧收场。 （王家龙原话）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;所以你看，旁人不知悉王家龙寻短过，都觉得他交很多女朋友很厉害。这些事他没人可以讲，因为不能展露自己柔弱的那面，他必须维护自己的尊严。当整个社会强调男尊女卑，男性要“像个男人”的时候，男性的苦难也根植于这一价值体系中。这些是我先前没意识到的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IzZQAXNo5QvBSgbB0M1rfpEv44vXH3YGKZqwUaJw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;677&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IzZQAXNo5QvBSgbB0M1rfpEv44vXH3YGKZqwUaJw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;在茶店仔，他们作为人被看见&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;心理咨询师和研究者的角色其实很不同。跑田野的时候，每当我有话想跟对方讲，我都会问自己现在究竟是谁、站在怎样的角度开口讲话。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我的一位老师说过，想为田野做点事情当然没有问题，但必须在清楚了解田野到底发生了什么之后。有时候我们想帮助别人，很可能因为还不够了解导致介入太过粗野。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;所以码头工人抱怨我不懂的时候，我不会不舒服。在码头呆了两个多月后，一位报道人说，魏小姐你天天跟我们在候工室谈，没有晒太阳，也没有在半夜候过工，你不会知道我们的辛苦，问出来的东西会贴近我们的真实情况吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我就说好，隔天半夜跟着他一起去码头，一直坚持到田野结束。这是田野里的“一道门”。凌晨出现在码头的那天我知道自己被他认可了，虽然我还是不懂，但我想要理解他们的世界，而不是站在一个很远很舒适的位置上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;跟这群码头工人跑了几个月后，我发现自己搜集的资料缺了女性这块。那时码头工人去“茶店仔”的机会已经不多，但这仍是他们很常聊到的话题。尽管2009年早过了码头工人所说基隆最热闹的时期，但走在港口市街，清茶馆、茶店仔、卡拉OK这类休闲娱乐场所散落各处。它们与紧邻铁轨的红灯户（性产业区域）连接成基隆港城1990年代末前最人声鼎沸的地区。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这里距离码头不到一公里，码头工人日常聚集于此。以茶店仔为例，男人们不只在里面闲聊消磨时间、等候船只，屋里每间小的屏蔽空间也是他们联结各层关系、协调工作的地方。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;茶店仔的劳工大多是经济有困难的外地女性——多为配偶或自身的赌债，或者上一代累积下来的经济困顿。她们只身或手牵幼子迁入这座陌生港城，成为茶室里称不上青春的“阿姨仔”（女性服务员）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我第一次踏进茶店仔是和李正德（报道人之一）一起。进门后，只见里头亮着一盏桌灯，灯光映照着柜台里一位低着头的女士，李正德随行的朋友一进门便对着她喊“阿姨仔”。后者从柜台里抬起了头，愣了一两秒钟后笑着回应：“唉，阿亮，你来啦。”被阿亮唤作“阿姨仔”的陈女士留着长波浪卷发、薄施脂粉，约60岁。简单寒暄后，陈女士带我们上楼梯，帮我们点菜，分别和三人简单聊些话。短短十几分钟里，她像是不经意却关注了每个人，没有人在对话中遭冷落或被遗忘。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有人吐露一些不快，有人在敬酒碰杯时得到慰藉。我在当中体会到的并非动情、激素之类的暧昧流动，而是码头男人被催化出的浓度极高的情感往来，以及阿姨仔在那样一个小房间里展现出的对屋内所有人的关照。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这种被关照和看见的感觉是码头工人无法从家庭中获得的。他们忙碌一天回家后，被期待有个丈夫的样子：把家用带回家，看护小孩。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/V3qL8sq2s98Jfb7nY1pP0mpnkOOxcPYK0OOZVUmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/V3qL8sq2s98Jfb7nY1pP0mpnkOOxcPYK0OOZVUmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;基隆，一位渔民骑着单车经过码头停泊的渔船&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们假想一个场景：妻子一天在家做了许多家务很疲惫，接到老师电话说孩子在学校调皮捣蛋，孩子放学回家后还带回一张待缴费清单，她却发现钱不够了。这时，丈夫下班回家，她首先想到的肯定是钱不够，有没有办法给我钱，她可能也希望丈夫可以去管教一下小孩，无暇顾及丈夫脸上的疲惫神色。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;丈夫和妻子的关系本来就隐含了一些责任和义务，而码头工人与阿姨仔的社会关系完全不同，他们去茶店没有责任要承担，只要享受被照顾就好。这也是伴文化在码头工人中盛行的原因。男性一旦结了婚，就会被很单薄地认为是丈夫和父亲的角色，他们作为人的角色只有在茶店仔这样的空间才被复原。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;所有的结局都是未完待续&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;谈到茶店仔的码头工人也都会提到红灯户，但他们会强调自己比较常去的是茶店仔。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;码头工人去茶店仔与阿姨仔聊天，会认为彼此是平等的，没有涉及性。即使二者后来发展为浪漫关系和性关系，但在他们心里，阿姨仔与红灯户的女性截然不同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这种区分其实是受儒家文化影响，也就是说，一个人是通过自己的身体（在儒家文化里是被极度贬抑的）还是劳力来换取金钱，有着高低之分，她们是泾渭分明的两种阶级。而作为消费者，他们去茶店仔会被视作经济资本很足，可是如果拿钱去红灯户，则“沦为”相对没有能力的人——需要直接通过金钱才能得到性关系。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这种区分不仅针对女性，也针对他们自己。比如我作为一个女性的研究生，他们跟我讲话的方式与跟阿姨仔也不一样。我对他们来说是读书人，作为女性的性别被淡化了。他们和我聊天时会配合我的用字遣词，会从方言转换成普通话，也从不抽烟。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1990年代末，随着国际航线的快速转移，国际货船相继离开基隆港口。在民营公司的削价竞争下，码头的装卸工人与货柜车司机成为跨境企业宣称的“薄利”时代的直接承受者。大部分工人被迫离开码头，留在码头上的工人薪资削减大半。这不仅意味着他们经济条件的改变，更重塑了他们原来群聚式的工作空间。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6mG5MbmwjFb10YpfsU1dKX8xixRgScScZdRAHAxc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6mG5MbmwjFb10YpfsU1dKX8xixRgScScZdRAHAxc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;基隆港的货柜场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;伴随着下岗潮，码头工人被赶回家庭。可漫长的时间里，伴文化早已将码头工人拉离家庭，当他们在底层时代回归，发现仅存无话可说的家庭晚餐气氛、子女对父亲早年缺席的指责，以及因父亲无法再给予充足金钱而来的争吵冲突。他们昔日的活动空间也被当地政府开发打造成海洋广场，以吸引更多游客。他们因自身形象不符合国际观光意象，而被驱逐出可见的公共空间。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;让人难过的是，他们往往把滑落归咎于自身。当一个人的苦难来自社会结构，却被视作是个人的问题时，他可能会动弹不了，有很多自责。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2016年，《静寂工人》在台湾出版后，许多读者说很好看，觉得码头工人的故事很凄惨。听到这些评价我也在反思，读者看的还是故事，怎样连接我们与码头工人身上发生的事？因此我写《受苦的倒影》时转换了笔触，分析性很强，我不想做卖故事的人。今年《受苦的倒影》出版后，读者说读得很痛苦，我说这就对了，因为痛苦才是人生的真相。也有不少读者问我，我们的受苦看起来都与整个大环境有关，我们怎么办？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不要忘记，社会结构再大，也是由众多个人组成的。如果我不认为个人是有力量的，我不会推掉所有工作去写书。即使我们现在做的事符合社会文化期待的样子，只要我们的意识清楚，假以时日，你可以逆向而行。只要人的自由意志还在，就没有被收编，没有稀里糊涂地成为自己不喜欢的样子。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果你最近有机会来基隆，你会发现观光客常去的海洋广场有了极具地方特色的街头艺人，他们唱的歌也是码头工人会听的歌。到了傍晚，大家就坐在广场上看海听歌。海洋广场本来被规划成一个很中产的地方，但地方的人改写了它的用途。所以啊，就像我在《受苦的倒影》里写的，所有的结局都是未完待续。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（部分内容引自《静寂工人》和《受苦的倒影》。感谢陈美伊对本文的帮助。参考资料：《镜周刊》。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深圳一安居房被指总造价1亿，未完工已提取10亿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;奥一新闻从人民网“领导留言板”留意到，9月中旬，多名网友反映称，位于龙华区的天和北苑项目建设进度缓慢，楼体未按照施工计划全部封顶。同时存在建设资金超额提取问题，主体建设总资金是1.041亿元，实际未完工就已经提取了10亿元，恳请有关部门介入调查，将资金纳入监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，龙华区住房和建设局和深圳市住房和建设局通过上述平台作出回应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，天和北苑项目位于深圳市龙华区福城街道龙观大道与石清大道交叉口。项目住宅全部为安居型商品房，一共3栋塔楼。预计交付使用时间为2025年6月30日前。配售均价27250元/㎡。开发商为深圳市栢恒商贸有限公司，隶属远洋集团旗下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/b863e53bd47586c3b7f6a8b9613d52ae.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/b863e53bd47586c3b7f6a8b9613d52ae.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;公开资料&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;问题一：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;楼体未按照施工计划全部封顶&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月14日，有网友表示，天和北苑项目施工进度缓慢，截至当天3栋塔楼未封顶。“按施工计划反馈7月底可以实现北苑3个单元全部封顶，但施工进度一直在拖延。经保障署沟通反馈8月31日可以封顶，但是又一次没有完成封顶，开发商一直在磨洋工，最新反馈是9月20日全部封顶。”该网友补充说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从其他网友提供的“天和北苑施工及验收计划表”可见，主体结构开始施工时间为2023年6月14日，完工时间为8月30日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f8027eefc4c09c6b8e5213a9a52890f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;547&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f8027eefc4c09c6b8e5213a9a52890f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月3日，深圳市住房和建设局就网友反映的问题回应称，“市住房建设局已约谈建设单位项目负责人和企业负责人，并发函督办，要求建设单位增加人力、物力、财力投入，精心组织施工，加快施工进度，确保按时交楼。天和北苑已于9月19日封顶。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d31cc51ff48fe0f45eab59ed59b9e5a4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d31cc51ff48fe0f45eab59ed59b9e5a4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;问题二：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;建设资金超额提取&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月14日-15日，多名网友集中反映称，天和北苑项目存建设资金超额提取问题。主体建设总资金是1.041亿元，实际未完工就已经提取了10亿元，恳请有关部门介入调查，将资金纳入监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0a9589e082888d0fe44d261b2319625e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0a9589e082888d0fe44d261b2319625e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;网友附上的工程概况图显示，该项目工程总造价为1.041亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fcb9152d01206ad3f516ceb8900b188c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fcb9152d01206ad3f516ceb8900b188c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，9月22日，龙华区住房和建设局表示，“经了解，天和北苑项目资金监管协议由建设单位、银行、监理单位三方签署，按照三方签署的协议及相关规定，由银行、监理单位监督预售资金的使用。为了响应业主诉求，做好项目资金的监管工作，我局已责令开发企业将预售款资金账户纳入行政监管范围，开发企业表示同意并予以配合。由于银行配合度较低，我局已发函要求监管银行配合将项目预售资金账户纳入行政监管范围，同时将相关情况告知市住建局，协助推动预售资金账户纳入行政监管工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;龙华区住房和建设局称，“下一步，我局将加强与市住建局和银行沟通协调，尽快将天和北苑项目预售款资金账户纳入行政监管范围，严格监督开发企业专款专用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/566e782610518e8fb7de969a4e843741.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/566e782610518e8fb7de969a4e843741.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月3日，深圳市住房和建设局回应称，“关于预售资金使用监管问题，市住房建设局已要求龙华区住房和建设局对已使用资金情况进行核查，并加强预售资金的监管工作，确保资金正常使用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0d163bf84be799d03fac6abebe1c9b64.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0d163bf84be799d03fac6abebe1c9b64.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;奥一新闻综合自人民网“领导留言板”、深圳市住房和建设局&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘玉栋痛批男篮“软骨头”“没血性”：赛场是社会的映像]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258174]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，篮球名宿刘玉栋在接受专访时，对男篮场上表现提出了尖锐批评：“他们不肯努力，条件这么好，不肯努力。上去都是软骨头，一点精气神都没有”“展现不出来他的血性一面，就是平时养成习惯了”“这个男人应该去干的，你必须去战斗，你当个男人都缩手缩脚，你不像个男人在战斗”，引发了不少共鸣与讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是不是运动员的收入高了、训练条件好了，反而失去了斗志与锐气？显然，两者不必然相关，也不乏顶级运动员收入更高、训练条件更好，照样斗志昂扬，这种情形甚至更常见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一种可能的解释是激励机制。如果运动员的水平并不出众，与国际水平比有显著差距，但由于国内球迷的热捧以及在此基础上商业代言就可以得到高收入，那对运动员来说，继续努力的边际收益就很小了，赛场上能交差就行了，何必拼死相搏？反之，如果运动员只有在赛场有出众表现才能拿到高薪，那么他就有很强的动机去努力，把自己的最大潜能发挥出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，除了激励之外，作为运动员，内驱力也很重要，甚至更重要。要把一件事做好，仅仅靠名利之类的激励是不够的，你必须觉得做好这件事是有内在意义的，你有强烈的动机去做成它，支撑这一切的是你个人的内在禀赋：你得有旺盛的生命力，有血性、有勇气、有斗志，有荣誉感，有自内而外的场，灵魂强健而放光，一言以蔽之，你得有强大的精神内核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，要做成一件事，方法论或技术路径是第二位的，做成这件事的动机或内驱力才是第一位的。有内驱力，你才不会觉得努力有什么辛苦，才会全身心投入，一步步企近目标。反之，你要是需要外界或外人的强力推动才去做这件事，你的内在动力是不足的，既不会对自己设置高目标，也不会有心思精益求精，只会得过且过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种旺盛的生命力或内驱力或勇气，经常被称为“阳刚之气”。整个社会期待男性身上能拥有这些特质，所谓“像个男人”。但这并不意味着，勇气或“阳刚之气”只有男人才有，撒切尔夫人与董明珠就是这类女性的典范。其实，无论男女，无论身处哪个时代、哪个国度，一个人要取得成就，个人最重要的特质就是要有勇气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观赏体育，人们希望从健儿赛场挥洒汗水的拼搏中感受到速度与力量之美，感受到勇气与血性，见证对人类自身极限的挑战与突破。花钱花时间看赛事的人希望得到的是这个。运动员不能提供这个，就是对消费者/支持者的亏欠。应该在这个意义上看待刘玉栋对男篮的批评，说到底刘玉栋当初明白自己要做什么，一直明白大众从运动员身上期待什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在某种程度上说，赛场是社会的映像。大众对勇气或“阳刚之气”有一个长期讨论。讨论针对的现象是：现在的孩子似乎越来越脆弱，男孩越来越缺乏“阳刚之气”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;精神脆弱不是好事。孩子不能承受一点挫折，如何成长为合格的成年人？这导致诸多孩子长大后“幼态延续”，没有成年人应有的精神状态。男孩缺乏“阳刚之气”也不是好事。不能一边觉得男性阴柔一些没什么大不了的，一边又希望男性见到不义能挺身而出。也不能一边觉得孩子必须“听话”“乖”，一边又希望他们长大后有强健的精神内核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大家看到了“消失的课间十分钟”，这诚然是诸多因素造成的，多方都有责任。也不难发现，此举主要考量是杜绝孩子在学校面临的各种风险。这种做法及其教育观是非常成问题的，孩子课间不能下楼、不能去操场，大多数时间困在教室里，这与孩子爱自由、爱玩耍的天性是相违背的，怎么可能让孩子在精神上健壮、鲁棒与反脆弱？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有，常见的计班级集体分，导致孩子对孩子监督、打分，一个孩子犯不大的事儿扣班级集体分，搞集体连坐与陪绑，制造师生、孩子与孩子之间的对立。稍微有些个性的孩子会受到各种规训、压力与“打磨”。教育是为了把孩子的天赋最大地发挥出来，把好的精神品质与价值观激发出来，而不是一味规训与培养服从，令其精神脆弱萎靡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;读一读龚自珍《病梅馆记》：“梅以曲为美，直则无姿；以欹为美，正则无景；梅以疏为美，密则无态”，这是病态的审美观。 “斫其正，养其旁条；删其密，夭其稚枝；锄其直，遏其生气”，这是基于病态审美观的病态做法。不要把我们的孩子养成病梅。 “纵之顺之，毁其盆，悉埋于地，解其棕缚；以五年为期，必复之全之。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，赛场有问题，但恐怕不仅仅是赛场的问题；运动员有问题，但恐怕不仅仅是运动员的问题，其所折射的社会问题，更值得关切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[相似的人为什么会产生吸引力？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258164]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/LptLfvffb5ltkCpCuQ9EKoy47JeD9aGBVQcu2P5I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/LptLfvffb5ltkCpCuQ9EKoy47JeD9aGB VQcu2P5I. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Birds of a feather flock together, and people flock together. A large amount of research shows that similarity attracts a powerful rule in interpersonal communication. R. Matthew Montoya, a psychologist at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, has analyzed more than 300 related experiments and surveys, and the results show that the relationship between interpersonal attraction and similarity is very significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this association is not only reflected in the actual similarity, but also in the perceived similarity. That is to say, in social interaction, not only the objective degree of similarity will generate attraction between people, but also the subjective feeling of similarity will enhance interpersonal attraction. Therefore, even if two people have only a short relationship or even no interaction at all, as long as they feel that they are similar to each other, they may be attracted to each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, why does similarity attract? For a long time, psychologists did not agree on the mechanism behind this. Recently, researchers from institutions such as Boston University and Stanford University tried to explore the mechanism behind the similarity attraction effect through a series of experiments. Their findings suggest that the psychological laws of self-essentialist reasoning may lead to people being attracted to similar people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Imagination of essential fit&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Essentialist reasoning is actually very common in daily life. In addition to using &quot;nature is hard to change&quot; to predict a person&#39;s In addition to human development trends, people are also accustomed to making moral judgments by tracing the good and bad of their &quot;essence&quot; to comprehensively evaluate people&#39;s behaviors and motivations. In the process of essentializing everything around them, people will try to find the inherent unchangeable characteristics of a thing to define it, and at the same time, get rid of the illusion attached to it to recognize the essence of a thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, although wolves and dogs look very similar, a wolf is a wolf and a dog is a dog. There are essential differences. The behavior of a group of people may be very different and elusive, but through their occupation, community, region and other social attributes, the essentialist reasoning method will allow people to naturally deduce some essential attributes they share. In the process of essentializing the self, people will also unconsciously ask what kind of nature the true self has deep inside. When carrying out various social activities and facing complicated interpersonal relationships, this nature of the self will be revealed. Doctrine reasoning has become an important reference for people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through four sets of experiments involving more than 2,000 people, researchers believe that the reason why people are attracted to similar people can be roughly divided into two processes. First, people gain insight into some of their own essential characteristics based on the belief in self-essentialism, and then refer to these to define people with common attributes as people who are very similar to themselves. Secondly, use essentialist reasoning to project their other essential characteristics onto similar people, and form an overall impression of similar people through speculation, thereby strengthening their own understanding of the world. Relevant research was published in the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology in April 2023, providing a new explanation for revealing the laws of interpersonal communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first set of experiments, nearly a thousand participants were randomly assigned to some controversial social issue situations to learn their views on the death penalty, euthanasia, gun ownership and other issues. Subsequently, the researchers also introduced participants to a virtual character named Jamie through reading materials. To some, Jamie has similar views on social issues, while to others, Jamie has very different views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers then measured people&#39;s essentialist beliefs about themselves, as well as indicators of Jamie&#39;s attraction to them. As expected, the more participants endorsed self-essentialism, the belief that there are constant qualities within themselves, the more likely they were to be attracted to Jamie, who shared similar views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In subsequent experiments, the researchers continued to verify some of the key nodes and found that even small similarities are enough to generate attraction. However, if the essentialist concept and broader similarities are severed, The correlation between people makes people believe that the similarity of opinions has nothing to do with the essential fit, and the effect of similarity attraction is weakened. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Complex Attraction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the reasoning of attraction through similarity, the process of inferring commonalities against the essential characteristics of individuals is extremely critical. . People usually start from the similarities they find between the two parties and imagine in their minds that they have more things in common with each other, thereby feeling stronger attraction to the other party. But when the researchers told participants that this cognitive style was inaccurate and could not form reliable perceptions of others, the effect of similar attraction also weakened. These controlled experiments further suggest that some of the thought processes associated with self-essentialist reasoning may be causally related to the similarity attraction effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The phenomenon of attraction through similarity has been discovered for a long time, but previously, psychologists mainly explained this phenomenon from the aspects of motivation and cognition. For example, one view is that there are people with similar ideas to oneself, which actually validates one&#39;s own ideas and satisfies people&#39;s pursuit of a consistent worldview, which will obviously generate positive emotions and attraction. There is also the idea that shared characteristics and perspectives mean greater support, which is positive information for a social goal. The findings of the latest research mean that the unconscious cognitive mode of self-essentialist reasoning may be a major mechanism behind similar attraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human social relationships are complex. Some people attract much attention and are attractive to many people, while most people have limited attraction. Psychologist Matthew Montoya once proposed a two-dimensional model for understanding interpersonal attraction, which focuses on assessing a person&#39;s abilities and willingness. Interpersonal attraction to another person is strong if one person has both the ability to promote the needs and goals of another and the underlying willingness to do so. And these attractions are usually expressed through some behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, some researchers summarized some attraction-related behaviors through survey analysis, such as eye contact, smiling, imitation, etc. These behaviors caused by interpersonal attraction also contribute to trust. of construction. Compared with indirect behaviors such as eye contact, smiling, and imitation, more direct behaviors such as physical contact and conversation have a stronger relationship with perceived attraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, once a threat is anticipated and the possibility of rejection is high, people&#39;s behavior will be affected even if they feel emotionally attracted. The research, published in the Psychological Bulletin, provides some insights into concrete understanding of attraction. Compared with these external manifestations, the latest research focuses on the source of attraction, providing a mechanistic explanation for the phenomenon of similar attraction. It should be noted that the latest research also has some obvious limitations that may affect the understanding of related phenomena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the attraction measured in the study belongs to the first impression. Although the first impression is also very important when meeting by chance, going on a blind date, or communicating with strangers on social software, it is not important in daily life. In subsequent interactions, there are actually a large number of different social situations, and attraction may not only depend on the first impression. Furthermore, the social and cultural background of the psychological experiment participants in the study lacks sufficient representation, and the differences in the idea of ​​self-essentialism in different cultural environments may affect relevant conclusions. These need to be confirmed by more research in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is not easy to understand others&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In modern society, contact with strangers is a normal part of life. In some interactions, a few words of conversation can give you the feeling of feeling like old friends and cherishing each other at first sight. According to the latest research, this warm experience of finding similar people is likely based on self-essentialist beliefs and related reasoning processes. For society as a whole, this discovery may help people understand some of the bad phenomena related to human nature in modern society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, people can infer or even assert the nature of others based on only a small amount of observations, and divide people around them into different camps based on similarities and differences in only some of their views, creating group antagonisms. In these cases, whether it is the attraction caused by similarity or the distance caused by dissimilarity, it affects people&#39;s ability to obtain the real situation and is not conducive to making accurate judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of researchers, understanding others is an extremely difficult thing compared to understanding oneself, and new research findings mean that people are always accustomed to using their own feelings to understand others through speculation and other methods. People, and this way of reasoning obviously has certain problems. Although the similarity attraction effect allows people to see themselves in other similar people, get to know themselves better, and build their own social circle, this way of thinking of labeling people based on initial impressions can also easily exclude some people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In public life, this may lead to people fighting against dissimilar people because of less important differences such as interests and hobbies, and in business decisions, an overly self-centered approach to decision-making can also lead to The efficiency becomes lower. Using self as a reference to judge who is more like you and who is not like you. This model of attraction generation may seem simple, but it may not be an effective way. &amp;nbsp;Nevertheless, the attraction generated by similarity as a guide for relationships appears to be an important rule in the development of romantic relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Youyou Wu, a researcher at the Department of Psychology at the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom, and others pointed out in a study in Psychological Science that relationships between partners and friends Not only will they be more similar in terms of region, age, education level, concepts and IQ, but they will also be more similar in personality. However, Wu Youyou also explained to Southern Weekend reporters that it is not yet certain whether people are together because they are similar, or whether they become similar because they are together. There is also insufficient evidence whether attracting people together by similarity is more conducive to the development of relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A rational view of the attraction effect&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, even so, some other phenomena found in romantic relationship research still support the similar attraction effect to a certain extent. Influence. For example, it is common for friends to develop into lovers. A survey by psychologists at the University of Victoria showed that nearly two-thirds of people said they had or currently had the experience of developing a relationship with a friend. In the friend stage, they not only spend a lot of time together to understand and communicate with each other, but also have many similarities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, psychological research based on German society also found that people tend to find another person with similar personality traits to their ex even after breaking up. Relevant research was published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS) in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yoobin Park, a scientist at the Department of Psychology at the University of Toronto who participated in this study, told Southern Weekend reporters that repeatedly looking for similar people as romantic partners has both advantages and disadvantages. The place. The good thing is that people already have relatively familiar strategies for getting along with similar people, and can make better use of their past social experiences to deal with future challenges. But the bad thing is that once you encounter similar obstacles that you can&#39;t get over, the ending of the relationship may be similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These phenomena that may be related to the similar attraction effect remind people that they should treat the attraction caused by similar partial characteristics rationally. From age, height to income and job, many people are accustomed to using quantitative comparison as a reference for finding a partner or even a marriage partner, in order to find someone with very similar material conditions. However, large-scale studies on partnerships have shown that indicators such as a partner’s personal characteristics are generally less effective in predicting the quality of a partnership. Whether it is a high degree of education or a high income, it does not mean that you will definitely have a high-quality partner in the future. relation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most predictive indicator is the relationship itself, which is the dynamic feelings partners have toward each other during their long-term relationship, such as trust, mutual appreciation, perceived commitment of the other party, etc. Combined with the findings of the latest research, these dynamic relationship situations are not achieved by similar attraction like love at first sight, but rely on the continuous maintenance of the relationship during the long-term relationship between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, it is worth noting that the similarity attraction effect is not only reflected in romantic relationships, acquaintance relationships or even real relationships. As a more common psychological phenomenon, between strangers who pass by each other, Even between people who interact only virtually, attraction can arise because of similarity. The relationships between these strangers, and the corresponding risks, also deserve attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[议长麦卡锡被本党议员罢免，共和党发生了什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258176]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/8JIm3FXtzEvK6ZLvOiGThdO8pWzxcRrYA4R56xdj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/8JIm3FXtzEvK6ZLvOiGThdO8pW zxcRrYA4R56xdj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, the U.S. Capitol in Washington, Florida Republican Congressman Martin Gates talks with reporters after the House Republican meeting &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 3, 2023, United States A shocking scene unfolded in the House of Representatives. Proposed by Republican Congressman Matt Gaetz, a majority of 216 votes to 210 voted to remove House Speaker McCarthy, who will only take office in January 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since taking office on January 7, 2023, McCarthy has only been in office for 269 days, making him the speaker of the House of Representatives with the third shortest term in U.S. history. This is also the first time in the history of American politics that a speaker has been removed from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, the reason for McCarthy&#39;s removal was that he cooperated with the Democratic Party to pass a temporary federal funding bill before the October 1st deadline, which prevented the Biden government from shutting down and angered those in the party. Far right. The current hijacking of the entire party by far-right groups within the Republican Party has made it difficult to bridge the gap between the traditional right-wing represented by McCarthy and the far-right represented by Matt Gaetz. This may be the deeper reason for McCarthy&#39;s removal. reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/fSmZnF5IF2nbIUzWskCfOK3Ocmsj83OZ0yP5eAmv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/fSmZnF5IF2nbIUzWskCfOK3Ocmsj83OZ0yP5eAmv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, in Washington, the United States, former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi (front right) and Representative Maxine Waters (front left) Conversation outside the Capitol &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The budget is the trigger&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;November 2022 In the mid-term elections, the Republican Party won 222 seats in the 435-member House of Representatives, becoming the majority party, but with only a slim 9-vote advantage. This made the far-right &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; (Freedom Caucus) with only a dozen people a &quot; The key few forces are those who fail to succeed but fail to succeed. In January 2023, Rep. Kevin McCarthy, a Republican from California, was elected speaker after a record 15 rounds of voting. The reason was the constant vetoes from members of the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot;, of which Matt Gaetz was the leader. member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, McCarthy gave them major concessions, including allowing anyone in the party to bring a motion to remove the speaker—a new rule that McCarthy later backed down to, which he himself had nodded to months earlier. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of the matter is the budget. The U.S. government&#39;s new fiscal year begins on October 1 of each year. Presumably to allow time for protracted bargaining in Congress, the Biden administration had already proposed a budget for the next year as early as March 2023, but the two parties have been unable to reach a consensus in the next six months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The far-right Republican Party hopes to significantly reduce government spending to alleviate the serious fiscal deficit and ease the debt crisis. At the same time, it will spend more money on domestic issues such as the border refugee crisis and reduce aid to Ukraine; the Democratic Party believes that Assisting vulnerable groups is the government&#39;s obligation. Supporting specific industries through tax cuts and subsidies is to maintain the competitiveness of the United States. Aiding Ukraine is an international obligation of the United States as a global leader, so it opposes spending cuts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The matter was delayed until the end of September. If there is no budget, according to the law, after October 1, except for a few essential public services, all other government workers must take unpaid leave. This is commonly known as a &quot;government shutdown.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1976, there have been 21 government shutdowns in the U.S. government, most of which occurred during Clinton’s term as president. The then Speaker of the House of Representatives, Gingrich, caused many artificial shutdowns because of his disagreement with Clinton. The &quot;Government Shutdown&quot; incident; the longest government shutdown occurred from 2018 to 2019, when then-President Trump and congressional Democrats were in a stalemate over the construction of a border wall, resulting in the failure of the government budget to pass. That government shutdown lasted 35 days, running through the Christmas and New Year holidays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that the government shutdown was about to happen again, House Speaker McCarthy pushed the House to propose an interim budget a few hours before the deadline. It was finally passed by a vote of 335 to 91, and then the bill was passed in the Senate It also passed by a vote of 88 to 9 to extend federal funding until November 17. The crisis of government shutdown is temporarily lifted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although McCarthy deliberately excluded the content of aid to Ukraine in the interim budget to appease the extreme right wing of the party, the latter did not appreciate it. They found it difficult to accept McCarthy&#39;s betrayal of cooperating with the Democratic Party, so they left it to the Democratic Party. Gates took the lead in proposing a motion to remove McCarthy from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although McCarthy was dismissed by the Republican Party because he cooperated with the Democratic Party to pass the interim budget, politics is realistic. The Democratic Party does not intend to help McCarthy retain the speakership, and they also have a high degree of distrust in McCarthy, including McCarthy. Not long ago, he also led the launch of the impeachment investigation against President Biden, and tried his best to please former President Trump after the Capitol riots on January 6, 2021, etc. The 2024 election is only a year and a month away, and Democrats are probably happy to see their competitors in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the centrists of the Democratic Party had communicated with McCarthy in private before, but McCarthy did not show goodwill and put forward clear exchange conditions, so the Democratic Party had no incentive to come to the rescue. Jeffries, the Democratic leader of the House of Representatives, said in a letter to all his fellow Democratic members: &quot;It is the responsibility of Republican members to end the Republican civil war in the House of Representatives.&quot; As a result, all Democrats voted in support of the recall bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, of the 216 votes supporting the recall, Gates and his Republican comrades only contributed 8 votes, while the Democrats contributed 208 votes; the Republicans voted 210 against; among the 7 who did not vote, 4 Democrats and 3 Republicans. Gates&#39; political revenge, combined with the Democratic Party&#39;s political calculations, ended McCarthy&#39;s career as speaker just 72 hours after the interim budget was passed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;McCarthy finally accepted the vote results with a smile and said he did not regret cooperating with the Democratic Party. It should be said that he demonstrated the sense of responsibility and responsibility of a veteran politician. This kind of cross-party cooperation based on national interests was originally very common and considered a fine tradition of American politics. However, in recent years, due to the deepening of partisan differences, it has become It&#39;s becoming increasingly rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/XFX5oFvfLliIzWgZhhS2xlPhyLL09UnsUHmUNjrL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/XFX5oFvfLliIzWgZhhS2xlPhyLL09UnsUHmUNjrL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, live footage of the House of Representatives voting to remove Republican House Speaker McCarthy in Washington, D.C.&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who is Matt Gates? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Matt Gaetz, who took the lead in calling for McCarthy’s removal, was born in May 1982. He has been a federal representative representing Florida’s first district since 2016 and has been re-elected three times. His father, Don Gates, was also a politician and served as president of the Florida Senate. Matt Gates had previously been implicated in a scandal of paying for sex with underage girls, but the Justice Department finally decided not to prosecute in February 2023 after a two-year investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matt Gaetz represents a congressional district with conservative values. Since running for the House of Representatives for the first time in 2016, he has led by more than 30% in a total of 4 elections. , there is no need to worry that his idiosyncratic behavior will have a negative impact on his political career. Voters obviously like his ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of philosophy, Gates actually has a lot in common with the left wing of the Democratic Party, such as opposing foreign military intervention, supporting the decriminalization of certain recreational drugs such as marijuana, and calling for stronger supervision of large technology companies. ,etc. But Gates is often classified as far-right, more because of his combative style than ideology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ostensible reason why Gates is so obsessed with removing McCarthy is that McCarthy worked with Democrats to pass an interim budget, allowing the government to avoid a shutdown, which is beneficial to the Biden administration. However, the underlying reason is still personal political interests: Gates is a fan of Trump, and his political methods are similar to Trump&#39;s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Trump, Gates is good at turning politics into entertainment and using social media and Fox News to build momentum for himself and attract voters to maintain his personal attention. For example, in October 2019, during the impeachment investigation of Trump by House Democrats, he led more than a dozen Republican congressmen into the sensitive information isolation room of Congress and live broadcast the confidential impeachment hearing content to social media; the new coronavirus epidemic During this period, he once wore a gas mask to work; then in early 2023, he repeatedly vetoed McCarthy as speaker and removed McCarthy this time. US media speculated that the congressman is considering running for Florida governor in 2026: due to term limits, current Governor Ron DeSantis will not be able to seek re-election by then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rise of Matt Gates, like the rise of Trump, has a profound social background: the development of globalization has caused a large number of blue-collar jobs in the United States to be transferred overseas, and the knowledge economy has made educational attainment and success Directly linked, and less than 30% of American adults have college diplomas. As a result, the biggest losers in this process are the white middle class who have graduated from high school but do not have college diplomas. Most of these people have gathered under the Republican Party. They are opposed to globalization. dissatisfaction, and the conservative attitude of never giving in on moral issues such as anti-abortion, anti-same-sex marriage, and gun rights, are all reflected in the Republican Party&#39;s platform and style of conduct. Whether it is Trump’s vulgarity or the sex trafficking scandals in which he and Matt Gaetz have been accused, their supporters regard it as a manifestation of “masculinity” and are harmless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Gates alone cannot remove McCarthy. Seven other Republican congressmen agreed to remove him, most of them from the far-right &quot;Liberty Caucus&quot; in the party. This caucus originated from the &quot;Tea Party&quot; wave in 2010. Its members were very dissatisfied with the inability of the mainstream Republican Party to check the strict fiscal discipline adopted by the Obama administration. They believed that it was necessary to establish a new organization to exert the collective influence of right-wing members and appeal to the Republican leadership. Put pressure on them to restore the tradition of &quot;financial prudence&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; is an alternative within the Republican Party, which is dedicated to having trouble with the top leaders of the party. In 2015, the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; believed that then-House Speaker John Boehner was not tough enough on Obama and forced the former to resign; in 2017, the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; tried to launch a challenge to then-Speaker Paul Ryan through its internal members, and the latter Forced to resign early to avoid humiliation. From this point of view, McCarthy&#39;s recall motion by members of the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; is just another flashback of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/jTeN4HMXqVTUgmkklGWfCpYGB0UlzieGHvaBdrTB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/jTeN4HMXqVTUgmkklGWfCpYGB0UlzieGHvaBdrTB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, in Washington, the United States, McCarthy spoke to media reporters. The U.S. House of Representatives voted on the same day to pass a resolution to remove Republican House Speaker McCarthy &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pelosi was Impact&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After McCarthy steps down, according to the rules of procedure of the House of Representatives, the position of acting speaker will be filled by a person recommended by the former speaker himself. At the top of McCarthy&#39;s recommendation list is North Carolina Rep. Patrick McHenry, a close McCarthy ally who has begun serving as acting speaker, responsible for convening next week to re-elect the speaker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;McHenry was furious at McCarthy&#39;s ouster. In retaliation, he emailed former Speaker Pelosi to vacate her office in the Capitol, and also expelled former House Majority Leader Steny Hoyer, a Democrat. According to tradition, these two people have previously retained their offices in Congress. It is rumored that the vacated office of Pelosi will be allocated to McCarthy. Staff had already started cleaning the office on the evening of the 3rd. After McCarthy was dismissed, she criticized Pelosi for &quot;treachery&quot; and accused her of failing to stand up for him at critical moments as promised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Republican side, some congressmen held up their mobile phones at the voting site to show fundraising text messages sent by Matt Gaetz’s camp, criticizing him for attracting attention just to attract more donations and sponsorships. Some pro-Republican parties The media also criticized Gates as a liar and a reputation seeker. The other seven Republican congressmen who voted after Matt Gaetz were either wildly criticized on TV shows or threatened to cut off financial support from the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/9p8cYVY2tWBoprZUp6JWOxCvqeDGTVR91WztDJWZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/9p8cYVY2tWBoprZUp6JWOxCvqeDGTVR91WztDJWZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 1, 2023, pedestrians walked past the &quot;Treasury Debt Clock&quot; in New York, USA. The National Debt Clock updates the total U.S. public debt in real time and shows how much each American household has to shoulder. On the same day, the U.S. Senate voted and approved the bill related to the agreement reached by Democratic President Biden and Republican Speaker of the House of Representatives McCarthy on raising the federal government’s debt ceiling, thereby avoiding a U.S. debt default&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua Social/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The canvassing for votes for the new speaker has already begun. McCarthy has stated that he will not participate in the competition again. Currently, Scalise, the majority leader of the House of Representatives and the second-ranking figure in the Republican Party, , House Republican Whip Emmer and House Judiciary Committee Chairman Jordan are already eager to try. Former President Trump was not directly involved in this infighting, but there are still Republican congressmen who have expressed support for him to become the speaker. Legally, there is no requirement to be a member to serve as speaker, but according to the House Republican rules of procedure, anyone accused of a felony cannot hold a leadership position, and Trump has been sued four times, regardless of whether he admits it or not, and the charges are Basically all are felonies. Moreover, Trump’s goal is to be re-elected as president, so it is impossible for him to really go into this muddy water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But no matter who ultimately takes office, it will not change the political reality that the Republican Party is kidnapped by a small number of far-right parties. His future situation will not be much better than McCarthy&#39;s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老师疲于应付举报：关键在重建家校间的应有权利边界丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258120]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, Beiqing Daily published an in-depth report on &quot;The hidden worries behind teachers&#39; extensive reporting: trapped in self-certification&quot; , choosing to &quot;lie down&quot; caused concern and discussion, and many voices expressing sympathy for the teacher appeared on social media. However, how long can such voices last, and to what extent can they be translated into actual support for teachers’ work? The answer is probably not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report listed various unreasonable reports: a teacher was reported for responding to parents’ messages three hours late; a teacher wore a skirt and was complained by a student’s mother as “not like a serious person”; A teacher was reported by his parents as being inexperienced and unable to lead the class on the second day after he joined the job... It makes people feel that some parents use their strong energy to find faults and act wantonly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report quoted some teachers as saying that the problem stems from &quot;preparation and hostility permeating the gap between schools and families, and the vicious news of many teachers beating children has exacerbated distrust. Some people will take advantage of this emotion.&quot; , to satisfy their own demands.” This explanation is that: some teachers have lost their ethics → public opinion added fuel to the flames → an atmosphere of &quot;precaution and hostility&quot; → some parents took the opportunity to cause trouble and profit. This chain is reasonable but incomplete, and there is still room to further dig into the root of the problem. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the home-school relationship has gone through a good period. This stage was roughly before the rise of the mobile Internet and smartphones. The main setting for teachers and parents to meet was the parent-teacher conference, which was a rare meeting on weekdays and they were contacted by phone for important matters. This brings a benefit: &quot;Distance creates beauty.&quot; Teachers and parents do their own thing without interfering with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technological progress is a double-edged sword. WeChat home-school groups and DingTalk groups have been established one after another, allowing teachers and parents to communicate in real time. On the surface, it improves the communication efficiency between the two parties, but it also invisibly removes the traditional barriers and boundaries between home and school. From then on, school teachers asked parents to check in here and pick up the relay in that group. Most parents did not dare not cooperate even if they were busy at work, for fear that their children would be treated differently in school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this transformation process, the teacher is only an executor and cannot help himself. But as more and more educational and non-educational tasks are carried out, and are pressed down to parents through the school-teacher chain, schools have become grassroots governance organizations, woven into every family with children. As the saying goes, &quot;little hands hold big hands&quot;, children become the leverage to control parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the surface obedience and harmony, tensions between the school, teachers and parents are constantly accumulating. This tension stems from parents’ dissatisfaction with being subject to various controls and disciplines by the school. If they cannot find an exit here, they will find an exit there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the distrust between home and school is also deepening. In addition to the &quot;vicious news about many teachers beating children&quot; mentioned in the report, it also includes the fact that the canteen in the school is sold at a sky-high price and students are not allowed to do it themselves. Bringing in bedding, all the controversies surrounding prepared meals, etc. all contribute to and exacerbate parent distrust of schools. These may not all be the school&#39;s responsibility. Teachers often take the blame, but parents will (only) point the finger directly at the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there is no need to excuse some parents. It is true that some parents are troubled and unreasonable. At this time, the response and actions of the school and its authorities are very critical: if you adhere to the principles and do not get along with each other, although you may face a lot of pressure at a time, you can avoid forming bad incentives for other parents and avoid long-term consequences. , also established justice. Unfortunately, they often adopt a calm attitude. Any complaints from parents are taken seriously. &quot;I would rather submit to teachers than to parents&quot; is based on the same mentality. In this way, can there not be too many unreasonable complaints from parents? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beiqing Daily reported: A 12345 operator in Chengdu believed that some reports were &quot;outrageous&quot; in her opinion. A parent called to complain because he was dissatisfied with the teacher&#39;s arrangement of his children&#39;s seats in the back row of the classroom. The parent admitted that although the teacher had clearly stated that seats were arranged according to height, he still felt it was unreasonable because those sitting in the back were He is a poor student. Although his child is tall, he studies well and should not be arranged like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report said: In a certain boarding school, more than a hundred students called 12345 at the same time to report that the school ended too late. In response to such reports, the school tried giving Friday afternoons off, but parent dissatisfaction immediately came back. They received reports from parents one after another from 12345 and the mayor’s mailbox: The school did not have classes in the afternoon. What kind of handling method caused the school to suffer back-and-forth attacks from parents and students? I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s not just a problem between parents and students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary to solve the problem of massive unreasonable complaints from parents and students against the school, to eliminate the &quot;preparation and hostility&quot; and distrust that pervades the home-school relationship, and to prevent teachers and schools from &quot;giving up&quot; because of this. &quot;The key to &quot;putting down the problem&quot; and &quot;laying it down&quot; is to re-establish the boundaries of rights between home and school, so that family education and school education can return to their respective places, and no longer make parents tired by assigning various non-educational tasks to parents through schools and teachers. If you can&#39;t cope with it, don&#39;t treat your children as fat sheep and try to make money from them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, when 12345 faces complaints with the education authorities, it should adhere to principles, reason, and right from wrong. It should not force teachers to prove their innocence, not give in to bad parents, and establish decent values. Stimulate the good in human nature and restrain the evil in human nature. Only in this way can schools carry out educational activities normally and pass on good values ​​to children. Our children can continue to improve in knowledge, morality and values, and inspire and demonstrate their conscience and talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[札达土林：远古“宫堡”，藏西秘境丨眼睛在旅游⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257607]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>