<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[94岁“包租婆”邝肖卿成中国女首富 房地产仍是女企业家财富首要来源]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260670]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Kwong Siu-ching, the wife of 94-year-old Sun Hung Kai Properties (0016.HK) founder Guo Desheng, invested 72 billion yuan in Net worth, she became the richest woman in China for the first time; Yang Huiyan, the &quot;tenth consecutive winner&quot; as the richest woman, dropped to fifth place; nearly 60 of the 50 female entrepreneurs on the list started from scratch, and real estate is still their largest source of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, Hurun Research Institute and the Business Women&#39;s Growth and Social Platform Hong Kong Beauty Club jointly released the &quot;2023 Hong Kong Beauty Club·Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List&quot;) as shown above information. This is the eighteenth consecutive time that Hurun Research Institute has released this list, and the deadline for wealth calculation is September 1, 2023. Unlike the Hurun Rich List, the list of female entrepreneurs separately calculates the personal wealth of female entrepreneurs that can be separated from family wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;94-year-old &quot;No. 1 Tenant&quot; Kuang Xiaoqing became the richest woman in China&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the past 18 years, the threshold for the top 50 Chinese female entrepreneurs has increased from 500 million to 13.5 billion , increased nearly 30 times.&quot; Hurun Report, chairman and chief research officer of Hurun Report, said above. However, judging from the Hurun Report&#39;s overall list, the proportion of female entrepreneurs dropped by 1.3 percentage points to 25.4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List shows that 94-year-old Kuang Xiaoqing became the richest woman in China for the first time with a wealth of 72 billion yuan. She is also the sixth richest woman in China in the past 18 years on the Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List. The top five are Zhang Yin (three times) ), Yang Huiyan (ten times), Wu Yajun (twice), Zhou Qunfei (once), Chen Lihua (once). Wu Yajun, the founder of Longfor Real Estate, remains the richest self-made woman in China with 66.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3eaa8871e004d592302015eeabe4487e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3eaa8871e004d592302015eeabe4487e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258386&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;(Hurun Female Entrepreneurs List TOP10, Source: Hurun Report)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Kuang Xiaoqingsheng Born in Huashan Town, Huadu District, Guangdong Province in 1929, she is the wife of Hong Kong entrepreneur and founder of Sun Hung Kai Properties, Kwok Desheng, with a total wealth of 72 billion yuan. She is also the largest shareholder of Sun Hung Kai Properties. She is highly respected in the family and is the soul of Sun Hung Kai Properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Hung Kai Properties is one of the largest real estate developers in Hong Kong. According to data from Sun Hung Kai Properties in fiscal year 2023 (July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023), the company’s operating income was HK$71.2 billion. Net profit attributable to the parent company was HK$23.91 billion, with a net profit margin of 34.52%, a year-on-year increase of 2.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kuang Xiaoqing is known as &quot;China&#39;s No. 1 Housekeeper&quot;. Judging from the financial reports of Sun Hung Kai Properties in the past five years, property rental has always contributed the largest proportion of revenue, about one-third. Judging from the latest financial report, as of June 30, 2023, Sun Hung Kai Properties&#39; land bank in Hong Kong is approximately 58 million square feet (approximately 5.38 million square meters), of which more than 60% are diversified properties, most of which are used for Leasing and long-term investment bring considerable recurring income to the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hurun Report, Kuang Xiaoqing became the richest woman in China for the first time, mainly benefiting from the rise in the Hong Kong dollar exchange rate this year and company dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the rise in the Hong Kong dollar exchange rate, since the beginning of this year, the RMB exchange rate against the Hong Kong dollar has risen from around 0.8 to around 0.9, with a maximum of around 0.93. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the company&#39;s dividends, Flush shows that Sun Hung Kai Properties is one of the blue-chip stocks that have been purchased the most by domestic investors, with a cumulative cash distribution of HK$71.72 billion in the past five years. In fiscal year 2023 (July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023), the company will distribute cash twice, with an amount of HK$14.34 billion, and a dividend payout ratio of 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in the latest fiscal year (dividend payment date is November 16), Sun Hung Kai Properties paid a dividend of HK$3.7 per share, which was three times the dividend of the previous fiscal year. Kwong Xiaoqing personally holds less than 0.01% of Sun Hung Kai Properties, which is 25,020 shares. Kwong Xiaoqing and his immediate family members jointly hold 19.5% of Sun Hung Kai Properties&#39; shares, totaling 565 million shares. Based on a dividend payout of HK$3.7 per share, Kuang Xiaoqing’s personal shareholding and the shareholding jointly held with others will make a profit of approximately HK$2.091 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The ranking of &quot;Ten Crowns&quot; Yang Huiyan dropped to fifth place&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this list, another major focus is the substantial wealth of Yang Huiyan, who has won the title of the richest woman ten times. Shrunk, ranking fell to fifth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the changes in the Hurun Women Entrepreneurs list, Country Garden Chairman and Executive Director Yang Huiyan’s wealth has shrunk the most in 2023 compared to last year (27 billion yuan), ranking 5th with 48 billion yuan; followed by It is Cheng Xue, CEO of Haitian Flavor Industry, whose performance has declined due to the additive incident, and his wealth has shrunk by 16.5 billion yuan; and Zhao Yan, chairman of Bloomage International Investment Group, the &quot;Queen of Hyaluronic Acid&quot;, whose wealth has shrunk by 14.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in 1981, Yang Huiyan is the second daughter of Country Garden founder Yang Guoqiang. In 2005, Yang Huiyan returned to China after graduating from the Ohio State University majoring in marketing and logistics, and joined Country Garden as Yang Guoqiang&#39;s personal assistant and served as purchasing manager. She has held important positions in Country Garden Investment Center, Procurement Department, Human Resources Center, Digital Management Center and other departments. In March 2023, Yang Huiyan officially became the successor of the family business and served as the chairman of the board of directors of Country Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2007, Country Garden was listed in Hong Kong, and Yang Guoqiang transferred all his shares to Yang Huiyan. 26-year-old Yang Huiyan topped the 2007 Forbes rich list with $16.02 billion, and became China&#39;s new richest woman. In the 16 years from 2007 to 2022, Yang Huiyan aspired to be the richest woman in China ten times. It is worth noting that Yang Huiyan’s wealth has shrunk by nearly 60% year-on-year in 2022, but she still ranks first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/e2b3c063491daeb6cf2b77ab07539ef4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/e2b3c063491daeb6cf2b77ab07539ef4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258388&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Yang Huiyan aspired to be the richest woman in China ten times, source: Hurun Report)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Huiyan’s wealth has shrunk and Country Garden Crisis is closely related. In 2023, due to increasing uncertainty in the macro economy and real estate, Country Garden&#39;s debt has frequently shown red lights. &quot;Faced with the two-way tightening on the consumer side and the financing side, the group&#39;s liquidity is under unprecedented pressure.&quot; Country Garden said in its 2023 mid-term report. From Country Garden&#39;s annual and interim reports for the past five years, we can find that Country Garden&#39;s strategic goals have changed from prudent and pragmatic replenishment of high-quality land reserves to &quot;guaranteing the delivery of buildings&quot; and making every effort to arrange debt repayments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 30, 2023, Country Garden Services (6098.HK) announced that Yang Huiyan, the company’s controlling shareholder, non-executive director and chairman of the board of directors, donated RMB 64 million to Guoqiang Charity Foundation (Hong Kong) Co., Ltd. HK$100 million worth of stocks will be used for charity. But this move caused controversy in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List shows that the number of new female billionaires on the list is 8, which is the lowest in 18 years and 3 less than last year. Among the newcomers, the top one is Zhou Chaonan of Runze Technology, which is engaged in the big data center and computing infrastructure industry, with a wealth of 20 billion yuan; followed by Shu Ping, one of the founders of Haidilao, with a wealth of 18 billion yuan; and then Yulon of Taiwan. Car boss Yan Chen Lillian has a fortune of 16 billion yuan. Newcomers also include Ye Qiongjiu, director and deputy general manager of Tonghuashun, with a wealth of 13.5 billion yuan. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Nearly 60% of female entrepreneurs started from scratch. Real estate is still the largest source of wealth&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of wealth sources, nearly 60% of female entrepreneurs started from scratch, and nearly 40% inherited it. . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, the Hurun Female Entrepreneurs List shows that there are 34 self-made female entrepreneurs in 2023, accounting for 59%, which is basically the same as last year; 24 are not self-made, 2 fewer than last year position, accounting for 41%, compared with 43% last year. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-made female entrepreneurs mainly start their own businesses or start businesses with their husbands. For example, Wu Yajun of Longhu, Chen Lihua of Fuhua and Wang Laichun of Luxshare Precision, Fan Hongwei of Hengli, Guan Yamei of Tongwei and Pan Dong of Blue Moon, etc. Non-self-made female entrepreneurs, on the one hand, inherit wealth, such as Zong Fuli of Wahaha, Yang Huiyan of Country Garden, etc.; on the other hand, they are the widows of entrepreneurs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of age, the average age of self-made female entrepreneurs is about 59 years old, and the average age of successors is 54 years old. &amp;nbsp;The wealth of the 7 post-80s generation on the list is all inherited. They are: Yang Huiyan, 42, from Country Garden, Yan Xin, 40, from Sushang, Zong Fuli, 41, from Wahaha, and 40-year-old Dali Foods. Xu Yangyang, 36-year-old Ruan Zeyun of Flat Glass, 39-year-old Luo Yi of Hesheng and 35-year-old Jin Junmiao of JA Solar Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the industries in which female entrepreneurs work, real estate is still the largest source of wealth for female entrepreneurs, accounting for 17% of the people on the list, the same as last year; energy and consumer goods tied for second, accounting for 13%; food and beverage, non-ferrous metals, health and other industries all increased, while the chemical industry and investment industry declined. &lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f7cacbc072e830304eff09b6e09ce447.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f7cacbc072e830304eff09b6e09ce447.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;258387&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Distribution of industries engaged in by male and female entrepreneurs, source: Hurun Report)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &quot;Relatively speaking, Chinese female entrepreneurs are better in the real estate and consumer goods industries, while male entrepreneurs are better in the food and beverage, media, entertainment and automobile industries.&quot; Hurun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Hurun said: &quot;The female entrepreneurs who performed well this year mainly come from the Apple industry chain, including Zhou Qunfei of Lens Technology and Zeng Fangqin of Lingyi Intelligent Manufacturing; secondly, thanks to the post-epidemic The entertainment and catering industries are recovering, such as He Chaoqiong of MGM China, Li Haiyan and Shu Ping of Haidilao; the third is Ma Dongmin of Baidu, etc. driven by ChatGPT.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育不是功名利禄的“油门”，而是做人做事的“把门”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The third uncle came to me to complain, saying that he had helped his cousin pay off a debt of 10,000 yuan, and then sighed as usual &quot;It&#39;s better for you to study&quot;, the word &quot;ah&quot; is a long sigh, which contains many thoughts of the third uncle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going back twenty years, Uncle San’s attitude towards studying was not a “good” one, but his own judgment. He is a capable person, with great strength and a sharp mind. He can handle all kinds of farm work with ease. He can adapt immediately to work in the city. From skills to interpersonal skills, he can handle it with ease, making money and gaining popularity. Therefore, his family has the most prosperous life in the village and can be called the &quot;richest man&quot;. He is a person who &quot;stamps his feet in the east of the village and trembles in the west of the village&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He often said that he had not studied for a few days and had not received any advanced education, but his life was better than others. Go to school and study, and ultimately you have to live a good life. As long as you live a good life, don&#39;t care too much whether you get an education or not. Therefore, when other families were worried about their children&#39;s poor grades, the third uncle was very indifferent and didn&#39;t care about his cousin&#39;s grades. He didn&#39;t praise his cousin if he got 100 points in the exam, and he didn&#39;t beat or scold him if he failed. He told his son, How many points you earn is not a matter of ability, the key is being able to make money. Uncle San has this attitude towards school education and instills this into family education - as long as you master the ability to make money, you will win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My third uncle is very disdainful of those families that invest too much money and energy in education, especially my family. Although the tuition fees at that time were not high, they were still a big burden for rural families. Before the start of each school year, many parents were worried about the tuition fees, and it would even take a long time after the school started to raise the funds. Uncle San didn’t understand the idea of ​​collecting tuition fees. Since he had no money, why would he still go to school? He went to elementary school, middle school, and university. After graduation, if he didn’t find a job or the job was not good, he would have to invest more than ten dollars. Wasn’t the money spent in the year wasted? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I performed abnormally in the high school entrance examination and felt that I could not reach the admission score. I was very depressed and lost. My relatives and friends could not come to comfort me. Only my third uncle came over and told me, don’t worry. In the worst case, I would learn to repair cars with him. Studying is easy and you can make money. It made me dumbfounded. Fortunately, it was just a false alarm. A month later, I successfully entered high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to differences in educational concepts, the relationship between father and third uncle is very delicate. The two brothers often quarrel over this difference when eating and drinking, and break up on bad terms. My father was firm at first and kept encouraging me, saying that I should study even though I was selling everything. But as his cousin entered the society, his father&#39;s heart was shaken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the neglect of his third uncle, his cousin barely survived until he graduated from junior high school. Then he refused to go to school and wanted to go out to the city to try his luck. The third uncle expressed his support and entrusted him to a do-it-yourselfer. Relatives take care of business. The third uncle gave his cousin a sum of money and asked him to make the first pot of gold by himself. My cousin is not very old, but he has inherited the talents of his third uncle. Before he was 18 years old, he was already prosperous in the city, and at least he started taking money from the family. And I was still &quot;burning money&quot; in college at that time. Every time I came home for vacation, my father would always talk about the legend of my cousin getting rich, and his tone was full of admiration. Later, he gradually expressed his blame for my slow success in studying, from sighing to complaining, which made me afraid to appear at the same time as my cousin. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reversal occurred in my second year on the job. My cousin started to get into debt. He liked to make rapid progress in business. In addition, he entered the society at an early age and gained stubborn self-confidence. He turned a deaf ear to the old man&#39;s advice. Moving money here and there and negotiating in the west have become the norm, and we are gradually unable to make ends meet. At first, the third uncle felt that the family was rich and the loss was nothing. But when he realized that something was wrong, it was too late. The cousin’s debts spanned both black and white, including relatives and friends. He was unable to repay them, so he owed it to the stronger third uncle. On the head. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After going bankrupt, only one-tenth of the debt was paid. The third uncle, who has become a grandfather and enjoys his old age, decided to start over. He took up the craftsmanship of his youth and worked two or three jobs at the same time. He works hard and makes money to pay off his debts with amazing perseverance. Relatives&#39; debts, bank loans... one after another, all relied on him and his third aunt to support the repayment. The cousin, who was used to wallowing in money, couldn&#39;t accept the life without money. He just settled down after falling into debt. His parents had to bear the huge burden. Even his own son was taken care of by an old man while working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has been going on for ten years, and the debt has finally been repaid. I haven&#39;t changed much, I just keep going to and from get off work. The ones who have changed are my father and my third uncle. My father began to be grateful for his investment in education. Although I did not earn much money, I learned to be steady and not easy to &quot;learn bad things&quot;, and he believed in me more than before. The third uncle began to repeat, &quot;How good it is to study.&quot; Education costs money, but the money is worth spending, because those who study have a &quot;doorkeeper&quot; and something to pull them when doing things, and they will not keep &quot;stepping on the accelerator&quot;. &quot;, no matter what. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I gradually understood that although education is not a panacea, it may not be able to directly solve very real problems such as employment and making money. But nothing is possible without education. We often think of education and society as a cause-and-effect relationship. Education must be responsible for what we can do when we enter society, otherwise it will be useless. In fact, a major function of education is to be responsible for what you do not do when you enter society. You should not just focus on &quot;doing something&quot;, but also pay attention to &quot;doing something not to do.&quot; Through the words of the third uncle, I think that regardless of family education, school education, or social education, if you focus on using education as the &quot;gas pedal&quot; for profit, you will definitely lose control. In an increasingly &quot;fast&quot; era, education is needed as the &quot;brake&quot; role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a Changchun media person)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; 163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[千年造像被“毁容”，只为他们还个愿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260666]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 16:29:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, a cliff was excavated in Nanjiang County, Bazhong, Sichuan more than 1,400 years ago in the late Northern Wei Dynasty. The statues were defaced and vandalized, causing concern. After seeing the pictures, netizens lamented: &quot;It makes me want to cry. The protection of cultural relics has a long way to go.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The daubed statue is a new discovery in 2021&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Pictures posted by netizens show that the statue has been painted colorfully. The rosettes, clothes, headdresses, and utensils in the hands of some statues are painted in different colors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ffe3c063109a418dd2eedacb2e70eb9b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;773&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ffe3c063109a418dd2eedacb2e70eb9b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258373 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ff121ba98253a1dc0f5db6fc41a74a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ff121ba98253a1dc0f5db6fc41a74a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258371&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A cliff statue in Nanjiang County after it was daubed (top picture) and before it was daubed (bottom picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1ac7a7a97d55273821119a68f82869d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1ac7a7a97d55273821119a68f82869d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Relevant archaeological survey reports show that the statues here are newly discovered in 2021. In February 2022, the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau, the School of Archeology and Museum of Sichuan University, the Xi&#39;an Forest of Steles Museum and the Nanjiang County Cultural Relics Protection Research Center jointly conducted an investigation of the cliff statues. The subsequent report concluded that:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;Cliff statues were rarely excavated in the late Northern Wei Dynasty, and were continued in the early Tang &lt;span>;, Wu Zhou and middle and late Tang dynasties. The excavation date was early and the formation process was complicated. The entire natural stone package on the ground was excavated into a stele for the statue. The characteristic practice is an isolated example in Sichuan. These materials have very important academic value in completing the development sequence of Sichuan grottoes and revealing the Buddhist culture and art exchanges between Sichuan and the northern Central Plains.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bba7b257b7a0b0b11359cbf62d37a1f6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;740&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bba7b257b7a0b0b11359cbf62d37a1f6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f853a85bd792a1975d1d34c3a761dd02.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;688&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f853a85bd792a1975d1d34c3a761dd02.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After another local cliff statue was daubed (top picture) and before it was daubed (bottom picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; The cultural protection staff did not have time to stop it after discovering it&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter called the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau. A staff member said that the incident happened two days ago, and he went to stop it after discovering it through surveillance. &quot;Because it is in a barren mountain, they had already finished painting it when we arrived. The statue was discovered only two years ago and has not yet been included in the cultural protection unit. We have built a cultural relic shed and surveillance, but it is too far away.&quot; Inside the mountains, local protection capabilities are also limited. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff said that those who daubed the statues were all old men in their 70s and 80s, saying that they were &quot;clothing the Bodhisattva and fulfilling his vows.&quot; &quot;It is not easy for us to deal with it, we can only criticize and educate. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As to whether the statue can be restored to its original appearance, staff from the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau said that the paint used on the statue is mainly acrylic. Relevant experts have been invited to demonstrate, &quot;It should be possible to restore it, and we will Strengthen publicity and education on cultural relics protection, and also call on everyone to increase awareness of cultural relics protection through the media. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;Local report: The public security organs have intervened in the investigation&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the early morning of the 15th, the Nanjiang County Cultural Relics Protection Research Center issued a report on the &quot;Shifei River Cliff&quot; Report on the situation of &quot;the statues were painted&quot;:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 13, some of the cliff statues in Shifeihe County were painted, which aroused widespread concern among netizens. After preliminary investigation, in November On the 6th, Li Mouhua, a resident of Langzhong City, Sichuan Province, entrusted Wang Mouguo, a villager of Jinyin Village, Chixi Town, Nanjiang County, Bazhong City (Li Mouhua’s mother) to ask Yue Moubang, a villager of Shehongzhai, Gaota Town, to investigate Some of the cliff statues in Shifeihe were painted with the words &quot;dress to make a wish&quot;. After the incident, the local area immediately added protective measures to the site to prevent secondary damage caused by inappropriate behavior. At the same time, the public security organs are conducting investigations in accordance with the law.&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;On November 14, experts from the Sichuan Provincial Cultural Relics Bureau, the Institute of Cultural Relics and Archeology and the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau conducted on-site inspections and studied and formulated a protection and restoration plan. The Nanjiang County Cultural Relics Protection Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has Contact an institution with cultural relics appraisal qualifications to evaluate the value of the cliff statues and the losses caused by smearing. In the next step, our center will promptly announce the investigation, disposal and restoration status to the public.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;Some &quot;unpopular&quot; cultural relics are fading&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, due to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;grassroots cultural relics protection&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;power&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The quantity is relatively weak, and similar damage to cultural relics across the country&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is not uncommon.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the Forbidden City, the Summer Palace, and the Terracotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shi Huang’s Mausoleum In addition to other famous scenic spots, ancient tombs in the mountains and forests, the Great Wall in the wilderness, Buddhist caves on the cliffs... In places we can&#39;t see, some &quot;unpopular&quot; cultural relics are fading, weathering, collapsing, and disappearing.&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ce507c82b8b7fa9ff0ead260d16c3678.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1 ;&quot; width=&quot;696&quot; height=&quot;462&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ce507c82b8b7fa9ff0ead260d16c3678.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258379&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;B station UP owner @Heritage Jun was deeply touched by this. “In 2015, I visited nearly 20 ancient buildings in Shanxi, and most of them were dilapidated. Some wooden buildings in the Song and Yuan Dynasties had their entire roofs collapsed and their walls also collapsed. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;That’s when he decided to become a cultural relic sharing blogger. In the past 8 years, he visited more than 2,000 cultural relics and historic sites across the country and published more than 25,000 cultural relics Post.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/901a46703586733096a575be26dbe445.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;1244&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/901a46703586733096a575be26dbe445.png&quot; data-key =&quot;258380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In recent years, the country’s efforts to protect cultural relics have gradually increased. “I went to Shanxi again in the past two years and saw that the situation has improved a lot. As long as it is a &#39;national security unit&#39;, it has basically been restored and I can hardly recognize it anymore. &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;National Protection Units&quot;, that is, key cultural relics protection units in the country, are directly allocated by the State Administration of Cultural Heritage for protection and are the most intensive. However, 767,000 places in our country cannot be protected. Among the movable cultural relics, only 5,058 are protected by the state, less than 0.7%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those low-level cultural relics scattered in the countryside and mountains are more worrying.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the Great Wall of Shanxi was excavated. &lt;span>; Hot search: In order to &quot;take a shortcut&quot;, two workers used an excavator to dig a large gap in a section of the Ming Dynasty Great Wall.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/d29fd6d458b2e88c9451e89efef8ea9c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width= &quot;463&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/d29fd6d458b2e88c9451e89efef8ea9c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;The tragedy of the Ming Great Wall in Shanxi was not an accident. In 2018, when the blogger Heritage Jun was traveling in Dunhuang, on his way back to the city from Yangguan, he saw a private car running straight over a section of the Han Great Wall. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/c4dcf40358bb7a5ec5a2e99748948b4e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;788&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/c4dcf40358bb7a5ec5a2e99748948b4e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258381 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Many less popular cultural relics have experienced similar destruction. &quot;Zhu Zhanyun, a special researcher at the School of History and Cultural Heritage of Xiamen University, said that in recent years, there have been fewer large-scale and organized thefts of cultural relics, but there are still many &quot;unintentional losses&quot;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/290f9a466b3f682a9e94d2a596b97b72.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/290f9a466b3f682a9e94d2a596b97b72.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;A Tanhua Mansion in Qing Dynasty in Shanxi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;We can’t help but ask why these cultural relics that should be protected are Most of them cannot escape decline?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品还是毒品？女子网上转售父亲遗留止疼药一审判贩毒罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73519&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70321&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/847db34e88.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3217.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;In July 2023, Liao Hua was a patient Photos of drugs released by Yaozhuanqun. Pictures provided by interviewees&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/847db34e88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258309&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2023, Liao Hua Photos of medicines posted by patients’ medicine transfer group. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, Guangzhou woman Liao Hua (pseudonym) was pursued across provinces by Shandong police on suspicion of drug trafficking, which attracted attention. Liao Hua repeatedly stated that the analgesic drugs she resold for 260 yuan were left behind by her father after his death. With the idea of ​​saving and not wasting, she transferred the drugs among her patients, not knowing that they were &quot;drugs.&quot; &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Yangxin County Court of Shandong Province held in the first instance that Liao Hua violated national regulations on drug management and, for the purpose of profit, trafficked drugs controlled by national regulations. Psychotropic drugs that make humanoids addictive constitute the crime of drug trafficking. In the first instance, he was sentenced to two months&#39; detention, suspended for three months, and fined RMB 1,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua said that after the verdict of the first instance was announced, the more she thought about it, the more aggrieved she became. Previously, she only thought that she was violating laws and regulations by selling prescription drugs, but she did not expect that it would be a serious criminal charge such as &quot;drug trafficking&quot;. Since her job is administrative accounting, the criminal stain will greatly affect her career development. Liao Hua chose to appeal. At the end of October 2023, the second instance of the case was heard in Binzhou Intermediate Court, and no verdict has been announced yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, the judge in charge of the Binzhou Intermediate Court case told Southern Weekend reporters that the court will conduct an investigation in accordance with legal provisions, and the direction and progress of the investigation will be determined during the trial. It won&#39;t be announced until it&#39;s over. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Both drugs and drugs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua said that the drugs he sold were all leftovers taken by his father before his death. Liao Hua&#39;s father suffered from advanced rectal cancer. During the treatment, he often suffered fractures and suffered severe pain. The hospital prescribed many types of painkillers. After his father died of a serious illness, Liao Hua didn&#39;t know what to do with the leftover medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2023, Liao Hua entered a &quot;patients exchange residual medicine transfer group&quot; through the introduction of patients, and transferred his father&#39;s remaining 15 medicines to treat COVID-19, joint pain, etc. Put the medicines together, take photos and send them to the WeChat group. At that time, a person nicknamed &quot;Xiao Wang&quot; in the group quickly added Liao Hua and sent a private message to inquire about purchasing tramalin hydrochloride and telenine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua told Southern Weekend reporters that after the accident, she noticed that although people in the group often switched to drugs, most of them were anti-cancer and chemotherapy drugs, which were relatively small. Painkillers are less common. The three boxes of tramalin hydrochloride and two boxes of Telenine that she resold to Xiao Wang for 260 yuan were &quot;other narcotic drugs and psychotropic drugs controlled by the state that can induce humanoid addiction.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 14, 2023, after receiving the express delivery, Xiao Wang drove to the local police station, reporting that he had purchased the national drug online without a prescription. Controlled drugs, “These are narcotics and can also be regarded as drugs.” The police&#39;s transcript of their inquiry showed that Xiao Wang was a drug addict in Yangxin County, Shandong Province. He had &quot;skated on the ice&quot; (smoked methamphetamine) before and wanted to use these drugs as a substitute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Jianbin, a lawyer at Beijing Jingdu Law Firm who has long represented drug criminal cases, told Southern Weekend reporters that the national drug control targets include heroin, methamphetamine, marijuana and other traditional drugs. In addition, there is also a type of &quot;narcotic drugs&quot; that have both medicinal properties and drug properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Jianbin introduced that in judicial practice, to judge whether it is a &quot;drug&quot;, we must first check whether the substance is in the list of nationally controlled anesthetic drugs, that is, the national The latest &quot;Catalogue of Narcotic Drugs&quot;, &quot;Catalog of Psychotropic Drugs&quot; and &quot;Supplementary Catalog of Controlled Varieties of Non-Medicinal Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Drugs&quot; released by the Food and Drug Administration, the Ministry of Public Security and the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter checked and found that these lists are dynamically updated. For example, codeine in cough drops is an analgesic, but due to its addiction Sex, as early as 2000, there was an addiction to cough drops. Relevant departments have successively issued a series of regulations, requiring &quot;sales based on prescriptions&quot;, &quot;sales and purchases in appropriate amounts&quot; and &quot;monitoring of flows&quot;; in 2015, codeine-containing compound oral liquid preparations were included in the second category of psychotropic drug control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The tramalin hydrochloride resold by Liao Hua this time is a central analgesic, mostly used for various postoperative pain relief, cancer pain, labor pain, etc. treat. Excessive use can cause bradycardia, convulsions, respiratory depression and coma, and is addictive. In 2008, tramadol (including its salts, single preparations and possible isomers) was included in the Class II psychotropic drugs for control. However, tramadol’s compound preparations will only be included in the Class II psychotropic drugs on July 1, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tylenine (oxycodone tablets), another drug resold by Liao Hua, is a compound preparation of oxycodone and is also widely used clinically. Analgesic drugs were included in the management of Class II psychotropic drugs on September 1, 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After July 1, 2023, the nationally controlled varieties of anesthetic drugs and non-medicinal anesthetic drugs have reached 456 types and 2 entire categories (fentanyl, nicotine and synthetic cannabinoids). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Listed&quot; means that tramalin hydrochloride and oxycodone paracetamol have dual properties of drugs and drugs. &quot;The first is the nature of drugs,&quot; Tang Jianbin explained. The listing of these anesthetic drugs does not automatically equate to drugs. They will only become &quot;drugs&quot; if they flow into the illegal drug market or are smoked by drug addicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;2023 National Court Drug Crime Trial Work Conference Minutes&quot; (Kunming Conference Minutes) issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court on June 26, 2023, knowingly Criminals or drug addicts who smuggle or sell drugs and sell narcotic drugs or psychotropic drugs that are controlled by the state and have legal medical or other uses shall be convicted and punished for the crime of drug trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the minutes of the Kunming meeting, &quot;there is definite evidence to prove that for the purpose of treating diseases and other related purposes&quot;, those who privately operate anesthetic drugs with legal medical purposes are not allowed to Punished as a drug crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, whether Liao Hua still sold tramalin hydrochloride and paracetamol and oxycodone even though he knew that the other party was a drug addict has become the key to the case. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73518&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70320&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/15/3af0ad6d97.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3215.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Chat records between Liao Hua and drug buyers. Picture provided by the interviewee&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3af0ad6d97.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258310&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liao Hua’s chat history with drug buyers. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Is it &quot;fishing for law enforcement&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the process of purchasing drugs online, Xiao Wang once revealed that he was a drug addict. The chat records between the two parties show that Xiao Wang once said: &quot;I used to skate, but now I can&#39;t buy it. I use these medicines instead! I&#39;m still a little addicted now! It&#39;s too hard to quit.&quot; Liao Hua did not reply immediately, and Xiao Wang later mentioned To: &quot;I&#39;m not sick. I used to play music and smoke marijuana, but it&#39;s hard to find it now! Use this medicine to replace it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua argued, She didn’t know what “skating” meant, and her understanding of tramalin hydrochloride and telenine had always been limited to painkillers. She didn&#39;t pay attention to the words Xiao Wang said about addiction and difficulty in quitting.在寄出药品后，她还建议小王如果有疼痛，可以试一下中医的针灸，这是她此前照顾父亲时的止痛经验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;湖北今天律师事务所律师付成晨认为，该案的关键在于能否认定明知“毒品”。廖华上述说法可以作为辩护理由，但客观上廖华实施了贩卖“毒品”的行为，且其转卖的是父亲自己使用过的药，她对药效是十分清楚的，甚至可能在医生开药过程中对管制处方药性质有一定了解。要认定其“不明知”是毒品，还需看进一步的证据材料，以及法官的裁量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据廖华提供的另一份聊天记录，她还给一位已手术的胃癌患者转赠了芬太尼止疼贴，对方表示感谢。廖华称自己本意是病友互助，不是专门卖药。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而在该案案发一个月后，曾联系廖华买药的小王，再次在微信群中想要加转让药品的群友。廖华注意到，该群友转让的药物合照里也包含盐酸曲马林缓释片。她怀疑此人在“钓鱼”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;汤建彬分析，吸毒人员在转药群里购买替代药品时，主动表明自己吸毒的行为不大符合常理。而在本案中，这几句话恰恰构成了廖华犯贩毒罪的关键。需要考量这一做法是否有“犯意引诱”的嫌疑，即当事人本身没有这个犯罪意愿，特殊人员诱导其犯罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据昆明会议纪要，隐匿身份人员存在“犯意引诱”的情况下获得的证据材料应予以排除。排除上述证据后，在案证据达不到认定被引诱人有罪的证明标准的，应当依法作出证据不足、指控的犯罪不能成立的无罪判决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但目前，廖华质疑的“钓鱼执法”并无确切证据。在相关笔录中，举报人是主动开车到派出所报案，并未提及是警方线人等身份。南方周末记者数次联系小王，未获回复。 11月13日，阳信县公安局工作人员表示由于案件正在二审，相关信息不便透露。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;付成晨提醒，没有取得药品经营许可证，是不允许私下转卖药品的；转卖管制药品涉刑，转卖一般药品情节严重也涉刑，数额未达到刑事立案标准的，也会面临行政处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在病友群里，有人转发了廖华的案件报道后，群公告上写到：“各位病友、病友家属，止疼药国家严格管控，含有毒品成分，私自交易买卖，属于违法犯罪，轻者拘留取保候审，重者判刑，敬请大家遵纪守法！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[校准航向再出发——新华社五论中美关系如何重返正轨]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260645]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;应美国总统拜登邀请，国家主席习近平将于11月14日至17日赴美国旧金山举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。两国元首将就事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，以及事关世界和平与发展的重大问题深入沟通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;元首外交是中美关系的“指南针”和“定盘星”，中美各界和国际社会也因此对这次旧金山会晤倍加期待，期待中美关系在元首外交战略引领下尽快回到健康稳定发展的正轨。在此关键节点，新华社推出“推动中美关系回归正轨”系列评论报道，呼吁美方同中方相向而行，克服干扰、排除障碍、积累成果、营造氛围，共同推动中美关系重回健康稳定发展轨道。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;一论回归元首共识：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;重返巴厘岛、通往旧金山&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81189d3f04a246747fbb029002acbbe4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81189d3f04a246747fbb029002acbbe4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让对稳定和发展中美关系的期待成为现实，需要中美相向而行。行动路线图也很清楚，就是重返巴厘岛、通往旧金山，把中美元首巴厘岛会晤共识真正落到实处，扩大双边关系积极议程，减少消极议程，为旧金山会晤创造条件、排除干扰、积累成果、营造氛围。毫无疑问，重返巴厘岛、通往旧金山的路程，不会是一马平川，不能靠“自动驾驶”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有重返巴厘岛，才能通往旧金山，重返巴厘岛是基础、是前提。最近一段时间，中美关系之所以出现一些积极迹象，正是因为对两国元首巴厘岛会晤共识的跟进和落实得到了提速。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希望美方在近期中美互动中所展现的积极姿态不是政治算计和战术投机，所作出的口头承诺能够成为具体政策和实质行动。也希望美方能够不被国内党争羁绊和政客私利左右，同中方共同行动、持久努力，让中美关系中的好消息、好势头不断累积，推动两国关系真正稳下来、好起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为世界上最重要的一组双边关系，中美关系牵动着人类的前途命运。巴厘岛会晤时，习近平主席强调应从把握世界大势的高度看待和处理中美关系。世界大势是什么？是和平、发展、合作、共赢成为时代潮流，任何国家或国家集团都再也无法单独主宰世界事务；是全球南方全面开启“大觉醒”时代，人类社会加速进入多极化世界；是人类越来越成为你中有我、我中有你的命运共同体，同时也面临着诸多全球性挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;二论校准关系航向：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;中美必须找到正确的相处之道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ac4418ea1390505b89c25926818c887.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ac4418ea1390505b89c25926818c887.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为两个世界大国，中美能否确立正确相处之道，攸关世界和平发展和人类前途命运。一段时间以来，两国关系的变化牵动世界人心，其跌宕起伏的曲折历程，一方面表明了中美关系的严峻性和复杂性，确立大国正确相处之道并非易事，其间会受到各种因素的影响扰动；另一方面，双方最终排除干扰达成“重返巴厘岛”“面向旧金山”的重要共识也再一次证明，只要本着对历史、对世界、对人民负责的态度，对彼此树立正确理性的认知，对改善关系抱持最大诚意，中美关系就能朝着积极的方向发展，真正实现稳下来、好起来，回归健康稳定发展的正轨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于中美如何正确相处，习近平主席早已给出了明确答案，那就是相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢。这三大原则，是审视中美关系半个多世纪风云跌宕得出的重要论断，是当今时代大国之间彼此交往的正确之道，是保证中美两艘巨轮不偏航、不失速、不相撞的重要航标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有尊重，就谈不上信任；没有信任，就无法避免冲突，也谈不上真正的合作。这是中美交往积累的重要经验，也是双边关系重回正轨的基本前提。守住和平底线，这是中美必须做出的正确抉择。合作共赢是中美关系半个世纪以来的真实叙事，也是双方应当继续争取的共同目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从巴厘岛一路走来，中美关系回暖来之不易，值得倍加珍惜。面向旧金山，双方应从过往汲取现实的启迪，汇聚相向而行的力量，共同探索构建新时代的中美关系，创造中美两国的美好未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;三论正确定义关系：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;竞争对抗不符合时代潮流&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3d831fec756e7799ca88717c940571ca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3d831fec756e7799ca88717c940571ca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美关系如何发展，归根到底取决于两个大国对于彼此的认知。以合作面主导认知，双边关系就能朝好的方向发展；以竞争面主导认知乃至以竞争定义全部关系，对抗性就会不断增强，就有滑入“新冷战”深渊的风险。当下美方理顺对华关系，关键是树立正确的对华认知，走出零和博弈思维，积累扩大合作面，持续推动中美关系稳下来、好起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为两个大国，中美在贸易、技术、外交等领域既有合作也有竞争，不是你输我赢、你死我活，而应当是你追我赶、共同进步。中国不回避竞争、不惧怕竞争，但竞争应该是公平、合理、良性的，有红线、有禁区，不能无视市场经济规则和国际关系基本准则，更不能将核心利益问题作为竞争工具、挑衅手段。中国认为的竞争，应该是田径赛，有赛道有规则，可以在你追我赶中提升各自成绩，就像运动员竞技追求的是不断提升自己、突破自我，取得更好成绩，而不是给其他运动员“使绊子”或恶意干扰，否则只会因为违规而被罚出局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竞争更不是中美关系的全部。中美经济互补性远大于竞争性，中美经贸合作的本质是互利共赢。当前形势下，中美共同利益不是减少了，而是更多了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美作为两个大国，对人类繁荣发展担负着重要责任。通过合作共同开启人类发展的新纪元，还是滑入大国冲突对抗的深渊，是两国必须回答好的世纪之问。跳出谁赢谁输的狭隘视角，追求人类一起赢的高尚目标，应该成为新时代中美两国的共同追求。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;四论增进合作共识：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;地球容得下中美各自发展、共同繁荣&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bbf6559966456f470c67eaca5d5e8e57.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bbf6559966456f470c67eaca5d5e8e57.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近一段时间以来，中美正向互动趋势不断增强。美国一方面在“竞争”意识主导下继续推出对华科技、经贸合作限制措施，一方面也在各个渠道寻求与中国接触，出现了近年鲜见的“求同”苗头。究其根本，中美是全球最大的两个经济体，中美关系是全世界最重要的双边关系，两国经济关联既深且广，两国和世界都无法承受双方误判意图、对抗冲突之重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美双方的发展进步完全可以成为对方的机遇而不是挑战，两国经济互补性远大于竞争性，中美应该互利共赢而不是零和博弈，双方可以彼此成就，做大共同利益的蛋糕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美合作不仅有存量优势，还有增量优势。中美虽然互为重要贸易伙伴，每年有数千亿美元的贸易额，但双边贸易额仍然有增长空间，这是美国与其他国家双边经贸关系无法比拟的。合作将为双方开辟更多更宽广领域增长空间。“碳中和”领域技术研发交流和联合投资将使双方受益；未来中美老龄化人群对医疗服务的需求将大幅增长，医疗技术和数据的交流将给双方带来巨大价值；中国超大规模中等收入人群为美国农产品提供难以估量的潜在市场；美中两国都受益于双向投资流，鼓励相互投资将多角度反哺两国经济……双方合作的单子可以拉得很长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宽广的地球完全容得下中美各自发展、共同繁荣。中国人民和美国人民一样，都是自尊自信自强的人民，都拥有追求美好生活的权利，两国之间存在的共同利益应该得到重视，各自取得成功对彼此都是机遇而非威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;五论夯实民意基础：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;汇聚中美交流合作的正能量&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/817b7b6597dfe47c2b5300188083c049.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/817b7b6597dfe47c2b5300188083c049.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258352&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美虽远隔重洋，但中美人民的交流合作源远流长。“国之交在于民相亲”。追忆往昔，中美民间的友好交往从没有中断，两国人民也在交往中结下了深情厚谊，为中美关系发展发挥了重要作用。历史已经充分证明，中美两国人民完全可以跨越制度、文化、语言的差异，建立起深厚的友谊。中美民间交流互利共赢，不仅是两国人民做出的自主选择，更是不可阻挡的历史潮流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中美关系处于关键十字路口的当下，持续不断的民间交往和人文交流合作尤显珍贵，为两国关系的健康发展注入源源不断的正能量。横跨太平洋的航班越多、货轮越多、游客越多、学生学者越多，中美两国关系发展的民意基础就越厚实，空间就越广阔，动力就越强劲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美都应该本着对两国人民负责任的态度，从两国人民的福祉出发，处理好、管控好、发展好两国关系，为两国人民继承和弘扬珍贵友谊遗产创造有利氛围和条件，筑牢两国友谊与合作的民意基础。近期中美关系“大气候”回暖，越来越多的中美各界人士为两国扩大交往合作鼓与呼，为两国人民相知相亲四处奔走，传递出中美民间友好的积极信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美关系眼下仍面临不少困难和挑战，稳定和改善两国关系任重道远。所幸的是，从历史中走来的这些根基性民间纽带仍在，推动中美关系向前发展的正能量正在不断聚集。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“去中国躲一下”，缅北战区逃生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“我们老家打仗了，去中国躲一下。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月10日上午，缅甸“90后”阿兰在云南瑞丽口岸排队等待入境。相较于7天前，这一次的速度快了很多，“中国国门这边，一个小时就办好了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兰家在缅甸掸邦木姐市贵概镇，祖籍中国云南。今年10月下旬，阿兰回老家短住时，意外遇到了突发的战火。“开始几天可以听到枪炮声，去中国的路也封了。”直到11月4日，阿兰才再次回到木姐口岸，在那里看到了很多像她一样排队去中国的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明清以来，大量汉族移民迁入缅甸北部，逐渐形成重要的华人聚居区。这里与中国云南密切相接，不少居民说汉语、写汉字，对中华文化有天然的亲近感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;缅北冲突爆发后，像阿兰一样“到中国躲难”的缅北华人不在少数。在上千公里的边境线上，他们或入境中国，或进入中缅边境难民营救点，期待在这里感受片刻的和平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73514&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70316&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/4f8ecd78b4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;瑞丽.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;中国云南德宏州瑞丽国门。出入境通道开放时，中缅边民可以凭借通行者便利地跨境互市。（李春华/图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/4f8ecd78b4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258311&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中国云南德宏州瑞丽国门。出入境通道开放时，中缅边民可以凭借通行证便利地跨境互市。（李春华/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;亲历交战，&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;四面八方都有枪声&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月27日凌晨，原属缅甸政府军控制的清水河兄弟桥响起枪声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据缅甸民族民主同盟军旗下媒体“果敢民族之声”披露，当日上午，同盟军成功占领兄弟桥。随后的29日，缅甸清水河国门升起同盟军的军旗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴星的家是一栋四层小楼，距离清水河兄弟桥只有百米远。这座桥横跨缅甸果敢清水河特区与缅甸佤邦南邓特区，同时靠近中国云南耿马县孟定口岸，是一处交通要道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴星说，平日里桥上能看到缅甸政府军的士兵巡逻、把守，而桥对岸则是佤邦的地盘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73515&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70317&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1b92d02e95.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;兄弟桥.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10月27日凌晨，缅北果敢清水河特区发生武装冲突。清水河兄弟桥正是交火点之一。（受访者供图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1974&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1b92d02e95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258312&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月27日凌晨，缅北果敢清水河特区发生武装冲突。清水河兄弟桥正是交火点之一。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不知道是怎么打起来的，反正四面八方都有枪声。”吴星和丈夫亲历了这场交火。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和丈夫被惊醒时大约是凌晨3点多。从窗户往外望去，外面天还是黑的。她觉得，这次枪炮声跟以前不一样，听声音威力比较大。他们躲在楼道处避险，一墙之外就是交火的地方，“当时桥上打得很凶，听到有人在惨叫”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴星家附近的住着二十多户在此务工的缅族人。随着天光渐亮、枪声渐弱，一些工人来到街上探路，结果被占领此地的武装士兵发现。“那里还有一伙老缅！”吴星听到有人喊了一声，随后密集的枪声突然再次响起，她的心再次悬了起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在这里，很多华人把缅族人称为&#39;老缅&#39;。”吴星看到，在武装士兵要求下，这些工人双手抱头、男女分开，检查是否携带武器。发现他们是老百姓之后，工人们被放行。“没有真的开枪打人，应该就是&#39;吓唬他们一下&#39;。”吴星说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天亮后，穿军装的士兵处挨家挨户叫门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来到吴星家门口时，她赶忙解释说自己是本地老百姓。“他们让人快点离开，说等下可能有缅军飞机会来轰炸。”吴星和丈夫马上以最快速度动身。“一人一套衣服，再带上一些现金。其它的什么都没带了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冲突发生前，听到风声的吴星就把女儿和母亲提前送到了孟定，而自己和丈夫则抱着侥幸心理留下。惊险过后，吴星不禁感慨：“真没想到还能活下来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，吴星和丈夫在佤邦南邓暂时安顿下来。这里离家很近，开车回去仅需要10分钟。接连数日，吴星白天开车回家，下午再返回南邓特区。她说，家里基本上没有受到破坏，院子里停放着一辆汽车、一辆摩托车。回去的时候都还在原地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有几家房子被炸毁了，但大部分还是好的。”说完之后，吴星又补充道，“不知道以后会不会再炸。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;边境避难，&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;道路一度拥堵&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;11月9日清晨6时许，淡白色的雾气笼罩着缅甸果敢125难民救助点。深蓝、浅绿色的防水帐篷在泥地上一字排开，不远处高高地立着黄色小楼。“这个地方原来是作为经济合作区设计的，但没有发展起来。现在就留下了一些烂尾楼。”救助点志愿者阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据阿伟介绍，125难民救助点设在果敢125工业园，占地超过百亩。缅北冲突发生后不久，就有超过2000人涌入救助点。摄于救助点的图片显示，很多儿童和老人住在室外的简易帐篷中。在黄泥地上铺上席子就是床。一些家庭在门口搭土灶台生火做饭，拿彩色的塑料矮凳当餐桌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“来得早的难民，可以住进室内的铁皮大棚，来得晚的，就只能到外面搭帐篷。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73517&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70319&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/23181e76b0.png&quot; img-title=&quot;难民4.png&quot; alt=&quot;缅甸果敢125难民救助点内，很多缅甸老百姓只随身携带了少量行李。（受访者供图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1434&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/23181e76b0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258313&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;缅甸果敢125难民救助点内，很多缅甸老百姓只随身携带了少量行李。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;救助点的物资是按户发放，每家可分到50斤一袋的大米，两三天发一袋。不过，这无法满足难民需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“果敢不像中国，这里每家每户平均4-5个孩子。”阿伟说，有一些家庭冒领物资，救助点管理人手有限，常常上当。“有人叫儿子领一次，爸爸又领一次。还有人领取后高价转卖给别人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“储存的大米基本上都没有了。”阿伟11月9日告诉南方周末记者，救助点的物资来自外地爱心人士捐赠、本地购买、从中国境内进口等。受当地冲突影响，从下缅甸到老街的路不通，包括粮食在内的救援物资无法运入，帐篷、大米等物资告急。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;救助站靠近中缅125界碑，与中国的南伞口岸仅有一墙之隔。很久一段时间里，这里是果敢边民进入中国的主要通道。“从果敢到中国，最便捷的地方就是南伞。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，南伞口岸位于中国云南临沧市镇康县南伞镇，这里距离果敢首府老街仅有约10公里。然而，当前中国南伞口岸出入境临时关闭，很多持有通行证的果敢人也无法通过口岸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月13日起，镇康当地发布公告，推动边民互市贸易正常化。据公布流程，当日起，镇康内边民、企业等可提前申报，并在口岸做好车辆、货物的接收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国国门开了之后，物资可以从中国进来，物资短缺的情况应该会有所改善。但缅甸人员依然无法从南伞口岸出入境，目前还是只通货，不过人。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了中国边境，与果敢相邻的佤邦，也成为不少缅甸百姓的避难选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73516&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70318&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/05c118ff2b.png&quot; img-title=&quot;难民.png&quot; alt=&quot;10·27缅北冲突爆发后，缅北佤邦南邓特区涌入了大批逃难的百姓。（受访者供图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1766&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/05c118ff2b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258314&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10·27缅北冲突爆发后，缅北佤邦南邓特区涌入了大批逃难的百姓。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;龚先生老家在云南曲靖，目前在缅北佤邦、小勐拉一带做衣服批发生意。缅北冲突爆发后，他在佤邦南邓特区现场目睹了很多缅甸老百姓从战区涌入。他向南方周末记者展示的视频中，大量民众聚集在位于南邓的救援点，等待物资发放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“27日早上战事开打，27日下午就有很多人跑到南邓。”龚先生称，逃难的民众被安置在一处开阔的广场上，佤邦军士兵负责登记人员、维持秩序、免费发放物资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有条件的开车来，普通人骑摩托车、走路。可能因为事发突然，很多人都是两手空空。还有的人只披着一张毯子出门。”龚先生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为逃难人员众多，从果敢战区逃亡临近佤邦道路一度拥堵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“果敢民族之声”11月7日消息，连日来，石园子至厂街路段至少有400余辆车，约五六百民众欲前往邻邦地区避难却被困其中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其发布的图文资料中，宽约三四米的水泥公路上，一条蜿蜒的“车龙”正驶向佤邦方向。心情急切的人推开车门，三三两两站在道路上，伸着脖子向“龙头”遥望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样迁移到佤邦的吴星感慨，“幸亏我们走得早，要不然也要被堵在路上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“以后要给爸妈办通行证”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;阿兰兄弟姐妹8个，在家中排行老二。小时候，阿兰父亲烧炭养活一大家子，常年住在山上。阿兰和兄弟姐妹们就帮父亲拿炭、背炭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“什么防护措施都没有。比如你先进去，把炭一块块递出来。你顶不住了，就换我进去。”阿兰记得，从炭窑出来的时候，整个人被炭灰染黑，“连咳出来的痰都是黑的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为家穷，阿兰的书只念到小学，16岁起就到瑞丽打工。在她的家乡，很多同龄小姐妹选择到中国打工。相较于缅甸本国如仰光、内比都等大城市，瑞丽“距离近、工资更高”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，阿兰是整个家里唯一一个有中缅边界通行证的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一次入境后可在瑞丽停留七天；七天后，她要回到缅甸木姐，完成一次出入境后，又可以停留七天。通过不断地“续签”通行证，阿兰无需办理流程更麻烦的护照就可以跨境往来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国瑞丽国门和缅甸木姐国门之间仅有数十米距离，途中可以看到中缅81号界碑。对于阿兰来说，这条路再熟悉不过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“先过了中国国门，去到缅甸（国门）盖个章。然后再过来中国（国门）盖个章，就办好了。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在瑞丽打工的日子里，一开始阿兰在中国人经营的饭店里当服务员。因为认识汉字、会说汉语，她的工资总比其他同来的缅甸老乡高一些。十几年来，她的工资从每月200涨到了每月2000元。挣来的钱大部分都补贴家里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着近年来直播平台兴起，阿兰开始在社交平台分享生活，同时做电商带货。每隔一段时间，她都要把产自缅甸的茶叶、蜂蜜、土特产等订单发往全国各地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多中国的哥哥姐姐们支持我，特别感谢他们。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出入境通道开放时，中缅边民可以凭借通行证便利地跨境互市。缅甸的大米、白糖、橡胶、牛肉、茶叶等农副产品由此销往内地，商人们从中赚取价差。缅甸的翡翠原石等矿藏也由此集散。对于中缅边民来说，这里代表着无限商机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，办好一张通行证大约要花十几万到50万缅币不等，合计人民币几百到一千元。由于家里经济比较困难，阿兰家一直没有额外再办证件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因战火滞留在老家，阿兰感到非常煎熬。睡觉的时候都在担心，枪炮会不会突然落在自己头上。直到返回瑞丽后，她才能放心睡个好觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次缅北冲突发生后，阿兰坚定了要给爸妈办证的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我正在想办法，这次花钱也要办。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“哪一方都得罪不起”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在1983年制定的缅甸民族表中，果敢族被缅甸政府列入135个民族之一。特指生活在缅甸掸邦北部与中国云南省临沧市的镇康和耿马两县毗邻的果敢地区的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国缅甸研究学者王士录在《缅甸的“果敢族”:族称、来历、状况及跨国互动》一文中指出,“果敢族”的称谓从民族学上来讲是很不科学的,这些被称为“果敢族”的华侨、华人,事实上应当是缅甸华侨、华人中的“云南帮”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在民间，不少缅北华人习惯性称自己是“汉族人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今阿兰的老家里，依然看到熟悉的汉族习俗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，房屋大门门框上贴着红底金字的对联，中堂里赫然立着“天地君亲师”的牌位，台前供有香炉。阿兰说，每逢农历七月半、春节等，全家人还要摆上贡品，在这里庄重地跪拜、祈祷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兰的爷爷去世很早，奶奶告诉阿兰，他们祖籍在中国云南保山的龙陵县。对于祖籍龙陵，阿兰没去过，也没什么印象。她说，最想去的中国城市是北京，有朝一日想去看天安门。“我们读的都是中文书，从小读书时就很向往”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1948年，缅甸脱离英联邦正式独立后，国内几十股地方武装在边境地区与中央政府长期武装对抗，寻求独立。而北部中缅边界的果敢、佤邦、缅甸克钦邦第二特区和缅甸掸邦东部第四特区则分别由四股强势的武装力量掌控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很长一段时间里，缅甸中央政府并不能真正控制该地区。在多重矛盾下，缅北地方武装势力轮番主政、地区战事不断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，缅甸政府对缅北民族地方武装展开打击，地区控制力逐渐增强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年3月25日，果敢地区正式更名为“缅甸掸邦北部果敢自治区”。2015年3月26日，缅甸军方宣布控制整个果敢地区，对果敢地区采取了融入缅甸的政策，大力引入缅语教师，采用缅语教学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们从小读的是中文书、说的也是中国话。但我们又是缅甸人，要听缅甸政府的。”吴星说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅仅8年后，果敢地区再次响起炮火。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“果敢民族之声”11月13日消息，“10·27军事行动”开始18天以来，联军已攻占清水河、勐古、滚弄等城镇，夺回大小军事据点141个，缴获一批武器弹药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;频繁的战事、变换的地方政权，让民众对各方力量讳莫如深。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“果敢地区三年打一小仗，五年打一次大仗。”阿伟不到50岁，已经历了四五次战争。他希望媒体报道难民救助点时能保持中立，因为“哪一方都得罪不起”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在我们这个地方，死一个人像踩死一只蚂蚁一样，如果你没有势力、没有朋友，你什么都不是。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;【掸邦概况】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;掸邦位于缅甸东部，北与中国云南省西双版纳接壤，东面与老挝和泰国相接壤，西面与克钦邦、克耶邦、克伦邦、曼德勒省、实皆省相连。掸邦是缅甸境内面积最大、人口最多的一个邦，首府在东枝市。历史上，来自中国云南的华人移民大量移入，在此逐渐形成缅北华人聚居区。掸邦南部有主张独立的武装力量存在，东部与泰、老交界地带即有名的金三角地区，北部与中国接壤，是缅甸境内果敢族（汉族）主要的聚居地。1986年至1989年，原属武装统辖地一分为四，成为缅甸掸邦第一特区（果敢）、缅甸掸邦第二特区（佤邦）、缅甸克钦邦第一特区、缅甸掸邦东部第四特区（勐拉）。近年来，华人新移民大量涌入，社会生态变得更复杂。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不清剿电诈决不收兵”，揭秘中国警方通缉的缅北电诈家族]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;11月12日午间，公安部刑侦局发布通告公开通缉缅北诈骗集团重要头目明学昌、明国平、明菊兰和明珍珍四人，引发国内外舆论高度关注。该消息之所以引人瞩目，与明学昌的身份不无关系。据公开报道，明学昌系缅北果敢自治区“老领导”，长期在果敢担任要职，曾任果敢县长，2011年任掸邦议会议员、果敢自治区副主席、果敢自治区日常工作委员会和领导委员会委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/8d368b52f3d66b9c9f41a4c1854a62a7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/8d368b52f3d66b9c9f41a4c1854a62a7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次一同被警方通缉的还有明国平、明菊兰、明珍珍，均系明学昌子女，明氏家族在果敢势力庞大，被指仅次于果敢四大家族（一说为四大家族之一）。连日来，有关明氏家族的消息不断发酵，网上流传果敢10月20日发生多人被枪杀、活埋事件，地点位于果敢首府老街由明学昌家族控制的卧虎山庄园区。与此同时，明学昌孙子明光忠获北京大学取录通知书照片以及多张明学昌与明光忠在升学宴会上的庆祝图片在网上传播。北京大学宣传部13日回应称，明光忠并非北大学生，校内无任何其申请北大记录。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;明学昌与背后的明氏家族&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;位于缅北的果敢自治区与云南省接壤，人口约14万，以汉人居多，历史上与中国渊源颇深。2011年，果敢自治区正式成立，隶属掸邦，现由缅甸军政府控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，现年69岁的明学昌早期曾追随果敢军阀彭家声加入缅甸共产党，参与创立缅甸民族民主同盟军，缅甸内政交替之后被缅甸军政府任命为果敢县长，2011年任掸邦议会议员、果敢自治区副主席、果敢自治区日常工作委员会和领导委员会委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国公安部通缉令发出前，明学昌曾以果敢地区老领导的身份出面参加当地治理电信网络诈骗会议。据当地媒体10月26日报道，“为进一步落实工作要求，强化电信诈骗等各类衍生违法行为的打击力度，自治区召开专项工作会议。自治区主席李正福、委员觉觉伍中校、白应能、吴缪索旦、纽伦伍警长及各级部门、治安单位负责人、乡/社区负责人参加会议。此外，地区老领导明学昌、赵德强、刘正祥参加会议。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也是明学昌最后一次出现在公开报道中。据中国公安部发布的通缉令显示，此次一同被通缉的还有明家三人，42岁的明国平系明学昌之子，是果敢自治区石园子乡民兵中队中队长。同岁的明菊兰为明学昌之女，还有一名明氏家族成员为27岁的明珍珍，有媒体报道其为明学昌孙女。值得一提的是，明菊兰和明珍珍的户籍地均在云南临沧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81afe7325cd8d48ecb33865a1cd59709.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;592&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81afe7325cd8d48ecb33865a1cd59709.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;明学昌&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在果敢地区，明氏家族势力庞大，缅甸当地媒体报道称，明学昌是当地首富之一，明家与四大家族关系密切。果敢素有四大家族之称，指的是白所成家族、魏超仁家族、刘国玺家族和刘阿宝家族，明家算是“后起之秀”。媒体报道称，果敢老街的矿产、赌场、地产经营等均被四大家族控制，四大家族同时是果敢地区电诈集团的靠山。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国公安部发布的通缉令则直指，以明学昌为首的犯罪集团长期组织开设诈骗窝点，公开武装护诈，实施针对中国公民的电信网络诈骗犯罪活动，诈骗数额巨大，同时涉嫌故意杀人、故意伤害、非法拘禁等多种严重暴力犯罪。通告敦促其认清形势，悬崖勒马，主动投案自首，争取宽大处理。警方通缉令中还表示，对提供有效线索和协助抓捕有功人员将给予10万至50万人民币奖励。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在通缉令发布后，网上流传果敢10月20日发生多人被枪杀、活埋事件，地点正位于果敢首府老街由明学昌家族控制的卧虎山庄园区。同时多名被捕电诈头目忏悔片段在网络中引发关注，包括果敢四大家族成员魏家二公子魏清涛、刘阿宝胞弟刘正琦，及明学昌女婿毕会军等均出境剖白，敦促家人主动自首，称中国“不清除电信诈骗，绝不收兵”。缅甸佤邦新闻局13日回应媒体记者称，上述三人确系电诈成员，目前已被司法机构控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;缅北爆发内战局势紧张，缅甸当局承诺年底&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;彻底消除电诈&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;近期，缅北部分华裔少数民族武装与军政府交战，联合国人道主义事务协调厅称，自10月27日爆发冲突以来，已至少6000人流离失所。本次华裔少数民族武装部队的首领彭德仁为彭家声之子，对外声称此次交战正是为了清剿电信网络诈骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国外交部发言人汪文斌对此表示，中方高度关注缅北冲突态势，敦促各方立即停火止战，“坚持通过对话协商，以和平方式解决分歧，避免事态升级，并采取切实有效措施确保中缅边境安全稳定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此次网络流传的视频中，四大家族魏家二公子魏清涛也在自白中称，目前缅甸爆发战乱，随时可能造成严重伤亡，叮嘱家人抓住最后机会打开园区，把园内的中国人主动交回中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据央视新闻报道，2021年2月以来，缅甸国内紧张局势加剧，为电信诈骗集团纷纷入驻缅北、缅东，并与当地地方势力形成“利益共同体”提供更多的空间。仅在缅泰边境的妙瓦底，就有上百个诈骗园区，加上盘踞在缅北部分地区的诈骗集团，总计至少有1000个园区，每天有超过10万人在实施电信诈骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“缅北、缅东电诈集团聚集区域仅为缅甸国土面积的极小部分，且多为少数民族地方武装控制区，但其却给缅甸国家形象带来致命打击。”央视报道如此表述。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，中国政府不断加大合作力度，同缅甸、泰国等多国开展联合执法行动依法严厉打击电信网络诈骗，尤其今年以来，中方严打的态势更甚。日前，中泰缅老四国警方启动合作打击赌诈集团专项联合行动，旨在严厉打击本区域电信网络诈骗和网络赌博犯罪，坚决扭转人口贩运及绑架、拘禁等犯罪高发态势。据不完全统计，今年9月以来，已陆续有多批电信网络诈骗人员从缅甸、柬埔寨等境外被押解回国，10月14日，2349名涉电诈人员从缅甸移交中国更是创下历史新高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在战乱爆发期间，10月31日，缅甸国家管理委员会主席敏昂莱在内比都会见国务委员、公安部部长王小洪。王小洪提及，两国执法安全部门将在打击电诈网赌、反恐、禁毒、湄公河流域执法、重大项目安保等领域加强合作，维护好两国安全和发展利益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有分析人士认为，一系列动作彰显中方严打电信网络诈骗的决心。近期，缅甸国家管理委员会发言人佐敏吞也表态，缅甸当局决心在2023年底前，彻底消除缅北地区的网络赌博和网络诈骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[食品还是药品？争议中医院药膳“生意”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/5a2c29f80e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/5a2c29f80e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258298&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;中医院竞相扩展业务领域、进军药膳“生意”，与流传上千年的“药食同源”中医理论以及人们日益觉醒的“养生血脉”有关。视觉中国| 图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“没想到打败奶茶的是中医院的酸梅汤”“一帖只要一块钱的酸梅汤谁还不会开”……社交平台上网友的“安利帖”，让浙江省中医院的线上便捷配药系统一夜之间陷入瘫痪——1.34元一帖的酸梅汤茶包被抢购一空。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“去中药房配酸梅汤”，2023年秋在社交平台掀起的这股热潮，并非中药茶饮第一次出圈。早在2020年，广西柳州市中医医院就凭借东院药膳坊推出的中药奶茶引发关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;走红网络后，浙江省中医院相继推出秋燥润肺饮、煲汤三宝方和冬令进补膏方，其中茶饮煲汤方单帖价格在20元以内；柳州市中医医院则更新药膳坊菜单，研发出药膳汤类、炒菜类、粥类、药茶类、糕点类、面点类等六大类药膳，价格在2-55元不等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;不同的是，前者的药膳方在互联网医院平台以药材包的形式线上售卖，按照药品管理；后者的药膳产品则由第三方餐饮公司线下销售，作为食品经营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;据南方周末记者了解，除上述两家中医院，国内已有大批中医院在互联网医院平台销售中药茶饮、膏方等院内协定方。这些方剂通常标有明确的功效和禁忌人群，消费者无需面诊即可自助下单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中医院竞相扩展业务领域、进军药膳“生意”，与流传上千年的“药食同源”中医理论以及人们日益觉醒的“养生血脉”有关。药膳业务扩张，客观上带动了线下中医门诊的就诊量提升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;不过，现实中，药膳经营也因“药食不分”面临尴尬境地——产品定位是药品还是食品，关系到不同的经营主体、材料选用和监管标准，也影响消费者的预期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“养生药膳有别于临床药膳，必须选用国家卫健委批准的&#39;药食同源&#39;药材，也不能谈疗效。严格来说，没有经过医师问诊辨证的协定方，不能是具有明确治疗作用的临床药膳。”中华中医药学会药膳分会主任委员、山东第一医科大学第一附属医院中医科主任宋鲁成向南方周末记者表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;上线一年突然走红，女性用户占八成&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;酸梅汤火得有些“猝不及防”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“到了下架前一天，酸梅汤单日销量甚至突破了4万帖。”浙江省中医院医务部主任吕晓皑告诉南方周末记者。要知道出圈前，该院酸梅汤日均订单只有几百帖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;事实上，早在一年前，2022年5月31日，浙江省中医院就开始在互联网医院平台上线中药茶饮，包含健脾祛湿、平肝降脂、明目润眼等多款茶饮协定方，药方由院内名医工作室研制，单帖价格在2-17元不等。酸梅汤则在2022年夏季推出，由乌梅、山楂、甘草、陈皮四味药材组成，药方详情页显示，该方有解暑、生津、开胃功效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;上线一年后突然走红，吕晓皑认为这反映了当前年轻人养生热情的提升。睡眠障碍、腰痛、咳嗽、月经不规律、疲劳综合征是浙江省中医院2023年9月接诊人数排名前五的病种，都是上班族常见的亚健康困扰。中药茶饮针对常见病推出，契合了年轻人的健康需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;浙江省中医院提供的数据显示，此次抢购酸梅汤的用户以年轻女性为主，女性用户占比超八成，17岁-30岁用户占71.25%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;生活在杭州的王慈在第一时间购买了浙江省中医院的酸梅汤，“想着拿来代替奶茶，健康又好喝”。两年前，二十八岁的王慈因内分泌失调确诊甲亢，从此开始坚持配茶、煲汤，用药膳养生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;世界中医药学会联合会药膳食疗研究专业委员会副会长、福建中医药大学教授、医学博士华碧春向南方周末记者表示，中医药膳历来是中药的应用形式之一，在中医药理论的指导下，通过中医师辨证施膳，不同年代不同地域常以不同的形式流行，渗透到老百姓日常生活和防病治病、康复养生的方方面面。“中医学的基本特点是整体观和辨证论治，中医药膳学是以中医药理论为指导，研究中国传统药膳、食养的理论和经验，并加以整理提高，使之与现代营养治疗学和营养卫生学相结合的一门医疗保健方面的实用科学。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“中医治疗疾病的基本方法是利用合适的药物、食物性味组合成一定的处方来治疗疾病。医生在开具临床处方之外，也需要嘱咐病人宜吃什么，不宜吃什么。”宋鲁成说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;从线上到线下&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中医院做药膳“生意”并不新鲜，新的是经营方式，目前主要存在互联网医院和餐饮门店两种经营形式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;互联网医院平台推广药膳，与疫情期间全国公立医院互联网医疗服务的发展有很大关系。当时，全国大批中医院利用互联网医院平台推出新冠预防制剂，打通了线上开单、配送到家的在线购药流程，并将其沿用至药膳业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;比如，河北省中医院曾在2022年12月推出“防疫食疗方”系列“药膳包”“发酵膏”；厦门市中医院在2022年11月推出中药防疫方，并于2023年4月上线健脾祛脂茶；推出酸梅汤之前，浙江省中医院也曾在互联网医院平台上线两个防疫药方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;除了线上开方，药膳推广更贴近市场化经营的路径，是在线下打造药膳餐饮品牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;柳州市中医医院治未病中心主任刘静告诉南方周末记者，“食药同园”药膳坊开业三年以来，结合广西道地药材和地方气候特色，推出了菜、汤、粥、糕点、饮品、面点等不同形式的药膳产品，其中中药奶茶最受年轻人好评。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“中医院不能直接经营餐饮业务盈利，因此我们委托有资质的第三方餐饮企业生产药膳产品，所有产品配方都由治未病中心药膳团队研发，药材也由医院申领，保证药材质量。”刘静说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;刘静介绍，“食药同园”药膳坊的对面是柳州中医医院的营养科门诊，提供营养筛查与评估、营养咨询与指导等服务，“前来就餐的消费者如果追求适合个人体质、更有针对性的药膳，可以来门诊进一步咨询”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;线上购药膳，规定不一&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;药膳的定位不同，经营路径亦不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;互联网医院平台推出的药膳产品定位为药品。以浙江省中医院为例，中药茶饮的药方详情页明确标注了药品名称、适应症、用法用量、禁忌和注意事项。在药材选用上，为保证药方的安全性和普适性，以药食同源物质为主，但也会选择相对平和的临床药材。消费者下单茶饮时，系统自动跳转在线复诊处方，由便捷配药门诊医师开具相关诊断信息后方能进入支付页面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;作为药品的药膳，如何辨证施治？浙江省中医院为每款协定方设置包含三道问题的问卷，用于判断消费者体质。如勾选项与答案不符，则会弹出“暂时不推荐购买，建议去医院就诊”的提示信息。不过，南方周末记者发现，用户可不限次数进入页面重新作答。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;对此，浙江省中医院在产品宣传文章中曾提示消费者“设置题目的初衷是为了辨别是否适合这个药方，不要为了跟风而去尝试各种答案，按需选择合适的就好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0c6134d93a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1989&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0c6134d93a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258299&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;浙江省中医院线上购买中药茶饮，需先回答三道问题辨认体质。 浙江省中医院互联网平台便捷购药系统截图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，目前不同中医院对于线上购买药膳的管理规定并不统一。如广州中医药大学附属清远中医院的自助购药系统就要求“仅复诊者才能进行线上购药”，如系统未能读取近三个月的院内就诊记录，则无法线上开具药膳方。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;食品药膳：药材受限、不提功效&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;相比中医院里定位为药品的药膳，市场更为广阔的药膳产业中，药膳通常作为食品经营。以北京同仁堂、郑州东济堂、上海童涵春堂为代表的中药房是药膳产业的主体，少数中医院则借助第三方公司开拓食品药膳业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;无论中药房或中医院，经营食品药膳都面临药材选用和疗效宣传的限制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;a>;2002&lt;/a>;年以来，国家卫健委曾多次更新“按照传统既是食品又是中药材的物质目录”，确定了共计102种“药食同源”物质（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;其中包含9种试点物质&lt;/span>;）。按照规定，面向大众的药膳食品只能选用药食同源目录内的药材作为原料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中国药膳研究会会长杨锐在接受中国小康网专访时曾指出，药膳是一个“常在河边走”的产业，一不小心就容易触碰“食品中添加药品”或者“非法行医”的法律红线，但目前“按照传统既是食品又是中药材的物质目录”还不够健全和完善，很多既符合老百姓传统食用习惯又属于中药材的物质，例如辣椒、大蒜、黑豆等列入了《中国药典》，但却没有进入食药物质目录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;此外，养生药膳食品不同于药品，不能标注疗效。北京市海淀区市场监督管理局广告监督管理科副科长徐莹向南方周末记者表示，根据《中华人民共和国广告法》第十七条、第四十六条，以及《药品、医疗器械、保健食品、特殊医学用途配方食品广告审查管理暂行办法》第二条规定，药品不能随便做广告，药品广告必须经药监部门审查后发布，非药品的食品则禁止宣传疗效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;柳州市中医医院药膳坊营业之初，曾在菜单上标注了药膳的对应功效，经有关部门提醒后，目前的菜单仅保留主要成分，菜品名称也删除了涉及功效的词汇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;刘静认为，药膳的科普宣传和广告宣传应有所区别，找到平衡点。医疗机构对于药膳的科普宣传无法提及功效，可能让药膳推广陷入尴尬的境地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;宋鲁成注意到，有些药膳餐饮商为了规避监管，会巧妙地改变说法，“比如针对宫寒症状的药膳产品，就通过&#39;关心大姨妈&#39;这样的词汇暗示消费者”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;广东省食品安全保障促进会副会长、食品产业分析师朱丹蓬向南方周末记者表示，虽然以酸梅汤为代表的中药茶饮消费频次提升，但药膳餐饮产业目前尚无国标出台，以目前的发展水平很难形成大规模市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/07ef06f8e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;818&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/07ef06f8e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2022年10月29日，南宁，药膳展示现场。黄艳梅(广西分社)/中新社/视觉中国&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“一个人的美食，可能是另一人的毒药”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;既是食品又是药品的药膳，也需要消费者正确认识和对待。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中药酸梅汤走红后，顾华跟风在浙江省中医院下单了健脾祛湿饮，服用完10帖20包，顾华发现自己全身乏力、脾胃虚弱的症状并未得到改善，“原本以为喝完会健康一点，没想到毫无效果”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“这些药膳产品虽然定位为药品，实际上仍以养生效果为主。就好比打仗，药膳和临床用药都朝着同一个目标，但一个是步枪，一个是大炮，打击的效果不一样。”浙江省中医院中医内科主任、中医师夏永良说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;多位中医师向南方周末记者表示，中医药膳讲求“因时、因地、因人制宜”，切忌盲目跟风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;比如，同样是睡眠不好，有人需要清热安神，有人需要补气血，有人需要活血化瘀&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;，只有明确自身体质后服用合适药材的茶饮，才能改善症状。四川和浙江两地同样湿气深重，但人在四川吃麻辣食物可以祛湿，到了浙江就不行，这是地域湿寒和湿热的区别。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;酸梅汤风行时，“喝中药茶饮能不能加冰”曾被广泛讨论，夏永良认为，这需要根据个人体质和茶饮用药的药性来决定，“如果是体热人群服用凉茶这样清热去火的饮料，可以适当放冰。但如果茶饮性温而个人体质偏寒，加冰就会降低药效”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“一个人的美食，可能是另一人的毒药。”宋鲁成说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，王慈、顾华为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[育人集团贷款上班：企业巧立名目规避非法集资，员工贪图“利息差”难洗合谋嫌疑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今年9月，河南郑州育人教育集团“让员工贷款养企业”一事曾引发广泛关注。当时集团多名员工向《红星新闻》反映，该集团从2019年起，一直让员工向郑州市农村商业银行以“装修贷”的名义每人贷款10万到15万元供企业使用，贷款总额2000余万元。另据9月央视财经频道报道，该集团财务发布的统计表格显示，2021年1月，集团有181人共贷款2602万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;育人集团曾向员工承诺以校舍与土地提供抵押担保，借来的钱用于“共渡难关”，提出的优厚条件是以1.33%的标准向员工支付每月贷款利息，高于银行的0.66%，同时在子女上学、房产购买上给予员工福利。而从2021年底以来，集团经常停发利息，导致一部分贷款已经逾期、征信受损，还有一部分员工的贷款也将到期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年8月2日，7名员工代表就违法放贷问题向国家金融监管总局河南监管局进行了举报。近日，国家金融监管总局河南监管局出具回复员工代表的调查意见书。经调查，郑州农商行在发放郑州育人教育集团员工消费贷款过程中，存在违反贷款“三查”规定和信贷管理不到位问题。部分员工违反合同约定改变贷款用途，协助育人集团挪用贷款资金并获取一定的经济收益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这并不是“贷款上班”第一次成为新闻。 2022年9月，兰州公交集团提出要员工以个人名义向银行贷款用于解决6到9月份工资，公交公司提供连带担保，负责按月结息、到期还本；2023年3月，国美也推出了“员工贷款”计划，引入民生银行信用贷缓解员工的欠薪压力，在公司发薪之前，每月为员工报销3万元以内的贷款利息，超出部分员工自行负责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰州公交“贷款上班”是为了给员工发工资，国美集团的“员工贷款”是为了缓解欠薪压力，育人集团的“贷款上班”则是笼统的“供集团使用”：让员工以个人名义贷款，然后员工将贷来的钱又交给企业，企业承诺以高于银行的利息向员工偿还这笔钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观事件全过程，首先要问的就是，为何企业不以自身名义进行社会融资，反而却要找员工借钱？这里面可能有经营风险较大、缺乏有效担保抵押品、企业信用低等问题。而如果企业直接向员工借钱，那么就是纯粹的民间借贷关系，企业需要承担偿还责任，还可能涉嫌非法集资罪。育人集团鼓动员工以个人名义向银行申请“装修贷”，等于是利用员工有正式工作单位、信用记录完整的条件，将员工的个人贷款资格拿来供自己使用，不仅成功地向银行贷到了钱，借款人还是员工而非企业，可谓“用心良苦”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，员工为何愿意帮助企业贷款“共渡难关”？ “部分员工违反合同约定改变贷款用途，协助育人集团挪用贷款资金并获取一定的经济收益”，金融监管局在调查意见书中的这句话显示，事件中的员工并非完全是浑然不觉的“被贷款”，至少有部分员工了解贷款资金的去向，但仍然与企业合谋完成了贷款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些员工是为了贪图那点“利息差”，还是为了保住公司也保住自己的职位，或两者兼而有之，目前看都有可能，员工与企业之间形成了实质上的共谋关系。金融监管局在意见书中“举报人提出的将借款主体变更为郑州育人教育集团的诉求属于民事纠纷，应按照民事法律法规规定通过协商或诉讼途径解决”的表述，也等于是在表明，员工既然在借款合同上签字盖章，就应承担责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅如此，当事员工甚至可能涉嫌违法犯罪。根据《中华人民共和国刑法》第175条，以转贷牟利为目的，套取金融机构信贷资金高利转贷他人，构成高利转贷罪，处以拘役、徒刑或罚金；而根据最高法《关于审理民间借贷案件适用法律若干问题的规定》第13条，育人集团与员工之间签订的“专项贷款使用协议”恐怕也有很大概率属于无效合同，双方的纠纷还需要通过协商或诉讼途径解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观这起事件，企业巧立名目让员工以个人信用为企业贷款，银行疏于审核借贷人资格与贷款用途，员工贪图所谓“利差”与目前的职位，监管方疏于把关，各方在事件中均负有责任。 “贷款上班”事件也显示，育人集团员工与企业之间的关系出现了问题。试问，一家企业已经窘迫到需要拿员工的名义贷款来救活自己，员工保住这份工作的意义又在哪里？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除非有员工持股计划或是期权计划，否则员工与企业之间仅仅只存在普通的雇佣关系。育人集团的“贷款上班”称得上是巧立名目，这种行为既规避了非法集资，也不是公司内部的理财产品，也不算企业直接向员工借款，更不是什么员工持股计划或是期权计划，倒像是员工负债计划，结果也是呈现出企业与员工双输的局面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起事件中“员工贷款养企业”的行为更像是让自己沦为了企业的人质，贪图“利息差”的表现也称得上是“利令智昏”。员工与企业之间应是权责对等的雇佣关系，超越法定权责之外的“谈钱”或“谈感情”，都是站不住脚的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花上万块在五星级大酒店吃一年自助餐，真划算还是大冤种？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美两国发表关于加强合作应对气候危机的阳光之乡声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 10:33:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;11月15日，中美两国发表关于加强合作应对气候危机的阳光之乡声明，声明全文如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;关于加强合作应对气候危机的阳光之乡声明&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重温习近平主席和约瑟夫·拜登总统在印尼巴厘岛会晤，中美双方重申致力于合作并与其他国家共同努力应对气候危机。为此，中国气候变化事务特使解振华和美国总统气候问题特使约翰·克里于2023年7月16—19日在北京、11月4—7日在加利福尼亚阳光之乡举行会谈，并发表以下声明：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一、中美两国回顾、重申并致力于进一步有效和持续实施2021年4月中美应对气候危机联合声明和2021年11月中美关于在21世纪20年代强化气候行动的格拉斯哥联合宣言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、中美两国认识到，气候危机对世界各国的影响日益显著。面对政府间气候变化专门委员会（IPCC）第六次评估报告等现有最佳科学发现的警示，两国致力于有效实施联合国气候变化框架公约和巴黎协定，体现公平以及共同但有区别的责任和各自能力的原则，考虑不同国情，根据巴黎协定第二条所述将全球平均气温上升控制在低于2℃之内并努力限制在1.5℃之内，包括努力保持1.5℃可实现，达成该协定的目的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三、中美两国致力于有效实施巴黎协定及其决定，包括格拉斯哥气候协议和沙姆沙伊赫实施计划。两国强调，公约第28次缔约方大会（COP28）对于在这关键十年及其后有意义地应对气候危机至关重要。两国认识到，两国无论是在国内应对措施还是共同合作行动方面对于落实巴黎协定各项目标、推动多边主义均具有重要作用。为了人类今世后代，两国将合作并与公约和巴黎协定其他缔约方一道直面当今世界最为严峻的挑战之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四、中美两国决定启动“21世纪20年代强化气候行动工作组”，开展对话与合作，以加速21世纪20年代的具体气候行动。工作组将聚焦联合声明和联合宣言中确定的合作领域，包括能源转型、甲烷、循环经济和资源利用效率、低碳可持续省/州和城市、毁林以及双方同意的其他主题。工作组将就控制和减少排放的政策、措施和技术进行信息交流，分享各自经验，识别和实施合作项目，并评估联合声明、联合宣言和本次声明的实施情况。工作组由两国气候变化特使共同领导，两国相关部委和政府机构的官员以适当方式参加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五、中美两国将于COP28之前及其后在工作组下重点加速以下具体行动，特别是切实可行和实实在在的合作计划和项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;能源转型&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;六、在21世纪20年代这关键十年，两国支持二十国集团领导人宣言所述努力争取到2030年全球可再生能源装机增至三倍，并计划从现在到2030年在2020年水平上充分加快两国可再生能源部署，以加快煤油气发电替代，从而可预期电力行业排放在达峰后实现有意义的绝对减少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七、双方同意重启中美能效论坛，以深化工业、建筑、交通和设备等重点领域节能降碳政策交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;八、中美两国计划重启双边能源政策和战略对话，就共同商定的议题开展交流，推动二轨活动，加强务实合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;九、两国争取到2030年各自推进至少5个工业和能源等领域碳捕集利用和封存（CCUS）大规模合作项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;甲烷和其他非二氧化碳温室气体排放&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;十、两国将落实各自国家甲烷行动计划并计划视情细化进一步措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十一、两国将立即启动技术性工作组合作，开展政策对话、技术解决方案交流和能力建设，在各自国家甲烷行动计划基础上制定各自纳入其2035年国家自主贡献的甲烷减排行动/目标，并支持两国各自甲烷减/控排取得进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十二、两国计划就各自管理氧化亚氮排放的措施开展合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十三、两国计划在基加利修正案下共同努力逐步减少氢氟碳化物，并致力于确保生产的所有制冷设备采用有力度的最低能效标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;循环经济和资源利用效率&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;十四、认识到循环经济发展和资源利用效率对于应对气候危机的重要作用，两国相关政府部门计划尽快就这些议题开展一次政策对话，并支持双方企业、高校、研究机构开展交流讨论和合作项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十五、中美两国决心终结塑料污染并将与各方一道制订一项具有法律约束力的塑料污染（包括海洋环境塑料污染）国际文书。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;地方合作&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;十六、中美两国将支持省、州和城市在电力、交通、建筑和废弃物等领域开展气候合作。双方将推动地方政府、企业、智库和其他相关方积极参与合作。两国将通过商定的定期会议，进行政策对话、最佳实践分享、信息交流并促进项目合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十七、中美两国计划于2024年上半年举办地方气候行动高级别活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十八、双方欢迎并赞赏两国已开展的地方合作，并鼓励省、州和城市开展务实气候合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;森林&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;十九、双方承诺进一步努力，以到2030年停止和扭转森林减少，包括通过规管和政策手段全面落实并有效执行各自禁止非法进口的法律。双方计划包括在工作组下讨论交流如何增进努力，以加强这一承诺的落实。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;温室气体和大气污染物减排协同&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;二十、两国计划合作推动相关政策措施和技术部署，以加强温室气体与氮氧化物、挥发性有机物和其他对流层臭氧前体物等大气污染物排放的协同控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;2035年国家自主贡献&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;二十一、重申国家自主贡献由国家自主决定的性质，回顾巴黎协定第四条第4款，两国2035年国家自主贡献将是全经济范围，包括所有温室气体，所体现的减排符合全球平均气温上升控制在低于2℃之内并努力限制在1.5℃之内的巴黎温控目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;COP28&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;二十二、中美两国将会同阿拉伯联合酋长国邀请各国参加在COP28期间举行的“甲烷和非二氧化碳温室气体峰会”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十三、中美两国将积极参与巴黎协定首次全球盘点，这是缔约方对力度、落实和合作进行回头看的重要机会，以符合巴黎协定温控目标，即将全球平均气温上升控制在低于2℃之内并努力限制在1.5℃之内，并与缔约方决心保持1.5℃温控目标可实现相一致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十四、两国致力于共同努力并与其他缔约方一道，以协商一致方式达成全球盘点决定。两国认为，该决定：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应体现在实现巴黎协定目标方面取得的实质性积极进展，包括该协定促进了缔约方和非缔约方利益攸关方的行动，以及世界在温升轨迹方面相比没有协定明显处于较好的状况；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应考虑公平，并参考现有最佳科学，包括最新IPCC 报告；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应在各个主题领域保持平衡，包括回顾性和响应性要素，并与巴黎协定设计保持一致；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应体现实现巴黎协定目标需要结合不同国情，在行动和支持方面大幅增强雄心和加强落实；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应在能源转型（可再生能源、煤/油/气）、森林等碳汇、甲烷等非二氧化碳气体，以及低碳技术等方面发出信号；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——认识到国家自主贡献的国家自主决定性质并回顾巴黎协定第四条第4款，应鼓励2035年全经济范围国家自主贡献涵盖所有温室气体；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应体现适应至关重要，并辅以一项强有力的决定，以提出一个有力度的全球适应目标框架——加速适应，包括制定目标/指标以加强适应有效性；为发展中国家缔约方提供早期预警系统；加强关键领域（例如粮食、水、基础设施、健康和生态系统）适应努力；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应注意到发达国家预期2023年实现1000亿美元气候资金目标，重申敦促发达国家缔约方将其提供的适应资金至少翻倍；期待COP29通过新的集体量化资金目标；并使资金流动符合巴黎协定目标；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应欢迎并赞赏过渡委员会关于建立解决损失和损害问题的资金安排，包括为此设立一项基金的建议；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——应强调国际合作的重要作用，包括气候危机的全球性要求尽可能广泛的合作，而这种合作是实现有力度的减缓行动和气候韧性发展的关键推动因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十五、中美两国致力于进一步加强对话、协作努力，支持主席国阿联酋成功举办COP28。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>