<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[危险的快递驿站：一场不该发生的意外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh20BlLq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;589&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh2 0BlLq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The doctor asked us to prepare for the worst&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At noon on August 25, 2023, Zhang Xiang, who was on a business trip, received When I got the call that my wife was injured and rushed back to Taiyuan, Shanxi Province, it was already past two o&#39;clock in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The son was sitting on an iron chair in the waiting area, keeping his mother&#39;s mobile phone, myopia glasses, and the pair of white sandals that he had thrown off when he fell from the second floor. Lin Mei was lying on the hospital bed with her eyes open and her face pale. She was soon sent to the intensive care unit (ICU). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon that day, Lin Mei had cut the vegetables. The message pushed by the Tmall APP on her mobile phone showed that the plasticine purchased online for her son had arrived at the Cainiao Station near the community. She put down the kitchen knife, casually wore a pair of jeans and a pair of white sandals, and took her son out to pick up the express delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If everything goes well, she will pick up the express delivery and return home in 10 minutes and prepare lunch. They had just moved into this new house, and the developer called the couple to apply for a real estate certificate together. Unfortunately, the housing management center was off work at that time, and they agreed to do it as soon as they got back from a business trip. She and her husband are high school classmates. They have known each other for 20 years and been married for more than ten years. After working hard together, they finally have a car, a house and a 10-year-old son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The first floor of the station is a convenience store, and the second floor is the Cainiao Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by respondent)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the later surveillance video that when picking up the parcel, Lin Mei was looking at the pickup code on her mobile phone while looking for the express delivery on the shelf. She did not notice at all that there was an open hole under her feet. , she unfortunately fell into the hole at her feet while looking sideways for the courier. The opening is usually used by the boss to load and unload goods. The height from the opening on the second floor to the ground on the first floor is 2.8 meters. The opening should usually be closed, but it was not closed in time when the incident occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Cainiao Station uses a steel frame and steel plate structure to divide the space of a shop into two floors. The first floor is a convenience store selling fruits and vegetables, and the second floor is for express delivery. You usually need to go to the second floor to find the items. Self-service scan code pickup. The express delivery station and the convenience store have the same owner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the owner of the inn, he once fell from the entrance of the cave. At that time, he accidentally dodged and fell. He only injured his leg and rested for a while. &quot;He had psychological defenses, but my wife didn&#39;t have any psychological defenses. She was completely confused when she fell and had no idea what happened.&quot; Zhang Xiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lin Mei in the hospital bed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Outside the ICU door, Zhang Xiang wrote a few lines of note about &quot;Don&#39;t think about it&quot; and asked the nurse to send it in. He also added in the blank space of the paper &quot;You can visit at five o&#39;clock every afternoon&quot;, drew two smiling faces, and included a pen for him to send in. Lin Mei can write something. When the note was sent out later, it was wet and there was no writing on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After his vital signs stabilized, he underwent three surgeries in succession, and various complications occurred, including pneumonia, urinary system infection, pressure ulcers, and blood clots. “The four major complications accounted for all, and there were new ones every day. Challenge.&quot; Zhang Xiang lost more than ten kilograms in more than a month. &quot;It&#39;s so painful!&quot; He described that the filter for treating blood clots was implanted into the blood vessel from the thigh when it was made, and was removed from the neck when it was removed. come out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first major surgery was cervical spine surgery, and Zhang Xiang was deeply impressed. He remembered that when Lin Mei came out of the operating room, she was lying down with a relaxed expression and a smile on her face, &quot;Because I felt that the operation was finally completed, and I felt that it might be very promising and that she might be cured soon.&quot; Later, like this The smiles are getting fewer and fewer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yu, the attending physician at the Rehabilitation Medicine Department of the Second Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, told Southern People Weekly that during the fall, Lin Mei hit her head on the side wall and suffered a cervical vertebra fracture. Partial spinal cord injury, resulting in quadriplegia. The lower limbs are completely immobile and the upper limbs have very little movement. There is a loss of sensation and movement in the legs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A note written by Zhang Xiang when Lin Mei was in the ICU&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;He explained that the cervical spinal cord is a part of the brain tissue that extends from the brainstem to the spinal canal of the body. After injury, it is not controlled by the brainstem, so symptoms of paralysis will occur. Spinal cord injury results in a loss of the ability to transmit sensations to the brain, resulting in abnormalities in lower-level neurons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The doctor asked us to prepare for the worst.&quot; Zhang Xiang said, &quot;It&#39;s too painful. If cancer is a death sentence, spinal cord injury is equivalent to Ling Chi.&quot; Lin Mei was unable to turn over on her own, and even He cannot move his toes, only pathological twitching, unable to control his nerves voluntarily, has no sweating function, and cannot sense cold or heat. She would suddenly shiver but not feel cold. Sometimes I feel very cold, like being in a world of ice and snow, but actually the quilt covers me well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My upper limbs have little strength and I cannot hold the dishes, so I can only feed him. Zhang Xiang rented a house near the hospital and cooked for his wife. His family members and caregivers took turns taking care of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yu said that there is very little hope of recovery from complete spinal cord injury, and there is almost no hope of recovery. &quot;Lin Mei is currently in a state of complete injury. It is very difficult to recover both legs, but we cannot make a conclusion on the time. Our hospital usually takes about 3 months. If the signs and symptoms are still the same after 3 months , you can draw a conclusion.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Lin Mei’s cumulative treatment expenses have exceeded 180,000 yuan, and there will be many expenses in the future. After many communications, Cainiao has only paid 20,000 yuan so far, and the owner of Cainiao Station has paid 35,000 yuan. For more than a month after the incident, the rookie inn was still operating normally, and even the hole was still in use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An accident that should not have happened completely changed the fate of a family and the life of a 37-year-old woman. Her son had just entered the fifth grade of elementary school, and she might be in a hospital bed for the rest of her life. spend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident exposed many hidden dangers of the express delivery station model. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Dangerous Occurrence: How does Cainiao Station operate? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The owner of a rookie inn in a county told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that his store was opened two years ago, and there are two relatives in the store to help. &quot;For a normal inn, two or three people are enough.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;According to his description, Cainiao does not charge a franchise fee, and the initial investment to open a Cainiao Station is not high: you need to purchase scanners, workbenches, cloud monitoring, shelves and other equipment from the Cainiao official website, and the cost is about 1 About 10,000 yuan; plus the 3,000 yuan deposit, store rent, and water and electricity bills, the cost of opening a rookie post station is basically about 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of store review, “You need to submit an application online after looking at the place and house. The store’s requirements are not strict. After the application is completed, they will come over to see it. Then go directly to the courier or courier company. The person in charge of the area can negotiate the price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The income source of the post station is mainly cooperation with the express company, and the express company pays the delivery fee and mailing income to the owner of the post station. The official website of Cainiao Station shows that the delivery fee for each express delivery is 0.5-1 yuan, and the shipping income is 3-5 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rapid coverage of the post station model is also related to the intensifying price war in the express delivery industry. When express delivery companies trade price for scale, profits will inevitably be affected, resulting in lower outlet delivery fees and further compression of profit margins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save the cost of terminal distribution in the &quot;last mile&quot;, express delivery stations came into being. Survey data from the China Logistics Association shows that terminal distribution costs account for more than 30% of the total costs in the logistics industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Jun was once a self-operated express outlet operator under an e-commerce platform, responsible for the &quot;last mile&quot; end delivery. &quot;The company has indeed made a lot of money.&quot; She mentioned that the express company is responsible for renting houses. Fees, electricity and water bills, and free computer equipment and camera installation. The basic salary of three people at the outlet needs to be paid. In addition, the delivery fee for each express item needs to be paid. The operator only needs to pay a deposit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She and her relatives have been operating the outlet for about 6 years, and the delivery fee has gradually decreased from 4 yuan at the earliest to 1.5 yuan and 1 yuan. In this store, two people are responsible for delivering express delivery, and one person is responsible for guarding the store, responsible for dividing items, sending express delivery, and handling returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will deliver the goods to each customer&#39;s door and call them one by one. At around 4 o&#39;clock in the morning, I need to get up and go to the highway intersection to pick up the express delivery, and then come back to unload the goods and scan the code to separate the parcels. Every day&#39;s parcels must be delivered on the same day. When facing consumers directly, you will encounter various situations. If you want to do this job well, you must have a strong sense of service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, the e-commerce platform shut down its self-operated express delivery company due to high logistics costs, and Chen Jun stopped operating it. &quot;Compared with the ones we did before, this express delivery station model does save a lot of costs for the express delivery company and saves the energy of the courier, but it is not as convenient for users as before.&quot; The express delivery company is fully responsible for end-of-line delivery , it became the inn owner who was responsible for his own profits and losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competition in the industry is fierce, and there are more and more brands of express delivery stations, such as Jitu Express Station, Yuantong Mama Station, Zhongtong Tuxi Life... There will even be multiple express stations in one community. Some netizens use their own Complaints from experience: &quot;Because the community is relatively large, I picked up 6 parcels from 6 different stations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Delivery fees also continue to fall. Two rookie station owners interviewed by &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; Said that in their area, the delivery fees are only 0.3 yuan and 0.5 yuan per order respectively, which are both lower than the prices a few years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Cainiao Station in my community has changed seven or eight owners in the past two years.” A netizen said that the transfer fee of this kind of station is generally not low. The situation of &quot;Po Lee&quot; - the money earned from operating the inn is not as much as the transfer fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, running a side business becomes an option that can increase your income source. According to the official website of Cainiao Station, it mentioned in the introduction &quot;How does Cainiao Station make money?&quot; In addition to the stable fee income, relying on the fixed flow of people brought by the station, it can run side businesses, sell daily necessities, fast-selling products, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the problem is that, as a high-frequency life scenario, express delivery service is the critical &quot;last mile&quot;. If the shop owner cannot invest enough energy, it will be difficult to ensure service quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was the case at the rookie station where Lin Mei had an accident. In this store, the post station has become a side business, and the main business is a fruit and vegetable supermarket. &quot;Since everyone is coming, this is a natural drainage channel, so they put the fruits and vegetables on the first floor, and pick up express delivery on the second floor, and it is self-service.&quot; Zhang Xiang mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUOJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Drilling &quot;holes&quot; privately in the steel frame structure poses safety risks. The &quot;hole&quot; was open at the time of the incident, and Lin Mei fell out of it &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The criticized franchise Model and legal risks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Data from the State Post Bureau show that from 2010 to 2022, my country’s express delivery business volume increased 47.3 times. The rapid development of e-commerce has brought huge demand growth to the express delivery industry. The express delivery station model came into being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;JD.com has built its own logistics since 2007, and has won a reputation among customers with its high-quality services. Alibaba is well aware that the cost of building its own logistics is high. In order to improve the platform&#39;s express delivery service quality, it joined forces with retail, real estate, logistics and other companies to build the Cainiao Network in 2013. Its model is relatively light and it is positioned as the &quot;data hub&quot; in the logistics system. &quot;, that is, a logistics platform that adopts a franchise model. Cainiao Company does not bear the specific operating costs of the station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Jack Ma also stated that he would &quot;definitely not do logistics.&quot; This played a role in the development of Taobao and Tmall and in wooing logistics companies, allowing him to further control the logistics sector. Cainiao has both the traffic provided by Alibaba e-commerce and a stable logistics and distribution network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Alibaba’s 2023 fiscal year annual report, Cainiao Group has become the fastest-growing business within Alibaba Group, with revenue of 55.681 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 21%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, Cainiao Smart Logistics Network Co., Ltd. officially submitted a listing application to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, becoming the first business group to officially start the IPO process since Alibaba’s “1+6+N” organizational reform . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight years ago, Cainiao launched the first &quot;Cainiao Station&quot; to provide express delivery services in Wuhu, Anhui. The prospectus shows that Cainiao now has more than 380 logistics distribution centers and 170,000 post stations around the world. It operates the world&#39;s largest Cainiao post station network and handles more than 80 million packages per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This franchise model has also attracted controversy. Its original intention is to provide consumers with diversified last-mile services and improve delivery efficiency, but it is also very easy to shirk responsibility from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, the courier company is only responsible for the step to the post station, and the post station directly makes money from the courier company, not from the consumers. There is no direct transaction relationship between the rookie and the consumer. . Cainiao has brand influence, but it is difficult to strictly supervise each franchise station, so it is difficult for customers to obtain a better service experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The express delivery station model itself also has certain legal risks. Article 25 of the &quot;Interim Regulations on Express Delivery&quot; issued by the State Council in 2018 stipulates that enterprises engaged in express delivery business shall deliver express delivery to the agreed address, recipient or recipient designated by the recipient, and notify the recipient or The recipient shall accept the goods in person. The recipient or agent has the right to accept the goods in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in the post mode, it is difficult to deliver goods to your door. The owner of the Cainiao Station in the above-mentioned county said that there are indeed many requests for door-to-door delivery. &quot;Everyone can deliver it. Now if the station does not deliver, it may fall on the courier company. The express company will ask the courier to deliver it to him, and then he will complain later.&quot; There will be a fine if you use the post station.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, on social platforms, some users said, &quot;It is useless to complain. You will be blacklisted by the post station, and you will not be included in the warehouse in the future. You will have to return it from the post station every time. When you go to an express delivery outlet, your delivery will always be slower than others. Currently, there is no effective method.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Yinggang, a partner at Jingheng Law Firm, told Southern People Weekly that without Consumers agree that express delivery companies have no right to put goods purchased by consumers into express delivery stations. The e-commerce contract signed by consumers through the Internet stipulates that the purchased goods will be delivered to the designated address with free shipping or payment of postage. &quot;If the express delivery company changes the delivery location or delivery method without the consent of the consumer, it will constitute a breach of contract. They should be responsible for continuing to perform the contract or other remedies, and bear liability for breach of contract.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consequences of the safety hazards caused by poor supervision of the station are even more serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the official website of Cainiao Post, the specific requirements for the post store are: located on the first floor (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;parallel to the road&lt;/span >;), there is no floor limit for office buildings and commercial buildings. However, the station where Lin Mei&#39;s accident occurred did not comply with this requirement and built a steel frame structure privately, and was not subject to supervision and rectification by Cainiao Company during its operating hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Consumers have absolutely no idea what the relationship is between the head office and the outlets. They only know that Cainiao is a big company. Going to pick up packages is completely the information pushed to us by Tmall’s backend. This is a public operation. place, but there was no safety guarantee at all, which led to the tragedy.&quot; Zhang Xiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Yinggang said that in the Lin Mei incident, &quot;In the case of franchising, from the perspective of consumer protection, and based on franchising, the franchisor and the franchise store should bear joint and several liability to the outside world. The owner of the station If its own negligence or fault causes harm to others during the service process, the liability for compensation cannot generally be exempted. Without the consent of the consumer, the express delivery company should also bear joint tort liability.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;After the Fall&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wake up every day is the most painful moment for Zhang Xiang. Do you think this is true? If only it were a dream. But the reality is so cruel and real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he needs to cheer up and comfort his lover when she is depressed and breaks down crying. He read Su Dongpo&#39;s poems and Shi Tiesheng&#39;s articles to Lin Mei by the bedside, telling her that a person&#39;s destiny cannot be perfect and there will always be some ups and downs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than two months, Lin Mei has been lying in the ward most of the time. Occasionally, she can see the clouds outside the window. &quot;Look, there are more and more clouds outside.&quot; She looked at the clouds, Tell Zhang Xiang. This reminded him of an ordinary day in the past. When the two of them were walking together, Lin Mei would say: &quot;Look at the clouds in the sky. In fact, let&#39;s take a walk outside together, look at the clouds in the sky, and enjoy the beautiful scenery of nature.&quot; The wind is very happy.&quot; Zhang Xiang said, &quot;Now that I think about it, I was the happiest at that time, but I didn&#39;t think so at that time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Xiang&#39;s eyes, Lin Mei is a very simple and knowledgeable person. The person who runs the house, she is the only one who knows where everything in the house is. Just after the accident, Zhang Xiang stayed home for one night, but &quot;I couldn&#39;t sleep at all. I felt very uncomfortable every night. I saw her marks and shadow everywhere in the house. I couldn&#39;t do anything about it.&quot; Sleep. In a rental house, a strange place is better.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since they were together, Lin Mei would make dumplings for Zhang Xiang in person every year on his birthday. Not long ago, on Zhang Xiang&#39;s birthday, Lin Mei said to him, &quot;I can&#39;t make dumplings for you today.&quot; &quot;Later, my mother made dumplings and I went home to get them. She didn&#39;t eat many, only five or six.&quot; Zhang Xiang recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the business trip, Zhang Xiang went to the supermarket to buy a crucian carp and made Lin Mei&#39;s favorite crucian carp soup. He remembered that Lin Mei was very happy to finish eating that day. She took out his leather shoes and polished them. The white edges of the black leather shoes were polished as white as snow. &quot;It&#39;s like new ones.&quot; Zhang Xiang sighed, &quot;When I came back, I saw this pair The edges of the shoes are still white, but the person is no longer the same.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yu mentioned that in the hospital, the golden recovery period is 3-6 months. If you are paralyzed for a long time, the unavoidable complication is the reduction of cardiopulmonary function. If there is no financial pressure, you can do some rehabilitation training and use movable limbs to compensate for the out-of-control limbs. Some training in life and work can improve other functions of the body. maintained at a certain level. The follow-up care and family recovery stages place higher demands on caregivers, and require a lot of hard work from family members and caregivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I once promised to take her to some places. I originally planned to go this year. No matter how she recovers in the future, I will take her there even if she is in a wheelchair. Of course, it will be very inconvenient to sit in a wheelchair, so I just want to cure her as much as possible and fulfill my promise to her.&quot; Zhang Xiang said that he would continue to &quot;demand justice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a young writer, Zhang Xiang had a new book published in August. After Lin Mei’s accident, the publishing house sent him a sample book by express delivery, but he found that he could only go to the Cainiao Station to pick it up. “I feel like I don’t want to do this all my life. I have to go to that place again, but I have no choice but to get my book, because I have no choice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Mei and Chen Jun are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直男最爱的迪卡侬，靠卖一条裙子赚了几十亿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a style of sports culottes has become popular on social media What is surprising is that this &quot;fairy skirt&quot; is neither Lululemon, a must-have for the middle class, nor well-known brands such as Nike and Under Armor, but Decathlon, an old friend of straight men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Decathlon, which has always been known as an affordable paradise and a favorite among straight men, why did it rely on women to get out of the industry this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data shows that since 2022, the number of notes about Decathlon on Xiaohongshu has reached 100,000+. With the surge in traffic, it has also driven the sales of its women&#39;s products. Sales, according to the top 5 sales of its Taobao official flagship store, the lowest-ranked women&#39;s yoga pants have sales of up to 30,000+. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, Decathlon’s annual sales will reach 14 billion euros, and China has become one of the largest overseas markets, among which women’s demand is the most dazzling. In Decathlon’s official store, Women&#39;s products account for about half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is closely related to the development of China&#39;s outdoor economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China&#39;s outdoor products market will reach 315 billion yuan in 2020, and is expected to reach 599 billion yuan in 2025. Compared with European and American countries, the scale of my country&#39;s outdoor economic market is still Larger development space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A survey shows that the groups participating in outdoor sports in China are mainly young women in the front line and new front lines. They spend more, buy more, and save more to become contemporary women. The three major characteristics of tourism consumption have gradually set off a niche movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, Decathlon has seen the development potential of &quot;female consumers + niche sports&quot;. Today, &quot;Know&quot; will take you to explore Decathlon&#39;s transformation secrets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73293&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70108&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256944&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73287&quot; group-id=&quot;0 &quot; asset-id=&quot;70102&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P2 .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256945 &quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73288&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70103&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256946&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73289&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70104&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P4. jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256947&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73290&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70105&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256948&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img -id=&quot;73291&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70106&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; img -title=&quot;P6-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256949&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73292&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70107&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P7-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256950&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省卫健委党组书记、主任朱宏接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260404]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:55:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision: Zhu Hong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law. He voluntarily surrendered and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Hong’s resume&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Hong, male, Han nationality, born in September 1966, with an on-the-job postgraduate degree, started working in September 1982, and started working in March 1986. Joined the Chinese Communist Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has successively served as member of the Party Committee and Vice President of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, director of the Guangdong Provincial Medical Academic Exchange Center, secretary of the Party Committee of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, and secretary and director of the Party Leadership Group of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探索宇宙中相互竞争的隐秘力量：欧几里得望远镜发布首批照片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 09:14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 7, 2023, Beijing time, the European Space Agency released the Euclid Telescope (Euclid) The first 5 full-color pictures taken. These images are the result of scientists&#39; preliminary processing of the first batch of data obtained by the Euclid Telescope, but they have already demonstrated the powerful observation capabilities of the telescope - no telescope has ever obtained such clear images across such a large area of ​​the sky before. image. They believe that this telescope is ready to create the largest three-dimensional map of the universe in history, helping us gain insights into the nature of dark matter and dark energy in the &quot;dark&quot; universe, thereby revealing the hidden secrets of the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclid is a famous ancient Greek mathematician and is known as the &quot;Father of Geometry&quot;. His &quot;Elements of Geometry&quot; has been passed down to the world and laid the foundation for the development of geometry for more than two thousand years. Foundation. Scientists now realize that the density of matter and energy is closely related to the geometry of the universe and determines its future. Therefore, the European Space Agency (ESA) decided to name the telescope that explores the structure and evolution of the universe after Euclid to commemorate the pioneer of geometry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Key Questions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the current mainstream cosmological theory, only 5% of the visible ordinary matter in the universe is , the remaining 95% includes 25% dark matter and 70% dark energy. Therefore, understanding the nature of dark matter and dark energy has become one of the most important issues in science today. The Euclid telescope is expected to play an important role in research in this area over the next decade and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a range of up to 10 billion light-years, Euclid will observe billions of galaxies in more than 1/3 of the sky, creating a picture of the large-scale structure of the universe. picture. Scientists hope to study five key issues in cosmology by exploring the composition and evolution of the &quot;dark&quot; universe: the structure and evolutionary history of the cosmic web (matter in the universe is arranged in a huge network), what dark matter is, and the nature of the universe. How expansion changes over time, what the nature of dark energy is, and whether we really fully understand gravity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2007, researchers proposed two research plans in response to the European Space Agency&#39;s space exploration plan from 2015 to 2025, namely the &quot;Dark Universe Explorer&quot; (Dark Universe Explorer). DUNE) and the Spectroscopic All Sky Cosmic Explorer (SPACE). Both proposals propose complementary techniques to detect dark energy. After a period of evaluation and demonstration, the two plans were merged, and this became the later Euclid Telescope. In October 2011, the European Space Agency&#39;s Science Mission Committee selected the Euclid Telescope; in June 2012, the telescope project was officially established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than ten years of demonstration, design, construction and testing, the Euclid Telescope is finally ready for use. On July 1, 2023, the Euclid Telescope was successfully launched from the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Site in Florida, USA, on board the Falcon 9 rocket of the US Space Exploration Company (SpaceX). At the end of July, the telescope flew near the Sun-Earth&#39;s second Lagrange point, about 1.5 million kilometers away from the Earth, and successfully entered its working orbit. The European Space Agency&#39;s Gaia telescope and NASA&#39;s James Webb Space Telescope are also in orbit around this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artistic illustration of the workings of the Euclidean telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope is about 4.7 meters high and 3.7 meters in diameter. It consists of a service module and a load module composition. Among them, the payload module that performs the detection function includes a 1.2-meter-diameter telescope and two scientific instruments: the visible light band camera (VIS) and the near-infrared band camera (NISP); the service module mainly includes power generation and distribution, attitude control, data Devices for handling, propulsion, thermal control, remote control and telemetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Space Agency has high hopes for the Euclid telescope. &quot;Dark matter pulls galaxies together, causing them to spin faster than visible matter itself can explain; dark energy is driving the accelerating expansion of the universe. For the first time, the Euclid Telescope will allow cosmologists to study these competing forces simultaneously Dark mysteries,&quot; European Space Agency science director Carole Mundell said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website. &quot;The Euclid Telescope will help us make leaps in understanding the entire universe, and these beautiful images show that , the mission is poised to help answer one of the biggest mysteries of modern physics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Amazing Images&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The first five images released by the Euclid Telescope are the Perseus Cluster of galaxies, the spiral galaxy IC 342, the irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822, the globular star cluster NGC 6397 and the Horsehead Nebula. Picture of (The Horsehead Nebula). The field of view of the telescope for observation is very large, reaching 0.5 square degrees, which exceeds the sky area occupied by the full moon. It took less than a day to shoot the five images released this time. From bright stars to faint galaxies, the Euclid Telescope relies on its powerful observation capabilities to create exceptionally clear visible and infrared images. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perseus is one of the largest known structures in the universe, located 240 million light-years from Earth. This image of the Perseus Galaxy Cluster shows the 1,000 galaxies that are part of the cluster, along with more than 100,000 more distant galaxies in the background. This is the first time astronomers have been able to capture so many of the Perseus Galaxy at such a high level of detail in such a large image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Perseus Galaxy Cluster photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of these faint galaxies have not been observed by astronomers before because some of them are very They are so far away that it took 10 billion years for their light to reach us. Astronomers have shown that galaxy clusters like Perseus could only form if dark matter was present in the universe. They will observe many galaxy clusters like Perseus through the Euclid telescope and map the distribution and shape of the galaxies in them to learn more about how dark matter binds these galaxies together to form galaxy clusters and shapes us The universe as seen today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While in orbit, the Euclid Telescope will image billions of galaxies, revealing the invisible effects of dark matter and dark energy on them. Among the first galaxies observed by Euclid, one was nicknamed the &quot;Hidden Galaxy&quot;. This spiral galaxy similar in shape to the Milky Way was officially numbered IC 342, also known as Caldway. Er number 5. Thanks to the infrared capabilities of the Euclid Telescope, astronomers have discovered key information about the stars in this galaxy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The spiral galaxy IC 342 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early universe, most galaxies did not look like the typical spiral shape of the Milky Way. Not only are they irregular in appearance, they are also small and form the building blocks of larger galaxies like the Milky Way. We can still find some such galaxies in the relatively nearby universe. Among the images released by the Euclid Telescope, there is an irregular dwarf galaxy numbered NGC 6822, 1.6 million light-years away from the Earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope also photographed the globular star cluster NGC 6397, which is the second closest to Earth globular star cluster, about 7,800 light-years from Earth. Globular star clusters are collections of hundreds of thousands of stars held together by gravity. Currently, no other telescope other than Euclid can see an entire globular cluster in a single observation and identify so many stars in the cluster at the same time. These faint stars can tell us about the history of the Milky Way and the location of dark matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Globular star cluster NGC 6397 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the celestial objects for which the Euclid Telescope released images this time, the Horsehead Nebula is the closest One, also known as Barnard 33, is part of the constellation Orion and is about 1,500 light-years away from Earth. In this image of the Horsehead Nebula, we can see not only the spectacular panorama, but also the fine details. In new Euclid observations of the stellar cradle, scientists expect to find many faint, never-before-seen Jupiter-mass planets in their early stages of formation, as well as young brown dwarfs and baby stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Horsehead Nebula taken with the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Six years&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;continuous observation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Although only 5 pictures were released in the first batch, these pictures already reflect the tremendous efforts of the scientists and engineers behind the development of the telescope to create these masterpieces. Euclid project manager Giuseppe Racca said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website: &quot;Our high standards for this telescope have paid off. There is so much detail in these images, thanks to Special optical design, perfect manufacturing and assembly of the telescope and instruments and extremely precise pointing and temperature control.&quot; said René Laureijs, Euclid project scientist Comment: &quot;We have never seen astronomical images like this before, with so much detail. They are more beautiful and clearer than we could have hoped for, showing us much that has never been seen before in the known regions of the nearby universe. Characteristics. Now we are ready to observe billions of galaxies and study their evolution throughout the history of the universe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The debut of the Euclid Telescope has inspired the astronomical community, and many people insist that Have the same opinion as Rene Laures. The images demonstrate the extraordinary capabilities of the Euclid Telescope&#39;s various instruments, which allow astronomers to study the distribution of matter in the universe and its evolution on the largest scales. Based on a large number of high-quality observations covering large areas of the sky, they will show us dark and hidden parts of the universe. And beyond the realms of dark matter and dark energy, these images show how Euclid can help astronomers create a treasure trove of information about the physics of individual stars and galaxies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclidean Union director Yannick Mellier said: &quot;Over the next few months, Euclid Union scientists will analyze these images and develop A series of scientific papers are published in the journal &lt;em>;Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics&lt;/em>;, as well as papers on the scientific objectives and instrument performance of the Euclid mission.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In the months since the Euclid Telescope was launched, scientists and engineers have been testing and calibrating the telescope&#39;s science equipment. The team is currently making final fine-tuning in order to begin regular observations in early 2024. As the mission progresses, data obtained by the telescope will be released annually and open to researchers around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, the Euclid telescope will carry out observations for six years, after which the possibility of extending the mission will be evaluated based on the remaining amount of cryogenic gas used for propulsion. In the next six years, we can expect that the Euclid Telescope will continue to bring us new surprises and use more wonderful pictures to show us the hidden charm of the universe. The analysis of observational data will last longer, and astronomers will carefully search for clues to unravel the mysteries of dark matter and dark energy in these data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[万亿特殊再融资债券：云南、内蒙古、辽宁超千亿，北上广未发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260402]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73412&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70221&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG211250367208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan , ranking first in the country. Visual China/Picture&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257853&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan, Ranked first in the country. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All creditors have been notified to settle their arrears.&quot; A grassroots official from a western province told a Southern Weekend reporter that the funds for the special refinancing bonds issued this time have been received and are being paid. Complete government debt. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, various regions began to issue special refinancing bonds on a large scale. According to statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, as of November 5, 25 provinces (municipalities and autonomous regions) have issued a total of 1.13 trillion yuan, equivalent to Gansu&#39;s GDP in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special refinancing bonds are issued by provincial governments. For municipal and county governments, they are equivalent to an extra amount of low-interest debt repayment funds, which can replace high-interest debts and lengthen the repayment cycle. Compared with refinancing bonds issued in ordinary times, special refinancing bonds do not list specific bond information for repayment. According to past issuance history, it is mainly used to repay implicit debts in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A number of local financial system officials revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that this special refinancing bond has two main investment purposes, one is to replace high-interest non-standard debt, and the other is to repay the debt owed by government departments to enterprises. accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of this round of special refinancing bonds, the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on July 24, emphasizing the need to effectively prevent and resolve local debt risks and formulate and implement a package of debt reduction plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Zhang Qingsong, deputy governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, said at the International Financial Leaders Investment Summit that &quot;a few provinces may face debt repayment pressure, and most of the debts of the relevant provinces are backed by real assets. Add A package of market-oriented plans has been formulated, and I believe that with the implementation of targeted policies, some local government debt risks will gradually be reduced.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, and Liaoning issued over 100 billion yuan&lt;/p>; h4>; &lt;p>;According to the issuance information of this special refinancing bond, as of November 5, the top three provinces by issuance amount are: Yunnan (107.6 billion yuan), Inner Mongolia (106.7 billion yuan), Liaoning (100.6 billion yuan) . The region with the least issuance is Shanxi, with only 2.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the debt ratio is calculated as (government debt/GDP)*100%, in 2022, the debt ratios of the above three places will rank first among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions (excluding Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan). Nine, tenth, twelfth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, only six regions including Beijing, Guangdong, Shanghai, Zhejiang, Hainan and Tibet did not issue special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Guangdong, Zhejiang, Shanghai, and Beijing have low debt ratios and developed economies. The government debt of Hainan and Tibet is not large. In 2022, Tibet&#39;s government debt balance is only 56.8 billion yuan, ranking last among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions. Hainan’s debt balance is 348.7 billion yuan, ranking fourth from the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of issuance structure, as of November 5, among the special refinancing bonds issued, the scale of general bonds was 759.4 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%; the scale of special bonds was 368.6 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%. 32.7%. General bonds have a wide range of uses for funds, while special bonds have limited investment options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this round of special refinancing bond issuance, no department has yet explained the quotas for each region. However, judging from the issuance situation, funds still flow more to the central and western provinces with relatively low fiscal self-sufficiency rates, as well as regions with larger debt scales and higher debt ratios. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The province requires us to deal with high-interest non-standard debt first.” A financial system official in a northern province told Southern Weekend reporters that after issuing special refinancing bonds, his prefecture-level city obtained With more than 10 billion yuan in funds, arrangements are currently being made to redeem non-standard products. Since the beginning of this year, there have been many non-standard defaults in the local area, which has put great pressure on repaying principal and interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to debt replacement, another important purpose is to pay off the government&#39;s debts to enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, the bond issuance information disclosed by Inner Mongolia showed that it plans to issue 66.32 billion yuan of refinancing general bonds, and the funds raised will be used to repay the arrears of corporate accounts that the government is responsible for repaying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, the above-mentioned bond issuance materials were updated, and the purpose of the funds was adjusted to repay existing debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Audit Work Report on the Budget Implementation and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures of the Autonomous Region in 2022&quot; previously released by Inner Mongolia showed that the policy of clearing up the accounts of small and medium-sized enterprises owed to private enterprises has not been implemented, and 62 companies are owed 111 million yuan. . In addition, at the end of 2021, Inner Mongolia&#39;s temporary payment balance was as high as 47.055 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 20, Premier Li Qiang chaired an executive meeting of the State Council. The meeting pointed out that the provincial government should take overall responsibility for the settlement of arrears in the region, promptly solve the problem of government arrears on corporate accounts, and untie the &quot;chain&quot; of mutual arrears between enterprises, and central and state-owned enterprises should take the lead in repayment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Every creditor is now required to complete the procedures first.” The grassroots official in the western province mentioned above said that for example, in the past when building a road, the company had to complete a complete set of procedures for completion acceptance and submit it to the province for review and approval before releasing the loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some regions have begun to offer discounts to repay accounts owed to companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, Wuxi Delinhai Environmental Protection Technology Co., Ltd. (688069.SH) issued an announcement stating that the company, Yuxi Water Conservancy Bureau and Dali Erhai Protection Investment and Construction Co., Ltd. had receivables for some projects. The accounts receivable reached a debt restructuring plan, and the above-mentioned accounts receivable totaled 160 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement, Delinhai agreed to give the debtor a certain discount and is expected to recover 120 million yuan through this debt restructuring. Industrial and commercial information shows that Erhai Investment Company is a state-owned enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement explains that there are two backgrounds for this debt restructuring. First, the above-mentioned National Council meeting requires that the problem of corporate account arrears be solved; second, the Yunnan Provincial Government strives to resolve the existing hidden debts and implement hidden debts. The policy of clearing sexual debts was implemented and the implementation of a number of debt reduction measures was implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The issuance of special refinancing bonds is undoubtedly an important part of the debt reduction measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73413&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70222&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG1515.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2266&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257854&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Faster and higher than the previous two rounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, there have been two peak issuance periods of special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that from December 2020 to September 2021, a total of 627.8 billion yuan of special refinancing bonds were issued, mainly used for the pilot program of implicit debt resolution in incorporated counties. Immediately afterwards, from October 2021 to June 2022, a total of 504.18 billion yuan was issued, mainly for the pilot program without hidden debt in the entire region, concentrated in Beijing, Shanghai, and Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Luo Zhiheng, president of the Guangdong Securities Research Institute, the proportion of local government bond renewals from 2018 to 2022 were 81.3%, 87.3%, 87.2%, 86.3% and 86.1% respectively, all at the The higher level is mainly to repay bonds issued in 2015-2017. From January to August 2023, the renewal ratio will increase to 90.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maturity renewal ratio = (refinancing bonds - special refinancing bonds) / maturity size. Generally speaking, after local government bonds mature, in addition to issuing refinancing bonds, fiscal funds, etc. will also be arranged for repayment. In other words, as the tight financial balance of local governments intensifies, they rely more on issuing bonds to renew maturing debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the previous two rounds of special refinancing bonds issued, this issuance is faster. In just over a month, the issuance amount exceeded one trillion yuan. The amount of this issuance is also close to the sum of the previous two rounds, and it has not yet ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that after refinancing bonds replace implicit debt, it will increase the government debt balance. According to current regulations, local government debt (general debt and special debt) is subject to limit control. The difference between the debt limit and the debt balance is the maximum issuance amount of local special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the main issuance of general bonds as an example. As of November 5, seven regions including Inner Mongolia, Tianjin, and Guizhou have exceeded the local maximum issuance quota, that is, the debt ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Laicheng, a professor at the Central University of Finance and Economics, told Southern Weekend reporters that the issuance of special refinancing bonds in some places may exceed local debt limits. To this end, the Ministry of Finance will make overall adjustments and increase the debt limits of some regions on the basis of the local debt limits approved by the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the &quot;Report on the 2022 Municipal Budget Adjustment Plan (Draft)&quot; released by Chongqing City in September 2022 mentioned that the Ministry of Finance requires that the balance limit of special debt should be approximately 70%. It is retained by each province (autonomous region and municipality) and recovered by the central government at a proportion of approximately 30% for overall deployment among provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as a special means, special refinancing bonds can only relieve local government debt pressure in the short term, and the issuance amount is limited, which cannot completely solve the hidden debts of various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An executive of a county-level urban investment company in the north told Southern Weekend reporters that his province issued tens of billions of special refinancing bonds this time because the company had successively experienced non-standard overdue incidents this year. Due to heavy debt pressure, he reported to higher-level government departments to apply for bond funding support, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, after the issuance of trillions of special refinancing bonds, the financing demand of local urban investment platforms remains strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of a financial leasing platform in Shanghai told Southern Weekend reporters that several provinces he is responsible for have issued special refinancing bonds, but it has not affected business development. Several urban investment platforms he has recently contacted, Liquidity is still urgently needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花都华侨农场访问记：海外中国人筚路蓝缕，在国内也同样熠熠发光]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260343]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent weekend, I took my son to wander around Ersha Island in Guangzhou and accidentally stumbled into the Guangdong Overseas Chinese Museum. , the overseas Chinese farm in one of the exhibition halls aroused my strong interest. As a teacher engaged in sociology, I came up with the idea of ​​visiting the overseas Chinese farm. I searched online and found out that there is an overseas Chinese farm on the outskirts of my city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were no classes on November 6, so early in the morning, I made an appointment with a colleague to go to the destination - the overseas Chinese farm located in Huadong Town, Huadu District, Guangzhou City. Huadu Overseas Chinese Farm has an area of ​​14.55 square kilometers and a registered population of more than 5,200, including residents from 13 countries and regions including Indonesia, Vietnam, Malaysia, Thailand, Japan, Singapore, Cambodia, India, Laos, New Zealand, Madagascar, Hong Kong, and Macau. There are more than 4,800 returned overseas Chinese and their family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The past and present life of Overseas Chinese Farm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After an hour&#39;s drive, we arrived at the &quot;Overseas Chinese Farm&quot; bus station. After briefly consulting an aunt at the canteen, we went to Qiao Xingyuan Community across the road. She said that many returned overseas Chinese live here. The community is not small, with nearly 30 houses together. Half of the houses have an elevated first floor, and there are some privately built houses scattered on the mountain behind. On the empty platform on the first floor of a house, we met two aunties who were busy packing mobile phone cases. They were returned overseas Chinese from Vietnam. My colleagues and I chatted with them while helping to install mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They returned to China in 1978, when they were only 10 and 8 years old respectively, and were placed here together. At that time, the management of the farm separated men and women, and they lived in collective dormitories. Even if they are a family, they must be spread out and cannot live together. The dormitory at that time was made of mud bricks, with rows of bunk beds inside. Due to the large number of people, the space was very small. Later, because too many returned overseas Chinese were accepted, the dormitories were not enough, so they had to live in ancestral halls in nearby villages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of agricultural production and livelihood, the farm is similar to the surrounding villages. They are also divided into several production teams. In addition to planting rice, vegetables, peanuts, fruits, oranges, lychees, and mangoes, they also cultivate On the hillside, tea plantations are planted. It is reported that as early as the late 1970s, the Overseas Chinese Farm was the most important tea production base in Huadu. The tea industry was once prosperous, and the tea produced was well-known throughout the province and sold at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene of planting tea in the mountains is still vivid in my mind. An aunt said that everyone used axes and hoes to open up the densely forested hills and turned them into tea planting bases. Without machinery, they carried small tea seedlings to the mountains with bare hands to plant them, and then carried buckets of water for watering. Gradually, a lush green tea mountain was formed in the Qifengtian and Wan Gongtang areas, covering an area of ​​several hundred hectares. At that time, we had to work on time every day. We usually got up at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning to pick tea, because the dew was thick at that time, which was the best time to pick tea. Although the conditions are difficult, everyone is very motivated. During the lunch break, everyone will gather together and listen to one of them reading the day&#39;s newspaper aloud, and sometimes someone will take the lead in singing...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is , all returned overseas Chinese who settle on farms can enjoy the same benefits and treatment as urban residents, including food stamps, cloth stamps, meat stamps and other material supplies. Now, after they have retired for many years, they can also enjoy retirement salary benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, the aunt told us that rural people in eight villages within ten miles are proud to marry their daughters to the farm, because the daughter will immediately become an &quot;employee&quot; who can &quot;enjoy benefits&quot;, and her personal destiny will be A major turnaround could occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, the local government decided to implement a housing renovation project for Huaqiao Farm, investing 130 million yuan, with a total construction area of ​​more than 70,000 square meters, and built new buildings such as Qiaonan Garden, Qiaogang Garden, and Qiaoxing Garden. In residential areas, employees only need to pay a small amount of money to live in spacious and bright houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aren&#39;t the surrounding villagers envious of you?&quot; I asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That was true at the time, but it&#39;s different now. We envy them very much.&quot; said an aunt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government of Huadong Town, where the overseas Chinese farm was originally located, has taken advantage of its proximity to Baiyun International Airport in recent years and is committed to building an aviation logistics industry cluster, an aviation maintenance industry cluster, an e-commerce industry cluster and a temporary logistics cluster. It is an empty advanced manufacturing agglomeration area and carries out high-intensity development of overseas Chinese farms and nearby villages. Because overseas Chinese farms themselves are state-owned land, they are land development and utilization activities within the government that do not involve property rights replacement, and provide visible benefits to farm employees. However, the situation in nearby villages is different. Many villagers have received considerable compensation for their land expropriation. Some even only need to pay an additional tens of thousands of yuan to live in various comprehensive and complete buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aunts can earn 80-100 yuan a day by doing odd jobs packaging mobile phone cases. Anyway, when they are free at home, they just look at their mobile phones and do something, which makes them comfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original words of an aunt were, &quot;When I was very young, my mother taught me to be hardworking. Now that I am retired, but my body is still strong, I just find something to do, and I feel at ease.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some people know how to play cards and check their mobile phones after retirement, but I don&#39;t like it. I feel bad when I lose money playing cards; it hurts my eyes because I look at my mobile phone all the time. I feel uncomfortable, so I might as well do something.&quot; Another person An aunt said this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The role of returned overseas Chinese&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nearly 12 noon, the aunts will go home for dinner. After saying goodbye to them, we went to Qiao Nan Garden across the road to find food. In a restaurant, we met a family of returned Indonesians having dinner. We simply said hello to them and explained our purpose, but they were so enthusiastic that they invited us to eat with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the chat during the dinner, I learned that my aunt’s surname was Wen, and she was the fourth eldest child in the family. She had an older brother, two older sisters, and a younger sister. She returned to China in 1960, when she was 6 years old. Today, the old mother is 98 years old, her mind is still clear and her spirit is still strong. Aunt Wen said that her grandfather went to Indonesia in his early years and was one of the first batch of people to &quot;go to Southeast Asia&quot;. They raised pigs, made tofu, got married and settled down locally. Her parents also inherited their ancestors&#39; business and made a living mainly by making and selling tofu in small cities or towns in southwestern Indonesia. Obviously, they have no choice to settle or make a living in capitals or big cities where competition is fiercer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diligence, frugality, running a small business, and moving forward in hardship and adversity cannot be underestimated. These traits have laid the foundation for Aunt Wen’s generation to be smart and understand business since childhood. After returning to China, Aunt Wen and her family successively ran a bean product factory, a garment factory, a wood processing factory and a restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be noted that these so-called &quot;small and micro enterprises&quot; are not privately owned, but are owned by the farm. The products produced must be handed over to the farm for unified sales or other disposal by the farm. Compared with the nearby villagers who have been farming all day long, Aunt Wen&#39;s family and others like Aunt Wen who have worked abroad for a long time are obviously better in thinking and ideas. They have largely promoted the comprehensive transformation and upgrading of the farm, and have contributed to the farm&#39;s development. Industrial diversification has blazed a trail. Relying on their foresight and example, the farm has begun industrialization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a larger scale, Aunt Wen and a group of people took the lead in promoting the rural industrialization process in the Huadu area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as Aunt Wen is concerned, she is bold, outgoing and sociable. She obtained a Class A driver&#39;s license at the age of 18 and became the only female driver in the farm driver class in the 1980s. She often drove long trailers Traveling all over the country, I naturally have a lot of knowledge and quick thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Wen is also an authentic food maker. During every festival, whether it is a Chinese festival or an Indonesian festival, or when someone in the neighborhood gets married, has a baby, or has a child going to school or joining the military. During the banquet, she would prepare various ingredients a week in advance, sometimes even making a special trip to Hong Kong to purchase them, and make all kinds of exquisite snacks with Indonesian characteristics, such as thousand-layer cakes, manjian kueh, pagoda rice, Padang dishes, fermented soybean cubes, Gadot-Gadot, etc., for relatives, friends and neighbors to taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that the status of returned overseas Chinese has allowed the specialties of various countries to be inherited and promoted in overseas Chinese farms. The neighbors are engaged in cross-cultural exchanges while tasting the delicacies of various countries. Such coexistence and frequent exchanges day and night undoubtedly create a It creates a diverse and culturally rich community atmosphere, which plays a positive role in resolving community conflicts and disputes, building a community development community, improving community self-organization capabilities, and enhancing community governance efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The status of returned overseas Chinese also sets an example for the development of future generations. Also present at the dinner was Aunt Wen&#39;s nephew. After dinner, he was about to leave for Hong Kong and then transfer to Indonesia. It turns out that his parents settled in Hong Kong very early. He went to elementary school and middle school in Hong Kong, completed college and graduate school in the United States, and currently works for a real estate company in Bali, Indonesia. It is not difficult to see that the transnational experiences of ancestors or elders have a profound impact on the education level and life experiences of future generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Wen told me that there are a large number of third-generation transnational immigrants on the farm, who to some extent benefit from or benefit from the transnational contact network built by their ancestors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My thoughts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At about 3 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, we asked Aunt Wen to take us to visit some of the places where she had &quot;battled&quot;. She readily agreed, and we successively Went to teams five, six and nine. Along the way, we discovered that the former temporary farm management offices, tea factories, and garment factories had long been transformed, and many new enterprises involving new energy and high-tech fields had been built on the original sites. The simple truth is that Overseas Chinese Farm is a state-owned unit, and its management methods follow the planned economic system to a large extent. Many traditional industries have difficulty keeping up with the new development situation. Many companies have gone bankrupt. Instead, new projects have been launched and new companies have entered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing the place where they once worked, with only a few labels standing there alone, Aunt Wen showed an expression of regret and helplessness. Times are changing, and overseas Chinese farms are also undergoing transformation. This is an unstoppable objective law. In the future, overseas Chinese farms will continue to be deeply integrated into urbanization and modernization. In this process, I think relevant parties can try to carry out the following things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, university teachers, relevant researchers or student groups should be encouraged to carry out oral history research on returned overseas Chinese and their descendants, conduct interviews and surveys of people of all ages, and become a representative of Huadong Town and even Huadu. An important part of district local history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, through cooperation between the government and the private sector, establish an overseas Chinese rural museum or exhibition hall to promote overseas Chinese culture and overseas Chinese spirit, and make it a feature and highlight of Huadu tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, actively apply to build a provincial or municipal international community. Overseas Chinese Farm is a real and genuine international community. Relevant departments cannot or should not do so during the upgrading and follow-up planning process. Blindly &quot;de-farming&quot;, overseas Chinese farms, as a local characteristic, have long become an important component of local knowledge in Huadong Town or Huadu District. Relevant parties need to fully respect the place and respect the authenticity of the place, so that the above-mentioned places can be used in the new era. During the period, the international community construction process was reflected and bloomed, which undoubtedly greatly assisted place marketing and became an important social capital for attracting investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[弄虚作假？二次污染？85亿元苏钢“毒地”疑云]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260398]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:53:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257847&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;On March 18, 2023, technical consultants and volunteers from the public welfare organization &quot;Beijing Grassland Alliance&quot; went to Suzhou Reading International School for investigation. There was a red alert at the gate. Several public interest organizations launched public interest litigation on this matter. Photos provided by interviewees&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Plot snapped up for 8.5 billion&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;actually&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;contains&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;poison&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;cannot be put into operation after development and construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, Listed Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Shanghai Lujiazui Financial and Trade Zone Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Lujiazui)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Requirements&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Go to court&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, Lujiazui issued an announcement to Jiangsu Province due to soil pollution problems. Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;the following&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Abbreviation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and a number of Suzhou government agencies and institutions initiated litigation and claimed 10.044 billion yuan from Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. At present, the Jiangsu Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court has filed the case and has not yet opened a hearing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;before &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, Lujiazui sold it at a high price&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;former site&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;17 plots of land,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;with a total construction area of ​​over 1 million square meters&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui is in&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;The announcement issued on September 29, 2023 stated that &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;02&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;year,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;of which 2 Lot No.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;has been&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;built into a school&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;apply at&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;School License&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&#39;s&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; ;&quot;>;Process&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;One ​​after another, including the &amp;nbsp;2&amp;nbsp; plot Many plots of land are polluted&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>; Since&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Multiple&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;announcements,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;express&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation revealed that a total of 14 pieces of land were polluted, and the area and degree of pollution far exceeded what was disclosed during the listing. 2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In 2022, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;related&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Songti&quot;>;Plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; was named by the central environmental protection inspector, and the local government commissioned a third-party investigation and found that the pollution exceeded the standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui stated in the announcement that the &quot;regulatory changes and transfer process of this land&quot; In the case, each defendant committed a series of violations, committed fraud, and failed to perform their duties in accordance with the law. &quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Release&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Announcement 6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;天&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Later,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;On January 10, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group issued a situation statement, saying&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_ GB2312&quot;>;We are actively responding to the lawsuit and putting the health of the people and the legitimate rights and interests of home buyers first. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Indicates&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Song Dynasty&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Yifang&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot; &quot;>;In 2019, we have&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;learned that Lot 2 does not meet environmental protection requirements&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>;but &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>; was not completed in accordance with the law Soil pollution investigation and remediation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;launched the project Land project construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;and&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;During the development and construction period&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Existence&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Secondary pollution caused by irregular construction operations&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Situation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; &quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter’s interview found that Su Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The plot is a typical industrial land redevelopment case, with soil investigation and evaluation, restoration and land transfer development and utilization spanning the &lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Seven&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, during which our country The laws, regulations, technical specifications and standards for soil pollution prevention and control have been continuously improved from a few to many. The different assessment results before and after may be due to repeated changes and tightening of soil pollution assessment standards, and the rich water system in the south of the Yangtze River, which makes pollution easy to migrate. In this kind of situation, who is responsible for pollution remediation is also a legal problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Buy &quot;poisonous land&quot; at a high price? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In 2016, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group will establish a wholly-owned subsidiary&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank Real Estate Development Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; (hereinafter referred to as &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;) 95% equity is listed for sale, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;’s core assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; are 17 pieces of state-owned land. The land is located to the north of Sutong Road and east of Sugang Road, Xushuguan Town, Suzhou High-tech Zone. It was originally the production plant of Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. After 222 rounds of fierce bidding competition, Lujiazui became the winner of the land with 8.525 billion yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee .png&quot; data-key=&quot;257848&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Suzhou Steel History. Suzhou Steel Group official website/picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The announcement disclosed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;information about Suzhou Iron and Steel Group’s listing in August 2016,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The soil in the non-scorched area of ​​the plot under its name and groundwater are basically not polluted and can be redeveloped and utilized; the pollution in the coking area is mainly concentrated in the local area of ​​No. 4 plot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>; stated in the announcement released on April 14, 2022, &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Based on the public market equity listing information Trust, and reasonable reliance on the administrative actions of government departments&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot; &quot;>;Bidding&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;equity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Su Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Situation Description&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Disclosure&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;,&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Song Dynasty&quot;&quot;>;When transferring the equity in 2016, our company has truthfully disclosed the existence of land under the name of Suzhou Green Bank to a third-party professional agency The investigation results and full text of the report on partial pollution, and the asset assessment report clearly stated that some plots in this area were originally steel coking production areas and may have soil pollution risks.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The &quot;Memorandum on Equity Transactions&quot; signed between Lujiazui and Suzhou Iron and Steel Group shows that the two parties agreed &quot;about the existence of soil pollution in some plots of land&quot; Regarding the matter, according to the relevant investigation and evaluation report filed with the Suzhou Municipal Environmental Protection Bureau, there are no technical obstacles to soil environmental treatment. After the treatment is completed, it will comply with national and local environmental quality standards and can be carried out in accordance with the requirements of existing planning documents. Development and construction. Suzhou Iron and Steel Group will provide environmental management matters for&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Green Bank Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Provide coordination and support&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;According to the plan, Lujiazui will build the first million-square-meter city in Suzhou High-tech Zone here A regional complex project, the project was launched in May 2017, and the development cycle is planned to be 8 years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In addition to building commercial buildings and &quot;Splendid Lanshan&quot; residential buildings, Lujiazui also introduced Suzhou Reading School, a nine-year consistent international school jointly built by Suzhou Lunhua Education Group and Reading School in the UK, is located on Lot 2 of the project. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Unexpectedly&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;The school was built, but it could not recruit students smoothly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, in 2021, Suzhou Reading School is applying for a school license During the certification process, according to the requirements of the Environmental Protection Bureau of Suzhou High-tech Zone, Lujiazui commissioned a third-party agency to investigate The soil pollution status of the land where the school is located was found to be seriously polluted and it could not be put into use through environmental impact assessment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default &quot;>;Mentioned in the fact sheet:&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2019&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot; >;year,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitated Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Lujiazui Yi&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitated Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;fang&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;know&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_ GB2312&quot;>;Plot No. does not meet environmental protection requirements and has not been completed in accordance with the law&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;The soil pollution investigation and restoration treatment of plot No. =&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; started the project construction of this plot. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; year, due to failure to pass the environmental impact assessment acceptance Failed to enable. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; The Lujiazui announcement in Song Dynasty also showed that the Suzhou Municipal Assets and Planning Bureau restored plot No. 2 to industrial (research and development) land, and the Reading school project objectively failed to complete comprehensive acceptance. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot; >;In March 2023, technical consultants and volunteers from the public welfare organization &quot;Beijing Grassland Alliance&quot; went to Suzhou Reading International School for investigation. Several public interest organizations launched public interest litigation on this matter. Photos provided by interviewees&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; A year later, the &quot;poisonous site&quot; was named by the Central Environmental Protection Inspection Team. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In April 2022, Jiangsu Province announced the &quot;Second Central Ecological Environmental Protection Supervision &quot;Processing Status of the Sixth Batch of Letters and Calls Transferred to Our Province&quot; mentioned that the test results of the third-party testing agency showed that many plots of land in the Suzhou Green Bank Project&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The soil&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;benzo[a]pyrene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and naphthalene seriously exceeded the standards and did not meet the land use standards. At the request of the Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee, Lujiazui has suspended&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Related development, construction, and sales work, and implemented strict management of the above-mentioned contaminated land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Inspector&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The report&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;shows that &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee attaches great importance to it and has established a special work class&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation report obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that in 2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;In August 2019, the People&#39;s Government of Xushuguan Town, Suzhou High-tech Zone entrusted the Nanjing Environmental Science Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment to conduct detailed &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; According to the &quot;Song Dynasty&quot; investigation, 7 plots of land exceeded the standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot; >;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;The situation statement mentioned&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;these 7 plots&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312 In 2016, Lujiazui Party and Su Gang agreed to commission a third-party professional organization, the Nanjing Institute of Environmental Science and Technology, to conduct a detailed investigation of the pollution situation in the land. Coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;3&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot; , serif&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;5&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;No. and non-coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; plot (of which only &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song _GB2312&quot;>;plot has been developed and constructed) and can be safely used after treatment and restoration. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Already occupied by residents&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;14&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;Plot No., developed and constructed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;8&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot; >;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;13&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;16&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;Plot and undeveloped construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot; , serif&quot;>;11&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;17&lt;/ span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Plot No. is a land that can be safely used. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>; Land planning diagram. Lujiazui Announcement/Picture (Editor’s note: Because the picture is tilted, the plot number and plot location are not completely aligned.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Based on Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Announcement&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The number of contaminated plots is more than 7 pieces&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;20&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; &quot;>;Over the past 22 years, Lujiazui and various environmental investigation agencies have determined the name of Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The next 14 blocks of land are polluted. Lujiazui filed a complaint against Suzhou Iron and Steel Group, the Suzhou Environmental Science Institute and Suzhou Suzhou Environmental Technology Co., Ltd., as well as related parties, the Suzhou National High-tech Industrial Development Zone Management Committee and the Suzhou Natural Resources and Planning Bureau. Go to court&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;宋体&quot;>;As&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;the third party in the case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters called the plaintiff and third party in the case, and multiple staff members said Regarding the case, you need to ask the Lujiazui Group’s Board Secretary’s Office. On November 9, the Board’s Secretary’s Office responded, “The group has a unified voice and does not accept interviews.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Based on&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Two&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;EIA announcements,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Environmental Science Institute and Environmental Impact Assessment&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Responsibility&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Party&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Relevant personnel of Suzhou University of Science and Technology&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;neither got in touch or&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; refused to be interviewed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Different reference standards lead to different test results&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The development and utilization of contaminated sites requires strict environmental monitoring, assessment, restoration, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;process&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, why are the houses already built? /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The outside world says there is&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;pollution&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The Central Environmental Protection Inspectorate mentioned two pollutants that exceeded the standard:&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Comparison&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;These two pollutants are in 2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014-2022 Numerical values ​​in multiple reports&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;can reveal the hindsight of the &quot;poisonous land&quot; of the Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd. , it is possible that the pollution does exist, but the standards used in the assessment are different, resulting in different&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;different results&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; 2014&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;Divide the land into non-coking areas and coking areas&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>; (heavy pollution),&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty &quot;>;Entrust a third-party environmental company to conduct soil surveys separately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc.&quot;>;Environmental protection organizations&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc. Line&quot;>;Guangzhou Green Network Environmental Protection Service Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;applied to the Suzhou Ecological Environment Bureau for disclosure and obtained the &quot;Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Old Areas (Except for Unclosed Areas)&quot; Preliminary Soil Investigation Report&quot; &quot;Preliminary Investigation Report on Site Pollution in the Coking Area of ​​the Old District of Jiangsu Sugang Group Co., Ltd.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;Site Pollution in the Coking Area of ​​the Old District of Jiangsu Sugang Group Co., Ltd.&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Details&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Investigation Report&quot; and &quot;Coking Area in the Old Area of ​​Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Soil and Groundwater Human Health Assessment Report&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation scope of the four reports covers &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;non-coking areas and coking areas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Benzo[a]pyrene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;It is a type of carcinogen that is also produced during barbecue and is a semi-volatile organic compound&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;is between volatile organic compounds and semi-volatile organic compounds. A soil survey was conducted in the non-coking area in January 2014. Benzo[a]pyrene was not detected at any of the 35 sampling points&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene was not detected in most sample points (34). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;At that time, the investigation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Songti&quot;>;The standard based on is the &quot;Exhibition Land Soil Environmental Quality Evaluation Standard&quot; (HJ350-2007) (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Exhibition Land Standard&quot;), which is an industry standard formulated by the former Ministry of Environmental Protection.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;No&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;It is clear that these two pollutants require mandatory testing&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In other subsequent reports, such as&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Notice from the Central Environmental Protection Inspection Team in April 2022, announcements issued by Lujiazui,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In August 2022, a survey commissioned by the Suzhou High-tech Zone and the Nanjing Environmental Science Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment showed that benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene also exceeded standards at some points in the non-coking area. At this time, the reference standard is the national standard &quot;Soil Environmental Quality &amp;nbsp; Soil Pollution Risk Management and Control Standard for Construction Land (Trial)&quot; (GB36600-2018) (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Construction Land Standard&quot;) implemented on August 1, 2018. Previously, Benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene, which are not required to be measured, have been required to be measured. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;equiline&quot;>;&quot;Possible contamination of benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene in non-coking areas It has always existed, but it was not discovered because there was no detection before.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc. line&quot;>;Green Network&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc. line&quot;>;Work Personnel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Guo Lei guessed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;And the parts found in the coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Pollutants,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;are included in each&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;phase report&lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;detection&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, but &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;may be due to&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The limits in the new standards have been tightened, resulting in compliance with the standards before but exceeding them later. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene is like that. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014, 2015&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Soil&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot; >;The survey results show that only&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;sewage treatment area and crude benzene workshop&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; &amp;quot;&quot;>;(That is, part of the No. 4 plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>; mentioned above&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;is contaminated, and naphthalene in other areas does not exceed the standard. The reference at this time is the &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;Exhibition Land Standard&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;B-level standard,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The limit value of naphthalene is 530mg/kg. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;And in the subsequent &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Detection&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Reporting&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Not just&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Plot 4, there are&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;many&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and other pollutants &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Exceeds the standard. Subsequent&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;naphthalene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;limits for reporting reference have been tightened,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;respectively&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;is&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;25mg/kg(&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Type I land&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;70mg/kg (&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Second type of land)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, which are far lower than the previous standard&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;530mg/ kg. &quot;The previous standards were too broad, and the existing standards are based on factors such as human health and are more scientific&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The evaluation is relatively strict.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Guo Lei&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;493&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;257851&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;A summary of key pollutant detection results in various reports and notifications on Suzhou Iron and Steel’s “toxic sites”. Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou and Huang Siqi&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Compiled by Southern Weekend intern Xi Lijie&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Conservative principle&quot; in testing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Although there is no mandatory testing list in the 2014 soil pollution testing requirements, there is a &quot;conservative&quot; in the industry&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;性&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;principle&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In February 2014, the former Ministry of Environmental Protection issued the &quot;Technical Guidelines for Site Environmental Investigation &quot;Principles&quot; (HJ25.1-2014) mentioned that &quot;testing items should be based on the principle of conservatism&quot;: Optional testing items for general industrial sites include semi-volatile organic compounds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;This means that semi-volatile organic compounds such as benzo[a]pyrene are based on Based on the principle of conservatism, it is recommended to test. However, Guo Lei&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;pointed out&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; that the third-party environmental company entrusted by Suzhou Steel did not&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Adopted,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;No detection in non-coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Guo Lei&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;Introduction,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Semi-volatile organic compounds are common pollutants in the soil of steel plant plots. They are pyrolyzed and incompletely burned during coking and coal burning processes. It is released during the process, discharged into the atmosphere, and settles to the nearby ground, thereby contaminating the soil. &quot;Not only the non-coking area, but even the soil outside the factory area may exceed the standard.&quot; Other&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;steel plants&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;also had&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Similar situations have occurred&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;&quot;The Suzhou Steel land parcel is a typical redevelopment of industrial land. Case, its soil survey, land transfer and development spanned the process of our country&#39;s laws, regulations, technical specifications and standards in the field of soil pollution prevention and control from scratch, from less to more.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Guo Lei&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The period during which soil surveys were carried out in the Suzhou Steel plot in 2014&lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, relevant laws, regulations, standards, and technical specifications for soil pollution prevention and control in my country&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Yecai&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;has just started&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;It was not until 2014&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;that the above technical guidelines were born&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;; The Soil Environment Management Measures for Contaminated Lands were not implemented until July 1, 2017; the Soil Pollution Prevention and Control Law was not implemented until January 1, 2019. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Before this, there were only a few departmental notices issued by the former Ministry of Environmental Protection and other departments , does not have high legal effect. A person in the soil remediation industry recalled to Southern Weekend reporter, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Around 2014, the industry was in great chaos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Chongqing Municipal Ecological Environment Bureau and Planning and Natural Resources Bureau released &quot;About &quot;Notice on Further Strengthening the Classified and Hierarchical Management of Soil Pollution in Construction Land&quot; stated&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;:&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;Early Insufficient understanding of soil pollution status investigation, incomplete relevant technical guidelines and regulations, and limited investigation techniques have led to distorted survey results of construction land plots in some heavily polluting industries and inadequate repairs...Soil pollution investigation of some construction lands, The quality of the risk assessment, risk control and restoration effect evaluation reports is not high, the expert review is not strict, and there is a lack of restraint and management on the enterprises and review experts.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify ;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;Regardless of fraud, etc., the above factors alone will cause the soil survey accuracy to be low, resulting in a large gap between the survey results and the actual situation.&quot; Guo Lei said . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Second pollution? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter found that, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The pollution in the coking area is mainly concentrated in Lot 4,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The Lujiazui party was aware of it at the time of the transaction,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc.line&quot;>;has also prepared restoration plans and management. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;In September 2018, &quot;Remediation Project of Contaminated Site in the Coking Area of ​​the Old Area of ​​Suzhou Steel Block&quot; &quot;Environmental Impact Assessment Report Form and Special Assessment&quot; was announced, and the construction unit was Suzhou Green Shore,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;content&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;is soil original&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;>; position and ectopic repair. Announcement&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;>;The link to the original web environmental impact assessment report has expired, but there is a copy posted online&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;>; 97&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;>; environmental impact assessment report with the same name (hereinafter referred to as the environmental impact assessment report). Southern Weekend reporter contacted the environmental impact assessment party&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;>;Suzhou University of Science and Technology&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;>;Technology&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;人员确认，未获得&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;回应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告提到了苏钢老区焦化场地，自2015年启动初步调查、详细调查、修复方案等历时三年多，每一环节均经过专家评审，符合当时的环保要求，但是土壤修复中萘的修复目标值不符合新标准要求，修改后符合&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;GB36600-2018）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;。评价适用标准中，修复后规划为商业用地，土壤参考也是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”第二类&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;用地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;，萘的标准为70mg/kg。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;908&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257852&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;红色为曾进行土壤修复的大概位置。黄色为2022年新发现的4块污染地块。绿网公众号截图。 &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告显示，4号地块将进行土壤修复。但2022年后的多份检测报告显示，4号地块仍然有污染。有土壤修复业内人士向南方周末记者提醒，“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;焦化厂污染是疑难杂症，非常难治理。在江南地区的水文地质条件下，还需要特别注意污染迁移”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;雷丁学校所在的2号地块也被多次报告污染，地图显示，2号地块和4号地块相连。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;苏钢的情况说明提到：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;方在开发建设苏州绿岸地块期间，没有按照有关要求建设地下水阻隔墙及采取其他防护措施，存在扰动地下水、搬运土壤造成部分环境交叉污染的行为和施工作业不规范造成二次污染的行为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;对此&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，陆家嘴还未有回应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2022年7月&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;被苏州生态环境局处罚1.88万，原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违反土壤生态环境管理制度&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违法&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;事实对应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;土壤污染防治法第四十二条第三款&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;风险管控、修复活动完成后，需要实施后期管理的，土壤污染责任人应当按照要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;023年1月10日发布&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;公告表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，苏州生态环境局作出该项处罚的原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸在之前依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏钢集&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;披露的污染区域对&amp;nbsp;4&amp;nbsp;号地块土壤修复后未按要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;汇业律师事务所合伙人、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;环境资源与能源专委会执行主任张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;向南方周末&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;记者&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，如果&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;施工作业导致污染扩散，应对生态环境损害的扩大部分承担责任。但不能&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;排除苏钢集团是否需要对&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;号地块的污染负责，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;其中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;可能涉及多因一果的共同侵权，依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;民法典&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;第1231条的规定，在责任大小认定上需要结合污染范围、程度，以及行为对损害后果所起作用等因素确定&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;毒地修复责任归谁&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;根据已有材料，目前难以断定苏钢集团在交易时是否有所隐瞒、场地调查过程中是否存在不规范行为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;出让了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;标准更迭加严，应该由谁来承担土地污染修复责任？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀告诉南方周末记者，评价交易双方的土地污染修复责任，关键看土地交易交割时期的标准，尤其是强制性标准。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;如果交易前，场地调查已有明确的国家标准，出让方不存在未披露风险情形，在企业存续期间也做到了合法合规达标排放，即使倒查，也无法追究其历史上生态环境损害赔偿责任，交易后的土壤污染风险&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;应由继受人承担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;如果土地交易时&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;缺乏&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;明确的标准，双方也没有遵循保守性原则严格排查，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;那么&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;现有土地使用权人&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;就&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;具有土壤污染风险管控和修复的义务&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，在本案中，也就是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;这在一定程度上归因于受让方在交易前缺乏独立严谨的环境调&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;作为现有建设用地使用权人，具有对土壤污染的风险管控和评估义务，应承担土地污染修复责任。至于修复费用的追偿问题，有两种途径，一是行政途径，通过土地污染责任认定程序&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;二是通过民事诉讼途径，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;基于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;投资并购交易合同。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;介绍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;月，生态环境部会同自然资源部制定了《建设用地土壤污染责任人认定暂行办法》，规定建设用地使用权人可以向有管辖权的生态环境主管部门提出土壤污染责任人认定申请。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;不过，张秀秀认为陆家嘴与苏钢集团的责任认定存在较大难题。主要原因是目前国内土壤污染责任人认定办法出台时间短、实践案例少，推行阻力较大。 “很多地方的主管部门对于受理申请、启动认定程序非常犹豫，因为可资借鉴的案例很少。如果不被受理，使用权人只能通过交易合同关系&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;去&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;追究历史的污染责任人。但一般的合同关系里，如果双方对于土壤污染的约定不明确，受让了污染场地的一方就会比较吃亏。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者查询发现，陆家嘴目前的公开披露信息中，未明确提及是否启动土地污染责任认定程序。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀表示，该起环境污染责任纠纷案件的启示意义在于，土地交易中买受人应注重环境法律风险的排查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;首先，买受人要深度了解土壤污染状况和历史用途，如果地块历史用途或周边涉及污染，应重点关注土壤污染的风险。其次，买受人应对地块的调查保持一定的独立性，对于既有的专业报告、评审结论保持警惕性，不可轻信结论，如有必要，可以聘请第三方开展更详细的土壤调查。最后，基于投资的通盘考虑，愿意承担一定环境法律风险的交易，应对土壤污染治理成本进行评估，就土壤污染状况、风险转移及可追溯的相关法律责任，在交易合同予以明确。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[国家金监总局三定方案： 健全金融消保者保护制度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 21:18:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;国家金融监督管理总局职能配置、内设机构和人员编制规定&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第一条&lt;/strong>; 为了规范国家金融监督管理总局的职能配置、内设机构和人员编制，推进机构、职能、权限、程序、责任法定化，根据党的二十届二中全会审议通过的《党和国家机构改革方案》、第十四届全国人民代表大会第一次会议审议批准的《国务院机构改革方案》和《中国共产党机构编制工作条例》以及党中央对金融工作的有关要求，制定本规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局是国务院直属机构，为正部级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第三条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局在中国银行保险监督管理委员会基础上组建，将中国人民银行对金融控股公司等金融集团的日常监管职责、有关金融消费者保护职责，中国证券监督管理委员会的投资者保护职责划入国家金融监督管理总局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定确定的主要职责、机构设置、人员编制等，是国家金融监督管理总局机构职责权限、人员配备和工作运行的基本依据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第五条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局负责贯彻落实党中央关于金融工作的方针政策和决策部署，把坚持和加强党中央对金融工作的集中统一领导落实到履行职责过程中。主要职责是：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）依法对除证券业之外的金融业实行统一监督管理，强化机构监管、行为监管、功能监管、穿透式监管、持续监管，维护金融业合法、稳健运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）对金融业改革开放和监管有效性相关问题开展系统性研究，参与拟订金融业改革发展战略规划。拟订银行业、保险业、金融控股公司等有关法律法规草案，提出制定和修改建议。制定银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等有关监管制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）统筹金融消费者权益保护工作。制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划，建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度，研究金融消费者权益保护重大问题，开展金融消费者教育工作，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行准入管理，对其公司治理、风险管理、内部控制、资本充足状况、偿付能力、经营行为、信息披露等实施监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行现场检查与非现场监管，开展风险与合规评估，查处违法违规行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）统一编制银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的监管数据报表，按照国家有关规定予以发布，履行金融业综合统计相关工作职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）负责银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的科技监管，建立科技监管体系，制定科技监管政策，构建监管大数据平台，开展风险监测、分析、评价、预警，充分利用科技手段加强监管、防范风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行穿透式监管，制定股权监管制度，依法审查批准股东、实际控制人及股权变更，依法对股东、实际控制人以及一致行动人、最终受益人等开展调查，对违法违规行为采取相关措施或进行处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）建立除货币、支付、征信、反洗钱、外汇和证券期货等领域之外的金融稽查体系，建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制，依法对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证、处理，涉嫌犯罪的，移送司法机关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）建立银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的恢复和处置制度，会同相关部门研究提出有关金融机构恢复和处置意见建议并组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）牵头打击非法金融活动，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议，按要求组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）按照建立以中央金融管理部门地方派出机构为主的地方金融监管体制要求，指导和监督地方金融监管相关业务工作，指导协调地方政府履行相关金融风险处置属地责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）负责对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等与信息技术服务机构等中介机构的信息科技外包等合作行为进行监管，依法对违法违规行为开展调查，并对金融机构采取相关措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）参加金融业相关国际组织与国际监管规则制定，开展对外交流与国际合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）完成党中央、国务院交办的其他任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第六条&lt;/strong>; 职能转变。加强和完善现代金融监管，转变监管理念和监管方式，坚持既管合法又管非法，持续提升监管的前瞻性、精准性、有效性，强化中央和地方监管协同，消除监管空白和盲区，加强金融消费者权益保护，加大对违法违规行为的查处力度，牢牢守住不发生系统性金融风险的底线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强金融监管内部治理，强化对权力运行的有效制衡，规范政策制定、市场准入、稽查执法、行政处罚、风险处置等工作流程，强化对重点岗位和关键环节的监督制约，打造一支政治过硬、专业精湛、清正廉洁的监管铁军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第七条&lt;/strong>; 与其他部门的职责分工：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）打击非法金融活动职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立打击非法金融活动工作协调机制，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。2.国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会、国家外汇管理局依据各自职责对相关非法设立金融机构、从事特许金融活动等组织调查认定，采取相关措施或予以取缔。3.教育、养老、房地产、商贸服务等行业主管部门在职责范围内开展本行业本领域非法集资等非法金融活动的防范和配合处置工作。4.互联网信息内容管理部门、电信主管部门、市场监督管理部门等相关职能部门在职责范围内开展非法金融活动防范和配合处置工作。5.地方政府负责辖内非法集资等非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展风险排查、案件查处、善后处置和维护稳定等工作。6.对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，国家金融监督管理总局负责提出相关工作建议，按程序报批后组织实施，并及时采取应急措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）金融消费者权益保护工作职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局统筹负责金融消费者权益保护，牵头建立金融消费者保护工作协调机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。2.国家金融监督管理总局统筹制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划、建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度、开展金融消费者教育等工作，中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会予以支持配合。3.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立统一的金融消费者投诉举报流程和标准体系。国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会按分工落实或督促相关机构落实投诉举报处理主体责任，依法查处侵害金融消费者合法权益的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制。1.国家金融监督管理总局与公安部、最高人民检察院建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接工作机制，实现案件信息共享、协同办理。2.国家金融监督管理总局发现违法行为涉嫌犯罪的，按照有关规定移送公安部，同时抄送最高人民检察院。公安机关经调查发现依法需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由公安部向国家金融监督管理总局提出建议。3.检察机关决定不起诉的案件，需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由最高人民检察院向国家金融监督管理总局提出检察意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第八条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局根据本规定第五条所明确的主要职责，编制权责清单，逐项明确权责名称、权责类型、设定依据、履责方式、追责情形等。在此基础上，制定办事指南、运行流程图等，进一步优化行政程序，规范权力运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第九条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设下列正司局级内设机构：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）办公厅（党委办公室）。负责机关日常运转，承担信息、安全、保密、信访、政务公开、新闻宣传等工作。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委办公室日常工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）政策研究司。承担金融业相关改革开放政策研究与组织实施具体工作。对国内外经济金融形势、国际金融监管改革及发展趋势、监管方法和运行机制等开展系统性研究，提出相关监管政策建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）法规司。起草相关法律法规草案。拟订相关监管制度。承担合法性审查、法律咨询服务、行政复议、行政应诉等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）统计与风险监测司。拟订监管统计制度。承担监管报表编制、信息披露、数据共享以及行业风险监测分析预警等工作。统筹非现场监管工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）科技监管司。拟订相关信息科技发展规划和信息科技风险监管制度并组织实施。按分工承担网络安全、数据安全、关键信息基础设施监管等工作，推动数字化信息化建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）公司治理监管司。拟订公司治理监管制度。开展股权管理和公司治理监管等工作，承担金融控股公司、保险集团等机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）普惠金融司。督促金融机构落实普惠金融政策要求，拟订监督管理的规章制度并组织实施，指导金融机构开展对小微企业、“三农”和特殊群体的金融服务工作，规范普惠金融秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）金融机构准入司。拟订银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的准入制度，研究结构布局，对机构及其业务范围实行准入管理，审查董事、高级管理人员等任职资格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）大型银行监管司。承担政策性银行、开发性银行和国有控股大型商业银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）股份制和城市商业银行监管司。承担全国性股份制商业银行、城市商业银行、民营银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）农村中小银行监管司。承担农村中小银行机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）财产保险监管司（再保险监管司）。承担财产保险机构、再保险机构、保险中介机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）人身保险监管司。承担人身保险机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）资管机构监管司。承担信托公司、理财公司、保险资产管理公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）非银机构监管司。承担金融资产管理公司、企业集团财务公司、金融租赁公司、汽车金融公司、消费金融公司、货币经纪公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十六）银行机构检查局。拟订银行机构现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十七）保险和非银机构检查局。拟订保险业机构、金融控股公司及其他非银行机构的现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十八）机构恢复与处置司。拟订相关高风险机构风险处置制度、标准、程序，对出现严重风险、难以持续经营的机构开展风险处置等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十九）金融消费者权益保护局。拟订金融消费者权益保护发展规划和制度，开展金融消费者教育工作，承担相关金融产品合规性、适当性管理工作，组织调查处理侵害金融消费者合法权益案件，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十）打击非法金融活动局。建立非法金融活动监测预警体系和公开举报渠道，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展相关宣传教育、政策解释和业务指导等工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议。拟订小额贷款公司、融资性担保公司、典当行、融资租赁公司、商业保理公司、地方资产管理公司等地方金融组织监管制度，指导和监督地方金融监管部门相关业务工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十一）稽查局。拟订稽查工作制度。组织对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证，提出处理意见；涉嫌犯罪的，提出移送司法机关的建议。指导、检查金融机构安全保卫工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十二）行政处罚局。承担行政处罚案件审理等工作，提出审理意见，组织听证和集体讨论，送达行政处罚决定并执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十三）内审司（党委巡视工作领导小组办公室）。拟订系统内审和巡视工作制度、办法，监督检查系统贯彻落实有关重大决策部署情况，组织开展系统内审和巡视工作，对发现的问题及责任人提出处理建议，指导、监督、检查系统内审和巡察工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十四）国际合作司（港澳台办公室）。承担外事管理、国际合作和涉港澳台地区相关事务。承担外资银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十五）人事教育司（党委组织部）。承担机关、派出机构和直属单位等的干部人事、机构编制、劳动工资、教育培训和离退休干部管理工作。指导行业人才队伍建设工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十六）财务会计司。承担财务管理工作，负责编报系统年度财务预决算。依法强化对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等财会监督工作的督促指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十七）党建工作局（党委宣传部）。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委落实全面从严治党主体责任相关工作。承担系统党的建设工作，指导系统基层党组织建设、党员队伍建设、党风廉政建设和反腐败工作。负责系统党的宣传工作。领导系统统战、群团组织工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;机关党委。负责机关及在京直属单位党的建设和纪检工作，领导机关群团组织的工作。机关党委设立机关纪委，承担机关及在京直属单位纪检、党风廉政建设有关工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局机关行政编制910名。设局长1名，副局长4名；司局级领导职数114名（含首席风险官、首席检查官、首席律师、首席会计师各1名，机关党委专职副书记1名，机关纪委书记1名）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十一条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设立稽查总队，作为直属行政机构，正司级，负责相关案件的调查、取证，提出处理意见等。稽查总队的编制和领导职数另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局对派出机构实行垂直管理。国家金融监督管理总局地方派出机构、所属事业单位的设置、职责和编制事项另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十三条&lt;/strong>; 本规定由中央机构编制委员会办公室负责解释，其调整由中央机构编制委员会办公室按规定程序办理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据机构编制管理权限，由国家金融监督管理总局党委决定、报中央机构编制委员会办公室备案的机构编制事项，按照有关规定执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定自2023年10月29日起施行&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《漫长的季节》文学策划考编上岸：反思“铁饭碗”的人为何拥抱“铁饭碗”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一则“作家考编”的新闻引发关注。 2023年武汉市文联所属事业单位芳草杂志社公布了专项招聘名单，青年作家班宇、陈春成、王苏辛、淡豹（刘雪婷）在列。此事再次引发网友“宇宙的尽头是考编”的感叹。公示名单显示，班宇、陈春成与王苏辛“成功上岸”，淡豹则不幸名落孙山。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这则新闻的话题热度虽逊于去年的“明星考编”事件，但也提出了一些值得深入探讨的议题。此次“作家考编”之所以引发热议，还是因为在人设与选择上出了问题，让外界产生了强烈的违和感，这一点值得特别加以辨析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班宇曾被称为“东北文艺复兴三杰”之一，著有小说集《冬泳》，也是悬疑剧《漫长的季节》的文学策划。这部以上世纪末东北下岗潮为背景的热播剧，一大主旨就是对“铁饭碗”的反思，尤其是展现了其对人的束缚与异化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;淡豹拥有社会学与人类学学习背景，她的文学作品关注性别、阶层议题，也专长于非虚构写作，长期以来以“关注现实”的面目示人，怎么看都与“编制”扯不上关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无怪乎有网友评论道，看到这则“作家考编”新闻，颇有一种“孙悟空考上天宫编制”“《冬泳》终于上岸”的感觉，其中淡豹还喜提了“申公豹”的网络绰号。原因无他，只因作家之前的作品与“人设”，与考编的行为出现较大反差，让读者产生违和感。对比淡豹曾在访谈中“一个人怎么写，他就怎么活着”的说法，“作家考编”的短短四个字已经让“怎么写”与“怎么活着”互相矛盾了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说作家本人完全隐身于作品之外，并不希望读者“像吃了鸡蛋还要认识老母鸡”一样了解自己，那么“作家考编”就不会引发多么大的争议，比如那些深居简出、极少抛头露面也不搞营销的作家。问题在于，如今的文化界已经高度市场化，青年作家对外出售的除了文学作品，还有各种线上线下的访谈、演讲、见面会、分享会构筑的“人设”，也将这种鲜明的“个人IP”作为一种文化商品出售。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次考编的青年作家里，或多或少都在经营着市场化的人设，这种人设也帮助他们取得了作品的成功，甚至还有作品之外的成功，花钱买书的读者购买的就不止是作家的作品，也包括他们营销包装的“人设”，以及蕴藏其中的价值观与生活方式。读者期待他们实践人设，并对未能言行一致表示失望，这种失望也恰如其分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平心而论，没有任何一条法律法规禁止这几名青年作家考编，自由开放的现代社会当然也允许一个人实践他的价值观与生活方式，但他们这种“华丽转身”也未免有些“突如其来”，自然难逃外界乃至追随者的疑问：他们为什么要去考取编制？编制又能给这些已经取得不小成功的青年作家带来什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，武汉市文学艺术理论研究所（芳草杂志社）是武汉市文联所属二级事业单位，业务范围主要是各项文学学术研究、编辑出版发行《芳草》文学期刊。官网公示的招考条件显示，报考者除了年龄要在40周岁以下之外，还需要满足“三项条件其中一项”：作品获得省级期刊文学奖项，在中文核心期刊或是省级以上出版社发表过30万字以上作品，作品入围过几个特定的文学排行榜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次编制考试的招考条件可谓相当之高，三项条件恐怕就刷掉了绝大多数“普通做题家”。而从公示的成绩表与录取名单显示，此次“入编考试”分为专业能力评审、面试成绩两大类，最后依照综合成绩排名，并没有笔试环节，可见有别于普通的“考公考编”，称得上是为“青年作家”这个群体量身定做。试问，一家文学期刊为何拥有如此之高的招考要求，又为何可以吸引多名青年作家报考？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些青年作家本已在市场取得了成功，也没有逃避竞争去“吃皇粮”的迫切需要，在体制内期刊从事文学理论或是编辑工作多少有些大材小用的味道。因此比较合理的推断是，编制带来的好处不是明面上的“铁饭碗”，而是可以为这些市场化作家提供更好的社会地位，或者说某种身份标记，青年作家之所以要求得一官半职的傍身，大约是可以把两头的好处都占了，这自然符合“理性经济人”的决策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“学院憎恨天才，犹如修道院憎恨圣徒”早就是业界的共识。文学作品本就应该交给市场判断、交给读者选择，而不是一定要作家博得某个“盖章认证”，或是有一官半职傍身，其作品才能通行于世。几名青年作家遭遇的群嘲，也说明了这一点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开庭前拍摄法庭照片，律师手机被扣：一天后法院院长送还]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[受贿超9.795亿元，中信银行原行长孙德顺一审被判死缓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260353]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 18:26:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/b302121785ce1de591e109a5f01b5503.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;5413&quot; height=&quot;3371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/b302121785ce1de591e109a5f01b5503.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257805&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月10日，山东省济南市中级人民法院公开宣判中信银行原行长孙德顺受贿一案，以受贿罪判处被告人孙德顺死刑，缓期二年执行，剥夺政治权利终身，并处没收个人全部财产，在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释；对孙德顺受贿犯罪所得及其孳息依法予以追缴，上缴国库。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/4688eae7a6d36e3589bc81e09b3c7274.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4634&quot; height=&quot;3338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/4688eae7a6d36e3589bc81e09b3c7274.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257806&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经审理查明：2003年至2019年，被告人孙德顺先后利用担任工商银行北京市分行副行长，交通银行北京市分行行长，中信银行副行长、行长等职务上的便利，为有关企业在获取贷款等事项上提供帮助，非法收受财物折合人民币9.795亿余元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南市中级人民法院认为，被告人孙德顺的行为构成受贿罪。孙德顺受贿数额特别巨大，犯罪情节特别严重，社会影响特别恶劣，使国家和人民利益遭受特别重大损失，论罪应当判处死刑。鉴于孙德顺归案后如实供述罪行，认罪悔罪，积极退赃，受贿所得财物及其孳息已全部查扣到案，具有法定、酌定从轻处罚情节，对其判处死刑，可不立即执行。同时，根据孙德顺犯罪的事实和情节，决定在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释。法庭遂作出上述判决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>