<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[一个肉贩的十四宗罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258124]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/05/Zk3WQLdcl9B5xPVH4QAJXVuXousw1CA2eHTg9ud7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Zk3WQLdcl9B5xPVH4QAJXVuXousw1CA2eHT g9ud7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nanmen Vegetable Market in Yu&#39;an District, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Minyu/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bian Xiamian was arrested, and the notice offering a reward for reporting was posted all over the Internet. On the short video platform, fellow villagers who knew him mentioned that when Bian Xiu was killing pigs in the town more than 30 years ago, his family often went to him to buy meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After many years, the identity of the former butcher suddenly changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When questioned by the public security organs in October 2021, Bian Xiuxiu was already the vice president of the Anhui Pig Slaughter Association and a member of the CPPCC Yu&#39;an District, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province. Three of the five companies under his name were engaged in There is a designated slaughtering business for pigs and cattle, but in Yu&#39;an District, there are only four companies with relevant business qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In less than two years, the former entrepreneur became a prisoner. On June 28, 2023, the People&#39;s Court of Shucheng County, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province announced in the first instance that Bian Xiu was guilty of 14 crimes including organizing, leading, and participating in a mafia-type organization, robbery, provoking trouble, and forced transactions. 25 years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 31 defendants in this case, 14 were former public officials of the Commercial Circulation Association, the Pig Office, the Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, and even the Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan, who once served as the director of the Real Estate Management Service Center of Yu&#39;an District, Lu&#39;an City, was also identified as one of the principal criminals in the case. He was convicted of organizing, leading, and participating in a mafia-type organization, robbery, and picking quarrels and provoking trouble. , misappropriation of public funds and other 11 charges, and was sentenced to 23 years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verdict shows that when the pork business was just starting, Bian met Sun Changquan, then president of the Yuan District Commerce and Circulation Association of Lu&#39;an City, and relied on him to rise to prominence. However, more case materials show that during the 20 to 30 years of business activities, Bian Xiuxiu, who was a hawker, also met several leaders of Yu&#39;an District, and with their help, he monopolized the Yu&#39;an District pork market and continued to suppress it. Competitors and general merchants in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the secret investigation of the State Council Supervision Team discovered the problem, the underworld gang composed of Bian Xiuxiu, Sun Changquan and others was quickly punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bian Xiu and Sun Changquan refused to accept the first-instance judgment and appealed to the Lu&#39;an Intermediate People&#39;s Court. The second trial of the case has not yet begun. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From stall hawker to monopoly market&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1968, Bian Xiuxiang was born in Shouxian County, Huainan City, Anhui Province, a village bordering Lu&#39;an City. Bian Moxi dropped out of elementary school and learned to butcher pigs from his second uncle when he was 14, becoming a butcher. In 1991, Bian Xiu began to rent a stall at the Nanmen Farmers Market in Lu&#39;an City, and brought pigs killed in his hometown to the vegetable market for sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case record shows that between 1991 and 2003, Bian Xiuxiu successively met Yan Guang, the coordinator of the Fenlukou Township government who collected the pig slaughter tax, and the two directors of the Pig Office. The former later became the director of his company Deputy General Manager, the latter two provided new opportunities for his pig slaughtering business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Guang is also one of the defendants in this case. The Shucheng County People&#39;s Court sentenced Yan Guang to 20 years in prison for eight crimes including participating in a gangland organization, robbery, picking quarrels and provoking trouble, forced transactions, and extortion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2002, Bian modified the contract for the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan’s younger brother recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that after contracting the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse, Bian Xiangxi and Sun Changquan met after being introduced by a then leader of the Matoji Police Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shucheng County Procuratorate alleged that while contracting the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse to engage in the fixed-point slaughtering business of pork, Bian Xiu met Sun Changquan, then president of the Yuan District Commerce and Circulation Association of Lu&#39;an City, who took advantage of his power , arranged for the state-owned Yu&#39;an District Food Company (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Food Company&quot;) and the Yu&#39;an District Commercial Administrative Law Enforcement Brigade to suppress Bian Xiu&#39;s business competitors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just when Bian Xiu was developing his pig business through his network and everything was going smoothly, his biggest competitor since he started business appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 5, 2005, the Lu&#39;an Municipal People&#39;s Government signed an investment agreement with Hong Kong Xishang Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Xisshang Group&quot;). The Lu&#39;an Municipal Government promised to close other pig slaughterhouses in the city after the project is put into operation, and determined Xishang Group to be the only designated pig slaughtering plant in the city. At the same time, the office of the city&#39;s designated pig slaughtering management department will be located in Xishang Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2006, the Lu&#39;an Municipal Government Office issued Document No. 80, announcing the closure of three slaughterhouses in the city, including the Sanli Street slaughterhouse contracted by Bian Modi. In early 2007, the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse was officially closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Case materials show that Bian Xiuxiu and Xishang Group had constant conflicts, and both parties reported to each other. In December 2006, Bian Xiangxiu led dozens of people to forcibly prevent Xishang Company&#39;s pork products from entering the Nanmen Farmers Market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 18, 2007, the Lu&#39;an Municipal Economic Development and Environmental Protection Committee Office submitted an investigation report to the municipal government, recommending that the public security organs launch an investigation into Bian Xiu and his associates who are suspected of being evil forces. , and at the same time, the Discipline Inspection Commission launched an investigation into Sun Changquan, then deputy director of the Commerce Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the storm did not have a substantial impact on Bian and Sun. The transcript shows that after being reported by the Xishang Group, Bian Xiu went out to Hefei briefly and then returned to Lu&#39;an. Sun Changquan&#39;s position remained unchanged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 1, 2008, under the witness of the Lu&#39;an City Livestock and Poultry Slaughter Management Office, the Industrial and Commercial Bureau and other units, Xishang Company and Bian Modified reached an agreement that &quot;pork from urban areas will not be sent to the countryside, and pork from rural areas will not be sent to the countryside.&quot; &quot;Not entering the city&quot; agreement, the former occupies the urban market, the latter occupies the rural market, and the two parties do not interfere with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, Bian Xiuqiu successfully obtained the qualification to carry out designated pig slaughtering in urban areas through the acquisition of Lu&#39;an Tianan Food Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tianan Company). So far, Bian Xiu has a certain monopoly position in Lu&#39;an&#39;s pork market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan&#39;s official career has also been smooth, and he has served as deputy director of the Yu&#39;an District Commerce Bureau, director of the Yu&#39;an District Key Project Construction Management Bureau, director of the Yu&#39;an District Real Estate Bureau, and director of the Real Estate Management Service Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan did not deny his special relationship with Bian Xiu, admitting that the two had been in contact and understanding each other for many years, and confessed that Bian had bribed others for the pork business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Sun Changquan confessed that in the process of acquiring the qualification to carry out pig slaughtering in urban areas through the acquisition of Tianan Company, a leader in Yu&#39;an District who was in charge of the pilot work of building a &quot;safe meat&quot; system summoned the pig office , the District Discipline Inspection Commission, the District State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, the District Audit Bureau, the District Government Office and other units held several meetings and proposed that Tianan Company be handed over to Bian Xiu for exclusive management. In return, Bian Xiu paid for the leader&#39;s facade house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 27, 2023, the Anhui Discipline Inspection and Supervision website issued a notice stating that the leader had repeatedly violated regulations from 2013 to 2022 by accepting high-end liquor, gift cards, banquets and travel from management and service objects. Arrangement, he was dismissed from his post by the government and demoted to a fourth-level chief clerk. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The supervision team made an unannounced visit&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bian Momo, whose career is getting bigger and bigger, deliberately spends money to protect himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case record shows that at the end of 2015, on the recommendation of a leader of the Yu&#39;an District CPPCC, Bian Xiu, who had not graduated from elementary school, fabricated his undergraduate degree and was successfully elected as a member of the district CPPCC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2017, with the help of this leader, Bian modified and joined a certain democratic party. Afterwards, Bian Xiamian purchased a facade house worth more than 1.1 million yuan for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rewards are also huge. Three of the five companies under Bian&#39;s name are engaged in the fixed-point slaughtering business of pigs and cattle, while in Yu&#39;an District, there are only four companies with relevant business qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Bian Modi, who has obtained a monopoly position, is not satisfied with this. In addition to requiring the Pig Office to supervise the pork flowing into the rural market from Xishang Company, and to inspect the &quot;outside meat&quot; slaughtered outside Yu&#39;an District and sold into the rural market, Bian also forced the butchers who came to slaughter to use pig offal. Deduct slaughtering fees to monopolize and crack down on the meat slaughtering market in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verdict records that in early 2013, because he was dissatisfied with a butcher who wanted to take back the internal organs of the slaughtered pigs, Yan Guang publicly insulted and beat him, and finally choked him and pushed him out of the slaughterhouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why don’t you charge a slaughtering fee but forcefully take the pigs away? An operator who purchased pig offal from Tianan Company in 2017 said that over the years, the price of a pair of pig offal has been as low as 90 yuan and as high as 150 yuan. When African swine fever is prevalent, the price is even higher. , and the slaughtering fee is generally tens of yuan, and the value is much lower than that of pig offal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the audit by Shucheng Antai Accounting Firm, from March 2013 to September 2021, Bian Modified’s two companies slaughtered more than 1.13 million pigs and used pig offal to deduct pig slaughtering fees. In this way, he obtained illegal income of 71.756167 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, more than 80 pork vendors jointly submitted a letter of complaint, reporting that Bian Xiu and others were involved in gangs and evil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 4, 2021, the eighth supervision team of the eighth major inspection of the State Council came to Yu&#39;an District to conduct an unannounced inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A situation report written by the Yu&#39;an District People&#39;s Government Office in the same month showed that the inspection mainly focused on three specific people&#39;s livelihood issues: the issue of demolition and resettlement costs in a community, the issue of water meter replacement charges in a community, and pig products in the district Difficulty in circulation and sales. Issues such as law enforcement officers&#39; crackdowns on interfering merchants and the monopolistic behavior of a Shunxin slaughterhouse owned by Bian Hao were also included in the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For three consecutive days starting from September 4, 2021, the then Secretary of the Yu&#39;an District Party Committee held 4 meetings on the issue of pig slaughter and sales. On September 5, the Yu&#39;an District Government established a special investigation team on pig circulation issues, with seven units taking the lead in conducting investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, 2021, the Yu&#39;an District Government announced that the previously implemented registration of livestock products from other places entering Yu&#39;an did not comply with relevant legal regulations and had decided to cancel it. On the same day, the original livestock and poultry slaughtering joint law enforcement team was cancelled, and the relevant responsible persons were also held accountable by the Discipline Inspection Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspection incident was officially settled one month later. On October 11, 2021, the Yu&#39;an District Committee issued a completion report document, which mentioned that since 2013, the Yu&#39;an District Government Office has issued pig slaughter management working documents seven times in succession, but the legality of the Yu&#39;an District Justice Bureau has been verified After review, the relevant documents were annulled, and the legal representative of Tianan Company, Bian Xixiang, was also criminally detained by the public security organs and put on file for investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Deeply intertwined&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 21, 2021, January 18, 2022, and July 22, 2022, Lu&#39;an City Public Security Bureau The bureau has collected clues from the public three times about Bian Modification&#39;s criminal gangs involving gangs and evil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan’s defender introduced that the case was initially filed for investigation by the Yu’an Branch, and was later upgraded to the jurisdiction of the Lu’an City Public Security Bureau for investigation, and the Shucheng County Public Security Bureau was designated for further investigation. September 27, 2022 , the case was transferred to the Shucheng County People&#39;s Procuratorate for review and prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that the underworld gang headed by Bian Xiu and Sun Changquan was in its initial formation stage from 2001 to 2007. From 2012 to 2021, the gang &quot;through the deep interweaving of public power and organizational power, form an inseparable and unified whole.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that the criminal gangs of Bian Xiu and Sun Changquan carried out two robberies in total and suppressed other meat product operators in the name of law enforcement since 2007, which constituted the crime of provoking trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, the State Council implemented the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Pig Slaughter&quot; and implemented a system of designated slaughter and centralized quarantine of pigs across the country. The following year, the Lu&#39;an City Pig Slaughter Management Office was established, with a pig market inspection team responsible for the management, coordination, supervision, and inspection of pig slaughter in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Documents issued by the Yu&#39;an District Commerce Bureau show that in order to implement the &quot;Pig Slaughter Management Regulations&quot; of the State Council, the Yu&#39;an District Commerce Bureau established a commercial law enforcement and inspection squadron in 2000, headed by the deputy director of the Commerce Bureau. He also serves as the squadron leader and is responsible for inspecting non-fixed slaughtering and sales of pigs in the region, as well as the transportation of live pigs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 9, 2013, the &quot;Summary of the Construction of the &quot;Safe Meat&quot; System in Yu&#39;an District&quot; mentioned that in accordance with the document &quot;Strengthening the Management of Cold Fresh Meat from Other Areas&quot;, Yu&#39;an District conducts full supervision of external pork. , set up inspection points to maintain the order of the meat food market in Yu&#39;an District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Statistics from Southern Weekend reporters found that among the criminal facts related to the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, a total of 103 were related to the criminal gang confiscating meat products from other business owners or preventing their transportation and sale, and another 7 The incident was caused by the Tianan Company forcing the butchers to pay for the slaughtering fee by using pig meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan’s defender believes that among the more than 100 illegal and criminal acts of picking quarrels and provoking troubles charged by the public prosecution, except for a few cases where the victims were lawfully enforced for selling substandard meat, the rest were all due to the Pig Office’s It is caused by the inspection of meat. When the local pig office clearly stipulates that the pig office can implement market access to meat from other places, deviations caused by the implementation or understanding of the policy should not be considered as provocation and troublemaking behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, regarding the crime of robbery, a crime occurred at 6 a.m. on October 10, 2013. At that time, the deputy general manager of Tianan Company led a team to impose regulations on the &quot;Yurun Pork Monopoly&quot; on the grounds that Lu&#39;an City&#39;s urban pig product circulation management regulations require that urban pig products must be registered and filed with the Municipal Commerce Bureau and require &quot;secondary inspection.&quot; Pork from other places sold in &quot;shops&quot; will be inspected and seized. During this period, the boss Zhan Xian tried to stop him with a knife and called the police. Later, Bian Xiamian and Sun Bangsheng rushed to the scene. Several people had a physical conflict, and 600 kilograms of pork stored in the cold storage of the store was finally confiscated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Bangsheng is also one of the defendants in this case. The Shucheng County People&#39;s Court sentenced Sun Bangsheng to 12 years and 6 months in prison for the crimes of underworld organization, robbery, and picking quarrels and provoking trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to ask Zhan Xian for more information about that year, but he said it had been too long and he did not want to mention it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the criminal facts related to the sale of live pigs, the first-instance judgment also mentioned that at the same time as Bian Xixiang’s pork business started, starting in 2010, Bian Xiuxiang also entered the real estate field with Sun Changquan and developed many properties. A real estate project, but the first start-up capital came from embezzled public funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这一天，七位中国选手得到了他们迟到的奖牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258110]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the replacement Olympic medal ceremony for Chinese track and field athletes was held at the Hangzhou Olympics Held at the Sports Center Stadium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1caa387610.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1caa387610.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the supplementary Olympic medal ceremony for Chinese track and field athletes was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Stadium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, after the track and field competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese Olympic Committee held a replacement Olympic medal award ceremony at the competition site. The Chinese men&#39;s 4×100-meter relay team, composed of Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, Wu Zhiqiang and Tang Xingqiang, won the bronze medal in this event at the Tokyo Olympics as replacements; Qie Yangshi, Liu Hong, and Lu Xiuzhi won the women&#39;s 20-kilometer race walking gold, silver, and bronze medals at the London Olympics respectively. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Wu Zhiqiang, Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, and Tang Xingqiang (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1874077748.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/05/1874077748.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Wu Zhiqiang , Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, Tang Xingqiang (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the men&#39;s 4x100m relay final of the Tokyo Olympics in 2021, the Chinese team ranked fourth with a time of 37.79 seconds, and the Italian team, the British team and the Canadian team won the top three. According to the International Court of Arbitration for Sport&#39;s finding in February 2022, British athlete Gizindu Ujah was found to have violated anti-doping regulations during the Tokyo Olympics. Therefore, the British team&#39;s results in the men&#39;s 4X100m relay final were canceled and stripped of their silver medal. . On May 19, 2022, the International Olympic Committee announced that the Chinese team rose from fourth to third place and won the Tokyo Olympics men&#39;s 4X100 meter relay bronze medal. This is the first medal won by the Chinese men&#39;s 4x100m relay team at the Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Xie Zhenye said, &quot;This medal is a milestone for our Chinese track and field, allowing China&#39;s track and field to leave its mark on the world. ”” src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/5d36f1b4c8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/5d36f1b4c8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;Xie Zhenye said, &quot;This medal is a milestone for our Chinese track and field, allowing China&#39;s track and field to leave its own mark on the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 2023 On the evening of the 4th, Wu Zhiqiang, Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, and Tang Xingqiang waved to the media present.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/e1f0ba96b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/e1f0ba96b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253034&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Wu Zhiqiang, Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, and Tang Xingqiang waved to the media present. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Liu Hong, Sister Qie Yangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b6ff6478ba.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/05/b6ff6478ba.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The evening of October 4, 2023 , Liu Hong, Sister Qie Yangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the national flag was raised and the national anthem was played. The dedication of Chinese athletes has finally paid off.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dbe33ccd2e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dbe33ccd2e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the national flag was raised and the national anthem was played. The hard work of Chinese athletes has finally paid off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Russian athlete Kashnikina, who won the runner-up in the women&#39;s 20-kilometer race walk at the London Olympics, was disqualified by the International Olympic Committee for doping violations. Sister Qieyangshi, who originally won the bronze medal, , and won the silver medal. Another seven years later, in March 2023, the International Olympic Committee announced on its official website that Russian athlete Yelena Rashmanova, the gold medal winner in the women&#39;s 20-kilometer race walk at the 2012 London Olympics, was also disqualified due to illegal doping. and championship qualifications, Sister Qieyangshi eventually became the gold medalist, and the silver and bronze medals were redistributed to Chinese players Liu Hong and Lu Xiuzhi. The top eight spots in the event have also been adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, after receiving her Olympic gold medal, the famous race walker Qie Yangshi cried with excitement.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/12d1dce893.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/05/12d1dce893.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 4, 2023 In the evening, after receiving her Olympic gold medal, the famous race walker Qie Yangshi burst into tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tibetan, Sister Cheyangshi’s name represents luck and happiness. When she learned the news, she expressed on Weibo that she was both happy and sad: happy because she became a champion in her heart and could have an Olympic gold medal; sad because she had never felt what it was like to be a champion and had not won an Olympic championship. aura. At the end of the article, she wrote down her expectations: Let the past be in the past, and still work hard to get what you want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Liu Hong, Sister Qieyangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi walked down the podium and accepted photos from the media.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/0b1c1c2a4e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/05/0b1c1c2a4e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The evening of October 4, 2023 , Liu Hong, Sister Qie Yangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi walked off the podium and accepted photos from the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 4, Sister Qieyangshi won the championship in the mixed 35-kilometer race walk between men and women at the Hangzhou Asian Games. She won the Asian Games gold medal and the Olympic gold medal in one day. She said that honors belong to the past. When she steps off the podium, everything starts from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the audience raised their mobile phones to take pictures. This supplementary Olympic medal award ceremony focused everyone&#39;s attention.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/c521617812.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/05/c521617812.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The evening of October 4, 2023 , the audience raised their mobile phones to take pictures. This replacement Olympic medal awarding ceremony focused everyone&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[用最“快”的光照亮幽微世界——透视2023年诺贝尔物理学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258128]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 3, 2023, Beijing time, the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences announced that the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physics will be awarded to Pierre Pierre Agostini, Ferenc Krausz and Anne L&#39;Huillier &quot;for their contributions to the study of electron dynamics in matter&quot; Experimental method to generate attosecond light pulses.&quot; The three people each received 1/3 of the total prize money of 11 million Swedish krona (approximately 7.23 million yuan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Usy1cgehlyOdXJA6isO3Ca5Mv9MaY1vpRmSxOY6V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1582&quot; height= &quot;760&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Usy1cgehlyOdXJA6isO3Ca5Mv9MaY1vpRmSxOY6V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253044&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Winners of the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physics, from left to right, are Pierre Agostini, Ferenc Kraus and Anne Leweli Er&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nobel Prize official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Agostini received his PhD from the University of Aix-Marseille in France in 1968 degree and is currently a professor at The Ohio State University in the United States. Krautz was born in Hungary in 1962. He received his PhD from the Technical University of Vienna in Austria in 1991. He is currently the director of the Max Planck Institute for Quantum Optics in Germany and a professor at the Ludwig-Maximilians University of Munich in Germany. Le Huillier was born in Paris, France, in 1958. He received his PhD from Pierre and Marie Curie University in Paris in 1986 and is currently a professor at Lund University in Sweden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this award, Lehulier also became the fifth woman to win the Nobel Prize in Physics. The previous four winners were Marie Curie in 1903 and Marie Curie in 1963. Maria Goppert-Mayer in 2018, Donna Strickland in 2018 and Andrea Gates in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These three physicists were awarded this year&#39;s Nobel Prize in Physics because their experiments provided humans with new tools to explore the electronic world inside atoms and molecules. They demonstrated a method of creating extremely short light pulses that can be used to measure the rapid processes by which electrons move, or change energy. In 2022, Lehuillier and Kraus also won the Wolf Prize in Physics for &quot;pioneering contributions to ultrafast laser science and attosecond physics.&quot; At that time, another co-winner was a Canadian physicist. Paul Corkum, a professor at the University of Ottawa. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Finding the fastest &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &quot;shutter&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Events of short duration cannot be observed by the human eye. For example, a hummingbird can beat its wings 80 times per minute, but we can only see the blurry motion of the hummingbird while hearing the humming sound. Thanks to high-speed photography, we can see events that seem fleeting to us, like the beating of a hummingbird&#39;s wings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The faster events happen, the faster you have to take photos to capture those moments. If we want to explore truly ephemeral events, we need very special techniques. At the scale of molecules and atoms, events occur at extremely fast speeds. For example, within a molecule, the time it takes for atoms to move or change is on the order of femtoseconds. Femtosecond is a very short time, 1 femtosecond is equal to 10&lt;sup>;-15&lt;/sup>; seconds. At this point, the motion of the atoms can be studied using very short pulses generated by the laser. However, when electrons move inside atoms or molecules, changes in the femtosecond time scale become very blurry because they move too fast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in the world of electrons, changes occur in tens of attoseconds. Attosecond is a unit of time, and 1 attosecond is equal to 10&lt;sup>;-18&lt;/sup>; seconds, which is a very small time scale. One attosecond relative to one second is equivalent to one second relative to the age of the universe. Therefore, if physicists want to explore the electronic world inside molecules and atoms, they need to find a fast enough &quot;shutter&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dCHhgjLb11KQemJoZt6qZLFqlEBnkQCIRJFPMJ8F.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;636&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dCHhgjLb11KQemJoZt6qZLFqlEBnkQCIRJFPMJ8F.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253043&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Attosecond physics gives physicists the opportunity to observe the motion of electrons. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nobel Prize official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Femtoseconds have long been considered the limit of the shortest possible light pulses. Improving existing techniques is not enough to see processes taking place on the extremely short time scales of electron movement; doing so requires completely new techniques. Experiments by three of this year&#39;s laureates produced extremely short pulses of light, measured in attoseconds, demonstrating that these pulses can be used to provide images of processes inside atoms and molecules. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Birth of Attosecond Physics&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Light is a wave produced by changes in electric and magnetic fields. Different lights have different wavelengths and appear in different colors. For example, red light has a wavelength of about 700 nanometers, one-hundredth the width of a human hair, and it fluctuates about 430 trillion times per second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shortest light pulse is the length of a single period in the light wave. If traditional methods are used to create ultrashort light pulses, the duration of each light pulse will never be less than femtoseconds, making it impossible to observe the movement of electrons. In the 1980s, physicists thought this was a very difficult limit to overcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the mathematics of describing waves shows that any waveform can be constructed using waves of the right size, wavelength, and amplitude (the distance between crests and troughs). The secret to building attosecond pulses is to create shorter pulses by combining more light with shorter wavelengths. To obtain these shorter wavelength light, we need to use a phenomenon called &quot;gas harmonics&quot; produced when the laser passes through the gas. The harmonics here are like the overtones produced when plucking guitar strings. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1987, Lehuillier discovered that when she passed an infrared laser through a rare gas, it produced more and stronger &quot;overtones&quot; than in previous experiments. When the laser passes through the gas, the laser interacts with the atoms in the gas. The extra energy gained by the electrons in the interaction is released in the form of light pulses, and these light pulses from the electrons are the &quot;overtones&quot; in the experiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once these &quot;overtones&quot; appear, they interact with each other. When the peaks of light waves coincide, the light becomes stronger, but when the peaks in one cycle coincide with the troughs of another cycle, the light becomes weaker. Under the right circumstances, the &quot;overtones&quot; coincide and a series of light pulses appear, each lasting a few hundred attoseconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Physicists understood the theory in the 1990s, but it wasn&#39;t until 2001 that they made a breakthrough in actually identifying and testing light pulses. Agostini and his collaborators in France succeeded that year in generating and studying a series of successive light pulses. Using a special trick, they combined these light pulses with delayed portions of the original laser pulse to see how the overtones synchronized with each other. This process allowed them to measure that each pulse lasted only 250 attoseconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, Kraus and his collaborators in Austria developed a technique to select individual pulses. The pulse they successfully isolated lasted 650 attoseconds, which the team used to track and the study of processes that pull electrons out of atoms. These experiments show that scientists can observe and measure attosecond pulses, and that these attosecond pulses can also be used in new experiments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The future of attosecond physics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the attosecond world is within our reach. These short pulses of light can be used to study the movement of electrons. Physicists can already obtain pulses as low as tens of attoseconds, and the technology continues to evolve. Eva Olsson, chair of the Nobel Prize Committee in Physics, said: &quot;We can now open the door to the world of electrons. Attosecond physics gives us the opportunity to understand the mechanisms governed by electrons. The next step is to exploit These mechanisms.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Chinese physicists are also conducting research on attosecond physics and are collaborating closely with international colleagues, including the winners of this Nobel Prize in Physics. For example, the Institute of Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Songshan Lake Materials Laboratory jointly established the Attosecond Science Center in Dongguan, Guangdong. The Institute of Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences built a comprehensive extreme conditions experimental facility in Huairou Science City, Beijing, which can provide ultrafast data of about 100 attoseconds. For light fields, the Xi&#39;an Institute of Optics and Precision Mechanics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences established the Attosecond Science and Technology Research Center in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attosecond physics has potential applications in many fields. For example, in electronics research, it is important to understand and control the behavior of electrons in a material. Attosecond pulses can also be used to identify different molecules, which could have applications in medical diagnosis. In the future, we are expected to see attosecond physics play a more important role in basic and applied research, helping us deepen our understanding of the physical world while bringing more benefits to human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:25:20 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不止于新冠疫苗，有可能引发疫苗革命 ——透视2023年诺贝尔生理学或医学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258126]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 13:46:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 2, 2023, Beijing time, the Swedish Nobel Prize Committee announced that for the invention of nucleotide base modification , thus developing an effective messenger RNA (mRNA) vaccine, American scientists Katalin Karikó and Drew Weissman won the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, and they will share 1100 SEK 10,000 bonus. Due to the great success of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccine, Carrico and Weisman have won many major awards including the Breakthrough Prize in Life Sciences, the Lasker Prize and so on. The Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine this time is truly well-deserved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/fAsK0dPttYF2W8soIvVJrdEUBDYF79H9JgXcOZRc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;982&quot; height= &quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/fAsK0dPttYF2W8soIvVJrdEUBDYF79H9JgXcOZRc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253045&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Drew Weissman and Katalin Karikó, the main pioneers of mRNA vaccines. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Cell website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Pioneer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Carico 1955 Born in Szolnok, Hungary, after receiving his PhD in Hungary, he moved to the United States in 1985 and entered into postdoctoral research at Temple University in Philadelphia and Bethesda University of Health Sciences, focusing on research on the medical application of mRNA. After experiencing a series of setbacks such as frustrated funding applications, demotions and salary cuts, and suffering from cancer, Carrico met her long-term research partner Professor Drew Weisman. The two met dramatically because of their fight for a copy machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Professor Weismann was already a moderately accomplished immunologist. Weisman, two years younger than Carrico, was born in Lexington, Massachusetts, USA. He received a doctorate in medicine from Boston University in 1987. When he met Carrico, Weissman had just established his own research group at the Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, working on research in areas such as AIDS vaccines. After learning about Carrico&#39;s research interests, Weisman suggested that Carrico switch to the field of mRNA vaccines and decided to collaborate with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But mRNA vaccine research is not easy because mRNA is an extremely unstable small nucleotide molecule. The mRNA molecule is widely present in living organisms. It is the &quot;messenger&quot; for DNA to guide cell cooperation proteins. It is responsible for transmitting the genetic information of the gene to the ribosome, which &quot;installs according to the diagram&quot; and assembles the amino acid &quot;parts&quot; into various proteins. Therefore, mRNA is called messenger RNA. After completing its mission, the mRNA is quickly broken down by enzymes in the cell and its existence time is very short. If mRNA is injected into the body as a vaccine, these mRNA molecules will be broken down quickly before they can instruct cells to synthesize proteins. What&#39;s even more deadly is that animal experiments show that injecting unmodified mRNA into the body can trigger an immune response in the body, leading to serious adverse reactions to the vaccine. mRNA vaccines have also been ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to these problems, Carrico and Weisman conducted a series of studies. Although funds were limited, they still persisted in this direction and made some major breakthroughs. In 2005, Carrico and Weisman discovered that some natural nucleotides in messenger RNA were important factors in causing adverse immune responses in the body. They found the nucleotides in messenger RNA that triggered adverse immune responses, and then used artificially synthesized Nucleotide replacement significantly weakened adverse immune responses. This study laid a key foundation for the subsequent development of mRNA vaccines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Carrico, Weisman and others improved the messenger RNA vaccine to increase the stability of the mRNA vaccine in the body. For example, they used a liposome &quot;coat&quot; to coat the messenger RNA vaccine. Wrap it up so that it cannot be broken down by nucleases before entering the cell. With the continuous improvement of technology, there is increasing hope for the industrialization of mRNA vaccines. Compared with traditional vaccines, mRNA vaccines have some obvious advantages, such as good safety, short design and development cycle, low production cost, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;New Opportunities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, before the outbreak of the new crown epidemic, mRNA vaccines had been tepid. At that time, dozens of mRNA-based vaccines were being developed around the world, and a few vaccines such as influenza vaccine, Zika virus vaccine, and rabies vaccine had entered clinical trials, but none had yet been approved for human disease prevention. This situation quickly changed due to the global pandemic of the new coronavirus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to long-term accumulation, BioNTech, a German biotechnology company where Carrico serves as vice president and head of RNA therapy development, quickly launched new crown vaccine research and development after the outbreak of the new crown epidemic. The mRNA COVID-19 vaccine BNT162b2, which targets the spike protein of COVID-19, was developed. Due to the emergency of the epidemic, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has also given the green light to clinical trials of COVID-19 vaccines such as mRNA vaccines, greatly shortening the pre-clinical animal testing and clinical trial time of COVID-19 vaccines, which originally took several years or even more than ten years. The clinical trial was completed in just 7 months. Fortunately, BNT162b2 not only shows good safety, but the effectiveness of the vaccine has also reached an astonishing over 90%, which is significantly better than traditional vaccines. Since the end of 2020, most countries and regions around the world, including the United Kingdom and the United States, have successively approved the emergency use of BNT162b2 vaccine. At the same time, the new coronavirus RNA vaccine mRNA-1273 developed by the American company Moderna also achieved similar results, and this vaccine is also based on the patented mRNA vaccine technology of Carrico and Weissman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In less than a year from vaccine design, clinical trials to approval for marketing, BNT162b2 and other mRNA COVID-19 vaccines have created a miracle in the history of vaccine research and development. This is of course related to the global pandemic of the new crown epidemic, but it is mainly due to the good safety and excellent effectiveness of the mRNA new crown vaccine. Judging from the real application data of subsequent large-scale immunization and the preventive effect against new coronavirus variants, mRNA new coronavirus vaccines such as BNT162b2 also performed well. According to the Nobel Prize website, more than 13 billion doses of COVID-19 vaccines have been administered around the world, saving millions of lives. BNT162b2 and other mRNA COVID-19 vaccines are among the most outstanding vaccines. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Vaccine revolution? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If the mRNA vaccine can only work in the new coronavirus epidemic, its charm will be greatly reduced. In fact, greatly encouraged by the success of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccine, dozens of clinical studies based on mRNA vaccines around the world are accelerating. If its application scope can be expanded, the mRNA vaccine technology pioneered by Carrico and Weismann is expected to start a vaccine revolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are currently two main application directions for mRNA vaccines. The first major application direction is to prevent infectious diseases. In addition to COVID-19, the current mRNA vaccines against human infectious diseases caused by pathogens such as epidemic viruses, Zika virus, cytomegalovirus, and respiratory syncytial virus have also entered Phase II or III. Clinical Trials. According to a press release issued by Moderna on September 13, 2023, the company has submitted marketing authorization applications for the respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) mRNA vaccine globally, and the seasonal influenza mRNA vaccine has been approved in three clinical trials. All trials also demonstrated acceptable safety and tolerability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second main application direction is the treatment of cancer. According to the US clinical trial website, there are currently nearly 50 mRNA vaccines related to cancer treatment in the world that have entered or completed phase II clinical trials, including Bion. A number of mRNA vaccines for cancer treatment developed by companies such as Tektronix and Moderna have entered Phase II clinical trials. These vaccines mainly target cancers such as melanoma, colorectal cancer, non-small cell lung cancer, and head and neck squamous carcinoma. Among them, there are high hopes that mRNA vaccines can be used in combination with other anti-tumor drugs to improve the effectiveness of cancer treatment. According to the results of a phase II clinical trial jointly released by Moderna and the US pharmaceutical giant Merck at the end of 2022, an mRNA vaccine developed by Moderna performed well when used in combination with Merck&#39;s checkpoint inhibitor Keytruda. Good, over 1 year, the mRNA vaccine combined with Keytruda led to a more than 40% reduction in the risk of cancer recurrence or death in patients with stage 3/4 melanoma compared with Keytruda alone. Moderna and Merck plan to launch phase III clinical trials of this treatment in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, apart from the multiple COVID-19 vaccines that have been approved for marketing, no mRNA vaccine has yet been approved for marketing. It remains to be seen whether the mRNA vaccine can show promising results in the prevention of other infectious diseases and cancer treatment. However, judging from the current progress of clinical trials, it is only a matter of time before a new mRNA vaccine is approved for marketing. The vaccine revolution initiated by mRNA technology may come soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[兰州一高中两老师深夜围殴学生：“突击查寝”制值得反思丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258086]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a school violence incident has attracted attention. According to a report by China Morning Post, based on the statements of parents and dormitory administrator Ma, the timeline of the incident is as follows: At 11:40 pm on September 26, four persons, the principal Wu and the admissions office director Hao, entered the They searched the dormitory and violently kicked in the door before entering. Suspecting the students to smoke, Wu and another teacher worked together to beat two students in the dormitory. The beating lasted for more than an hour, and the four did not leave until 1:20 a.m. the next day. During this period, Hao kept shouting, &quot;Beat him to death. If he is beaten to death, send him to the hospital.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, a student suffered from syncope and nosebleeds. The dormitory manager, Ma, fed the child candy and stayed with him to comfort him for more than two hours. Afterwards, &quot;the school confiscated the phone and watch and asked the students to write a guarantee not to tell their parents.&quot; Three days later, both parents &quot;discovered&quot; that the child had symptoms such as facial bruising, lethargy, nightmares and convulsions, which brought the matter into the public eye. The parents first contacted the dormitory manager, Teacher Ma. After hearing about this, Teacher Ma was &quot;filled with indignation and resigned.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recorded conversation between Teacher Ma and the principal Wu, Wu apologized and admitted that &quot;the action was a bit too big and a bit extreme&quot; and &quot;has already apologized to the students and parents.&quot; Afterwards, Teacher Ma also told the media that students on the entire floor witnessed the atrocities that night and &quot;I have no intention of doing it anymore.&quot; After the media called the principal Wu, Wu simply said, &quot;We are dealing with this matter.&quot; At present, the Lanzhou Municipal Government has established an investigation team on this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The timeline of this incident is not complicated, but there are still many questions that are worth analyzing one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the details of the incident are still quite ambiguous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the origin of the incident, the dormitory manager surnamed Ma said that he was &quot;inspecting the student dormitories on behalf of the school, but he did not expect to be so ruthless.&quot; It seems that the reason why the principal and his party entered the dormitory to check the dormitory and violently beat them was because they &quot;suspected the students of smoking.&quot; So, did the two students smoke? Why did the principal and his team violently kick in the door during the bed check? These are two key issues in this assault. There should be a logical chain between the student closing the door, the principal kicking the door and the student suspected of smoking to explain the cause of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The facts presented in the current media reports and interviews with the parties can only be interpreted as &quot;the students did smoke and locked the door for fear of being punished. The principal failed to open the door and then violently kicked it in, and finally surrounded him.&quot; . Even if two students do smoke, the principal and others can only punish the students, not corporal punishment, which is prohibited by the Teachers Law and the Compulsory Education Law. If the two students were not smoking at all, the behavior of the principal and others would be tantamount to violent madness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 7, paragraph 3, of the &quot;Penalty Rules for Primary and Secondary School Education&quot; (Trial) stipulates that if &quot;smoking, drinking, or behaving inappropriately and violating the student code&quot;, the school and its teachers should stop it and provide criticism and education , education and punishment can be implemented if necessary. However, any kind of disciplinary action does not include the violent beatings in this incident, which is &quot;corporal punishment that directly causes physical pain by hitting, stabbing, etc.&quot; which is expressly prohibited in Article 12. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the accusations made by the boarding manager and parents are true, then the principal Wu and others are also suspected of illegal and criminal acts. Judging from the descriptions of &quot;facial bruises&quot; and &quot;nosebleeds,&quot; the two victims may have met the criteria for &quot;minor injuries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this incident also shows a major problem in the current teaching management of primary and secondary schools, that is, there is an almost absolute &quot;management and obedience&quot; relationship between schools and students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a power relationship between teachers and students, and the principal and director of the admissions office are higher &quot;superiors&quot; than teachers. They come out to &quot;check the bed&quot; to discipline students, and they are also unconsciously or consciously expanding this power, which includes the power to unconditionally discipline students with corporal punishment. At the same time, students must obey the principal and other superiors unconditionally, otherwise they will face an escalation of corporal punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current law, once a violation of the student code such as &quot;student smoking&quot; occurs, on the one hand, the school can only punish and educate the students instead of corporally punishing and beating the students. On the other hand, the main responsible person they should hold accountable should be It is merchants who sell cigarettes to minors, parents or guardians who instigate or allow minors to smoke, rather than violently punishing minors who smoke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this incident also makes people rethink the management system of student dormitories and the so-called &quot;surprise dormitory inspection&quot; system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original intention of the student dormitory management system is to improve dormitory management, protect student safety, and ensure learning and living conditions. However, schools at all levels are now using the banner of &quot;benefiting students&quot;, which naturally takes over the private space of students&#39; study and life. In this incident, the principal and his team came to check the dormitory room at 23:40 in the evening and violently kicked the door. From every angle, they were eroding or even violating the students&#39; private space. As adults, college students will naturally complain about regulations such as &quot;forced self-study&quot;, &quot;locking the computer&quot;, and &quot;checking the bed every night&quot;; and judging from this incident, even if the high school students are minors, such &quot;surprise bed checks&quot; are not allowed. It was too harsh, and the subsequent &quot;confiscation of phones and watches&quot; further demonstrated the willfulness of those in power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High school students, mostly between the ages of 15 and 18, have the right to start taking over their own lives, manage their own personal space, and be responsible for their own actions. Whether high school boarding schools still need to treat older children like little ones is debatable, at least in terms of the dormitory management system. Schools should give students more private space to cultivate students&#39; self-management skills and better prepare them for adult life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the problem exposed in this incident is not just a simple issue of school violence, but also reveals problems in the teaching management of primary and secondary schools. As quasi-adults, high school students cannot just be subordinates who accept management and punishment unconditionally, but are future masters who should be cared for and cared for in the adult world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[“文坛祖母”冰心 用爱温暖世纪丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257697]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[提升软环境，善待游客始]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258090]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 11:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mid-Autumn Festival and the National Day are on consecutive holidays, and travel is popular. Experts estimate that more than 100 million people will travel during this long holiday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-driving has become the mainstream during long vacation travel. For those car owners who drive to Xi&#39;an, Shaanxi, Mianyang, Sichuan, Xinxiang, Henan and other places, this year&#39;s journey will have a lot less worries: the traffic police departments in these places recently announced that minor violations of foreign tourists&#39; vehicles will not be punished during the holidays. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such &quot;flexible law enforcement&quot; measures are generally welcomed by car owners. The car is in a different place and the road in life is unfamiliar. Even if you have a navigation system, various situations will inevitably happen. If you are slapped with a ticket and fined for this, you may not be in a good mood for the whole day. There are no penalties for minor violations of laws by foreign vehicles. This will allow foreign tourists to relax and have fun without having to worry about getting into trouble or losing money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actions of the traffic police in these places are not illegal, but based on evidence. The Administrative Penalty Law clearly stipulates that if the violation is minor and is corrected in a timely manner without causing harmful consequences, no administrative penalty will be imposed; if the violation is for the first time and the harmful consequences are minor and the harmful consequences are corrected in a timely manner, administrative penalties may not be imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the fundamental purpose of punishing traffic violations is to ensure safe and smooth traffic and improve traffic efficiency. If some minor violations do not cause traffic congestion or affect traffic safety and traffic efficiency, they do not need to be punished. If you use a high-power magnifying glass to see defects and you are punished for minor violations, it becomes a fine for the sake of fines, which is putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, tourism has become an important economic driving force in many cities. To attract tourists, in addition to unique attractions, the soft environment is also an important aspect of attraction. For example, this year&#39;s Zibo barbecue fire caused many tourists from out of town to come by car. There was no room in the parking lot, so some people parked their cars on the roadside. Faced with these illegally parked out-of-town vehicles, the Zibo traffic police did not come up and issue a punishment note. Instead, they called each one to notify them to move the vehicles. This practice was praised and attracted more people to Zibo to eat barbecue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, there were some places that had &quot;extremely strict law enforcement&quot; on foreign car owners. I drive this road, and when foreign car owners come, they have to find faults and fines. Some places even deliberately set up law enforcement traps to punish outsiders. In this way, foreign car owners are treated as &quot;water fish&quot;, and they will not come next time. Not only will they not come, they will also post online to appeal to others not to come. When such word-of-mouth evaluation spreads, there will naturally be fewer and fewer tourists, and the tourism economy will be out of the question. On the contrary, if foreign tourists are &quot;softly enforced&quot; and try not to be punished, so that tourists feel comfortable, they may stay here for a few more days. Next time they come, they will take the initiative to do voluntary publicity online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, foreign car owners who enjoy flexible law enforcement treatment must also consciously abide by traffic rules, try not to violate the rules, do not create congestion in the local area, and be decent in both directions. After all, only good traffic order can bring a relaxing and pleasant travel experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tourism environment is part of the business environment and a reflection of the overall business environment. There used to be some places that specifically targeted foreign investment merchants. In the early stage, they used various &quot;preferential policies&quot; to attract foreign merchants to invest in and build factories. After that, they started to &quot;harvest the wool&quot;. Not only were the original promises unable to be fulfilled, but they also had to eat all kinds of food. To get the card, &quot;beat the foreign businessmen to internal injuries and strip the domestic businessmen naked.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What kind of business environment there is, there will be what kind of investment enthusiasm. From the tourism environment to the business environment, they are essentially a reflection of the level of local public governance. Paying attention to one&#39;s own reputation and reputation is the basic prerequisite for local public governance to become good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“遛街子”累麻了，年轻人开始了“宅”式度假]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不是我不够努力” ：被清退的编外人员，如何过难关]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258088]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/04/1hbW3iqPCOVYPyAfvKOHLi72oS4xe6bm0iRJwOfY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1hbW3iqPCOVYPyAfvKOHLi72oS4xe6b m0iRJwOfY. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, a hospital in Zhejiang Province launched nursing skills training for nurses. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You are no longer from our hospital.&quot; One sentence announced that Chen Min has been a non-staff nurse for ten years The end of a career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In front of two doctors, three bedded patients and their families in the ward, the dismissal notice came suddenly. Staying for a second longer makes you feel embarrassed. In September 2023, Chen Min recalled to Southern Weekend that after hearing the order to leave, she did not hesitate, returned to the office, took off her nurse uniform, took away the cup and notebook, and kept a group photo with the department. In the cupboard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight months ago, Chen Ming just turned 35 and became the first batch of labor dispatch workers dismissed from a second-class hospital in Hunan where she worked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, she has shuttled between wards and departments, looking no different from other nurses. But somewhere invisible, there is always a thread named &quot;weaving&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using this line as the boundary, people like Chen Min who work in state agencies or institutions in the form of labor dispatch but are not within the establishment are called &quot;non-staff personnel.&quot; In addition, common non-staff personnel include “contract workers” hired by government agencies, hospitals, schools and other units who sign contracts with workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, information about “retiring non-staff personnel” that has appeared from time to time has attracted attention to this group. In 2022, Fangxian County, Hubei Province promoted the standardization of the clean-up of non-staff employed personnel, and stated that &quot;the clean-up of non-staff personnel involves a wide range of areas and a large number&quot;, and the clean-up process needs to &quot;effectively safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of government agencies, institutions and non-staff personnel.&quot; In February 2023, a symposium on the clean-up and standardization of non-staff personnel held in Tongcheng City, Anhui Province mentioned that clean-up and retirement is not the ultimate goal, but to standardize and rectify the chaos of non-staff employment and improve government administrative efficiency and service levels. Provide employment assistance for retired personnel, and actively and steadily promote special actions to clean up and standardize non-staff personnel.&quot; In August, the Lichuan City Institutional Establishment Committee Office in Hubei Province stated that the city had eliminated 301 irregular non-staff employees. In Jianli, Hubei, Linxiang, Hunan, Harbin, Heilongjiang and other places, public information shows that the removal of non-staff personnel is also in progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this wave, some non-staff personnel are deeply frustrated, and some take the opportunity to step out of their comfort zones and look for a decent job again. News from Daoxian County, Yongzhou City, Hunan Province stated that as of September 20, 1,038 laid-off non-staff personnel had been re-employed in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Premonition of unemployment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The non-staff personnel interviewed had a premonition of being laid off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2022, Chen Min heard from colleagues about the news of eliminating non-staff personnel. At first, he didn’t believe it. Later, he searched online and found that other cities had taken action. But the news only circulated secretly in the hospital, and she never saw the red-headed document. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 31, 2022, the contract signed by Chen Min with a third-party labor dispatch company expired. The hospital leader told her that &quot;the epidemic has just ended and there is no time to sign the contract, so she must go to work first.&quot; Just two or three days later, she was fired on the grounds that &quot;the state had issued a policy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, similar &quot;gossip&quot; spread in a hospital in Dengta City, Liaoning Province. Li Zhen, 28, has worked in the vaccination department of the hospital for nearly seven years. In this hospital with less than 400 employees, it only takes a few turns for the news to reach her ears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Zhen felt the signal even stronger. Salaries that cannot be paid on time, successive layoffs in other departments, rumors that leaders in charge of each department are fighting to keep their subordinates, the newly appointed dean twice went to the vaccination department and mentioned &quot;there are too many people&quot;... these have given rise to unemployment. The real feeling of pressing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more precise news came on the night of May 16, the day before she was dismissed. She heard from a relative who had an acquaintance working in the hospital that the layoffs might &quot;be your turn.&quot; A few.&quot; The next day, the leader in charge of the department called: &quot;There is bad news. You can&#39;t keep it this time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhen said that in the memories of the old nurses at the hospital, there were more than 30 people working in the hospital. This is the first time that no one has been laid off in recent years. The hospital told her, &quot;The hospital now owes money and cannot support so many people. You should understand the hospital.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xiaodong, a professor at the School of Politics and Public Administration at China University of Political Science and Law, analyzed to Southern Weekend the existence of non-staff personnel. There are historical reasons for this and development, which were influenced by the thinking of “more people make things easier” and the increase in workload at that time. When public institutions like hospitals are saturated with workload and existing staff cannot complete the work, they recruit non-staff personnel to assist in the work. And the hospital&#39;s &quot;most of the funds for supporting non-staff personnel come from their own income.&quot; The main reason for dismissing non-staff personnel now may be related to its own profits and policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Hu Xiaodong mentioned that the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; released in March 2023 mentioned streamlining the establishment, but it was limited to central and state agencies and local party and government agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Non-staff personnel in some government agencies have been affected before. 29-year-old Lin Jiangtao has been working in a government unit in Yuxi, Yunnan for four years. At the end of December 2022, while he was on paternity leave, he received a notice of competitive employment from the unit. Due to economic layoffs, 36 people outside the establishment were required to undergo written examinations and interviews. Decided to stay or go. &quot;I probably understood it when I heard this. I guess I will be laid off this time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Uneasiness surged in Lin Jiangtao&#39;s heart. He recalled that at that time, he frequently looked at job information on local talent recruitment websites, viewed short videos on social media that taught people how to deal with middle-aged unemployment, and even asked a master to tell fortunes. Lin Jiangtao sent his birth date and work address, and the master told him that he &quot;may not be unemployed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For insurance, Lin Jiangtao hired a teacher to conduct structured interviews, which cost 1,500 yuan for two days. On December 29, 2022, the day before his birthday, he still received a text message that he was dismissed. He was competing for the last place in the induction examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The removal of non-staff personnel is related to the reduction of staff. Hu Xiaodong explained that the key to the increase or decrease of establishment is whether the use of establishment can improve work efficiency. Nowadays, non-staff personnel in government departments at all levels bear the actual work of many internal staff. “It is necessary to return the civil servant work performed or replaced by existing non-staff personnel to the civil servants themselves and return the responsibilities of civil servants.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Before the crisis&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After graduating from technical secondary school, Li Zhen once thought about working in Shenyang, which is 40 to 50 minutes&#39; drive away from home. As the only child in the family, her father was reluctant to let her go away, so he asked someone to find connections to get her to come to this hospital. Although the average salary was only more than 2,000 yuan a month, &quot;as long as she has a place to occupy herself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are eight people in the vaccination department, all of whom are &quot;contract workers.&quot; Li Zhen is mainly responsible for vaccine information registration in the department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost all children in the county are vaccinated at their hospital. During busy times, it takes three hours in the morning to register the information of about a hundred children. Over time, Li Zhen developed the habit of speaking and typing quickly. When I met the children and parents who came for vaccination, I blurted out three key questions in Northeastern dialect: &quot;Is the child sick, has he taken medicine, and is he healthy?&quot; In the time it takes a new colleague to enter the information of one child, Li Zhen can enter the information of three. As soon as he sees the child&#39;s age in months, he knows which injection should be given to the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you have free time, you can get off work early after finishing your busy morning. &quot;The job is easy, the salary is fixed&quot;, and there is also medical insurance and pension insurance paid by the hospital - this is already a good job in a small county. Li Zhen has no mortgage, car loan or children, and her husband&#39;s monthly salary is five to six thousand yuan. They live a stress-free life in a small county with low prices. With the idea of ​​&quot;leaving this place for retirement&quot;, Li Zhen never thought of leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the unemployment crisis, many people believed that non-staff work could be done &quot;until retirement&quot; because it was &quot;close to the establishment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for Lin Jiangtao. In his view, his job is no different from that of a clerk, &quot;delivering information, setting up accounts, and at most compiling information at the end of the year.&quot; Because of the nature of the company, I need to go to the company for safety inspections, and I don’t have to strictly stay on duty. There are also five insurances paid by the company. “I can’t find a more satisfying (job) than this.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When &quot;Lingping&quot; was in the unit, two or three non-staff colleagues left because they were admitted to civil servants or public institutions. Lin Jiangtao felt envious, but did not act. It wasn&#39;t until he lost his job that he realized how &quot;fragrant&quot; the establishment was. If the time could go back ten years, he would like to advise his 19-year-old self to make a good life plan and consider taking a job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the cruel reality is that even if Lin Jiangtao goes back to ten years ago and tries his best to take the exam, the result may not be satisfactory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Min spent ten years preparing for the exam. From the time she got a part-time job, her life was spent working and preparing for exams. After get off work every night, her schedule is to go back to her room to read and prepare for exams. She is unable to respond to her colleagues&#39; calls to eat and play cards, and she cannot &quot;waste&quot; more time cooking or spending time with her family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike the comfort Lin Jiangtao felt at work, Chen Min&#39;s work in the hospital was unstable. In the past ten years, she has been rotated through at least eight departments. The shortest one she stayed in was only half a year, and the doctors in the department were not fully recognized. The longest one was less than three years. When I go to some new departments, I even have to start from scratch. However, the transfer of colleagues within the staff will not be so frequent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her perception, hospital employees are divided into four levels based on employment forms. The highest level is within the establishment, followed by personnel agency, labor contract, and labor dispatch. Dispatched workers also have five insurances and one housing fund, but their wages are the lowest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference buried in daily work always reminds me that I am a &quot;non-staff person&quot;, and the age limit of &quot;under 35 years old&quot; for the staff examination is tightly pressed, which further intensifies Chen Min&#39;s pursuit of staff. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whenever there is a recruitment announcement in her hospital, Chen Min will sign up. On several occasions, she passed the written exam but was dropped again after the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/HUsJgmRsZHd34X3wdBGavXwIPRGxouwipDVaif7w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/HUsJgmRsZHd34X3wdBGavXwIPRGxouwipDVaif7w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Many places require that the removal of non-staff personnel be actively and steadily promoted. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Survival and Emotion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After being fired, for more than a month, Chen Min is immersed in anxiety and relies on medication to maintain sleep every day. At a rehabilitation hospital near her home, Chen Min was diagnosed with moderate depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The treating doctor advised Chen Min to learn to look away and not push herself too hard. Her parents-in-law also told her that it didn’t matter if she didn’t go to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those who have accumulated some &quot;capital&quot; after working for many years, after losing their jobs, survival is not the first concern that arises, but emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the past few years, Chen Min considers himself devoted to his work. Her home is close to the hospital, only ten minutes&#39; walk. When she was not working the night shift, she also told the doctors and nurses after work, &quot;If you are too busy at night, just call me and I will come right away.&quot; Her WeChat ID is still left in the previous department for patients Appointments, consultations, return visits. Chen Min described her work as her lover, and the sudden unemployment felt like being separated from her lover. &quot;It will probably be difficult to get out of it within a year or two.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For retired non-staff personnel, a buffer period may be needed. Hu Xiaodong mentioned that for the sake of humanistic care, the unit should set up a buffer period to &quot;give them a buffer space from psychology to behavior. The unit can also help non-staff personnel who are about to be laid off find new jobs in accordance with laws and regulations.&quot; In addition, he also suggested designing a return-to-work appointment system. When these non-staff personnel are needed again in the future, units can give priority to hiring personnel with return-to-work certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to divert his attention and renew his suspended social security payment, Chen Min began to look for a new job. Health care centers, specialized hospitals, private clinics, confinement centers, and places related to nursing are the first to be considered. More than ten years ago, she applied for the nursing major because &quot;it was easy to find a job.&quot; Now the number of nurses has exceeded 5 million, and employers have more and younger choices. Chen Min said that because she was over 35 years old, she was either unable to register for the exam or was not accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Jiangtao also encountered a similar situation. He saw a job opening at a vocational training company on the local talent recruitment website. On the day of the interview, his boss, who was in his forties, introduced to him what he had achieved in his twenties and asked him: &quot;Why are you still looking for a job at the age of 29?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Jiangtao restrained his emotions. , replied calmly: &quot;Why can&#39;t you find a job at the age of 29? People who are 59, 69 or even 79 may be looking for a job.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first lost his job, Lin Jiangtao also had self-doubt. But soon, he told himself that when he was at a low point in his life, he must not push himself too hard or go against himself; when he encountered a suitable opportunity, he would take the initiative to fight for it, but there was no need to be too anxious. &quot;Looking for a job is like looking for a partner, take your time.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Step out of the comfort zone&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From May to August, Li Zhen rested at home for three months. Not long ago, he went to Nantong, Jiangsu, intending to try home textile live broadcast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are requirements for live broadcasts. You must dress fashionably and wear heavy makeup. You can&#39;t just wear sportswear and white shoes on the inside, a nurse&#39;s uniform on the outside, and light makeup like you do in the hospital. Even when he speaks, he pays attention to standard Mandarin. &quot;After speaking Northeastern dialect for so many years, it suddenly feels so awkward.&quot; Li Zhen stood next to the anchor, feeling a sense of discomfort that made her shrink back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After staying in Jiangsu for half a month, Li Zhen returned to his hometown and spent 7 days learning to make milk tea locally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September, she and her friends opened a milk tea shop near the school. Although it was more tiring, she could adapt. The work is busier than before, but she thinks that the more work she does, the more she will get. &quot;Maybe by selling this extra hour, I can make more money. I think it is for myself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people have taken bigger steps, such as Chen Min, who moved from the hospital to small restaurants and barbecue stalls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After looking for a job for more than a month and asking for more than 20 nursing-related positions, Chen Min still found nothing. After consulting teachers from her previous school, she turned to preparing for the Licensed Pharmacist Qualification Certificate. If she passed the exam, she could work in a chain pharmacy. &quot;It&#39;s relatively stable and there&#39;s no age limit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But before that, I have to find a job to transition. Chen Min walked along the street from shop to shop until he saw a notice recruiting waiters at a small restaurant on the street, and worked as a waiter there. After being introduced by the restaurant owner&#39;s wife, I came to work part-time as a dishwasher at a nearby barbecue stall. The total of the two salaries is not much different from that of working in the hospital. Chen Min also paid social security again in the form of flexible employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Chen Min still has her own concerns about these two jobs. When looking for a job, she deliberately avoided being near the hospital because she didn&#39;t want to run into her former colleagues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When working in the hospital, the nurses wear the same uniforms and masks, with their eyes exposed. Most of the time, patients have difficulty even distinguishing nurses with different appearances, and they treat nurses with the same courtesy and respect. But after taking off her nurse&#39;s uniform and mask, she was still a little worried when facing the guests, food and dishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now her time is divided into four periods. She gets up at 7 a.m. to prepare for the exam, works as a waiter in a restaurant from 10:30 a.m. to 7 p.m., then washes dishes at a barbecue stall, and returns around 12 p.m. home, and then continue reading until 2 o&#39;clock in the morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her parents-in-law still take care of everything at home for her, and her husband also supports her to continue taking exams and do what she wants to do. Occasionally, my 7-year-old son saw Chen Min reading in her room and brought her own books to keep her company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media, Chen Min wrote: &quot;My failure to pass the establishment examination is definitely not because I didn&#39;t work hard enough, but I still believe that hard work will reward me in another way in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Chen Min, Li Zhen, and Lin Jiangtao are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[调停俄乌冲突，百岁基辛格的功绩与争议丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258084]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 24, 2023 local time, according to the &quot;Ukrainian Pravda&quot; report, Ukrainian President Zelensky During his recent visit to the United States, he met with former US Secretary of State Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Andrei Yermak, director of the Ukrainian Presidential Office, posted the above news on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger visited China two months ago and attended the Bund Financial Summit online on September 23. The centenarian is still playing his part on the international stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why Kissinger is still active&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The world today is facing huge risks, unlike any risks since the Cold War. Previous risks, whether the United States sent troops to Afghanistan or Iraq, occurred between world powers and small and medium-sized countries, and the risk of escalation is unlikely. But this time, it has become a confrontation between world powers and a strategic confrontation between nuclear powers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the Russia-Ukraine conflict and the Great Game between Russia and the West behind it have had a strong impact on the post-Cold War world order. The conflict between Russia and Ukraine marks a serious challenge to the post-Cold War world order. On the other hand, this is also the first indirect confrontation between Russia and the US and Western camps after the Cold War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Yermak&#39;s account, Kissinger told Zelensky during the meeting, &quot;Before this war, I opposed Ukraine joining NATO because I was worried that it would set in motion the war we are seeing now. process (the outbreak of the conflict). Now this process has reached such an extent that the idea of ​​​​keeping Ukraine neutral in this situation no longer makes sense.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time Kissinger has mentioned Ukraine joining NATO. On May 17, The Economist published an exclusive interview with Kissinger. During the interview, Kissinger stated that he supports Ukraine&#39;s membership of NATO. He also said: &quot;Ukraine should continue to be protected by Europe, rather than becoming an isolated country that protects itself on its own.&quot; Regarding Russia, Kissinger said, &quot;If I talk to (Russian President) Putin, I will tell him , Ukraine will be safer if it stays in NATO.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Kissinger called on all parties to sit down and carry out diplomatic negotiations. He warned that there is now a risk that the great powers&#39; military relationships dominate their geopolitical calculations. The Russia-Ukraine conflict may therefore develop into a global conflict, and diplomatic negotiations will become &quot;increasingly important.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Sino-US relations have undergone qualitative changes since the Trump era. Conflict has begun to replace cooperation and become the key word in Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the relationship between the world&#39;s major powers, represented by the relationship between China, the United States and Russia, has become very dangerous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, Kissinger became increasingly worried about Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by Xinhua News Agency on June 16, Kissinger said in an interview with the media that Sino-US relations are on &quot;a cliff&quot; and &quot;the current trajectory of the relationship must change.&quot; Later, Kissinger also said that the Cold War between China and the United States is now &quot;walking on a mountain road.&quot; Kissinger believes that China and the United States &quot;both believe that the other side poses a strategic threat. We are moving towards a confrontation between major powers.&quot; This is a process that &quot;should not continue&quot;. Once a conflict breaks out between China and the United States, it will be comparable to World War I. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Kissinger actively mediates the conflict between Russia and Ukraine and drags his old body to visit China, which is an attempt to stabilize Sino-US relations and exert his residual energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why Kissinger? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the United States, there are many influential strategists. There are also many people who are worried about the international situation and are trying to improve Russia-Ukraine relations and Sino-U.S. relations. But why Kissinger and not someone else? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Kissinger has a superstitious admiration and sense of mission for the United States. As a German Jew who escaped the Nazi regime, to hold a high position in the United States is an example of an American success story. This also makes him always grateful to the United States. He once wrote: &quot;The same generosity of spirit and lack of malice can be found anywhere else.&quot; This almost sentimental gratitude and admiration for the United States made him serve the United States at all costs in diplomacy and devote himself to Maximize the national interests of the United States. For this reason, he did not hesitate to sacrifice his personal beliefs and did not care about his personal success or failure, reaching the height of &quot;living and dying for the benefit of the country, how can he avoid it for the sake of misfortunes and blessings&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, more than half of Kissinger’s diplomatic achievements are in Sino-US relations. Kissinger is an eyewitness and operator of America&#39;s transformation from decline to prosperity. If President Nixon had not accepted his suggestion, destroyed the Sino-Soviet alliance, and shifted the strategic focus of the United States from Asia to Europe, it would have been difficult for the United States to win the Cold War in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he entered American politics, the United States was experiencing its lowest point after World War II, and was experiencing triple crises of foreign strategy, economy, and society. The United States was trapped in the Vietnam War and was unable to extricate itself; it was in economic difficulties, and the U.S. dollar lost its ability and credibility to redeem gold; domestic society was in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Kissinger left American politics, the United States had successfully transformed China from an enemy of the United States into a &quot;friendly non-ally&quot; of the United States against the Soviet Union. Although the U.S. dollar can no longer be redeemed freely with gold, it has been tied back to the oil trade, achieving an upgrade from the U.S. dollar to an international standard currency. The U.S. dollar has transformed from an intermediary in world economic and trade to a truly hegemonic currency and an international standard currency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These all make Kissinger unique and a myth and legend in the diplomatic community. His status and influence in international politics, especially in Sino-US relations, are irreplaceable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Symbol of the Times&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On June 16, 2023, according to Xinhua News Agency, Kissinger said in an interview with the media that American politics is polarized , is currently &quot;overly focused&quot; on its own interests, and if its foreign policy fails to balance the interests of the United States and the world, the United States &quot;will become isolated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Sino-US relations turned from hostility to cooperation was that both countries had to deal with the threat from the Soviet Union. However, without Kissinger&#39;s insight and courage, it would be difficult for China-US relations to quickly restart in such a bad bilateral relationship. The symbolic effect produced by this overlapping interaction between individuals and times is something that no one else can possess. Kissinger has become a symbol, a symbol of an era, and is unrepeatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, it was a product of the times when China and the United States united to fight against the Soviet Union during difficult times. When Kissinger secretly visited China, it was the Soviet Union&#39;s rise and hardening period, and it was a difficult period for China and the United States. The handshake between China and the United States across the Pacific and across the ideological divide not only created a diplomatic legend, but also stabilized the world situation at the time and destined the outcome of the Cold War in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Kissinger came to China, he saw the strategic contradictions and ideological differences between China and the Soviet Union, and wanted to contact China to jointly fight the Soviet Union. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, China and the United States have become the biggest beneficiaries of the end of the Cold War. After the end of the Cold War, both China and the United States were able to get rid of security concerns, reduce security burdens, and focus on economic development. The rise of China in the world and the rise of the United States within the Western camp complement each other. It can be said that Kissinger&#39;s personal luck lies in standing at a turning point in Sino-US relations and the world structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a personal level, Kissinger is often called a realist, mainly because he puts strategic thinking ahead of ideology. This distinguishes Kissinger from the current strategic researchers in the United States who are guided by ideology. However, he did not take ideological factors into consideration. In fact, he calls his foreign policy principles &quot;liberal internationalism,&quot; which is equivalent to the neoconservatism of the George W. Bush era. It is the product of combining the emphasis on values, internationalist principles, and diplomacy based on national strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because of this kind of liberal internationalism that he offended the two US presidents, Trump and Biden. On November 25, 2020, Trump fired Kissinger from his position as an advisor to the U.S. Defense Policy Council. However, he is also dissatisfied with Biden&#39;s withdrawal from Afghanistan, believing it to be an irresponsible act that betrays the tradition of U.S. foreign policy dating back to President Wilson. One result of expressing this rhetoric is that Biden inherits Trump&#39;s approach to Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are many talents in the U.S. strategic field, and many of the younger generation of strategic people than Kissinger have also withdrawn from the stage. The young and middle-aged strategic talents in the United States are now leading the charge in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, age is a major advantage for Kissinger. Kissinger is 100 years old and has outlived all his friends and opponents. Kissinger is the only 100-year-old international politician in the world who is still active and has great influence. This makes Kissinger&#39;s role largely unrepeatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Can Kissinger be copied? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Kissinger is a product of his times. Times cannot be repeated, and Kissinger cannot be copied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the shape of Sino-US relations has changed. During the Cold War, the biggest external threat to China and the United States was the Soviet Union. For the sake of their own security, China and the United States have established a quasi-alliance system across the ideological divide, which is in line with their own interests. Now, as China has unprecedentedly entered the center of the world&#39;s power stage, Sino-US relations have become the most important bilateral relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the characteristics of diplomacy have changed. The realists represented by Kissinger advocate personal factors and are superstitious about secret diplomacy. This was already outdated by the end of the Cold War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger was obsessed with those passionate years throughout his life, and was intoxicated by the thrill and excitement of secretly boarding a plane from Pakistan to Beijing. In the post-Cold War era, especially in the era of highly transparent and open self-media, these individual heroic diplomatic behaviors are difficult to reproduce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Kissinger’s influence in the United States has declined much faster than in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of the new era, many Americans are also reflecting on and challenging Kissinger&#39;s past contributions and achievements. The famous international relations scholar Hans Morgenthau has long said that Kissinger, like Odysseus in Homer&#39;s epic poem, &quot;has many facades.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the United States, there are two descriptions of Kissinger: one is a liar. This person never tells the truth, always speaks ambiguous words, and almost never makes clear public comments on major events. This may be one of the secrets of his longevity in the world of international relations. Second, Kissinger is an amazing person with an excellent memory. He was an eyewitness and living dictionary of many major events. Christopher Hitchens&#39;s description of Kissinger is perhaps more accurate, calling him &quot;a stunning liar with an incredible memory.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, there is something very dangerous. Compared with Kissinger, whose main achievement was during the Cold War, current American strategists basically grew up in a peaceful atmosphere. For them, peace is no longer the primary goal of international politics, but the premise or background of international politics, which does not need to be fought for or paid for. Therefore, we can see that compared with Kissinger&#39;s concerns about the prospect of conflict, many American strategists seem not to be concerned about the possibility of conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, there will be no second Kissinger, but the crisis that Kissinger is worried about will continue to repeat itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the American Studies Center of Fudan University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为啥没有诺贝尔数学奖：因为诺贝尔的妻子被数学家拐跑了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258076]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It was not until Nobel&#39;s death in 1896 that his family, friends and colleagues knew that the Swedish billionaire 94% of his property was donated to the foundation to establish 5 awards: Physics Award, Chemistry Award, Physiology or Medicine Award, Literature Award, Peace Award, and held the first award ceremony in 1901 - today, There is also a sixth award, the Nobel Prize in Economics, which was established by the Swedish Central Bank in 1969 to commemorate Nobel, so it is sometimes not regarded as the orthodox Nobel Prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is the five Nobel Prizes or the six Nobel Prizes, mathematics prizes are not included. As for why, you may have heard a legend: Swedish mathematician Gosta Mittag-Leffler kidnapped Nobel&#39;s wife, so Nobel hated everyone who studied mathematics and refused to establish a mathematics prize from the foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is actually a complete rumor. Nobel was never married and had no wife at all. In fact, if Nobel had a wife and children, he might not be able to donate his property to the foundation to establish awards. Therefore, in some versions of the story, it was not Nobel&#39;s wife who was abducted, but his lover. However, when we look back at Nobel&#39;s life today, we will find that this extremely wealthy inventor did not have a smooth relationship. His only two scandal targets had nothing to do with mathematicians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, 1833, a baby boy was born to an intellectual family in Stockholm, Sweden. He was named Alfred Nobel. He later became a famous scientist, inventor, and businessman. and founder of the Nobel Prize. His father, Nobel Sr., was a construction engineer with extensive research in the field of rock blasting. Alfred Nobel later embarked on the path of developing explosives and engineering inventions, which was actually his family background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the same year that little Nobel was born, his father&#39;s career was not going well and he went bankrupt due to a construction accident. When he was 4 years old, the old Nobel saw that he could not make money in Sweden, so he decided to go to Finland and Russia to make a living. His wife and children were left behind to guard a small grocery store and eke out a living in Stockholm. As a result, little Nobel lived a very hungry and cold childhood, and did not go to school well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, old Nobel finally made a name for himself in Russia. He opened a machine shop in St. Petersburg and designed a new type of simple mine to provide equipment for the Russian army: He asked the Tsar and generals It was believed that the mines could prevent enemy ships from approaching the capital. During the Crimean War from 1853 to 1856, these mines successfully prevented British naval attacks on St. Petersburg. Russia&#39;s earliest central heating device was also manufactured in the old Nobel factory. The Nobel family was the first in Russia to install central heating. This was a big shock to the country of &quot;General Winter&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With his father&#39;s success in Russia, Nobel&#39;s family moved to St. Petersburg in 1842. Little Nobel, who had not even finished primary school, finally had the opportunity to receive a first-class education. Little Nobel was most interested in literature, chemistry and physics, and left a deep impression on his teachers: he was extremely intelligent but sickly, liked solitude and contemplation, and was particularly fascinated by English literature, especially the poets Byron and Shelley. - As a student, Nobel regarded Shelley&#39;s philanthropy, pacifism, agnosticism and atheism as his guiding principles in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the elder Nobel hoped that his sons could inherit their father&#39;s legacy and was dissatisfied with the younger Nobel&#39;s literary ambitions. He then decided to send the young man to study abroad to become a chemical engineer. In this way, the young Nobel came to Paris to study under the famous chemist Peroz. Under Professor Perozzi, he met Sobrero, a young Italian chemist. Three years ago, Sobrero invented nitroglycerin, a highly explosive liquid. Sobrero thought the thing was too dangerous to be of practical use. However, Nobel was very interested in nitroglycerin and believed that it had great future in engineering. After he completed his studies and returned to Russia, he and his father started the research and development of nitroglycerin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But by then the Crimean War had ended, and my father’s business was deteriorating, and he finally had to move back to Sweden. Nobel&#39;s two brothers remained in Russia, trying to save what was left of the family business. They eventually succeeded, turning to the emerging oil industry in southern Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1863, Nobel returned to Sweden with his father and concentrated on developing nitroglycerin dynamite. Unfortunately, these experiments went awry, resulting in the deaths of several people, including Nobel&#39;s brother Emile. The Swedish government has ordered a ban on explosives testing within the city of Stockholm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Nobel did not give up and moved the experiment to a barge on Lake Mälaren in Sweden. In 1866, his experiments finally achieved a breakthrough: by mixing nitroglycerin with a type of fine sand called diatomaceous earth, the liquid could be turned into a paste, and dynamite sticks could be made. He also incidentally invented the detonator, which could be detonated by lighting a fuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike his father who studied mines, Nobel, as a pacifist, put these inventions into civilian fields, such as drilling tunnels, blasting rocks, and building canals. The invention of explosives and detonators greatly reduced project costs and immediately became popular in the construction industry. Nobel therefore set up factories in 90 different places, but demand still exceeded supply. He lived in Paris but frequently traveled to his factories in more than 20 countries, earning him the nickname &quot;Europe&#39;s richest tramp&quot; by Victor Hugo. He also developed synthetic rubber, leather and rayon, and obtained 355 patents in his lifetime, making him a veritable invention king. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intensive work and travel left this inventor with no time to solve personal problems, and he has always been a bachelor. It was not until the age of 43 that Nobel hired Bertha Kinski, a multilingual and well-educated Austrian housekeeper. Nobel fell in love with her at first sight, but Bertha already had a crush on her. After working for Nobel for a short period of time, she decided to return to Austria to marry her fiancé. Despite this, Nobel and Bertha became good friends and continued to write to each other for decades. Bertha was a well-known anti-war activist and wrote the masterpiece &quot;Lay Down Your Arms&quot;. She had a great influence on Nobel, not only strengthening Nobel&#39;s pacifist belief, but also the key to Nobel&#39;s final establishment of the Peace Prize. After Nobel&#39;s death, the Norwegian Parliament awarded the 1905 Nobel Peace Prize to Bertha. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nobel’s second relationship originated from a commercial trip in the autumn of 1876. Nobel came to Austria and met the poor and beautiful girl Sophia. Nobel was attracted by her frankness and beauty, and Sophia was attracted by Nobel&#39;s money - it was obvious that this relationship was doomed to tragedy from the beginning. Nobel loved and cared for Sophia, gave her money, spent time teaching her, and tried to improve her moral character and knowledge, but to no avail. Sofia became more and more willful and took up a lover in the luxurious Paris apartment prepared for her by Nobel. Nobel decided to break up several times, but he couldn&#39;t stand Sophia&#39;s entanglement and indulged her willfulness year after year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since his student days, Nobel has been introverted and lonely, and was once hospitalized for treatment for depression. Continuous emotional difficulties aggravated his illness, so much so that he once wrote: &quot;Only in dogs can you find many friends.&quot; In his later years, Nobel suffered from hearing problems and angina, and the doctor recommended that he take nitric acid Glycerin - this is the explosive ingredient that made him famous. Nobel complained in a letter to his relatives and friends: &quot;It seems like an irony of fate that they prescribed nitroglycerin for oral administration to me!&quot; To this day, nitroglycerin is still an effective drug for the treatment of acute angina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring of 1891, just five years before Nobel&#39;s death, Sophia wrote him another letter asking for money on the grounds that she was pregnant. But Nobel knew that the child&#39;s father was a young Hungarian officer, and the two were preparing to get married. The main source of income for this young couple after their marriage was shamelessly writing to Nobel asking for a huge sum of money - and in Nobel&#39;s will, he actually took out a large sum of money from the remaining 6%. To Sophia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Swedish mathematician Gosta Mittag-Leffler who is rumored to have kidnapped Nobel’s wife, he was 13 years younger than Nobel. When Nobel moved to France, he was still there. go to school. Gosta had nothing to do with Nobel throughout his life, but he had a lot to do with the Nobel Prize: he was elected as a member of the Nobel Prize Committee in 1903, and insisted on awarding the Nobel Prize to Curie against all odds. A couple, not Mr. Curie alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>