<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[接连停运，有轨电车真的没“出路”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256990]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rS zHzGpQrZ3O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2019, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram in operation was nicknamed &quot; Dangdang car”. In June 2023, Zhangjiang trams will be suspended. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retro, good-looking, fresh... City trams once had such Internet celebrities label, but in the past few months, news of tram outages have appeared frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, an announcement circulated on the Internet stating that due to difficulties in operating funds, modern trams in Honghe Prefecture, Yunnan will cease operations on August 10, 2023. On August 11, the chairman of Honghe Prefecture Modern Tram Co., Ltd. responded that the announcement was false news. At present, the local tram has not been suspended and is operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the Tianjin Development Zone Guide Tram Line 1, which had been in operation for 16 years, announced that it would cease operation and started procurement of demolition projects. In June, Shanghai Zhangjiang Tram No. 1, which had been in operation for 13 years, was suspended and the tracks were quickly dismantled. Two years ago, in 2021, the trams in Zhuhai, Guangdong, were suspended and planned to be dismantled after more than three years of operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram was out of service, and workers were dismantling the track. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Shijun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, 3 of the 39 rail lines across the country have been suspended. According to the &quot;Urban Rail Transit 2022 Annual Statistics and Analysis Report&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Report&quot;) released by the China Urban Rail Transit Association, as of the end of 2022, a total of 39 tram lines in 23 cities across the country have been put into operation, with an operating mileage of 578.3 kilometers. , equivalent to half the distance from Beijing to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The primary reason for the suspension of operations is low passenger flow. This is not the first time such news has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2015, after the opening of the Chengdu Tram Chengdu Tram Line 2&#39;s first section, the line was not connected to the urban rail transit network and the passenger flow was low, which led to great pressure from public opinion and suffered &quot;some problems&quot;. &quot;Trams are useless&quot; controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are trams frequently suspended? How to avoid the &quot;chair transport&quot; situation? Compared with subways with large passenger flows, trams are &quot;urban rail transit low-capacity systems,&quot; Li Hongchun, an expert and deputy director of the academic committee of the China Urban Rail Transit Association and vice president of the Modern Tram Branch, told Southern Weekend that doing a good job Line network planning achieves a high degree of integration of multiple transportation modes, and low-capacity systems can develop systematically and healthily. There are also many successful cases in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Low passenger flow is the key to the suspension of trams&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Insufficient passenger flow and serious losses are the key reasons for the suspension of trams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jiemian News, before the suspension, the daily passenger volume of Shanghai Zhangjiang trams had dropped sharply to about 1,000 passengers. Wang Qingfeng (pseudonym), a bus enthusiast who works in Zhangjiang, recalled that sometimes “when we get on the bus from the starting station, there are almost no passengers on the bus along the way.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 25, 2022, at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on a working day, there were almost no passengers in the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram car, and there was only one conductor. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The operating pressure of the Honghe Prefecture tram, which denies rumors of suspension, is not optimistic either. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the tram passenger intensity in Honghe Prefecture was 0.01 (10,000 passengers/km·day), ranking at the bottom in the country. The passenger volume that month was only 26,000, with an average of less than 900 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 29, 2018, a tram was undergoing joint debugging and testing in Honghe, Yunnan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low operating frequency is an important reason that affects passenger flow. The longer the departure interval, the lower the attractiveness of passenger flow. Low passenger flow further affects the departure interval, forming a vicious circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval between Zhangjiang tram trains before they stop running is 15 to 20 minutes. For commuters, the waiting time is too long. &quot;Instead of waiting for the tram, it&#39;s better to buy a shared bicycle.&quot; Wang Qingfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only shared bicycles, but also the opening and operation of many subway lines such as the eastern extension of Shanghai Metro Line 2, Line 11, and Line 13, have dispersed the passenger flow of trams. Before the suspension, in February 2023, Zhangjiang trams reduced their operating hours from 17 hours a day to only 4 trips during the morning and evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pudong Modern Rail Transit Co., Ltd. stated in the announcement that in recent years, the public transportation system in Zhangjiang area has been continuously enriched and improved. Multiple urban rail lines have been put into operation, and ground bus lines have been optimized and adjusted many times. The passenger flow of Zhangjiang Tram 1 has been declining year by year, and ground buses will replace the connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Insufficient technical applicability and high maintenance costs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to low passenger flow and long departure intervals, the trams in Tianjin Development Zone and Shanghai Zhangjiang are subject to The vehicles are imported products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both use the Translohr system produced by the French company Raul, which has rubber wheels, single track and a small footprint. However, not many cities around the world use this system. With the gradual decline of Raul after its acquisition, the production of related parts has been greatly reduced, resulting in high vehicle maintenance costs and long maintenance cycles, and some parts are facing the risk of &quot;supply interruption&quot;. Difficulties in purchasing parts have also led to difficulties and high costs in maintaining trams in Shanghai Zhangjiang and Tianjin Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qingfeng recalled that when he was riding a tram in Zhangjiang, he discovered that there was a thick wooden pole in the driver&#39;s cab. The tracks are sometimes blocked by debris, and drivers need to get out of the car and use wooden poles to clear the debris, which greatly affects traffic efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Zhuhai tram, Li Hongchun mentioned in an interview that the TramWave ground power supply system it used lacked engineering practice, and the builders had insufficient understanding of the applicability of the technology, resulting in system problems after the line was opened. The failure rate is high and the operation service is unstable. At the same time, factors such as low passenger flow and high maintenance costs have directly affected the remaining section of Line 1 that was originally planned to be rebuilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being low in frequency, the out-of-service trams were also considered too slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Report&quot; shows that the average travel speed of subways in 2022 will be 36.47 kilometers/hour, the average travel speed of trams nationwide is only 22.3 kilometers/hour, and the travel speed of Zhangjiang trams is only 19 kilometers/hour Hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the maximum design speed of Zhangjiang trams is 70 kilometers per hour. The reason for the slow running speed is that trams do not have dedicated right of way - they share the road space with all vehicles and are still subject to traffic lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height= &quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Zhangjiang tram does not have a dedicated right of way. It shares the road space with all vehicles and is still subject to traffic lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long trams waiting for traffic lights exacerbate congestion. For example, the Zhangjiang tram passes by Pudong Foreign Languages ​​School Affiliated to Shanghai International Studies University. Parents will park their private cars on the roadside when picking up their children. When the tram comes in, it will occupy the entire road. One citizen said: &quot;You can either use the non-motorized lane next to it to overtake, or you can only follow the Dangdang tram.&quot; Dangdang tram is the nickname given to Zhangjiang trams by Shanghai residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Planning issues, not standard issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking around the world, trams are not a niche issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;China Tram Development Report (2020)&quot; released by the Modern Tramway Branch of the China Urban Rail Transit Association shows that subways and trams are the mainstream systems of urban rail transit in the world, of which subways account for 47 %, trams account for 42%, and light rail accounts for 11%. In Europe, trams are the mainstream public transportation mode in many cities. For example, in Berlin, Germany, trams account for as high as 55.6% of the rail transit mileage. In China, this proportion is only 5.71%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some voices pointed out that the tram was &quot;unacclimated&quot; after it came to China. But Li Hongchun reminded that many tram projects are operating well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In very large and megacities, trams can be used as extension lines and encrypted lines of large and medium-sized transportation systems such as subways. For example, Beijing&#39;s Xijiao Line, as an extension of Metro Line 10, starts from Bagou Station and connects tourist attractions such as Xiangshan Park, National Botanical Garden, Yuquan Country Park and the Summer Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Western Suburb Line is positioned to be “mainly for commuting, supplemented by tourism,” Li Hongchun added. The Xijiao Line is the first tramway in the country to be operated with multiple connections - two train sets are connected together to increase passenger flow. During the &quot;Xiangshan Red Leaf Festival&quot; in 2019, the maximum daily passenger flow reached 94,700, making it the first single tram in the country. The daily passenger flow is the highest recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the May Day holiday in 2022, in order to reduce the full load of the carriages, the Beijing Xijiao Line will adopt a multi-connection operation mode. A single train will change from 5 carriages to 10 carriages, with 8 groups per day. Heavy-duty trains are put into operation with a minimum departure interval of 5 minutes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(China News Service reporter Jia Tianyong Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Huai&#39;an, Jiangsu, trams even serve as the city&#39;s backbone public transportation, ensuring Passenger flow demand. Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is the first tram line in China that enters the core area of ​​the city, and its passenger flow has always been at the forefront of tram lines in the country. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the passenger flow in Huai&#39;an was 580,000, reaching nearly 20,000 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 16, 2020, in Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province, modern trams that were suspended due to the epidemic resumed operation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In tourist areas, trams can also play the role of special tourist buses, such as the Nanping Wuyi New District Line in Fujian , connecting Nanping City High-speed Railway Station to Wuyishan Station, seamlessly connecting with Wuyishan Scenic Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the experience of successfully operating trams, unlike large-capacity systems such as subways, trams, as low-capacity systems, are redeveloped on existing road resources, which is difficult and needs to be adapted to local conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that the suspension of some trams does not reflect problems with the tram system itself, but problems in planning and design. For example, the area near the first phase of the Zhuhai tram project is mostly high-end communities. Residents mainly travel by car. Moreover, the north side of the line is dominated by mountains. The development intensity along the line is low, there is little residential land, a lack of commercial facilities, and the line radiates from one side. , resulting in low passenger flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to plan rationally? Li Hongchun believes that trams are positioned as an environmentally friendly transportation system that fills the gap between large-capacity subways and conventional buses. First, we must ensure a clear level of public transportation planning and strengthen integration with comprehensive transportation. For the connection of hubs, the division of labor between trams and conventional bus systems must be properly handled, and the line network layout must consider the integration of large-capacity systems and medium- and low-capacity systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 26, 2020, the first tram in Wuyishan City, Nanping City, Fujian Province slowly drove out of the Xiandian depot and entered the trial operation stage. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Sanya tram is located closest to the entrance and exit of Sanya Railway Station, and the Jiaxing tram The station is directly connected to the newly developed campuses on both sides by pedestrian tunnels, making these designs more convenient for residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Site selection needs to be supported by a certain population density. Li Hongchun mentioned that it is necessary to accurately predict the passenger flow in the line corridor to avoid the situation where the actual passenger flow does not reach the estimated amount. In terms of construction timing, &quot;we must first consider what needs to be built most, not where it is easier to build.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the first section of Chengdu Rong Line 2 was opened, the low passenger flow was questioned because it had not yet been connected to the urban rail network. After the opening of the second section, it was connected to the subway, and the passenger flow reached nearly four. Ten thousand people, an increase of dozens of times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of operations, regarding the issue of tram rights of way, Li Hongchun believes that priority signals should be provided for trams to ensure the safety, speed and efficiency of tram operations. For example, Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is equipped with three major systems: tram signal priority control system, intersection red light electronic police and road section checkpoint system, and intersection video surveillance system, and arranges traffic coordinators to realize tram priority at intersections. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that under the dual influence of my country&#39;s rapid urbanization and the substantial increase in private car ownership leading to congestion, the development of public transportation is an inevitable trend in history. The construction cost of the subway is at least ten times higher than that of the tram. Compared with the bus, the tram has the advantages of large transportation capacity, high comfort and punctuality. Under the trend of carbon neutrality, tram It is an important option for public transportation construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[哈尔滨：黄昏缄默的时候，建筑在说话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 9:30 am on October 26, 1909, Congkuanchengzi (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changchun&lt;/span>;) Ito Hirobumi, who arrived in Harbin by special train, stepped off the train. A short man wearing a peaked cap and western clothes calmly touched his chest, ribs, and abdomen. He fired three shots and then fired four shots at the accompanying Japanese officials, shouting &quot;Ula Golia!&quot; in Russian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened suddenly, and everyone was still dreaming. Ito Hirobumi was put on a special train and died 30 minutes later. The man with a resolute face, An Zhonggen, was captured in an almost tragic manner; the seven gunshots fired over the Harbin Railway Station, which was built in 1899 and named in 1903, rapidly and profoundly changed the 20th century. The situation in Northeast Asia at the beginning - Although the train station was demolished and rebuilt in 1959, there are still vivid traces of this incident in the station, including the Ahn Jung-geun Memorial Hall and the platform where the incident occurred: the &quot;Δ&quot; and &quot;□&quot; on the ground , respectively, where Ahn Jung-geun and Ito Hirobumi are standing, about 5 meters apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old scene of Harbin Railway Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Ruo Ge As Li said, &quot;When poems and legends are silent, only buildings speak.&quot; - Around the train station, everything is completely different from what it was more than a hundred years ago. Only the Church of Saint-Iver still quietly &quot;leans&quot; on it. Stand aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Street: &quot;The Cross-Communication of Multiculturalism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Old Harbin&quot; without city walls is actually neither ancient nor modern - it is The &quot;modern city&quot; grew up amid the roar of trains. China&#39;s defeat in the Sino-Japanese War and many factors such as Tsarist Russia&#39;s use of alliance with Japan as bait to seize more interests in Northeast China gave birth to the construction of the Middle East Railway. In 1896, Russia obtained the right to build the Middle East Railway. In June of that year, Russia&#39;s Middle East Railway The General Administration of Construction moved from Vladivostok (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Vladivostok&lt;/span>;) to Harbin. At the same time, the railway was divided into The six ends of the east-west and south-west lines are being constructed in opposite directions at the same time. As the center of the 2,500-kilometer &quot;T&quot;-shaped railway that runs from Manzhouli in the west, Suifenhe in the east, and Lushun, Dalian in the south, it has quickly become an international city with &quot;sky-high buildings, merchants, soaring land prices, and every inch of land is precious.&quot; - &quot;The desolate wilderness turned into a prosperous port in an instant.&quot; Capitalism has become the &quot;power&quot; for Harbin&#39;s rapid growth and rise, but at the same time, foreign capital has inhibited and hindered the development of national capitalism, making it an &quot;alien&quot; between traditional Chinese cities and modern capitalist cities; a railway has even more influence on Harbin. The local architectural culture has had a huge impact, with a wave of compulsory and replacement architectural design trends - integration, addition, mutation... In the silent dusk more than a hundred years ago, in this city with wonderful characteristics, it began Continuously “cultivating”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Harbin Railway Station and St. Iver&#39;s Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Red Army Street, which shoots out straight from Harbin Railway Station, was originally named Horvat Street. It is the starting point and germination of Harbin&#39;s city construction. It spreads outwards with it as the axis, showing the annual rings of the city&#39;s growth. The original site of the Longmen VIP Building was built in 1907. At the other end, there were the Russian Consulate General in Harbin and the Officers Club of the Russian Trans-Amur Military District, as well as the &quot;famous&quot; Yamato Hotel in the Northeast; the Sino-Russian Daosheng Bank, built in 1920, is now It is the Heilongjiang Provincial Research Museum of Literature and History, still maintaining the original French Renaissance style; the Cheschakov Tea House’s mixed classicism, baroque and Renaissance style exterior bay windows, overhanging awnings, and open-air balconies are set among the Among the green trees, looking at the signboard of &quot;HSBC Camera Company&quot;, it is difficult to imagine that it was designed by Zhdanov, a Russian Jewish architect who has lived in Harbin for 37 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Red Army Street and the east-west Dazhi Street once intersected at the ancient Gothic wooden structure St. Nicholas Church. Nowadays, there is no trace of the Church of San Nicola. The International Hotel built in 1937 looks like a huge accordion. Opposite it is the former Italian Consulate, the Gibelosso building built in 1919, which is full of exquisite reliefs. The octagonal exterior walls are stacked upward layer by layer to form a lovely eclectic building dominated by Baroque style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another group of &quot;solemn vs. cute&quot; buildings is on Dazhi Street. The famous &quot;big stone house&quot; Harbin Railway Bureau Office Building was completed in February 1904 as the Middle East Railway Administration. Magnificent, majestic and dignified, it is like a &quot;huge castle&quot;; the Harbin Railway Museum, just across the street, has a simple interior decoration, while the exterior maintains the yellow and white colors from its days as the Middle East Railway Club, full of joy. breath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lama Terrace&quot; where St. Nicholas Church is located is the highest point in Harbin. It can be protected from floods when the Songhua River rises. Therefore, starting in 1899, Russia began to regulate the location of this place. The Qinjiagang area (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Nangang District&lt;/span>;) is undergoing large-scale urban construction. Within five years, the China Eastern Railway Administration Building and the Moscow Shopping Mall Building were built. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Heilongjiang Provincial Museum&lt;/span>;) and other European-style buildings were completed, and the east-west axis of Qinjiagang - Horvat Street, Dazhi Street and Main streets such as the New Business Street (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today&#39;s Guogol Street&lt;/span>;) were built. In the 1930s, the Qinjiagang area had &quot;grand buildings, neat streets&quot;, &quot;fresh air and fragrant flowers&quot;. Most foreign consulates were concentrated here, becoming Harbin&#39;s administrative center and a gathering place for foreigners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qiulin Company located in Nangang District today&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;East and West The various subsystems of Fang civilization collide, rub, infiltrate, and blend with each other here. The unprecedented integration of the architectural culture of various ethnic groups in the world presents a &quot;cross-communication of multiculturalism.&quot; The Middle East Railway brought a large number of overseas Chinese - according to statistics, in 1923, the total population of Harbin reached 400,000, with nearly 200,000 overseas Chinese and more than 180,000 Chinese. Twenty or thirty years after the Russo-Japanese War, Harbin has become an international city. It brought Russian culture, Jewish culture, Japanese culture, Tatar culture... and nearly 70 churches including St. Nicholas Church, St. Sophia Church, and the Church of the Annunciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhdanov is to Harbin what Hudec is to Shanghai. Among the three churches &quot;clustered&quot; on Dongdazhi Street, the Church of Our Lady of Saints and Saints designed by Zhdanov (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Church of Our Lady of Protection&lt;/span >;) is the most eye-catching. This Byzantine-style church is said to have preserved the 2,600-kilogram bell that was cast in Moscow in 1899, but it is not available to see now. What can be seen is the notice board erected next to the church: &quot;Please pay attention to your behavior, God is working.&quot; Watching you”. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Church: Bells Echoing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike the Virgin Mary Church, which is located on the busy main road of the city, the Tatar Church, also designed by Zhdanov The Tai Mosque is hidden among the residential buildings on Tongjiang Street. The red and white walls are full of Byzantine style of quiet and dignified temperament. It is like a &quot;mysterious little castle&quot;. Especially at dusk, it has a sense of simplicity. From 1899, when the first Russian Jew, S. I. Berzeri, came to Harbin to the 1940s, countless Jews came to this &quot;second home&quot; and built buildings here, including a hexagonal church with a dome holding up the Shield of David. Many Jewish buildings including the Star Synagogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tatar Mosque&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least a hundred years ago, the majestic The bells once echoed over Harbin. In the sound of the bells, expatriates from all over the world, adventurers and exiles of all kinds stopped to listen and found a moment of solace in their hometown in this foreign land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The symbol of Harbin - St. Sophia Church, the melodious bells played on important religious festivals can be said to be the deep memory of the city for the older generation of Harbin people. It is said that in the church on a snowy day in winter, the Byzantine-style appearance can allow more snow to stay on the surface of the building. The wind blows the snowflakes, which are like the ultimate romance in a crystal ball; on a snowy night, the church will turn into gold bricks. The castle with bright tiles and the towering cross are like stars in the night sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hagia Sophia on a snowy night, the scenery is as dreamy as a crystal ball. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to observe the details of the church quietly, the best time is at dusk. The full dark green dome full of momentum is lifted very high by the main body of the clear red brick building. The golden cross shines brightly, showing a dynamic beauty of rising successively. Viewed from the side, the tops of the four tents are staggered, and the slanting light shines on it. The architectural details cast mysterious shadows, honest and simple. Step into the church and enjoy the daily rotating concerts, as well as the mottled walls and Roman-style arched windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The setting sun reflects on the top of the church, which reminds people of its sister with the same name on the other side of the Eurasian continent, and also allows people to relive the rich history of the city&#39;s past. In fact, this church had &quot;humble origins&quot; and was only the military chapel of the 4th Infantry Division of Tsarist Russia in Eastern Siberia. In March 1907, it was renovated with funds from the Russian businessman Cheschakov, whose home was on Red Army Street. In 1912 A layer of bricks was laid on the original foundation. In 1923, the Russian architect Kasikov re-selected a site in the southeast corner of the old church and built it. It was completed in November 1932, giving it what it looks like today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Concert in Saint Sophia Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saint Sophia The architectural style and decorative style of the church draw on the Russian brick carving art of the 17th century. The St. Alexeev Church at the corner of Gogol Street and Shikes Street organically combines a huge building volume with facade brick decoration. Giving it a strong Russian accent and unique mood. Although this century-old building, which was originally an Orthodox church and was converted into a Catholic church in 1980, also has a majestic and scattered beauty. Even under the clear blue sky in the northeast, it can be regarded as the appearance of the city&#39;s architecture, but it is not as lively as Sofia Square. There are very few people around after sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lights&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: Chinese Baroque&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Qiulin Kvass rustles after opening the bottle cap. This famous drink looks like Beer, slightly red in color but with only 1% alcohol content, is very suitable for &quot;bottle blowing&quot; when traveling and hiking - such as walking from Alexeev Church, along Gogol Street to the L-shaped building built in 1908 A grand building with a light green tone - Qiulin Yangxing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many old buildings on Gogol Street, but while maintaining their former glory, they have inevitably declined and become dilapidated - just like Daowai District. To the north from the train station, east of the railway across the river, is the Daowai District, formerly known as &quot;Fujiadian&quot;, where immigrants from Shandong and Hebei settled in Guandong. Although it is one of the earliest urban centers in Harbin, due to the lack of complete and precise planning, in the 1930s the streets here were &quot;narrow and uneven&quot; and &quot;everywhere you go is so disgusting that you have to cover your nose and avoid it.&quot; &amp;nbsp;——The folk proverb at that time said: &quot;Nangang is heaven, inside the road is the world, and outside the road is hell.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unique &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; architecture also grew here. Along the street, the Western Baroque facade is used, while incorporating the auspicious decorative patterns of traditional Chinese architecture. Iron railings or &quot;Guanyin bottle&quot;-style concrete railings are set up on the edge of the protruding platform. Stepping inside, it is purely a northern courtyard. The architectural shape combines earth and western elements, giving it its own charm. The Chinese Baroque neighborhood, which is mainly located on South Second and Third Streets and has been renovated into a tourist attraction, is lackluster. Many of the green brick streets and wide courtyards have been transformed into catering shops. They are more organized but lack the liveliness and prosperity of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, the &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; on Dong Jingyu Street in the neighborhood is the most authentic. Originally built in 1890, this long street was originally called Zhengyang Street. It is also the birthplace of Harbin&#39;s national commerce: Zhengyang Tower, Laodingfeng, Shiyitang, Daluoxin Department Store, Hengdeli, Tongji Shopping Mall... every inch of land Jin&#39;s Old Street used to be lined with businesses. At the intersection of Jingyu Street and Nantou Street, the four-story brick and wood structure Purification Hospital was built in 1920. It was formerly known as Tongyi Qinghuo Store. It is one of the masterpieces of &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot;: the swaying reliefs of vine flowers from Ioni The exterior walls of the sub-column and Corinthian columns are winding all the way down, and the gorgeous and luxurious style is unforgettable, fully reflecting the hope of fame of the national industrial and commercial people at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Purification Hospital located outside Laodao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All famous, Prosperity and bustle have their end. Today&#39;s Laodaowai has lost its popularity due to large-scale construction, and its decline is fully visible: dilapidated buildings can be seen along the street, and the roofs are covered with decaying grass, as if the old buildings are sighing; the cats and dogs wandering on the street look full of vicissitudes of life. Feeling; beside the ruins, you can occasionally see small electric cars with the sign of &quot;darning&quot;, which is a common livelihood for middle-aged and elderly women in the Northeast - sewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In old Harbin, if the window of &quot;middle&quot; is &quot;Zhengyang Street&quot;, the epitome of &quot;west&quot; is Central Street - in Xiao Hong&#39;s pen, the city street is like a &quot;complex and unclear color&quot; &quot;Map&quot;, Harbin today has similar characteristics - it is also a commercial street, Jingyu Street outside the road has become a large construction site, and Central Street inside the road, at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning, there are tourists wandering around carrying kvass bottles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Laodaowai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Night, spring night, Central Street is a night full of music. Music from homeless people, music from Japanese dance halls, music from foreign restaurants... After 7 o&#39;clock, in the middle of Central Street, at a crossroads, the loud loudspeaker screamed, this The singing almost resounded throughout the street.&quot; Xiao Hong once wrote about Central Street in &quot;Spring Hangs on the Treetops&quot;, with a lot of irony and banter; however, the &quot;gradually countless&quot; things she recorded were &quot;like long ropes pulled in the sun&quot; The bright lights, like a string of yellow copper bells, seem to be still hanging on the 1,450-meter-long Central Street, which starts from the Songhua River Flood Control Victory Memorial Tower in the north and ends at Jingwei Street in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;On some side streets, it is quieter. The light of the street lamps imprints the shadows of the leaves on the road. The aging Russians are talking about the good days that no longer exist. ... In You may think it is ugly during the day, but on a beautiful night, you put beautiful clothes on everything, and everything seems to be beautiful.&quot; The shorter streets in Jin&#39;s works form a fish-like formation with the Central Street. The bone-shaped street layout supported the &quot;enchanting&quot; appearance of this street after the completion of the China-Eastern Railway in 1903, where foreign merchants gathered and shops were dotted; especially in 1924, the Russian engineer Komut Rashok was responsible for the design and supervision of the construction. After the rectangular bread-shaped granite pavement was replaced, the bread stone road replaced the muddy dirt road. The appearance of the street was greatly changed, and it became rich and luxurious. In the 1930s, Central Street had become an architectural art gallery and an international architectural expo. Both sides of the street Most of them are Baroque, Gothic, Renaissance and other styles of buildings, creating a beautiful skyline; there are many foreign stores, dance halls and cinemas, restaurants and bars... At that time, Central Street became a place of pilgrimage for commodity fetishism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;China Street (today’s Central Street) is beginning to take shape&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the streets paved with square stones, the sound of Victorian carriages has long since passed into the twilight of history. Only the pieces of breadstone that have been worn away by the passing years are still shining brightly on today&#39;s pedestrian streets. Visitors tell stories about the smoky past of the long street - on summer evenings, the brilliant sunset shines slantingly on more than 70 European-style and imitation European-style buildings, and they seem to have their own unique character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Music: Soul of the North&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is also the Madiel popsicle that is essential when visiting Central Street - Matsuura 1918 West, which was renovated in the Matsuura Yoko Building. Diagonally across from the restaurant is Madiel&#39;s cold drink hall. Nowadays, &quot;Madiel&quot; can be eaten all over the country at different prices, but it is said that they are all &quot;a bit uninteresting&quot;. You still have to buy 5 yuan a piece here, which is made in the front store and in the back factory, without wrapping paper, which is the most authentic: In winter, the daily sales here start at 10,000 sticks, and sales usually explode on New Year&#39;s Day, with 30,000 to 40,000 sticks sold a day. During the peak tourist season in Harbin, &quot;Naked Madiel in the North Wind&quot; is one of the features of Central Street. Everyone wants to &quot;cool themselves down to the bottom.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After nibbling on the popsicles, you can turn around and taste the hot red cabbage soup, mandarin fish in milk and delicious canned shrimps at the Madier Western Restaurant - since the Russians started cooking pots in Tianjia in 1898 With the opening of railway canteens, Russian-style Western food began to take root in China. In the Central Street area alone, there are Tadaos and Huamei (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;former Mars There are more than 30 Western restaurants such as Western Food Tea Shop&lt;/span>;) and Madiel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The food and delicacies are endlessly memorable, especially when accompanied by music - whether in Matsuura, Huamei, or Madiel’s own Western restaurant on the first floor, Madiel can often be heard in the summer The music show on the balcony on the second floor of the hotel includes violin music, saxophone performance or bel canto solo. Artists who appeared to be from Central and Eastern Europe took turns performing hard, attracting tourists to stop and adding a lot of excitement to Central Street. It was also reminiscent of their &quot;predecessors&quot;, the foreign musicians who gathered here in the first half of the 20th century. : In 1936, singers Alexander Wilkinsky and Fedor Chaliapin came to Kazakhstan to hold a concert; in 1938, 10-year-old Helmut Stern came to China with his parents, and at the age of 14 He held a concert in Harbin and later joined the Harbin Symphony Orchestra, which was founded in 1908 and was once known as the &quot;First Symphony Orchestra in the Far East.&quot; After going to Israel in 1948, he became the chief violinist of the Berlin Philharmonic... Starting in the 1920s, Foreigners in Harbin have founded nearly 30 music schools. The strong music atmosphere that has lasted for a century has become an important cornerstone for Harbin to be awarded the title of &quot;City of Music&quot; by the United Nations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old view of Madier Hotel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Madiel Hotel Er&#39;s balcony music show is just a small note in the &quot;Music City&quot;. &quot;In the Madier Hotel, that hotel with a big stage and a luxurious hall, a play was organized between the movie screenings and a dance program was started... I happily put aside the boring rehearsals of the troupe and went to them specifically There.&quot; Dancer and poet Larisa Angell lived in China for 34 years and often performed at the Madier Hotel founded by Russian Jew Joseph Kasper in 1906. Her beautiful figure and summer Photos of Ryabin and Wilkinski, as well as tableware, lamps, electrical appliances, accessories, and promotional posters of Madier Cinema, together form the &quot;historical and cultural corridor&quot; in the hotel; during her years of activeness in Harbin , this very ancient building on Central Street is regarded as &quot;having the most luxurious ballroom and restaurant, the most modern and comfortable guest rooms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the scenery of the Madier Hotel was unparalleled, until the &quot;Casper Kidnapping Case&quot; that shocked Harbin in 1933 came to an abrupt end. On the evening of August 24 of that year, after dining at the Madier Western Restaurant, Simon, the son of Joseph Kasper Sr., was kidnapped by the Inspector General of the Kazakhstan Police Department, Martinov, and 15 gangsters; on December 3, Simon’s body was found It was discovered in Xiaoling near Harbin, causing an outcry. The following year, the sad old Joseph took his wife and children and left for France. Soon he died of illness in Paris. Madier also declined from glory to glory. Only the leather bag left by Casper in the &quot;Historical and Cultural Corridor&quot; of the hotel can be traced. Talk about being a witness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 25, 1948, representatives of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and democrats such as Shen Junru and Zhang Bojun in Kazakhstan reached an &quot;Agreement on Various Issues Concerning the Convening of a New Political Consultative Conference&quot; in the No. 1 conference room of the Madier Hotel. . At that time, the 73-year-old &quot;Heng Lao&quot; Shen Junru lived in a hotel and often went for walks along the Songhua River. He saw the rare scene of the river freezing and then thawing again, so he wrote a poem: &quot;After the river freezes, I see rushing water and snow. Even the tide is not full. The atmosphere of the earth also changes with people and events. From now on, geese from the north no longer have to go south.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/ MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Dormition Church in the Cultural Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south bank of the Songhua River at the end of Central Street is Stalin Park, a narrow and long &quot;riverside&quot;. From here you can You can enjoy the scenery of the river that is sometimes rapid and sometimes gentle, touch the soul of the northern city, and feel the carnival atmosphere of the &quot;Harbin Summer&quot; concert that has been held for more than 60 years in the summer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rivers and songs flow into the distance, deposited over hundreds of years. Harbin is like a sponge, absorbing all sounds, while those mottled old buildings become witnesses of the city&#39;s historical changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原副主任龚建华一审被判有期徒刑15年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, the Intermediate People’s Court of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province publicly announced the verdict of the original party group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress In the case of member and deputy director Gong Jianhua accepting bribes, the defendant Gong Jianhua was sentenced to 15 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 5.5 million; the bribery income of Gong Jianhua and his The interest shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251237&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 2004 to 2020, the defendant Gong Jianhua used his position as deputy secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, executive deputy mayor, leader of the Nanchang Municipal Planning Land Operation Leading Group, deputy secretary of the Yichun Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, and municipal Chairman, Secretary of the Fuzhou Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, Member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, Secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee, Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers or status, provide relevant individuals with land listing, project contracting, and project development. Provided assistance with matters such as job promotion and job promotion, and illegally received property equivalent to more than RMB 83.61 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the defendant Gong Jianhua’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes, and the amount of bribes he accepted was particularly huge. In view of the fact that Gong Jianhua truthfully confessed his crime after voluntarily surrendering to the case, and voluntarily confessed some bribery facts that were not yet known to the case-handling agency, he had the circumstances to surrender, confessed and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the bribery proceeds and their accruals have been sealed, detained, and frozen in the case, which is legal. , determine the circumstances of lenient punishment, and he may be punished leniently in accordance with the law. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次本不公开的学术不端自查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3 nh27B3yxPJUsd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, during an academic conference, Li Wei (pseudonym), a professor at the School of Physical Education of Shihezi University, casually agreed to a friend’s request for a paper name. It was a paper related to swimming. In 2021, a third-party agency discovered that the paper was suspected of being synthesized by reverse translation software and reported it to the Ministry of Education for confirmation, and the Ministry of Education fed back the situation to Shihezi University. The school launched an investigation and sent a letter to the other school, and found that Li Wei, the corresponding author, had not previously known about the existence of this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wei was punished and could not participate in various project applications and evaluations for three years. During the ongoing self-examination of academic misconduct in college theses and the cleanup of false claims, Li Wei was reported again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in late May 2023, many universities have successively announced the launch of self-examination and cleanup of academic misconduct in papers, requiring self-examination and cleanup of academic papers since January 2018. Previously, on April 27, 2023, the General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology issued a self-examination notice, requiring universities and scientific research institutes to self-examine and clean up common academic misconduct including plagiarism, plagiarism, forged peer review, ghostwriting and investment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main purpose of self-examination is to reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers and strive to curb the increase. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a self-examination operation that was not intended to be made public. Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the notice only became known to the outside world because two universities posted the notice as an attachment online. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The self-examination document is “not public &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the notices issued by each school, the main targets of this self-examination are These are all academic papers published by teachers and students of the school as the first signed unit. The focus areas of self-examination are basically the same, and they are all relatively common academic misconduct. It mainly includes six categories: plagiarism, plagiarism, and duplication of publications; forging corresponding authors, forging or manipulating peer reviews; forging, fabricating, and tampering with experimental data and pictures, using one picture for multiple purposes, and selective use; buying, selling, and ghostwriting papers; and purchasing experiments. Research data; nominal phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the notice of the Ministry of Science and Technology, universities and scientific research institutes in all provinces should carry out self-examination and clean-up work. However, according to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, only nearly 30 universities, including Shihezi University, Qinghai University, and Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture, have issued this notice on their official websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice was originally a non-public document, but it became known to the outside world after two universities posted it online as an attachment to the notice. In fact, the notice documents issued by the Jiangsu and Anhui Provincial Science and Technology Departments did state &quot;This matter will not be made public&quot; at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a top-down campaign to investigate academic misconduct. Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact nearly 30 universities that publicly released the notice. Among them, Shihezi University, Qinghai University, Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University were interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, different universities have slightly different self-examination methods. However, they all adopt the method of teachers filling in forms and reporting by themselves. The content of the form mainly contains the personal information of the self-examination teacher, such as position, school, research direction, etc., as well as paper information, including paper title, DOI/PMID, publication time, publication journal, author category, academic violations, etc. The college’s statistical researchers are required to screen academic papers published within the verification period, identify academic papers with the above six conditions, put forward rectification suggestions, and form a self-examination work summary report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specific inspection methods can be roughly divided into focused spot inspections and comprehensive inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University and Yanshan University adopted a comprehensive inventory approach. A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University told Southern Weekend reporters that they had comprehensively checked 8,671 papers signed by teachers at the school within the time limit. The school organized an investigation team. The teachers first filled in the self-examination form, and then the college compiled and submitted it. Finally, the school&#39;s scientific research office reported it to the XPCC Education Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Social Sciences Office of Yanshan University said that after the announcement, the secondary college organized teachers to conduct self-examinations and submit self-examination forms and commitment letters. The college issues a self-examination report based on the self-examination situation, which is finally summarized and reported by the Social Science Office. Southern Weekend reporters contacted some colleges of the school to inquire about the implementation status. Among them, a staff member from the office of the School of Construction Engineering and Mechanics confirmed the statement of the aforementioned person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinghai University and Southwest University of Science and Technology adopt focused spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that the school&#39;s Science and Technology Office takes the lead and adopts a two-level system. First, the college&#39;s professor committee organizes self-examination, and then the school inspection office conducts random inspections. Specific to different disciplines, the degree of rigor varies. For example, due to the subject characteristics of medicine, academic misconduct is prone to occur. The school conducted a census of more than 150 papers published by teachers from the clinical medical school between January 2022 and May 2023, while other disciplines were Spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the requirements in the notice are from January 2018 to May 2023, the aforementioned teacher in charge said that Qinghai University has two inspections every year, at mid-term and at the end of the year, so this time it will be from 2022 to the present. Check the thesis again as a key point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why he adopted the method of focused spot checks was that Qinghai University’s strong disciplines are mainly agriculture and forestry. “Due to the plateau specificity, many papers do not have experiments and data, and cannot be copied from other places. Therefore, The probability of academic misconduct will be relatively small.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spot checks are conducted on a proportional basis. He gave an example, based on the total number of papers published by the college within the period, for example, 50 papers were published, and 10 papers were randomly checked, including the original data of the scientific research and whether the person named on the paper was a member of the research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology said that they mainly screen key papers, and others mainly rely on feedback and reports from school teachers and other staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Almost no problems were found&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of large-scale self-examination has little impact on This is the first time for many universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant officials from Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University stated that similar large-scale system self-examination work had not been carried out before. The person in charge of Southwest University of Science and Technology emphasized that issues such as academic misconduct and pseudonymity were previously mainly investigated and handled through reports from others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in most notices, the self-examination time left for teachers is about one month. At present, the self-examination work has basically been completed at the school level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some self-examination window periods are shorter. The Science and Technology Office of Shijiazhuang Railway University issued a notice on July 26, 2023, requiring each college to complete the self-examination and cleanup work before July 30. If problems are found, a summary form should be filled out in a timely manner and submitted to the Science and Technology Office, and remedial measures such as corrections and retractions should be taken, and &quot;no feedback after the deadline will be deemed as a paper without academic misconduct.&quot; They gave each college only four days for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback from the four schools interviewed, the result of the self-examination was “almost no problems.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers at Yanshan University said that the self-examination work was completed at the end of July and &quot;no problems were found&quot;, and emphasized that the relevant results have been reported to the Provincial Department of Education. Teachers from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology also said that the school has completed a preliminary screening and found no relevant violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether a self-examination report needs to be issued, a staff member from the office of the School of Architectural Engineering and Mechanics of Yanshan University said, “The school only requires us to fill in a self-examination form and issue a report if there are any problems, but our school should no problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, the teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that since inspections were organized twice a year before, no serious academic misconduct was found this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only exception is Shihezi University. They self-identified three illegal articles. The violations were improper naming, purchasing data, and repeated publication. They belonged to the School of Physical Education, School of Medicine, and School of Animal Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the improper listing and purchase data are illegal articles that have been investigated before this inspection. Although notices from the science and technology departments of many provinces stated that papers that have been investigated and dealt with may not be included in the scope of this self-examination. However, the teacher in charge of the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University believes that it &quot;still serves as a warning.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to punish after investigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology stated that if problems are found during self-examination and cleanup, scientific researchers must promptly report to the unit and take remedial measures such as corrections and retractions. Those who comply with the lenient treatment circumstances specified in Article 34 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; may be given lenient treatment in accordance with the regulations; those who conceal or make false reports shall be punished in accordance with Article 3 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; Article 15 and other relevant regulations will be dealt with seriously and publicly announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University explained that the school has criticized and educated the teachers involved and required them not to apply for projects within three years. They are not allowed to be prioritized and receive talent titles, nor can they apply for science and technology projects. award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University will take lenient treatment for those who took the initiative to report in this self-examination. Zhang Xiaoqian and Li Jie of the School of Animal Science and Technology published the article &quot;The Effect of Culture Temperature on the Test Results of Streptococcus Thermophilus Inhibition Method&quot; in 2019. The teacher involved submitted papers to two journals, &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; and &quot;Chinese Dairy Cow&quot;, of which &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; was the core journal. In May 2019, &quot;Chinese Cows&quot; took the lead in publishing the paper, and four months later, &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; published this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discovering the duplicate publication, the author of the paper repeatedly negotiated with the person in charge of the journal &quot;Chinese Cows&quot; and asked the other party to withdraw the paper, but was rejected. It was not until July 2023 that the author of the paper negotiated with the relevant notice from the Ministry of Science and Technology, and the other party finally agreed to withdraw the paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University said that because the author of the paper took the initiative to report it and contacted the magazine several times to withdraw the paper, the handling was lenient and only criticized and educated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why self-examination? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why is there this large-scale top-down self-examination? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The explanation in the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice is to consolidate the main responsibilities of each unit, reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers, strive to curb the increase, and guide scientific researchers to strengthen their awareness of scientific research integrity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the core of self-examination is to eliminate the stock and curb the increase. The aforementioned person close to the Ministry of Science and Technology explained that for example, a scientific researcher bought an article ten years ago and either published it to apply for a professional title to make a profit, or it has never been used. If it doesn&#39;t work, I can only hold it in with all kinds of severe crackdowns now. Once it is published, it may explode one day. Either way, they will be uneasy. Self-examination and clean-up is a good opportunity, &quot;It is to give these scientific researchers who have made mistakes a chance, whether they were ignorant or lucky at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it also gives scientific researchers an opportunity to self-examine and sort out. &quot;It is always a good thing to sort it out, to enhance the awareness of integrity, to find out the family background, and to avoid the situation of being named but not knowing it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for curbing the increase, &quot;If you know that everyone is watching this matter , they will never do it again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the aforementioned person close to the Ministry of Science and Technology mentioned that since it is a self-examination, there are mitigating circumstances. &quot;If there is no profit from it, you may not even be held accountable, but criticism is definitely required.&quot; He believes that self-examination serves more of an educational and deterrent role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not the first time an inventory has been carried out. Southern Weekend reporters learned that this work was also carried out at the ministry level in 2022, with the purpose of letting relevant departments and local levels understand the importance that ministries attach to scientific research integrity work, but it was &quot;not made public&quot; at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the possible concealment of reports, the aforementioned people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology said that if there are no problems during the self-examination, but problems are found in the future, and they are within the time period from 2018 to the present, then the punishment will definitely be aggravated. , &quot;This is equivalent to confronting integrity checks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you look at it over a longer period of time, behind the self-examination are the increasing number of retractions of papers and the tightening of scientific research integrity management measures in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 20, 2017, academic publishing giant Springer issued a statement stating that 107 papers published in &quot;Tumor Biology&quot; had been withdrawn due to suspected peer review fraud. The papers involved are all from China and were published between 2012 and 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Association for Science and Technology expressed its opinion at the time, hoping that Springer Publishing Group could improve the internal control mechanism as soon as possible, strengthen the management of journals, and deal with problematic papers before publication instead of withdrawing them after publication. At the same time, we are highly vigilant about &quot;predatory journals&quot; that seek financial gain and collude with &quot;third-party&quot; institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 15, 2023, Healsan Consulting LLC of the United States released the &quot;2022 SCI Paper Retraction Briefing&quot;. The briefing shows that as of December 31, 2022, a total of 41,642 SCI manuscripts have been withdrawn worldwide, including 19,421 from China. Specifically, from January 1, 2022 to December 31, 2022, there were 5,488 SCI manuscripts retracted around the world, of which 2,879 were retracted in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also an increasing emphasis on scientific research integrity. In May 2018, the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued &quot;Several Opinions on Further Strengthening the Construction of Scientific Research Integrity.&quot; The opinions emphasize the need to severely crack down on behavior that seriously violates the requirements of scientific research integrity, establish a lifelong accountability system, and investigate and deal with it at any time once discovered. This is the first time that the central government has issued a document raising the importance of scientific research integrity to a very high level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, in 2020, the Science and Technology Progress Law was revised to further clarify the relevant punitive measures for breach of trust in scientific research. In 2022, 22 departments including the Ministry of Science and Technology revised the &quot;Rules for Investigation and Handling of Scientific Research Integrity Cases (Trial)&quot;, which resulted in more specific handling rules for the investigation and handling of scientific research dishonesty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, starting from 2018, the Ministry of Science and Technology has successively announced the results of investigations and treatment of untrustworthy conduct in scientific research every year. There are one batch of results from 2017 to 2019, two batches in 2020, and two batches in 2021 and 2022. Four batches were announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There will be follow-up after this round of self-examination. The aforementioned people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology said that, in particular, problems that have not been found at all are precisely within the scope of focus. &quot;This time I came with the red seal of my unit, and there was not a single problematic article. However, if the articles are frequently withdrawn later, or problems arise during the investigation, then the unit&#39;s main responsibility will definitely not be fully implemented, and it will be seriously investigated and dealt with.&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医生频频被举报，“飞刀”为何难合规？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257002]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsP srAMQWtq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Currently, consultation and multi-point practice are two ways to formalize &quot;flying knife&quot; The main path, but the remuneration standards of both should be consistent with the remuneration system in the main practice institutions. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the disease is not cured, should the surgery fee be refunded? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, Mr. Ma, a family member of a patient in Qixian County, Henan Province, said that his father &quot;had a bump on his face&quot; in July, so he came to Qixian Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital for treatment. The hospital informed me that a specialist from Kaifeng would perform the surgery and that a cash payment of 3,000 yuan would be required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The surgery was performed by experts from outside hospitals, the surgical fee was higher than the market price, and the cash payment was all reminders that Mr. Ma&#39;s father had undergone a &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery. &quot;Flying Knife&quot;, as the name suggests, &quot;hits the flying knife to open the knife&quot;. Doctors leave their hospitals to visit other places in their spare time, mostly performing surgical operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s interesting is that the patient’s condition was not good, and Mr. Ma wanted to repay the 3,000 yuan surgical fee charged by the surgeon. This was based on the “Interim Regulations on the Management of Physicians’ Out-of-Home Consultation” issued by the former Ministry of Health in 2005. Regulations regarding consultation fees should be paid uniformly to the consulting medical institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident was reported by Henan Metropolis Channel, it immediately attracted attention in the industry: Should &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery exist? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some doctors believe that &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery currently lacks institutional protection, brings risks to both patients and doctors, and should be banned. Some doctors also hold objections, believing that &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery helps experts earn income, patients receive convenient treatment, grassroots hospitals gain technical experience, and local medical insurance funds can stay local, so it should be supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, &quot;throwing knife&quot; surgery remains in a legal gray area. Policies that can make &quot;flying knives&quot; comply have encountered many obstacles in the hospital&#39;s internal management and institutional processes. Under the huge market demand at the grassroots level, private &quot;flying knives&quot; have always existed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Income issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For doctors, the core reason for the long-lasting success of &quot;Flying Knife&quot; is &quot;increased income.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, consultation and multi-site practice are the two main ways to formalize &quot;flying knife&quot;, but the remuneration standards for both must be consistent with the salary system within the major practice institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 &quot;Interim Provisions on the Management of Physicians&#39; Out-of-Home Consultation&quot; mentioned that the consultation fees involved in the consultation shall be subject to the regulations of the location of the inviting medical institution, and additional fees may be charged as appropriate on the basis of local regulations. The increase will be determined by the provincial price department in conjunction with the health administrative department at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The range of &quot;discretionary&quot; is destined not to be too high. Cheng Sheng, the department director of a secondary hospital in Beijing, told Southern Weekend reporters that the cost of inter-hospital consultations in Beijing is about 300 to 300 yuan. 500 yuan, &quot;Which expert is willing to waste time and energy by making such a trip?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the salary of multi-site practice, the former National Health and Family Planning Commission issued the &quot;Regulations on Promoting and Standardizing the Multi-site Practice of Physicians&quot; in 2014. &quot;Notice of Several Opinions&quot; stipulates that the salary of multi-site practicing physicians is determined by consultation between the medical institution and the physician at the place of practice based on factors such as actual working hours, workload, and work performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the income that doctors who perform daily surgeries in our hospital can earn, a respiratory doctor in Shanghai once revealed to a Southern Weekend reporter that his remuneration for each operation is about 300 yuan. A hard-working doctor Two or three operations are performed every day, and the monthly performance bonus income is about 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Corresponding to this is the income from &quot;flying knives&quot;. Wang Gui, who works as a &quot;flying knife&quot; agency, revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the cost of a &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery for a patient ranges from 3,000 yuan to 9,000 yuan, with the agency taking a 10% commission and the rest going to the doctor. The main factors that determine the cost are the doctor&#39;s level, the difficulty of the operation, and the distance of practice. An operation priced at 10,000 yuan may require the support of multiple doctors across provinces, and the operation lasts 7 to 8 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Agents tend to stratify experts. Top experts are generally subject leaders, master&#39;s and doctoral tutors, and department directors of top hospitals in their cities. These doctors are the first choice for foreign aid in large hospitals in provincial capital cities. The seniority and popularity of ordinary experts are low, and the general location of &quot;flying knife&quot; is county-level hospitals. “There are quite a lot of surgeons in general surgery, ophthalmology, gastroenterology, hepatobiliary surgery, thoracic surgery, and orthopedics,” Wang Gui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without an intermediary like Wang Gui, &quot;throwing knives&quot; mostly occur between doctors who have personal relationships. Most of the inviting doctors come from district and county hospitals, or have studied in the expert&#39;s department, or have studied under the same discipline. &quot;Both parties must know the basics.&quot; said Cheng Lei, director of thoracic surgery at a tertiary hospital in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, regardless of the form, compared with the above-mentioned &quot;Regulations&quot; and &quot;Notice&quot;, &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Formalization efforts have never stopped&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of some doctors, in addition to economic benefits, &quot;Flying Knife&quot; can also showcase their skills and improve &quot; Jianghu status&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Lei told Southern Weekend reporters that he once went to overseas hospitals to demonstrate technology under the organization of a surgical instrument manufacturer, helping a tumor ablation surgery to be implemented nationwide. “It’s more like a flying knife than a flying knife. It’s about teaching.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even as the chief physician of thoracic surgery, Cheng Lei has to ask for help from colleagues who can handle difficult surgeries. Cheng Lei&#39;s father was diagnosed with aortic dissection in a hospital in Jiangsu and suspected aortic aneurysm. The local hospital did not have the conditions for surgery, and it was hundreds of kilometers away from Shanghai for treatment. Once the tumor ruptured on the way, it would be life-threatening. Finally, Doctor &quot;Flying Knife&quot; solved the urgent problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, given the reality of uneven distribution of medical resources, governments at all levels have never stopped trying to bring &quot;flying knives&quot; onto the formal track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 &quot;Interim Regulations on the Management of Physicians&#39; Out-of-Home Consultation&quot; proposed an inter-hospital consultation system, and the 2009 &quot;Notice of the Ministry of Health on Issues Concerning the Multi-site Practice of Physicians&quot; responded to the concerns from all walks of life about allowing multiple sites. The call to practice. Since 2020, the construction of medical consortia has accelerated, and the consultation, training, and referral systems of hospitals within the same medical consortium have become increasingly mature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be understood that if an expert wants to perform surgery in the same hospital for a long time, he will usually apply for a multi-site practice registration. If it is a one-time operation, a consultation method will be used.” Senior Jingheng Law Firm Partner Zhang Li, who has been a doctor for six years, explained this to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the multi-site practice system, there was a restrictive rule that &quot;a doctor is not allowed to practice in more than three medical institutions.&quot; However, the &quot;Physician Practice Registration Management Measures&quot; promulgated in 2017 allowed doctors to Practice in multiple locations across provinces. It also stipulates that doctors who practice in multiple locations within the same provincial administrative region of their main practice institution only need to register with these practice institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change from a registration system to a filing system means that doctors can practice at multiple locations without permission from the main practice institution and the local health department. With the support of such policies, a set of data released by the National Health Commission in October 2020 showed that the number of multi-site practicing doctors in the country has reached 260,000, four times that of 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Hospitals don’t want to see their doctors flying around”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are still many obstacles to the promotion of multi-site practice, which also provides “ Throwing knives&quot; creates the soil of reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees mentioned soft discipline in hospitals. The Southern Weekend reporter obtained the &quot;Multi-site Practice Management Standards for Physicians&quot; implemented by a well-known hospital in Southwest China, which requires doctors to complete the multi-site practice registration, but also to register with the local health bureau and submit it to the hospital. Photo, physician qualification certificate, practicing physician license. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cumbersome in-hospital approval process is not an isolated case. According to public reports from the self-media &quot;Seeing Medical Circle&quot;, in 2020, the &quot;Measures for the Management of Multi-site Practice of Physicians (Trial)&quot; issued by Changsha First Hospital stipulates that doctors who practice multi-site must have intermediate professional titles or above, and their departments must be above. The department&#39;s year-end KPI assessment results for the first year rank above the average level, etc. The document also states that non-commandatory activities in medical institutions outside the hospital must be approved by the department director, reported to the medical department and the leader of the hospital in charge, and can only be registered after approval by the hospital office meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Multiple Practice Management Standards for Physicians&quot; of the above-mentioned Southwest Regional Hospital requires that multi-site practicing physicians should sign a labor agreement with the multi-site practice institution on the practice category, scope of practice, employment period, work tasks, Medical responsibilities, time arrangements, assessment methods, salary, insurance benefits, etc. are clarified, and the agreement is filed with the Medical Department of our hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pang Liang, a surgeon at a private hospital in Beijing, told Southern Weekend reporters that some hospitals have banned doctors from practicing outside their homes. One of the reasons is that they are worried that patients will be diverted to other hospitals, which will affect their income. Xie Rushi, honorary president of the Shenzhen Non-Public Medical Institutions Association, analyzed from a purely managerial psychological perspective, &quot;Hospitals don&#39;t want to see their doctors flying around. This is normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Flying knives&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Controversies continue, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The people will not hold the officials accountable&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Flying knife&quot; surgeries performed without permission may be classified as illegal medical practice and subject to severe punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the technical appraisal of medical malpractice determines that it constitutes a medical malpractice and bears the main responsibility, at the administrative level, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor may be suspended from practicing or even have his physician&#39;s practicing certificate revoked; if he violates criminal law, the doctor may also Prosecuted on suspicion of medical malpractice. If the medical malpractice is of equal liability and below, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor may be held administratively liable. As for the civil compensation part, the law stipulates that the subject of compensation is medical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a large extent, disputes related to &quot;throwing knives&quot; still belong to the category of &quot;people do not complain and officials do not investigate&quot;, and the patient&#39;s will has a great influence on the development of the case. In one case that Zhang Li represented, when a &quot;flying knife&quot; expert performed a chest nodule operation, the patient suffered from massive bleeding and &quot;could not get off the operating table.&quot;事后医生上门道歉，家属也认为国家培养一个医生不容易，选择放弃行政投诉及刑事举报，所以“飞刀”医生没有涉及行政与刑事处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在另一起案件中，医生进行一场胸部整形手术，患者术中同样出现大出血，康复之后告到了专家所在医院的卫生主管部门。最后专家被行政撤职、调离工作岗位、被罚暂停执业三个月。这是章李所接触过的处罚结果最严重的一起“飞刀”案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使不发生医疗事故，医生也可能被病人“闹”。一个广为人知的例子是，2019年，一山西患者请到了北京天坛医院医生对其进行神经外科支架植入手术。据中国青年报报道，事后患者家属在支付1万元现金“飞刀”费用时，偷偷录像并举报，导致涉事医生和该医院帮忙收钱转交的医生均被停职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个隐忧是，“飞刀”医生开完刀后拂袖离去，将术后护理留给基层医院，但后者可能缺乏相关知识，对病人福祉构成隐患。庞梁提到了2019年的一起医疗事故：一位男性患者在某医院进行了胃减容手术，由一位参加学术交流的外地医生执刀。术后5天，患者猝然离世。尸检报告显示，患者在术后继发胃漏、急性化脓性腹膜炎、腹腔脓血性积液，导致感染中毒性休克、多脏器功能衰竭而死亡。这可能是当地医院缺乏合适的术后护理的结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“病人觉得效果没到预期，要退钱，不退钱我就告你，一告一个准。”程磊表示，“飞刀”手术的灰色属性是医生们的天然软肋，高额的费用是上不得台面的。遇到纠纷，发出“飞刀”邀约的基层医院大多不会去找专家的麻烦，而是默默出钱“把事平了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;合法合规难题待解&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看似很美好的“飞刀”，仍未走出不合规的本质，这意味着身处其中的患者、医生的抗风险能力都极其脆弱。比如，一些医院会给医生投保医疗事故责任险，帮助减少发生事故后的经济损失，但未经备案的“飞刀”手术显然不在理赔范畴内。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生们也逐渐摸索出一种“半合规”的院外会诊操作路径。出诊前先让基层医院出具邀请函，在自己院内完成备案。会诊完成后，再在正常收入的基础上加收一笔钱。后者不计入财务流程，也不会由病人直接付给专家，而是经由邀请方医院转手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目前日常中都是这么干的，需要有一定的补充收益这样才有人愿意去会诊。”谢汝石告诉南方周末记者，如此一来，“飞刀”行为本身是合规报备过的，属于合法的医疗行为，但收入的部分属于红包，仍然见不得光，可能面临院内纪检部门的查处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于自我保护，医生们也会筛选“飞刀”病例，避免参与风险太高的“飞刀”手术。王贵表示，患者提出请院外专家执刀的要求后，管床医生会评估该患者家属是否“比较敏感”，容易挑刺，经济条件是否宽裕等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在庞梁的设想中，为了让“飞刀”收入走到阳光下，大医院应该建立一个公开的专家库，按照科室、级别对每位专家明码标价，供患者和基层医院选择。这一价格可以与日常执业的薪酬拉开差距。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是让“飞刀”真正获得名分。王贵所在的机构具备齐全的诊疗营业资质，控股民营医院。专家均在这家医院注册多点执业，再由该医院派遣出去提供咨询服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在章李看来，如此一来医生便能绕开公立属性的主执业地医疗机构，合法地进行外出会诊。在一篇教医生如何合法“飞刀”的文章中，他将这个做法称为“远程导弹”，而“洲际导弹”则是创建或加入医生集团、诊所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生集团主要是对接会诊供需双方，派遣集团医生前往基层医院提供服务。但医生集团不属于医疗机构，医生仍隶属于一个主执业医疗机构——或为医生的老东家，或为医生集团内的民营医院。本质上，医生集团只是中介平台，医生走的仍是多点执业或会诊道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾参与创办多个医生集团的谢汝石表示，医生集团可以与患者或派遣地医院签订告知协议，确定“飞刀”手术的价格，并且以医生集团名义收费。如此操作，使得处于灰色地带的“飞刀”费用合规。不过，医生集团面临的问题是，通过招投标形式与派遣地医院达成合作关系十分困难，而和患者一个个单独洽谈合作又不能形成商业模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使资质齐全，王贵所在的机构依然十分谨慎。他们对外宣称的商业模式是提供医生的咨询服务，包含术前评估、术后康复方案制定等，但不包含手术执刀。 “实际上是会执刀的，但不能这么说，因为没有文件允许我们这么做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中程磊、王贵、庞梁是化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新冠疫苗：每年秋天来一针？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些国家，新冠疫苗可能要像流感一样每年推荐接种了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月12日，美国疾病预防控制中心（CDC）发布建议，六个月以上的所有人都应该在今年秋冬季注射一针新版新冠疫苗。几天前，美国食品药品监督管理局（FDA）批准了莫德纳（Moderna）和辉瑞（Pfizer）的两种新版疫苗，新版疫苗针对的是名为XBB.1.5的奥密克戎病毒变体，这一毒株在全世界大部分国家广泛传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接种疫苗依然是预防新冠病毒住院和死亡的最佳措施。疫苗还可以减少长期的新冠影响。根据CDC发布的建议，近两个月没有接种过新冠疫苗的人，都可以接种这一新版疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们拥有了更多的工具来预防新冠病毒带来的严重后果。”美国CDC主任、医学博士、公共卫生硕士曼迪•科恩（Mandy Cohen）表示。发布这一建议的原因在于，新冠病毒仍在不断变异，新的亚型接连出现，而疫苗的保护作用随着时间急剧下降，接种新版疫苗能更好地保护大众健康。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CDC的独立咨询委员会以13∶1高票同意建议普遍接种这一疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赞成者之一、美国埃默里大学医学院副教授桑德拉·弗莱霍夫(Sandra Fryhoffer) 博士认为，新冠重症可能发生在所有年龄段包括没有基础疾病的人身上，加上很多人此前没有接种加强针，意味着对新冠病毒的整体免疫力都在下降，因此应该推荐全部人接种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;普通人打还是不打&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;鼓励接种新冠疫苗已逾三年，但疫苗策略正在悄然发生改变，大部分国家没有像美国一样，推荐所有人接种加强针。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，英国政府宣布，新版加强针免费提供的对象是65岁以上的老年人及一线医务人员和脆弱群体。法国不建议非脆弱群体接种加强针。德国压根没有秋季加强针计划，尽管它之前建议高危人群应该每年接种一剂新冠疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员普遍认为，由于新冠疫苗的主要作用是预防重症而非感染，因此高危人群接种受益最大。而低风险人群和未成年人要不要再接种，科学界仍存在争议。 “对于老年人、有基础疾病和免疫缺陷的人群接种加强针非常有意义。”约翰斯·霍普金斯大学健康安全中心传染病专家艾米什·阿戴尔贾（Amesh Adalja）表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;新冠病毒蔓延三年多来，不少人对病毒的感染逐渐麻木，选择接种疫苗的人数也逐渐下降。但事实上，无论在美国或是中国，反复感染新冠的人不在少数。美国CDC科学家报告称，自7 月中旬以来，因新冠住院的人数一直在增加，虽然其中大多数为幼儿和老年人，但住院的五岁以下儿童中有一半没有潜在的健康问题，这提醒人们即使其他方面健康的人也可能有罹患新冠重症的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在即将到来的秋冬病毒流行季，流感病毒、呼吸道合胞病毒和新冠病毒很可能交叉感染，这会对脆弱人群造成比较严重的后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;在冬季来临前做准备&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在我国，整体疫情处于局部零星散发状态，但新冠病毒并未消失，病毒在人群中的传播现象仍持续存在，身边不乏有人几个月前才经历“二阳”，现在又遭遇“三阳”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基于新冠的传染性极强，得过新冠后抗体自然衰减及没有绝对的保护性新冠疫苗，基本上多数人每年会感染1-3次。”深圳市第三人民医院院长卢洪洲教授解释，“对于免疫功能正常的人群，不会造成特别大的影响。”但对于高龄、糖尿病、肿瘤基础病等免疫功能低下人群，卢洪洲建议每年定期接种新冠疫苗。接种疫苗的策略，可以包括鼻喷疫苗和皮下注射疫苗联合免疫、多价新冠组合疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月25日，国务院联防联控机制综合组印发的《近期重点人群新冠病毒疫苗接种工作方案》提出，对老年人等重点人群实施针对性新冠病毒疫苗接种。明确在新冠病毒XBB变异株流行期间，重点是今年秋冬季，优先推荐接种含XBB变异株抗原成分的疫苗。专家呼吁已感染且未完成基础免疫的人群，应该在感染3个月后接种1剂次疫苗，这将有利于在后续可能发生的疫情中为重症、死亡高风险人群提供更好的保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有专家预计，9月开学后新冠病毒感染人数会增加。按照免疫力周期推测，下一波新冠流行可能出现在今秋11月左右。而此时也正逢流感季，新冠叠加流感，可能导致呼吸道感染相关重症增加，因此建议同时接种流感疫苗和新冠疫苗，这也是世卫组织的推荐——两种疫苗叠加可以最大限度地预防重症和减轻病毒交叉感染带来的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“住院和死亡人数增加表明，冠状病毒病将会长期存在，世界仍然需要预防、检测和治疗新冠的工具。”世卫组织总干事谭德塞博士在2023年9月6日的媒体通报会上强调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天降烟头烫伤女婴，DNA比对锁定嫌疑人：胜于住户连坐多矣！丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256968]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;前段时间，郑州一名女婴在小区里被天降烟头烫伤。警方对楼上所有住户采血与烟头上的DNA比对，成功锁定扔烟头的嫌疑人。这是又一起通过高科技手段锁定高空抛物嫌疑人的案例，也再次提醒，高空抛物危害极大，警方介入破案概率大增，切莫心存侥幸以身试法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据澎湃新闻报道，8月底，黄女士带4个月大的婴儿在楼下散步，一个未灭的烟头从天而降，将孩子的肩膀和脖子烫伤。虽然小区监控摄像头只覆盖了一层地面，没有高空监控，无法通过视频发现是谁扔下了烟头，但警方通过对楼上所有住户采血验DNA的办法，成功找到了高空抛物的嫌疑人。此人不仅要承担民事侵权责任，还很可能要受到刑事处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林立的高楼为我们提供了更多生活、工作空间，已经成为现代化的象征，然而也带来了高空抛物、坠物的风险。携带高空势能转变而来的高速动能，即使是一枚几十克的鸡蛋，也可能带来严重伤害，更不用说其它危险物品。近年来因为高空抛物、坠物砸坏汽车、砸死砸伤人的新闻不断。 2016年，四川遂宁一只铁质健身球从天而降，砸死一名不满周岁的女婴；2020年，浙江绍兴又有一名14个月大的婴儿，被楼上扔下的砖块砸中头部造成脑死亡……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有熄灭的烟头，虽然不太可能砸伤人，但是引起火灾或烫伤人的危险也不小。除了郑州最近的这一例，2021年四川泸州一小区也发生过类似的案例，一个高空扔下的烟头烫穿婴儿车顶，差点烫到婴儿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，高空抛物坠物带来人员伤亡或财产损失，通常只以民事侵权来处理，要由受害人自行收集证据起诉，除非影响极大，警方一般不会介入调查。而个人收集证据的能力自然是很弱的，多数情况下找不到肇事者。那怎么办？之前的法律规定，这种情况下由所有“可能的加害者”给予补偿，也就是说，一旦发生了高空抛物伤人事件，找不到肇事者，楼上所有的住户（除了有证据证明自己不是肇事者的，比如楼房空置没住人等）就要“连坐”。这一规定虽然使受害者得到补偿，但对没有往楼下扔东西的人却很不公平，甚至可能纵容了作恶者，因为作恶的后果由很多人共同承担了。这一法律规定以及相关的法院判决案例，都引起了极大争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决问题的关键，是要找到肇事者并严惩。这一方面有赖于技术进步，比如高空视频监控、DNA比对等技术，都有助于锁定肇事者。另一方面则是法律规定的改变。如果还是让受害人自己去收集证据，基本上还是走不通的。因为个人没有权利收集他人的DNA并进行鉴定，没有法律规定，物业也没有动力去安装高空监控系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而2021年开始实施的民法典和刑法修正案（十一），改变了这一规则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;民事方面，虽然“连坐”规定仍然存在，但民法典要求警方应依法及时调查，查清责任人。只有在警方也无法查清的情况下，才适用“连坐”规定。由此，查清高空坠物责任人就成了警方的法定职责。而警方具有更大的权力，也有更大的能力来进行调查，比如可以根据事发地点的手机信号等缩小侦查范围，可以强制要求“可能的加害者”提供生物样本进行DNA比对。警方通过这些技术手段，基本上可以让肇事者无所遁形。尤其是DNA对比，具有极大的震慑力。四川泸州天降烟头差点烫伤婴儿事件中，警方对烟头上残留的DNA鉴定完成后，肇事者就主动投案了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，民法典还规定，物业公司等建筑物管理人应当采取必要的安全保障措施防止发生高空抛物坠物侵权事件；否则要承担未履行安全保障义务的侵权责任。如此，物业才有动力做好防范、监控等工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在刑事责任方面，最高法2019年发布的司法解释就规定，对故意高空抛物、过失高空坠物等都可以按“以危险方法危害公共安全罪”“过失致人伤亡罪”“重大责任事故罪”等罪名定罪处罚。 2021年3月1日起生效的刑法修正案（十一）更增设了“高空抛物罪”。尽管这一罪名的处罚比“危害公共安全罪”的处罚要轻，但无论轻重，对犯罪行为警方都要立案调查。这也意味着，新刑法规定下，高空抛物入刑的门槛降低了，警方有更大的法定责任对此进行刑事调查。这样一来，肇事者被发现的概率就会大大增加，被处罚的可能性和处罚力度也大大增加，对高空抛物的震慑也就大大增加了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;用技术让法律长出牙齿，形成足够的威慑力。高空抛物必被捉，必被严惩，高空抛物者无处遁形，敢于以身试法者减少，我们头顶的天空才会更安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[坚守大山十年，月薪不到三千：支教老师“中年危机”何解]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国铁集团：不可能给第三方平台“优先购票权”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 18:31:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今日，铁路部门开始发售10月3日火车票，各个方向余票充足。 9月28日至10月2日，仍有余票。 9月27日及其以前预售期内的车票，各个方向余票充足。根据客流需求，铁路部门将于假期增开的100余列旅客列车的车票9月18日已经开售，每日可增加客座能力7万余席。 9月13日至18日，铁路部门共发售火车票1.11亿张。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据旅客出行需求，铁路部门已安排增开国庆假期100余列旅客列车，这些列车将于9月28日开行，车票已于9月18日开售。增开列车的主要方向是：南昌至广州、武汉至广州、长沙至南昌、南昌至上海、厦门至上海、深圳至长沙等。根据火车票预售、候补购票数据和铁路运输能力情况，铁路部门还将适时增开热门方向、热点时段旅客列车。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;假期旅客出行高度集中，部分热门方向、热点时段列车车票紧俏，旅客朋友可以选择候补购票、中转换乘等方式购票，也可以根据不同时段、不同方向余票情况，选择错峰出行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来动车组列车票价实施了差异化的浮动定价机制，主要依据市场供求关系和客流规律，以公布票价为最高限价，分时段、席别、区段实行多档次、有高有低的票价浮动策略。今年国庆假期高铁仍然实行差异化票价，比如北京至上海间动车组列车票价，二等座最高667元，最低404元，旅客朋友可以根据需求自行选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;铁路12306从未授权任何第三方平台发售火车票，也不可能给第三方平台所谓的“优先购票权”。第三方平台在旅客朋友购票过程中会保留用户信息，不仅有附加费、加速包、捆绑销售服务等陷阱，还可能存在个人信息泄露风险。请旅客朋友一定要通过铁路官方渠道购票，认准铁路12306网站（含客户端），注意保护合法权益和个人信息安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[治理矿山安全：实时监测八十余万名入井作业人员]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256970]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/SOkEroGpwkCPUDcHjKEN2TlsHU9Tjaruh9apHTj2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/SOkEroGpwkCPUDcHjKEN2TlsHU9Tjaruh9apHTj2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251165&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月18日上午，国务院新闻办公室举行《关于进一步加强矿山安全生产工作的意见》 新闻发布会。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（杜寒三/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;地方监管监察部门和国家监察机关，已经联网接入了所有正常生产建设煤矿的安全监控、人员定位、视频监控等感知数据，可实时监测全国60余万个传感器、80余万名入井作业人员、3.9万户作业视频监控数据，开发多种风险分析预警功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月18日上午，国务院新闻办公室举行《关于进一步加强矿山安全生产工作的意见》（以下简称“《意见》”）新闻发布会，国家矿山安全监察局副局长张昕表示，意见“着力从根本上消除事故隐患、从根本上解决问题”，进一步推动矿山安全治理模式向事前预防转型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《意见》是新中国成立以来第一个经党中央、国务院同意印发的矿山安全生产领域纲领性文件，围绕“事前预防转型”提出了一系列措施，在国家层面首次明确要求涉矿中央企业总部和涉矿大中型企业配备安全总监，并要求规范非煤矿山外包工程管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《意见》要求规范非煤矿山外包工程管理，承包单位向项目部派出项目负责人、技术人员和特种作业人员，并提出力争到2025年年底，生产矿山建立本单位采掘（剥）施工队伍或者委托具备相应条件的企业整体管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家矿山安全监察局安全基础司司长孙庆国介绍，2021年印发《关于加强金属非金属地下矿山外包工程安全管理的若干规定》后，全国共组织1360个检查组，派出了6800余人，历时7个月，检查外包工程矿山、资源整合煤矿和托管煤矿3895座，发现重大隐患134条，其间清退、转隶外包队伍461个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙庆国指出，通过专项整治，非煤矿山外包工程管理进一步规范，管理水平有了大幅度提升，“但依然存在人员队伍管理不统一，违规承包、分包，安全责任悬空，安全投入不足等问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《意见》对非煤矿山外包工程管理作出进一步的要求，明确了非煤矿山安全责任，对金属非金属地下矿山承包单位数量、承包单位人员配备和学历、爆破作业，以及建立自有采掘队伍都提出了明确要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“灾害不治、矿无宁日，重大灾害治理始终是推进事前预防的重中之重。”张昕表示，下一步将常态化制度化开展矿山隐蔽致灾因素普查治理，实现由被动防范向主动治理转变、由单一治理向综合治理转变、由井下局部治理向地面区域治理转变，“对未查清、未探明、未治理到位的，不得进行采掘作业，坚决不与灾害&#39;拼刺刀&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;非煤矿山安全监察司司长李峰介绍，今后不仅对重大隐患排查整改不到位，发生事故的企业和责任人追究责任，对排查整改不到位导致重大隐患依然存在的企业，也要追究责任，“体现了矿山安全治理模式向事前预防转型的理念”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小城千人围捕鳄鱼：已追回69条，仍有两条或在逃]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256981]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 17:31:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/598242ea15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/598242ea15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;鳄鱼抓捕现场。南方周末记者赵明摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月15日晚，鳄鱼场里的水基本抽干了，塘底淤泥翻涌出阵阵腥臭味。一辆皮卡车从夜色里驶来，停在附近路中央，车厢里是一条刚抓到的鳄鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;43岁的捕鳄人邱桂拽着鳄鱼尾巴，和队员一起将它拖下了皮卡车。他们要把这条鳄鱼转移到厢式货车里，那里已趴着三条被捆绑结实的鳄鱼。鳄鱼被拖至货车尾，四肢被束在身侧，长长的大嘴被胶带捆扎得不能开合。邱桂和另外三名戴着头灯的队员分站鳄鱼两旁，端着它的四肢，一齐向上发力：“一、二！”站在车厢里的人拽着鳄鱼头部的麻绳，也一齐向上发力，鳄鱼顺利入“仓”。在解开麻绳时，车厢里一条鳄鱼似乎怒意十足，向一旁的人用力甩出嘴巴被捆紧的大头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受台风“海葵”影响，广东省茂名市连日暴雨，9月11日，洪水冲垮北界罗村一鳄鱼养殖场围栏，造成部分鳄鱼出逃。据南方+消息，该养殖场内共饲有71条鳄鱼，截至9月16日，共抓捕鳄鱼69条，暂未出现鳄鱼伤人事件。目前，多个搜寻小队仍在日夜追捕最后两条外逃的鳄鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3846f4d486.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3846f4d486.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;鳄鱼出逃的养殖场。南方周末记者赵明摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;51个哨点，33支巡逻队&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;出逃的鳄鱼绝大多数是成年公鳄，品种为暹罗鳄。这是一种常见于海南、广东等地养殖场的鳄种，据相关文献记载，中国无野生暹罗鳄，仅有饲养种群，可持证交易经营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发鳄鱼场所属公司为广东渔丰鳄鱼养殖专业合作社，成立于2019年3月，法定代表人为许金旺。因养殖鳄鱼数量多达上万条，且有二十余年养殖经验，茂名人许金旺素有“鳄鱼王”之称。许金旺妻子柯艺明告诉南方周末记者，鳄鱼出逃后，他们的压力很大，损失同样很大，有两三百万元，“鳄鱼很值钱的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据81岁的北界罗村村民吴利明透露，许金旺用来养殖鳄鱼的鱼塘是四五年前他租给对方的，共计三十多亩，每年租金为2000元/亩，租了18年。吴利明告诉南方周末记者，鳄鱼出逃后，洪水水位仍未退下那段时间，他因害怕就天天打电话给许金旺：“让他处理好，（鳄鱼）很危险的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;柯艺明解释，养殖场被冲是天灾，“我们（养殖场）做得都很安全。那里水灾那么厉害，以后不敢在那里养了。”9月15日，南方周末记者在现场看到，各个鳄鱼池之间使用高约1.3米的塑料挡板隔开，对于使用塑料挡板能否有效保证鳄鱼不出逃，从业二十余年的专业捕鳄人邱桂向南方周末记者解释：“这种挡板是OK的，鳄鱼只要看不到外面，就会一直待在鳄鱼池里。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鳄鱼出逃的消息传来，吓坏了75岁的村民吴炎信：“害怕，怎么不害怕？”吴炎信住在镇盛镇大坡村，距鳄鱼场直线距离约400米。虽然害怕，吴炎信有安抚自己的办法：只要不下水，也不要到岸边就行，“鳄鱼在地面上走得没有那么快”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在鳄鱼出逃之前，吴炎信经常沿着彭村湖环湖路骑车、跑步，一圈8公里得跑70分钟。这是鳄鱼池周边的最大水域，站在环湖路上，吴炎信就能望见生活在池里的鳄鱼。鳄鱼出逃后，吴炎信不能再环湖骑车，路上被高约1.5米的铁丝防护网围了一圈，以防鳄鱼伤人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/333bc75667.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/333bc75667.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;环湖路用铁丝网围了起来。南方周末记者陈佳慧摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;安装防护网的工人是90后周辉和他的同事。9月17日，周辉告诉南方周末记者，鳄鱼出逃后，他们就开始沿着环湖路安装防护网，大概装了三四天才全部围完，后又花了几天时间加固。有天凌晨一点左右，他和同事在鳄鱼池那段路上安装防护网，在约20米远的地方，一条鳄鱼浮出水面张开大嘴，后又沉入水里；另一条三四百斤的鳄鱼趴在50米外的岸边，周辉拿灯一照，发现两只冒着黄光的眼睛正在盯着他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鳄鱼场居民小组监督责任人吴亚宏对南方周末记者说，鳄鱼出逃后，村委积极参与抓捕鳄鱼，安排值班，让村民不要出去，要注意安全。吴亚宏称，以前下暴雨时，他都会提醒鳄鱼场里的工作人员注意安全：“水差不多泡到你们鳄鱼塘了，鳄鱼跑出来不得了。但这次水太大了，泡过了（鳄鱼池），鳄鱼就跑出来了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相邻的大坡村村委会一位工作人员告诉南方周末记者，鳄鱼逃出来后，为确保不出现人员伤亡，“我们发动了党员、志愿者共计三十多人，24小时守着各个卡口”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为尽快抓捕鳄鱼，同时保障附近居民安全，事发地周边5公里范围内，均为重点排查区域。当地共设置了51个哨点，33支巡逻队伍，近千名工作人员在现场开展搜捕工作。9月15日，一位现场值守的民兵告诉南方周末记者，鳄鱼刚跑那天，水位还很高，养殖场里全是人，大家都忙着抽水、拿沙包堵水，“不怕鳄鱼出现，那么多人，怕什么，特警全部拿着枪”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/fb508a3153.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;626&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/fb508a3153.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;为了寻找鳄鱼，养殖场进行抽水排查。南方周末记者赵明摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;抓了56条鳄鱼的团队&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据茂南区农业农村局确认，鳄鱼场内71条鳄鱼中，有40条是在养殖场内捕获，其余31条或逃至养殖场周边5公里水域内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在鳄鱼逃出后的三四天里，吴炎信每天都能听到枪声，“砰砰砰”连响十来声。离他最近的一次枪响是在9月14日晚，那条两三百斤鳄鱼在他家水田附近的排水小沟里被发现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;枪击水中的鳄鱼，难度并不低。“你打一枪，它就钻水里了，不像打地上那些，打了就停在原地。”一位持狙击枪的特警说，一旁的同事给他出主意，“得有人补枪”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/187650e8d2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/187650e8d2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特警在寻找出逃的鳄鱼。南方周末记者赵明摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与枪击水中鳄鱼相比，邱桂认为，找到鳄鱼是最重要，也是最花时间的环节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了寻找出逃的鳄鱼，当地采用了声呐探测、无人机巡查，甚至将鸭子绑在岸边引诱鳄鱼捕食等手段。声呐队一位工作人员向南方周末记者介绍，声呐探测鳄鱼的难点在于，当鳄鱼游动时，很难探测到它们。而无人机发出的声音通常会吓到胆小的鳄鱼。鸭子诱捕效果更弱，鳄鱼出逃范围内水域面积广，鱼虾众多，鳄鱼根本不缺食物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和鳄鱼打了二十多年交道，邱桂有自己的方法。此次抓捕行动中，包括在养殖场，他们团队6人共抓捕了56条，其中，9月14日最多，共抓获14条。其余13条是由特警击毙，以及来自湛江、阳江、广州、佛山的捕鳄团队抓捕。被抓的鳄鱼多为两百多斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邱桂一行通常夜间出动，因白天鳄鱼警惕性较高，察觉周围有动静后会迅速躲进水里。而到了晚上，鳄鱼常会待在一个地方不动，比较迟钝，只要慢慢移动过去就能抓到它们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与人类不同，鳄鱼的眼睛从出生至死亡都不闭上。因此，只要在晚上用手电筒一照，泛着黄光的眼睛就会暴露鳄鱼的位置。9月18日凌晨2时，在搜捕最后两条鳄鱼时，邱桂再次登上了皮划艇，在彭村湖搜寻鳄鱼的踪迹。前一晚，他们在此发现并抓捕了三条鳄鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邱桂把手电筒对准岸边的水域和草地。他解释，鳄鱼喜欢在早上九、十点钟太阳变暖时上岸，晒太阳会让它更容易消化胃里的食物。一条200斤的鳄鱼一天可进食10斤，吃饱后就会上岸，如果没有惊吓，它会一直待到消化完再下水捕食。“找鳄鱼没有那么多学问，也没有捷径可走，就是拿灯去照。”邱桂说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夜晚的鳄鱼容易找，更容易抓。邱桂一行在发现鳄鱼后，会小心移船靠近，在鳄鱼一米的范围内，电晕鳄鱼，“电晕后的鳄鱼全身好像僵硬了一样。”趁着鳄鱼昏迷的10-15分钟，捕鳄人将鳄鱼拖上船，要在第一时间绑嘴、绑四肢。“只要绑住它的嘴，不让它张开，这只鳄鱼就100%被拿捏了。”邱桂说，最重要的是团队合作，没有默契是干不了的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被捆绑后的鳄鱼同样危险。鳄鱼苏醒后，它的头和尾仍能发出攻击，如果打到腿，“直接骨折，不是开玩笑的”。邱桂介绍，鳄鱼有个攻击范围，“我们一般是站在它中间位置，相当于在它的击打盲区。但也要离它1.5米的距离，会比较安全一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/eabb6219cc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/eabb6219cc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在一处围栏旁，一条鳄鱼被抓获。南方周末记者赵明摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;扩大水域寻找最后两条&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;抓捕鳄鱼并非一帆风顺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至9月15日，当时共抓捕了58条鳄鱼，剩余13条外逃，当天搜寻重点之一是几口鱼塘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鱼塘位于禾里镜村，距鳄鱼场直线距离仅有两三百米。9月15日，一口鱼塘的塘主告诉南方周末记者，已经在他的鱼塘里拉上来两条鳄鱼了，一条是电击的，一条是枪打的，鱼塘里面可能还有鳄鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因鱼塘有三四米深，且鱼较多，因此电击、鸭子诱捕甚至枪击的方法均不奏效。茂名市应急管理局一位工作人员对南方周末记者说：“水太深了，发现不了鳄鱼。要是能放到一米左右深的水最好了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初，村委会与鱼塘主协商放水后的补偿方案并不顺利。上述塘主的妻子蔡芳告诉南方周末记者，她家的鱼塘里投放了几万条鱼苗，还投放了一些鱼料。“一共几万块钱的成本，现在提出抽一半的水，补偿2000块钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蔡芳不同意补偿方案，她认为如果放掉一半的水，剩下的鱼会因为缺氧死去，而且担心鳄鱼躲在塘底的淤泥里没被搜寻到，“万一后来咬到人，我塘主来负责？”蔡芳更希望得到彻底的搜寻，可将塘水抽干，确保塘内没有鳄鱼，同时塘内的鱼也随便处理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过几轮交涉，9月15日晚，双方达成补偿协议，以每亩水面1000元的价格进行补偿。次日一早，挖掘机扒开了塘坎边，经过搜寻，未在这处鱼塘里发现鳄鱼的踪迹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至9月16日，共计抓回69条鳄鱼，仍有两条暂无线索。又经过两天的搜寻，这一数据仍未变动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/9f921aceea.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/9f921aceea.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;抓捕队夜间在湖上搜寻。南方周末记者赵明摄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月18日凌晨，邱桂一行又回到了鳄鱼场，他们怀疑那两条鳄鱼可能在养殖过程中已经死去。“鳄鱼在交配期是最凶猛的，它们会为了争交配权而打架，如果打得太厉害，有的鳄鱼会死的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月19日凌晨，鳄鱼搜寻的范围开始扩大，捕鳄人团队沿着彭村湖下游，距鳄鱼场一公里外的水域进行搜寻，整夜搜寻仍是无果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“最后两条没找到，不会收工的。”上述茂名市应急管理局工作人员称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，周辉、蔡芳为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>