<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[信用卡质效榜：股份行霸榜前四 城商行高度分化]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261776]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 17:34:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Heming, researcher at Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three years later, the domestic credit card market will open up to the outside world again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, the international credit card organization giant MasterCard’s holding company in China, MasterCard, obtained a bank card clearing business license and stated that Within 6 months, it will expand its member institutions in China and authorize the issuance and acceptance of MasterCard brand bank cards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a time when China’s credit card market is shifting from a race-and-spur rush to intensive farming. At the same time, China&#39;s credit card market as a whole faces the challenges of rising non-performing loan ratios and shrinking new card issuance volumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the second largest personal credit market after housing mortgage loans, how do commercial banks respond to the new situation of credit cards, a high-quality asset? Which card issuing bank has better risk management system and risk control effect? Which card issuer is more effective at retaining customers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center hereby conducts a multi-dimensional evaluation of the credit card business of 20 systemically important banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Five dimensions, 12 sub-indicators&lt;/h3>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center based on the public disclosure information related to credit card business of 20 banks in 2023. Based on this, the 2023 Credit Card Performance Ranking Index Evaluation System has been constructed. Consistent with the wealth management list, green finance list, digital finance list, data security list and life insurance efficiency list, the credit card quality and efficiency list indicator system designed by Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center is mainly based on quantitative and qualitative indicators, supplemented by external expert review and media factor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the quantitative and qualitative indicators include three major dimensions: business scale and growth, risk management, customer service and product innovation, with 12 sub-indicators, each sub-indicator. Indicators are given differential weights based on their importance. The total weight of quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. Among quantitative and qualitative indicators, business scale accounts for as much as 35%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center also invited 7 external authoritative experts to conduct an independent real-name review and scoring based on the overall understanding of each bank&#39;s credit card business, with a weight of 15%. At the same time, in order to encourage commercial banks to improve the transparency of information disclosure in the credit card field, the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center formed a media factor based on the feedback of 20 banks&#39; credit card business on a special survey, with a weight of 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73942&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70734&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/dc5c17a121.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Indicator system.png&quot; alt=&quot;Credit card quality and efficiency ranking indicator system&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1799&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/dc5c17a121.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260532&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Credit card quality and efficiency ranking indicator system (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p >; &lt;h3>;Pay equal attention to scale, risk control and innovation&lt;/h3>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The various dimensions of the credit card quality and efficiency list and the set quantitative and qualitative indicators below are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(1) Business scale is an important reflection of the credit card strength of major banks. There are six sub-indicators under this dimension, namely the number of credit card issuances and their changes, credit card loan balances and their proportions, the number of credit card users, and the amount of credit card transactions. The total weight of the six sub-indicators is 35%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(2) Risk management is a necessary dimension to examine the comprehensive strength of each bank&#39;s credit card. There are three sub-indicators under this dimension, namely credit card non-performing loan balance, non-performing loan ratio and their changes. The total weight of the three sub-indicators is 18%. Among them, in order to highlight the efforts and effects of banks in controlling the non-performing loan ratio, based on the credit card loan non-performing ratio indicator, a change rate indicator of the credit card loan non-performing ratio is set to directly reflect the results of the measures taken by each bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(3) Customer service and product innovation are inevitable choices for major banks to cope with the increasingly fierce competition in the credit card market. There are three sub-indicators under this dimension, namely bank card fee income, credit card complaints volume and their changes. The total weight of the three sub-indicators is 17%. Among them, the number of complaints about the credit card business and its changes can prove the customer&#39;s recognition of the bank&#39;s credit card business and is a negative indicator; bank card fee income directly reflects the use of the bank&#39;s credit cards in real transactions, thereby reflecting the bank&#39;s Credit card product innovation and customer service levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Joint stock banks dominate the top three&lt;/h3>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Comprehensive analysis of the quantitative and qualitative indicators, expert reviews and media factor scores of 20 banks, Southern Weekend New Financial Research The center has constructed the 2023 credit card quality and efficiency list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73941&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70733&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/fa546ff341.png&quot; img-title=&quot;List.png&quot; alt=&quot;Credit card quality list&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2237&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/fa546ff341.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260533&quot; style= &quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Credit card quality and efficiency list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The credit card quality and efficiency list shows that China Merchants Bank, China CITIC Bank and Guangfa Bank took the top three overall scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China Merchants Bank ranks first in quantitative and qualitative indicators, expert review scores and media factors, and is the only company to receive &quot;double perfect scores&quot; from expert reviews and media factors. Bank of. The bank won the championship with a large lead of 12 points, which reflects the competitiveness of the bank&#39;s credit cards in all aspects such as business, finance and reputation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;CITIC Bank narrowly defeated China Guangfa Bank with a slight advantage of 0.24 points. The two joint-stock banks ranked second and third in the credit card quality and efficiency list respectively. Together with Ping An Bank, which ranks fourth, in the 2023 new financial competitiveness sub-list released this time, the credit card quality and efficiency list is also the only sub-list in which a joint-stock bank has achieved the top four rankings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although external review scores and media factors have partially weakened the influence of scale indicators on the list, only from the perspective of quantitative and qualitative indicator performance, China Merchants Bank, CITIC and GF The score is still in the top three. Among them, Guangfa Bank&#39;s credit card loan balance accounts for as high as 48% of the bank&#39;s personal loan balance, far exceeding its peers. This proves that the credit card business has a huge influence on the bank beyond its peers. At the same time, despite the overall contraction in credit card issuance, China CITIC Bank and China Guangfa Bank still maintained positive growth in card issuance, which also shows the considerable strength of the two joint-stock banks in the credit card business. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The five major banks ranked among the top ten&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although they were not among the top three, the five major banks of the China Construction Bank of China, Workers and Peasants, all ranked among the top ten, still showing that overseas There are major banks with overall strength in the credit card business. The credit card business of major state-owned banks started early and has a huge customer base. It has always been significantly ahead in the scale of credit card business. However, in recent years, with the fluctuation of credit card asset quality and the stricter supervision after the implementation of new credit card regulations, a large number of invalid and inefficient credit cards issued in the early stage have withdrawn from the market. In the midst of this ebb and flow, the scale advantages of large banks in various countries are gradually being eliminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The credit card business is not as important to large state-owned banks as it is to joint-stock banks. Looking at the proportion of credit card loans in personal loans, the average proportion of credit card loan balances in the five major banks is 9%, while this indicator for the nine joint-stock banks is as high as 27%. In this sense, despite being at an overall disadvantage in entry time, asset size and customer base, joint-stock banks can occupy half of the credit card market, and their comprehensive competitiveness beyond their opponents is obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, the ranking of the five major banks in the credit card quality and efficiency list is appropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The leading city commercial banks are catching up&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The credit card scores of the five city commercial banks are highly differentiated. Among them, Bank of Ningbo’s comprehensive score is second only to ICBC, ranking 6th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first half of 2023, the bank&#39;s credit card issuance volume increased by as much as 40% year-on-year, ranking first among 20 banks; at the same time, the bank&#39;s credit card issuance volume increased by 40% year-on-year. The bank&#39;s credit card non-performing rate is only 1.19%, the best among peers; while maintaining an ultra-low credit card non-performing rate, the bank&#39;s credit card non-performing rate is still on a downward trajectory, which is even more difficult. This reflects that leading city commercial banks are working hard to catch up in the credit card business and have made great progress in some indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared to Bank of Ningbo, the other four city commercial banks all rank at the bottom, showing that they still have a clear gap with large and medium-sized banks in terms of comprehensive credit card strength. Affected by factors such as their short time in the credit card market, small business scale, and weak customer base, the four city commercial banks overall lagged behind in indicators such as credit card issuance volume and credit card loan balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鸟兽、巫气与万物：一位北方作家来到大陆最南端]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261772]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/DA1pphxCP4G16cI6bvENaZqH1ZaKtpT80Myy4jIm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/DA1pphxCP4G16cI6bvENaZqH1ZaKt pT80Myy4jIm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Half is ocean, half is land&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Leizhou Peninsula, at the southernmost tip of mainland China, faces Hainan Island across the sea. The writer Sun Pin came here and stayed for two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we arrived on the island, Sun Pin kept walking and looking, identifying every plant and animal one by one. She talked with local people of different ages and learned some Leizhou dialect. &quot;Eating&quot; means &quot;exemption&quot; and &quot;problem&quot; means &quot;taking responsibility&quot;. She tried her best as a northerner to feel the temperament and character of this land and water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leizhou Peninsula is filled with &quot;witchcraft&quot; temperament. Tianhou Temple and Mazu Temple can be found everywhere, and there are various other gods in each village. &quot;Faced with such a huge thing as the ocean, human beings cannot help but be in awe and ask for its blessings.&quot; The worship of the ocean and the many gods it derives permeates many details of the daily life of people living near the sea. &quot;The folk customs here The folklore is very peculiar, and I was very curious about it, so I had this idea at that time and wanted to write about this land-sea junction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the novel collection &quot;The Magician of the Sea&quot; published in 2023, Sun Pin fictionalized a seaside village located at the southernmost tip of Leizhou Peninsula: Papaya Town. The first novel in the collection, &quot;The Magician by the Sea,&quot; tells the story of a northerner who comes here to look for her brother who has disappeared for many years. For Sun Pin, searching is a very fascinating process. &quot;You keep moving forward on a road. You don&#39;t know what kind of people and what kind of stories you will encounter ahead.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, this northerner met the old lady who asked her not to scare Jackfruit, &quot;Jackfruit is very attached to people and likes to be touched and praised most&quot;; she met Sister Mei who lived with many plants and animals, and saw her Taking the leaf cake to the grave in the woods, she believed that the ghosts of her family were living in the black cat; she also met a person who looked like a carp spirit. In order to make her believe her words, the carp spirit faced her before speaking. The Mazu statue enshrined in the house burns incense and worships the gods, &quot;If I tell you in front of Mazu, there will be no lies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In this small town, many boundaries are blurred. People, plants and animals, living people and dead people, and the ground and the underground can all travel back and forth with each other. All things have animism and live together in a big family...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &quot;This place still has a barbaric temperament. On one side, it frequently draws out its swords to attack people, causing blood to splatter five feet away. On the other side, it believes in animism. Each village has its own gods, and each god&#39;s birthday is different. Similarly, the birthday of the gods is a grand festival for the whole village, collectively called the calendar. Thunder operas must be sung to the gods on the stage, fine wine must be offered to the gods, fresh boiled chicken must be prepared, and firecrackers must be set off all day long. , there is a lion dance, and there is an extremely grand ceremony for the wandering god, while the god just sits in his temple and quietly watches people wishing him a birthday.&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The Magician on the Beach&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nature is the cause and life is the effect. Being with the sea all day long gives the folk life in Leizhou Peninsula an atmosphere of fantasy and mystery, and hidden behind this is the huge powerlessness and loneliness of human beings when facing the ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Sun Pin saw the sea for the first time, his reaction was no different from that of many inland people, &quot;It&#39;s so big that you don&#39;t know what is hidden inside.&quot; Regarding living on land For people on earth, land means a stable life, walking and living on land, building ancestral halls and ancestral temples, and reproducing from generation to generation. And what is life at sea really like? Facing the huge, mysterious and unknown sea, how should people settle their &quot;rootless&quot; sea life that is destined to wander? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the ferry back and forth from Xuwen Port to Haikou, Sun Pin took a total of more than ten boats and tried to chat with the crew. Crew members are often very silent, especially ocean-going crew members. One or two years of sailing at sea often cause them to lose contact with their friends on land, and people on land gradually forget their existence. &quot;This kind of life on board is separated from the land. They are a world of their own, a world on board.&quot; When talking to Sun Pin, a captain called himself a &quot;seaman&quot;. She noticed the particularity of this term. &quot;Not a crew member or a sailor, but a seaman.&quot; &quot;This distinction is no longer a professional one, but a separation based on the fundamental standpoint of human beings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This loneliness will eventually Leading to what? Sun Pin discovered that after catching expensive fish, some fishermen would take the money from selling the fish and go to the city center, find a hotel room, eat some delicious food, spend the money and then go back to fishing. She heard that many ocean-going sailors were like this. When the ocean-going ship docked for supplies, they would disembark and desperately buy things. Sun Pin tried to explain the origin of this compensation mentality, &quot;For example, fishermen may die when they go out to sea in a small boat. Under this kind of impermanent fear, once you have a chance to get rid of or relax, you will desperately want to compensate yourself. .&quot; &quot;Or it may be a very simple idea, spend the money as soon as possible, in case I die tomorrow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sea is silent, and the people in the sea are silent. The ship is like a natural prison. &quot;Because of the narrow space and its separation from the land, it is likely to become a prison, and the crew will become prisoners, enduring torture-like loneliness.&quot; &quot;But, can we change it?&quot; How can we understand it from another perspective? This closed and isolated space can actually be turned into a Thoreau-style cabin, a unique space suitable for philosophical speculation?&quot; In the second chapter of the novel collection &quot;Seagull Knight&quot;, Sun Pin fictionalized a The captain wears a suit, combs his hair every day, burns incense, drinks tea, and plays the piano. &quot;He still behaves elegantly in a place where no one is around, just like a ghost duke dormant in an old castle... He is sometimes very easy-going, sometimes very...&quot; He is gloomy and occasionally fierce. When he is in a good mood, he will talk about literature and art elegantly. There is something between noble and gloomy in him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She wanted to ask, when a person is in a In such a closed and lonely environment, how can we find a broader and richer spiritual space for ourselves? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ITb5ucIQFPiL5aDf64GMrGUJvfQR2x1szlqjhh0m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;820&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ITb5ucIQFPiL5aDf64GMrGUJvfQR2x1szlqjhh0m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259996&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In The Crack of Civilization&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Two years ago, Sun Pin&#39;s collection of novels &quot;In the Name of Birds and Beasts&quot; was published. Fan Xiaozhe, editor of People&#39;s Literature Publishing House, edited Sun Pin&#39;s book for the first time. &quot;Whether she writes about the grand and lush plants in the south, the rich aquatic products in the ocean, or the uninhabited dense forests in the north, these things are just the material of Sun Pin&#39;s novels,&quot; Fan Xiaozhe said, &quot;and in the end all novels point to modern times. Civilization (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Modernization, urbanization&lt;/span>;) has an inner impact on people, and at the same time, they are looking back or questioning.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In &quot;In the Name of Birds and Beasts&quot;, Sun Pin turns his attention to the mountain people in his hometown of Luliang Mountain. There, modern urban civilization is constantly entering this &quot;barbaric&quot; land. Sun Pin created a mountain man named You Xiaolong. He walked out of the mountains and had a decent civil servant job in the town. But this profession did not provide him with a sense of identity. “His roots are still in the mountains.” In Sun Pin’s view, what You Xiaolong represents is the suffering suffered by some people in the process of urbanization. “They My soul has nowhere to rest, I can’t go back to my hometown, and the city doesn’t belong to me.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Don’t you think this is the epitome of a large part of the people in China?” Sun Pin’s voice came from the other end of the phone. came, &quot;Of course, urbanization is a necessary stage in the development of human society. But in fact, every step of development of the times requires the blood and tears of hundreds of millions of people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The focus on urbanization also continues Go to the third novel in the new collection of novels, &quot;Sunset Coral&quot;. In the novel, Sun Pin meticulously recorded the urbanization process of Papaya Town: in the 1980s, 100,000 talents came to Hainan, and all the people in Papaya Town became small traders; in the 1990s, the Wenzhou real estate speculators allowed smuggled cars to invade and devour the entire town. And when the tourism and vacation trend started in Hainan Island, Papaya Town rushed to operate a coral B&amp;B... Between the city and the countryside, Sun Pin once again chose the gap between civilizations as the perspective of her thinking. The protagonist &quot;I&quot; in the novel once walked from Papaya Town to the city. &quot;I originally went to pursue modern civilization, but I could never really enter the city.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From north to south, from the mountains and forests to the sea, in the literary geography Under the changes of migration, Sun Pin always paid attention to the spiritual state that is not limited by geography, that has a certain universal &quot;solitude&quot; - the personal spirit that is difficult to place in the gap between modern civilization and the turmoil of the times. Therefore, what Fan Xiaozhe said about &quot;looking back&quot; not only constitutes the writer&#39;s fundamental questioning of modern civilization, but also Sun Pin&#39;s inner connection with his own life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Sun Pin, the &quot;post-80s&quot; generation, she feels that every change in the times has an impact on her and her generation. She witnessed workers being laid off during her childhood. As a teenager, she became a &quot;hard-working problem solver in a small town.&quot; &quot;By the time I graduated, the sense of superiority that still existed among college students in the 1990s had disappeared, and college students had turned into grains of dust.&quot; When she was in college, she would still think, &quot;We have entered the 21st century, how can we still be there?&quot; What is the difference between formal and non-establishment work?&quot; After working for a short time, her thoughts changed. The cruel reality of society seemed to have taught her what life is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everything I have experienced and every change in society has definitely had an impact on me. And in the process, I am constantly thinking about the impact of each wave of the times. &quot;Individual coercion,&quot; when these thoughts slowly accumulate, &quot;you just want to express it.&quot; Sun Pin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from university, Sun Pin successively published novel collections &quot;Pain&quot;, &quot;Salt&quot; and &quot;Crack&quot;. Many readers and critics noticed the pain of soul and spirit in his works. &quot;Because you can only write about the pain if you really feel it, so I put high-concentration emotions into my early novels,&quot; Sun Pin said. As the title of the novel suggests, these creations reveal a young man&#39;s confrontation with society and the world, as well as his irreconcilable mental state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at her creations when she was in her twenties, Sun Pin felt that they were very normal and in line with a young person’s state of mind at that time and her understanding of the world. “When I didn’t understand society well enough, I walked into it. &quot;Without society&quot;, what follows is the weakness and helplessness of individuals, as well as the rupture and impact when they suddenly fall from the ivory tower built by literature and education into reality and face life head-on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s just that I can’t still burn my emotions as hard as I did when I was 20 years old at 40 years old. My novels when I was 20 years old focused on the deep and struggling hearts of young women. As I grow older, I will try to understand more people and pay attention to the wider world, which is interesting. Writers burn themselves throughout their lives, but later on, what I burn is no longer just emotions, It’s about a better understanding of this vast world.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While editing “In the Name of Birds and Beasts”, Fan Xiaozhe felt that Sun Pin “began to become more open-minded.” She believes, “In “Pain”, “Salt” and “Crack”, she paid more attention to individual pain, but starting from “In the Name of Birds and Beasts”, she combined some natural things, plants, mountains and rivers, including their backs The history of the world was brought out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anthropological writing inspired her. In anthropology, Sun Pin saw a deeper and more contextual care for human beings. She wrote &quot;In the Name of Birds and Beasts&quot;, using anthropological methods to deal with the changes in the mountains, the history of vegetation and mountains, and deeply describing the evolution of the lives of mountain people between the city and the mountains and forests. This persistent gaze on human beings and the world in which they live is full of patience and &quot;the greatest respect for different people.&quot; And when she looked at these mountain people, fishermen and sea people with the same patience, these &quot;wild&quot; people in the eyes of urban civilization, she truly realized the unique vitality among them. In &quot;The Rider of the White Horse&quot; she wrote about all kinds of strange mountain people, the bachelor brothers who raised their adopted daughter together, the short man who ran a peasant university in the mountains... &quot;You see, their living conditions are actually very difficult. You can also use the word barbaric to describe them,&quot; Sun Pin said, &quot;but their language and their thoughts are full of vitality. That kind of vitality does not belong to cities and civilization, but it is equally sincere and moving.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/M1E2gOKlClUjsXDouWgXuwEBVlGv9k0TDRGcW43M.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;321&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/M1E2gOKlUjsXDouWgXuwEBVlGv9k0TDRGcW43M.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Pin collects scenery at the seaside of Xuwen&#39;s Bocheng Port&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Orientation A Wider World&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the &quot;Seaside Magician&quot; new book sharing event, writer Li Jingze said: &quot;Although Sun Pin&#39;s creation has changed a lot, I feel that her direction has not changed. There has always been an intention to establish a connection between people and all things, which is particularly important. A common situation in Sun Pin&#39;s novels is that as we walk, there are fewer and fewer people, and where there are few people, all things thrive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he grew older, Sun Pin found that he was less interested in people. &quot;When there is a lot of disappointment in people or human nature, or when one cannot find deep comfort in the crowd, this complex relationship between people will gradually become a cramped space that will constrain people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She got to know the plants and animals, the rivers she passed by, and tried to communicate with people who didn&#39;t speak Mandarin to try to understand them. &quot;This itself is a very interesting process,&quot; Sun Pin said, &quot;because you are gradually understanding the world, and this is actually very healing for people living in high-rise buildings.&quot; When she came to the mountains from the city Like the ocean, regional changes affect the state of mind of those who are in it. &quot;You will become more and more tolerant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This change in the state of mind in life ultimately changed her creation. &quot;My early novels were entangled in the relationships between people, and then I got a little tired of this kind of writing,&quot; Sun Pin said. &quot;It doesn&#39;t make much sense to continue writing like this. I want to make some attempts and adjustments. Moreover, I think every writer’s attempt must have a premise that makes himself feel relaxed and happy, and has the function of healing and nourishing the author himself. It is impossible for a person to say that I write to do hard labor and write about those things. Things that I don’t want to write, even if it can bring more fame to the writer himself.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Pin imagined himself becoming the fictional captain in “Seagull Rider”, trying to create a better , greater spiritual space - &quot;Because writing itself is the healing and placement of oneself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that moment, I thought, if everything is really animistic, then a person After death, you just leave human society, but enter a broader world. In that world, plants, animals, mountains, rivers, sun, moon, oceans, hurricanes, gods, dead souls, monsters, and elves are all They can communicate with each other. This kind of communication cannot be seen by living people, but some traces are revealed in those who are lonely and traumatized...&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The Magician of the Sea&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Escape and settlement exist at the same time,&quot; Sun Pin said, &quot;You can understand this kind of escape as a result of people&#39;s Escape caused by the powerlessness of reality and the material world, but at the same time, in the process of escaping, you also construct a new world for yourself, a world that belongs to all things, no longer limited to human beings, but in the world of heaven and earth. Time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Questions still exist. Fan Xiaozhe believes that Sun Pin&#39;s creations always deal with her inner confusion. &quot;First of all, she felt that communication between people in modern civilization is difficult, so she became confused.&quot; &quot;In &quot;Pain&quot;, &quot;Salt&quot; and &quot; &quot;In &quot;Split&quot;, she started from her individual feelings and constantly wrote about confusion.&quot; &quot;Later, she further inquired about the source of confusion. Is this a human problem or a social problem?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; At this stage, she did not look for answers among the crowd, but looked for them in all things.&quot; On the edge of modern civilization, in the depths of mountains, forests and islands that no one knows, those ships, sailors, mountain people, birds and beasts , are all self-consistent. &quot;In all things, her confusion was diluted and alleviated, or healed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Pin likes the &quot;elf-like temperament&quot; in Emily Dickinson&#39;s poems, and also likes Shen Congwen&#39;s poems. Writing, this kind of textual atmosphere is the state she yearns for, &quot;In him, there is no trace of integration between human beings and all things in nature, very comfortable and natural stitching and connection.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 17:25:12 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[尼泊尔爆发抗议：君主与共和之争？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261760]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“Whistles sounded frequently at the scene, and a large number of police officers gathered together. They were wearing body armor, holding shields, and motorcycles. The sound of the car starting kept making a loud sound, and many people gathered around to watch.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recalling the scene a few days ago, the Nepali Mata still remembers it fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, thousands of people came to Kathmandu, Nepal, to hold a large-scale demonstration. &quot;Restore the monarchy, abolish the republic,&quot; chanted protesters in Kathmandu, Nepal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to local police estimates, about 9,000 people participated in the protest called by Durga Prasai, a former member of the Communist Party of Nepal (United Marxist-Leninist) and medical entrepreneur. Although police described the demonstration as &quot;largely peaceful,&quot; two workers suffered minor injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Addressing the crowd later that afternoon, Prasai urged his supporters to break through the security cordon and march towards Maitigal. Police then used water cannon and tear gas to disperse the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As political competition between the current republic and the pro-monarchy has intensified recently, the Nepali government has deployed about 10,000 security personnel from the Nepal Police, Armed Police Force and investigators to prevent the two groups from interfering. possible conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The capital is &quot;in chaos&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhu Ming opened a restaurant in Nepal. He told Southern Weekend reporters that Nepal is an overall peaceful country, but in terms of certain political needs, Nepal There would be riots from time to time. Nowadays there are local police on every main street to maintain order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The young man Kariqi remembers clearly that the protest conflict took place at an intersection in the capital. People gathered and ran at the scene, and police sirens were heard continuously. “There was the sound of some kind of gunshots being fired, and there was an obvious Smoke Trail”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On that day, the local police fired 146 tear gas canisters and 5 rubber bullets to disperse Plase supporters in Barku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plasse, who claims to be a maverick and has been adhering to anti-government and anti-corruption stances in recent times, said in a speech at the rally that Prime Minister Prachanda failed to rule the country and the country was heading towards bankruptcy and demanded that &quot;He surrendered to the people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plasse also claimed that his supporters would continue to hold protests elsewhere and would ignore Kathmandu&#39;s ban. Earlier, the government declared the Baneshwar stretch of Maiti as a no-go zone for protests. He said his campaign would not stop until the monarchy, the Hindu state and the 1990 constitution were restored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plasse has long been considered a &quot;controversial&quot; businessman who is trying to overthrow Nepal&#39;s current government and calls the protests a &quot;national rescue operation.&quot; He said the protests were against the government&#39;s failure to curb anarchy, corruption and rising inflation. Prashay wanted to restore the monarchy and the Hindu state by abolishing the current federal, republican and secular institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also asked for the support of businessmen in the capital at the protest site, asking them to close their businesses from November 24. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The youth wing of the Communist Party of Nepal (United Marxist-Leninist), the Rastiya Youth Party, and its student wing, the Nepal National Free Students Union, also participated in the demonstration in Tinkun. There are also many protesters who came to Kathmandu from the southern plains of Nepal. They are also &quot;victims&quot; of bank microfinance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plasse said that banks are trying their best to exploit borrowers&#39; money and called on people to give up their loans in banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, demonstrators supporting the current republican regime also took to the streets. They believe that only a republic can guarantee social justice and equality and &quot;allow everyone to have the opportunity to realize their dreams and pursuits.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the scene of the conflict, pro-monarchy protesters and counter-protesters clashed. The anger of the protesters spread from Barku, the designated protest area, to various areas such as Tinkunne, Garigaon, Sundara, Thapatali, Fudong and other key points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Kathmandu police arrested a total of 261 protesters, set up roadblocks and water cannons on the streets, and installed closed-circuit television to monitor Praset&#39;s supporters around the clock. Police have also deployed additional sniffer dogs around the conflict site and on rooftops to ensure safety and prevent possible incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to prevent conflicts between rival groups, the police designated two different protest areas. But the opposition between those who support the monarchy and those who support the republic is huge and will lead to heightened tensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhu Ming said that the protests had little impact on local life. Because the protesters marched in designated areas, except for traffic closures during the march, other areas including the main business district and the World Tourist Center were not affected, and shops were open for business normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Political systems in conflict&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nepal, nestled in the Himalayas, has a rich and colorful culture, natural landscape and political history. But its political system evolved over the centuries, from a feudal monarchy to a federal democratic republic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Xiangyu, an associate researcher at the Institute of South Asia at Sichuan University, said that the current republic has indeed achieved certain positive results since its establishment, including the expansion of people&#39;s democratic rights and more protections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the beginning of the 21st century, Nepalese politics underwent major changes. In 2006, Nepal&#39;s civil war ended and the government and rebels signed a peace agreement. Two years later, in 2008, Nepal officially declared itself a federal democratic republic, abolished the monarchy, the head of state became the president, and power was dispersed among the central government, federal state governments, and local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Nepali government began to formulate a new constitution and established a federal system. Nepal is divided into seven federal states, each of which has a certain degree of autonomy and is responsible for managing its own affairs. This constitution-making process went through many political crises and protests, but was finally adopted in 2015 and became the current constitution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are mainly two groups of people who are dissatisfied with the republic.” Zeng Xiangyu said that one group of people are young people who have grown up with modern education and have more expectations for the country. Another group of people are those who have experienced the monarchy era. They believe that although the monarchy has many shortcomings, politicians can at least compete within a limited range and achieve general stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu said that in the process of Nepal&#39;s modern politics is still cultivating, the current chaos is more not due to the problem of the political system itself, but due to the problems of the political family class, the operation of the current system is operating. There are many problems, which also causes more dissatisfaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the end of the monarchy, political instability has troubled Nepal, and more than ten government changes have occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu said that although Nepal has not been similar to the previous civil war, the political scene has been in a political party for a long time, and the political situation has been turbulent for a long time. The continuous division of political parties and the continuous changes in policies have disappointed voters. Voters want to establish a stable government through elections and let the country go on track, but politicians often use votes as chips for political negotiations of political parties, causing strong dissatisfaction among voters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The political situation is unstable, and economic development has also slowed. Millions of young people go out to find jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu told the southern weekend reporter that Nepal&#39;s economic development has always been unable to come up, and the public is in a state of extremely confused and extremely sleepy state. Many people who study abroad or are working abroad are unwilling to come back. Some young people are more willing to go to the bay or India to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The recent outbreak of protests also shows the controversy and differences of the political system within Nepal society. Obviously, Nepal&#39;s politics still faces some challenges and problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhu Ming sometimes &quot;chat&quot; with protesters. He said that the real appeal of the protesters was to return to the era of king&#39;s power. &quot;Because only the king will think about the people.&quot; He said that the protesters believed that no matter which party, they represent their respective interests, and they would be bought by different international forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There are multiple political forces in Nepal, and behind the scenes of the interests of various political parties.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu believes that although this is the disadvantage of the current republic, it has a fierce confrontation or in the era of civil war. Compared to &quot;it is better.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Is the &quot;curry flavor&quot; protest valid? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; conflict and violent protests are not the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kathmandu Police said that on the afternoon of September 7, 2023, the 47 -year -old Hiammum Sapokta attacked the Nepalese National Party&#39;s co -General Secretary of the National University of Kathmandu. The back of the neck was deeply cut, and was then sent to the hospital for treatment by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the incident, a video circulating on social media showed that Sapoka shouted demanding to restore the monarchy of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In December 2020, people who support the monarchy and Hindu education march on the streets of Kathmandu, demand that the monarchy and Nepal are used as Hindu countries, and the federal system is abolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The controversy about the constitutional system has always existed, and it has been dragged for many years, and it has not been completely resolved yet.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that Nepal is a multi -ethnic country, with tension and differences between different ethnic groups and social groups. Some local people are dissatisfied with the distribution of federal division and autonomy, which leads to protests and political turmoil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu analyzed, as a federal country, the relationship between the central government and the provinces, and how the provinces are named and where the capital is located. The issue of disputes has continued until now, and the disputes are even greater. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At present, the current political situation in Nepal is still turbulent. There are serious differences in political concepts of monarchy and republican supporters. This opposition is not limited to ideology, but also involves the people&#39;s views on the country&#39;s future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Nepalese political parties, especially mainstream political parties, the speed of differentiation combinations is particularly fast, and it is completely based on political interests.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu commented that various political parties have not regarded the specific policies of the country as a job as a job. The center of gravity is keen on the struggle of political parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before the parade, Zhu Ming asked the people who participated in the protests &quot;would it succeed&quot; and the answer was &quot;energy&quot;. But as far as the current results are concerned, &quot;the probability does not achieve the purpose.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu said that the political situation in Nepal will not continue to fluctuate due to this protest, or it will continue the original track. &quot;The appearance&quot;, the economic and social development will not make great breakthroughs for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Democratic and republics are impossible to make mistakes.&quot; For this protest, the chairman of the Communist Party (United Marxism -Leninism) said that individual rights may make mistakes, but this does not mean that the entire system has defects in the entire system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Oli said that restoring the monarchy is unimaginable. Just like humans cannot return to the Stone Age, we cannot return to the monarchy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The goal of the protesters cannot be achieved.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu analyzed that the monarchy is already the past and does not conform to the trend of the times. protest. &quot;It is almost possible to achieve the goal of restoring the monarchy.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; But this protest mood may be an opportunity for Nepal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This is a reminder to the Politician class of Nepal.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu said, &quot;More than ten years have passed, and the public will miss the monarchy and vent the dissatisfaction with the status quo. Reflection. In Nepal, there are also some new political parties representing the voice of young people and achieved good results. But if they want to replace traditional political parties, they still have a long way to go. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:55:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王贤才丨两次焚稿，九译其书：我翻译《希氏内科学》的历程]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261714]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 15:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/12/02/E8B0F8C820.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1611 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/mdias/image/23/12/ 02/e8b0f8c820.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260450 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; At the beginning of this century, Wang Xiancai and his wife Zeng Hanying re-entered the birthplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; My ancestor was born in Yong&#39;an Township, Jiujiang County, Jiangxi. In the 1920s, his grandfather moved his family to Shanghai. In the 22nd of the Republic of China, &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; (1933) &lt;/span>; I was born in the &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (now Jianguo West Road) &lt;/span>; (now Jianguo West Road). October 30, 2023 is my 90th birthday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When I visited the former residence with my wife Zeng Hanying at the beginning of this century, Jianye has become a dangerous house, and the residents have been relocated. The guard asked Qing Lai, allowing my old resident to go in and walked in a circle, leaving this photo at the door of Lineong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the autumn of 1946, I returned to Jiujiang with my parents and lived in the ancestral house under the grandfather of Du Tianxiang. When Jiujiang was liberated in Jiujiang in May 1949, I was a high school student in the same language. When the spring of 1951 was about to be promoted to the third year of high school, he was ordered to go to Wuhan Zhongnan Group School to study &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (Jiangxi belonged to Central South District) &lt;/span>;. When I got back in July, the Youth League Committee asked me to stay in the student department and officially participate in the work. Life rhythm slows down. I am not used to the lives of institutions cadres. At this time, the national universities across the country had passed for the first time. Suddenly, I found that Shandong University Medical College still had to enroll students separately, so I asked to resign. The Student Minister agreed that the Organization Minister believed that this was a bourgeois -class individualist thought, and he did not obey the decision of the organization and forced the &quot;retreat&quot;. This is the first time I have encountered in politics and became my &quot;original crime&quot;. People of insight believe that the bumpy encounters in my first half of my life are related to this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After being forced to &quot;retreat&quot;, he said goodbye to his parents and left home sadly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/6f4d1658ee.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1541 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f4d1658ee.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260451 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Apply for the registration photos of the University of Shan University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Although I have never thought of studying medicine, I can only do so, otherwise it will have to wait another year. Later, I found that this passive major also protects me to a large extent. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Because I got a heavy price to get the opportunity to get in school, I was painful and glowed with hard work. At that time, the university had no textbooks, and kept taking notes in class. I concentrate on listening, asking myself not only to understand, but also to remember, sort out notes with memories after class, and then supplement Chinese and foreign information from the library. of more. I am the first in the class during each course of all courses during college. Professor Lu Yunming, a professor of physiology, gave me 110 points on the percentage test paper because my answer has exceeded his teaching content in the classroom. Thirty years later, I returned to Qingdao to participate in the school celebration. Mr. Lu was also pleased to mention it with me. The important thing is that my medical translation is also starting in the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/729c561658.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 700 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/729c561658.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260452 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; During the period of studying, take a photo in Qingdao Beach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After entering the clinical course, I know that there is a world -renowned medical masterpiece &quot;Hishene Science&quot; in the United States. Teachers joked that it was the &quot;Capital&quot; of clinical medicine. I went to the school library to register and queue up, and I borrowed this heavy masterpiece. In reading and learning, it deeply feels its profound profoundness. It discusses the system and rigor, especially focuses on clinical and basic theoretical connections, and has the idea of ​​translating it into Chinese. I think this is a very meaningful thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The journey of thousands of miles starts under the foot. I want to do it in two steps: first translate a smaller book, after getting experience, and then move that most of the head. Later, I picked up the &quot;Clinical Surgery Notice&quot; written by Professor HC Owen for the intern and low -aged inpatients (&lt;em>; An An Approach to Clinical Surgery &lt;/em>;). I can grasp it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But whether you want to translate &quot;Hydine Science&quot; or the trial translation of this booklet, it was still my secret at that time. Only one close friend of the same class &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style _GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (Liu Yiren) &lt;/span>; Knowing this, he has always been optimistic about me, encouraged me, and found a&quot; secret &quot;translation location for me attic. It was a cobweb, and the low -aged fighting room. I had to bow over and bend over. &quot;Table&quot; is a superposition soap box, sitting on a brick wrapped in newspapers. I get up every morning and hide here to translate. The attic is not electric, and you can only use candles to light up. My vision is not good. When I look close, I often smell a burnt, that is, the hair is burning. He quietly returned to the dormitory at six or seven o&#39;clock, followed the pace of life of the students, and washed, meals, and went to the ward together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/e53a0d5f09.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1662 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/e53a0d5f09.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 260453 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; A photo of secretly translating the book in the attic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; My low -key and confidential work have done a good job, until I finished this small book of more than 200,000 words, and the &quot;underground activity&quot; was not discovered. In 1993, I returned to Qingdao to participate in the parent school celebration. Liu Jingru, a classmate who lived in me, &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (at the time of the Qingdao Health Bureau) &lt;/ &lt;/ Span>; acknowledged that he knew nothing about these activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/400851e4cb.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1676 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/400851e4cb.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260454 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In 1993, he returned to Qing medicine to participate in the school celebration activities and took a photo with Liu Jingru (middle), the old classmate of the Qingdao Health Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1957, &quot;Instructions for Clinical Surgery&quot; published in Shanghai Health Publishing House, I have graduated from Beijing to work in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/cf8354f25c.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1078 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/cf8354f25c.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260455 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; After this small book is published, I have repeatedly passed the bumps and almost lost everything. This is an old book bought from the Internet. There are three types of printbooks: Shanghai Technology Publishing House (1960, 1961) and Hong Kong Business Press (1970). &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Entering &quot;Heri&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The publication of &quot;Clinical Surgery&quot; has given me a lot of encouragement. It marches. This translation is not a &quot;underground activity&quot;, and colleagues know that I am doing this. But my time was not good, and soon I came to the right movement. Although I was so safe in 1957, because the hospital&#39;s anti -rights indicator was not completed, by June 1958, the Soviet Medical was remedied for the &quot;deliberate&quot; Soviet Medicine. At this time, the anti -right orgasm had passed. The two additional rights and I had not been distributed in the hospital. They stayed in the hospital to supervise the labor, and the monthly living expenses were 32 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two months later, the hospital was suddenly ordered to move to Hohhot, Inner Mongolia to support the local leap forward. The pressure I feel is getting greater. Finally, on the night of a month, about 400,000 words of manuscripts translated into the ninth edition of the ninth edition of &quot;He&#39;s&quot; were burned in a wasteland next to the hospital. Although I was very sad, I could barely convince myself: Now that I am not a translation, I have to work hard to take off the &quot;hat&quot; on my head. Science is always developing, and new versions will come out at that time, and I will start again. &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I have been ordered to &quot;act as an acting doctor&quot; since 1960. Every morning, I lead the inpatients and intern to check the room. At this time, I am their superiors. After the inspection, they returned to the office. Everyone needs me to do it and I can do it, I do it actively. Because I am not the same as them, I am a supervised rightist. At that time, the enemy of the people was the &quot;reactionist&quot;. So I think about it day and night, and my heart is &quot;picking hats&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking forward to the stars, looking forward to the moon, finally looking forward to this day. In November 1961, the Party Committee of the Academy announced that he would &quot;take a hat&quot;. At this time, the situation has also changed a lot: the Soviet Union became &quot;Su Xiu&quot; and the target of our criticism, not a &quot;older brother&quot;. I re -filed the old industry again, bought the 11th edition of &quot;He&#39;s&quot;, and marched into &quot;He&#39;s&quot; again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the life is good, and the &quot;Four Qing&quot; campaign came again. The leader of the leadership movement warned me: Do not recur on the old disease, the &quot;right&quot; hat can be picked up and can be worn again! I hit my &quot;key&quot;. I have to cliff! Finally, the manuscript of the 11th edition of the 11th edition of the &quot;Xishi&quot; manuscript &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (also more than 400,000 words) &lt;/span>;, next to the hospital In the wasteland, ignition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A celebrity said that the most painful thing in life is to wake up and go without way. When I was wearing a &quot;hat&quot;, I could do the dream of doing the &quot;hat&quot; after picking up. What way can I go now and what dreams do I have? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Life is sometimes harsh and not lost: After more than 20 years, I was invited to return to Hohhot to discuss with the science and technology personnel in Inner Mongolia. Beside, I built on the wasteland of the manuscript twice, and couldn&#39;t help but talk about this past with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Upgrade again &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The &quot;Four Qing&quot; movement has not completely ended, and it has entered ten years of catastrophe. I have upgraded to the &quot;current counter -revolutionary&quot; with the &quot;right -haired right&quot;, sentenced to 12 years in prison, deprived of political rights for 4 years, and entered labor reform. Fortunately, the authorities used my skills to serve the transformation of sentences in the health department of the labor reform team to avoid general labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1971, the difficulty friend Cheng Cheng, who was released, sent me a strict &quot;high gift&quot; to me. Open it, it was the 13th edition of &quot;He&#39;s Internal Science&quot;! Cheng Dalu was a educated youth in Shanxi in Shanghai. He was sentenced to 5 years in prison for &quot;anti -revolutionary&quot;. He was hospitalized here for a long time due to pleurisy. We get along well. He knew that I was determined to translate the &quot;Hishene Science&quot; and remember it in my heart. At that time, it was stipulated that people who were in large cities and along the coast could not go home after the release. >; Employment. Therefore, after he can use the prisoner to work every day, there is no chance to send me a book to send me a book. Cheng Dalu has only 29 yuan &quot;salary&quot; per month, and he also helps his sister who put it on Anhui. However, after he found the new &quot;Hythonic Science&quot; (photocopy) in a foreign language shop, he tried to find it to sell clothes for me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b574c980bd.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 579 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b574c980bd.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260456 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In 1984, I saw it after Jiujiang and Chengda Road (pictured left). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Suddenly seeing the long -lost &quot;He&#39;s&quot;, things are wrong, and the feeling in my heart is really unspeakable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the prisoners work every day, lunch is eaten at the construction site, and it will not be completed until 6 pm. So after I finished the ward in the morning, I could read a book. The patients sent by the teams sent by the teams at night can be stopped at eight or nine o&#39;clock. I watched the 13th version of &quot;He&#39;s&quot; and found that with the progress of the times, the content is very different from the previous versions. Heri himself has already retired. There are 177 authors of this book. The chief editor is Professor Paul B. Beeson of Oxford University (later transferred to the University of Washington University in the United States). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c79b574a0b.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1437 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c79b574a0b.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260457 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; &quot;Hythi Inn science&quot; 13, 14, 15, the chief editor-in-chief Bi Sen sent me a signature photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Translation in prison &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; I can&#39;t help but want to use the current timing translation book. I am not impulsive, whimsical, but after careful consideration and serious consideration. Since I went to the labor reform team, I have always worked hard at work and cautiously, such as the abyss, such as the abyss, such as the thin ice, have not made mistakes, have not had a medical accident, especially using the idle microscope for a long time, and found from the main factory&#39;s large library. Analyze the balance of balance and optoelectronics, and establish a laboratory to do the clinical and biochemical test of general hospitals at that time. One year&#39;s reward) &lt;/span>;, so the leader trusts me very much. I think I can win the support of leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to regulations, cadres cannot come to me to see a doctor, but from the political commissar of the factory leader Li Hengwen, I often come to me to see the doctor. Of course, I have no right to refuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On this day, Li Zheng came to me to see a doctor again. He was about half a year old and was an anti -Japanese cadre and was the director of the public security. He often suffers from slow heart rate and the cause is unknown. After thoroughly inspected and tested, I believed that it was a manifestation of coronary heart disease. In the era when the supplies were short, people&#39;s general malnutrition, coronary heart disease was still rare in China. Occasionally, large hospitals saw several cases of coronary heart disease, myocardial infarction, and written papers can be published in national academic journals. Doctors have lack of experience and difficult to contact foreign medical information. Later, the outside hospital also recognized my diagnosis, which also increased the trust of Li Political Commissar to me and asked me how I thought of coronary heart disease slowly from my heart rate. I took the opportunity to move out of that big book and said that it told me that I wanted to translate it so that more Chinese doctors could see it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li&#39;s political commissar turned the big book without answering me. I haven&#39;t spoken for a long time. I feel a little uneasy, and I should not take the liberty to make this request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He put the book from the book and said to me, &quot;Since it is such a good book, you will translate it here. We support you. After the translation, we cannot publish it, and we print it! &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; That&#39;s what he said, I still remember it so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Learn &quot;Dumb Japanese&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In this way, I translated &quot;Hishei Science&quot; for the third time in the Labor Reform team, and wanted to realize the wish of student days. There are naturally many difficulties in such a closed environment. Although there are many people in the labor reform in that period, the problem of strong professionalism is still difficult to find out. Remember to translate a paragraph about CT and stuck. Now CT is already a household name, but at that time, CT had just come out, and I couldn&#39;t from the two English words of &quot;Computerized Tomography&quot;. , Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (literally means&quot; computer -disposal body photography &quot;) &lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through the prisoner of this city, please ask the family to help find the commentary information about CT. Finally found a copy of it, but it was Japanese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is just a Japanese expert in the ward: Mr. Luo Yuanzhen, a professor at the Department of History of Shanxi University. In his early years, Luo Lao studied early Japan&#39;s early Daada University and married the Japanese lady &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (suspected to be &quot;Japanese agent&quot;) &lt;/span>;, he is &quot;not Decision &quot;, the detention center was overcrowded and sent it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the interval is like a mountain, and Luo Lao, who is proficient in Japanese, can&#39;t see the Japanese information about CT, saying that only you can see it yourself; you can learn Japanese without understanding Japanese. I was a little hesitant: Is it too much to learn foreign languages ​​in order to read a little Japanese information? Luo Lao said that he can quickly make it: learn a &quot;dumb Japanese&quot;, just read books, do not ask to write articles, just make a month. In that kind of environment, there is no choice, and this is the only way. So the translation was suspended and learned Japanese with Luo Lao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/0F3BF689C9.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1467 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/0F3BF689C9.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260458 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The Japanese teacher in prison, Professor Luo Yuanzhen (1906-1993), a professor in Shanxi University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After checking the room every day, I invite Luo to my room. span>; Come and learn Japanese. In less than a month, the &quot;dumb Japanese&quot; was rough, understood the Japanese information about CT, and returned to the translation of &quot;Heri&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One night in late September 1975, the 13th edition of &quot;He&#39;s&quot;, the full book &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (3.4 million words) &lt; /SPAN>; The translation of the manuscript is finally killed. I put the last translation of the translation in the manuscript. Each page of 300 words of manuscript paper has a page number to more than 11,000 pages. The code is like a hill, trembling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The wish of the student period is finally completed, but Shaohua is no longer, and I am no longer young. I still translate books in such a situation, which is regrettable! Although I can feel a little gratifying, almost at the same time, at the same time, another kind of unspeakable sadness has penetrated my body and mind: Will I be forced to burn them again ... &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; At this time, the night was quiet, and the monitoring room was silent. I am very close to the wall here. You can see the high -voltage line and the sentry of the shot -shot -shot of the shot of the Ganglou on the high wall ... &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Refining the release of the judgment &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; After translating &quot; The 13th edition of Hydine Science is less than ten days, and my life ushered in another major change: Inner Mongolia High Court decided to revoke the original judgment to me and change the sentence for eight years! This is the twice of Comrade Xiaoping, and proposed the result of Mao Zedong&#39;s &quot;three instructions as the outline&quot;, and all walks of life must be rectified. I was arrested and sentenced in 1967. Based on this, I have been serving for 8 years, so I decided to change the sentence for 8 years. But they do n’t understand that I have been reduced for 1 year. The day of the judgment was September 27, 1975. Sit more and sit more. At that time, there was no state compensation, and I had nothing to say. The Labor Reform team decided to let people go, and allowed me to take away all the translation of all the 13th edition of &quot;He&#39;s Internal Science&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/bed71ffd4f.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 606 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/bed71ffd4f.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260459 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The 13th edition of the 13th edition of &quot;Hishei Science&quot; translated in prison is 3.4 million words in the book, and the Jiujiang Museum is now Tibetan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Back to the home of Jiujiang, depending on his mother. Soon I was hired to be hired as a factory hospital as a temporary work &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; (as a doctor) &lt;/span>;, 34.5 yuan per month. At this time, I had the 14th edition of &quot;He&#39;s&quot;. I bought it back and used it to compare and add and supplement the 13th edition of the translation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In December 1978, the Party Central Committee held a historic Session of the Eleventh Central Committee of the Eleventh Central Committee, from &quot;class struggle as the outline&quot; to the center of economic construction. The central government issued documents No. 55 to &quot;remove the hat&quot; to the national rightists. I was arranged at the Second People&#39;s Hospital of Jiujiang City. However, the original unit must be done to correct peace. So in 1980, I returned to the original work unit of Inner Mongolia. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Signing and publishing &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Right -faction correction, the injustice is all smooth, and there are unexpected joy: because my injustice is in the catastrophe period, according to regulations, the salary of the deducted penalty at that time was Can be issued, so I suddenly became a &quot;10,000 yuan households&quot;! This was a huge amount at the time. When I was waiting to be approved step by step, I went to the Inner Mongolia People&#39;s Publishing House to inquire about publishing for a manuscript. The editor Xu Cheng, who received my editor, is the deputy director of the head of the Technology Editorial Office. Xu Cheng was not interested in the manuscript of his friend. He asked casually: Is there any manuscript? I also said casually: &quot;Are you interested in the big manuscript?&quot; Hishene Science &quot;.&quot; I don&#39;t want Xu Cheng&#39;s eyes to light up, and it&#39;s coming. He asked the manuscript and my situation carefully and asked me to give him a little time. Twenty days later, Xu Cheng ran to me to sign a contract, saying that they decided to publish them in 10 volumes, and they were out for three years! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xu Cheng&#39;s words surprised me: A book of such a big book decided? We never know each other. How can he trust me? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this day, around this book, he has done a lot of work: he knows that I am a doctor and inquire about my name in Inner Mongolia. The ministry&#39;s &quot;Instructions for Clinical Surgery&quot; has been carefully read; two seminars have been opened, and one of them specially went to Beijing to open. Then report to the leaders and signed me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I think more important reasons should be: reform and opening up, all of which are awake, people are eager to understand the outside world, but after these years of tossing, English talents are rare. Live, there is this ready -made translation. This is my luck, but it is actually my luck. Nevertheless, I admire Xu Cheng&#39;s professionalism. He was 12 years younger than me and graduated from the Department of Biology, Inner Mongolia in 1966. I will become a lifetime with him in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1499da72df.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 871 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1499da72df.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260460 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Xu Cheng (Tu right) talks about the press &quot;Hishene Science&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Back to Jiujiang, I immediately sent the first &quot;Book 5&quot; cardiovascular disease translation to Xu Cheng. At that time, printing was still the age of the lead. Choose this album first, not because I am a doctor of this major, but because Xu Cheng&#39;s marketing considerations: there are many patients with cardiovascular patients. &quot;>; (Later, it was true, and the first printed 10,000 volumes were out of stock after two months, and then added) &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>;. However, during the typesetting period, I received the 15th edition of &quot;He&#39;s&quot;, and the content has also changed a lot! The author has increased to 277, and the length of the book has also expanded to about 5 million words, and even the arrangement style is very different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is another severe test for me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I can take a more relaxed road: According to the requirements of the contract, I will post the completed translations one after another, and use the book for 3 years. This is not backward internationally. But after all, I do not publish a book for the book, but to pursue it as a career. If I can&#39;t dedicate the latest and best version to the reader, even if this book comes out, it will leave deep regrets. I experienced a fierce inner struggle at night. Dawn got up and wrote to Xu Cheng. The letter just sent it. I couldn&#39;t help but go to the Telecommunications Bureau to call him a long -distance call to explain the original committee. Please immediately notify the printing factory to stop the printing and recover the translation. For the manuscript, I decided to start from scratch and re -translate the 15th edition of the book to ensure that the 5th band of the first ranking of the first row within three months was about 500,000 words of translation. The 10 banks in the book will still be in about 3 years! &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Re -translation of the 15th edition &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; This is my fifth translation of &quot;He&#39;s&quot; to achieve the success of the early years. I know the difficulty and workload of re -translation of the book, but I think it is much more convenient to translate books in the labor reform team. In order to grab time, I have never had any holidays, and the lunch habit that has been developed over the years has also been eliminated. From the beginning of the morning every morning, Xingxing Yexian, work in desk. In February 1982, the 5th Substance of the Lena was published as scheduled. At the end of December 1984, a total of 4.7 million words were finally completed in the 15th edition of &quot;Hishene Science&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f1b522794.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;Height =&quot; 1441 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f1b522794.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260461 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Re-translate the 15th edition of &quot;He&#39;s Internal Science&quot; day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In June 1985, all the ten albums were all out. Although we have gone through some twists and turns, we are the first countries in the world to launch the 15th edition of &quot;He&#39;s Internal Science&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/c0f4b042c0.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 604 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c0f4b042c0.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260462 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In 1985, the 15th edition of the &quot;Hydine Science&quot; was published in 10 editions of Chinese translations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking back in the past years, I have contacted five different versions, two burns, five translations of their books, and translated about 10.7 million words in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Ministry of Health was reviewed by the Chinese translation organization of &quot;Hydine Science&quot;, and experts expressed satisfaction with the quality of translation. The Ministry of Health decided to set up a &quot;Medical Translation Special Award&quot;. In February 1987, Minister Cui Yueli awarded me in the Ministry of Health. His wife Zeng Hanying was also invited to participate in the award ceremony due to the hard work during the translation and publishing process. This prize so far is the only one. One year later, Xu Cheng also won the important award of the publishing front &quot;Bole Award&quot; in Inner Mongolia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/cef17b4f83.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 746 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cef17b4f83.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260463 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In the spring of 1987, he accepted the &quot;Medical Translation Special Award&quot; in the Ministry of Health. Director of the Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I am not the first person in China to translate &quot;Hishene Science&quot;. During the Republic of China, the Chinese Medical Association organized a group of domestic experts to collectively translate and publish the 7th edition of the 7th edition of &quot;Heri&quot;, but it is limited to the relevant content of the Department of Internal Medicine, not the whole book, so it uses the title of &quot;Hythi Science&quot;. In addition to the various systems of clinical medicine, the original book also includes related content such as surgery, obstetrics and gynecology, pediatrics, dermatology, eye, ear, nose and throat, and public health, medical statistics, clinical testing and radiation diagnosis, medical genetic and ethics. So the original book title is &quot;&lt;em>; Cecil Textbook of Medicine &lt;/em>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (&quot; &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot; &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Heri Medical Textbook &quot;) &lt;/span>;. I translated the whole book, which is also the first full translation in my country, but also used the title left by the predecessors when translated: &quot;Hishei Internalism&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《希氏内科学》中译本问世，受到广泛关注，这不是我真的做了什么了不起的事，而是那个时代的特色：改革开放，人心振奋，一台戏， A movie, a novel, can often cause a coaxing effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/09ffc11e53.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/09ffc11e53.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;应邀在北京参加《希氏》第15版中译本首发式,左为责任编辑徐诚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《希氏内科学》在北京首发时，不能分册选购&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（往常可以）&lt;/span >;.购者还是纷至沓来，络绎不绝。有位老人早早地骑车从郊区赶来买书。他是工程师，家里也没有学医的人。我为他签名时提醒他这不是科普的书，但他还是坚持要买。以后我做《希氏》第17、18版补译工作时，领导居然决定，译稿先在一个综合性医学期刊上连载，随译随发&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为此增加了刊物篇幅）&lt;/span>;，一年发完，再交出版社汇编出书。这个决定见报后，那年该刊的邮发量竟因此而增长了近三倍！这些都是现在无法想象也很难理解的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为世界医学名著，《希氏内科学》已有意、日、西、葡等多种文字译本，各国翻译该书，都是上百人的专家班子集体翻译，从来没有一个人完成《希氏》全书翻译的。卫生部顾问、著名麻风病专家马海德&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（美裔华籍）&lt;/span>;说，海外媒体称王贤才是“中共十一届三中全会后冒出的&#39;出土文物&#39;（unearthed relics）”，问我有何观感。我说他们看到三中全会、改革开放的决定性作用是对的，但也不是我特别能干，是我的境况和经历决定了只能孤身拼搏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;后记&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;以后一些年里，我还译下了：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《简明希氏内科学》第2版&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（141万字&lt;/span>;）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《希氏内科学》第17、18版补译本&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（150万字）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《西氏内科学》第21版全书&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（600万字，因与西安世界图书出版公司合作，他们建议改“希氏”为“西氏”）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《西氏内科学》第22版全书&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（815万字）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/60a8a893fe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/60a8a893fe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;陆续译出的不同版本的《希氏内科学》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;连同最先出版的第15版《希氏》，我先后接触过9个不同版本，共计译成和出版2106万字。在迄今我的全部译著中，《希氏》系列约近其半；结缘可谓深厚了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是2003年11月70岁时退休的。 《希氏》第22版&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（815万字）&lt;/span>;是退休后的译作。回顾我这一生，出版的主要译著15种37部约5000万字，可能是中国，也是世界上译著字数最多的人，因为发达国家是无需大量科技翻译的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b95d5cc5b9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1375&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b95d5cc5b9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;我和我的主要译著。前下是1957年最先出版的稚嫩的小书《临床外科须知》。它是丑小鸭，微不足道，但它引领了后来的那些译著，也开启了漫长的坎坷之路，所以我对它始终有着更多的感情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽芜湖一医院超收患者21万余元医疗费，省医保局通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261764]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 14:37:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notice on the illegal use of medical insurance funds by Wuhu Second People’s Hospital&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;On July 18, 2023, our bureau received a petition report from Yang Moumou, which reflected that Wuhu Second People’s Hospital illegally and illegally used fictitious and exchanging diagnostic and treatment services while his father was hospitalized for cerebral hemorrhage. Medical insurance fund. Our bureau attaches great importance to it. Based on the data screening and analysis, on August 8, a provincial and municipal joint inspection team of more than 20 people was formed with the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau to station in the hospital to conduct an investigation on the hospital charges and medical insurance reimbursements during the hospitalization of the reporter’s father. Conduct a comprehensive verification. Through medical record verification, on-site questioning and data comparison, it was verified that 10 of the 15 issues involved in the report were basically true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, the hospital had problems such as over-diagnosis and treatment, over-examination, over-prescribing of medicines, repeated charges, fraudulent charges, and excessive charges, involving illegal medical expenses of 218,200 yuan, including illegal use of medical insurance funds. 187,000 yuan. In order to maintain the safety of the medical insurance fund and protect the legitimate rights and interests of patients, according to the medical insurance service agreement for designated medical institutions signed between the hospital and the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Department, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau first handled the matter in accordance with the agreement: First, the medical insurance fund used in violation of regulations was recovered in full , and a penalty of 56,074.41 yuan was deducted at the maximum rate of 30%; the second was to interview the relevant person in charge of the hospital and order him to make immediate rectifications; the third was to hand it over to the public security and health departments for further verification and processing. At present, all the above treatment measures have been completed. At the same time, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau has initiated administrative penalty procedures in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Supervision and Management of the Use of Medical Security Funds&quot;. While verifying the reported issues, the provincial and municipal joint inspection teams drew inferences from one example and conducted a comprehensive and extended inspection of the hospital&#39;s use of medical insurance funds from April 1, 2022 to May 31, 2023. Further verification is currently underway, and follow-up will be based on The procedures will be handled seriously in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 25, Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau, in accordance with the &quot;Implementation Rules for Handling Reporting Clues in the Supervision and Management of Anhui Medical Security Fund (Trial)&quot;, gave written feedback on the verification and handling to the whistleblower in the form of a supervision notice. . In accordance with the &quot;Measures for Reporting Rewards for Illegal Use of Medical Security Funds in Anhui Province&quot;, the whistleblower was given a reporting reward of RMB 5,364.04. We welcome all sectors of society to supervise the use of medical insurance funds in designated medical institutions. We will deal with the verified problems seriously and will never tolerate them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;Anhui Provincial Medical Security Bureau&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;December 2, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[朱丹为闺蜜担保背负巨债：友谊塑料，情比金坚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261762]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Being let down, betrayed, and deceived by friends can have many endings - such as &quot;stabbing in the back&quot;, such as when I Nearly 30 years ago, I lent a large sum of money to my best friend, but it was never repaid. This money was supposed to be used to prepare me for big things. But there are very few people who are as miserable as Zhu Dan and have no friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Zhu Dan revealed when participating in a program that he was defrauded of all his savings by a friend many years ago. She was deceived by her friend into being a debt guarantor and wrote her name on a blank piece of paper. As a result, she was forced to use all her savings to pay off all her friend&#39;s debts. Even if he won the lawsuit, the matter would end in Zhu Dan&#39;s misfortune because his shameless friend declared &quot;bankruptcy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much this money is, many people are concerned about this issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the parties did not disclose specific figures, it is impossible to confirm. But this is not important, because we only need to know that this amount of money is beyond the imagination of ordinary people. The important thing is that this incident happened while Zhu Dan and Yiwei Yiwei were in love, but Yiwei Yi chose to repay the debt with Zhu Dan. In the program, when Zhu Dan recounted this unbearable event in a calm tone with red eyes under the wind chimes, Yiwei Yiwei looked at her with a distressed and forgiving look, as if he were facing a child who had been wronged. This scene It’s very emotional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that many people have met people who do things without thinking, otherwise there would be so many &quot;easy to deceive people&quot; in the world. How stupid is Zhu Dan&#39;s hasty behavior? As one netizen said, your behavior as a human being should not be too outrageous, and you must have a basic bottom line. Zhu Dan&#39;s best friend sent her a piece of white paper, and she dared to sign it. It was difficult for a middle school student to do this. Even the judge couldn&#39;t help &quot;teaching&quot; Zhu Dan that he was legally illiterate. As long as he signed on the white paper, It is equivalent to admitting everything on this piece of paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This netizen said that he does not have such a wife, but he has such a mother. These words also touched the sensitive parts of many people&#39;s hearts. I have relatives and friends who are like this. They don&#39;t listen to anything they say, and they only wake up after being deceived. However, it doesn&#39;t take long for them to fall into new routines again. As the saying goes, &quot;Dangdang is different&quot;, some people just can&#39;t get out of this tragic scam &quot;reincarnation&quot;. What can you do? Anyway, I heard that in addition to some parents &quot;paying the bill&quot; for their deceived children, there are many examples of couples breaking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I very much agree with what this netizen said: Yiwei Yi helped her pay off the debt. This behavior cannot be described as high-spirited and upright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, Yiwei Yi seems to be indifferent to Zhu Dan, which is one of the reasons why some &quot;black fans&quot; have been criticizing Yiwei. Not only do they feel that Yiwei is not good to Zhu Dan, but they also habitually show off in public places. The &quot;poker-faced&quot; Zhou Yiwei got a lot of insults on his head. There are even rumors that the two are getting married. But now, many netizens woke up from the misunderstanding and discovered that Yiwei Yiwei is so good - &quot;I apologize for talking about Yiwei before. If he can avoid divorce after such a thing, I respect him as a real man.&quot; &quot;We endure hardships and enjoy happiness together.&quot; &quot;There are not many people who can repay debts together. And it&#39;s a man, even less.&quot; &quot;I thought he was quite shrewd, and it seemed like he was in love. I thought this kind of thing could only be done by parents to their children.&quot; &quot;Come out&quot; &quot;Yiwei Zhou is a relatively aloof but loyal type&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You know, at that time Yiwei could have broken up with Zhu Dan without having to sacrifice himself. Even if the two are already married, Yiwei Yi has every reason to ignore the &quot;bad debt&quot;. After all, even according to the marriage law, it is not his responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Dan was tricked by his friends, which is a typical example of being defrauded. According to legal principles, whether you have an obligation to repay debts caused by being defrauded depends on whether the debts are used jointly by the husband and wife. Unless there is evidence to prove that the debt belongs to the couple&#39;s common living use, the other party has no obligation and responsibility to repay it.很明显，朱丹债务的产生，和周一围无关，也不属于两个人共同商量的结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s ridiculous is that one netizen even commented that Zhou Yiwei actually used this matter to manipulate Zhu Dan and gain a useful slave. This is illogical. What can you do if you have tens of millions in your hand? What can you buy and eat? Do you have to give up half your life savings to someone else? Those who say this, and those who believe this, can also pay 10 million or 20 million for someone to treat you as a &quot;master&quot; and see if you are willing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is really sad to see people without knowing their surroundings. We should feel lucky to still have such a kind and loving man like Yiwei Yi in our sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because of the old saying that &quot;husband and wife are originally birds of the same forest, and they fly separately when disaster strikes&quot;, acts of friendship are particularly noble. If a couple wants to maintain a long-term relationship, it is not enough to just have an emotional foundation. In a world that is difficult and full of changes, if there is a lack of moral support and a little noble personality from both parties, it is not surprising that the couple breaks up halfway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿童木会流泪吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261742]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/H4PoJ90PIQJmpKm7m3yKcQmBPcEXKYYenxj2YfGt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;648&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/H4PoJ90PIQJmpKm7m3yKcQmBPcEXKYYenx j2YfGt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recently launched animated series &quot;PLUTO&quot; by Netflix, the audience once again saw the familiar robot Astro Boy from their childhood. This animated work depicts the existential crisis of humans and robots after the Central Asian War. The information is dense, neat and compact, and its lightness is as impressive as its heaviness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hideo Kojima, the game producer and a well-known science fiction fan and animation fan, said, &quot;This work is completely different from robot animations and hero animations that can only fight. This is Japanese manga (&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Comics&lt;/span>;), this is animation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The birth of ChatGPT made mankind realize that it may be replaced in the new technological environment Species crisis, the Palestinian-Israeli conflict caused tragic casualties. In this reality, &quot;PLUTO&quot; appeared: the shadow of the post-war period shrouded the entire earth, and Persia, which had lost its country, created the giant robot Pluto and wanted to destroy him. Seven of the world&#39;s strongest robots, including Astro Boy. In the fictional story, &quot;war robot crisis&quot; replaces &quot;nuclear crisis&quot;, and &quot;robot sanctions&quot; replace &quot;nuclear sanctions&quot; in international politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, Japanese cartoonist Osamu Tezuka released the special &quot;Astro Boy&quot; episode &quot;The Strongest Robot on Earth&quot;. From the 1950s to the 1970s when Japanese comics were on the rise, most cartoonists of Tezuka’s generation took a left-leaning political stance because of their experience in World War II. They were anti-war, respectful of life, and advocating equality in their works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, with the permission of Osamu Tezuka&#39;s son, cartoonist Naoki Urasawa created &quot;PLUTO&quot; based on &quot;The Strongest Robot on Earth&quot;. &quot;PLUTO&quot;, born in 2023, is an animated series created by Netflix on this basis. From the anti-war thoughts in 1964, to the Iraq War in 2003, to the Palestinian-Israeli conflict in 2023, the three creations of &quot;PLUTO&quot; correspond to the war backgrounds of different eras. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has long allowed the world to accept the artistic language of comics. Tokiwa-so cartoonists headed by Osamu Tezuka have redefined the depth and breadth of comics. Their depiction and exploration of emotions have made their works Crossing the boundaries of the audience. Although &quot;PLUTO&quot; takes place in the context of a grand robot war, its setting is still classical: How can a robot become more like a human? On the one hand, humans are afraid of being replaced by machines; on the other hand, they are full of discrimination against androids - humans have emotions, and robots are just inferior species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Robot, are you really not sad? When robots cry, even they themselves are surprised. Who am I? Am I really grieving? Are these reactions emotions, or a set of codes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While watching this animation, I needed to press the pause button several times and stop for a while. Its perception and depiction of emotions are very innocent and beautiful, and sadness comes in an extremely light way. When Astro Boy is destroyed, will he be allowed to declare &quot;death&quot;? Or it can only be declared &quot;damaged and scrapped&quot;. Naoki Urasawa continues Tetsuka&#39;s exploration of &quot;the relationship between man and others&quot;, and still almost stubbornly depicts the possibility of &quot;understanding&quot; in a world full of fragmentation and disputes. For example, the robot North 2 went to the hometown of a stubborn artist to find the piano music in the artist&#39;s dream; the dinner between the robot Astro Boy and Dr. Pegasus; Ulan, who lost Astro Boy, could not face his own perception. The little robot keeps running around, trying to help sad humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t seen such an animated work for a long time. The last time it gave me such an emotional experience was the animated film &quot;Ghost in the Shell&quot;. Its English name is &quot;Ghost in the Shell&quot;. Those whispers in the machine body may be just ghosts that are difficult to define, but it happened after all, didn&#39;t it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 13:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[母亲起诉儿子返还购房款：对家庭是一个警示丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261756]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 11:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;Today&#39;s Statement&quot; report, Yang&#39;s mother is a single mother, and her original condom was located in Dongcheng District, Beijing. The only house I have is my only son, Xiao Yang. She got 3.7 million from selling her house and transferred it to her son. She used it to buy a larger house in Tongzhou District, which she lived in and used as a wedding house for her son. Only her son&#39;s name was written on the property ownership certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2019, Xiao Yang got married, and Yang’s mother lived with Xiao Yang and his wife in the new house. Soon after the marriage, the daughter-in-law had conflicts with Yang&#39;s mother over daily trivial matters. The relationship between Xiao Yang, who firmly stands by his wife, and Yang&#39;s mother continues to deteriorate. After that, Xiao Yang and his wife moved out of their new house. Later, because his wife had another quarrel with Yang&#39;s mother, Xiao Yang became angry and blocked Yang&#39;s mother on WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, in order to solve the problem of her daughter’s schooling, Xiao Yang sent a WeChat message to her grandmother: “Sell the house in Tongzhou and let my mother use the money from her original sale to buy another house, and I will save money. Buy a house.&quot; &quot;If my mother can&#39;t agree, I will go to court to sue my mother in one month. If it really goes to court, there will be no turning back on our mother-son relationship.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Known After what her son said, Yang&#39;s mother said she was &quot;completely heartbroken&quot; and said she would be &quot;homeless&quot; if Xiao Yang sued her for obstruction. So Yang&#39;s mother sued Xiao Yang to return the purchase price of 3.7 million yuan for future pension purposes, and received the support of the court. This decision is in accordance with common law, or good customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a typical case of the conflict between the extended family orientation and the small family orientation. The current statutory legal framework talks about the individual standard and the small family standard: the division of property is based on the boundaries between individuals and small families, and small families implement the &quot;community property system&quot;; parents have raised their children to adulthood and have done their best to support them. Adult children have the obligation to support their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children who are minors must rely on their parents’ care, care and protection. Parents have custody and control over their children. When children become adults, they separate from their parents and form a nuclear family. If they get married and buy a house on their own, and do not receive support from their parents, nor do they expect to receive large amounts of property or inheritance from their parents, then the parents have not interfered with their children. A legitimate reason and effective starting point in life, children are &quot;independent&quot; from the extended family and gain the &quot;sovereignty&quot; of the small family. This is a normal intergenerational power transfer in a family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if on the one hand, the children get a large amount of support from their parents when they get married and buy a house, but on the other hand, they want to have a soft life and refuse their parents&#39; interference in their lives (whether it is &quot;suggestions&quot; or &quot;pointing fingers&quot;) Well, it’s actually the same thing), which essentially refuses parents to fulfill their “investor rights/powers”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as this case is concerned, the quarrel between the daughter-in-law and Yang&#39;s mother over &quot;daily trivial matters&quot; may have started because the daughter-in-law couldn&#39;t stand her mother-in-law&#39;s lifestyle, or she couldn&#39;t accept her mother-in-law&#39;s interference in the couple&#39;s lifestyle. The specific quarrel may have different rights and wrongs, but the underlying reason must be: the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law are fighting for the right to speak or dominate the house or the family, or one party believes that the other party has usurped his rights to the things in the house or the family. power or dominance. This is the essence of many conflicts between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a lot of poisonous chicken soups on the Internet nowadays, such as &quot;A husband must stand for his daughter-in-law, otherwise he will be a mama&#39;s boy.&quot; This is probably because the daughter-in-law or the person who acts as the daughter-in-law by herself is online more, while the mother-in-law is less online, and the former has a higher voice. bigger. After Yang&#39;s mother paid 3.7 million yuan to provide a wedding house for the young couple, after the conflict between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, the son did not reconcile the conflict, but blindly sided with the daughter-in-law, further intensifying the conflict, which shows that the son has nothing to do with his mother, who is an elder and investor. respect. There are many voices on the Internet who ridicule Xiao Yang for &quot;taking a wife and forgetting her mother.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, it was originally a tough and feasible plan to &quot;sell the house in Tongzhou and let my mother use the money from her original sale to buy another house while I save money to buy another house.&quot; But at the same time, Xiao Yang threatened his mother with &quot;prosecution&quot; and &quot;mother-child affection&quot;, which made her a little confused. During the court hearing, Yang&#39;s mother requested that the 3.7 million be recognized as a loan, while Xiao Yang requested that it be recognized as a gift from his mother, which seemed to contradict his promise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court ultimately determined that the money was a loan. But even if it is a gift, it is conditional and can be withdrawn. Mother Yang gave the money to her son to buy a house and only wrote his son&#39;s name on it. What she really meant was not &quot;I gave this money to you unconditionally. The house I bought will be written on your name.&quot; You can name it whatever you want.&quot; Instead, &quot;Mom, I have given all my belongings to prepare a wedding room for you. I will live with you. You have to take good care of me when I grow old. I only write your name because I hope you can compare my feelings with mine. Not only do they have the right to live, they should also be respected.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xiao Yangs not only failed to manage intergenerational conflicts and despised the rights/rights of investors, but instead took the initiative to escalate conflicts and regarded their widowed mother as an enemy. Such a move is morally wrong, and it is unfair to weigh the interests and benefits. Sensible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s okay to adhere to individual orientation + small family orientation, and at the same time insist on living independently and rejecting large-amount funding from parents; if you accept large-amount funding from parents, you must respect the rights/powers of the investor, and even You must have the awareness to be a low-key child. Of course, high-profile parents may not intervene, but in this case, not intervening is a sign of affection, not a duty. &quot;Having both&quot; doesn&#39;t work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, this case is also a warning to parents. By raising the children to adulthood, the parents&#39; duty has been completed and the legal responsibilities have been fulfilled. You cannot hand over your old capital to your children casually, and your main assets must be in your own hands. If a child needs a large amount of financial aid, it can be lent in a clear way, stipulating the principal, interest and repayment plan, or at least it should be clear that the parents have the right to claim it back. Don&#39;t let the children feel that their parents&#39; love for them is unconditional and they can take whatever they want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parent-child love must be two-way. It is sad that many parents become the tools of their children, providing money and effort, and then being picked on and stabbed by their young couples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[霞浦：摄影与旅游之间的距离]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/1TJD3qtqOhvQJaFThYraZxJdd9xdF8ml83fADU1S.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/1TJD3qtqOhvQJaFThYraZxJdd9xdF8ml8 3fADU1S. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259981&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take pictures of the sunrise at the seaside of Huazhu Village, Sansha Town, Xiapu County&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Becoming a photography resort&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the sunset was about to dissipate, a group of foreign photographers returned At the B&amp;B on the mountain, we stood on the observation deck facing the coast and chatted. Looking down from the observation deck, there are still tourists taking pictures on the highway bridge at the foot of the mountain. Dongbi Village and Yugongting Village in Sansha Town, Xiapu County are famous for their sunset scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While waiting for the seafood banquet, a local member of the team introduced the owner of this B&amp;B to the photographers, Zheng Dexiong, the president of the Xiapu Photography Association, the person who famously photographed the Xiapu beach. His last introduction was: , &quot;The man who made Xiapu housing prices increase countless times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts are more powerful than words. An abandoned rural self-built house in Sansha Town can be sold for more than 100,000 yuan a year. Rented to B&amp;B owners, if the property rights can be traded, the price of a house can be as high as several million. And B&amp;B owners just for a piece of land, they knocked down their houses and rebuilt them, decorating them carefully. The price for a sea view room per night in the off-season is four figures. The skyrocketing housing prices have become a difficult problem for Sansha people who moved away due to lack of local industries in the early years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After greetings, Zheng Dexiong sat back on the outdoor seat on the other side of the observation deck and was busy planning the shooting schedule for another upcoming photography group. There were two more shoots arranged by the local government the next day. meeting. Everyone who comes to Xiapu for research and inspection wants to meet Zheng Dexiong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Zheng Dexiong, no one focused on tidal flat photography, and almost no one realized that the beautiful scenery of Xiapu was rare enough to be displayed. Zheng Dexiong, who has been engaged in commercial photography since the 1990s, was convinced of the uniqueness of Xiapu scenery after seeing many photos of seaside scenery. In 2002, Zheng Dexiong began photographing the tidal flats in his hometown in his spare time. Two years later, at the suggestion of a friend, he held the first photography exhibition in Xiapu on the street of Longshou Road. He also submitted articles to many photography magazines. His works were repeatedly published and won awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kasumigaura and its tidal flats are famous in the photography circle. Xiapu was rated as &quot;the first of China&#39;s top ten landscape photography holy places&quot;. Photography bases were built in small fishing villages along the coast. Fishermen who were engaged in seafood fishing returned to the shore, and young people who went out to work returned to their hometowns and started the tourism industry from scratch. . Zheng Dexiong remembers that 20 years ago, Xiapu County had only one short street and no foreign population. But now the city has expanded all the way to the seaside, and Taikang Road filled with food stalls is busy until late at night. In 2022, Xiapu, with a population of just over 500,000, received 7.2 million tourists. A few photos changed the fate of a county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s easy to say, but it’s not that simple. Over the past 20 years, we have actually invested a lot in transforming from private power to strong government support and from free services to a business model.” Zheng Dexiong objects to easy generalizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first started photographing the tidal flats, Zheng Dexiong walked along the more than 400 kilometers of Xiapu coastline. It turned out that there were no roads on the shore and it was a barren mountain. He had to bring a machete and a hoe to open a road while walking. When shooting at Shajiang Pier, in order to find a shooting point with a suitable height, he climbed up from the bottom of the mountain. When he reached the top of the mountain, he discovered that there was a stone road built by the village on the other side. Several of Xiapu&#39;s early famous photography spots were discovered by Zheng Dexiong in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Dexiong paid for the early foreign photographers who came to Xiapu with his own money, until he could no longer afford the money. On May 1, 2007, he opened the first paid photography group. A one-week trip for 20 people cost more than 1,000 yuan per person. The local government saw the power of photography in the tourism industry and began to hold national photography competitions and create logos for photography spots. More importantly, the government has taken the lead in gradually building and improving supporting infrastructure for photography spots, including roads, parking lots, and observation decks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, new photography spots are constantly being discovered. The 2017 edition of the &quot;Xiapu Photography Guide&quot; issued by the Xiapu Culture and Tourism Bureau lists 28 photography spots, and the number has increased to 33 in the 2021 edition. The infrastructure and tourism model around the photography spots have not yet been fully finalized, and both locals and tourists are adapting to the differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/xcAgdGZJ83aXw3hloXo7guXtXzsKDTWVPvIFJqAp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/xcAgdGZJ83aXw3hloXo7guXtXzsKDTWVPvIFJqAp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259979&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiapu tidal flat scenery through Zheng Dexiong&#39;s lens&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Perfect Photo&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first people to profit from photography are the characters closely related to the shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Dexiong believes that shooting in Xiapu is a test of skills and experience. &quot;The ebb and flow, changes in light and shadow, the alternation of four seasons, and different labor scenes in each season.&quot; This also means that shooting in Xiapu is uncertain. There are too many factors, including weather, tides, and seasons. The absence of any one element will lead to deviation from the default. Weather and tides can be grasped by experience, while labor scenes out of season can only be reproduced through performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of 2005, a Taiwanese photographer came to Xiapu to take pictures, but the whole series was missing a picture of Xiaohao Village catching fish fry in spring. Considering that it was not easy to travel from Taiwan to the mainland, Zheng Dexiong asked local fishermen to cooperate in posing for photos. This is how the new profession of fishing model was born in Xiapu. To this day, even if no one buys fish fry anymore, the fishing models in Xiaohao Village still hold up a triangular fishing net frame every time they perform - this kind of special-shaped net is specially used to catch fish fry, and because of the award-winning photo shoot There are three fishing models, so the trio is also fixed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Three people make a good photo.” Every time they perform, Bao Xuexian, who is in her fifties, her aunt in her seventies, and her aunt’s brother-in-law will put on knee-length rubber shoes, wearing Put on your straw hat, carry your fishing net and bamboo basket, and walk on the Xiaohao beach after low tide. The photographer would stand on the top of the mountain behind the village and shoot with a telephoto lens from a distance. Bao Xuexian&#39;s uncle Lin Jisong was responsible for reception on the mountain and conveyed the photographer&#39;s instructions to Bao Xuexian and others via radio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance fee for a performance is 300 yuan, and the fishing model costs 100 yuan per person. More than half of the days a month, people will be invited to perform, but Bao Xuexian does not think that fishing models are an enviable job. &quot;Only those who can&#39;t make money become fishing models, and those who can make money go to cultivate oysters and grow seaweed.&quot; &quot;When there are no performances, Bao Xuexian and her aunt weave fishing nets and sell them for money. A two-layered large fishing net sells for 31 yuan, and a three-layered one sells for 42 yuan. They can weave up to two per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Jisong receives guests at the top of the mountain, but does not participate in the distribution of performance fees. He has other income. Most of the people in Xiaohao Village were originally fishermen. Lin Jisong did not know how to fish. 24 years ago, he built a temple on the top of the mountain and made a living by collecting incense money. When fishermen go to sea, life and death are determined by fate, and they will worship gods before leaving. After the Xiaohao Tidal Flat became famous, the government built an observation deck on the top of the mountain, right next to the temple built by Lin Jisong. He felt that the angle of the path on the cliffside was better, so he paved a stone road and placed a few plastic stools. Anyone who goes to take pictures on the stone road must &quot;donate&quot; 10 yuan for the film fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Famous photography spots have regular fishing models, such as Jiang Lianshui in Beiqi Tidal Flat and Lao Cheng in Yangjiaxi. They have taken award-winning photos together and know better than novice photographers about how to take photos. &quot;They all know the angle, focal length, aperture, and speed.&quot; Zheng Dexiong found it very interesting. &quot;Initially, we went to the village to select models. There were no special criteria. They just had to be fishermen.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the government building In front of the roads and observation decks, outsiders who come to take pictures of Xiapu have to find local photographers who know their way around. Photography directors came into being, referred to as photography directors. With supporting facilities in place, photography guides are still needed because outsiders can’t figure out the tide schedule and the best time to take photos at photography spots. Nowadays, the threshold for photography guides is much lower. Not only members of the local photography association, but also taxi drivers, travel agencies and villagers have joined in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, Zheng Dexiong also proposed to the Culture and Tourism Bureau to provide centralized training for people engaged in photography and photography to improve their service awareness and photography skills. Later, there were too many people and it was difficult to coordinate. When he was out shooting, Zheng Dexiong heard the cameraman introducing him to the tourists. They stood face to face and neither could recognize the other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/GTBvngW7gqrVPIMUmksJuIhHm4SEcIpFR8OCw4jE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/GTBvngW7gqrVPIMUmksJuIhHm4SEcIpFR8OCw4jE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259980&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists vacation at a B&amp;B in Dongbi Village, Sansha Town, Xiapu County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;Advantage Judgment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the minds of photographers, different photography spots have different ratings. Zheng Dexiong believes that although Xiaohao Village has the most award-winning films, the scenery does not change much and is the same regardless of the season; Huazhu Village only has sunrise, and the location is best only in winter, which is relatively monotonous; Beiqi Village can be photographed in any season. However, the pole frames for planting seaweed have been moved from the coast to the edge of the inland sea, and the beauty of the tidal flat patterns and pole shadows can no longer be photographed. The coast of his hometown, Dakyo Village, is more suitable for tourism than photography, because there are only beaches in that area and no tidal flats, and tidal flats are the core of Kasumigaura photography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Zheng Dexiong likes most is the east wall. The scenery changes endlessly throughout the year. In 2019, Sansha Town invested 20 million to build a light and shadow plank road to connect the photography spots along the east wall, making this area more popular. When the tide goes out a few days after the first and fifteenth day of the lunar month, more people come to the road. I can&#39;t even stand on either side. The highway bridge where the Dongbi Photography Spot is located is on one side of Dongbi Village and on the other side is Yugongting Village. The two villages have become a gathering place for boutique B&amp;Bs. Zheng Dexiong and his students all stay here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what the photographer thinks, the villagers have their own way of judging their own advantages. Uncle Zhang, the owner of Huazhu in the countryside of Huazhu Village, was originally doing business abroad. In 2020, he returned to the village to run a B&amp;B. He saw the potential of Huazhu. “Huazhu is a scenic spot for watching the sunrise. It is a must-go spot for anyone who comes to Xiapu. You must watch the sunrise. , you will most likely have to stay the night before.&quot; Uncle Zhang currently has 6 rooms, and the price per night is 400 to 600 yuan. According to his statistics, the occupancy rate is about 80%, and it is fully booked almost every day in the peak season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another characteristic of Huazhu is that it is the Hokkien-speaking area of ​​this small town in eastern Fujian. Uncle Zhang talked about the history of Huazhu, starting from three hundred years ago, &quot;Our ancestors were Those who moved from southern Fujian didn’t have big boats before. Fishermen fished along the coast and came all the way along the coast. Maybe they came here to escape the wind and rain. Later, they saw the abundant seafood here and settled down.” Huazhu Village speaks Hokkien and lives in stone houses. , pronounced &quot;厝&quot; in Hokkien. When building the B&amp;B, the village committee required that the exterior appearance must retain the appearance of a house. Uncle Zhang plans to do a crowdfunding project to raise 8 million yuan to build 8 more B&amp;Bs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/UOC1TGi6Zn3AvbzELnYAgfV5g5HwSETROd1qh1iY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/UOC1TGi6Zn3AvbzELnYAgfV5g5HwSETROd1qh1iY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259978&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Xuexian’s aunt is in her seventies. When she is not performing, she makes money by weaving fishing nets&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yang Xin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the light and shadow plank road was built on the east wall, Niulangang Natural Village was gradually lost, but they were not willing to lag behind. Niulangang Village is the opening point of Xiapu’s first boutique B&amp;B CaoMuRen Teahouse. It has always regarded itself as the birthplace of Xiapu B&amp;B and is close to the county seat and the entrance to the highway. The introduction reads: “It is surrounded by mountains and sea, with beautiful scenery and convenient transportation. The location advantage is obvious and the tourism resources are unique.&quot; In the summer of 2023, Niulangang Village began construction to build an asphalt road and a viewing platform on the mountain where B&amp;Bs gather, hoping to regain the limelight as the first choice for tourists in the off-season. However, the construction team still started work during the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day, which caused several negative reviews for surrounding B&amp;Bs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sightseeing route from Gaoluo Beach, Dajing Beach to Hawei Island is named Donghai Route 1. Although there are few photographers, it is the route recommended by everyone in Xiapu. According to the observation of Xiaona, a stall owner on Xiawei Island, the sea caves on Xiawei Island are the internet celebrity photo spots that occupy the high traffic volume of social platforms. Since being photographed by an Internet celebrity at the end of 2021, it has attracted countless tourists. &quot;On May Day, one kilometer of road can be blocked for several hours.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Na and the young people in the stall area They originally worked in the county or around Ningde City. After their hometown became a tourist attraction in the past two years, they came back to set up stalls. &quot;No matter how much or how little you earn, at least you have more freedom.&quot; Xiaona&#39;s husband also came back to work as a photo guide, using his home An idle small off-road vehicle will charge 150 yuan to pick up passengers from Xiawei Island to another nearby scenic spot, the lighthouse; if it is a chartered vehicle, the price per day is 600 yuan, and you can choose Donghai Line 1 or Sansha Dongbi Line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It only takes two days to visit all the popular photography spots in Kasumigaura, and most tour groups’ itineraries are customized within two or three days. Xiaona has heard from many tourists that a three-day and two-night tour that includes transportation, food, and accommodation only costs more than a thousand yuan. “But the tour group doesn’t care about the weather and tides, and skips some spots if you can’t see them. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ttxFP6MudBOg1At6KJCYvZuBEW5ytgpsqAZwwxwM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ttxFP6MudBOg1At6KJCYvZuBEW5ytgpsqAZwwxwM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259977&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the planning of Huazhu Village, the appearance of the B&amp;B should retain the unique stone house style of southern Fujian&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yang Xin/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Uneven&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The most common thing Ou Shao of Beiqi Village hears from tourists is, &quot;Why is it different here from the photos?&quot; ”所以他现在见到游客会提前说明，“到霞浦玩一定要注意天气，天气好跟坏，拍照天差地别。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在郑德雄看来，摄影点和旅游点本身It’s just different. “Some tourists come to the photography spot and feel that there is nothing to see, because photography has requirements on time and light.” The aesthetic perspectives of photographers and tourists are also different. The photographer was on the highway bridge on the east wall. There are three types of landscapes you can take pictures of - the grand landscape of the sunset, the seaweed net on the lake and the lines of the tidal flats under the bridge, but tourists generally only look at the sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ye Yu, who sells coffee under the observation deck of Huazhu Village, remembers that no one in the village cared about the sunrise before. When fishermen go out to catch fish, they go out at high tide and return at high tide. They look at the tide table, which has nothing to do with sunrise and sunset. On New Year&#39;s Day in 2013, CCTV broadcast the sunrise live in Huazhu, which earned Huazhu the title of &quot;China&#39;s Sun Viewing Landmark.&quot; The sunrise footage captured by CCTV was posted on the wall under the observation deck, and a stone tablet was erected next to it: &quot; How blessed to be in the same time and space as this sunrise.&quot; Ye Yu remembered that the CCTV sunrise was filmed by the staff who set up tents on the top of the mountain and lived there for a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beiqi Village was probably the first place to realize the different needs of tourism and photography. The Ou Shao family opened a B&amp;B in the village in 2013, and began taking tourists out to sea for sightseeing and fishing entertainment in 2020. So far, it has developed nearly ten projects, including tourist charters, fishing outings, parent-child trips to the sea, sales of dried seafood, and cage nets. &quot;The passenger flow here is unstable, so we can only develop more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Shao&#39;s family used to be fishermen, and their income from fishing was unstable. &quot;There are not so many fish now, and every May The fishing season is closed from the 1st to August 31st, and large boats can park on the shore.&quot; They considered daily fishing and tourism during the fishing season, and found that it was not cost-effective to only do it for three months. &quot;Do it all year round. If you do this, you will accumulate many old customers.&quot; So they concentrated on the tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Shao’s father now goes out to sea to fish, always accompanying guests on a chartered boat. The price of chartering a boat is 600 yuan, and the catch is uncertain. “It’s okay to catch more or less. Some tourists are Those who have come from the inland have never seen the sea and find it very fresh.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More tourists choose to spend 30 yuan to take a 20-minute boat ride to see the seaweed that has been planted on the edge of the inland sea. The Ou Shao family built a new boat in May 2023, costing 50,000 to 60,000 yuan. The cabin area was specially enlarged to accommodate up to 30 people. There are several families involved in the boat tour project in the village, including Ou Shao&#39;s relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ou Shao was soliciting tourists at the beach, an electric bicycle rode on the village road and he also talked to the tourists on the roadside. I asked Ou Shao, &quot;Is that your relative or a competitor?&quot; Ou Shao replied: &quot;It&#39;s my relative and a competitor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two of them stood guard in front of the entrance of the seaside parking lot, taking turns. Go up and ask the private car coming in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nRn68R4EnzQITldKMsR5Tb86hebJFP3gNZzks7Wm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nRn68R4EnzQITldKMsR5Tb86hebJFP3gNZzks7Wm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Uncle Zhang is making fire hoses for a B&amp;B by hand. He believes that returning to his hometown to build a B&amp;B is a feeling for his hometown&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Characters Weekly reporter Nie Yangxin/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under construction&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all famous photography spots can catch up with the tourism boom. Xiaohao Beach is the earliest famous, but the surrounding areas The supporting facilities and B&amp;B design are lagging behind those of Dongbi and Huazhu on the same line. The B&amp;Bs in Xiaohao Village are concentrated in the new area on the edge of the old village. A large open space from the new area to the seaside is filled with sand, gravel, soil, fishing nets, construction waste and domestic garbage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The B&amp;Bs in Xiaohao Village are mainly self-built houses in rural areas. Villagers rent and sell spare rooms in their own houses. The decoration style of the rooms is basically the bedrooms of ordinary commercial houses. In order to reduce the difficulty of cleaning, a pile of public slippers are placed at the door of each B&amp;B for guests to change into. Such a room costs 300 yuan a night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Muhai B&amp;B is one of the few boutique B&amp;Bs currently in operation. It has floor-to-ceiling glass windows facing the sea and a small outdoor garden. The proprietress Wu Sister-in-law said that the design fee for the B&amp;B cost 60,000 yuan. . Sister-in-law Wu’s husband is a village cadre. When the houses in the new district first started to be decorated in 2018, he suggested that the villagers decorate them in the style of a B&amp;B, but the villagers were unwilling. Sister-in-law Wu said, “Someone asked at that time, and I bought it after all the hard work. If you decorate a house yourself and enjoy it, why should you let others live in it? By the time they want to think about a B&amp;B again, it will be too late.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister-in-law Wu&#39;s B&amp;B will open in 2021, and only 5 of the two floors have been repaired. In the peak season, the price of a suite and bathtub room is as high as thousands of yuan per night, but in the off-season, there are almost no guests. She believes that the supporting facilities around Xiaohao Village have affected the development of B&amp;Bs. “There used to be a parking lot that could park 70 cars, and the roads were beautifully built, but it was demolished in 2021 and has not been built yet.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2021, Xiaohao Village has been caught in a storm of accountability for illegal land occupation and illegal construction in rural areas. After investigation and verification by relevant departments, Xiaohao Village actually built 121 homesteads, of which 61 were built by non-village personnel. It also introduced commercial health care projects and occupied 16 homesteads. In March 2022, information released by relevant departments at higher levels stated that &quot;all illegally sold collective land has been taken back to the village collective, and the land will be restored to its original state after demolition.&quot; The villagers also don&#39;t know what will happen to this empty land filled with waste. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Natural conditions also restrict the development of some photography spots. Although the Xiawei Island Sea Cave is popular, it can only be revealed after low tide. Tourists who want to take pictures have to climb down the seaside rocks with bare hands. A warm reminder in the &quot;Xiapu Photography Guide&quot;, &quot;The reefs on the shore are easily slippery due to corrosion by sea water. It is recommended to wear non-slip shoes and walk slowly. Elderly people with limited mobility should not go there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sea caves are equipped with The rescue workers said, &quot;Every day, tourists slip off the rocks and fall into the sea.&quot; The scenic spot originally wanted to build a wooden boardwalk, but the rocks were severely corroded and broke when nails were hammered in, so they had to give up. &quot;Do you know why the scenic spot doesn&#39;t charge admission tickets? If it does, the compensation (if something happens) will be up to the sky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is nearly 50 kilometers from the county seat to Xiamei Island, and there is a long stretch of road in the middle. It is a gentle mountain road. In recent years, a new road has been built close to the coastline. This road is open even before it is included in the map navigation. Just like the tourism industry here, it seems that it has not yet been completed, but the reception of tourists has already begun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我和物业博弈的这一年：解决问题有多难？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261740]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The fate that every new owner cannot escape is to deal with and confront the property. This is his homework and his of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since I took over the house and became an owner in October last year, I have started to form a front with my neighbors and compete with the property management. Today, the team has collapsed, losing ground, and the rights protection has ended in failure. It&#39;s the same as the mental process of decorating, from being full of emotions to being discouraged, and finally giving up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the house was handed over for inspection, the quality of the house was worrying and many areas needed repairs. However, the developer did not do anything and delayed to solve most of the problems. Until now, the paint surface of the corner of my second bedroom is cracked. The seam is still there intact. This is indeed the developer&#39;s problem. The property management company can only help me communicate my needs, but they belong to the same company, and the property management company has collected property fees early. I have to discuss an explanation with the property management company. It is not unfair at all to take the blame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of fighting with the property owners, each other&#39;s tactics also changed according to the other&#39;s actions, and they continued to see each other&#39;s progress and retreat. If the housekeeper responds politely and politely, I will also communicate politely. If I am tougher, she will get angry at me. More often than not, the housekeeper will use low-grade deception, but I can&#39;t expose her directly. I have to leave a little kindness so that we can meet each other in the future and everything can be discussed. She told lies and fully accepted my needs, saying that she would urge and reflect them, but my problems would not be advanced or solved. She treats me as a fool. If she can evade something, she will do it first. Later problems will be dealt with later. The rhetoric will always be dealt with in a unified manner later. In the end, he couldn&#39;t do anything perfunctorily and ran out of patience. The housekeeper simply stopped making excuses and played the emotional card. She admitted that the developers were rogue and the property management companies were rogue. She only received a salary of a few dollars a month, so how could she have the final say? Without pretending, I was moved by her words that were completely embarrassing, and I began to accept in my heart that this was the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before I paid the property fee, I had to ask the housekeeper to get the key when I opened the door of my house. The owner of the owner group once privately suggested that I replace the lock cylinder and argue with the property management company about when to solve the problem and when to pay. . I didn&#39;t want to take an extreme approach, and I was eager to get a property certificate to install charging piles, so I had no choice but to surrender. Once the money is handed over, it becomes even more difficult to ask them to do something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this year’s negotiations and observations, I found that one of the main job responsibilities of the property management company is to collect fees. As early as September, before the previous year&#39;s property fees were due, the housekeeper started a show of fancy reminders to pay the next year&#39;s property fees. Taking advantage of the fact that the owners were at home at night, the housekeepers divided their forces and went door to door to collect property fees. Everyone among the owners condemned this behavior of only enjoying rights without assuming obligations. A few days later, the property management company sent out a notice with bait, offering free rice and cooking oil if the property management fee was paid during this period. So, I often see the housekeeper walking in the community carrying grain and oil, and watching her retreating back, I wonder, if the execution of solving problems is so touching, why are we here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a year of fighting, my interest in fighting for the rights of my neighbors has slowly cooled down. Recently, there have been voices in the group that want to replace the property, but I no longer have such high expectations for the final result. Confrontation between property owners and property owners has become the norm. I am afraid that my property and I, as well as the domestic property management industry, still have a long, long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an employee of a state-owned enterprise in Hangzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to you Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香港仔：太平山B面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261712]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Take the green-painted Star Ferry from Tsim Sha Tsui. Rows of high-rise buildings slowly approach and zoom in. Behind them The Taiping Mountains are spread out like a belt, rising and falling gently in the porthole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original name of Taiping Mountain is Hard Head Mountain, also known as Xianglu Peak. It was renamed because after the surrender of the great thief Zhang Baozai during the Jiaqing period of the Qing Dynasty, the residents of Hong Kong Island thought that there would be peace from now on. In a broad sense, Taipingshan is composed of Mount Chechi, Lufeng Gorge, Gough Hill, Kwun Lung Kok and Mount Keli; in a narrow sense, it refers to Mount Chechi, the highest peak on Hong Kong Island with an altitude of 554 meters. There are two theories about what flag-pulling is: one is that Cheung Po-tsai raised the flag as a signal when he was a thief and commanded the people at the bottom of the mountain to rob merchant ships; the other is that in 1841, the British army occupied Hong Kong Island and raised the Union Jack here. Austin, who served as Colonial Secretary of Hong Kong from 1868 to 1878, named the mountain Mount Austin, and later renamed it Victoria Peak after the Queen of England (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;Victoria Peak&lt;/span>;) and is still used today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After living in Shenzhen for more than 20 years, I have traveled to Hong Kong many times and visited Victoria Peak. To be precise, it is the crowded places on the north bank of Victoria Peak such as Central, Admiralty, Causeway Bay, and The Peak. Among Hong Kong people, the Peak refers specifically to Victoria Peak, and there is no ambiguity. However, most tourists today mistake the cable car terminal and Lingxiao Pavilion area for the top of the mountain. In fact, it is called Lufeng Gorge. Even for me, it was a few months ago that I walked through the slightly deserted Austin Mountain Road and climbed to the top of the real mountain for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the observation deck on the top of the mountain, leaning on the railing and overlooking the sky, the north bank is surrounded by red dust and glitz; on the south bank, countless low hills seem to be eager to embrace the South China Sea... If the noise and commotion were the Taiping Mountains The A side of Taiping Mountain, then, silence and tranquility are the B side of Taiping Mountain. A green mountain magically captures a completely different contrast. Unfortunately, due to other arrangements, I had no time to get close to Nan&#39;an Fangze that day. This time, Aberdeen, Hong Kong, where I made a special trip, is located in the center of Side B of Victoria Peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian looking at Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for Hong Kong Village&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;At Admiralty, transfer to the MTR South Island Line. One stop will bring you to the famous Ocean Park in Hong Kong, and then take a short shuttle bus to the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel you booked. Speaking of which, I am no stranger to Fullerton. Many years ago, I stayed at the Fullerton Hotel in Singapore on a business trip. It was a neoclassical building completed in 1928. It is as legendary as the Peace Hotel in Shanghai. I still remember that the passage on the ground floor leads directly to the Merlion, the landmark of the Lion City. The Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel where I stayed this time is located in the geometric center of the south bank of Victoria Peak. When the bus turned around and got rid of the noisy city, the transparent windows were suddenly filled with green mountains and blue and white sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Aberdeen location map courtesy Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260441 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Aberdeen location map&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hotel faces the sea, on the left hand side, dozens of steps away, is 2021 The Ocean Park Water Park, Asia&#39;s first all-weather seaside water park, opened in 2016, has layers of recreational facilities that spread over the entire hillside like terraces. On the right, two breakwaters piled with rocks are as gray as scratches, collecting the treasures of the rich. &quot;Toys&quot; - yachts and sailing boats; and directly ahead, Ap Lei Chau, which looks like a duck swimming in water, has half its head and body buried in the sea, vividly dividing the sea area connecting Victoria Harbor and the South China Sea into There are two waterways, wide and narrow: within Ap Lei Chau, the narrower one is called Aberdeen Strait, which is used by small boats; outside, the wider one is called East Lamma Strait, which is used by large ships. Stop for a moment, and before your eyes, you can see the endless busyness of various ocean-going ships and the slow and leisurely pace of various yachts and sailing boats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;View of Ap Lei Chau from The Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel. Photography by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/dc6241d429.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/dc6241d429.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;260442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Ap Lei Chau from the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel. &amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entrance to Aberdeen Country Park is on Nam Fung Road near Ocean Park. Like Hong Kong citizens, hiking in Aberdeen Country Park is one of my bucket list for this trip. Unexpectedly, after walking a few steps along Nanfeng Road, I encountered a small black and white road sign with an arrow pointing north to &quot;Wong Chuk Hang Stone Carvings 250m Meters&quot;. Soon, on the north side of the Jockey Club Science Building, behind a stack of easily overlooked cement steps and next to a rushing stream, I saw the Wong Chuk Hang rock carvings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a relic dating back about 3,500 years. A yellow mountain cliff stands on the right bank of the creek. Although it has been weathered and eroded, three groups of slightly blurred swirling patterns on the six or seven square meters of rock surface still look like the eyes of an animal staring at me as I &quot;break in&quot;. This reminds me of the similar Shang and Zhou bronzes &lt;span>;Taotie pattern&lt;/span>;. Taotie is a vicious and greedy monster in ancient Chinese mythology. &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; believes: &quot;Greed for money is gluttony, gluttony is gluttony.&quot; In modern times, with the rise of peace, its meaning has become a description of a foodie who is fond of delicious food. As for the Taotie pattern, it first appeared on the pottery and jade of the Liangzhu Culture in the lower reaches of the Yangtze River. Because the patterns often have heads but no bodies, they are also called &quot;animal face patterns.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perusing the on-site cultural relics plaque, I learned that there are nine ancient stone carvings in Hong Kong. Only two existing ones on the south coast of Hong Kong Island are Tai Long Bay and Wong Chuk Hang. Among them, the Tai Long Wan Stone Carvings were the first to be listed as a statutory monument (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978&lt;/span>;), while the Wong Chuk Hang Stone Carvings are the only ones located inland. , stone carvings far away from the coast. So, why is the stone at this moment? According to my judgment, if the stream under my feet has flowed forever, this is probably the place where ancestors worshiped water sources and drew fresh water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where there is fresh water, there must be villages. When I turned back along the original road, I noticed that the stream took advantage of the grass and rocks to penetrate into the underground culvert of Nanfeng Road and disappeared without a trace. Fortunately, there is a blue sign reading &quot;Old Walled Village&quot; erected at the opposite intersection, eye-catchingly pointing to the Nanfeng Trail branching off from Nanfeng Road. &quot;Wei&quot; is a common name for villages in Lingnan in the past. It not only means &quot;gathering people here&quot;, but also has an &quot;image summary&quot; of the walls and houses built in the village. Jiuwei and Laowei are equivalent to the old villages and old villages in the north, and refer to the villages with the longest history in the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The full name of Jiu Wai Village is Wong Chuk Hang Jiu Wai, because of the ravine with flowing water in the former village (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; span>;) is named after the broom-shaped yellow bamboos that grow all over the place. However, according to Ye Lingfeng&#39;s book &quot;Hong Kong Stories&quot;, Jiuwei Village was first called Hong Kong Village or Hong Kong Wai. It is recorded in ancient books such as &quot;Yue Da Ji·Guangdong Coastal Map&quot; by Wanli in the Ming Dynasty and &quot;Xin&#39;an County Chronicle&quot; by Kangxi in the Qing Dynasty. At that time, the production and sales of Wanxiang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;referring to the agarwood produced in Dongguan, Shenzhen, Hong Kong and other areas today) were booming, and this area became prosperous. As the initial distribution center. As late as 1866, the &quot;Comprehensive Map of Xin&#39;an County&quot; printed in Leipzig, Germany still marked the name of the village &quot;Hong Kong Wai&quot;. The name of Hong Kong today &quot;was gradually popularized based on the name of this small village.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south wind path is not long, and the old walled village is huddled on the steep slope at the end. The lower slope is filled with vehicles; the upper slope is incredibly covered with squatter houses made of iron sheets. Entering the village and walking around, except for a small Buddhist hall and a small mountain shrine that were dimly lit by incense, I didn&#39;t find any ancient meaning. I asked the grandmother who tended the vegetable garden and learned that many years ago, the Aberdeen Tunnel Toll Station and Wong Chuk Hang Hospital were built, and the old houses were demolished. While I was talking, suddenly, four or five big yellow dogs came close to me and barked at me. When I was young, my experience in fighting dogs in the countryside came in handy. I forced myself to stay calm and made steady progress. At this time, I saw a bamboo pavilion and a nest of slender bamboos at the entrance of the village, which perfectly echoed the name of the village in Wong Chuk Hang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The swimming pool of the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel faces the East Lamma Strait. Photo courtesy of Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/02/d712e53ef0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ d712e53ef0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The swimming pool of the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel faces the East Lamma Strait. &amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hiking in Aberdeen&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Returning to Nanfeng Road, after hiking for several miles, I plunged into the Aberdeen Country Park embrace. As you walk higher and farther, your body and mind rise and fall with the mountains, as if you are immersed in the fragrance of the forest and the occasional singing of birds. Aberdeen Country Park is one of the first country parks in Hong Kong. It was established in 1977 and covers an area of ​​about 423 hectares. It encompasses the Nip Ko Sun, Cameron Highlands, Ban Na and Tin Wan mountains from east to west. The hiking trails in between are connected with those elsewhere, and can reach the entire Hong Kong Island. At the end of the 19th century, the old houses in Jiuwei Village were still there, and the surrounding fields and grassy fields attracted visitors from Victoria City (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today’s Central and Sheung Wan, Hong Kong High-ranking officials, wealthy businessmen, gentlemen and ladies from the area (&lt;/span>;) came in droves to spend time. The more people walking, the more roads there are in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbing to the mountainside, a water diversion channel (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Aqueduct&lt;/span>;), which is more than 1 meter wide and deep, is clearly visible. Eyes, U-shaped bottom trickling gurgling. As we all know, fresh water in Hong Kong is poor, especially on Hong Kong Island. In order to alleviate the tension, in the 1960s, Guangdong Province successively built the Shenzhen Reservoir and the Dongjiang-Shenzhen Water Supply Project to provide support. The Hong Kong government excavated diversion channels and other facilities in the mountains to collect spring water and rainwater, and then directed them into reservoirs (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That is, the reservoir&lt;/span>;). Today, aqueducts and reservoirs have become &quot;standard features&quot; in almost all country parks in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Lady King&#39;s Horse Racing Trail offers a bird&#39;s eye view of the center of Aberdeen. &amp;nbsp; Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the water diversion channel turned around and rushed down the pit, at the feet, the road surface of Mrs. Jin’s Horse Racing Trail changed from gravel to loess. Mrs. King&#39;s Horse Racing Trail, also known as Mrs. Gold&#39;s Trail, is named after the wife of the 17th Hong Kong Governor Clementi Clementi. It is about 5 kilometers in length, and some sections overlap with the famous Hong Kong Island Trail. Mrs. King&#39;s name was Mary Ayers. She was born in 1889 and later moved to Hong Kong with her father, Admiral C.J. Ayers. In 1912, she married Clementi, who was 14 years older than her. The two were deeply in love as a couple and loved traveling and Chinese culture. Clementi was even promoted to Governor of Hong Kong in 1925 because of this. During his tenure, Clementi worked hard to eliminate the negative impact of the general strike in the province and Hong Kong on Hong Kong, improve relations with the mainland, and promote Chinese education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under his initiative, the University of Hong Kong established a Chinese Department in 1927 and invited a group of former Qing Dynasty officials to teach old classics. Unexpectedly, this move aroused verbal and written criticism from figures in the New Culture Movement such as Lu Xun and Hu Shi. What is right and what is wrong has changed with time. However, it is also an indisputable fact that the Department of Chinese Language and Literature of the University of Hong Kong set off a trend of attaching importance to Chinese education, and later emerged famous literary figures such as Zhang Ailing, Huang Zhan, and Lin Xi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to official duties, Clementi often accompanied his wife on horseback riding outings here to appreciate the mountains and seas of Aberdeen. Writer Liu Kexiang pointed out in &quot;Three Quarters of Hong Kong&quot; that in winter, there are six to seven hundred &quot;mountain eagles&quot; in the Aberdeen Country Park area. &lt;/span>;) favored urban green fields&quot;. Maybe I came a little early in the season and only saw a few flying birds. But the Clementi couple should have seen the scene of the eagle circling and covering the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hiking in Nanlang Mountain, photo provided by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/27c1665f22.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/27c1665f22.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Hiking in Nanlang Mountain&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Dan Family and Seafood Fang&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;At this moment, at 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, I arrived at the Buchang Bay Pier and was immediately surrounded by ships on the sea and shipyards on the shore. At this time, the sun jumped down from Yuguishan, the main peak of Ap Lei Island on the opposite side, catching red, blue, green and white reflections to fight. In a daze, I was placed in the background of a certain Hong Kong movie, which was a bit outdated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bu Ching Bay is adjacent to Tai Shue Wan, where the Fullerton Hotel is located, to the south and Sham Wan to the north. Many online posts explain that Buchang Bay got its name from the many garment factories that used to be there. In fact, this is not the case. According to my on-site observation, &quot;cloth factory&quot; should be a homophonic corruption of &quot;bunchang&quot;. Yangjiang Pichang, the hometown of Guan Shanyue, the master of traditional Chinese painting, is a wharf close to the sea and wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian on a sampan swimming from Shenwan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ 474c20fddd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/474c20fddd.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;260446&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Sampans swimming from the other side of Shenwan&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shaoqing, the other side of Shenwan A small boat with a red hood swam up, with yellow flags on all sides, fluttering in the wind. After getting on the boat and sitting down, we found that the tent was full of decorations: red lanterns, artificial flowers and plants, and small &quot;ten thousand flags&quot; with the names of Hong Kong places. As soon as the boat started to sail, it swayed slightly. Grandma Zhu, who was driving the boat, said proudly: &quot;This sampan is the most beautiful one on the water in Aberdeen, Hong Kong.&quot; The most handsome among the people on the water in Aberdeen.&quot; The boat made a beautiful arc, the motor hummed, and headed in the direction it came from. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people on the water are called &lt;span>;對&lt;/span>; in the mainland and are mainly distributed along the southeast coast. Historically, the Dan family had various names, such as Yaiyazi, Baishuilang, Danmin, 蜑, Zhi, Yaohu, etc. Until the Tang and Song Dynasties, they were collectively called &quot;獍&quot;. Liu Zongyuan&#39;s &quot;Lingnan Jiedushijuntang Ji&quot; of the Tang Dynasty is the earliest document in which &quot;獍&quot; appears. Regarding the views on the origin of the Dan family, scholar Chen Xujing has made statistics, and there are as many as thirty kinds. Among them, the most romantic ones: first, they are derived from the mermaids, or mermaids; second, they are the descendants of Fan Li and Xi Shi of the Yue Kingdom in the Spring and Autumn Period. The generally accepted view is that the Dan family are descendants of the Baiyue people who fled the country during the Qin Emperor and Han Dynasty&#39;s expedition to the southeast. The &quot;Lingwai Daida&quot; written by Zhou Qufei of the Southern Song Dynasty said: &quot;Those who use boats as houses, regard water as land, and float on rivers and seas are Dan&quot;; Yang Wanli&#39;s &quot;Poems of Dan Households&quot; says: &quot;God divides his life by water. , taught him to step on the waves since he was a child. When cooking crabs as food, you can recognize rice, and when you gather bananas for cloth, you don’t need gauze.&quot; Since the 1950s, Dan families from the mainland have come ashore to settle one after another, but there are still survivors in Hong Kong and Macao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Grandma Zhu did not agree with the views in the book. She told me that in the past, people and boats on the water were too small to raise pigs and cows, so we had to raise chickens, ducks and geese. People on the shore come to the beach to buy eggs. After a long time, they call the people on the water &quot;Dan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tongdan&lt;/span>;) home. &quot;If my mother were still alive and heard about the Dan family, she would curse people. It&#39;s so taboo.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Pang Mian, Granny Zhu, who has been driving a sampan all her life&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Grandma Zhu who has been driving sampans all her life&amp;nbsp; Photography Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1841, when the British army first came, Chen Qun, a Dan family member, was asked to lead the way. When passing through Hong Kong Village, when asked about the name of the place, Chen Qun, who had a Dan family accent, answered &quot;Kang Kong&quot;, so the British army recorded it as &quot;Hong Kong&quot;. Of course, this is just a legend. As far as I know, in 1793, when the British Macartney mission left China, relevant reports already mentioned &quot;HongKong&quot;: &quot;Lingding (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Now Shenzhen&lt;/span>;) and Hong Kong are suitable for colonization.&quot; But no matter what, this legend also reflects the relationship between Hong Kong and the Dan family. As for the origin of Aberdeen, it is also related to this legend: after Hong Kong became the name of the entire island, in order to avoid confusion, the people changed the name to &quot;Aberdeen&quot;, that is, &quot;Little Hong Kong&quot;. Later, the British Hong Kong government changed the English name of Aberdeen from &quot;LittleHongKong&quot; to Aberdeen (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Aberdeen&lt;/span>;) to commemorate the George Hamilton-Gordon, the fourth Earl of Aberdeen and British Foreign Secretary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boat entered the deep bay, revealing an empty water surface, with a huge neon sign reading &quot;Welcome&quot; coldly. A little far away, there is a dim painted boat - Taibai Seafood Boat - moored, like an aging lady reminiscing about her youth. &quot;The original location of Jumbo Seafood Restaurant,&quot; Grandma Zhu said, and the guests turned their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 1930, the Dan family from Guangzhou brought the &quot;Getang Chu&quot; to Aberdeen. This kind of floating restaurant that combines singing, dancing, entertainment and sightseeing, coupled with the famous local fresh seafood, quickly became popular. Even a number of cultural celebrities who visited Hong Kong from the south, such as Hu Shi and Cai Yuanpei, came here to enjoy the aroma, follow the smell, invite friends and company, and enjoy the food here. After entering the 1950s, there were more than ten upgraded versions of the &quot;Getang Chu&quot; seafood boats. In 1971, a fire broke out during the decoration of Jumbo Seafood Restaurant and was seriously damaged. When Macau gambling king Stanley Ho heard the news, the Dan family gene in his bones awakened (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;his great-grandmother was a Dan family&lt;/span>;), he formed a partnership with others and made huge investments It was bought and renovated for more than 30 million Hong Kong dollars. In 1976, the Zhenbao Seafood Restaurant, designed in the style of the Ming Dynasty palace and able to accommodate more than 2,300 people, opened. A few years later, Stanley Ho acquired his biggest competitors, Taibai Seafood Restaurant and Haijiao Palace. The world&#39;s largest restaurant at sea - Treasure Kingdom was born, becoming a feasting landmark in Hong Kong. At that time, when politicians and celebrities visited Hong Kong, they all came here to &quot;check in.&quot; Grandma Zhu, a young and vigorous woman, earns over 10,000 yuan a month by ferrying guests to and from people on a ferry boat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, the glorious era of the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot; was also the period when Hong Kong films were at their peak and most prosperous. From Bruce Lee to Jackie Chan, from &quot;Enter the Dragon&quot; to &quot;Infernal Affairs 2&quot;, this place has become a popular filming location for Hong Kong films. Especially in &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;, the scene where Stephen Chow flutters in white clothes, steps on the clear waves, and flies through a broken window has left a deep memory for star fans. By the way, the real shooting location of &quot;God of Cookery&quot; was at Taibai Seafood Restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, the Asian financial crisis severely damaged the &quot;Jewel Kingdom&quot;. Haijiao Palace first closed down and then moved to Qingdao. From then on, the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot; went from bad to worse. In 2022, the Jumbo Seafood Boat towed away from Hong Kong was swallowed up by wind and waves near the Paracel Islands in the South China Sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo courtesy of Pang Mian, Taibai Seafood Restaurant, the filming location of &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02 /fc2b691b61.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/fc2b691b61.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;260448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Taibai Seafood Restaurant, the filming location of &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Typhoon Shelter View Sunset&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Crossing the Ap Lei Chau Bridge, more and more water birds appeared, flapping their wings up and down to welcome us. Guests constantly stood on the bow of the boat to take selfies, capturing the moment of being in the same frame with the water birds. The girl next to me also excitedly held up her mobile phone and looked around, but she didn&#39;t know which one to take a good picture of. &quot;Look, there is a big fake bird beside the boat.&quot; We looked along the girl&#39;s fingertips. Perhaps the sea breeze carried her words, and the &quot;fake bird&quot; instantly &quot;resurrected&quot;, twisted its long neck, and &quot;glared&quot; at us. Amid roars of laughter, the Aberdeen Typhoon Shelter arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original meaning of a typhoon shelter is a water surface where small and medium-sized boats can temporarily take shelter from typhoons. When Aberdeen was still called Seac Pai Wan, the Dan family was already engaged in fishing and short-distance water transport here, and participated in the bulk transshipment of stones, incense, etc. But what I saw before me was unexpected. It was clearly a floating city on the water. Vegetable selling boat, shop boat, house boat, repair boat, trafficking boat, ferry boat, marine police boat, fish collecting boat, sightseeing boat, catering boat, cleaner&#39;s boat, selling seafood Ships, luxurious ships, simple ships, dilapidated ships, brand new ships, hurried ships, slow and leisurely ships... I can&#39;t help but think of American William C. Hunter&#39;s comments on the Pearl River Estuary 198 years ago. Description: “The river was crowded with local boats... In addition, there were sampans and ferries plying to and from Henan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;South Bank of the Pearl River&lt;/span>;) , there are also some barber boats and boats selling various food, clothes, toys and daily necessities sold in shops on the shore.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma Zhu slowed down and moved closer to a sampan with pots and stoves on it. Over there, they waved their hands early; here, Grandma Zhu praised &quot;Business is good&quot; and resumed the boat&#39;s speed. It turned out that it was a &quot;fenzai boat&quot; that specialized in selling fish egg noodles and roasted pork noodles. In the 1960s and 1970s, Aberdeen&#39;s fishery production reached its peak, and &quot;pink boats&quot; became very popular and could be seen everywhere in typhoon shelters. In addition to frequent visits by fishermen and sailors, citizens and tourists also come here and wave for boats on the shore. Now, there are still three or two boats doing it from time to time. &quot;It depends on your luck whether you can eat or not.&quot; Grandma Zhu continued, &quot;This boat is the most popular on the Char Siu River (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Powder&lt;/span>;). Right.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What also needs to be &quot;checked for luck&quot; is the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival in the typhoon shelter. According to Grandma Zhu, the Zhu Daxian worshiped at the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival is Zhu Bajie. Because he served as the Grand Marshal of Tianpeng and was in charge of the Tianhe River, he was regarded as the god of the sea by the people on the water in Aberdeen and recognized as &quot;Master Qi&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Godfather&lt;/span>;)&quot;, whose status is second only to Queen Mazu. Among all the Jiao festivals in Hong Kong and Macao, only the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival is held entirely at sea every year, so it is also called the Jiao Festival on the water. Since the meeting period is not fixed, when to hold the meeting has to be determined in advance. Whether you can enjoy the prosperity depends entirely on luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the countless boats, we found one, no, two Zhu Daxian Temples. It looks like it was transformed from a double-decker cruise ship, with a towering flagpole on the cabin and a fluttering yellow triangular red flag against the setting sun. The reason why there are two, Granny Zhu explained, is because &quot;Old Zhu Daxian&quot; needs to lead &quot;New Zhu Daxian&quot; to get familiar with the personnel of the typhoon shelter. After a few days, the shift will be completely handed over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Watching the sunset on a sampan is one of the &quot;compulsory courses&quot; for traveling in Aberdeen. Photo provided by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/fae0742e11.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/fae0742e11.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Sitting on a sampan to watch the sunset is one of the &quot;compulsory courses&quot; for traveling in Aberdeen. &amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the boat with great excitement, we passed by the &quot;ruins&quot; of Zhenbao Seafood Boat again. The night rose, submerging the neon sign in a mass of black shadow. And ahead, the lights are bright and brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>