<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[鲁迅 不会挖矿的医生不是好作家丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257470]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 09:26:20 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鲁迅：我这一辈子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257328]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/23/RYvzS4EwCdyaokXiS3BOILQxoYZCXlcUS7N3Tpsh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;22120&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/RYvzS4EwCdyaokXiS3BOILQxoYZCXlcUS 7N3Tpsh. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251689&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[监测排泄物的成果获另类诺奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257537]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/cn1wfGSFo6MykZdwYGLmjOCTbBCbHdcGGhZBsIPT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/cn1wfGSFo6MykZdwYGLmjOCTbBCbHdcGG hZBsIPT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October of each year is when the Nobel Prize is announced, but before the Nobel Prize, there is also an alternative Nobel Prize (IgNobel Prizes), also known as the Ig Nobel Prize. The award will also announce the winning projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several of this year’s alternative Nobel Prizes just announced are related to human health and life. First, the Public Health Award goes to Stanford urologist Park Seung-min for his invention of the Stanford toilet: a &quot;smart toilet&quot; that can monitor health conditions such as urinary tract infections, diabetes and others by analyzing a user&#39;s urine and feces. signs of disease. Additionally, toilet-mounted sensors can identify users based on the unique characteristics of each person&#39;s anus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second prize in medicine was awarded to the team of Natasha Mesinkovska, a dermatologist at the University of California, Irvine. He and his team members carefully observed the noses of human corpses and determined whether there were the same number of nasal hairs in each nostril. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Alternative Nobel Prize has been awarded since 1991. It is an interesting imitation of the Nobel Prize and rewards achievements in 10 aspects. Its name comes from the combination of Ignoble and Nobel Prize. The organizer is the scientific humor magazine &quot;Annals of Improbable Research&quot; (Annals of Improbable Research), and some of the judges are real Nobel Prize winners. The aim is to select studies that &quot;make you laugh at first and then thought-provoking&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 Alternative Nobel Prize for Public Health is not just laughable, but indeed innovative and practical. Disease prevention is better than disease treatment, this is the consensus of everyone. Annual physical exams are just a means of prevention. But even this kind of physical examination is considered daunting by many people, because it is not only troublesome to draw blood, defecate and defecate (urinate and defecate), but also requires a special visit to a hospital or physical examination company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the invention of smart toilets may solve these problems and make physical examinations easier, especially for urine and feces examinations, which can predict and predict people&#39;s physical conditions and what diseases may occur. sign. Urine itself can reflect various conditions of the urinary system. When inflammation, stones, tuberculosis, tumors, kidney transplant rejection, renal failure, etc. occur, the composition of urine will change; when certain diseases cause changes in blood composition, Corresponding changes in the composition of urine may also occur, such as diabetes, pancreatitis, jaundice, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stool can reflect more conditions of the body. You can know whether there is inflammation and infection in the digestive tract and the bile ducts leading to the digestive tract, including parasitic infections; There is no bleeding caused by lesions, and when colon tumors or ulcerative colitis occur, bloody stools are the main symptom; the fecal occult blood test (chemical method or immunological method) can detect bleeding that cannot be identified with the naked eye, and can also be used as the first step in the general screening of digestive tract tumors. Screening means; through bacterial culture or microscopy, the intestinal tract can be checked for pathogenic bacteria (such as typhoid bacilli, salmonella, dysentery bacilli) to prevent and treat intestinal infectious diseases; it can assist in the diagnosis of certain hepatobiliary diseases, such as obstructive jaundice The stool is clay-colored, and small stones can be detected in the stool when suffering from cholelithiasis; the digestion status of food in the gastrointestinal tract can be understood. For example, oil droplets in the stool indicate maldigestion and absorption of fat, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smart toilet comprehensively detects and quickly analyzes human excrement through a series of high-end technologies such as test strips, computer vision systems, cameras, and image recognition. It also combines artificial intelligence, so it can detect the size of a person. It&#39;s fast and convenient. However, what needs to be confirmed is whether the detection results of this smart toilet are accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This detection is similar to the original invention to detect cell-free DNA (cfDNA). cfDNA is a DNA fragment discharged into the blood by human cells, with a length of about 167 base pairs. The content in the blood is very low, and it mainly comes from dead somatic cells. Cancer patients have higher cfDNA content in the blood, which comes from dead tumor cells in their bodies. These cfDNA from tumors are called circulating tumors (ctDNA), which can be used as one of the biomarkers for detecting cancer. Now many medical examination companies have also launched ctDNA testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another function of cfDNA is to detect fetal abnormalities. Human embryos will also discharge some DNA into the blood, called cell-free fetal DNA (cffDNA), which enters the maternal blood circulation through apoptotic trophoblast cells shed from placental tissue. In 1997, Professor Lo Yuk-ming from Hong Kong, China, discovered that cffDNA could be extracted from the blood of pregnant women to diagnose fetal malformations, such as congenital dementia (Down syndrome). He is also known as the founder of non-invasive DNA prenatal testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;non-invasive prenatal diagnosis&quot; (NIPT) technology invented by Lu Yuming has been widely used in more than 60 countries and regions around the world for many years. Because this kind of test is simpler and more user-friendly, it does not require a large amount of blood to be drawn or amniotic fluid puncture, which saves pregnant women a lot of trouble and risks. For this reason, Lu Yuming was awarded the &quot;2022 Lasker Clinical Medicine Award&quot;. This is one of the most prestigious awards in the medical field, known as the &quot;Nobel Weather Vane&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the smart toilet that won the Alternative Nobel Prize this year can accurately diagnose urinary tract infections, diabetes and even tumors by analyzing the user&#39;s urine and feces, it will undoubtedly be the first Alternative Nobel Prize in recent years. The trend is that this award will become more and more practical, not just what people think of as &quot;funny&quot;. As for whether it will become another benchmark for the Nobel Prize, that is another matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又丧气又温暖，这纪录片真神奇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257434]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;In 2021, Martin Scorsese once He teamed up with Netflix to produce a biographical comedy documentary &quot;Pretend This Is a City.&quot; The film stars Martin&#39;s longtime friend, writer and critic Fran Lebowitz. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fran, who has a strong intellectual aura, is enough to make those who love her happy when she walks on the streets of New York. But she herself was furious because other people were always in a hurry, rushing around, and had no idea what &quot;citywalk&quot; meant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/b2b360a7ba13d4c9eee7aeea83ad8ae0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;581&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/b2b360a7ba13d4c9eee7aeea83ad8ae0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251671&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Fran Perhaps she didn&#39;t realize that there were people like her on the streets of New York, also observing the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This person also made his observations into a series of videos called &quot;How to Make One Hundred Thousand by John Wilson&quot;. From the first season of 2020 to the third season of this year, it has been widely praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/e702c88a0f36cf922e540af603401509.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1046&quot; height= &quot;548&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/e702c88a0f36cf922e540af603401509.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251669&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three-season ratings always Stable at 9 points or above, the Rotten Tomatoes score is 100% fresh every quarter. Netizens commented that &quot;if the earth is destroyed, there will be one video left for aliens to understand human beings, and this is it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;John Wilson, an i-person (introverted personality trait) whose main theme is mourning and who has a bit of positive energy from time to time, wears many hats from director, starring, photography to narration, and has made A unique personal vlog in this era: weird, nonsensical, depressing, but inexplicably warm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/a64cc804c0e1636b89d0878c2c4748a1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;731&quot; height= &quot;411&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/a64cc804c0e1636b89d0878c2c4748a1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251667&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Documentary Quarterly 6 episodes, each episode is about 30 minutes. There is no limit to the topic, including brain training content such as &quot;how to make small talk&quot; and &quot;how to improve memory&quot;, as well as life-oriented content such as &quot;how to cook the perfect risotto&quot; and &quot;how to appreciate wine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this is by no means a scientific and educational video. Even if you watch it carefully, you will not be able to master these skills. Because documentaries are wild and unconstrained, they often go off topic at great lengths, and occasionally focus on a &quot;life flow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the first episode of the third season, John summarized his experience in finding a public toilet in New York. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-cleaning toilets can be used for 15 minutes by inserting a 25-cent coin, but the quantity is very small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/cf5a8e9ed817dbd56d0bd5f64040caae.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;324&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/cf5a8e9ed817dbd56d0bd5f64040caae.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251672&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From Trash You can use the merchant&#39;s bathroom by picking up receipts, but it&#39;s a bit unethical to rummage through the trash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/097c7d1c49bd73027a1d41dc91c28902.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;631&quot; height= &quot;376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/097c7d1c49bd73027a1d41dc91c28902.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251670&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can&#39;t find it At that time, most people will choose all-purpose plastic bottles to solve the problem, but leaving a bottle on the ground from time to time hinders the appearance of the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/cf54c63fc22eb7955fa5f37910f099fb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;747&quot; height= &quot;417&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/cf54c63fc22eb7955fa5f37910f099fb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251668&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Or directly from Address the problem at its source – reduce the urge to urinate by injecting Botox into the bladder. This is too cruel. If it is not necessary, who would be willing to try it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/3f15b224e0de2b9c07ae7c6d018d3bf4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;696&quot; height= &quot;382&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/3f15b224e0de2b9c07ae7c6d018d3bf4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251673&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All of the above, On the surface, it seems that John is teaching everyone how to solve the problem of going to the toilet outside, but in fact he is conveying his observations and thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;John is an unconventional person. He has worked as a private detective, photographer, and film and television migrant worker. His rich experience makes the painting style of his works unique. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/f47163e9b8e7bf3bfcb7b92ed3c7bd9d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height= &quot;399&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/f47163e9b8e7bf3bfcb7b92ed3c7bd9d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And common The vlog is different. John rarely appears in front of his camera, and his dubbing is not cadenced. He uses the calmest tone, but he can always say the most unexpected lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/e6613df7c45303bd0bae692c705581bf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/e6613df7c45303bd0bae692c705581bf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251674&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Episode 2 It&#39;s called &quot;How to Clean Your Ears&quot;, and the first two minutes are quite to the point, honestly talking about the ear-picking process, but as he goes on, John gets to the issue of noise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/e30a0923baed2ee2243c8496d874dc52.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height= &quot;223&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/e30a0923baed2ee2243c8496d874dc52.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ears sharp , the noise becomes clearer. The sound of cars and yelling and cursing at any time and anywhere are uncomfortable. If the neighbors do not understand the rules and hold a party in the middle of the night, the workers will not be able to sleep at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can escaping the city solve it? Even in the so-called &quot;Utopia&quot; where the use of electronic devices is not allowed, various frictions between landlords and tenants, landlords and wives are still constant. Once one problem is solved, there will always be another problem waiting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/418d30e8d653786e815f4f90f4938881.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;370&quot; height= &quot;206&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/418d30e8d653786e815f4f90f4938881.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;John finally got Conclusion: &quot;Everyone has a different definition of what a reasonable volume is. Even if you manage to find a quiet place, it won&#39;t be quiet for long...because no matter how far you move, you can never escape. Noise is the sound in your head.&amp;nbsp;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you think about it carefully, this can be regarded as contemporary Ah Q&#39;s spiritual victory method. If you can&#39;t beat it, accept it. Otherwise, what else can you do? This series seems like people who have been drained of energy by work and life are trying to regain their youth and vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/3237514351a1c0fcbfe835e6176db284.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;374&quot; height= &quot;209&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/3237514351a1c0fcbfe835e6176db284.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the third In the third episode of the season &quot;How to Get Fit&quot;, John, who is out of shape and can&#39;t find the energy to do anything, plans to rebuild his self-confidence through fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But suddenly the camera turned to focus on a piece of chewed gum and began to output: &quot;That piece of fresh clay with infinite possibilities hardened into a disappointing thing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sure enough, before he saw John&#39;s figure change, he changed his focus and started filming cat beauty pageants, being left out at parties, and being questioned by his junior brothers and sisters when he returned to his alma mater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/b6495aab04212e1e5f921ba2d837ae32.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;613&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/b6495aab04212e1e5f921ba2d837ae32.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251677&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Season 3 The most heartwarming episode may be &quot;How to Watch the Game&quot;. It started with John&#39;s sudden idea: he wanted to watch a sports game. But unfortunately it was raining heavily that day, so he met a fan on the way and invited him to his home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;John was moved by the closeness between the fans and his father and decided to invite his friends to watch the game when he returned home. Since you are going to invite people over, it shouldn&#39;t be too messy. At least the house must be cleaned first. But the vacuum cleaner broke and needed to be repaired, so John accidentally entered a vacuum cleaner competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/7ff6fa89d8f2ca2b88b9f6effbe6deaa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/7ff6fa89d8f2ca2b88b9f6effbe6deaa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251678&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the competition Everyone is a vacuum cleaner enthusiast and has various models of vacuum cleaners at home. For them, vacuum cleaners are an emotional sustenance for missing their relatives and friends. Everyone has their own exclusive vacuum cleaner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of weird and pure love actually moved people, which shows that John is talented in deceiving people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/7024986aa720af6bbc0693f947f56660.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;903&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/7024986aa720af6bbc0693f947f56660.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251679&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is also this A major feature of the series is that it is like an uncontrolled adventure where all kinds of things happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And John is the carrier, and various emotions and events flow through him. The various confusing behaviors he captured also make people truly feel that as long as you are not embarrassed, others don&#39;t actually care that much about how you spend your life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people love growing pumpkins, some collect dozens of vacuum cleaners, some fill their homes with team-related items, some use plastic bottles to store urine...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/570bfbd323e3dff24232dc640c9dac04.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/570bfbd323e3dff24232dc640c9dac04.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are so weird yet unobtrusive, leaving the audience in a state of shock and confusion. In the novel mood, I realized the importance of &quot;making myself happy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coupled with John&#39;s mentality of being able to connect with everything, the seemingly ordinary life day after day becomes more vivid and interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New York is far away from us, but the loneliness and anxiety recorded by John, as well as his clumsy and hard work to find things that make him happy, are very resonant. This is also what we really need to learn: no matter what, don’t be numb to life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[盘州市盘关镇山脚树煤矿发生一起事故 16人已无生命体征]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257561]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 20:57:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At about 8:10 am on September 24, 2023, at the foot of the mountain in Panguan Town, Panzhou City An accident occurred in Shu Coal Mine. It was initially determined that the transport tape caught fire, trapping 16 people. After rescue efforts by the mine rescue team, the fire has been extinguished and the temperature and gas at the working surface have returned to normal. After preliminary verification, 16 people have no vital signs, and other work is being actively carried out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国企垄断本地殡葬拒绝中介被判违法：警惕行政垄断隐蔽化丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257531]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Supreme People’s Court issued a series of typical anti-monopoly and anti-unfair competition cases. Among them, the &quot;Basic Funeral Services&quot; refusal to trade dispute case involves the identification and legal liability of public enterprises&#39; refusal to trade, which is worth mentioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the website of the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the basic facts of this typical case are: Quanzhou Licheng Lisheng Funeral Service Co., Ltd. (Lisheng Company), which is mainly engaged in funeral intermediary services, sued for the prosecution of Quanzhou Jiying Funeral Service Co., Ltd. (Jiying Company) is a public enterprise that provides basic funeral services such as cremation of remains. Because Lisheng Company reported that Jiying Company charged illegally, Jiying Company refused Lisheng Company to apply for cremation services on behalf of the relatives of the deceased, which violated the regulations. In accordance with the provisions of the Anti-Monopoly Law prohibiting administrative monopoly, we requested a court to order Jiying Company to resume handling relevant business for Lisheng Company and to compensate for economic losses of 80,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court of first instance held that Lisheng Company failed to prove that Jiying Company was the executive entity of the administrative monopoly regulated by the Anti-Monopoly Law, and ruled to reject all claims of Lisheng Company. Lisheng Company was dissatisfied and appealed, claiming that Jiying Company&#39;s refusal was an abuse of market dominance prohibited by the Anti-Monopoly Law. The second instance of the Supreme Court found that Jiying Company, as a public enterprise with a monopoly position in the basic funeral service market in central Quanzhou, refused to handle relevant business for Lisheng Company, constituting a refusal to trade prohibited by the Anti-Monopoly Law, and ruled that Jiying Company Compensate Lisheng Company for losses of RMB 80,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trial process of this case is very interesting. In the first instance, Lisheng Company held that Jiying Company&#39;s refusal to trade with it violated the provisions of the Anti-Monopoly Law prohibiting administrative monopoly. The court of first instance held that Lisheng Company failed to prove that Jiying Company was the executive entity of the administrative monopoly regulated by the Anti-Monopoly Law, so it rejected Lisheng Company&#39;s appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what are the provisions of the Anti-Monopoly Law on administrative monopoly? According to Chapter 5 of the Anti-Monopoly Law, administrative agencies and organizations authorized by laws and regulations to manage public affairs shall not abuse administrative power to exclude or restrict competition. From a legal perspective, the implementing entities of administrative monopoly should be “administrative agencies and organizations authorized by laws and regulations to manage public affairs.” On the surface, Jiying Company is an enterprise, not an administrative agency, and is not authorized by laws and regulations to manage public affairs. It does not seem qualified to be the subject of administrative monopoly. So what kind of company is Jiying Company? After digging through the layers, it was discovered that Jiying Company is a state-owned company 100% controlled by the Quanzhou State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. More importantly, Jiying Company operates the only funeral parlor in the main urban area of ​​Quanzhou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, funeral parlors in other places are generally public institutions affiliated with the civil affairs department, but Quanzhou City hands over the operation of funeral parlors to a state-owned enterprise. This state-owned enterprise is responsible for providing basic funeral services, including cremation of remains, in the main urban area of ​​Quanzhou City. This is the only funeral home in the main urban area of ​​Quanzhou that can provide cremation services. According to the reply letter to the CPPCC members&#39; proposal published by the Quanzhou Municipal Civil Affairs Bureau in 2019, the funeral business in the main urban area of ​​Quanzhou was transferred to Jiying Group for management. In other words, Jiying Company’s monopoly on the basic funeral service market in the main urban area of ​​Quanzhou is the result of administrative transfer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it legal for a state-owned enterprise that provides basic public services, which is in a monopoly position due to administrative orders, to refuse to trade with a downstream enterprise because it reported that it charged excessively? The court of first instance rejected the plaintiff&#39;s petition on the grounds that the defendant was not a qualified subject of administrative monopoly. There seemed to be nothing wrong with the procedure. However, it objectively maintained Jiying Company&#39;s monopoly status and made it impossible for the plaintiff to carry out normal operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, during the appeal, Lisheng Company changed its strategy and claimed that Jiying Company’s refusal was an abuse of market dominance and refusal to trade. The Supreme Court also held in the second instance that Jiying Company is a public enterprise with an exclusive position in the local basic funeral service market, and the basic funeral services it provides are specific services that are indispensable for the downstream funeral intermediary companies to carry out services, and the downstream funeral agencies There is no alternative to the agency. Jiying Company refused to handle relevant business for Lisheng Company, which resulted in Lisheng Company being completely excluded from the funeral agency service market in downtown Quanzhou, excluding and limiting competition in the funeral agency service market, and damaging its reputation as a countermeasures company. The interests of consumers’ relatives of the deceased in the sense of the Monopoly Law constitute a refusal to trade prohibited by the Anti-Monopoly Law. Therefore, it was ruled that Jiying Company should resume Lisheng Company’s application for the cremation business on behalf of the relatives of the deceased under legal and compliant conditions, and compensate them The refusal to trade caused a loss of 80,000 yuan to Lisheng Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the relevant judgment documents published on the China Judgment Documents Network, the cause of the incident was a business of renting ice coffins to store remains in October 2019. The plaintiff believed that the defendant had illegally charged an extra 200 yuan in rent. Complaints to market regulatory authorities. After that, the defendant no longer accepted the plaintiff’s application to the defendant for cremation of remains on behalf of the deceased’s family. In order to protect their rights and interests, the plaintiff complained to the Quanzhou Municipal Market Supervision Bureau, Civil Affairs Bureau, and National Development and Reform Commission, and took the civil affairs, municipal supervision and other departments to court many times for administrative inaction. However, these complaints and lawsuits all failed without exception. Even in the first-instance civil lawsuit heard by the intermediate court in another place, there was still no support. It wasn&#39;t until he appealed to the Supreme Court that he was finally supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar phenomena are not uncommon. Some local governments transfer the responsibility of certain basic public services to state-owned enterprises, which is called marketization and actually forms an administrative monopoly. These state-owned enterprises have an absolute monopoly in this field of public services and may even be assigned some management functions that should be the responsibility of the administrative department. Their leaders are often close to the regulatory authorities. Therefore, these state-owned enterprises are often arrogant when facing downstream enterprises or consumers. Once downstream companies or consumers mess with such state-owned enterprises, they will be put in the shoes of others. Just like in this case, because Lisheng Company complained about Jiying Company&#39;s excessive charges, Jiying Company used the excuse that Lisheng Company violated laws and regulations during the funeral process and refused to allow Lisheng Company to handle the cremation business on behalf of the family of the deceased. However, it is very difficult for downstream companies or consumers to safeguard their rights. Locally, they will basically encounter obstacles everywhere, and they can only be solved at a higher level or even at the central level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this kind of public service provision by enterprises designated by administrative power does not comply with the legal provisions on &quot;administrative monopoly&quot; on the surface, it is essentially the same as administrative monopoly. They both rely on administrative power to monopolize the market. Put on a pair of &quot;corporate&quot; white gloves. These &quot;public enterprises&quot; with monopoly status should not be viewed with caution against administrative monopolies to prevent them from using their monopoly status to harm the interests of upstream and downstream enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在德国小镇，偶遇“乱世佳人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257446]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/2xLRyrFir4VYv8Pl4SihiUfphbeTRVncavXAsDeI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/2xLRyrFir4VYv8Pl4SihiUfphbeTRVncavXAsDeI. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Portrait of Barbara and herself when she was young&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Children&#39;s words/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meeting Barbara and her story was a completely unexpected gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I originally just came to see an old friend. She settled in Rothenburg, Germany, a small town that even Germans are not very familiar with. After not seeing each other for many years, my friend and I wasted no time chatting, and the topic somehow ended up on her German mother-in-law, Barbara. My friend really wanted me to talk to this old lady. Before I could ask why, she couldn’t help but introduce Barbara’s life: she was born into a wealthy manor family, and later became a refugee. It was like the movie &quot; Scarlett in &quot;Gone with the Wind&quot;! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had already smelled the flavor of the story. It happened to be that Friday, and my friend made an appointment to go to my mother-in-law’s house, so I quickly followed. The walk to Barbara&#39;s house was short, just through the garden from the back door of a friend&#39;s house. The kitchen door opened, and a silver-haired old man walked out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Ewe46mb8M527fPetxAplol6ggihKhOi2qtw1apBB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Ewe46mb8M527fPetxAplol6ggihKhOi2qtw1apBB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251386&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Barbara&#39;s family&#39;s manor&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Children&#39;s words/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First meeting with Barbara Bara, I can&#39;t help but marvel: This old lady is so tough! He walks steadily and has a loud voice. He doesn&#39;t look like he is 93 years old. After her husband&#39;s death, Barbara lived alone for more than ten years. Not only did she take care of her own daily life and food, but she also took care of the two-story house and large garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing me as an unexpected guest, Barbara generously invited me in. A friend suggested that we sit at the dining table and chat. Barbara pretended to be angry and shook her head: &quot;How can we sit comfortably?&quot; She moved the brewed tea and small cakes to the coffee table at the end of the living room. The room was a little dark, so Barbara turned on the light, turned to the room, took out two photo albums, and placed them in front of me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/OcMHVTXqMHcQe2kwEIEp8f4ukEVBp6ihHTZqqzLr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/OcMHVTXqMHcQe2kwEIEp8f4ukEVBp6ihHTZqqzLr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The three Barbara sisters and their mother&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Children&#39;s words/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This It’s my old home,” Barbara said. She pointed to a black and white photo in the center of the album&#39;s home page. The pixels were very low and a bit blurry, but I could still tell that it was a large castle-like house that could accommodate at least a dozen luxurious suites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Barbara, who was born in 1931, has lived in this big house with her two sisters since she was a child. Her family is very wealthy, and the town where the manor is located, whether it is farmland, shops or churches, is all Barbara&#39;s family property. They hired thousands of employees to take care of everything in the manor. Barbara&#39;s childhood was pampered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But such a privileged life came to an abrupt end when Barbara was 14 years old. In 1945, Germany was defeated and the country was occupied by partitions. Barbara&#39;s family estate was located on the border of East and West Germany, and was transferred to East Germany at the last minute. If they were ordinary people, they might not be affected too much. The prominence of the Barbara family and the &quot;corrupt farmer life&quot; they lived made them the target of public criticism. On the eve of the end of the war, the Soviet army that took over captured Barbara&#39;s father and gave orders to other family members to pack up and leave within 4 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/yoMl9Fb7ylFmYAlyagMxakIViKgJyJrPZuxY4mGV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/yoMl9Fb7ylFmYAlyagMxakIViKgJyJrPZuxY4mGV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Barbara&#39;s Little Bear&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Children&#39;s words/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One night During this time, Barbara was reduced from an aristocratic lady to a refugee. Fortunately, thanks to my mother&#39;s bravery and resourcefulness, the family of five was able to reunite safely. They climbed onto the train in the dark, crossed the border, and hid with relatives in West Germany. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From then on, Barbara not only had to take care of her own life, but also had to learn farm work from scratch. When I asked Barbara if she ever felt particularly miserable, she smiled. She is always smiling, and when she talks about the past, it feels like she is describing someone else&#39;s adventure story, without any resentment or sadness on her face. She even looked like a child, her shoulders curled up when she was happy, and she leaned on the sofa with a smile on her face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Barbara said that she did not feel bitter at all, but felt extremely lucky. After all, the family was intact. She only remembers the ruins of post-war towns, or the happy times she spent laughing in the rice fields with her family. Later, they came to settle in the small town of Rothenburg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The war delayed Barbara&#39;s studies, but she has always had a dream to become a flight attendant, because her mother said that being a flight attendant allows her to experience different cultures. At that time, Germany had very high requirements for flight attendants, and you had to master two foreign languages ​​to apply. In her early twenties, Barbara decided to go abroad. Her family contacted a family in Sweden who needed a nanny for her, and she set out alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Barbara stayed in Sweden for three years and met her future husband, who was also German. Her husband wanted to return to Germany, so Barbara&#39;s dream of being a flight attendant ended. She settled down to become a housewife and raised four children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/iUpQf4uhYGqNGZWs078ZkOGV7cdJHXt16OvID5OU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/iUpQf4uhYGqNGZWs078ZkOGV7cdJHXt16OvID5OU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Barbara in her garden&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Children&#39;s words/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up In the 1970s, Barbara&#39;s family contacted the East German government. After numerous lawsuits, Sister Barbara finally received some compensation. The former manor is now managed by a government foundation. The pastoral scenery and splendor of the past can only be recorded thanks to the photos taken by Barbara’s mother during her lifetime. If no one asked, Barbara rarely told her story to outsiders. She just typed out an &quot;autobiography&quot; of more than thirty pages on a typewriter and left it to her four children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The epic story of nearly a hundred years was condensed into one afternoon&#39;s narration, which I found intoxicating and exciting. I asked Barbara if there was one item that she still regrets leaving in her home at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Barbara spent a few minutes thinking, and I guessed that the answer might be related to gold and silver jewelry. Unexpectedly, she answered: &quot;My little stuffed bear!&quot; She pointed behind her seriously. Said: &quot;So I sewed one for myself!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After hearing this, my friend and I burst into laughter. Barbara explained a little embarrassedly: &quot;I was only a 14-year-old child at the time...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before leaving, Barbara took out a small notebook and asked me to leave a message in it. I wrote in Chinese and Swedish respectively: Dear Barbara, I wish you health and happiness forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电影《流水落花》：努力将生活这张旧报纸展平]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257533]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The veteran escort for the Best Actress who has failed nine times finally stepped onto the podium. At the 41st Hong Kong Film Awards, Sammi Cheng, who won the Best Actress Award, couldn&#39;t hide her excitement: &quot;I want to thank God for not letting me have a smooth journey. It is these lack of smooth sailing that have taught me to be humble and gentle... (At this moment) I can’t be gentle. I’m really happy tonight. I finally don’t have to run silently with you on the track, and I can finally cross the finish line with my head held high.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, nearly half a year after winning the award, Sammi Cheng &quot;Flowing Water and Falling Flowers&quot;, the film&#39;s best-selling novel, has finally been released in mainland China. But in the movie, the honors on the awards podium disappear along with the ambition. People saw that Sammi Cheng appeared on the screen without any appearance and almost gave the most &quot;light&quot; performance in her career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6iHG1ya14BlHIBF5Hl1mIeOOZ3W0uzIhzOHXLmqu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6iHG1ya14BlHIBF5Hl1mIeOOZ3W0uzIhzOHXLmqu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sammi Cheng (left) in the movie &quot;Falling Water&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story of &quot;Flowing Water and Falling Flowers&quot; is not complicated. Tianmei, played by Sammi Cheng, was originally a car rider on the school bus. As a caretaker, due to a change in the school bus route, she quit her job and returned home to be a temporary mother in a &quot;foster family&quot;. Together with her husband, Bin, who drove for her boss, she raised the children from social welfare institutions in stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The children come from different family backgrounds: some have fathers in jail, and some are waiting for adoption due to their own illnesses. Life revolves around children again, and the hidden pain belonging to this family slowly emerges: a few years ago, Tianmei and Bin&#39;s young child died. Being a foster parent is also filling the void of &quot;parent&quot; status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To some extent, Tianmei, Bin and the passers-by in this family are all &quot;aphasic&quot; in society. When this family decided to become a foster family, they began to encounter scrutiny from the so-called healthy operating system. Every time the social worker asked to come to the door in half an hour, Tianmei felt like she was facing an enemy. According to regulations, one of the couple must stay at home with the child during the parenting period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bed and table should be as tidy as possible, cigarettes are an absolute taboo, and even the smell of cigarettes must be dispersed, which is regarded as a sign of &quot;unhealthy&quot;. But for such a couple who have been silently enduring the shadow of the loss of their child for a long time and living a difficult life, they really can&#39;t imagine a healthier way to resolve it - those moments when they are discouraged, worn out by daily life, and scattered and need to be sorted out. It needs to be dispelled by a silent cigarette. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Movies that focus on people at the bottom of society or on the margins can easily tend to over-emphasize their social side, as if people’s situations have become props to display social problems; the other extreme is an excess of warmth that overwhelms people. The details of getting along too warmly with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Flowing Water and Falling Flowers&quot; tries its best to stay in the middle ground. It never gives up on capturing tender moments. A foster boy was injured and sent to the hospital for injuries while he was alone at home. The social worker then questioned &quot;Aunt Tianmei&quot; and &quot;Uncle Bin&quot;, and he cleverly excused them - Aunt Tianmei was not at home and had gone to buy medicine for herself. They spent the Spring Festival together, watching the fireworks bloom over the city, and their emotions were intimate and harmonious. But almost the next second, the life of this relationship in the image came to an abrupt end. A new foster child has arrived. There were no ostentatious farewells or overly bitter farewells. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Flowing Water and Falling Flowers&quot; has a vague flavor of Japanese movies. When it needs concentration, it often falls into a sentimental and mournful atmosphere. For example, Tianmei was sitting on the balcony eating cake, letting the rain and wind splash into her territory, leaving water stains on her pants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She often stood alone on the bridge, waiting for the sunlight to move inch by inch over the narrow water channel, taking away the darkness from her side. &quot;I don&#39;t like to express my feelings with open and wide expressions, but I like to observe things from a detached and cold perspective, so the film may be the same.&quot; Director Jia Shengfeng said in an interview with the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no narrative ambition in the movie, and some exciting sequences seem to be just making up for the excessive static of life itself. When the mother of a foster boy came to her door feeling out of control, the social worker apologetically told Tianmei that she would immediately help find a new foster family. Tianmei therefore expressed dissatisfaction: He is not a commodity and can be moved around at any time. This is obviously not the first time a similar situation has occurred. The boy had just established trust with them, and they were about to be separated again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/c78u1GrqVdJMyQ3r85w3y4ocTJQqFYq0t5q7onpZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/c78u1GrqVdJMyQ3r85w3y4ocTJQqFYq0t5q7onpZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251820&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the movie &quot;Flowing Water and Falling Flowers&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the foster children, Tianmei once considered adopting a girl with cleft lip and palate. But the social worker told her that adoptive families do not have the right to choose their children. According to certain assessment standards, the best adoptive parents for a girl with cleft lip and palate are an American couple, implying that Tianmei and Bin are economically disadvantaged. Tianmei rarely expressed anger: Have you asked your children for their opinions? How to judge the best? At that time, the girl with cleft lip and palate already called Tianmei &quot;mom&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, turbulent past events emerge suddenly and briefly, such as during bedtime conversations or invitations for intimate behavior. Her husband repeatedly proposed having another child, but Tianmei retorted: What should I do if there is another genetic disease this time? The conversation stopped there, with no further emotion. They accepted the death of their son tacitly, and had no intention of chewing, sorting out, or repeating their grief. Their life is like an old newspaper that is constantly being rubbed by fate. The purpose of living is just to flatten it bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the title of the film &quot;Falling Flowers in Flowing Water&quot; suggests, foster children are like flowers that have fallen temporarily, and life has temporarily brought them to Tianmei&#39;s family. Some netizens commented: In the first half of the film, the children are like falling flowers and the foster families are like running water. In the second half of the story, the foster family becomes the fallen flower, and the children are the running water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed. Looking at it, after losing their children, Tianmei and Bin&#39;s lives have almost come to a standstill. The life they have been practicing year after year cannot see many changes. When the children arrived, the family just regained some vitality and was full of dynamics - the children&#39;s childhood naughtiness was left in the form of graffiti on the wall. Pencils marked the gradually rising height lines and pasted them on the mirror to teach the children to smile more cheerfully. The flower stickers were put on and then taken off, and a pair of siblings who loved skipping classes wrote on the wall: Jia Xi Jia Lang is here for a visit. These connected graffiti show the flow of time within this family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Flowing Water and Falling Flowers&quot;, there is a scene that illustrates the director&#39;s intention to capture the true form of time - in Tianmei&#39;s imagination and memories, the children who have been in this family stand in rows according to their size. Arranged like cell phone signals. The first little boy to come to the foster home was the shortest and was in a stage where he would wet his pants in fear; while the last boy to stay in this family, 17 years old, was already able to help Tianmei carry rice and thread needles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven foster children have stopped in this family. With age groups ranging from elementary school to middle school to high school, &quot;Falling Water&quot; shows all the parenting issues a couple might encounter. In this design, the film erases the particularity that trauma brings to this family and restores a more universal family situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the parent fun day in primary school, like all normal parents, they helped their children participate in sports competitions and encouraged their children to regain their confidence; when the 17-year-old boy expressed that he wanted to stay at home forever, he was calm Accept that your child will eventually go out into the larger world. In this sense, the director filled a warm base under the cold and distant film style. After all, for Tianmei and Bin, this may be the best ending in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[病儿为何大额捐赠自家？儿慈会明星项目“冲配捐”调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257557]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 17:59:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to arouse the enthusiasm of the whole people to participate in public welfare, the organizers of 99 Charity Day They introduced matching donations. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a charitable organization with strong fundraising capabilities, the China Children’s Charity Aid Foundation (referred to as Children’s Charity Society) has recently fallen into disarray. In the midst of the donation turmoil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2023, Ke Mouxiao was accused of using the Children&#39;s Charity Society&#39;s &quot;9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Assistance&quot; project (hereinafter referred to as 9958) to defraud families of seriously ill children out of nearly 1,000 yuan. 10,000 life-saving money was detained by the police. The Children&#39;s Charity Association publicly stated that Ke Mouxiao was not its staff and had only served as a volunteer in the Hebei Langfang Team Cooperation Organization of the 9958 Project. But the controversy has not yet died down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many parents of children who were deceived said that they participated in the &quot;matching donation&quot; initiated by Ke Mouxiao and transferred the funds to Ke Mouxiao. They expected that within a period of time Afterwards, a return higher than the principal amount will be obtained, and the excess will be donated by the enterprise. Because this kind of &quot;matching donation&quot; is a normal operation mode in the charity sector, and families of seriously ill children are accustomed to it, there is no doubt about the authenticity of the project initiated by Ke Mouxiao. (For details, please see Southern Weekly’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685?source=131&quot;>;China Children’s Charity Association volunteers are involved in nearly 10 million yuan in aid, and families with serious illness are in trouble again. Matching donation scam&lt;/a>;》)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the &quot;matching donation&quot; that parents of children with children are accustomed to, is it a arbitrage donation in a gray area? According to relevant laws and policies, it is illegal for charitable organizations to induce parents of children with self-raised funds to participate in matching donations or donate for their own use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Does the Children&#39;s Charity Association know about such &quot;matching donations&quot;? Southern Weekend reporters discovered that deficiencies in the management and operation of charitable organizations provide a breeding ground for the alienation of matching donations. The more money is raised, the more matching donations are made - with the same goal, the people who need the money most take their money out of their pockets, boosting the charity&#39;s fundraising figures. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Who dares to do it if you can’t get the money back?”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It’s the 99 Charity Day in September every year. Li Shan (pseudonym) from Guangxi I want to raise more life-saving money for my daughter who is suffering from leukemia. He decided to participate in &quot;matching donations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;99 Charity Day is a national charity event jointly launched by Internet companies and hundreds of charity organizations, enterprises, and celebrities. September 9, 2015 is China&#39;s first Internet Charity Day. In order to arouse the enthusiasm of the whole people to participate in public welfare, the organizers introduced a popular foreign method-matching donations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Matching donation is matching donation. After one donor donates a sum of money to a charity organization, another donor (usually a company) will randomly or according to Donate a certain percentage of money to the same charity organization. The original intention of the matching donation model is to encourage the public to participate in donations. According to its original intention, the donation amount including corporate matching should not be used for the donor himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Charity Law also clearly stipulates that when a donor and a charitable organization agree on the purpose and beneficiaries of donated property, the donor&#39;s interested parties shall not be designated as beneficiaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Li Shan has never heard of the above regulations. On the eve of the 99 Charity Day in 2023, Li Shan opened a &quot;Donate Together&quot; charity matching donation project for each of the three charity matching projects launched by the Children&#39;s Charity Society: &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot;, &quot;Girls in Need Guarantee Plan&quot; and &quot;Aiding Children in Need to Dream of Going to School&quot;. ” fundraising link and named it after his daughter, who has leukemia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Donate Together&quot; is a charity game launched by Tencent Charity Platform. Users click the corresponding button on the public welfare project homepage and fill in the target amount and sponsor information to generate a link. Donors open the link and enter the amount to donate. Subsequently, this donation information and the corresponding matching donation will be recorded in the initiator&#39;s &quot;Donate Together&quot; and can be publicly queried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the public information and implementation plan of the project, the recipients of &quot;Sunflower Guarding Children in the West&quot; are children in need in the western provinces under the age of 18. &quot;Girls in Distress&quot; The &quot;Guarantee Plan&quot; will provide long-term assistance to girls in need across the country, and the goal of &quot;Assisting Children in Need to Dream of Going to School&quot; is to allow children in need to go to school with peace of mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I really don&#39;t understand this.&quot; On September 17, 2023, Li Shan listened to a reporter from Southern Weekend introduce the above three projects and said that he neither I don’t know who these projects are aiding, and I don’t know whether my behavior counts as a donation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But before that, in the three days from September 7th to 9th, Li Shan raised more than 210,000 yuan for these three projects through &quot;donate together&quot; , including several &quot;donations&quot; worth 3,000 yuan and 4,000 yuan. According to the rules, Tencent will donate more than 22,000 yuan for this purpose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shan explained to Southern Weekend reporters that these &quot;donations&quot; were all his own money. &quot;The people who &#39;donated money&#39; were some relatives and friends. I gave the money to them first and then asked them to donate it to the project.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shan said frankly , for the more than 200,000 yuan he &quot;donated&quot;, he had no intention of using it to aid children or girls in need in the west. &quot;We are all short of money ourselves.&quot; He believes that the money &quot;donated&quot; and matched by enterprises will eventually come back to him. &quot;Who dares to do it if he can&#39;t get (the money) back?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that during the three days from September 7th to 9th, a total of 12,000 people participated in the above-mentioned activities in the form of &quot;donate together&quot; For the three projects, they &quot;donated&quot; a total of more than 8.86 million yuan. Each &quot;donate together&quot; raised an average of 45,900 yuan, and the largest single &quot;donation&quot; was 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251851&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A &quot;Donate Together&quot; link initiated by a parent of a seriously ill child for the project of &quot;Aiding Children in Distress to Dream of Going to School&quot;. (Internet screenshots/pictures)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Self-raised, self-donated, self-used&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Through &quot;matching donations&quot;, the money &quot;donated&quot; can be returned &quot;with interest&quot;. Li Shan began to form this understanding in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he was hospitalized in Dongguan with his daughter. In order to seek medical treatment for his daughter, who has not yet entered elementary school, he claimed to have spent at least 700,000 yuan in two years. He remembers that day, the patient next to him took out 2,000 yuan and asked him to &quot;donate&quot; the link he had opened for him, and at the same time help answer the questions (according to the rules of the platform, those who answer the questions will have a chance to get more matching donations). The patient told him that after doing so, the platform would randomly match an undetermined amount of matching donation, and &quot;after certain procedures,&quot; the patient would not only get the matching donation, but &quot;the principal can also be returned.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the eve of 99 Charity Day in 2023, Li Shan joined a &quot;matching donation group&quot;. He said that the organizer of the group is a staff member of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team, and the group members call him &quot;teacher&quot;. Southern Weekend reporters were unable to confirm whether the organizer was an official staff member of the Children&#39;s Charity Society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tencent Foundation has provided a matching donation of 299.99 million yuan for all charity projects participating in the 2023 99 Charity Day activities. According to the matching donation rules announced by the platform, starting from 10:00 am on September 7th to 9th, every user donation greater than 1 yuan may receive a random amount of matching donation. The daily matching donation amount is on a first-come, first-served basis while supplies last. Together with the funds donated by donors, it will be transferred to the donated charity projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Li Shan’s understanding of “matching donation” is obviously different. &quot;He (the group organizer) told us when to start investing, and then we started donating money.&quot; Li Shan recalled that through mutual communication among patients in the group, he learned that as long as he launched the &quot;Donate Together&quot; fundraising link in the designated project , find someone to donate money and help answer questions, the &quot;teacher&quot; can apply for a &quot;matching donation&quot; for him, and the principal can be returned through &quot;relevant procedures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the start of the 99 Charity Day, the &quot;teacher&quot; announced the &quot;quota&quot; in the group, and he signed up in the group; after signing up, he sent it to his relatives and friends Transfer money; at 10 o&#39;clock on the day of the event, while there is still a matching donation quota, you must &quot;raise it yourself as soon as possible, otherwise you will not be able to vote later and the link is full&quot;; after the event is over, wait for the refund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Within three days, Li Shan &quot;donated&quot; more than 200,000 yuan to three projects initiated by the Children&#39;s Charity Association. &quot;No parent asked why he donated to these projects. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information of the project shows that a total of 54 people initiated &quot;Donate Together&quot; within three days of &quot;Assisting Children in Distress to Dream of Going to School.&quot; Two years after the project was launched, it has completed its fundraising goal and raised 4.35 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of press time, &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot; has reached the public fundraising goal of 5 million yuan. In addition to Li Shan, 102 people have launched the &quot;Donate Together&quot; &quot;. 78 people participated in the &quot;Donate Together&quot; program of the &quot;Girls in Distress Protection Plan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5944ffaa94.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5944ffaa94.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251852&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot; has reached its public fundraising goal of 5 million yuan. (Internet screenshot/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It can be seen from public information on the Internet that during the 99 Charity Day, most of the link names of &quot;Donate Together&quot; are named after children. Naming; often multiple accounts repeatedly &quot;donate money&quot; to a link, with a single amount reaching a thousand yuan; multiple names appear in different projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fundraising link is named after the child, allegedly to facilitate later repayment. Wang Qiang (pseudonym) who once worked in a local team of 9958 said that after the 99 Charity Day, parents would send screenshots of &quot;Donate Together&quot; named after their children to the financial staff of the 9958 local sub-center, who would then make statistics on each donation. How much money did each parent actually invest? The &quot;Donate Together&quot; page will display the funds raised by parents and the amount matched by the platform. The self-raised portion will be returned to parents after the 99 Charity Day. “This is the money in the account of the Children’s Charity Association.” The matching donation portion will have to wait until the platform transfers the matching donation funds to the Children’s Charity Association, “and then through the local people’s charity.” It will not be returned to parents through organizations or other channels.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Qiang also explained to Southern Weekend reporters that when allocating the matching donation amount, parents need to provide the staff with an invoice that is consistent with the total allocation amount of the foundation, &quot;For example The principal is 50,000, and the matching donation is 20,000. Parents must provide an invoice with a face value of 70,000 to the foundation, otherwise the accounts will not be balanced.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The content of the invoice provided by the parents of the children must be related to the child&#39;s condition. Invoices for hospitalization, outpatient services or purchased medicines are all acceptable.&quot; Wang Qiang further mentioned . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 17, Li Shan said that he had not received the refund yet. After the Ke Mouxiao incident was exposed, he was worried that he would not be able to get back the money he invested. &quot;(The staff) didn&#39;t say when they would give us the money. Before the incident, they said we would submit the child&#39;s information and wait for the foundation (Children&#39;s Charity Society) to give us the money back, but now we are in a panic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Southern Metropolis Daily, some parents who have successfully received &quot;matching donations&quot; have presented bank transfer slips, and the payee was the Children&#39;s Charity Association. However, Sun Dandan, director of the platform communication department of the Children’s Charity Society, said that some parents received funds from the Children’s Charity Society not because of “matching donations”, but because they met the rescue standards of the 9958 project, and local teams or rescue stations submitted the funds for their children. If the information and situation are evaluated and meet the rescue standards, the rescue funds will be released according to the rescue process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tencent Charity reported on September 13 that although Ke Mouxiao’s behavior did not occur on the Tencent Charity platform, based on the platform operating rules, industry self-discipline conventions and user-oriented principles, the following was made: Decision: Suspension of fundraising for all 9958 projects pending official investigation results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The team calls on parents to donate large amounts&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Does the Children&#39;s Charity Association know about Li Shan&#39;s &quot;matching donations&quot;? A WeChat group communication record obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that it was at the call of staff and volunteers that many parents of seriously ill children actively participated in the so-called &quot;matching donations&quot; on the 99 Charity Day in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This group is called &quot;Core Personnel of the Four National Branch Centers of the Children&#39;s Charity Society Project&quot;, with a maximum number of more than 70 people. The leader of the group is Wang Yu, whose name is the deputy secretary-general of the Children&#39;s Charity Society, Director of the 9958 Rescue Center of the Emergency Rescue Department. Almost all the 9958 project staff shown in the 2022 annual report of the Children&#39;s Charity Association are in the group, in addition to the &quot;responsible persons&quot; of various 9958 local teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Emergency Relief Department is also known as Project Department 4. According to the official website of the Children&#39;s Society, the 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Relief Center is established under it. The 2022 annual report of the Children’s Society shows that the 9958 Rescue Center of the Emergency Rescue Department has 16 staff members, which is the largest department in the Children’s Society. Its 9958 children&#39;s emergency rescue project was established in 2012 and is an independent brand project of the Children&#39;s Charity Association. Over the years, this project has established 25 relief sub-centers across the country in Weinan, Henan, Shanxi, Tai&#39;an, and Shijiazhuang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since August 2023, the staff member whose group nickname is &quot;9958-Cao Lifang&quot; has frequently shared information and reminders related to 99 Charity Day in the group. According to the WeChat public account &quot;9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Rescue&quot; and the 2022 annual report of the Children&#39;s Charity Society, Cao Lifang is the director of the fourth project department of the Children&#39;s Charity Society and also serves as the director of the 9958 Rescue Center. During the 99 Charity Day, he was also the coordinator of the 9958 project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 23, Cao Lifang informed the group that &quot;the platform is conducting a donation matching test&quot; and asked staff to make small donations to participating projects and experience the event process. . &quot;It is not recommended to allow parents to participate in the test. It is impossible to determine the amount of parents&#39; investment, which will take up the remaining fundraising space of the project.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 29, she said again Reminder, &quot;Participating children should pay attention to whether the disease type is consistent with the project. If the disease type is not specified, the project will treat it as all diseases. If the project specifies autism, premature infants, and congenital heart disease, the team will ask the parents to respond accordingly. Disease type, if the item is for girls, please ask the team to check that boys do not use it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Two days later, she shared with everyone the matching donation for 99 Charity Day Understand the rules. For example, if you need help from friends to answer the question &quot;Whether you answer correctly or not, you will have a chance to get a matching donation,&quot; parents can follow the training materials of the Children&#39;s Charity Association to learn to improve their charity status, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The team can directly call on parents to donate large amounts, and 80% of the donations must be completed on the 7th.&quot; Cao Lifang said in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A charity figure who once worked in 9958 explained to Southern Weekend reporters that on the 99 Charity Day, many parents of children with children will invest money in multiple projects. , the platform has a high probability of matching the most funds to the project with the largest donation amount. &quot;A friend can only help the parents of the same seriously ill child once a day, and large donations will get the most matching donations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 4, Cao Lifang informed everyone in the group: &quot;Parents who participate in 99 Charity, please transfer money to relatives and friends in advance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the matching donation started on September 7, the group nickname was shown as &quot;9958 Platform Development Department-Xu Jiawen&quot; (the annual report showed that this name&#39;s position was &quot;9958 Relief Center Project Officer&quot; ) notified in the group, &quot;Public donation is a voluntary and free act. Please mobilize and regulate management to jointly protect the credibility of the industry.&quot; But more than half an hour later, the group nickname was &quot;Jia Zhen, 9958 Platform Development Department&quot;. Said, &quot;Parents with high allocation should hurry up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above-mentioned charity person explained that &quot;high allocation&quot; refers to the platform&#39;s matching donation ratio on that day is relatively high. &quot;Hurry up.&quot; &quot;Reduce&quot; is because after the matching donation starts, the amount of matching donation will be smaller as the time goes by, until the matching donation quota for the day is completely used up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At around 19:00 on September 7, &quot;9958 Platform Development Department-Xu Jiawen&quot; released statistical results in the group. On that day, the fourth project raised more than 82.44 million yuan and received allocation. Donated more than 5.61 million yuan. The Shijiazhuang team raised a total of more than 29.64 million yuan (including 1.82 million yuan in matching donations), ranking first among the 17 local teams; the Tai&#39;an team raised a total of 19.51 million yuan (including 1.16 million yuan in matching donations), ranking second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 23, Southern Weekend reporters called the mobile phone numbers reserved by Cao Lifang and Jia Zhen on the public platform, but no one answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6e635b278e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6e635b278e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251853&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, the fundraising rankings of various local teams were released in the &quot;Core Personnel of the National Branch Centers of the Four National Branches of the Children&#39;s Charity Project&quot; group. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; Volunteers&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”, execution fees, fundraising rankings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than 80 million yuan raised in one day, confirming the success of Erci In recent years, it has left people with the impression that it has super fundraising capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public financial reports show that 714 million yuan in donations will flow into the Children&#39;s Charity Association in 2022; this number will be 838 million yuan in 2021 and 838 million yuan in 2020. It’s 834 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, 9958, as the star project of the Children’s Charity Society, has generated revenue of 322 million yuan (2020), 262 million yuan (2021) and 262 million yuan respectively in the past three years. 227 million yuan (2022), accounting for approximately one-third of the total annual revenue of the Children&#39;s Charity Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, public data does not show how much of the Children’s Charity Association’s annual fundraising is strictly public donations, and how much is for matching donations. self-donated for personal use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tencent Charity Regulations in 2023 stipulate that during the 99 Charity Days, fundraising organizations can use 20% of the income matching donations for the operation and development of the organization. This means that the higher the amount raised by an organization, the more matching donations it will receive from the platform, and the more incentives it will ultimately receive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, during periods other than matching donations, each fundraising organization can receive up to 2 million yuan in unrestricted donations as incentives. This part of the incentive payment is first come, first served, and the institution does not have to use it for project execution. At around 15:30 on September 7, Xu Jiawen informed everyone in the group: &quot;The backstage non-matching rewards have reached 2 million (ten thousand), and no new incentives will be obtained.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this matching donation controversy, The Children&#39;s Charity Association stated that it has never entrusted Ke Mouxiao to personally raise funds for the 9958 project. Ke Mouxiao is not a staff member of the association, but a volunteer of the 9958 Langfang team cooperation organization. However, Wang Qiang and the above-mentioned charity people said that this kind of personnel cooperation mechanism is common in the Children&#39;s Charity Society. Many people who organize fund-raising in the name of &quot;9958 staff&quot; are not official staff of the Children&#39;s Charity Society, but they are raising funds Although he has greater authority, he is also under the pressure of fundraising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters that after he joined a local 9958 team as a staff member, he did not sign a labor or labor contract with the Children&#39;s Benevolent Society or the local 9958 rescue center. He said that his usual salary is paid by local non-governmental organizations or enterprises, and the same is true for his colleagues around him. In a sense, Wang Qiang&#39;s identity is the same as Ke Mouxiao, and he is also a &quot;volunteer&quot;, but in external publicity, he is called the operations specialist of the 9958 team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Wang Qiang cannot be considered a volunteer in the strict sense. According to the &quot;Volunteer Service Regulations&quot;, volunteer services should follow the principle of free payment. Some legal scholars once suggested that the behavior of raising funds for patients and collecting execution fees is more like the professional fundraisers commonly seen in foreign charitable relief. It is only because the current domestic fundraising system is imperfect that all parties call this group &quot;volunteers&quot; &quot;. (For details, see Southern Weekend’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/203083&quot;>;Suspicions about “matching donations” among “fundraising volunteers”&lt;/a>;”)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; During the several years of working in 9958, Wang Qiang felt that he was &quot;like a businessman.&quot; If you only do your job, your monthly income will not exceed 4,000 yuan. If you want a higher income, you need to find more families with seriously ill children and help them raise funds publicly on several Internet platforms as &quot;volunteers.&quot; Wang Qiang described the fundraising link as an &quot;online project&quot; and claimed that he could get an execution fee of 3% or more of the total fundraising amount, but he did not produce a transfer voucher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with public donations without specific beneficiaries, parents of seriously ill children have a stronger motivation to raise funds and can help &quot;volunteers&quot; reach their fundraising goals faster. In fact, Ke Mouxiao himself may be a parent of children with serious illnesses. Information about his fundraising for children with blood cancer in 2021 can be found on the Internet, as well as bank statement receipts in which he is the payee and a charity organization is the payer. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Some parents are so pitiful that they will kneel down and beg you for a fundraising project.&quot; Wang Qiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even different teams will compete for &quot;business&quot;. The aforementioned charity worker who worked at 9958 told Southern Weekend reporters that he had previously worked with a seriously ill child in a cancer hospital and had collected the child’s information and was preparing to take photos of the child, write fundraising copy, and upload it to the Internet the next day. , &quot;As a result, the parents refused to let me take the photo the next day, and asked me for a letter of authorization (for the agency) to publicly use the child&#39;s photos before I left. Later I found out that someone from another team had snatched the child away.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9958 will also conduct internal team fundraising rankings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 20, 2023, the group nickname was &quot;9958 New Media~Sun Shuo&quot; (the annual report showed that the name and position were &quot;9958 Rescue Center&quot; &quot;Project Officer&quot;) published in the work group the ranking of the amount of funds raised by teams from various regions on the Kuaishou platform from August 11 to August 18: the Beijing team raised 51,000 yuan, the Guiyang team raised 5,320 yuan, and the Anhui team raised 5,320 yuan. The total amount raised was 3,326 yuan, the Lanzhou team raised 1,912 yuan, and the Tai&#39;an team raised 801 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s still far behind other team teachers.&quot; A person with the nickname &quot;Taian Team Mengmeng&quot; said in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;September 9, the 2023 99 Charity Day is coming to an end. Xu Jiawen reported the data of the 9958 project in the group over the past three days: the total fundraising received in the three days exceeded 134 million yuan, and the total matching donations received exceeded 11.81 million yuan. She also attached a ranking chart of the total fundraising of each local team from high to low: the Shijiazhuang team ranked first, raising more than 36.4 million yuan; the Tai&#39;an team ranked second, raising more than 28.04 million yuan; the Weinan team ranked third, Raising more than 27.36 million yuan; Shanxi team ranked fourth, raising more than 20.74 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Thank you to all the teachers for their efforts during the event. Teachers have worked hard.&quot; Xu Jiawen said in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters were unable to obtain the list of local teams established by 9958 through public channels. However, according to the above chat records, there are at least Shijiazhuang, Tai&#39;an, Shanxi, Guangdong, There are 17 teams in Shanghai, Weinan, Qingdao, Lanzhou and Baoding. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Vague information disclosure&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How the funds raised by the Children’s Aid Society from the many projects of 9958 will be used. According to regulations, it needs to be disclosed, but it is open to the public. To varying degrees. The death of female college student Wu Huayan in 2020 once plunged 9958 into controversy over insufficient information disclosure and over-age rescue. (For details, see Southern Weekend’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/174760?source=131&quot;>;&quot;Wu Huayan&#39;s death&quot; triggers reflection by public welfare individuals&lt;/a>;&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The disclosure of vague project information has created convenience for donations and matching funds to return to the hands of Li Shan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take the projects Li Shan participated in as an example. Among the three projects that Li Shan &quot;donated&quot; under the organization of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team, &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot; and &quot;Guarantee Plan for Girls in Distress&quot; have not yet entered the implementation disclosure period, and &quot;Assisting Children in Distress to Go to School Dream&quot; (referred to as &quot;School Dream&quot; ) project has been established for nearly two years, and it has disclosed several aspects such as project progress and finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The information disclosure of public welfare projects is related to their own scope of assistance. For example, medical assistance projects should disclose the list of recipients, types of diseases, and information about medical institutions. and rescue standards. However, there are contradictions between the existing public information of &quot;School Dream&quot; and its own purpose of assistance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The project introduction states, &quot;A donation of 10 yuan can support a child to buy a set of school supplies. A donation of 50 yuan can support part of a child&#39;s living expenses. &quot;. However, its 2022 financial disclosure details stated that the more than 2.06 million yuan allocated to recipients were all medical subsidies for recipients, and the corresponding living allowance was not announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The student aid program provides tuition fees, which are usually recorded as &#39;living allowances&#39; in financial terms, unless the children being rescued need medical treatment at the same time.&quot; Enyou Finance co-founder Zhou Zaoying found it difficult to understand the problems with this detailed list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;School Dream&quot; has disclosed the financial expenditure invoices for 2022 on the Tencent Charity Platform. In June, October and December, the Children&#39;s Association will realize the dream in Tai&#39;an City The Public Welfare Development Center (referred to as Tai&#39;an Dream Realization) allocated 3.39 million yuan, 1.63 million yuan, and 270,000 yuan respectively, and indicated that nearly 1.292 million yuan came from the &quot;School Dream&quot; project. The 2022 audit report of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Society also shows that Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng, as a &quot;large payment object&quot;, received a rescue activity fee of 1.287 million yuan from the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the executor of the public introduction of &quot;School Dream&quot; is the 9958 Beijing Xiangyang Group Rescue Center, and Southern Weekend reporters did not find that Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng has a public business relationship with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The invoice information sent to Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng by Children&#39;s Charity Society shows that the reviewer and payee of Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng are both Li Mengmeng. According to the 2022 annual report of Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng, Li Mengmeng is the chairman of the organization and You Guobao is the administrative person in charge. According to the content released by the 9958 WeChat public account, the above two people are also the directors of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team. Southern Weekend reporters also discovered that Li Mengmeng’s WeChat nickname and avatar were consistent with the “Taian Team Mengmeng” in the above-mentioned Children’s Society work group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 23, a Southern Weekend reporter called Li Mengmeng. The other party said he would not accept an interview and refused to disclose the specific nature and whereabouts of the funding. Southern Weekend reporters called the charity’s platform department, communications department and children’s emergency hotline, but were unable to get through. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Mengmeng raised funds as the director of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team, and also executed the project as the legal representative of Tai&#39;an Dream Realization. From an optimistic perspective, &#39;going to school Meng&#39; is a national public welfare project. If she is familiar with the situation in Tai&#39;an, she can implement it more efficiently locally.&quot; Zhou Zaoying said. But from a pessimistic perspective, “Insufficient and difficult-to-explain information about projects may lead to a crisis of public trust in the public welfare industry.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7a90c82ab7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7a90c82ab7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251854&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The invoice shows that in June 2022, the Children&#39;s Charity Association allocated 3.39 million yuan to Tai&#39;an Dream. (Internet screenshots/pictures)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Who does fake matching donation harm?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;&quot;Donations must be voluntary and gratuitous. If parents invest money in public welfare projects on the premise of returning donations and obtaining matching donation funds, it is not even a donation.&quot; Legal Research and Services of Shanghai Fulen Social Organization Lu Xuan, chairman of the center, explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some people believe that some parents of seriously ill children are also in need of public welfare assistance, and it is understandable to obtain matching donation funds through self-donation. But Lu Xuan doesn&#39;t see it that way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Very bad.&quot; Lu Xuan analyzed that the public welfare nature of a charity organization determines that its mission is to help unspecified objects in society. If project staff encourage parents of seriously ill children to donate money to the project before arranging allocations, it will become a &quot;specific target&quot; to be helped. In addition to constituting a donation arbitrage that violates the principle of good faith, it also violates the public welfare nature of a charitable organization. The principles of “openness, fairness and impartiality” that should be followed in the selection of project beneficiaries that do not comply with the Charity Law. This may prevent the needy people who are more in need of assistance from receiving relief funds, and also detract from the overall social evaluation of the charitable organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ma Jianyin, associate professor at Beijing Normal University Law School, also does not believe that the behavior of &quot;first investing money in public welfare projects and then taking money from the foundation&quot; is a donation. &quot;This is a false donation made to obtain matching donations. If the evidence chain is complete, it is a kind of &#39;fraudulent donation&#39;.&quot; Ma Jianyin analyzed that the deceived in this behavior are the main ones who use funds to make matching donations. &quot;They You can hold the organizer accountable or report it to the civil affairs department.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Parents of seriously ill children who need help from public welfare organizations often have limited income and do not have the strength to do so. Strong social ties may be to vulnerable groups in society. A legal expert who studies social organizations analyzed to a reporter from Southern Weekend that if this group learns that they can make &quot;donations&quot; through organizations, they will have a very strong motivation to participate, &quot;because they will feel that they are the beneficiaries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But this kind of behavior will hurt more potential targets who also need help, and deprive other disadvantaged groups of the public support that may belong to them. In addition, it will also make it difficult for public welfare organizations that are already lacking in resources to develop. The industry generally calls for separation of fundraising and use in charity fundraising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 4, 2023, Cao Lifang sent a document called the &quot;Self-discipline Convention for the 99 Charity Days of Children&#39;s Charity Association&quot; to the above-mentioned work group. Each team leader was also required to sign and fingerprint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 7 of this self-discipline convention states, &quot;Put an end to any form of extortion of matching donations.&quot; If there is any violation, &quot;I will bear all the responsibilities and consequences arising therefrom and accept all the handling of this matter by the Chinese Children&#39;s Benefit Association.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;With the issuance of internal regulations, does the organization no longer have management responsibilities?&quot; Lu Xuan analyzed that even if the staff of the local teams have no direct labor or relationship with 9958, Labor relations, but these people have actually provided services to 9958. Through the exchange of funds between institutions, it can be proved that there is a certain contractual relationship between several entities. &quot;If the local team of 9958 makes a mistake, it doesn&#39;t make sense for the local team to take responsibility in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从寻找F-35战机，看失事战机“僵尸飞行”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257548]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of September 18, 2023, local time, after an intensive 28-hour search, the U.S. military The wreckage of a previously missing F35B fighter jet was found in a field northeast of Joint Base Charleston, South Carolina. Aerial videos circulated on social platforms showed that there was a large area of ​​charred land on the field, and the woods on one side were in a mess. A large number of trees were knocked down, and there were obvious signs of excessive fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before, an F-35B &quot;Lightning&quot; II Joint Strike Fighter had an accident during a routine exercise. The pilot chose to eject to escape in an emergency. After that, the fighter jet continued flying in a &quot;zombie state&quot; and lost contact over South Carolina. In order to recover the missing F-35B fighter jet, multiple U.S. military services and departments jointly launched a &quot;missing notice&quot; on social media to solicit clues from the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bizarre incident involving a large-scale search for fighter jets has sparked heated discussions on the Internet, with many people finding it unbelievable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Carolina Congresswoman Nancy Mace asked on social media: &quot;What happened? How did you lose an F-35? Why is there no tracking equipment? You have to ask the public to help find it. Fighters and turn them in?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Air force training bases are generally established in the suburbs of cities, and radar deployment cannot be comprehensive. When the aircraft stalls and is at a lower flying altitude, it is not uncommon for the radar to fail to detect the target. More What&#39;s more, the F-35B fighter jet has excellent stealth capabilities and its radar reflection surface is extremely small.&quot; Wang Qunhuai, a former naval officer, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is not unprecedented for fighter jets to fly away without pilots. There have been fighter jets that flew nearly a thousand kilometers long distances after losing control of the pilot, until they ran out of fuel and crashed in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Where did the fighter jet go?&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;If you have any clues that can help us find the F-35 fighter jet, please call the Base Defense Operations Center. &quot;On September 18, 2023 local time, the United States Joint Base Charleston released an &quot;Opportunity Notice&quot; on social platforms, which attracted public attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The missing fighter belongs to the 501st Fighter Attack Training Squadron of the 2nd Air Wing of the U.S. Marine Corps, which is mainly responsible for pilot training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 17, a US military pilot flew an F-35B &quot;Lightning&quot; II fighter jet and took off from Joint Base Charleston to perform a training mission. But not long after, the fighter plane suddenly had an accident, and the pilot chose to eject to escape at a critical moment. At about 2 p.m., the pilot landed safely in the Charleston community and was later taken to the hospital, but the whereabouts of the F-35B he was flying was unknown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A spokesman for Joint Base Charleston told NBC that after the pilot ejected, the fighter jet was in autopilot mode, complicating tracking. Agence France-Presse reported that the fighter jet will continue to fly in a so-called &quot;zombie state&quot; until it crashes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that an F-35 fighter plane was accompanying the flight at the time of the incident. But the pilot did not continue to follow the drone and chose to return to base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the fighter plane disappeared, the U.S. military quickly joined forces with the Marine Corps, Navy, FAA, Civil Air Patrol and local law enforcement agencies in South Carolina to surround Moore, north of North Charleston. A three-dimensional search was conducted from the air and on the ground in the area of ​​Terry Lake and Marion Lake. In the evening of September 18, several search aircraft circled an area of ​​woods and farmland near the town of Starkey in Williamsburg County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a day and night of searching, a spokesperson for the U.S. Marine Corps confirmed that the wreckage of the F-35B fighter jet was found in a field in Williamsburg County. The crash site is about 129 kilometers from Joint Base Charleston. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The F-35B combines many advantages such as stealth, short takeoff, and vertical landing, and has a high level of versatility and interoperability. It is one of the most advanced and popular fighter jets in the world. &quot;Shepard Media, a well-known British defense media website, commented. But it is such an advanced fighter plane that is known as the &quot;main killer of future air combat&quot;, but it has set off an Internet group ridicule in the United States of &quot;Where have the fighters gone?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ABC News contributor and retired colonel Steve Ganyard complained, &quot;Even though it is a stealth aircraft, it is really surprising that such an expensive and complex aircraft can disappear. Ridiculous.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is not as easy for radar to capture stealth fighters as people think.&quot; Wang Qunhuai pointed out that on the one hand, the air warning radar has a high elevation angle, and the electromagnetic waves emitted basically propagate in a straight line. It can be effectively identified only when it flies to a high enough altitude; on the other hand, the F-35B fighter&#39;s maximum flight speed can reach up to thousands of kilometers per hour, and it can fly hundreds of kilometers in a few minutes. Once the transponder loses its function, it is basically invisible to the radar. You can only search with your naked eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The F-35 fighter jet is equipped with a Longbo lens. Wang Qunhuai said that this is to deliberately increase the reflected signal and make it easier to be detected by air traffic control radar when landing. &quot;Of course, when stealth flight is required, the Longbo lens The lens will be retracted”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the U.S. military considers the accident to be a Class A accident, the highest level of severity, but has not revealed the name of the pilot involved or the cause of the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not the first time that an F35-B fighter jet has suffered a Class A accident. Four months ago, an F-35B fighter jet of the US military stationed in Japan had parts falling off during flight training, and the fighter jet subsequently returned to the Iwakuni base. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;MiG-23 across Europe&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The mysterious disappearance of advanced fighter jets is surprising, but this is not the first time in history. The &quot;zombie flight&quot; experience of the MiG-23 fighter more than thirty years ago is more legendary than the F-35B. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, the Berlin Wall still stood high between East and West Germany, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, headed by the United States, and the Warsaw Pact, headed by the Soviet Union, were in a tense confrontation in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public records, on the morning of July 4th, Colonel Nikolay Skuridin, who had just finished his vacation, boarded a MiG-23 fighter jet as usual and flew from near Kołobrzeg, Poland. Take off from Bagiz Air Base. For this experienced pilot, this was just an extremely ordinary flight training. He did not expect that this day would be recorded in the history of world aviation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Skuridin piloted the plane to climb to an altitude of 150 meters, he suddenly found that the thrust of the engine afterburner had dropped sharply. When he realized that the plane had begun to fall, Skuridin immediately reported it to the ground command center. Engine failure problem. After receiving the tower&#39;s instruction to abandon the aircraft and parachute, he decisively pressed the emergency canopy ejection button. The MiG-23 fighter canopy detached from the fuselage, and Skuridin was safely ejected from the cockpit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, the unmanned MiG-23 fighter jet did not die in the Baltic Sea as expected. Instead, it suddenly raised its head and climbed upwards under the action of ejection, and soon resumed normal flight. gesture, flying westward over northern Poland and across what was then the Democratic Republic of Germany (East Germany). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the air defense radar stationed in Poland recognized the fighter plane, it mistakenly thought it was a routine training and its flight trajectory was not interfered with. In less than half an hour, the MiG-23 fighter jet entered the territory of the Federal Republic of Germany (West Germany) and was detected by the NATO warning radar deployed in Hamburg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the alert, the NATO military command urgently dispatched two American F-15 fighter jets stationed in the Netherlands to intercept. Compared with the US fighter jets, which were waiting in a tight formation, this MiG-23 fighter did not make any evasive maneuvers and maintained its current speed and flew smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When American pilots who were ready for air combat approached the MiG-23 fighter, they found that the fighter had no canopy, no pilot, and no ammunition. As a result, the NATO military command lifted the interception order and ordered two F-15 fighters to follow the MiG-23 fighters. Subsequently, the MiG-23 fighter jet flew westward through Dutch airspace and entered Belgium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 10:30 a.m. local time, 80 kilometers away from the Belgian capital, a MiG-23 fighter jet that ran out of fuel crashed into a house in the town of Kortrijk-Belleheim in western Belgium. Wim Dral, a 19-year-old boy who was sleeping, died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, the Soviet Union was looking for the wreckage of MiG-23 fighter jets in the Baltic Sea. It wasn&#39;t until they saw reports from Western media that the Soviet Union knew that its fighter jets continued to fly unpiloted for 79 minutes, traveling more than 900 kilometers across Poland, the Democratic Republic of Germany, the Federal Republic of Germany, the Netherlands and Belgium, and finally landed in Belgium. crashed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 6, Belgium protested to the Soviet Union over the plane crash. In the end, the Soviet Union paid approximately 625,000 euros in compensation to Belgium, most of which went to Dral&#39;s family. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cornfield Bomber&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot; Jedi encounter&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;生&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Dayton, Ohio, USA, is the hometown of the Wright brothers, the inventors of the aircraft. It is home to the U.S. Air Force Museum, the oldest and largest military aviation museum in the world. According to the official website, the museum houses about 400 aerospace vehicles dating back to World War I. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the various aircraft on display at the U.S. Air Force Museum, one of the F-106 fighter jets with a large delta wing design and a wasp-waisted fuselage does not seem to be conspicuous. But the legendary experience of its aftermath has been passed down orally from generation to generation of American pilots. They regarded it as a lucky fighter and affectionately called it the &quot;Cornfield Bomber.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 2, 1970, pilot Lieutenant Gary Foster took off in the F-106 fighter jet with tail number 580787. At the same time, three other F-106s took off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a routine tactical confrontation training that took place at Malmstrom Air Force Base in Montana, USA. According to the original plan, Lieutenant Foster will form a team with one of the pilots and conduct a peer-to-peer air combat exercise with two other F-106 fighters. However, due to a problem with the drag chute of one of the aircraft, the originally scheduled two-aircraft confrontation project turned into a &quot;one-on-two&quot; &quot;battle.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But when Lieutenant Foster piloted the F-106 fighter jet to an altitude of 10,000 meters, the fighter suddenly stalled and fell into an extremely dangerous horizontal rotation state, and then rapidly dropped to an altitude of about 3,657 meters. Foster attempted the spin recovery procedure multiple times without success before ejecting himself from the cockpit of the aircraft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the weight reduction of the fighter plane after the pilot ejected, the center of gravity changed, and the explosive force of the seat rushing out of the plane pushed the nose of the plane downwards. The F-106 fighter jet got rid of the rotation and flew without any control. Under human control, it enters a stable gliding state and flies smoothly in a straight line at a speed of more than 300 kilometers per hour. And this is exactly the approach speed of the F-106 fighter jet for landing under normal conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foster, hanging on the parachute, could only watch as his plane flew further and further away. He then landed in a nearby mountainous area and was rescued &lt;span>;by a local resident using a snowmobile&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The F-106 fighter jet he was flying landed safely in a cornfield near Big Sandy, Montana after flying for a certain distance. It even perfectly avoided the center of the field during taxiing. Rock pile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the local police arrived at the landing site, the aircraft engine was still running normally and the radar was still scanning. One hour and forty-five minutes later, the F-106 fighter ran out of fuel and the engine automatically shut down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, technicians from the Logistics Center at McClellan Air Force Base in California arrived at the scene. They were surprised to find that except for a few meters of scratches on the belly of the aircraft, the entire fighter aircraft was very slightly damaged. One rescue official even said that if the damage was less serious, he would fly the fighter directly back to the base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Qunhuai&#39;s view, it is a rare thing for a manned fighter plane to land on its own without human control, and it is basically difficult to achieve. &quot;Aircraft landing is one of the most dangerous aspects of flight. It requires deceleration and descent to maintain the appropriate speed and altitude, and the attitude and thrust of the fuselage must be adjusted to adapt to the runway position and airflow conditions. If there is a problem in any aspect, it may Posing a threat to the landing of aircraft.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the &quot;War History Online&quot; website stated that the thick snow on the ground provided a buffer for the fighter planes to land lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the F-106 fighter was transported back to California, Air Force staff repaired it, and the fighter was subsequently put back into service. In 1979, Foster flew this fighter into the sky again to participate in training at Tyndall Air Force Base in Florida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1986, this F-106 fighter aircraft numbered 580787 was retired and subsequently donated to the U.S. Air Force Museum. A few years later, all F-106 fighter jets were retired from the U.S. military and completely bid farewell to the stage of history at the beginning of the 21st century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[超“潮”！杭州亚运会开幕式的中式浪漫细节]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257519]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The evening of September 23&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Held in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/254915ccf2ad57ad9fd7a8bf4127acda.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/254915ccf2ad57ad9fd7a8bf4127acda.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;251769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony was themed &quot;Tide Asia&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Presenting an epic picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/d8965edd72e7460a1ad6640a1a391f41.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;998&quot; height=&quot;516&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/d8965edd72e7460a1ad6640a1a391f41.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251767&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the romantic Chinese details at the opening ceremony? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s take a look↓↓&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The five-star red flag and the beautiful rivers and mountains are in the same frame&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the opening ceremony, the five-star red flag entered the scene&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/113dfe346ea641241d9d713533e00e6b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;753&quot; height= &quot;424&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/113dfe346ea641241d9d713533e00e6b.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dang Mei The rivers and mountains and the five-star red flag are stunningly framed together&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This scene is absolutely beautiful! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/21b1af400cf0fb531b1befc20cf1c3bc.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;751&quot; height=&quot;422&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/21b1af400cf0fb531b1befc20cf1c3bc.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251770&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The whole place was excited! The Chinese sports delegation enters the venue&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/00ed01e32ff8894166c5846c6f43c841.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;312&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/00ed01e32ff8894166c5846c6f43c841.gif&quot; data-key= &quot;251771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the Chinese sports delegation entered the venue&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Singing the Motherland&quot; sounded and the whole place was excited! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/855a12dc90b7d9abbd7c61e02fffba58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/855a12dc90b7d9abbd7c61e02fffba58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251768&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Qin Haiyang and Yang Liwei serve as flag bearers&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese delegation consists of 1,329 people&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them 886 athletes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;407 will participate in 38 major events A small competition&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/401fe6dcb5612723582820c87ad4e7de.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style= &quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;756&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/401fe6dcb5612723582820c87ad4e7de.gif&quot; data-key=&quot; 251774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2c13b27bb61d2712af91bef80f028c3f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2c13b27bb61d2712af91bef80f028c3f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251773&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/8ae77ea6de049cccf7c7254ee29e7574.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1 ;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/8ae77ea6de049cccf7c7254ee29e7574.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251775&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Dancing on the ink painting is so amazing&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0e3612c6710e7439d9a4d4d839acad47.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1547&quot; height=&quot;842&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0e3612c6710e7439d9a4d4d839acad47. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The live performance is full of Chinese style&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dancers in blue dresses&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the ink painting scroll Dance on the top&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The skirt is full of ancient buildings&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/56890b6aa69140ca6f24e046e30ec363 .gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /56890b6aa69140ca6f24e046e30ec363.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the scene changes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A huge lotus leaf blooms on the water surface&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/241cc68604b11023cb4f6a0009468f8d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/241cc68604b11023cb4f6a0009468f8d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251779&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/a297502f7c0c230d4838bd0d0b0e993d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/a297502f7c0c230d4838bd0d0b0e993d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251780&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plucking lotus leaves in the fields in the south of the Yangtze River&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;Shows the picturesque scenery of Jiangnan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7acbca835fed4d95ab9578dfdf4b7714. gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ 7acbca835fed4d95ab9578dfdf4b7714.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251777&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenery of lakes and mountains transforms into the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far away is Hangzhou Gongchen Bridge&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7227ba118f5e0557b0e3dc1c4d22dedb.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot; 180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7227ba118f5e0557b0e3dc1c4d22dedb.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lantern flies up, Blessings fill the sky&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3D dual wires dance with the tide&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/cb3ee83f8277450f92d40e8e11601998.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/cb3ee83f8277450f92d40e8e11601998.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251778&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3D Dual Wire Technology is used in a large sports venue for the first time&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three-dimensional actors and actresses flying in the air with the tide Dance together&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/fa31bc5b144375c18135d90f6a855a65.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/fa31bc5b144375c18135d90f6a855a65.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251781&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2ef01dad5618a2259346fe82ac0a043d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2ef01dad5618a2259346fe82ac0a043d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251787&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On the ground screen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cross tide, first line tide, turning tide, fish scale tide, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiantang tides come and go&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ff07a37f056e8d3500debd2ee749af77.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1835&quot; height=&quot;1033&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ff07a37f056e8d3500debd2ee749af77.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tide of Qiantang River recedes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spectacular &quot;tide trees&quot; grow on the beach&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a natural ink painting&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/24/b6568a95f14f1cf907245071f4915917.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/24/b6568a95f14f1cf907245071f4915917.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251784&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ebb and flow, the cycle goes back and forth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tide &quot;irrigates&quot; Tree of the Earth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three Little Ones&quot; played &quot;Water Waves Piano&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/0b183e711d7634282dc53990d314c6c0.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/0b183e711d7634282dc53990d314c6c0.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251788&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mascots of the Hangzhou Asian Games are Chenchen, Congcong and Lianlian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tide the tide. The piano, with waves as keys&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plays the rhythm of youth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/e7c3846d9b645959e3dbd466cada5411.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/e7c3846d9b645959e3dbd466cada5411.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ 478a26620674162a53deb0e0cb1f6c9d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/478a26620674162a53deb0e0cb1f6c9d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital people light the main torch&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first lighting ceremony with the participation of &quot;digital people&quot; in the history of the Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Across time, space and national boundaries&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ce082e171957d53d52544072ace4031b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ce082e171957d53d52544072ace4031b.gif&quot; data-key= &quot;251790&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/b3d7106e79df9cc18660c91508b02874.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/b3d7106e79df9cc18660c91508b02874.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251792 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Digital People&quot; composed of more than 100 million &quot;Digital Torchbearers&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Together with the last torchbearer Wang Shun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jointly use methanol Fuel&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Light up the main torch tower of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ae4694e4e310ac14ff6ec493e95f8fd3 .gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;608&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /ae4694e4e310ac14ff6ec493e95f8fd3.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251791&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the fire of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearts follow the tide, hearts are together&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearts are looking toward the future, Aida&#39;s future! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>