<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江一煤矿发生事故，已有多人失联]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261481]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 16:43:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At around 15:00 on November 28, an impact occurred at the Shuangyang Coal Mine of Heilongjiang Longmei Shuangyashan Mining Co., Ltd. Ground pressure roof accident. The reporter learned from various sources that as of 16:00 on November 28, it was initially understood that many people were lost in the accident and related rescue work was in progress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:55:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[MH370乘客家属索赔案开庭，此前已对马航等相关方提起多轮诉讼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the morning of November 27, 2023, the compensation case for the families of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was held in Chaoyang, Beijing The District People&#39;s Court holds a hearing. Photo provided by People&#39;s Vision&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2637cede22.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2637cede22.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 27, 2023, the compensation case for the family members of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was opened in the Chaoyang District Court in Beijing. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of November 27, 2023, the compensation case filed by the families of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not a single lawsuit. More than 40 family members independently sued Malaysia Airlines and related parties. The defendants include Malaysia Airlines (old Malaysia Airlines) and Malaysia International Airlines Berhad. (New Malaysia Airlines), Boeing Company, Rolls-Royce Holdings Limited, Allianz Insurance Group, etc. The trial will last from November 27 to around December 5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter learned that on the first day of the trial, the plaintiff and defendant had not yet entered the cross-examination phase, and Malaysia Airlines had not submitted new evidence, and they were all going through the legal process. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly ten years after the accident, can this air crash come to a legal end in China? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Lost lawsuits in the United States and Malaysia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first lawsuit against the MH370 incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past ten years, the families of MH370 passengers have traveled to China, the United States and Malaysia, and have filed multiple rounds of lawsuits against Malaysia Airlines and other related parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;MH370&#39;s departure point is Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, and its destination is Beijing, China. There are no transfers or stops during transportation. For this type of international air transport incident, the main international treaties to refer to for the attribution of civil jurisdiction are the &quot;Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Air Transport&quot; formulated in 1929 and the &quot;Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Air Transport&quot; formulated in 1999 Convention (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the Montreal Convention&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the latter sets the compensation standards for civil aviation accidents and has the effect of priority application. China, the United States and Malaysia are all parties to the Montreal Convention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 33 of the Montreal Convention stipulates that a claim for damages may be brought at the plaintiff&#39;s option to the carrier&#39;s domicile, principal place of business, or the principal place of business where the contract is concluded. , destination and, in certain circumstances, the passenger’s fixed and permanent residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This means that in the MH370 air crash case, both Malaysia and China have jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, from the beginning of 2016 to March 7, Chinese family members sued Malaysia Airlines and related parties in the United States, Malaysia and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the lawsuits in the United States are mainly divided into two categories. One is a claim against Malaysia Airlines and insurance companies based on the Montreal Convention, and the other is a claim against the aircraft manufacturer Boeing. The company filed a product liability lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hao Junbo, a lawyer who has represented the families of an air crash in transnational litigation, told Southern Weekend reporters that the United States has the highest air crash compensation standards in the world, so worldwide, If an air crash occurs in almost any country, as long as the plane has a connection point with the United States, such as an engine or parts manufactured by an American company, attorneys from various countries will strive to prosecute the case in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Senior international aviation lawyer James Healy-Pratt wrote in 2021 that based on the jury’s recognition of unlimited compensation for bereavement, etc. Considering all these factors, the average amount of compensation awarded by American courts for air crash victims is the highest in the world, reaching US$5.2 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Hao Junbo said: &quot;In recent years, the possibility of foreign air crashes being tried by U.S. courts is very low, and they are generally dismissed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2018, the judge of multidistrict litigation in the United States ruled as forum non conveniens (&lt;em>;forum non conveniens&lt;/em>;) (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The principle of forum non conveniens means that after a court accepts a foreign-related case, it considers the many inconvenient factors in the trial of the case and believes that it is more convenient for the court to hear the case in other jurisdictions, so it gives up the case. The court dismissed all lawsuits arising from the disappearance of MH370 on the grounds of jurisdiction (&lt;/span>;), and the court believed that Malaysian courts were more suitable to hear these cases. The family chose to appeal, and in 2020, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit upheld the original verdict and dismissed all the family&#39;s lawsuits in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2017, 15 Chinese family members sued the Malaysian government, the Malaysian military and the Malaysian Civil Aviation Authority for &quot;negligence&quot; in Malaysia, demanding disclosure. the truth. In 2018, a Malaysian court ruled against the family due to insufficient evidence. In addition, from 2016 to 2020, the cases brought by family members against Malaysia Airlines and the Malaysian government in Malaysia were also lost due to insufficient evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The trial will not be affected by the outcome of foreign litigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The domestic litigation of the MH370 case can be traced back to 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced in 2015 that Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 crashed and it was presumed that all people on board were killed, Malaysia Airlines subsequently announced a compensation of 2.52 million to the families of each MH370 crash passenger. Yuan Yuan, but asked the family to give up pursuing responsibility against the Malaysian government, Malaysia Airlines, Malaysian military, and Boeing Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, nearly two-thirds of the families refused to sign the settlement agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2016, some family members who did not sign the agreement went to the Beijing Railway Transport Court to sue Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia Airlines International Berhad, Boeing Company, and Rolls-Rolls— Royce Holdings plc, Allianz Insurance Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2016, the Beijing Railway Transport Court announced that it had filed and accepted 36 civil claims for compensation from passengers involved in the crash of Malaysia Airlines flight MH370. At the end of 2017, the Beijing Railway Transport Court held a pre-trial meeting on the case, which was later designated by the Beijing High Court to be under the jurisdiction of the Beijing Chaoyang District Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, almost all family members who lost cases abroad returned to Chinese courts to sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Qihuai, a lawyer representing some of the family members, said in a previous interview that for more than nine years, the court has actively promoted reconciliation between the two parties, and the family members and Malaysia Airlines and insurance companies have More than half of the cases are waiting for the parties involved to reconcile. As of March 2021, 89 families have refused to settle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, the lawsuits filed by the families of Chinese passengers involved in the crash were not supported by the courts in the United States and Malaysia. Will this result affect domestic litigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the relevant provisions of the judicial interpretation of the Civil Procedure Law, for cases where both Chinese and foreign courts have jurisdiction, one party will file a lawsuit in the foreign court, while the other party will file a lawsuit in the foreign court. If a lawsuit is filed in a Chinese court, the domestic court may accept the case. After the judgment, if a foreign court applies or the parties request a domestic court to recognize and enforce the judgment or ruling made by a foreign court on the case, it will not be allowed, unless otherwise provided for in an international treaty jointly concluded or acceded to by both parties. In addition, if a foreign court&#39;s judgment or ruling has been recognized by a domestic court, and the party files a lawsuit in a domestic court with the same dispute, it will not be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;An unnamed civil procedure law scholar told Southern Weekend reporters that generally speaking, even if a civil case is successful in a foreign country, the effective judgment must be made in If you apply for execution domestically, you should first apply to the domestic intermediate court with jurisdiction for recognition and execution. After passing the review, the court will rule to recognize its validity and issue an execution order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For civil cases that are lost abroad, first of all, there is no need to apply for enforcement. Secondly, as long as there are no special provisions, the parties can still sue domestically based on the same facts and causes of action. &quot;The aforementioned scholar told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although China and Malaysia have signed a bilateral judicial assistance treaty, namely the Treaty between the Government of the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Government of Malaysia on Criminal Judicial Assistance, the bilateral treaty stipulates that The content covers criminal cases and does not take into account judicial decisions on civil disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This means that the results of previous lawsuits filed abroad by the families of MH370 passengers will not affect the Chinese court&#39;s hearing of the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to CCTV news reports, the amount of civil compensation filed by the passengers’ families is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. Because each family’s situation is different, the amount is also different. , a large part of the compensation costs is mental damage solatium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明月与乌皮靴：探寻“光影世界”之外的李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/28/a8b47c1659.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 28/a8b47c1659.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bright moon is a classic image in Li Bai&#39;s poems. The picture shows Li Bai under the moon in the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On the screen, Li Bai was pardoned and released, and he was walking on a pole on the Yangtze River. With his temples completely white, he finished chanting &quot;Apes on Both Sides of the Strait&quot; I can&#39;t stop crying, the boat has passed the Ten Thousand Mountains.&quot; When he was excited, he raised his hand and threw the long pole into the water. In the cinema, children happily recited the poems and adults shed tears. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2023, an animated film &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot; will follow the &quot;National Treasure Season 2&quot; and &quot;Chang&#39;an Ten Thousand Miles&quot; in previous years. Programs such as &quot;Two Hours&quot; once again put Li Bai&#39;s name on the hot search list. Different types of games such as &quot;Hundred Scenes of Jiangnan&quot;, &quot;Glory of Kings&quot; and &quot;Ink Soul&quot; have all invited Li Bai into their own world. Dramas, operas, dance dramas, musicals, and Cantonese operas all use Li Bai as the protagonist, summoning the soul of more than 1,300 years ago in the theater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1283&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bronze statue of Li Bai in Taibai Hall, Sichuan, by Li Xiangqun. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if he put on black leather boots and entered the court, Li Bai still could not unfold his arms throughout his life. He endlessly expressed in his poems Chanting, &quot;If I don&#39;t look toward the east mountain for a long time, the roses will bloom several times. The white clouds will disperse on their own, and who will the bright moon fall on?&quot; Xie An&#39;s seclusion in Dongshan after his achievements made Li Bai fall in love, and &quot;Ming Yue&quot; became the embodiment of the ideal that Li Bai pursued throughout his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Two years before his death, Li Bai met a Shu monk in Jiangxia, who was about to go to Chang&#39;an. Li Bai wrote, &quot;The moon of Mount Emei returns to you, and the wind blows west to Chang&#39;an. The Chang&#39;an Avenue spans nine days, and the moon of Mount Emei shines on Qinchuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai himself resumed his status as a commoner and never went to Chang&#39;an again, just like he left his hometown of Jiangyou, Sichuan when he was 24 years old and never returned in his life. In October 2023, Southern Weekend reporters revisited the two places to explore his wanderings between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9610ad4dd1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9610ad4dd1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259843&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Want to go up to the sky and embrace the bright moon&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was 20 years old, he and another writer Zhang Shuo were known as &quot; Su Ting, who was &quot;extremely generous&quot;, went to Chengdu to take up his post. Li Bai took the opportunity to visit him on the way with his poems. Su Ting admired the young man in front of him very much, and said to his staff: &quot;This young scholar has outstanding talent, and his writing style is like a flowing river. Although his current writing is not strong enough, he already has a unique style. If he continues to grow His knowledge will definitely be comparable to that of Sima Xiangru in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Perhaps Li Bai did not expect that this was already the most glorious visit in his life. In the next twenty-two years, he experienced various failures and setbacks in &quot;every prince&quot; and &quot;experienced ministers&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 730, Li Bai first came to Chang&#39;an. He lived in Princess Yuzhen&#39;s villa in Zhongnan Mountain, and also visited other princes and ministers, but to no avail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 734, he passed by Xiangyang, visited Han Chaozong and handed him the &quot;Book of Jingzhou with Han&quot;. Han Chaozong was known as a good scholar, but he was indifferent to Li Bai&#39;s request for recommendation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1120f704f1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1120f704f1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259844&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot;, the wandering Li Bai recited &quot;Quiet Night Thoughts&quot; under the moon. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Throughout his life, Li Bai never participated in the imperial examination, which was an extremely rare phenomenon among literati in the Tang Dynasty. One voice thinks that Li Bai disdains to participate, while the other is that Li Bai cannot participate. &lt;p>; qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Contemporary scholars such as Professor Lang Baoru of Inner Mongolia University interpret that even if it is not a &quot;family of industry and commerce&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s family &quot;hidden back to Guanghan in the early days of Shenlong&quot; and was not in the Ministry of Household Affairs Registration, no genealogy. Xiang Gong needs to provide documents that can prove his family background and identity, such as household registration and genealogy, for review by the Ministry of Household Affairs. People with &quot;unknown origins&quot; like Li Bai were naturally not eligible to be selected as tribute candidates by prefectures and counties and take part in the imperial examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai can only realize his ambition through other means. &quot;Roaming in the mountains and rivers, living in seclusion to study Taoism, making friends with Taoist priests, paying homage to local governors and ministers of the government and the public, all with the purpose of raising one&#39;s worth and creating a sensational effect in becoming famous in the capital and the emperor, and only then was Tianbao summoned to the capital.&quot; Chongqing Xiong Du, a professor at Technology and Business University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taoism was respected in the Tang Dynasty, and the royal family regarded Laozi and Li Er as their ancestors. During the Xuanzong period, respect for Laozi and Taoism reached its peak. From the emperor to his relatives, nobles and bureaucrats, everyone believed in Taoism. Xuanzong&#39;s two younger sisters, Princess Jinxian and Princess Yuzhen, simply became female Taoists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the age of 5, Li Bai lived in Changlong County, Mianzhou, central Sichuan (now Jiangyou City, Sichuan Province) for 19 years. As the birthplace of the Five Pecks of Rice Taoism, Shu Taoism is very popular and there are caves and heavens all over it. According to legend, Zhang Daoling, the founder of the sect, once lived in seclusion in Heming Mountain and preached in Qingcheng Mountain. There is still a Jinguang Cave in Qianyuan Mountain in Jiangyou, which is said to be the place where Nezha became a disciple and practiced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai was immersed in the atmosphere of Taoism. He visited famous Taoist mountains such as Mount Emei, Daitian Mountain, and Ziyun Mountain, and made many unique friends. He once lived in seclusion in the south of Minshan Mountain with Dong Yanzi, raised many birds, and learned the art of calling birds to his palm. Yuan Danqiu later became his best Taoist friend throughout his life, and invited him to visit Taoism in Songshan Mountain several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have traveled to the gods for fifteen years, and they have never stopped traveling. ... The jade boy in Xishan made me refine gold bones.&quot; &quot;Alchemy bones&quot; means refining elixirs. It seems that Li Bai was deeply influenced by Taoism at the age of fifteen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In traditional Chinese philosophy, Taoism is the philosophical category with the deepest exploration of the universe.&quot; Both Ding Ying and her father had an indissoluble bond with Li Bai. The father and daughter successively served as the director of the Li Bai Memorial Hall. She analyzed to the Southern Weekend reporter that Li Bai and Su Shi were both from Sichuan, and their poems were full of elegant and romantic atmosphere. &quot;We are in a basin, and it is difficult to get out. The only exit is the sky. Sichuan people have developed the habit of using their own brains to make up for the reality, so they all have magnificent imaginations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Modern people are no longer sure of the specific locations of the fairy mountains in Li Bai&#39;s works, but they may as well pay tribute and commemorate his enthusiasm. Today, there are more than 20 scenic spots in Jiangyou related to Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/bbdf37ed70.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/bbdf37ed70.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of young Li Bai in front of Longfeng Hall. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown in Qinglian Town, also known as Longxi Courtyard, has a colorful sculpture mountain gate screen wall and a courtyard left over from the Qianlong period of the Qing Dynasty. Residential. The Longfeng Hall, built in 2003, enshrines Li Er, the founder of Taoism, Li Guang, the general of the Western Han Dynasty, and Li Hao, the king of Xiliang in the Northern Dynasty - the latter two are ancestors jointly recognized by Li Bai and the Li Tang family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ef7f9cab54.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ef7f9cab54.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259846&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house in Li Bai’s hometown was rebuilt in the 53rd year of Qianlong’s reign in the Qing Dynasty (1788). Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​kilometer away from Longxi Hospital, there is a Taibai Temple. Wen Zaiqiao, director of Li Bai’s hometown, works here. He likes the tranquility here. . He mentioned to Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, when worship was still allowed, before the Mid-Autumn Festival every year, Guangdong businessmen would often come to the ancestral hall with their families and ask Taoist priests to perform rituals for three days. &quot;Li Bai likes the moon.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai never left Taoism throughout his life. However, there were many motivations for learning Taoism. Taoism&#39;s pursuit of freedom and eternity in individual life is exactly in line with Li Bai&#39;s pursuit of a spiritual state of indulgence and freedom. When he was politically frustrated, Li Bai often turned to mountains and rivers and wandering immortals. Taoism undoubtedly gave him spiritual comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The subtle relationship between studying Taoism and seeking official positions is much more secret. While the Tang Dynasty implemented the imperial examination system, it also recruited secluded wise men from time to time, asking them about political affairs, or asking them to come out to assist the king. Many of these people were Taoists. Xiong Du discovered that, compared with the strict scrutiny of family background in the imperial examination, talents specially ordered by the emperor could escape this rule. For example, Taoist figures such as Zhang Guo and Ye Fashan, who were rumored to have the secret of immortality, were recruited by the emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also speculated that the reason why Li Bai is good at immortal Taoism may be related to this, &quot;It is to create for Xuanzong that he not only has the talent of Wang Zuo, but also a You really have the impression of being an &#39;immortal&#39; with an &#39;immortal spirit&#39;, so that you can avoid the trouble of tracing your family background and place of origin when you join the officialdom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spirit of taking off your boots is still in your sleeves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Night shrouds Xi&#39;an, and the lights of the &quot;Datang Everlasting City&quot; commercial street at the foot of the Big Wild Goose Pagoda come on. &quot;Prosperity of the Tang Dynasty&quot; performances are being performed all over the street. Amidst the loud drum music, &quot;Li Bai&quot; dressed in white clothes slowly rises from the rotating lanterns. Every night, this NPC (non-player character) will come here to exchange poems with tourists, &quot;Everyone, come and listen to this one again, the most difficult one among Taibai&#39;s poems.&quot; What he throws out is &quot;Thoughts on a Quiet Night.&quot; There is also a &quot;Li Bai&quot; in Xi&#39;an. In the &quot;Twelve Hours of Chang&#39;an&quot; theme district, a certain liquor company has built a Taibai wine shop. He holds a wine bowl and invites tourists sitting at the table to drink with him while reciting &quot;The wine will come in&quot;. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the Datang West Market Museum, a middle-aged lady who came with a group from Anhui told a Southern Weekend reporter that she observed that people traveling to Xi&#39;an pay attention to &quot; The most popular ones are the Terracotta Warriors and Horses, and the current recommendation is Li Yang’s Love.” Her tour guide, Xiao Liu, a native of Xi&#39;an, talked about Li Bai twice in the museum, &quot;casually&quot;. He admitted that he didn&#39;t know Li Bai at all before working, and he had relatively little contact with him after working. Except for a few tourists who like history, most of them People are similar to themselves, &quot;After watching &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, I understand a little bit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai actually did not have a fixed residence in the Tang Dynasty. He neither bought a house, nor was it found in relevant documents that he rented it. So like Bai Juyi, as his official position rose, his residence was from the south of the city to the imperial city, so the status level determines the level of wealth.&quot; Mao Jingru, education specialist of Xi&#39;an Museum, told Southern Weekend reporters that in history, &quot;Chang&#39;an It is not a place where he (Li Bai) has lived for a long time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 742, Li Bai received Xuanzong&#39;s order to enter Chang&#39;an. During the Sui and Tang Dynasties, some northern Hu people&#39;s clothing became popular in society, including the &quot;black leather Liuhe boots&quot; worn by the Hu people. Later, the official officially designated it as the standard wear for officials, which is quite similar to the black leather shoes commonly worn in modern formal occasions. When he first arrived in Chang&#39;an, Li Bai was still wearing the white linen clothes that symbolized the common people. This time, he changed into a round-neck robe and black leather boots and entered the capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai wrote &quot;Nanling Farewell Children Entering Beijing&quot; before leaving, &quot;It is not early to persuade the children to endure the hardships, and ride the whip on the horse for the long journey. ... Looking up to the sky and laughing out loud &quot;How can I be a Penghao person?&quot; Years of depression were relieved, and the ideal of displaying talents and strategies was given the opportunity to be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he had the ambition of &quot;lobbying thousands of people&quot;, and the position he was awarded was Hanlin enshrinement, or Hanlin waiting for the imperial edict. Unlike Hanlin scholars who are in charge of edicts and participate in political affairs, Hanlin ministers are a group of professionals in various fields who stay by the emperor&#39;s side to serve him. They had the opportunity to have real positions after being favored by the emperor. For example, Wang Shuwen, who was good at playing chess, and Wang Qian, who was proficient in calligraphy, waited for the imperial edict, were appreciated by Dezong, and served as attendant readers and calligraphers, and were promoted step by step. However, Li Bai entered the Imperial Academy with poetry and prose as his skills, and he always stayed in the position of a literary attendant and never entered the formal bureaucratic ranks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As time passed, Li Bai, who was living in the Hanlin Academy, found that his political ideals were becoming disillusioned. &quot;It&#39;s easy for blue flies to get together, but it&#39;s hard for white snow to harmonize with each other. It&#39;s meant to be dispersed,&quot; he said. People have repeatedly criticized others and promoted criticism.&quot; Not only could they not be reused, they were also slandered and ostracized by others. Opportunities that once seemed close at hand are actually out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/895515d194.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/895515d194.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259847&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai once lamented in a poem that &quot;the road is difficult and divergent&quot;, but then he wrote, &quot;There will be long winds and waves, and the clouds and sails will rise across the sea.&quot; &quot;. The picture shows a still from the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an 30,000 Miles&quot;. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yangbing&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Thatched Cottage Collection&quot; and Liu Quanbai&#39;s &quot;Li Junjie Ji&quot; both pointed out that there were more than one or two people who slandered Li Bai. Wei Hao&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; names the slanderers: Xuanzong once intended to appoint Li Bai as Zhongshu Sheren, but he was slandered by his consort, Zhang Shuo&#39;s son Zhang Bian, and it was not realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, Li Bai&#39;s own political limitations are gradually being valued and emphasized. Zeng Yueyu and Zhou Shi described Li Bai&#39;s incompetent official performance in the novel &quot;Li Bai Trilogy&quot;: &quot;Li Bai has drafted several official edicts, which are related to the recent personnel changes in the DPRK. Logically, before the official announcement, the content must be strict Keep it secret. Li Bai, who was drunk, didn&#39;t care about that at all. He took advantage of the drunkenness to use the internal information as oral news, spreading it around regardless of occasion or location.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;There is no way to verify whether Li Bai ever drafted official documents, and the degree of leakage may not be as exaggerated as described, but there is evidence for such writing. Fan Chuanzheng, who wrote the inscription for Li Bai, said that he &quot;went in and out of the province while drunk, and had to talk about the greenhouse trees.&quot; Wang Qi of the Qing Dynasty also suspected that he &quot;had leaked the secrets of the ban while drunk, and the Ming Emperor ignored it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Fangmin, a professor at Northwest University, researched based on Li Zhao&#39;s &quot;Hanlin Chronicles&quot; that the Hanlin Academy in the Tang Dynasty had particularly strict requirements on work style. Any carelessness in words or deeds would be punished. It may ruin the political future. He concluded that those who served in the Hanlin Academy would be more cautious than bureaucrats in other institutions. He also discovered that Xuanzong himself had personal experience of the harm of drunkenness and had abstained from alcohol for the rest of his life. Therefore, Li Bai&#39;s addiction to drinking could not help but make Xuanzong worry about appointing him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For Li Bai, returning from the political center frustrated, being slandered and alienated can be said to be his true feelings at that time. However, due to his personality and officialdom Political alienation and conflicts led to another reason for his political failure, which was also obscured to some extent. In the final analysis, Li Bai&#39;s frustration in waiting for imperial edicts was the political failure of a talented poet.&quot; Li Fangmin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xuanzong, who once &quot;gave food on a bed of seven treasures and a spoon in his hand&quot;, gave the poet a grand courtesy, but whether he would let Li Bai participate in politics must be marked by a question mark. In Duan Chengshi&#39;s &quot;Youyang Zazu&quot;, Xuanzong said to Gao Lishi, &quot;This man is really poor.&quot; Meng Qi&#39;s &quot;Benshi Shi&quot; records that Xuanzong &quot;used it as a non-corridor temple vessel, so he dismissed it with an imperial edict.&quot; Everyone is saying that Li Bai left an impression on Xuanzong, and that this person was not worthy of elegance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The discord between Li Bai&#39;s celebrity temperament and officialdom is concentrated in the matter of &quot;taking off his boots&quot;. Academic circles have different opinions on whether Li Bai ever asked Gao Lishi to take off his boots. Some scholars regard it as a novelist&#39;s statement and cannot be trusted. Zhou Xunchu, a professor at Nanjing University, believes that although Gao Lishi was the most favored eunuch by Xuanzong, under normal circumstances, Li Bai would not have ordered him to take off his boots. However, &quot;Li Bai was wild in nature and was drunk, so there was no clear reason to exclude this matter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The movie &quot;The Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; combines the two anecdotes of Lishi taking off his boots and writing &quot;Qing Ping Tiao&quot;. Gao Lishi asked Li Bai to compose a poem for Yang Yuhuan, and Li Bai took off his boots. After two rounds of fighting, Gao Lishi reluctantly took off a black leather boot for Li Bai. Li Bai was half drunk and half awake while writing &quot;Qing Ping Diao&quot;, which was praised by Yang Yuhuan, but Li Bai bluntly said that he did not write it specifically for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Tang Dynasty is really amazing if you have you.&quot; In the movie, Yang Yuhuan appreciates this sincerity. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The moon shines on Qinchuan on Mount Emei&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 744, on a spring night in Chang&#39;an City where flowers were blooming, Li Bai drank wine alone. There was no one around, but he was determined not to drink the contents of the cup quietly, so he sang and danced wildly, inviting the bright moon in the sky and the lonely shadow on the ground to drink together. He wants to get drunk, and then heaven, earth, and himself will cease to exist, and everything that is not going as he wants will be annihilated. At this time, it was less than two years since Li Bai was waiting for imperial edict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On an autumn night half a year ago&lt;/span>;, he was slandered and shunned in the officialdom, and his ambitions were difficult to realize. The frustrated Li Bai thought of the moon in his hometown: &quot; The dim clouds are falling, and the love of the past is dim. The green rose moon on the autumn mountain, who will see it tonight?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Finally, he left Chang&#39;an, leaving only Read such masterpieces as &quot;Drinking Alone Under the Moon&quot; and &quot;Wine to Ask the Moon&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, Li Bai had gone through two-thirds of his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;On the Nine Heavens of Chang&#39;an Palace, this place was once a close minister.&quot; Everything suddenly disappeared and became a memory. Li Bai&#39;s hope of finding a way out in the court was shattered, and he urgently needed to find spiritual sustenance. His deceased wife left behind a pair of children, but the time he spent with the children was far less than the amount of time he spent practicing Taoism in seclusion with the Taoist priests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Ziji Palace of the Taoist Temple in Jinan, Li Bai asked the Taoist priest Gao Rugui to teach him the Taoism and became a Taoist priest. From the time when Tianbao left Chang&#39;an in the late spring of the third year of Tianbao&#39;s reign, to when he traveled south to Wuyue in the fifth year of Tianbao&#39;s reign, this was the period when he was most worldly-minded. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Du Fu and Li Bai also met at this time. Du Fu experienced the blow of failing the imperial examination, and with a common depressing mood, he saw the depth and persistence behind Li Bai&#39;s wild and unrestrained attitude. &quot;We spend our days drinking and singing wildly, who is the hero of flying and domineering.&quot; This sympathy for each other continued in the lives of the two poets, even if they never met again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While wandering in the south, Li Bai kept witnessing the disappearance of old friends, and his mentality changed. When he arrived in Siming (now Shaoxing, Zhejiang), he paid homage to He Zhizhang, who died of illness here, and missed the years when they met in Chang&#39;an to exchange wine with each other. While in Jinling, another series of bad news came: his friend Cui Chengfu was demoted, Li Shizhi was forced to commit suicide, and Li Yong and Pei Dunfu were killed with a stick. Li Linfu, who was in power, was imprisoned many times, unjust cases appeared one after another, and the government and the public were filled with an atmosphere of terror. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai could no longer feel safe in seclusion. He often worried about the fate of the country, and his passion for serving the world deep in his heart burned again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He often expressed his longing to retire to the wild mountains and rivers, but whenever he had the opportunity, he always expressed his desire to return to the court immediately. He just couldn&#39;t get rid of going to the emperor&#39;s side. The ideal and desire to achieve great things,&quot; Ha Jin wrote in &quot;The Road to Heaven: The Biography of Li Bai.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After getting married for the second time in Liang Yuan, he went north to the land of Youyan, hoping to seek development by joining the army. In the poem presented to the judge He Changhao, Li Bai&#39;s intention is obvious. He is ashamed to be a scholar of Zhangju, and he is unwilling to be like Geng Yin. He actually wants to rise up with a sword and collect extraordinary achievements in the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On this trip north, Li Bai arrived at the jurisdiction of Anlu Mountain, and perhaps saw clearly the truth that the latter was preparing to rebel. Li Bai returned frustrated. He felt helpless against the internal and external troubles of the Li Tang Dynasty, so he could only seek seclusion in the south again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Besides studying Taoism, Li Bai, who has stars on his temples, is increasingly aware of the importance of one thing. &quot;Knowing what is wrong at fifty is what the ancients have done. If you make up for your mistakes with words, you will live forever.&quot; &quot;I am determined to delete the story and reflect it for thousands of years.&quot; He made it clear that there is no hope of meritorious service, and perhaps his destiny is to make words. It can also be said that Li Bai truly became aware of his identity as a poet when he was around fifty years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s first wandering ended with the scene of entering Chang&#39;an; the last wandering also had an event that brought it to an end, that is, joining the team of Yongwang Li Lin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, the Anshi Rebellion broke out, and people fled the war and were displaced. Wang Changling returned to his hometown, and when passing through Jianghuai, he was killed by the governor who hated him. Du Fu moved his family to Yanzhou for refuge. He heard that after Suzong ascended the throne in Lingwu, he went north to Lingwu and was captured by the rebels on the way and taken to Chang&#39;an. The poet Wang Wei was taken prisoner to Luoyang by the rebels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai and his wife Zong fled south to seek refuge and lived in seclusion in Lushan Mountain. He once planned to lobby the Li Tang clan in Jiangnan to raise troops to serve the king, and had dealings with both Xu Wang Yannian and Wu Wang Zhi. It happened that Yong Wang Li Lin raised his army and patrolled eastward to Xunyang. He repeatedly invited him to be an aide, and Li Bai finally agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is 56 years old and this is probably his last chance. This person with a complex of the Eastern Jin Dynasty feels that the old dream of the previous dynasty is right in front of him. At the end of the Jin Dynasty, the Five Husties disrupted China, and the Eastern Jin Dynasty established its country in Jinling, inheriting the lineage of the Central Plains. Will the Anshi Rebellion achieve Li Bai just like the Battle of Feishui in the previous dynasty achieved Xie An? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Fangmin understood that it was inevitable for Li Bai to join the Yongwang Li Lin. This move combined the objective situation and subjective wishes. He speculated that when Li Lin&#39;s lobbyist Wei Zichun was lobbying Li Bai, he hinted that Li Lin&#39;s actions in Jiangling and even on the eastward tour were in accordance with Xuanyuan&#39;s purpose and had the strategic purpose of managing Jiangnan. With these, he was able to impress Li Bai, who had an old love for Xuanzong as a monarch and a minister, and once again inspired his desire to help the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Lin was defeated, Li Bai was downgraded from a capital crime to a first-class crime, and was sentenced to Changliu Yelang. He set out from Xunyang, traveled to Dongting, and went up to the Three Gorges. When he first arrived in Wushan, he encountered a nationwide amnesty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, the counter-insurgency war was still going on. Not only was a large area of ​​land north of the Yellow River in Shi Siming&#39;s hands, but the rebels continued to invade the south. The situation was very serious. After wandering for thousands of miles, Li Bai once again had the idea of ​​​​serving the world. In Jiangxia, the political center of the south, while waiting for news about his friend Wei Liangzai in the capital, he went to visit some officials and waited for several months. , the imperial court showed no sign of conscription. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; I hopeless, Li Bai thought of making poems at this time. &quot;Qu Ping&#39;s words are hanging from the sun and the moon, and the king of Chu is empty hills.&quot; He compared the two kinds of life of Qu Yuan and King Chu: Qu Yuan was loyal and loved the country, but he was exiled, but his resignation could compete with the sun and the moon. Poor and extravagant desire to build palace towering pavilions, and now it is gone in the early days, and it is empty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai has compiled a collection three times before his birth. Once was invited Han Dongqian, once it was Wei Yan, and the other was his uncle Li Yangbing. Qian Gong&#39;s manuscript, I do not know what to do. Wei Yan followed Li Bai thousands of miles, and the two were covered with the same way, and Li Bai gave him all the manuscripts at the time. Wei Bai is the editor selected by Li Bai in the condition of his health and thoughtfulness, but the &quot;Li Hanlin Collection&quot; compiled by Li Bai is mostly the residual volume of the &quot;chapters of the sentence&quot; of Anshi. Li Bai couldn&#39;t afford to be sick in his later years, and he was too late to sort out the draft. There was only one Li Yangbing around him. The poem is entrusted on the pillow, there is no choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai was 60 years old, returned to Puyang, and then boarded Lushan, and decided to spend the remaining years with Youxian Dao. However, after all, he could not do the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; When he heard that the power of history is re-prosperous, Li Guangzhang sent troops to suppress, and resolutely asked to participate, and returned because of the disease. Li Bai is old. But his popularity since he was young has never extinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;His understanding of things, his political ideals and thinking have been like this for a lifetime. People like us will not know himself ten years ago, but he has maintained a innocent young man&#39;s heart from youth to twilight. &quot;Ding Ying sighed to reporters from the south weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 762 years, Dai Zong is ascended, and searched for Junyi to grant Li Baizuo&#39;s official position. When the order came, Li Bai had died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The cause of Li Bai&#39;s death, there are divergent opinions, &quot;jumping the river and catching the moon&quot; or &quot;riding a whale to catch the moon&quot; has always been talked about. Japanese sinologist Matsuura Kojan believes that these legends are sensitive to Li Bai&#39;s hobby. Li Bai&#39;s existence of the moon is unconditionally affirmed, and he tries to pursue integration with the Mingyue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Bai Juyi, who was born in Li Bai in the 71st year of Li Bai, left the Li Bai tomb in Anhui, leaving a seven rhythm. There are shocking places. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; One thousand years later, Gong Zizhen said in &quot;The Most Record Li Bai Collection&quot;: &quot;Zhuang (Zhou), Qu (Original) Real two, not merged, not, And think about the heart, the beginning. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d4e3.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d4e35ee3.jpg &quot;data-&quot; 259848 &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Taibai Monument, the inscriptions are mainly Li Bai&#39;s poems written by famous calligraphy and painting masters and praised Li Bai&#39;s couplet poems. Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuanwan &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;People do not see the ancient moon today, this month used to follow the ancients.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探寻“光影世界”之外的李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261467]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 15:05:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; Animated movies, TV shows, games, drama ... all kinds of works are based on Li Bai as the protagonist, summoning more than 1,300 more than 1,300 The soul of the year ago. In 2023, why do people talk about Li Bai?</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[滴滴“崩了”的12小时：损失千万订单量和超4亿成交额]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261466]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 14:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; At about 10:30 am on November 28th, according to the southern+reporters, it was found that the reporter was measured in Guangzhou in Guangzhou. At present, Didi Chuxing, including online ride -hailing and shared bicycles, has returned to normal, and this comprehensive functional paralysis lasted for nearly 12 hours, which is also the longest failure of Didi Chu Paralysis in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the third quarter of the 2023 financial report released by Didi Chuxing, the total transaction volume of China ’s travel business in the single quarter was 72.5 billion yuan, and the average daily single volume reached 31.3 million. The failure of the &quot;failure time, it is estimated that it will lose more than 10 million orders and transaction volume over 400 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The cause of the long collapse of the Didi Chuxing APP has not responded to Didi Chuxing as of the time of press time. Didi&#39;s own computer room network problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Data show that as a network service with high requirements for data volume response, the frequency of Didi Chuxing&#39;s failure is not low. On September 22, 2022, users&#39; feedback Didi Chuxing could not be used normally. At that time, Didi Chuxing responded that &quot;due to the network failure of the computer room, some of the services of Didi were affected.&quot; At that time, the failure had been repaired within half a year. On February 25, 2021, &quot;Didi collapsed&quot; also appeared on the hot search. Didi Chuxing replied at the time that it was because of &quot;system abnormalities&quot; and quickly resolved the problem. In the earlier October 2019 and July 2016 and October 2015, Didi also had a system failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that the cloud service of Didi Chuxing is mainly supported by Didi Cloud. According to Didi Cloud&#39;s official website, Didi Chuxing&#39;s cloud computing services are based on Didi Chuxing&#39;s business technology and experience accumulation. It adopts leading cloud computing architecture, high-specification server cluster construction, high-performance resource allocation mechanism, and refined operation model, and is committed to Yu provides developers with simple, fast, efficient, stable, cost -effective, safe and reliable IT infrastructure cloud services. According to southern+reporters, as early as March this March, Didi Cloud no longer provided public cloud services. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Didi.com and other services have been restored? Real measurement of reporters: &quot;Paralysis&quot; in Guangzhou &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; On the morning of November 28, according to the reporter in Guangzhou Completely solved, Didi Chuxing&#39;s online car rental service still cannot be accurately located, and the green orange bicycle cannot scan the code. The system will display &quot;the system will drive a small difference, please try it later.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/634912d001c6227b916Fa85968.JPEG&quot; &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; OPAC it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 1422 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/634912d001c6227B95968.jpeg &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;259865&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/739F6A430C50CA5B142bf5b06FFFF.JPEG&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPACI Ty: 1; &quot;width = &quot;640&quot; height = &quot;1422&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/739F6A430CA5B142bf1bef56fff.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;2 59864 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In addition, Didi Chuxing told the south+reporters that the inconvenience caused by the failure caused by the occurrence of the Didi Chuxing APP is &quot;very sorry&quot;, and it is still working hard to solve the problem. Users pay attention to safety. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Didi Chuxing: services such as online car rental have been restored, and services such as cycling are still being restored. &lt;p>; On the morning of November 28, Didi Chuxing&#39;s official Weibo posted that the technical team was repaired overnight, and the services such as Didi.com have been restored. Cycling and other services are still being restored, and all Qingju vehicles that can be unlocked or unlocked can be ridden for free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/8903bee1065a927825016b0bbff.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPAC it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 626 &quot;height =&quot; 712 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/8903bee1065a927825016b0bbff.png &quot;data- key = &quot;259866&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[上班要不要强制穿工服，这是一个问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260326]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 13:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some netizens attended the classmate gathering, and a total of ten people came. As a result, three classmates who worked in different financial institutions were almost the same in work clothes. Different units today have different requirements for dressing. Some require employees to wear work clothes at work, while others do not require. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This seems to be a small problem, but it is not. For example, in September, the U.S. Senate was not allowed to make a fellowship because of whether parliamentarians entered the parliamentary building. In the end, the US Senate Modified Standards: Allow senators to wear hoodie and shorts. This move has attracted criticism from mainstream media such as the New York Times and the Washington Post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The world&#39;s institutions, companies, and organizations face a choice question on employees&#39; dressing: Do you want to dress uniformly? What are the considerations or not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/tqrexqi6pppqr6nfmev6iqb9pvta67a.jpeg&quot; widt = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;667&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/tqrexqi6pp7lbrxzwlpqr6iqb9pvta67a.jpeg&quot; data-key = &quot;259823&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot; >; Real considerations of unified dress &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The so-called &quot;work service&quot; is actually from the same institution or organization, wearing uniform costumes to identify it to identify it Identity, showing their occupations, showing their duties. Generally speaking, work clothes are uniform, rigorous, and individualized, which is different from the personal dress of employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; From the perspective of a company, employees in work uniforms often have realistic considerations. First, this is a need for shaping the image of an enterprise. The employees are unified and neat and orderly, which will leave the preliminary impression of the enterprise&#39;s rigorous and serious, positive and upward impression; the unified workwear generally has the company&#39;s logo, which can play a propaganda role in the image of the enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Second, for those who have more communication with customers and customers, such as the financial industry and the lawyers industry Professional perception helps to dispel the doubts of customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For the job, when wearing a unified professional worker, it can play a psychological suggestion, help yourself enter the state of work, improve your work, and improve your work. execution ability. At the same time, wearing work clothes can also restrict the personal behavior of the staff, reminding him not only the personal image, but also the image of the unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are also some special occupations, uniformly pretending to reflect the authority and seriousness of the occupation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;比如我国对一些公权力机构提出了统一着装的要求，其中就包括公安部门、国家安全部门、司法部门、法院系统、检察院系统、 Customs systems, tax systems, national quality inspection departments, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In contrast, the reason why the US Senate relaxed the requirements for clothing was caused because public opinion was worried that this would harm the seriousness of Congress. The New York Times wrote like this: In the current division of the United States, one of the last harmonious signs of the Senate is the decoration specification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Although it cannot eliminate the profound differences under the surface, it does remind each senator that their goal is still the consensus of most people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are also some occupations unified dress, which is determined by the characteristics of the occupation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For example, the doctor&#39;s white coat is the earliest to promote the disinfection habits in surgery. The white coat also helps doctors to prevent static electricity during treatment. Many medical devices are very precise instruments. The effects of static electricity on equipment may mislead the results of diagnosis and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; When a doctor enters the operating room, he wore a blue or green surgical jacket, which has something to do with &quot;visual retention&quot;. During the surgery, when the doctor saw the patient&#39;s red blood, when he moved his eyes to the doctor&#39;s white robe, the phenomenon of &quot;color replenishment&quot; appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As long as the doctor looks at the red complementary color of the red-such as blue or green, it can immediately alleviate the role of &quot;color replenishment&quot; and slow visual fatigue, so surgery Most of the service will use blue -green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/28kkdyi9mv0KEF1GEF1GEF1Gen4exeibztev2.jpeg&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;720&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/28kkdyi9mv0KEF1GEF1GEF1GEF1Gen4exeibzxTev2.jpeg&quot; Data-Key = &quot;259824&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot; >; Relaxation requirements are not necessarily bad. &lt;/H4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some units and institutions require unified dress, with reasonable reasons, but this does not mean that uniform dressing is suitable for all all to all of all Units do not mean that uniform costumes are favorable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some people who have experienced the 1970s and 1980s may be impressed by the &quot;unified dress&quot; of that era. At that time, there was a name called &quot;law enforcement&quot;, and all a public unit would be uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the one hand, it reflects the sense of honor, &quot;there is a head&quot;; on the other hand, the work uniform is the &quot;invisible benefits&quot; of the unit, and some units take the staff The clothing all year round was packed, but the finances were paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So that some industries and personnel who did not have the functions of administrative management were also uniformly dressed, and they moved closer to the dressing of the law enforcement department. It has damaged the seriousness of the law enforcement department, wasted the finances, and also had a bad impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, starting from 1986, the State Council rectified the unified dress. In 1988, 1991, 1992, 2003, the State Council issued a unified dress issue. Related notices, criticizing those departments that uniformly uniform dressing, &quot;not only affect the seriousness of uniform dressing, but also lead to increasing fiscal expenditure.&quot; Later, the State Council also made clear stipulation on the unified dressing department and personnel. It can be seen that it is not uniform or good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unified dressing will bring constraints, stereotypes, and uncomfortable feelings to some professionals. Therefore, many employees opposed the unified dress. A British survey showed that 61%of the people looking for new jobs in 2017 said they would have a negative view of any company that executed the decoration specifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In order to fight monotonous uniform clothes, the Western workplace was born in the Western workplace. On the day, at least on this day, you can grasp the autonomy of dressing and be free to be yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another study shows that if the dressing requirements are easier, most British labor will feel higher efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Those big companies that pay attention to creative ideas often do not require employees&#39; dressing, such as Microsoft and Facebook. Although the employees may be different, such as the programmer loves a plaid shirt, Zuckerberg wore the same casual clothes every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; These technology companies not only do not require employees, they will also improve the work environment. Stimulate employees&#39; imagination and creativity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In short, it is difficult to generalize whether employees need to be unified. Some occupations emphasize seriousness, and some occupations value the perception that they bring to customers. Some occupations have special occupational attributes, and some occupations are more concerned about how to maximize the creativity ... Different demands are facing pretending to pretend to pretend to be pretending to be. There are different requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For the staff, the unified dressing problem is not so big, if the unit is free to send the work service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南开段峰：“拿着金饭碗讨饭”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261413]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; In June 2022, Duan Feng team implemented an intervention brain interface in the sheep brain for the first time; one year later In May 2023, led by Duan Feng&#39;s team, the first &quot;non -human spiritual long animal (monkey) interventional brain machine jointly completed by the Duan Feng team (301 Hospital) and Shanghai Xinwei Medical Technology Co., Ltd. &quot;Interface Test&quot; successful. This study has been believed by many media that the disadvantages of the invasive and non -invasive brain interfaces have been overcome, and the third new paradigm of the brain interface has been created. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Duan Feng, 46, is currently a professor, doctoral supervisor, and the director of the key laboratory of Tianjin&#39;s intervention of brain machines and intelligent rehabilitation. Due to the outstanding results of Duan Feng in the fields of brain -machine interface, artificial hibernation and smart aircraft, he was elected as a science and innovation person in the Southern Weekend 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the southern weekend science and technology conference&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/298bbbf676.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/imedias/23/11/27/298bbbf6766 .jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259781 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the southern weekend conference of science and technology innovation conferences &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the definition of the Chinese Communications Institute, the Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) technology is a transformed human-computer interaction. Establish a new communication and control channel with external equipment, which has the effect of monitoring, replacement, improvement/restoration of damage or obstacles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a cutting -edge technology with multidisciplinary interdisciplinary. It can not only assist in the diagnosis and treatment of some neurological diseases, half part or fully realize the compensation of certain human functions, and it is expected to cure some psychological diseases. Medical is considered to be its most market prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are three main implementation methods of brain machine interfaces, non -invasive, invasive and vascular intervention. Non -invasive brain -type interface mainly refers to collecting brain electrical signals in the brain scalp layer, without surgery; invading type requires implantation of electrodes into deep brain parts, and surgery such as craniotomy and drilling bone; Electric electrical signals are collected into the corresponding inner wall of the corresponding blood vessels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the research of the brain interface is mostly in the basic research stage, and it has also achieved some clinical results. In June 2022, researchers at Johns Hopkins University completed the world&#39;s first bilateral transplantation of bilateral -integrated brain interface human trials. A 30 -year -old subject successfully controlled the machinery through brain electrical signals and completed Delivery cakes and autonomous food; in China, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital started the brain -pass interface and deep brain electrical stimulation method in 2020 to treat refractory depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the addition of Meta and &quot;Silicon Valley Iron Man&quot; Elon Musk (Neuralink, Elon Musk, the entry of the brain interface in recent years has increased unprecedentedly. Duan Feng was also established in 2023 The company tried to transform the results of the brain interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, since the return of Japan in 2009, he has been on the way to grasp teaching and research and starting a business with one hand. To this end, he did not plant a few followers. &quot;10 years of 100 billion yuan, do it,&quot; also became his &quot;test gold stone&quot; that he tested whether investors sincerely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The following is the interview with Duan Feng on the southern weekend: &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Want to build a &quot;integrated industry, research, research integration&quot; platform &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; From the perspective of academic background, you obtained a master&#39;s degree from the School of Mechanical Engineering, Tianjin University, and studied for precision mechanical engineering at the University of Tokyo, Japan. Degree, entrepreneurially chose medical rehabilitation equipment because it has always been interested in machinery? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I took the college entrance examination in 1998. The major I want to learn is actually electronics. The file was filled with obedience and distribution, and was adjusted to the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University. Studying in Japan is also an accidental choice. During the master&#39;s degree, the instructor sent me to two engine companies to cooperate. At that time, the mechanical industry was downturn and went to the family to close the family. It was very embarrassing. It happened that the enrollment of the University of Tokyo, Japan, not only exempt from the application fee, but also provided scholarships, round -trip air tickets and accommodation. The conditions are very good. I chose precision manufacturing related to machinery in their admissions major. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How did you turn to the brain interface? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I have studied intelligent service robots and unitized flexible production lines in Japan. Go to the brain interface. I first heard the concept of the brain interface at a lecture at the University of Tokyo. At that time, I felt very interesting, but at that time, I couldn&#39;t share my body to study in depth. The biggest reason is that I want to copy Japan&#39;s &quot;industry -university -research&quot; model in China. During my studies in Japan, I encountered many companies to go to colleges and universities to ask students to eat, use talents, provide students with scholarships, provide teachers with scientific research project funds, and realize the integration of &quot;industry -university -research&quot;. Rare. After graduating, I returned to China to enter Nankai University. After completing the teaching task, I could study the fields I am interested in, and then set out to build a company to industrialize the research results. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How did you start a business at that time? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I taught at the university while understanding the market situation. Specifically, it is something that is urgently needed to cooperate with enterprises to develop markets but has half a step left in technology development. At that time, some friends introduced some small medical device enterprise cooperation assistive device products, which was the type of limb movement with external forces, but it was not autonomous exercise. I hope to be an instrument that can be used by people to control the device to drive physical exercise, but I don&#39;t want to sell products, because it needs a series of problems such as equipment registration, quality inspection, and business promotion, so I anchor the technical research and development of the front end of the product. When I first returned to China, the monthly salary was only 3800 yuan, the rent was 2,000 yuan, the child&#39;s kindergarten tuition fee was 1,500 yuan, and there were only 300 yuan per month. I think most entrepreneurs should have more money than me. Because I have no money, I have always pinned the hope of raising money to find partners or investors, so I also took a lot of detours and experienced a process of registering, cancellation, re -registration, and cancellation. The east wall supplemented the west wall, there was a difficult period. Earlier I considered making some small rehabilitation stimulating equipment. A company talked to me about cooperation and asked me to do the front -end research and development. Zi, there is nothing behind it. There are also companies that let me share their technology and promise to give their equity. As a result, we have cooked money, spent time, and invested a lot of energy. After the technical molding, the &quot;partner&quot; ran away. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How did the start-up start gold solved? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; Selling technology is saved. It is to help the enterprise develop what they need, and then sell it. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The impact on you is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is you. What? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I am also reflecting and summarizing it myself, whether it is scientific research or industry, and ask myself if this is the matter What I really want to do, if no one wants to do, I want to do it, then it should be done. When I do n’t pin my hope on others, rely on my own efforts and persistence to do what I want to do, many people who help me take the initiative to find it. Some bring money, some bring resources. Others bring some new ideas and ideas, and slowly this matter. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; No &quot; Is it &quot;liar&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; When you have some &quot;step on the pit&quot; experience, it is easier to evaluate the risk of the person. Now come to me to talk about In a few minutes, you can know if it is suitable. I will not accept other people&#39;s investment casually. Some people come to me to talk about. I usually ask a question, &quot;10 years of 100 billion, do you do?&quot; If you don&#39;t want, don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. Here, it is okay, no, no, there is no middle area. These 100 billion were not coming to make a picture of the head, and it was scientifically estimated. I do an interface test of the blood vessel intervention -type brain machine. Each electrode is grinded by hand by hand. This takes 24 hours to run for 10 days to make one. Get up at least 100,000 yuan; if you use a large animal monkey for experiments, buy a monkey 200,000 yuan, and you need to spend 300 yuan a day. This cost is very high. &quot;Ten years of 100 billion&quot; is only used to test whether investors have patience and sincerity to accompany the product to grow, not to say that someone must take out 100 billion yuan. If the other party spent how much time and how much money, there is no minimum perception of possible investment returns. Come and say that they are familiar with the people of the governments of other local governments. To do our best, these are not partners we will choose. We also hope to cooperate with ideal and ideal people. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Whether an invasive or non-invasive formula, it is not optimistic. Kaita_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Research on brain interfaces in the past few years is very hot. What are the advantages and disadvantages of invasive and non -invasive brain machine interfaces? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Non -invasive brain machine interface, because it is non -invasive and safer. It mainly collects nerve discharge signals gathered on the surface of the scalp. Because this signal collection must be through the skull and layer of tissue cells, and there are more interference signals of the scalp, so the collected brain electrical signals are not very stable, collect some large large large, collect some large large large, collect some large large, and collect some large large. The action brain electrical signal is okay, but the time is long or the actions are finely identified. The invasive brain interface is to implant the electrode in the brain by turning on the skull. If you want to collect signals in a certain aspect, you need to implant the electrode into the corresponding brain area. Generally, within half a year, the signal collected by the invasive brain machine interface is more accurate, and the effect of human -machine interaction is also better. For example, the completion of the control of robotic arms grasping items is relatively high. But after half a year, it is difficult to say, because the electrode is harmful to the brain, it may be rejected, pus can be used, and the accumulation of scar tissue can be easily formed around the electrode. The damage is also relatively large. Therefore, its sustainability is very poor, and the brain electrical signal collected in the later period will also weaken, and it will not even be a signal. This is also a fatal short board for intrusion brain machine interface. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; September 2023, the invasive brain of neuralink The machine interface began to recruit clinical trial objects. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Entry -type damage is great, but there are still many companies to do. What is a person? Is it carbon -based creature? What are these electrode materials? People are fundamentally compatible with these materials. I have done a mouse&#39;s invasive brain -type interface, and the mice are dead. Musk also died before the test of Musk. This direction is problematic in terms of long -term security. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body _gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Why do you do this &quot;the first non-world non-world non Human spiritual animal (monkey) intervention brain interface test &quot;? How do you choose animal type and what is the test process? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; Try &lt;span>; Whenever it was done in June 2022, and it was originally to verify the feasibility of the interventional brain interface. Although there are some relevant reports internationally, it is true and false, and only after verification can it be known. In terms of details, such as verifying the sensor, can it last for more than half a year in the brain of animals. For blood vessel intervention -type brain machine interfaces, too small animals, such as mice, the blood vessels are too fine electrode cables. Although the sheep&#39;s blood vessels are thinner than humans, they are relatively thicker and the price is cheap. Basic movements can be distinguished Come out; after the test is successful, then test the monkey, let the monkey&#39;s initiative to control the robotic arm to grab food, because monkeys are a species similar to human beings. There is no problem in it. . The overall process is more tortuous. It is not a problem to find the partners and venues such as the hospital and the laboratory, because everyone knows that this is a very new study. Later, there are good papers, and it is good to get projects. There are also certain market prospects. The difficulty is that during the epidemic period, many engineers and students are often closed and often controlled. They need to think of various methods to coordinate personnel. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot; in January this year, Synchron in the United States announced it. The clinical trial of the &quot;vascular intervention&quot; brain machine interface successfully allowed four paralyzed subjects to control external equipment and completed the operation of sending text messages, personal financial management, and online shopping. How to understand that some media tell your research as &quot;the new paradigm of the third brain interface&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; It is recommended not to interpret it without conmics. This &quot;pioneering&quot; and &quot;the world&#39;s first case&quot; must be seen together. When making sheep test, it actually refers to the new paradigm of the third brain interface in China, because no one has done related research in China; the world&#39;s first case is that I am the first in the world to do it on the monkey species. People with such experiments. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the test was successful, it brought you to you What are the influence? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In terms of mentality, there is no impact, I see very flat. According to our plan, this experiment will immediately enter the clinical stage, that is, to test on people, but the ethical review phase of the hospital is currently in the hospital. But I did receive some volunteer emails. I was impressed. A lady was lying on the ICU, who hoped that her husband would participate in the clinical trial of the brain interface; and a grandson to save his grandma, the child must be a volunteer; there is a blind man, and there are blind people I want to restore me ... These faith are very touching, but our test ethics have not yet been recruited. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Some scholars believe that &quot;the development of brain machine interfaces It is currently in the bottleneck period, and the research of new principles and new technologies to drive related fields into the next rapid development period. &quot;What do you think? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The current research on brain machine interface technology is indeed in a bottleneck period. Many problems about the existence of brain machine interfaces are now. Global issues are not unique to China. There are too many players, whether it is non -invasive or invasive track, if you can make achievements long ago, there are too many smart people, and there are many money capitalists. At present, everyone is in a relatively stagnant state. To some extent, there is a problem with this road. It is recommended that you consider changing the track. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I am not optimistic about the invasion or non -invasive type, because I have done it, and there are many companies or institutions in China. Have done. In China, the focus of the industry is still non -invasive. Everyone is crowded on this track and has to traffic jams. But I do n’t follow any industry, and I am currently focusing on the brain interface technology of vascular intervention. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; I hope more people can do research at ease. , Stkaiti; &quot;>; Many people currently focus on the industrialization of rehabilitation medical brain interfaces. Why? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; Patients in this field are large and the number of patients is large. Exercise, so the market potential is relatively large. In addition, it is not difficult to technology, and some low -threshold products are better. As long as companies can integrate and get corresponding certification licenses, companies can quickly realize. In the future, if the price of products drops again, such as a product of 100,000 yuan becomes 20,000, the demand will be higher. There are two main chains in rehabilitation medical care, one innovative chain and one are the industrial chain. The industrial chain is to low -end high -end technology into product sinking. After sinking, more people can be used. After more people, there are more data in scientific research. There are more data. After the data, it will be fed back to the innovation chain to form better technology and better products. What I currently build is such a dual -chain cycle platform. So I did not worry about making specific products, but calmed down to make the electrode. After the electrode automation was completed, it could serve many products. My entrepreneurship is a relatively stupid situation, which is equivalent to holding a golden rice bowl for meals. My positioning for myself is not to do specific, low -end, and repetitive things, but to make the enterprise a platform and the core system for rehabilitation medical care for brain machine interfaces. In the future, this platform will also be open. ，可以让更多的人、企业、机构，在这个平台上一起来做事。只要他们别忽悠我，踏踏实实想干事，都欢迎。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;目前中国脑机接口产业化的整体生态是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;段峰：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得现阶段关于脑机接口的概念过热，也有一些不负责的媒体为了博眼球，用噱头来偷换概念。比如那种闪烁的图片，实际上就是视觉诱发的脑电信号，是一种条件反应，在媒体的报道中却被描述成用“意念”操控，好像很玄幻，其实很简单。就脑机接口企业来说，实际上真正能耐得住寂寞去做底层研发的人不多，因为底层研发太烧钱了，而且短期看不到现金回报。我由衷希望行业里有更多的人愿意踏踏实实做好基础研究。现在的投资者也不存在盲目跟投的情况，因为大家都没什么钱，可能因为炒概念的挺多的，所以真正有耐心陪伴创新型企业成长的人不多。这种投资者我也不愿意接受他们的投资。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你看来，国内脑机接口相应的产品开发，亟待解决的问题是什么？最为紧缺的是哪类人才？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;段峰：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得未来理想的脑机接口产品应该是通过血管介入实现的，为了实现这一目标，目前亟须解决电极的稳定性问题，在稳定性有保障之后，再想办法实现自动化生产，以降低产品的成本。从人才涉及的专业领域看，需要更多的跨领域的、复合型人才。比如在材料、加工、机械、电路、医学等领域至少在两个以上的领域有交叉。最为关键的，是这些人能够静下心来踏实做事，不会今天这家工资高去这家，明天那个领域赚钱去那里，没有情怀的人，做不好事。在这个前提下，还要有很好的悟性，有独立思考和探索的能力。这两者都很重要。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了脑机接口，你还有其他研究Simultaneously? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;段峰：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们目前同时进展的还有可以垂直起飞的智能飞行器、大鼠的人工冬眠。后续我们希望人工冬眠的试验可以跟介入式脑机接口结合，把特殊刺激信号，通过血管内的电极刺激，来影响全脑，或者通过这种方式改造大脑，让人冬眠，未来可以把这个技术应用在一些医疗救治领域。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[风波过后，脱口秀行业复苏在望？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data-style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 18px;&quot;>;开放麦演出锐减&amp;nbsp;演员另谋出路&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;今年5月，脱口秀行业经历了一系列整改。 Among all cities, the most affected one is Shanghai. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;知情人士向记者透露，自5月清查行动以来，上海大部分脱口秀俱乐部所在的黄浦区文旅部门增强了对演出内容的监管力度，每周对演出录像的抽查也更为严谨，演员须严格按照报批内容来进行演出。如果演出录像与报批内容存在不符的情况，演出机构将受到5万-10万元的罚款处分。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;这导致上海脱口秀演出发生了两方面变化。一是演员的个人专场或主打秀减少，因为这类演出对内容完整性要求较高，演员较难将其中的段落进行删改；二是，大部分俱乐部不再举办“开放麦”演出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“开放麦”是专为新演员练习以及老演员试讲新段子而开设的脱口秀演出。由于演出内容质量不稳定，大部分俱乐部的开放麦票价较低，如19元、39元等。演员讲开放麦并没有酬劳，主要目的是打磨内容和练习技术。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;据记者了解，大部分开放麦的报名形式为演员提前递交稿件给机构统一报批，然后再根据自己的实际情况，在演出前的一至两天内报名。因演员个人创作习惯以及时间等因素，开放麦演出的内容与阵容都存在一定的不可控性。演员在上台前临时修改调整新段子或有突发状况无法上台、需要其他演员顶替的情况都较为常见。因此在目前较谨慎的环境下，上海的大部分脱口秀俱乐部都不再开办此类形式的脱口秀演出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;上海开放麦演出锐减，导致新演员没有上台机会，老演员也无法更新创作内容。一些全职演员会选择去其他城市的开放麦试新段子，杭州则成为了他们的首选。贰叁叁脱口秀俱乐部主理人“谢谢海涵”告诉记者，其俱乐部就有四五名签约演员选择到杭州发展。目前，杭州的脱口秀俱乐部至少有10家以上。但这并不意味着演员们能在杭州赚到钱，而是在杭州更“卷”了。 “大家愿意往杭州去，更多是因为（要上）开放麦，想赚演出费是比较难的，因为现在市场体量没有那么大了，就导致供大于求。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259815&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space : normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;贰叁叁脱口秀俱乐部主理人“谢谢海涵” . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data-style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;从增量到存量&amp;nbsp;市场的下行与向上&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;在记者的走访中，多位脱口秀从业者都提到，其实早在今年5月的舆论风波之前，脱口秀的市场就已悄然下行。 The head of a Shanghai talk show club told reporters that the current box office level of its club back has returned to 2017 and 2018. The number of performers is reduced to about 1/3 of each week. Step.而这样的情况，似乎并不仅是因为半年前的那一场行业大地震。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;贰叁叁主理人“谢谢海涵”告诉记者，在近两年里，俱乐部票房并没有上涨的趋势，于是其开始向南京、福州等二三线城市拓展业务。 “整个上海的（市场）体量其实已经到极限了，想再增长业绩的话，要么就是拓展城市，要么就是提高单价，但现在大家的票价整体都在降，所以也不是特别好提（票价），只能拓展城市。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;他提到，目前俱乐部的演出场次数量没有太大变化，但上座率有明显降低。 “上座率能到百分之六七十就算是比较高的了。我们的剧场以前坐300人左右是没问题的，但现在基本上就100人左右，六七十人都会有，周末好一点的时候可能会到200人。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;相比之下，贰叁叁俱乐部在福州市的票房情况是较为稳定的：“因为竞争没有那么大，当地就两家（俱乐部）。”高笑喜剧主理人车洪君告诉记者，“对一些二三线城市来说，他们不像上海和北京有那么多的娱乐形式，脱口秀对那边来说还算比较新鲜。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;在脱口秀演员大力的观察中，脱口秀演出市场的黄金期是在2019年开始的：“脱口秀综艺节目播出后，脱口秀在线下直接起飞。 ”2020年，新冠疫情防控期间，所有演出行业都遭受影响，而体量相对较小的脱口秀则“趁虚而入”，抢占了其他类型演出市场的份额，再加上脱口秀综艺节目的现象级爆火出圈，助推了线下演出的流量迅速增长。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/6VOahMXiiui9rwAiMcfXtnAuyHgcSUwGKG2d9NMx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;797&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/6VOahMXiiui9rwAiMcfXtnAuyHgcSUwGKG2d9NMx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259814&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;脱口秀演员大力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;而在2022年，随着市场的饱和、资源的消耗，脱口秀演出的颓势已初步显现，行业开始迎来瓶颈期。 Hercules wrote in Xiaohongshu: &quot;Every year online program broadcasts, offline performance box office will have a significant rise, but this phenomenon is gone in 2022.并没有提高。不是线上节目对演出票房没有助力，其实也有，只是这个时候（脱口秀演出）票房的自然流量在下滑，线上节目的助力空间已经带不动它下滑的速度，所以两种力量对冲了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;高笑喜剧主理人车洪君在接受记者采访时表示，目前的脱口秀市场已经几乎没有增量，大家都在“卷存量”。一部分俱乐部可能会打起“价格战”，“有的厂牌价格已经开始往50去探，甚至更低”。但另一方面，他仍然认为“这个行业是在向上的”，因为“大家也都在卷质量，尤其是现在比较流行专场演出，一个人讲一个小时的专场或者45分钟的主打秀，这样的演出质量是非常高的。潮水退去，大家开始真刀真枪地拼了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;脱口秀演员大力也在他的小红书上写道：“未来演员已经不能再靠着15分钟的商演段子讲一辈子了，很多演员现在都在开专场，从某种程度上来说，这是好事。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;在行业极速成长的时期，出现了大批只想赚快钱、吃红利但并不重视内容的俱乐部、演出商，攒几名演员凑个拼盘就能卖票；而大量来看脱口秀的观众也是在看到线上节目后奔着“追星”来的，对喜剧本身并不了解。但在如今冷淡的大环境下，随着这一部分人的退出，行业经历洗牌后，慢慢进入了一个沉淀期。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;多位俱乐部主理人在接受记者采访时表示，由于票房整体情况不佳，他们更愿意将演出机会留给内容更好、带票能力更强的演员。 “之前可能一个演员的段子达到三四十分就会有商演机会，现在低于六七十分的话，你的演出量就会很少，很多人已经接不到演出了。前两年大家都在风口上，就不会有优胜劣汰，现在确实过得比较艰难，但我觉得这是单口（喜剧）应该走的路。”贰叁叁主理人“谢谢海涵”说道。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data-style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;未来在哪？必要的线上流量与健康的行业生态&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“今年没有脱六，但我有次梦见自己上过，结果不是很好。”11月3日，曾获得某档脱口秀综艺节目冠军的周奇墨发了这样一条微博，他想象了一段自己参加节目突围赛然后被淘汰的经历，最后总结道：“脱口秀的根还是在线下”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;而当线上节目缺席，彻底回归线下后的脱口秀发展得更好了吗？在记者的走访中，几乎每一位从业者都肯定了一个观点：线上节目的流量助推对脱口秀行业而言仍然必要，尽管线上节目与线下演出在创作上存在非常大的不同. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;车洪君在接受采访时提道，“比赛的形式会很内耗演员的创作，5分钟的体量太小，需要快速地和观众共情，话题就会很局限，专场才是单口喜剧的终极形态。”但他仍然认为行业需要线上的流量来助力破圈，因为随着当前线下演出与文娱形式的日益丰富，脱口秀这门艺术正面临着更加激烈的竞争。 “我们的竞争对手不是脱口秀同行，我们的竞争对手是所有的大众娱乐方式：看电影、KTV、短视频……一切都是你的竞争对手。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“还是需要线上流量的推动。”脱口秀演员大力告诉记者，“我身边的很多朋友也认同这个观点。线上节目可以让线下市场不至于降得太快，如果还没有流量推动的话，差不多到2024年底，脱口秀线下演出市场就会比较惨淡了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;事实上，许多俱乐部与演员都在尝试打造线上IP。由复旦大学“旦口喜剧社团”发起、衍生成立的“高笑喜剧”俱乐部自制了综艺《旦口喜剧大赛》，于10月在B站播出；许多俱乐部在坚持做播客节目来进行品宣及维系粉丝黏性，如猫头鹰喜剧的《不开玩笑》、喜剧联盒国的《嘻谈录》、贰叁叁的《三言两语》；更多的演员也在尝试用自媒体来打造个人IP、助力线下售票。但大部分人都尚未能在线上渠道实现稳定的商业转化。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/No32mZOtGmh9sap3X4dsPbSOUUN9XgrmNnopc5dP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1066&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/No32mZOtGmh9sap3X4dsPbSOUUN9XgrmNnopc5dP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259817&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“高笑喜剧”俱乐部自制综艺《旦口喜剧大赛》。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/QcmAdcyT2b6LEHhInNxJclB8fhfjsVtwnbWQ1ExT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/QcmAdcyT2b6LEHhInNxJclB8fhfjsVtwnbWQ1ExT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259813&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“喜剧联盒国”演员线下演出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;从行业生态的角度来看，国内的脱口秀行业是随着《今晚80后脱口秀》《吐槽大会》《脱口秀大会》等相关综艺节目的走红而崛起、发展的。而当一个行业的体系、从业者的上升通道与一家公司、一档节目深度绑定，势必存在着极大的风险——事实也已经证明了这一点。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aQFCDTjRkI4imCOJvI6cAxM5hXJEmyQrutwCuUeb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aQFCDTjRkI4imCOJvI6cAxM5hXJEmyQrutwCuUeb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259816&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;《今晚80后脱口秀》. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;一名脱口秀演员在接受记者采访时表示，相比起下一档爆款节目的出现，她更希望看见的是行业能迎来一个健康的生态：“不同的公司可以百花齐放，有相互的竞争，也有相互的合作，每个公司都有拿得出手的演员也好、节目（线上IP）也好，就像其他行业一样。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武汉市卫健委：暂停武汉普仁医院出生医学证明签发资格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261446]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 11:13:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;11月28日，湖北省武汉市卫生健康委员会发布通报，针对网友反映的武汉普仁医院从事代孕、武汉瑞博祥司法鉴定所出具虚假亲子鉴定等问题，武汉市卫生健康委员会会同公安、司法等部门，进驻涉事医院及鉴定机构开展调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，已暂停武汉普仁医院出生医学证明签发资格，对该院生育服务及出生医学证明办理等情况进行专项核查。 The Wuhan Ruiboxiang Forensic Appraisal Institute has been instructed to stop its forensic appraisal business and accept investigation and handling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，武汉市卫生健康委员会将根据调查情况，依法依规严肃追责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在巴黎十年被抢近50次：移民导致社会治安恶化，法国社会治理失败]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261430]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;最近，一位女网红自述：在巴黎生活十年，被偷、抢、讹诈了47.5 Second-rate.为什么带小数呢？ Because she was robbed three times, she took it back, so it was only half a time, which means that it was actually 49 times. It&#39;s amazing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在外交口的亲友，1990年代中期曾在巴黎学习、工作过。 After retiring, I re -swimming in Europe. I feel that in 30 years, the changes in France can be regarded as people and not: Paris&#39;s urban appearance and infrastructure have not changed much.但居民构成发生了很大变化，社会风气和文化习俗与30年前相比迥然不同。亲友与女网红的切身感受颇有异曲同工之处：随着移民增加，法国的治安明显恶化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;移民犯罪率高企的原因：法国有很多来自非洲的移民，由于宗教信仰、文化传统、风俗习惯不同，这些移民及其后代在教育方面的劣势，使其社会地位和经济地位均处于较低层级。渴望欧洲那种富裕的物质生活，但在经济方面却难以支持，当然会导致违法犯罪行为增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大量涌入法国的移民、非法移民，算“殖民主义”的反向后遗症，可以说法国正在被反向殖民。在17-20世纪初期，法国在非洲占领了大量殖民地，成为仅次于英国的世界第二大殖民帝国。而两次世界大战，使法兰西人口损失巨大，为弥补兵源不足，法国从殖民地法属非洲招募了数十万当地青年，参加法军、对德作战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战争结束后，大量殖民地士兵留在法国，成为早期移民。法国电影《光荣岁月》（Indigènes）有着生动描述，很多黑人士兵问：我们为法兰西而战，为什么不能留在这里？问得法国政府和民众无言以对。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过这些早期移民，他们在非洲的亲友们得知了法国的发达与富有，大批后续移民、非法移民源源不断涌入。官方数据：目前在法黑人800多万，考虑到非法移民，实际数量可能达1000万，占法国6600万总人口的15%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人口结构变化，大大改变了法国传统的宗教信仰、文化理念、生活习俗，激化了意识形态冲突，带来犯罪率升高、社会动荡、族群与阶层双双对立。街头示威抗议、打砸抢烧，成为持续十几年不断的家常便饭，堪称巴黎一道奇妙风景线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;动荡的社会环境，不但影响了法国经济发展，而且也影响到每一位在巴黎生活者的人身及财产安全。在这种乱哄哄的环境里，丢个钱包、手机稀松平常，而且这么高的犯罪率，警察根本查不胜查、普通居民防不胜防。万般无奈之下，他们采取的办法是抬高立案门槛：把抢劫之类严重罪行轻罪化，把轻罪视为违法，而对违法干脆就尽量不管。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国也学了这一套，2014年加州通过法案，偷窃1000美元以下一律视为轻罪，可通过社区服务抵罪。用这种办法避免警匪冲突、减少警察与黑人的矛盾。这套法律理念和司法实践，催生了欧洲和美国的“0元购”运动：大群人（以移民为主）一齐冲进商店，拿了东西就跑，店家无力阻止，警察不愿管。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在治安问题之外，还有个看似不相干的生活细节变化：法式面包。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亲友早年留法期间，对法式餐饮印象深刻。尤其对法式面包赞赏有加：在法兰西，面包不仅是饮食，更是文化。为做出香松可口的面包，法国面包师从和面、配料，到发酵、烘烤都非常讲究、精益求精，每每凌晨开工，以保证随着太阳升起，香喷喷、热烘烘的法式面包出炉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新冠乙类乙管后他再游巴黎时，惊讶地发现：法国不仅在社会和治安层面上物是人非，连法国面包都变得与30年前不同了，干硬、疲沓、口感不佳，掉渣严重……后来才得知，很多普通面包师都是缺乏法国文化和烹调传统的新移民，对他们而言，面包不再是国家荣耀、文化传承、悠久习俗和精致生活品味，而仅仅是份工作，没有感情，也不会投入太多精力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位喜欢旅游的亲友说：现在反而是东南亚的老挝和越南等前法国殖民地，法式面包做得比巴黎稍正宗些。那里还有较严格的劳动纪律，对员工有一定要求，还遵循着传统的法式面包烘烤技艺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与之对应的是：法国人每年150天休息日（美国多数州每年为116.5天），每年平均工作1490小时（美国人为1791小时）。大概是因为新移民太多了，基层工作尽可能由移民来干，收入较高的法国原住民，日子过得越来越轻松、越来越不愿意上班，面包师这种曾经有相当社会地位的职业，也懒得去干了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就好比：一家已经在走下坡路的企业，不是进行新的科技与生产力革新、力图扭转颓势，而是削减工时、提升薪资、弱化考绩、放弃管理……后果会怎样? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国的“传统丢失、文化退潮”问题，既不止于社会治安，也不止于餐饮。曾令法国人引以为傲的，也确曾经做到世界巅峰水平的文化和艺术，亦面临着同样的危机。曾经的法国影帝德帕迪约纠结了一帮法国演艺界人士，大骂好莱坞搞文化侵略，还焚烧了美国国旗泄愤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，好莱坞既没有通过武力强迫，也没有通过不平等条约对法国进行“文化侵略”，而是人们（包括法国人）不愿再消费法国电影、戏剧、游戏。法国人真应该自省下：自己在思想观念、意识形态、文化理念、艺术创作，以及国际政治、经贸关系、社会治理，甚至烤制面包……各个方面都出问题，究竟是怎么回事？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;移民所带来的社会治安恶化，体现了法国政府的社会治理失败。而移民问题所带来的文化冲击、意识形态碰撞，则体现出更深层次隐患。 French social governance failure and ebb to ebb. The internal cause is that the spiritual power of the contemporary French is dissipated, the traditional values ​​are abandoned, and the national culture is lost.法国人慵懒、闲散、快乐地生活着，如同坐滑滑梯般惬意地印证着“从善如登，从恶如崩”的古语，这种生活状态值得深思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，也希望大家思考那位人到中年仍在全力奋斗的马斯克（Elon Musk）所言：我不想利用人性下坠的力量赚钱。亦如《Jupiter Ascending》对重力的解读：Up is hard，Down is easy(向上非常难，下坠很简单)。社会和个人的成功，都需要昂扬向上的精神内核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一座湖南县城“利剑出鞘”：八百公职人员进退公租房]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261401]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月14日上午，润中小区内一租户搬家。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月14日上午，湖南涟源，润中小区内一租户搬家。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“全民监督，让公租房更&#39;阳光&#39;。”一条横幅挂在润中小区正门上，2023年11月以来，从该小区搬离的住户突然增多，&lt;span>;搬运&lt;/span>;家具的皮卡车进进出出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;搬家本是平常事，近期却在湖南娄底代管的县级市——涟源传得沸沸扬扬。 This stems from a centralized consolidation of public officials to occupy public rental housing. In addition to Run Mid -Mid -Community, the phenomenon of large -scale moving also appeared in the Runze Garden Community, Huimin Community, and Runyuan Community.当地人介绍，这四个小区都是涟源市的公租房社区，那些搬家的人，基本都是涟源的公职人员及其亲属。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者获得的一份统计表显示，以上四个公租房小区排查出入住的公职人员878户，外加4户入住单位公房的公职人员，总计882户，其中包括正科级及以上的公职人员28户。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;多位涟源公职人员称，在这份名单上的人，都要在11月月底前腾退。 “这也是几十年来第一回，这么大面积清退住户。”涟源市住房保障服务中心（以下简称住保中心）的一位工作人员告诉南方周末记者，这一行动跟湖南省巡视组要求整改有关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“不要把过去的惯例替代现在的规章制度，绝不能与民争利。”10月20日，涟源市委书记召开会议，调度公租房运营管理和服务工作。 “涟源在线”公众号发布消息称，会议强调，公租房是保障性住房，各相关部门要统一思想；要成立领导小组和工作专班，深入研究、分析、查找存在的问题漏洞和薄弱环节，分门别类建立台账清单，加大整改力度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月，湖南涟源，润中小区正门。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/edfd4a5f6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/edfd4a5f6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月，湖南涟源，润中小区正门。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“这么大力度清退，住保中心哪有这个能力”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月中旬，南方周末记者走访公职人员入住较多的润中小区和润泽园小区，多处围栏和墙面上挂有打击违规使用公租房、转租出借公租房的红色横幅。在两个小区内，每栋楼前后都贴有涟源市住保中心的公告：“市委、市政府正在对违规使用公租房开展清理整治，欢迎有关单位、组织和个人向我中心举报违规租赁公共租赁住房情况（含以转借、转租、转卖等其它方式实际入住情况），一经查实，将对举报的单位、组织和个人奖励500元/次。”公告落款日期为10月31日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“这两天搬家的人少了，好多人前几天都搬走了。”11月13日下午，润中小区里一位居民告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;公租房，全称公共租赁住房，是指限定建设标准和租金水平，面向符合规定条件的城镇中等偏下收入住房困难家庭、新就业无房职工和在城镇稳定就业的外来务工人员出租的保障性住房。按照住建部2012年发布的《公共租赁住房管理办法》，公租房租赁期限一般不超过5年，期满后不符合续租条件的，应当腾退。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源市这场集中腾退的缘起，据多位公职人员说，是湖南省委第十一巡视组到涟源市工作2个月（2023年9月7日—2023年11月7日）期间，有群众举报公职人员违规占用公租房，转租转卖，导致真正需要房子的贫困户无房可住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者获得一份涟源市委办公室下发给市直各单位的红头文件——《关于开展公职人员租赁公共租赁住房调查摸底的通知》也提到，湖南省委第十一巡视组于2023年10月17日向涟源市下发交办函，反馈涟源市公租房存在公职人员与民争利的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;该通知要求各单位要对本单位工作人员&amp;nbsp;(含家庭成员)公租房情况认真开展调查摸底，并于2023年10月23日17:00前将《公职人员租赁公共租赁住房统计表》报市住保中心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“很多老百姓拿这个事情到巡视组去反映，巡视组觉得这是一个普遍问题，一查有八九百户公职人员（住公租房）。”住保中心的工作人员林敏（化名）告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;公职人员违规占用公租房的现象并非个例。公开信息显示，2021年5月，四川省广元市青川县纪委监委督查检查发现，当地公职人员违规使用公有住房412套，其中违规使用公租房275套，涉及公职人员145人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;再往前，2019年，湖南省益阳市安化县纪委监委也查出此类现象。 4名公职人员转租公租房，5名公职人员转借公租房，不符合承租资格条件未及时退出的公职人员有28名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据涟源市融媒体中心公开信息，2023年10月25日晚，湖南省委第十一巡视组成员在涟源市委常委会会议中再次强调，对于民众反映强烈和高度关注的公租房问题，要动真碰硬，稳步扎实推进问题整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;实际上，在巡视组到来前，涟源市也曾试图整治该问题。据湖南日报2023年年初报道，涟源市住保中心于1月9日至18日开展过一次公职人员违规使用公租房专项清理整治行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“1月份那次，把十多户严重不符合的公职人员报上去了，就是名下又有车又有房的。然后又换掉一部分人，最后清了几户。”林敏介绍，按照涟源市惯例，这样的专项清理整治每隔两三年就会组织一次，但整治力度较小。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“现在这么大力度清退，我们住保中心哪有这个能力？如果不是巡视组来了，市委书记亲自调度，谁会搬？”按林敏的说法，公租房整治涉及多位干部，市住保中心实行起来有难处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月13日下午，一位公职人员搬离润中小区。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/8c9a7b4242.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/8c9a7b4242.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月13日下午，一位公职人员搬离润中小区。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;空置太多，不住浪费？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;公职人员是否有资格入住公租房？长期研究住房保障的北京航空航天大学公共管理学院副教授聂辰认为，一些收入较低且住房困难&lt;span>;、&lt;/span>;符合条件的公职人员入住公租房，属于正常现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“1998年福利分房制度取消之后，全国大多数省市就不再&lt;span>;由&lt;/span>;单位建房分给职工。的确有一些公务员工资不高，家庭负担比较重，买不起房，那么他就符合申请公租房的条件。”中国建设管理与房地产法研究中心主任王才亮说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但就涟源的情况，有知情人士告诉南方周末记者，入住公租房的公职人员，多数通过摇号入住，少部分则是通过“批条子”拿到入住名额。 “有的在娄底买房的，涟源没房；有的在涟源有房，但他想要这个房；也有的是帮朋友或者亲戚批条子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“重灾区是润中小区，大多数公职人员都在那边，那边靠近市中心，地理位置比较方便。”该知情人士称。南方周末记者对比润中小区三次公租房电脑摇号结果公示名单与涟源市公职人员租赁公共租赁住房统计表发现，润中小区三次摇号总计入住1826户，小区内公职人员有669户，占小区居民总数约37%；其中522户在摇号结果公示名单中，其余147户不在摇号名单之列。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者另获得一份涟源市《正科及以上领导干部租赁公共租赁房住房退房统计表》显示，多个单位有28名正科级干部在2023年10月底已退房，家具还在清理中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为什么会有如此大规模的公职人员住进润中小区？上述知情人士透露，润中小区建成后，在2017年、2018年公开摇号时，因为一些特殊原因，“只要参与摇号，都能分到房子”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“润中小区一次盖了2300多套房子，没人住，但它要求入住率达到90%，住保中心要是完不成也会被批评。因为你要盖那么多房，肯定代表有这么大的需求量。”该知情人士称，在配租时，住保部门曾向涟源市政府报告入住率低，后涟源市政府开会商议放宽条件，在涟源无房的公职人员均可申请摇号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月24日，南方周末记者致电涟源市住保中心相关负责人求证该说法，对方以“不需要”为由，拒绝接受采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源市住保中心另一位工作人员告诉南方周末记者，润中小区地处蓝田街道建中村、胡家村，2012年年底开工建设，包括廉租房和公租房，当时称为“建中廉租房、城东公租房项目”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源市政府官网2013年的信息显示，建中廉租房、城东公租房项目是涟源市“十二五”住房保障规划内实施的保障性住房建设重点项目之一。该项目占地188亩，规划总建筑面积达14万平方米，总投资额1.8亿元，计划建设住房共2076套，建成后将成为涟源市住房面积最大、功能最齐全、宜居环境最佳的安居小区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021年润中小区一份物业招标书提及，小区房屋总建筑面积14万平方米，共计30栋，其中住宅有2218套，非住宅（服务用房）742个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;“涟源在线”公众号发布的建中廉租房全景图（上）， 《涟源年鉴（2019）》刊载的润中小区全景图（下）。资料图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1223&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“涟源在线”公众号发布的建中廉租房全景图（上）， 《涟源年鉴（2019）》刊载的润中小区全景图（下）。资料图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廉租房，指政府以租金补贴或实物配租的方式，向符合城镇居民低生活保障标准且住房困难的家庭提供社会保障性质的住房。聂辰告诉南方周末记者，“某种意义上，廉租房就是公租房，它面对更低收入的人群，房租比公租房更低。2014年廉租房与公租房并轨，现在基本上都称公租房。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;聂辰分析，2010-2015年，国家大规模推行公租房、廉租房，当时提出目标：2012年末解决1540万户低收入住房困难家庭的住房问题，2015年保障住房覆盖面要达到20%。 “当时各地都有目标要完成，建了大量公租房。”但聂&lt;span>;辰&lt;/span>;在实际调研过程中发现，包括北京、上海、内蒙古包头在内的部分地区出现因公租房位置偏远或其他因素，申请租赁的人较少，导致公租房空置的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“现在有一个趋势，就是公租房在逐渐放宽条件，甚至出现转成保障性租赁住房的现象，将保障的范围扩大。”聂&lt;span>;辰&lt;/span>;说，保障性住房的租金一般不高于同地段同品质市场租赁住房租金的90%，“但不可以直接转成商品房，因为政府对公租房有严格的控制权”&lt;span>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;值得注意的是，2020年10月，涟源市纪律检查委员会与涟源市监察委员会通报了一起关于建中廉租房建设的串通投标问题。 2012年11月，涟源市人民检察院原反贪污贿赂局副局长梁某与张某贤(以谭某平为首的黑社会性质组织的积极参加者)为取得涟源市建中廉租住房、城东公租房小区第十四标段的工程建设项目，先后联系湖南涟源湘中工程公司等四家公司串通投标，后中得该工程项目。相关判决书显示，梁某与张某贤二人在该项目工程中违法所得129万余元。 2020年8月，梁某受到开除党籍、开除公职处分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除润中小区外，惠民小区与润泽园小区的公职人员也不少。一位惠民小区的公职人员称，惠民小区也是因为空置房源太多，逐渐对公职人员放宽条件。另有多位公职人员也称，此前涟源各公租房小区的申请条件宽松，只要在涟源没有房子的务工人员，均可参与摇号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“公职人员的工资本来也不高，很多也是符合（摇号入住）条件的。”入住公租房的副科级公职人员陆柯（化名）表示，涟源市城镇常住人口不到30万，让交了社保且名下无房子的贫困户住满公租房存在困难。 “先去照顾低收入人口，如果还有空房，肯定要放宽条件，否则也属于公共资源的浪费。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王才亮认为，应从摇号、批条两种入住方式分别看待涟源案例。 “公租房是从过去的经济适用房发展下来的保障性住房，主要是解决一大批收入不高的工薪阶层，买不起市场化房子的问题。如果还存在批条子这种行为，就是在滥用职权。”而对于符合申请条件、摇号入住者，临时清退或存在违约之嫌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月，湖南涟源，润泽园小区内贴有打击违规使用公租房的横幅。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月，湖南涟源，润泽园小区内贴有打击违规使用公租房的横幅。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“打补丁”与“一刀切”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月1日，《涟源市公共租赁住房管理办法》新规发布，提出了更细化的要求。聂辰告诉南方周末记者，公租房的管理条例一般都由地方政府根据当地的经济条件自己制定。但国家有统一规定，承租人需满足“低收入”和“住房差”两个条件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源新规条例显示：涟源市城镇低保、低收入、中等偏下收入住房困难家庭，新就业无房职工和在城镇稳定就业的外来务工人员等符合本地公共租赁住房准入条件的应纳入公共租赁住房保障范围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其中，城镇中等偏下收入住房困难家庭是指家庭人均可支配年收入低于上一年度城镇居民人均可支配收入、家庭存款低于18 万元(含公积金)、在县级及以上城市无不动产的住房困难家庭；新就业无房职工是指参加工作5年以内、且在本地就业、家庭在本地无住房的职工。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;林敏分析，家庭人均可支配年收入限制和工作不满5年的限制，足以将大部分公职人员排除在外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“有二十多个不满5年的公职人员没有发清退通知，其余全部一刀切。”林敏回忆，住保中心在内部会议上要求，对工作满5年的公职人员一律清退，“上下传达是这样说的，先全部退出来，满足其他入住公租房条件的再申请下一轮摇号”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陆柯也告诉南方周末记者，自己单位入住公租房的公职人员，除了几名工作不满5年的大学毕业生，其余全部腾退. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一名因工作年限超过5年、被要求腾退公租房的基层事业编工作人员，在涟源市政府官网信箱写下：“（本人）原本在涟源无亲无故也无房产，低收入人员，完全符合条件，达不到与民争利，恳请领导酌情考虑外地人员，不要一刀切，基层工作人员也是民。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在新规推出之前，公职人员入住公租房是否真的没有与民争利？南方周末记者随机采访了两户润中小区居民，均非公职人员家庭，当时按正规摇号渠道申请到公租房。其中一位称，自己的哥哥和母亲也是这样申请到了公租房，此前未遇到申请不到公租房的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;林敏认为，后来出现群众反映无公租房可以申请，是新阶段出现的新问题。 “有些当时不需要公租房的，后来儿女成家，又需要房子了，也有的&lt;span>;是发&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;生&lt;/span>;家庭变故。”加之近几年，涟源未再新建公租房。因国家政策调整，2016年以后，原则上不再新建公租房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月8日，涟源市住保中心发布公告，于当日至11月20日期间集中受理公租房轮候对象申请，符合新规条件的可以申请公租房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月13日下午，一位公职人员搬离润中小区。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月13日下午，一位公职人员搬离润中小区。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据多位公职人员讲述，2023年11月9日，星期四，在巡视组即将离开涟源之际，城管局一位临近退休的公职人员组织多人前往巡视组办公处反映诉求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“带头那个人（在被腾退的公租房里）搞了一些装修，看看（政府）能不能赔点钱。”一位城管局的公职人员说，去找的有几十人，涉及多个单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位入住润泽园的公职人员告诉南方周末记者，自己家人也跟着去反映情况。 “本来第一次下通知是12月10号前搬，但是他们去（反映情况）以后，第二天就下了通知，11月30号之前必须要搬。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位涟源市发改委的公职人员回忆，星期五（11月10日）早晨，单位组织开会，要求签承诺书，必须在11月30日之前搬离公租房。另一位从事教学工作的公职人员也称学校当天早晨紧急召开会议，“领导让我们签一个承诺书，如果月底不搬，年度考核先评不及格，绩效工资都没得了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我们单位开会开得更厉害一些，星期六星期天都在开。”前述城管局的公职人员说，城管局有一二十人去反映诉求，“我们单位的房子大部分都装修了，意见比较大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据林敏所知，入住公租房的公职人员中，装修花钱最多的有二十多万元。关于装修是否给予赔偿，林敏介绍，公租房合同里明文规定“来修去丢”，装修不做赔偿。 “因为它不是毛坯房，卫生间、厨房、灯具都是装好的，达到交房标准就可以基本入住，这是国家补助给贫困户的，你装修跟政府出租还是有点违背的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此外，多位受访者告诉南方周末记者，涟源市转卖公租房的现象比较普遍。 “我听说，一间五十多平米的房子，价格高的有卖到五六万的。”林敏说，之所以有很多人会装修公租房以及转卖，或许是当地一个根深蒂固的观念所To. “在我们涟源有一个思想，就是政府把这个房子给我了，就代表这个房子就是我的了，我从来没担心过这个房子我会住不下去，没想到巡视组来了让我们搬。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随之而来的是，涟源部分靠近公租房小区的房租也有了涨幅。 “幸福路以前两室一厅的房子，一年租金不到四千块钱，现在都涨成五千块钱了。”一位住在润中小区的公职人员告诉南方周末记者，按照公租房的价格，一年只需要交2000元出头。另外两位被清退的公职人员也证实：“突然之间有八百多户人搬出去，（附近出租房）房源肯定是紧张的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月14日，南方周末记者以“不愿退房的租户”身份向一位住保中心工作人员咨询。对方称，如果认为自己符合入住公租房条件，可以提交材料要求重新审核。申请截止时间在当日中午12点，已有八九十户不愿退房者提交材料。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位提交过材料的公职人员说，他于11月18日收到通知，仍须腾退。据他所知，只有一名身体瘫痪、家庭困难的公职人员通过审核，可以继续租赁公租房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>