<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[包子铺卖豆腐脑被罚一万五：对小本生意岂可如此“用重典”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261051]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a Baozi shop in Beijing was confiscated by the municipal supervision department for selling tofu noodles and was fined 15,000 yuan and more than 7,000 yuan. attracted public attention and strong doubts. Selling tofu bread in a bun shop may indeed violate the regulations, but it does not necessarily require a huge penalty. Is there a more humane way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the China Quality News Network, a subsidiary of China Quality Newspaper and Periodicals, which is in charge of the State Administration of Municipal Supervision, an administrative penalty published on the official website of the Beijing Municipal Supervision Bureau recently showed that the &quot;Beijing Wannan Wenxin Baozi Shop&quot; will be closed in 2022. From April 23 to July 27, 2023, &quot;1,169 orders of tofu nao (salty) were sold on a food delivery platform, priced at 6 yuan/order, with a value of 7,014 yuan.&quot; The Chaoyang District Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that the bun shop sells hot food beyond the scope of its licensed business items and violates Article 16, paragraph 1, of the Measures for the Investigation and Punishment of Illegal Activities on Online Food Safety and the Measures for the Supervision and Administration of Food Safety in Online Catering Services 》Article 4 stipulates that he shall be fined 15,000 yuan according to law; his illegal income of 7,014 yuan shall be confiscated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is undoubtedly surprising that the bun shop cannot sell tofu pudding. As a result, the penalty quickly attracted a lot of attention on social media. Many netizens made fun of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The clause quoted in the administrative penalty decision stipulates that food operators shall not operate beyond the scope of the food business license. But why is it beyond the business scope of a bun shop to sell tofu? This really leaves a lot of people scratching their heads. According to the Chaoyang District Municipal Supervision Bureau, selling tofu curd is exceeding the permitted scope of selling hot food, but aren’t steamed buns a hot food? Since you can sell steamed buns, it means you have a hot food business license, so why can&#39;t you sell tofu puffs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public administrative penalty information does not provide any further explanation. Then we can only look up more information. Judging from the industrial and commercial registration information, the business license of this bun shop was registered in 2018, and its business scope includes catering services and food sales. According to the Food Safety Law, food-related business activities require a food business license. Then I checked its food business license information and found that its licensed business item is &quot;manufacture and sales of hot food (limited to staple food products)&quot;. The &quot;restricted to staple food products&quot; in the brackets is probably the reason why this bun shop was fined. Although they are all hot foods, steamed buns are a staple food, so their production and sale are allowed, while tofu curd is not considered a staple food, so they cannot be sold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, the punishment imposed by the Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau cannot be said to be illegal. However, its rationality is still questionable. First of all, why is the scope of the food business license of this bun shop so narrow? According to the &quot;Food Business License Management Measures&quot; formulated by the former State Food and Drug Administration, the food business license items applied for by catering service operators are divided into hot food production and sales, cold food food production and sales, raw food food production and sales, and cakes. Production and sales of food, homemade drinks and other types of food. Except for the specific varieties approved by the Food and Drug Administration, which should be clearly marked for the production and sale of other types of food, other categories do not need to be specially labeled. So why is the food business license of this bun shop marked as limited to staple food products? If regulations do not stipulate that different business licenses apply to staple food and non-staple hot food, is the license originally issued by the Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau suspected of not being administered in accordance with the law and improperly restricting the business scope of the business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be noted that information from the official website of the Beijing Municipal Supervision Bureau shows that the food business license of Wannan Wenxin Baozi Shop was issued on October 17, 2023. The penalty decision for operating beyond the scope was made on November 13. The illegal facts in the penalty decision show that Baozipu has been selling tofu nao on the takeout website since April 2022. So, when this bun shop applied for a food business license in 2023, why did it only apply for the production and sale of &quot;staple food&quot; hot foods? Knowing that in addition to steamed buns, their store also sells tofu puffs, and that there is no need to apply separately for hot food business licenses for staple food and non-staple food, the store deliberately only applied for a manufacturing and sales license for &quot;staple food&quot; to limit its business scope and Excluding the tofu pudding that you are already selling, are you digging a hole for yourself? Were you misled when you applied for a food business license? Have the staff of the competent department fulfilled their duty of explanation? Is it even possible that when applying for a license, they deliberately misled them to only apply for a staple food license, and then investigated and punished them for selling non-staple food beyond the scope? Considering that he was investigated and fined less than a month after applying for the license, such a timing coincidence can easily lead to other suspicions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if there are no problems with the above process, imposing such a heavy penalty violates the basic principle of administrative punishment that the penalty should be commensurate with the offense. The Administrative Penalty Law clearly stipulates that if the violation is minor and corrected in a timely manner without causing harmful consequences, administrative penalties will not be imposed. Baozi and tofu are both hot foods, and regulations do not make any special distinction between the safety supervision of the two. The sale of tofu in the bun shop has not caused any food safety consequences. Even if there is any violation of law, the circumstances are very minor, and it can be given a warning and ordered to make corrections. At the beginning, more than 7,000 &quot;illegal gains&quot; were confiscated and fined 15,000 yuan. A total of more than 20,000 yuan. How long does it take for a bun shop to make money back? At a time when it is difficult to make a living in a small business, imposing such heavy penalties on small businessmen will of course arouse strong dissatisfaction among the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for small mistakes to be punished heavily. In 2021, a vegetable shop owner in Yulin, Shaanxi Province was fined 66,000 yuan by the market supervision department for selling 5 kilograms of substandard celery. After being exposed by the State Council Supervision Bureau, the deputy director of the city&#39;s Municipal Supervision Bureau admitted that the punishment was too severe and was not proportionate. A CCTV report found that among the more than 50 penalties imposed on small and micro market entities by the city&#39;s Municipal Supervision Bureau since 2021, 21 cases were fined more than 50,000 yuan, and the case value was only tens or hundreds of yuan. The Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau in Beijing imposed a heavy fine on Baozi Shop, which is comparable to the case in Yulin. Is this kind of supervision for supervision or for fines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Food safety supervision is of course very important, but supervision cannot be for the sake of supervision, let alone supervision for the sake of fines. Under the current economic situation, providing good services to small and micro market entities and creating a good market environment should be the primary responsibility of regulatory authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“阿根廷特朗普”米莱：他承诺去做的和他将会去做的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261100]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/VYQXzpdI0T4ZMuFEFaFT7g8Rc2qZzVWbsN7BPZzu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/VYQXzpdI0T4ZMuFEFaFT7g8Rc2qZzV WbsN7BPZzu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259316&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, the candidate of the Argentine far-right electoral alliance &quot;Freedom Forward Party&quot; Milai greeted the people at a polling station in the capital Buenos Aires &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local On October 22, the results of the second round of the Argentine presidential election were announced. Far-right candidate Javier Milei, known as &quot;Argentine Trump (Donald Trump)&quot;, defeated the candidate representing the ruling coalition and the current economic leader. Minister Sergio Massa was elected as the next president. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Argentina’s “Olympic Team Member”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Millais, 53, is an Argentinian of Italian descent. He holds two master’s degrees in economics. After graduation, he has held positions including Financial executive positions, including senior economist at HSBC, have shifted to focus on research and teaching of economic and financial theories and development strategies since 2012. He has served in many well-known economic and financial think tanks and forums, and has served as a domestic He serves as a lecturer or part-time teacher in many foreign universities, and has published 9 monographs and more than 50 papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is an ardent believer of the &quot;Austrian School&quot; who advocates &quot;abandoning all financial and national economic controls and implementing absolute economic liberalism&quot;, and later gradually evolved into a combination of Milton Friedman-style monetarism ( The &quot;alternative Austrian school&quot; of Monetarism advocates that &quot;the government should do nothing except regulate the currency issuance through the central bank to control inflation.&quot; After entering politics, he further advocated that even the central bank can be eliminated. Argentina can completely abandon its local currency and Switch to the U.S. dollar to achieve the goal of controlling inflation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This idea of ​​being &quot;more Austrian than Austrian and more Friedmanian than Friedmanian&quot; is called &quot;native Austrian school&quot; by many economists in Argentina. It might as well be called As &quot;Argentine Olympic Team&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/nsPZYDEKzQ9IMyPzFBHKJADkWEcvxdFED3QjrcUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/nsPZYDEKzQ9IMyPzFBHKJADkWEcvxdFED3QjrcUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259317&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, in Buenos Aires, Argentina, voters voted at a polling station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After turning to &quot;retreat&quot;, he opened his own radio magazine radio program &quot;Demoliendo mitos&quot; (Demoliendo mitos), which long-term, systematic and dedicated criticism of the Argentine left-wing party He accused the government of being responsible for a series of long-term ills in Argentina&#39;s economy, society and people&#39;s livelihood, and quickly gained popularity. Since 2017, he has become interested in politics. In 2021, he founded the far-right political party &quot;Avanza Libertad&quot; (Avanza Libertad) and was successfully elected to the House of Representatives as the party&#39;s candidate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, he announced his participation in the presidential election. Initially, because he was a &quot;rookie&quot; in politics and his political party was very weak, he was generally considered to be a &quot;student with the prince&quot;, and even got the nickname &quot;El Loco&quot; ) nickname. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the primary election on August 13 (a unique electoral stage in Argentina. Due to the large number of small parties in Congress, several larger party alliances must be formed, and each alliance recommends a single presidential candidate. The purpose of the primary election (the single candidate for the election of each coalition), Millais not only stood out from the &quot;Juntos por el Cambio&quot; coalition composed of 12 right-wing parties, becoming the only candidate of the coalition, but also passed all 5 Among the candidates in the primary election, he topped the list with 30% of the vote and became the most popular candidate in the election overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first round of voting on October 22, Milais received 29.99% of the votes, second only to Massa (36.78%). Due to Argentina’s election rules, the person elected as president needs to obtain a majority. In the second round of voting on November 19, Millay won with an absolute advantage of 55.7% to 44.3%, and won 21 of Argentina&#39;s 24 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why was the &quot;madman&quot; elected?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Argentina&#39;s annual inflation rate has reached 140%, and may even exceed 200% by the end of the year. More than 40% of the population lives below the poverty line. In the past 20 years, It has defaulted on its international sovereign debt three times in the past few years, and the latest time it even caused neighboring Bolivia and Brazil to refuse to deliver the pineapples and bananas they ordered as part of the contract to avoid defaulting on their debts. Argentina, nicknamed &quot;the only developed country to develop into a developing country in modern times&quot;, ranked sixth in the world in terms of economic aggregate at the beginning of the 20th century, but has now fallen to 66th. Argentines have long complained about this. Not only that, massive public expenditures, deteriorating social security, and the prevalence of nepotism known as &quot;political casteization&quot; have become the targets of public outrage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was against this background that Milais, who appeared with an alternative image of &quot;wild hair and a big mouth&quot;, entered the political arena as an &quot;amateur internet celebrity gunner&quot; and shouted out a series of remarks that seemed shocking but were actually The alternative political platform of &quot;Directed Demolition&quot;: Abolish the central bank and the local currency and switch to the US dollar, which is intended to cater to the public&#39;s distrust of the local currency and central bank accumulated due to long-term inflation and local currency establishment, and the public&#39;s belief that &quot;strong medicine may be able to eradicate inflation and &quot;Wealth shrinkage&quot; is expected; the abolition of more than half of the ministries and commissions is intended to cater to public dissatisfaction with nepotism and bureaucracy; the withdrawal from the &quot;BRIC&quot;, the freeze of large-scale engineering projects, and the privatization of public service enterprises and educational institutions such as schools, radio and television facilities, and electricity ization is intended to cater to the public’s strong desire to reduce public expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for other &quot;alternative propositions&quot;, they are mostly put forward to highlight their &quot;core values&quot; or attract core supporters, such as advocating anti-abortion and anti-contraception, opposing energy conservation and emission reduction, and drastically cutting social welfare and Medical privatization, etc., are all in line with its &quot;basic color&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At one point, he also proposed that &quot;everyone has a gun&quot; and even allowed his die-hard supporters to insult the current Pope Francis, who is also an Argentinian. This was also his &quot;true performance.&quot; As for the drug liberalization policy, which is very different from the &quot;Trump replicas&quot; of most other countries, it was &quot;condescendingly&quot; proposed to cater to the tastes of some low-level people in Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most analysts point out that although the majority of the Argentine public may not really believe that Millais can &quot;cure all diseases&quot;, given the negative impact of left-wing Peronism in the past Having won 10 out of 13 general elections, the left wing has already overdrafted the trust and patience of voters, while the traditional right wing has failed to reverse the situation in the last two elections. Therefore, &quot;since other methods don&#39;t work, we might as well try strong medicine.&quot; This kind of &quot;maybe it might work&quot; thinking quickly became popular, and allowed Millay, who had participated in a &quot;copycat&quot; Rolling Stones band and was familiar with the way of pop success, to win the presidency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts pointed out that after Millais suddenly emerged in the primary election, the government used a propaganda machine to &quot;demonize&quot; him in a panic, which was counterproductive. Some works intended to arouse public panic about Milley&#39;s administration (such as claiming that Milley&#39;s public spending cuts will cause the Buenos Aires metro ticket to rise to 1,100 pesos, while the current price is only 56 pesos) have actually done the government a disservice because The public can easily associate this with the soaring prices, and be led away by Milley&#39;s propaganda that &quot;the government spends money indiscriminately like this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some local observers pointed out that Millais carefully created the image of a &quot;political outsider&quot; and successfully attracted a large number of grassroots votes under the banner of &quot;understanding the sufferings of the people&quot; and &quot;opposing nepotism&quot;, but his The image of &quot;grassroots spokesperson&quot; is carefully created by a group of the richest people in Argentina: billionaire Eduardo Eurnekian is one of Millay&#39;s most important supporters, and the media network &quot;A24&quot; he controls is Millay&#39;s The main shaper and promoter of successful political public relations images, and successfully &quot;killed&quot; the mediocre public media in a series of dazzling combinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The right-wing’s decisive choice after the first round is a tactical key: Patricia Bullrich, also a far-right but “relatively less right” candidate, won the primary election as “ The slogan &quot;Anti-high crime rate&quot; competed with Millais&#39;s snipe and clam, and won 23.81% of the votes in the first round, ranking third after Massa and Millais. After the first round, Milley decisively stopped his criticism of Burridge, who quickly announced his support for Milley after weighing the pros and cons. In fact, Milley&#39;s vote share in the second round (55.7%) was the same as in the first round. The combined votes of Millais and Burridge (53.90%) were about the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cdRisNIh3HwbGLwcb0IvcmMiztRxeqzryQU7RPLV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cdRisNIh3HwbGLwcb0IvcmMiztRxeqzryQU7RPLV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, Massa, candidate of Argentina&#39;s center-left ruling coalition Fatherland, gave a speech after voting at a polling station in Tigre, Buenos Aires Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Civil and military officials and the &quot;prime minister in black&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Because of the political party to which Milai belongs It is too small and the core team is not large. It is generally believed that he will widely absorb other larger right-wing parties that belong to the &quot;Common Change Alliance&quot;, especially political veterans who obey the orders of former President Mauricio Macri to join the cabinet or join the staff. However, core cabinet members will still try to arrange confidants and like-minded people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among them, the foreign minister has been identified as Diana Mondino, who co-founded the &quot;Free Progress Party&quot; with him. She and Milai were both &quot;Argentine Olympic team members&quot;; she was convicted of helping Argentina in 1996. Mariano Cuno Libarona, a celebrity lawyer and TV commentator who became famous after winning a drug-related lawsuit, will become the new attorney general. This celebrity who is well-versed in &quot;Internet celebrity economics&quot; is in the election campaign In the process, he came up with many clever ideas for Mi Lai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His vice-presidential partner Victoria Villarruel is a controversial figure: she has a high profile and considerable appeal in the right-wing camp, but because she was born in the former military government He comes from a family of military officials, and has been controversial for his public advocacy of &quot;rehabilitating&quot; important members of the military government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;prime minister in black&quot; who does not hold public office, but may have a significant impact on the new government&#39;s strategy and policy direction, in addition to the aforementioned billionaire Ernekian and others, he calls him Sister Karina Milei, who is known as &quot;My Moses&quot; and is called &quot;the one who has the greatest influence on Milei&quot; by insiders, is also a figure that cannot be ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Promises that will be fulfilled, will not be fulfilled and may not be fulfilled&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stay away from the &#39;BRIC&#39;&quot;, cut public spending and freeze large projects, it seems that Milai will come to power at present campaign promises that will definitely be fulfilled in the future, because these promises have a broader voter base and are interlocking (for example, the former government actively sought to join the &quot;BRICS&quot; in order to launch more large-scale project financing), which is also the reason for the left-wing and former government core platform and least popular policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Privatizing public media&quot; will also be launched as soon as possible, not only because too many public officials are the focus of social dissatisfaction (Millay once slammed &quot;6.2 million people in the private sector&quot; on a radio show Argentinian employees working in companies have to support 20 million public servants&quot;, which won a round of applause), and also because of the &quot;witch-hunting frenzy&quot; and &quot;targeted smear campaign&quot; against Milley after the primary election, fearing that Milley would lose his job if he came to power. Public media employees were in high spirits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ve41ebVCsbEYGL3fC3aemeeKyqzo5G3aO3NoKHhh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ve41ebVCsbEYGL3fC3aemeeKyqzo5G3aO3NoKHhh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259315&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 16, 2023, in Cordoba, Argentina, Milai (middle), candidate of the far-right electoral alliance &quot;Freedom Forward Party&quot;, attended a campaign rally&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some campaign promises will be fulfilled, but most of them will be &quot;discounted&quot;: ministries and commissions will definitely be reduced, but it is not expected to be as previously announced Shutting down more than half of the ministries and central banks is not only overkill, but as a smaller ruling party, it is also not conducive to arranging the personnel of allies based on merit; the &quot;alienation&quot; of countries such as Brazil and China will continue, but it will not go too far: Chapter 2 Before the second round of voting, he had low-key stated that he &quot;will abide by the contracts he has signed with Chinese companies.&quot; Many analysts pointed out that his &quot;National Olympics&quot; economic and financial strategy relies heavily on overseas financing. However, in the United States, whether the Democratic or Republican Party is in charge, (Interestingly, Trump, whom Milai admired and congratulated on his election, was an American politician who openly opposed continuing to provide financing facilities to Argentina). It was a mess. Relations with China, an important source of international investment, may not be of any benefit to Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, he once publicly threatened to visit the United States and Israel as soon as possible after being elected, and pay homage to many Jewish leaders (he once declared that he would convert to Judaism), but he has obviously lowered his tone recently because of the latest democratic reforms. Polls show that mainstream public opinion in Argentina is very interested in the U.S. dollar, but has little interest in having the country get too close to Israel, especially in having its president &quot;Judaized.&quot; Therefore, the visit is likely to take place, but it is not expected to be &quot;excessive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Promises that are almost certain to be unfulfilled include bashing the Pope (apologized before the second round of voting), &quot;guns for all&quot; (publicly abandoned after the first round of voting due to reverse polls), privatization of health care decentralization and large-scale cuts in public welfare (which has been significantly retracted after the strong reversal in the polls), as well as &quot;ceding the Falklands to the United Kingdom&quot; - most allies in his campaign coalition are openly opposed to it, and his vice presidential candidate Villarreal endorses it. Several Falklands War veteran organizations reacted fiercely to this, and public opinion feedback was not ideal. He has rarely mentioned it recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It remains to be seen whether or to what extent some of the promises are fulfilled, the most prominent being &quot;abandoning the local currency and switching to the U.S. dollar.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts believe that given that Argentina’s local currency has long been discredited at home and abroad, and that Argentine companies and ordinary people have actually begun to switch to the U.S. dollar, the resistance to “currency dollarization” is not as great as imagined. , coupled with public complaints about &quot;the government creating inflation and poverty through money printing,&quot; this move is also expected to gain popularity in a short period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But most analysts, such as William Jackson, chief emerging markets economist at Capital Economics and Thierry Larose, portfolio manager at Vontobel Asset Management in Zurich, believe that the situation is It’s not that simple: Argentina is the third largest economy in Latin America. Giving up its local currency and switching to the U.S. dollar means giving up control of its own fiscal and financial policies, “financial colonization” of the country, and letting the Federal Reserve control the lifeline of Argentina’s economy. Once the economic situation is further affected, Due to setbacks, public sentiment can easily reverse in the Latin American environment, thus putting the initiator of this policy into a desperate situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, because Argentina’s international credit rating is so bad, it is still unknown whether the Federal Reserve, which has tended to “America first” in recent years, is willing to accept the offer. They also pointed out that &quot;currency dollarization&quot; may be able to control inflation, but it cannot solve Argentina&#39;s financial difficulties, and the latter is the root of Argentina&#39;s economic and financial difficulties. In fact, in his victory speech, Milley did avoid slogans such as &quot;dollarization of currency&quot; and &quot;closing the central bank&quot; that he had repeatedly shouted before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also unknown whether the privatization of public services and large state-owned enterprises will be fully implemented, because refusing to fulfill promises will certainly offend many voters and continue to bear a heavy financial burden, but complete &quot;smashing&quot; will definitely cause In the violent social turmoil, it is difficult to decide how to choose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is recognized that there are two things that are not among the campaign promises but will definitely be done:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is to try international debt restructuring again. The reason why it will be done is because it is impossible not to do it. The reason why they did not make a big deal out of it is because the left wingers were doing the same thing when they were in power;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to carry out legal liquidation of dignitaries of the current government after taking office, such as the first lady and vice president who were criticized by the public. Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner is likely to be taken to court or even sent to prison after leaving office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many analysts believe that given that Milley’s party only accounts for 10% of the seats in the Argentine Senate and only 5% of the seats in the House of Representatives, the Alliance for Common Change is still a minority in parliament, and Milais is still a minority in parliament. Lai himself is also very inactive in parliament (it is said that he only participated in co-signing one law draft during his tenure as a member), and many of his too radical and controversial campaign promises will face varying degrees of &quot;discounting and dumping&quot; in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 09:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[融创完成900亿元债务重组，保交楼压力仍在]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261096]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A real estate project in Sunac Beijing. Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/87077a716b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/22/87077a716b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259327&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sunac Beijing A property. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 18 months, Sunac China (01918.HK) fully resolved the debt risk of approximately 90 billion yuan, and completed all domestic and overseas debt restructuring. The real estate industry ushered in the first large-scale real estate company to complete debt restructuring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, 2023, Sunac issued an announcement announcing that all conditions for overseas debt restructuring had been met and it officially took effect on that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement, creditors’ existing debt of approximately US$10 billion will be replaced with new notes, mandatory convertible bonds, convertible bonds, and shares of Sunac Services (01516.HK) at a consideration of 57 respectively. US$1 billion, US$2.75 billion, US$1 billion, US$775 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, three products: new notes, mandatory convertible bonds, and convertible bonds are expected to be listed on the SGX on November 21; Sunac Services shares have been transferred to the account of the plan creditors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the second half of 2021, more than 50 listed real estate companies have initiated debt restructuring. In May 2022, Sunac defaulted on its debt and completed domestic debt restructuring at the end of that year. &quot;In the next stage, the company&#39;s focus will be on the Baojiao Building.&quot; A Sunac insider told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Sunac can still be saved”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Information provided by the above-mentioned insiders shows that after the restructuring of Sunac’s overseas debt, it has reduced its debt by approximately US$4.5 billion (over 30 billion yuan) scale, the annual debt repayment pressure has dropped by nearly 2.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the debt restructuring, Sunac’s first extended note matures in September 2025. At the same time, the company has the right to extend it for one year. After the extension, it will mature in September 2026, providing the company with Breathing window in the past 3 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the company can choose to pay interest in kind in the first two years. In the first year, the interest can be fully capitalized. In the second year, the company can choose to support only 2% cash interest (the remaining part of the interest is capitalized), which reduces The company’s overseas cash repayment pressure within two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned insiders said that the restructuring plan won the support of more than 98% of the creditor&#39;s rights and more than 99% of the creditors at the creditors&#39; meeting in September 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Yifeng, president of the China Urban Real Estate Research Institute, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that the debt conversion of real estate enterprises usually requires the help of third parties, such as the intervention of financial institutions, central state-owned enterprises, overseas capital, etc., and the pledge of equity, land, etc. , protecting the principal and interest income of creditors. This way you can get an extension and avoid liquidation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the overseas debt restructuring telephone briefing on March 29, 2023, Sunac Executive Director and CEO Wang Mengde introduced that some loan extension projects are actively seeking support from banks and other financial institutions, and introducing AMC ( Asset management companies) and other third-party funds solve difficult-to-extend financing such as trusts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sunac’s official WeChat account, six banks led by Shanghai Pudong Development Bank, China Huarong (02799.HK), and CITIC Trust jointly injected capital into Sunac’s Shanghai Dongjiadu project, with a scale of over 12 billion yuan, the first Funding will be completed in January 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned insiders said that since 2022, Sunac has received a total of 19 billion yuan in bailout funds, and has carried out extensive cooperation with AMC, obtaining more than 20 billion yuan in new financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Yifeng believes that Sunac&#39;s successful debt restructuring reflects the fact that creditors and third-party institutions believe that &quot;Sunac can still be saved&quot; after evaluating its assets and debt situation. Confidence in the real estate market. Compared with other explosive real estate companies, Sunac&#39;s debt scale is relatively small and its asset quality is higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in his view, Sunac’s debt restructuring has limited reference significance for other real estate companies. Since the assets and liabilities of each real estate company are different, it needs to be evaluated on a &quot;one house, one policy&quot; basis. For example, Country Garden (02007.HK), Sino-Ocean Group (03377.HK), Gemdale Group (600383.SH) and other real estate companies that are also facing debt pressure have failed to apply for extension. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The annual guaranteed delivery target is 300,000 units&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the completion of debt restructuring only means that Sunac has eliminated short-term debt risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after the window period ends, Sunac still faces challenges. &quot;As long as the real estate market does not recover and the company does not receive payment from sales, there may be a default on debts such as commercial bills,&quot; Xie Yifeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained that Sunac is currently only extending domestic and overseas bank loans, bonds, etc., but the scale of commercial bills to pay for the project is still large. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sunac’s 2023 interim report shows that as of June 30, 2023, the company’s trade and other payables were 274.1 billion yuan, and contract liabilities were 292.6 billion yuan. This means that Sunac owes nearly 600 billion yuan to suppliers and owners of uncollected properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Yifeng analyzed that in an environment where real estate is down and the market is cold, in order to solve this level of debt risk, companies can only adopt three options: extension, using housing as payment, or introducing new shareholders to cooperate in development. Way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The primary focus of the next step is to speed up sales collection.” Xie Yifeng said that once there is a problem with sales collection, it is easy to have problems such as arrears in project payments and commercial invoice defaults. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 22, 2023, Sunac issued an announcement that the company was included in the list of persons subject to enforcement for dishonesty, which showed that Sunac had eight breaches of trust, involving a face value of approximately 6.6175 million yuan, interest losses, litigation costs, etc. , the reason is that commercial bills of varying amounts have expired and have not been paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Yifeng believes that after debt restructuring, real estate companies still need to increase revenue and reduce expenditure. While developing financing channels, we should deal with negative assets, reduce scale, reduce land acquisition, and reduce pressure on the capital chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned Sunac insiders said that the company’s consideration is to invest more funds and manpower in the guaranteed building in the window period of 2-3 years after the debt restructuring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As of October, we have delivered 205,000 units, ranking second in the industry.” He said that the company’s goal in 2023 is to deliver 300,000 units, and the task in 2024 is equivalent to this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that in the last two months of 2023, Sunac still has the task of delivering nearly 100,000 houses. The insider admitted that &lt;span>; the company is still facing delivery pressure and is using multiple financing channels to ease financial pressure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直击人性底线，大逃杀王者回归]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261053]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;Eleven years ago, &quot;Hunger&quot; The main trilogy of &quot;Game&quot; (four films in total) has become popular all over the world, with a cumulative box office of nearly 3 billion. Jennifer Lawrence, the &quot;eldest cousin&quot; who plays the heroine Katniss, has also become a smash star. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although there are endless battle royale-themed dramas nowadays, back then, watching a group of young people fight each other in a reality show was undoubtedly a new thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4826dc0358aad5db1fb014754cae12a9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4826dc0358aad5db1fb014754cae12a9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259108 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Hunger Games&quot; established a complete world view setting: Panem consists of a capital city and thirteen border areas. The people of the latter work hard to support the luxury of the nobles in the capital. Life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The capital created the Hunger Games, which is about brutal fighting. &lt;/span>;Every year, each district must send two people (also called tributes) to participate. Massacre is a TV show that the upper class watches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight years have passed since the completion of &quot;The Hunger Games&quot; series prequel - &quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot;, in which the protagonist becomes the young President Snow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7fd5250b4cb6c5a2adda60824ae5f6aa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7fd5250b4cb6c5a2adda60824ae5f6aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259110&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the main story, the elderly version of President Snow played by Donald Sutherland is calm and scheming. He is a ruthless ruler who has been committed to tripping up the heroine Katniss. In the end, they were unable to stop the revolutionary upsurge of the rebels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/da6705ab7be9297cbb1a459e9fc0a7a6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;861&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/da6705ab7be9297cbb1a459e9fc0a7a6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259107 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; pulls the timeline back to 64 years ago and tells the story of young Snow&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Tom Bryce)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s history of blackness. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As the mentor of the 10th Hunger Games, he has to deal with the tribute he is responsible for—Lucy, a girl from District 12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Rachel Ziegler) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Become a community with a shared future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the game of &quot;both gain and lose&quot;, they gradually developed feelings for each other, but how far can young and fragile love go? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6fa493ff4d2c11376e14d9bbe8f7c64d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6fa493ff4d2c11376e14d9bbe8f7c64d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259106 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After &quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; was released, Douban&lt;/span>; scored 7.1 points, but its reputation was mixed. Although it is titled &quot;The Hunger Games&quot;, it is a movie about people. It focuses on the exploration of characters and despises the design of the game. Therefore, it is less entertaining and critical than the true story, but more The thickness of a single character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——There are a few spoilers below, please read with caution if you mind——&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The best part of the whole film The point is that it completes the history of the slightly facial-looking villain President Snow in the main story. There is a saying: &quot;If you knew me before, you might forgive me now.&quot; If you know the young Snow, you may have a little more understanding of the old Snow. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The prequel did not whitewash Snow, but it did catalyze the audience&#39;s pity for him, especially under the performance of Tom Bryce, the 18-year-old Snow Appear handsome, proud and lovable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/baf3f171b7660a5eb3dfa2f5f3ee1907.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1035&quot; height=&quot;436&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/baf3f171b7660a5eb3dfa2f5f3ee1907.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259109 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Snow is the son of a general in the capital, but after his father&#39;s early death, the family fell into a dilemma. He, his cousin and his grandmother depended on each other in an empty mansion, and their lives were stretched thin. Under the empty noble title. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The opening of the movie is an important day when the school awards scholarships. With excellent grades, he is bound to win. As long as he gets the money, he can go to college. But he can wear school uniforms on ordinary days, but not on important days. He lacks a piece of clothing that he can use. Fortunately, my cousin was very ingenious. She first treated the yellowed old shirt with a curtain bleaching agent, and then used small pieces of bathroom tiles to make new buttons. Snow, who goes out with his head held high, is as confident and arrogant as Scarlett who sews clothes with curtain cloth in &quot;Gone with the Wind&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/92320b533d447c6d8c7ddbe810700e0f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/92320b533d447c6d8c7ddbe810700e0f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259111 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He talked with his classmates from the aristocratic school and explained that he was sweating because the driver failed to take him to the school gate, and that he skipped tea and snacks because he had eaten steak early in the morning. (and threw away half of it), and together with his classmates from the old-money class, he despised the upstart classmates who moved to the capital from the second district. In just a few minutes, an image of a person who hides his inferiority with arrogance, is determined to win everything, and is accustomed to bluffing appears on the page. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, things did not go as smoothly as Snow had imagined. The rules of the scholarship were changed, and the talented people were assigned as mentors in the Hunger Games. Only those who led the tributes to win the game could receive them. scholarship. Due to personal grudges between his parents, Snow was assigned to a lesser tribute - Lucy, who seemed completely unlikely to win. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/472fb5140a0ad446ff37759721516cf0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/472fb5140a0ad446ff37759721516cf0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259113 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Snow is good at accepting facts, observing world affairs and perceiving people&#39;s hearts. He quickly formulated a battle plan: perform in front of the camera and use public opinion to build momentum as much as possible. We may still remember that in the main story of &quot;The Hunger Games&quot;, Katniss and Pete pretended to be a couple to gain support from the people of the capital. The essence of reality shows has always been &quot;show&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Snow personally&lt;/span>; picked up Lucy at the train station, gave her roses, held hands with her in the zoo cage, and gave her food supplies. Encourage her to sing for the camera. Lucy, who was born as a minstrel, is also well versed in the rules of performance and is good at using singing to express emotions and ridicule rules. They are a perfect partner in the true sense, so it is very natural to have a little illusion of love under the suspension bridge effect. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/799efcc36f7d301c4a587e684443f2f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;950&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/799efcc36f7d301c4a587e684443f2f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259114 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; is divided into three chapters. The first two chapters focus on the Hunger Games themselves, but the end of Lucy&#39;s game is the beginning of Snow&#39;s game. , he faces the fate of his unscrupulous game. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Snow always lands on &amp;nbsp;top&quot; (Snow/Snow always falls on top) is Snow&#39;s personal creed, and this motto also implies his It&#39;s his destiny, so he will deviate from the track for a while, but once he has the opportunity, he will definitely find a way to turn around. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/45eb4ec796af6d3bace886ead45e02d0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/45eb4ec796af6d3bace886ead45e02d0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259112 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is not comprehensive enough to summarize &quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; as &quot;the history of Snow&#39;s transformation&quot;. The slogan on the title page of the novel &quot;From a handsome boy to a president, Snow The description of &quot;what a price was paid&quot; is also worthy of scrutiny. Judging from the information conveyed in the film, Snowburn is an ambitious, ruthless, paranoid, sensitive and powerful egoist. In the process of betraying his friends and abandoning his lover, he gradually tore off the mask of elegance and respectability, buried the compassion of the young man, and finally returned to his true self. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/d84e8f7ed303a2dcec5795c8f77bd148.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1036&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/d84e8f7ed303a2dcec5795c8f77bd148.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259115 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The successful portrayal of Snow is the biggest highlight of &quot;The Ballad of Songbirds and Snakes&quot;. His character arc in one movie even exceeds that of Kegnis in four movies. The latter is already a character carefully portrayed in commercial blockbusters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Otherwise, however, &quot;Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; is lackluster. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Let’s talk about the controversial heroine first. New actress Rachel Ziegler is good at singing. She won the Golden Globe Award for &quot;West Side Story&quot; and is also a new version. The heroine of &quot;Snow White&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In &quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot;, she sang well, but her acting skills were &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;speak&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; barely watchable&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; , and the gap between her and the male protagonist in the affectionate scene is extremely obvious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It’s not that the audience &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is harsh, but compared with Jennifer Lawrence, she does still have a long way to go. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/23d52c2f9a95d02fa380f7b0c909cbac.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;245&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/23d52c2f9a95d02fa380f7b0c909cbac.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259116 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/68fdf8e7c843b4f6df1bb52a55e95b42.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;545&quot; height=&quot;243&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/68fdf8e7c843b4f6df1bb52a55e95b42.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259117&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(The picture shows a comparison of the same action)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;About the game Setting, obviously the 74th Hunger Games depicted in the first part of the sequel is the best. Both the pre-game preparation and the actual combat are full of ingenuity, allowing the audience to feast their eyes on the visual spectacle. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The 10th Hunger Games in &quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; was quite simple. It was still an indoor game in a stadium, which made the action scenes that the series is proud of completely absent. No room for display. After watching the game, all I remember is that a group of tributes finished the game in a hurry, offering their heads one by one without any highlights. Audiences looking for the thrill of a battle royale game may be disappointed, because the movie is quite restrained in its presentation of spectacles such as killing and violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/86f56582524ffc2bd8dc4cc7acd95bc6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/86f56582524ffc2bd8dc4cc7acd95bc6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259118 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the other hand, the reflections on reality shows and the discussion of revolution in the main trilogy are nowhere to be found in &quot;The Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot;. This may be the filmmaker&#39;s strategy to avoid repeating itself, but it also blocks the possibility of the text digging deeper into derivatives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/9a1b5b6d556ed3df4774259cc065da4c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/9a1b5b6d556ed3df4774259cc065da4c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259119 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Therefore, if you are looking for the critical and gaming experience of the &quot;Hunger Games&quot; series in the movie, you may be disappointed. But if you are interested in character stories, you can still watch it. &quot;Song of Songbirds and Snakes&quot; does have some subtle touches in this regard, which makes people suddenly moved by the foreshadowing of fate. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;When old President Snow sees the rebellious girl Katniss from District 12 singing &quot;The Hanging Tree&quot;, will he think of his youth? His then lover Lucy also crooned for him? &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;When the 18-year-old Snow was shooting wildly in the foggy and miasmatic forest, destroying the corpse of his love, he probably also He would never have imagined that this belated bullet would hit him directly between the eyebrows a few years later. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[离世四年，崔雪莉生前纪录片公开：被装进偶像模具的孤独灵魂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261090]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;To the Truth&quot; is a film based on A documentary based on an in-depth interview with Cui Xueli. The 25-year-old candidly shared her inner feelings in her last days. (File photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/adda255b2f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;453&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/adda255b2f. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259322&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;To the Truth&quot; is a documentary based on an in-depth interview with Cui Xueli, 25 years old She candidly shared her inner feelings in her last days. (Information picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Let me briefly introduce myself first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A simple opening question was handed over from the other side. The answer to this question could be &quot;f(x)&#39;s Sulli&quot; or &quot;actress Choi Sulli&quot;. In front of the camera, senior artist Cui Sulli seemed a little unable to answer the question. She was silent and hesitated for about nine seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I am Cui Zhenli.&quot; His tone sounded calm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with &quot;Cui Zhenli&quot;, in the Korean cultural circle, Cui Zhenli has a more famous stage name &quot;Cui Shirley&quot;. What is bound to &quot;Cui Xueli&quot; is a sweet and pure face. In 2005, Choi Jin-ri became a contracted trainee with the Korean entertainment company SM. Four years later, she debuted as a member of the girl group f(x). Because her skin is fair and she loves to laugh, fans call her &quot;Peach in the World&quot; and &quot;Pocket Sister&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sulli Cui maintains a sweet image in front of the public. But she said that she is not a &quot;cute&quot; person and is far from the public&#39;s imagination of her as a &quot;pocket sister.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a certain moment, she doubted everything. &quot;I do what others ask me to do, but I don&#39;t know the reason for doing it.&quot; She began to seemingly rebelliously talk about a relationship that was not recognized by fans and family members, uploading sexy photos on her personal social platform, and in terms of gender concepts Conservative South Korea publishes avant-garde female perspectives. What happened next is known: the torrent of bad reviews hit her brutally. On October 14, 2019, she committed suicide at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 13, 2023, four years after Cui Shirley&#39;s death, Netflix released her posthumous work &quot;To the Truth&quot;. In this documentary, interviewers talk to her about her pain and weakness during those years, as well as her doubts and reflections about being in the star-making industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For each question, she remained silent and thinking for a long time. In &quot;To the Truth&quot;, she expresses the suppression of people by the entertainment industry. &quot;Do you know &quot;Nikita&quot;? It&#39;s like that movie. You can say that we are all puppets, who cares if we are tired?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Being a K-pop idol is the worst. &quot;In between interviews in the documentary, she bluntly said that people don&#39;t seem to think celebrities are people. &quot;When I first entered the entertainment industry, people kept telling me one thing, you are a product. I didn&#39;t think it was ridiculous at the time. You must be the most beautiful and first-class product facing the public.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;For a long time after her debut, Cui Xueli maintained a sweet and smiling public image. (Visual China Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/02bebfc189.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;967&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/02bebfc189. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259323&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;For a long time after her debut, Cui Xueli maintained a sweet and smiling public image. (Visual China Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The only thing I can control is self-blame and self-deprecation”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before becoming the artist Choi Shirley, Choi Jin-jin was born in Busan, South Korea. Her parents divorced when she was 7 years old. The mother raised three children and was financially strapped, so she had to work hard to make a living in the labor market. When Cui Zhenli reached the age of going to school, her mother thought, &quot;Instead of sending her to kindergarten, it is better to send her to an (acting) academy.&quot; That was the starting point for the intersection between Cui Jinri&#39;s life and the entertainment industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Zhenli only has a vague impression of his father - a man who is always half-lying and watching TV, but he has a deep attachment to his mother. When she was a child, her mother was often not at home. &quot;It was my job to wait for my mother every day. I wanted to make a doll that was exactly like my mother.&quot; She said that the relationship between mother and daughter was like &quot;twins or doppelgangers.&quot; &quot;I don&#39;t like green. It&#39;s not my favorite color. One day I asked her (mother), what is your favorite color? She said green. I told everyone that I like green.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the art film &quot;4: Clean Island&quot; based on Shirley&#39;s personal experience, the mother is an image who died very early. She writes a &quot;4&quot; on the face of her young daughter with blood, and the daughter grows up alone. Big, living as a butcher of pigs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why am I so unconfident in everything? I really think about the injuries I suffered when I was a child. Love. I left my father without doing anything wrong. I was afraid that if I did something wrong and caused trouble, even my mother would leave. So I always had no self and only agreed and listened to my mother&#39;s opinions.&quot; Cui Zhenli later Such revealing of inner thoughts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Zhenli became Cui Xueli because of a report. At that time, she was spotted by Lee Byung-hun, the director of &quot;Dae Jang Geum&quot;, and among more than a hundred young actors, she was selected to play the role of Princess Sun Hwa in &quot;The Rhyme of Sweet Potatoes&quot;. The reporter who came to interview felt that the name &quot;Truth&quot; had too strong a Christian connotation, so they discussed changing the name. Later, the report appeared in the newspapers, and Cui Zhenli became Cui Xueli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is how Cui Xueli was noticed by SM Entertainment. In the fifth grade of elementary school, Cui Xueli left Busan and started life as a trainee at SM Entertainment in Seoul. A new life unfolded, and while she was excited, she also felt hidden worries: &quot;Do I really have to live separately from my family?&quot; &quot;Can I adapt here?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While living in the dormitory, she was actually very worried. It is difficult to fully take care of your own life. My mother later learned from the staff that Shirley’s hair often had a rancid smell at that time because she couldn’t wash her hair cleanly. Cui Shirley once said during her lifetime that she &quot;often had to look at people&#39;s looks in order to survive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having just signed with SM, the company’s training goal for Cui Xueli is not a Korean idol, but an actor. At that time, Shirley had already made a name for herself in film and television productions such as &quot;The Sweet Potato Rhyme&quot;. She stayed in Seoul until she graduated from elementary school, and she suddenly grew to over 1.7 meters tall. This is an embarrassing height for a child actor. My body type is no longer suitable for being a child actor and playing teenage roles, and my mind and experience are not up to par. SM Entertainment, which made its fortune with idol groups, placed her on another track: becoming a member of a girl group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Cui Shirley debuted as a member of the Korean girl group f(x). She quickly became popular among fans for her outstanding appearance. After transitioning from an actress to an idol, she faced another complete, precise and streamlined idol-starmaking industry. There is an unwritten underlying concept in the Korean entertainment industry. Actors have a higher level than idols, and actors have more autonomy, while idols must be cautious even in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an idol, Cui Xueli has a wary attitude towards fame, &quot;I understand what it means to be famous, but I am also very scared. I always feel that it is a bubble. So try not to look at it. Try to Turn around.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the age of 20, Cui Xueli endured everything that &quot;beautiful&quot; brought to her - the support of the crowd and the love of fans. Korean entertainment reporters commented on her appearance, saying that even if she is away from the team, she can still attract fans with her beauty. But she also felt trapped by her appearance. &quot;Every time someone complimented me on my beauty, I wanted to know why they said that... I felt that I had to be beautiful. I was even left out because my behavior was not beautiful enough.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Truth, you seem to be under strict control and restraint. How do you cope with such great pressure?&quot; In the documentary &quot;To Truth&quot;, the interviewer asked a question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The only thing I have control over is blaming myself and putting myself down,” she replied. “The only time I feel like I have control is when I make myself miserable.”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&quot;But that&#39;s too painful. There is a limit to people&#39;s ability to endure pain. Maybe the problem is in the industry itself, not necessarily your problem.&quot; The interviewer said, &quot;This may not be your fault.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In front of the camera, Cui Xueli’s eyes suddenly became moist. She raised her head and said, &quot;No,&quot; pretending to be relaxed. Then she faced the camera, showed a standard smile, and asked, &quot;Can I laugh?&quot; She choked with sobs and said, &quot;I don&#39;t have this choice.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;She said that she has always been wearing a mask called &quot;being brave&quot; and often &quot;pretending to be okay&quot;. &quot;I always don&#39;t want to show that I am weak. I feel embarrassed. I often have such a sense of shame.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, she said more than once that she &quot;screwed up&quot; the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sulli Cui starred in the personal reality show &quot;The Truth Store&quot;. (File photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /22/d9d7e03505.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/d9d7e03505.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;259324&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sulli Cui appears in her personal reality show &quot;The Truth Store&quot;. (File photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The feeling of being left alone in this world&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the age of 20, Cui Xueli decided to break the idol&#39;s mask. She plans to do two things. The first is to find herself a therapist, and the second is to date someone else. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of many people, the &quot;personality&quot; of Sulli that fans and the public bought into began to collapse after she fell in love. In the past, the outside world fixed her image as the girl next door. News of her relationship broke out that she was dating Cui Zi, a member of the hip-hop group Dynamicduo, who is 14 years older than her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The first love rumors are inherently very sensitive for idols. Who the first love rumors are about is really important. Everyone is concerned about Sulli’s first love &quot;The target.&quot; TVDaily reporter Kim Ji-hyun said in an MBC documentary, &quot;The problem is Choi Ja who is too different in age.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother, Kim Soo-jung, was firmly opposed to this relationship, and the mother and daughter even broke up because of it. No more contact. In Jin Xiujing&#39;s view, that was the starting point of the family&#39;s misfortune. &quot;Before the love rumors broke out, our family was happy. It has always been.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fans are also dissatisfied with this relationship. When the love affair broke out, it was during the golden period of f(x)&#39;s development, and love affects the development of the team. Some fans noticed in the live stage video that Cui Xueli sometimes did not dance properly, and suspected that she was &quot;paddling&quot;. Kim Soo-jung revealed that since then, her daughter has suffered from depression and panic disorder. &quot;The fans are cheering right in front of me, and there are good and bad words. You have to listen to these while performing on the stage.&quot; After Shirley passed away, Jin Xiujing returned to the empty house and discovered countless medicines that were far beyond the digestion capacity of ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Cui Xueli felt happy in this relationship, during their relationship, Cui Zi caused controversy due to the more explicit lyrics in the new song &quot;Eat, Sleep,&quot;. In 2015, Sulli officially quit f(x). In 2017, the two announced their breakup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“(I) was hurt by others, and the whole person collapsed at that time. Because of these people, I can rely on someone. Hiding behind others, I can also feel positive energy. But I am very close to you. People close to me and people around me gradually left me. Because they are also cowardly people, they only take care of themselves. I also thought about asking for help, but they did not lend a hand at that time.&quot; Cui Shirley said that she had the feeling that &quot;a person is being The feeling of remaining in this world.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years before her death, many of the contents Cui Shirley posted on social platforms were accused of being &quot;out of line.&quot; A video of squirting cream in the mouth was considered by netizens to have &quot;sexual connotations&quot;; a dinner party with friends and the embarrassment of being drunk was considered &quot;crazy&quot;; a photo of a party with close friends showed a group of men and women hugging happily, causing &quot; Doing drugs&quot; suspicion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every move she makes is noticed, and the media loves to create some eye-catching headlines. Every time there is a new trend, abusive comments flood into the news links. During a live broadcast, a friend read out a comment from an onlooker: I came to the live broadcast room just to see what strange things Cui Xueli did again. She is called &quot;Guan Zhong&quot; by many people, which means: someone who loves to show off her position to attract people&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For young Cui Xueli, these turbulent malices and doubts are not easy to resist. In a video interview, Cui Xueli smiled and said to the camera as if begging for mercy: &quot;Viewers, please love me a little more, journalists, please love me a little more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I really am not Bad guy,” she said on numerous occasions. &lt;p>; 》Stills. (Information picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/b8ebb939ad.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/b8ebb939ad.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259325&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sulley Cui initially entered the entertainment industry as a child star in film and television productions, and later became a member of an idol group. She has stated many times that she would rather become an actor. The picture shows a still from the movie &quot;Real&quot;. (File picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Valuable Rebel&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Cui Xueli&#39;s condition seemed to be better. After a long period of silence, she participated in &quot;The Truth Store&quot; and Variety shows such as &quot;Night of Bad Comments&quot; have more public schedules. In the same year, she released her first album &quot;Goblin&quot;. In June of that year, at a fan meeting to commemorate the release of her first solo album, she told the fans in the audience: &quot;I will live seriously.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four months later, she lived alone He ended his life at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 2019 Korean variety show &quot;Night of Bad Comments&quot;, Cui Xueli, a pink-haired girl, responded one by one to the negative comments that netizens have put on her over the years. She talked about the &quot;no bra&quot; controversy that has been surrounding her, and naturally talked to the host about her understanding of underwear, &quot;underwear is like accessories.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When I first posted the photo without underwear, a lot of people were talking about it. I was scared and could have hidden it, but I didn’t. The reason was that I wanted to change people’s perception of it &quot;I also want to say that it&#39;s not a big deal,&quot; she said. &quot;I think it&#39;s about personal freedom. Underwear is not good for health. They have underwires, which are not good for the digestive organs. I also have problems with my digestion.&quot; . It’s more comfortable not to wear them, so I won’t wear them.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Shirley’s death, some foreign media commented that she is in an industry that “encourages performers to remain silent off stage.” She exists as a valuable rebel. Another potential consensus regarding idols as commodities in South Korea is that idols should not talk about current affairs or comment on social events. But Cui Shirley chose to break it time and time again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Korean society where gender concepts are relatively conservative, many of her public expressions appear to be avant-garde. She said she wanted to get rid of &quot;menstrual shame&quot; and told the male host on a variety show that if you support equality between men and women, then you are a feminist. On April 11, 2019, South Korea abolished the crime of abortion, and she was one of the few female public figures to publicly express support. On Instagram that day, she posted: &quot;Today is such a glorious day, giving all women the right to choose.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Those things I do on social media are all done because I want to Do. My behavior and consciousness are fundamentally consistent with those who support feminism. The idea that women should not do that, speak loudly or have strong opinions is contrary to who I am as a person. I don’t like what they say. Men can talk openly about sex, their desires or dissatisfaction, and will be praised for being outspoken in these areas. But if women do the same, they will be regarded as vulgar and self-righteous, and they will be reprimanded.&quot; In the documentary &quot;For&quot; &quot;Truth&quot;, Cui Shirley responded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The fact that Shirley repeatedly did things that misogynists didn&#39;t like and refused to apologize is what really attracted her attention.&quot; After Shirley&#39;s death, Indiana University Korean Culture and Society Expert CedarBough Saeji said in an interview with CNN, &quot;It&#39;s incredible that society criticized her so harshly just because she showed her personality in a way that didn&#39;t fully conform to the norms of Korean society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She Shortly before her death, a friend received a call from her. Friends recalled that Shirley&#39;s voice sounded worse than bad. She said she felt lonely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, Cui Shirley has had a need for a sense of belonging and security around her. &quot;From the beginning, I had to directly enter the complex real world. As a result, I didn&#39;t understand many things. This led me to want to find a sense of belonging. And the stable state that comes with a sense of belonging.&quot; In the documentary , the interviewer asked her who she cared about most, and she said they were the members of f(x). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a video interview, f(x) member Luna said that they had not seen each other for five years since Sulli left the group. Shirley once took the initiative to contact her and sent her a text message: &quot;Sister, I miss my sister.&quot; That was the first time in the 15 years since they had known each other that Shirley used the semi-speech between peers instead of honorifics to talk to her. Speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It feels like I sent this text message after enduring it for a long time. As a sister, I feel sorry. I should have gone to her first.&quot; Luna cried in front of the camera. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Xueli stayed in the &quot;unstable state&quot; of cutting off contact with her mother, falling out of love, leaving the team, and being criticized by the outside world for a long time. Sometimes, she broadcasts live and communicates with fans. Sometimes she shows almost restless excitement, and sometimes she falls into a trance, and her eyes almost lose their sparkle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sulli Cui participated in the creation of all lyrics in the album &quot;Goblin&quot;. One of them is called &quot;On the Moon&quot;, and her true feelings may be hidden in the lyrics. The lyrics read: &quot;Let us ride on the Galaxy Railway 999 together/Now I want to be/a happy girl forever/Your happy girl/Carry the doll in my sleeping dreamland/Drive away the fear in my beautiful dream / The little man on the shoulder took over my memories / Easily took away the flying colors that painted me / In the middle of the night, with my fascination with the world in the book / Take away the freedom of this cold body / Stop my mother from clasping her hands &#39;s prayer/to the moon.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, the five members of f(x) went to New Zealand to film a variety show, where they jointly buried their first time capsule as adults. Ten years have passed, and Cui Shirley never had the chance to open it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;(Main references: Netflix documentary &quot;To the Truth&quot;; MBC documentary &quot;Where does Shirley make you feel uncomfortable&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt; /a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年少时的心灵创伤如何疗愈？愿大家都能被温柔以待]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261049]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;《&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www .infzm.com/contents/260544&quot;>;&lt;u>;When a child is bullied, should he fight back? The article &quot;Talk about my courage education for children&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&quot; made me think back to my past cowardice and think again about what I should do when my children are bullied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day not long ago, my child came back and told me that a classmate always stepped on his feet when waiting in line and frequently pushed himself during outdoor activities. I asked him, had he told the teacher? The child said that he told her, but when confronted, the other party said that he had not stepped in, and then the matter was settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I thought about it and the only way I could think of was to stay away from him. I told my son, if he sees him approaching you during outdoor activities, you should stay away from him quickly. My son smiled and said he was so tired, and asked me what if I didn&#39;t guard against him. I was dumbfounded. I wanted to tell him to adapt to circumstances. The subtext of this sentence was to step back, but I didn&#39;t say it out loud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days later, I went to pick up my children from school. I went there early and was first in line. After picking up my children, I waited aside. When the child&#39;s parents showed up, I walked over and explained the situation to the other mother. The other mother was very polite and said that her child sometimes goes &quot;crazy&quot; and likes to be clingy to others. We will talk about it later. After some time, I asked the child if he had been stepped on recently. The child said that after successfully hiding a few times, he had not been stepped on recently. He went to step on others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My earliest memory of bullying is in the toilet on the rural primary school campus. Several children surrounded a classmate who was urinating. Some were holding small bricks in their hands, and some were moving their fists as if to do something. Ready to swing out at any time. At that time, I often timidly walked out after going to the toilet. Occasionally when no one was outside, I would shout &quot;The teacher is here&quot; and then run away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there were no obvious differences in the families of bullies or victims. The only obvious difference was that if the victims came from towns, they were more likely to have parents come to school to complain about their children, while victims from rural families were more likely Most of them will not be taken seriously by their parents. Firstly, they are busy with farm work. Secondly, they think that small fights are normal and not worth mentioning. Unless there is a serious physical injury, they will come to school to seek feedback from the teacher. Of course, the quality of the feedback depends on whether you can meet a fair and strict class teacher, rather than being a messy teacher. As for psychological trauma, in rural schools twenty years ago, almost no one had ever heard of such a term. Such neglect will make the victim&#39;s memory become unforgettable, and even decades later it will be awakened due to certain factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all these years, I still remember a Japanese drama &quot;Housekeeper Mita&quot; I watched ten years ago. In foreign works, I found some common emotional cowardice in human nature. In the play, while the family was having dinner, they watched a news story about a primary school student who committed suicide after being bullied, which aroused discussion among the family. During the discussion, the younger son was asked if he had been bullied, but he chose to conceal it and deny it. The youngest daughter who is in kindergarten asked Mita why some people bully others. Mita replied expressionlessly that it is because humans are fragile animals who bully the weak and fear the strong. The answer was sharp and harsh. The younger son experienced being coerced by classmates to cooperate in cheating, and finally when he was coerced into stealing, he chose to ask Mita for help. Mita&#39;s &quot;violence&quot; helped put the boy into a dilemma of more serious threats and misunderstandings by his relatives and teachers. When faced with more severe threats of bullying, the younger son once again sought Mita&#39;s &quot;violent&quot; help. This time the help rose to the threat of death. In the confrontation with the bully, the younger son completed his ideological transformation and awakening. He stopped Sita in time and started a boy-to-boy duel with him. Those words of accusation are heartbreaking, but these blood and tears have not changed the bullies, which makes people sigh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back on the bullying I encountered when I was young, the usual solution was to endure it or avoid it, mostly to survive the sorting or further education. So, when my children faced similar bullying, I didn’t have many alternative answers in mind, and the solutions I threw out were old and pedantic. When I asked a friend who has children, what do you hope to gain if your child is bullied by others, she said that she can communicate freely without being influenced by external factors. She said it in a subtle way. I know that what she is afraid of is encountering injustice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real-life cases, bullies rarely turn to kindness. Looking at the Korean dramas that are rich in campus bullying dramas, the mode of those dramas will probably move towards the &quot;cool drama&quot; mode, that is, in the end, violence is used to counter violence, and the victim In the end, the violence was suppressed, and the perpetrators were punished by law. However, the reality is that both parties often go to the abyss of tragedy, and the positive ending we expect rarely occurs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children can be healed from the trauma of bullying. In addition to a small chance of self-healing, the other part is the gentle treatment by other students. When children come back every day, they will share their happiness in school. In addition to occasionally telling who they were bullied by, they also share who helped them. For example, who shared a mosquito repellent bracelet with them, and who helped them forget to forget during outdoor activities. Take the kettle back to the classroom, etc. Those actions that many adults think are trivial have established the feelings of friendship and mutual help among children since childhood. At this time, I will tell him that when others encounter similar problems and you happen to be able to help, you should help. Such actions will invisibly take root and blossom in the other person&#39;s heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impact of injury or redemption in youth often lasts a lifetime. This has been verified in many realistic works. Fortunately, I still have a warm memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifteen years ago, I was in my second year of high school. There was a small college entrance examination that year. I took a few subjects in advance and needed to take a two-hour bus from the town to the city. I had never been on a long-distance bus before, and I started to get motion sickness as soon as I got on the bus. I was sweating and felt dizzy. There were more than a dozen seats in that minibus, and most people had to stand. The female classmates next to me quickly noticed something strange about me. The two girls stood up and asked me to lie down on the seat. They took out cooling oil and applied it to me. That kind of tenderness still warms my heart when I think about it. Their actions helped me learn and have empathy very early on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I were to compare my progress with that of the previous generation of parents when their children were bullied, it would probably be that my first reaction was to ask where the child was hurt, rather than asking why the child bullied you. Not bullying others. But my parents and I face the same dilemma. Apart from keeping our children away from bullies, there are not many routes and methods for us to choose calmly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a worker in the cultural industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders @163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多所高校督导学生坐前排：不提高“教风”先要求“学风”，属本末倒置丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261057]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, many colleges and universities have carried out &quot;study style&quot; construction and urged students to &quot;sit in the front row&quot; in class, which has caused concern. The school stipulates that if the front row is not full, the last row will be in violation, which is staggering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan Xinxiang Medical College has launched a school-wide special inspection of academic style since November 20. The inspections included &quot;four no&#39;s&quot;: not bringing teaching materials, not taking notes, not asking questions, and not sitting in the front row. Phenomenon. Henan Institute of Technology requires the establishment of an &quot;inspection-nurture&quot; system, focusing on checking the &quot;attendance rate, head-up rate, and front-row student occupancy rate&quot; of students&#39; classrooms. The School of Transportation Engineering of Changsha University of Science and Technology requires students to take the initiative to &quot;sit in the front row, raise their heads, bring teaching materials, and ask questions&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first impression this gives people is , treating college students as children. In addition to requiring college students to bring textbooks, sit in the front row, and take notes, many colleges and universities require students not to stay in the dormitory for self-study at night, and there are also bed and hygiene checks. In fact, except for professional courses, classmates may not take the same courses, and different courses use different classrooms. They do not have fixed classrooms and locations like middle school and high school students. Why should we discipline college students like children and fail to respect the right of adults to self-determination? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was in college more than 20 years ago, I still remember that there were two ways for people to occupy positions. For courses with well-educated teachers, wonderful lectures, and popular courses, the front rows will be occupied first, and those who come later will have to sit in the back; for courses with mediocre or unsatisfactory teachers, dry lectures, and less popular courses, Those who came first would occupy the back row, while those who came later had to sit in the front row, endure the direct attention of the teacher, and had to pretend to listen carefully and respond positively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former method is a medal for a good teacher. The latter method is often because although the class is not interesting or the teaching is poor, but you don’t want to fail, or because the teacher has to take attendance and take attendance, but he can’t retain the students. students will resist in a negative way. Therefore, some teachers often say in the first class: Come and go as you please, without calling names, but you will be responsible for not doing your homework or failing the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, for teachers, their primary mission is to transfer valuable professional knowledge and skills to students by relying on their profound knowledge and superb teaching skills. This is to attract students rather than force them to accept it. own teaching content. Good spiritual food is full of fragrant air. If you don&#39;t say anything about peaches and plums, you will make your own mistakes. A melon that is twisted is not sweet, and a horse that doesn&#39;t drink water is meaningless. These principles are well known to everyone, and this is also the basic way to be a teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, teachers and schools can only ask themselves to have a good &quot;teaching style&quot; and convince students; instead of first requiring students to have a certain ideal &quot;study style&quot;, There are no requirements for teachers’ teaching ability. This is simply putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lectures are clearly scripted and lackluster. They also require students to sit in the front row as if they are taking a popular course. They force students to raise their heads and act like they are listening attentively, interact in a pretentious manner, and deprive students of passive coping skills. The rights of the curriculum, this is simply to torture students mentally. Moreover, forcing bad courses and bad teachers to enjoy the same treatment as good courses and good teachers is like trying to sell rotten and sour apples at the same price as good and sweet apples. It is completely challenging the laws of the market and human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an economic point of view, higher education or packaged professional subject knowledge products are no different from other goods and services. Teachers and schools are the providers, and students are the demanders. The rights and interests of both parties They are equal in terms of personality, and there is no reason why one party can discipline the other party infinitely. Reasonable classroom discipline is required. For example, no student can disrupt the peace and process of the classroom, because this damages the dignity of the teacher and the rights of other students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But conversely, it cannot be established as a rule or obligation to require college students to listen carefully, because college students are adults. From the perspective of interests, if he feels that the content is important, he will listen carefully and even study further after class. However, if he feels that he has mastered it, either this part of the content is not important, or he underestimates the importance of the content and wanders around. Outside of that, as long as it doesn&#39;t disrupt the peace and flow of the class, it shouldn&#39;t be considered a problem that needs to be solved. From the perspective of rights, there are reasonable boundaries between teachers and students. Students&#39; passive coping is the basic freedom. Students&#39; activeness and seriousness are earned (earned), not deserved. Let students grab the front row and occupy a good seat to get the best. The mental and spiritual enjoyment is the goal of teachers and can even be said to be their duty. At this point, the treatment of college students should be different from that of primary and secondary school students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for supervising whether college students bring textbooks and take notes, this ignores the characteristics of university knowledge transfer. As long as you go to a higher-end university and have teachers who are interested in teaching, the teaching materials for a course are often only outlines and summary, which will definitely involve the reading and discussion of a large number of related books and papers. Unless certain courses follow the textbook, it will be difficult to read. There is no reason why all students must bring textbooks; of course, if the textbook itself is a classic and worthy of in-depth study word for word, then students should generally bring textbooks, but if a student occasionally forgets to bring them, it is not a problem. It can be a perfect solution when used together in the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the teacher is reading from the text, there is no need for students to take notes; if the teacher’s lecture is particularly exciting, then the students will pay full attention and devote themselves to listening, absorbing, and absorbing what the teacher has to say. It becomes your own thing. There is no need to take notes in class, so as not to affect the absorption effect of the present. It can be summarized and organized afterwards, and it can further deepen the understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good teaching and learning style is to respect students&#39; sovereignty as adults, allow students to exert their personal autonomy, enhance their ability to self-govern, and cultivate their sense of personal responsibility. The biggest difference between studying in universities and primary and secondary schools is that college students need to invest more in thinking and sharpen their personal understanding and analysis. Learning a major is to logically build a complete knowledge system in their brains and become a major. Part of subjectivity, the memory part is relatively secondary. Force and indoctrination are meaningless. Only things that students truly think through will become their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to improve the teaching style and study style of a certain university, a &quot;Typical Case of the School of Medical Imaging Testing and Rehabilitation&quot; was established, and three rules were established: &quot;Sit in the front row&quot;, requiring students to give priority to sitting in the front row; &quot;Double reporting&quot; , if the front row is not full, the school committee will record the list of students in the last row and report it to the teacher and counselor. Pay close attention to the implementation so that everyone does not dare to violate the rules: first time: anonymously report his behavior and ask other students to learn from it; second time: ask him to publicly review his name during the evening roll call, and the class will set up a special team to follow up and inspect; third time: Times: Inform parents that if they commit the crime again, they will need to come to the school to communicate, or they will be &quot;accompanied&quot;. Frankly speaking, this is a way to manage primary school students, and it is a very bad way to manage primary school students. It is not only inappropriate to use it on college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿光“明星”果蔬交易所被查，揭开“电子盘”风云二十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261073]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Shouguang is the largest vegetable distribution center in the country. Visual China/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/e4977a7f35.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/e4977a7f35.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shouguang It is the largest vegetable distribution center in the country. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being summoned by the police, Qian Moyouxin went to Zhouyi. He asked a reporter from Southern Weekend for his birthday information and asked &quot;Master Zhou Yi&quot; for a divination. After learning that he and the reporter were destined to meet, he chose an auspicious day to meet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we met in his office, he was arranging flowers in an open glass vase about half a meter high. The flowers were pruned orchids. An empty vase indicates &quot;deficit&quot;, and all empty vases must be filled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest loss in his life occurred in the &quot;Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Electronic Disk&quot;. In just four years from 2012, he lost millions of dollars. As a result, the family fell apart and the curve of life fell to the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electronic trading is an imported product. It originally referred to the electronic bidding platform of the Chicago Mercantile Exchange for matching transactions. In China, electronic trading generally refers to electronic platforms for spot trading of commodities outside of official futures exchanges. It was originally established to promote the circulation of commodities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray was born in 2009 and moved to Tianjin the following year. It is operated by Shandong Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group (Tianjin) Commodity Trading Market Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tianjin Trading Market). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shouguang is the administrative city of Weifang City and the largest vegetable distribution center in the country. Relying on the famous name of &quot;China&#39;s Hometown of Vegetables&quot;, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray once became a prestigious electronic tray, with agents all over the country and many traders. Until May 2020, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Pan suddenly announced that it would stop the account opening and deposit functions, and the company entity was canceled in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aftermath is even more turbulent. In April 2023, the Public Security Bureau of Ju County, Rizhao City, Shandong Province launched an investigation into the Tianjin Trading Market for &quot;suspected illegal business operations&quot; and took criminal measures against the operation management team and some regional agents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the county-level agent of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Distribution District, Qian Moyou was also implicated. In September, he learned from the local police that he was on the fugitive list and needed to go to the Ju County Public Security Bureau to explain the situation and turn over his illegal gains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another agent told Southern Weekend reporters that he had handed over two million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The subsequent development of electronic disks deviated from the original idea. A large number of trading platforms suspected of disguised futures and illegal operations were shut down and cancelled. &quot;It&#39;s a tough battle, a look back, and a clean-up. No industry can continue to clean up and rectify for more than ten years like the spot trading market.&quot; Wang Zaiwei, secretary-general of the Commodity Trading Place Innovation Service Alliance, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also introduced that there were more than 1,000 trading venues in the country at their peak, but today there are only about 200 left, and more than 200 of them are state-owned holdings and approved by provincial governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will the electronic disk, which has grown wildly, come to an end? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Business extended by agents&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“They were banned long ago, so there were not so many people entering the market later.” Qian Moyou recalled that the person who introduced him to open an account had vowed It is said that other trays will die upon inspection, but only the Shouguang fruit and vegetable tray is safe and sound, which shows that it is legitimate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was 2012. After more than 20 years of entrepreneurship, Qian Moyou had saved some funds, but the company was facing a development bottleneck. It happened that a friend introduced him to Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Pan to invest. Out of a businessman&#39;s caution and unfamiliarity with the agricultural products industry, he was hesitant at first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that he was still undecided, his friend found a teacher who was familiar with the operation of Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays. The teacher actually plays the role of &quot;calling orders&quot; and guides Qian Moyou to buy and sell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, Qian Moyou registered as an agent on the Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate website (you can open several accounts), along with several relatives and friends, including public officials and people in the financial industry. &quot;They saw that I had a large amount of funds and suggested that I register as an agent to save some handling fees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, the Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray should attract traders engaged in agriculture. However, according to Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate&#39;s &quot;Spot Spot Transaction Management Measures&quot; obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, you only need to provide your ID card and bank card number to open an account, and you do not need to provide supporting materials if you have a background in the agricultural products industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The software interface used for trading is the same as that of general futures and stock trading software. You can see the price trend K-line chart and centralized bidding transaction information. You can buy or sell agricultural product contracts by paying a 20% margin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Trading adopts the &quot;T+0&quot; system, and contracts of the same direction and type can be traded frequently on the same day. Varieties include pumpkin, winter melon, carrot, dried pepper, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the guidance of the teacher in the early stage, Qian Moyou made a small profit, so he invested more and more funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Moyou typed out the transaction records of several bank cards used for operations at that time, transferred a large number of accounts to himself, and transferred the funds to the Tianjin trading market. But Qian Moyou didn&#39;t want to pull anyone&#39;s head. The few names on the list that he couldn&#39;t remember were the handling fees he returned to the customers at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike Qian Moyou, most agents not only make profits from market transactions, but also service fees are their main source of income. Only when a steady stream of customers open accounts in their own names and guide customers to frequent transactions can agents bring generous returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electronic disk development relies on agents. For district and county-level agents like Qian Moyou, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray generally refunds 75% of the transaction fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a 2011 judgment, agent Cui signed an agreement with Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray, and the other party entrusted it to develop customers and give customers a 75% rebate on transaction fees. If Cui&#39;s downline Wang continues to develop customers, he will receive a 70% rebate, and if Wang continues to develop his downline Li, he will receive a 68% rebate, once a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted the original Zhengzhou agent of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Pan in the name of opening an account. He now provides online account opening for another agricultural product spot trading market, Shengtong Jiulong. If you recommend customers to him, you can open an account according to the daily schedule. The commission will be returned and 75% of the customer&#39;s transaction fee will be obtained. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After killing the long side, kill the short side&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After following the teacher for a period of time, Qian Moyou initially grasped the trading logic. Take potatoes as an example. Compare the market and spot prices. If the spot price is high, buy long; if the spot price is low, sell short. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He divided his own funds into more than 20 accounts, and worked with the company&#39;s employees to earn a few points from trading every day, which was enough for a day&#39;s salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the methods taught by teachers sometimes work and sometimes fail. Among Qian Moyou&#39;s friends, some have studied K-line technical knowledge, but they are of no use in the Shouguang fruit and vegetable tray. In the four years since he entered the market, Qian Moyou has &quot;cut his flesh&quot; three or four times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most severe &quot;overturn&quot; was the pumpkin contract in 2014. Qian Moyou made a short order based on the spot market and was able to earn a few points at the beginning. After big funds came in, the market stopped moving. After that, when he opened the website for several days, the limit dropped, and suddenly the limit started to rise in the opposite direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to keep his position, Qian Moyou had to continue to add margin calls, and even borrowed money from friends and invested all of it in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the delivery month, Qian Moyou will top up the margin according to the specified date. Having already made a heavy bet, he firmly believed that the market would return to the spot price and the loss would not be too large. However, the end result was that the market price deviated seriously from the spot price, which also made him want to find goods offline for delivery and close the position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, Qian Moyou contacted the pumpkin dealer in Yancheng. After some inquiries, the idea of ​​delivery was shattered. After seeing the product quality, appearance, color and other standards stipulated in the delivery agreement, a Yancheng melon seller regretted that the regulations were too detailed. Even if he collected the melons from all the melon farmers in the city and let him choose at will, he would not be able to get the goods stipulated in the agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Moyou finally came to his senses and decisively exited the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For someone like you, losing millions is nothing.&quot; Dong Hangge spoke in thick Hebei and Lu mandarin. Hearing what happened to Qian Moyou, as a friend he couldn&#39;t help but Ridicule. Dong Hangge, as the municipal agent of Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays, is now also under investigation by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Hangge’s experience in investing in electronic trading is much richer than that of Qian Moyou. He has participated in the famous Dragon Cauldron Trading and has learned the ropes of electronic trading - you have to buy against the main funds to make money. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a virtual disk, do you understand?&quot; Dong Hangge couldn&#39;t help but say, you are real money, and the person who is &quot;in charge&quot; is a string of fictitious numbers. Assuming that all the main funds are doing long, the market will pull in the opposite direction, forcing the long parties to cut their losses. Only by guessing the right direction can you make money along the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, working as an agent earns handling fees, but it is not enough to earn handling fees alone. He also has to help his big customers make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to inquire about the flow of funds on the market, Dong Hangge once hired a young college graduate to lurk into the municipal agent with the largest amount of client funds to inquire about the direction. He then directed his clients to go in the opposite direction. Do. On a potato contract, one of his big clients earned a full eight million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Hangge suggested that big customers should close the deal as soon as they get a good deal. Unfortunately, the customers were not satisfied. As Dong Hangge expected, the dish was full of flavour, and the customer vomited out more than half of what he had eaten. &quot;If someone (the banker) kills the short side, he will definitely turn around and kill you on the long side.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Taking the &quot;Shouguang Garlic Plate&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before going to the Public Security Bureau, Qian Moyou spent more than ten dollars I searched for information every day to study why I was &quot;operating illegally.&quot; Only then did we discover that the spot trading market was once a product of local economic revitalization and innovation and reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang Qing, founder of China Futures Market and former researcher at the Development Research Center of the State Council, told Southern Weekend reporters that agricultural product production is scattered and farmers need price signals that can reflect market supply and demand to rationally allocate resources. &quot;The Shouguang Vegetable Wholesale Market can solve the problem of vegetable circulation, but it cannot solve the problem of low prices of vegetables hurting farmers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 1990, China has successively established five major futures exchanges. However, most agricultural products failed to enter the futures market. Chang Qing explained that most agricultural products are not suitable for entering the futures market with a large amount of capital due to their small delivery volume and easy contract manipulation (forced position). However, these varieties can be traded and innovated by local platforms or wholesale markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Shouguang began to explore medium and forward trading of vegetables, which is equivalent to locking in the price of agricultural products for farmers in advance. It is a trading model between futures and spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2005, with the approval of the Shandong Provincial Government, four units including the China Vegetable Circulation Association jointly funded the establishment of Shandong Shouguang Vegetable Electronic Trading Market Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Shouguang Electronic Market), which can realize &quot;unplanted vegetables&quot;. &quot;Sell first&quot; and &quot;sell before receiving&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Jun, the manager of Shouguang Electronic Disk at the time, introduced that Shouguang Electronic Disk will announce the purchase price for the next 10 months, and the growers or brokers will sell the orders before planting, and deliver the quality products at maturity. goods to avoid the risks brought by falling prices to farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zaiwei began operating a commodity exchange in Shandong in 2007. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the trading volume of garlic varieties was good in the early days, and most of the participants were cold storage owners, garlic dealers and brokers. These people themselves are spot customers. Through electronic transactions, they only need advance payment to complete the transaction, saving warehousing and transportation costs. &quot;The purpose of (local trading venues) is to support the actual needs of spot customers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the electronic trading did not operate as originally envisioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shouguang electronic plate really started to become famous because of garlic, and thus got a more famous name &quot;Shouguang garlic plate&quot;. Garlic is also called &quot;white tiger&quot;. Tigers can eat people, and garlic can also eat people. If investors are not careful, they will lose all their money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high volatility of garlic prices has made it the most suitable variety for speculation among vegetables. Although Shouguang is the hometown of vegetables, it does not produce garlic. In 2005, Shouguang electronic disk entered the &quot;Garlic Township&quot; - Jinxiang County, Jining City, Shandong Province. By 2010, Jinxiang County had gathered five or six electronic trading markets. Among them, the two larger ones, besides Shouguang Electronic Trading, were Longding Electronic Trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;At that time, electronic disk was regarded as an emerging industry such as e-commerce, and many local governments actively introduced it as a key project.&quot; Zhao Defa, former vice chairman of the Shandong Provincial Writers Association, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Defa wrote in his documentary work &quot;White Tiger&quot; that &quot;Garlic God&quot; Dong Zigang helped Shouguang build a garlic electronic disk. A president of the Garlic Chamber of Commerce commented that since Dong Zigang joined the industry, traditional trade has been changed and capital operations have been introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Zigang is from Junan, Shandong, and settled in Weifang. He made his fortune in Shouguang Garlic Distribution, and successively operated Jinxiang Nandianzi and Hengli Distribution, and served as the president of Hengfeng Electronic Distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electronic disks also created a myth - Fu Haitang, a farmer with a background in pig raising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2009, Fu Haitang invested tens of thousands of yuan earned in soybean meal futures into Shouguang electronic trading. Coinciding with the rare &quot;garlic you are ruthless&quot; market, Shouguang electronic trading has introduced a &quot;centralized transfer&quot; system, that is, if there are three consecutive daily limit or three lower limit, positions will be closed by agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Haitang wrote in his self-report that the main short seller at the time greeted the exchange. When the market price of garlic increased 30 times, he only earned 700,000 and was transferred centrally, so he switched to Longding Pan. , earned 6 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also this wave of market conditions that caused the short sellers of the Long Ding Pan to misjudge the situation, which even dragged down the Long Ding Pan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, Rizhao City Deputy Mayor Wantong announced the results of the investigation into the Longding electronic trading incident to traders: After the garlic market changed dramatically, Longding failed to liquidate short sellers in accordance with regulations and instead lent Hou Dawei, the main short seller, used 30 million virtual funds to short-sell. After losing money, he misappropriated customer margins to continue short-selling and bet against traders, resulting in a serious deviation between the market price and the spot price. He lost hundreds of millions of margins and traders were unable to withdraw money normally. And after some contracts enter the delivery period, there are still huge amounts of open positions that cannot be delivered smoothly, causing disputes over delivery breaches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter quickly triggered a regulatory storm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission led 7 ministries and commissions to form a State Council commodity trading market investigation team that entered Shandong, and its first stop was Weifang. &quot;China Business News&quot; reported that Jiang Yang, then chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, inspected a commodity trading venue in Weifang and denounced the incident angrily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this round of regulatory rectification, many electronic disks collapsed due to problems such as virtual fund transactions, poor delivery, and founders running away with their money. Executives were arrested and jailed. However, the huge funds gathered in electronic disks It still attracts batches of &quot;gamblers&quot;. If you pour down a platform, you will burn a platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zaiwei once wrote that from 2007 to 2010, a large number of trading venues emerged in Shandong, forming a situation where &quot;the whole country looks to Shandong for bulk, and Shandong looks to Weifang for bulk&quot;. &quot;There was no approval, no review, no supervision, no rules. At that time, it was completely open to work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if you get the approval, you still rely on the platform to show your magic. There are various approval departments, &quot;There are National Development and Reform Commission, Commerce Bureau, as well as the Finance Office.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, the Economic Development Zone Branch of the Yancheng City Public Security Bureau of Jiangsu Province characterized Hengfeng Electronic Trading as a disguised futures market, and Dong Zigang was jailed for ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Shouguang electronic disk survived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Shouguang Electronic Disk was acquired by the private enterprise Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holding Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings), which was owned by Shandong Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group) ) is funded and established. On June 17 of the same year, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group established Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the official website, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group has been selected as one of the top 500 national key leading enterprises in agricultural industrialization and is a nationally renowned operator of the entire vegetable industry chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Move to Tianjin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Either leave or close.&quot; Wang Zaiwei said that Jiang Yang&#39;s inspection put great pressure on the Weifang government, and several local exchanges were forced to make a choice. It was at this stage that Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray moved to Tianjin, and Tianjin also became a new gathering place for various exchanges across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings revealed in an interview with the self-media &quot;High Power Lens&quot; that Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray was invited by the Tianjin Municipal Government to move to Tianjin in December 2010 as a key agricultural financial innovation project. Settled in Binhai New Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Each region’s understanding and cognition of commodity trading are very different.” Wang Zaiwei said that whether trading venues can continue to operate at this stage depends on the attitude of local regulatory authorities. In other words, the attitude of local regulatory authorities is crucial. play a decisive role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the clean-up and rectification becomes more stringent, provincial people&#39;s governments formulate regulatory rules for exchanges. Some local governments assign regulatory responsibilities to the Commerce Bureau and some to the Financial Bureau. &quot;There are still huge differences in regulatory policies across the country.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Economic Herald, from 2010 to April 2013, the professional managers of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray were Ji Hairong and Meng Qingchao (who did not hold shares). President Ji Hairong is the soul of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate. He has worked for many commodity exchanges. People in the industry are more familiar with his QQ nickname &quot;Tycoon&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2012, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray also revealed the problem of poor settlement that cannot be escaped from electronic trading. In April 2013, Ji Hairong and Meng Qingchao both lost contact. Later, it was confirmed by the media that Ji Hairong and others had been taken compulsory measures by the Shouguang City Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray is still operating normally after the accident of the two responsible persons. In their resignation announcement, they also stated that their business operations during their tenure were in compliance with relevant national laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the years of operation of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray, its historical shareholders include Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings, etc., and the major shareholder is Yang Ming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Ming is quite mysterious and low-key, and the locals know little about him. At present, his appearance can only be seen from the company&#39;s official website: sparse hair, a shiny forehead, and a beer belly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A municipal agent has participated in several Shouguang fruit and vegetable plate meetings and met Yang Ming and a group of senior executives. The guests attending the meeting were all government officials and experts in the futures field, and they preached about the standardization of the platform. After the meeting, experts will also attend a banquet with the leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The offices of Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group and Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings controlled by Yang Ming are both located in Shouguang Vegetable Building. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6bc7c988e8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/22/6bc7c988e8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shouguang Vegetables of Yang Ming Holdings Industrial Group and Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings, their offices are located in Shouguang Vegetable Building. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Futures or spot? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Electronic disks like Shouguang fruit and vegetable disk were established as spot trading markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Deyi, director of Beijing Xunzhen Law Firm, told Southern Weekend reporters that in the Shouguang fruit and vegetable market, a large number of customers engage in electronic transactions without physical delivery and buy and sell standardized contracts in a centralized transaction manner. There are many cases in the Supreme People&#39;s Court. This is the core feature of &quot;illegal futures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of spot commodities, Wang Deyi’s legal team has obtained the first winning verdicts in many places, and has represented many contract disputes between Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray investors and trading platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Zhihui, who lives in Jiangsu, is one of the few investors interviewed who has had delivery experience. Since most investors have never actually participated in the delivery, they do not know the location of the delivery warehouse for Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2016, You Zhihui has been operating in Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray for a year and a half, but lost 1.2 million yuan. What really made him lose trust in the market was a delivery the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of delivery, You Zhihui received a delivery note for dried chili peppers sent to him by the agent. The payment date was March 1, 2017, and he was required to complete the delivery procedures on March 2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bill of lading shows that the quality grade is standard product, the unit of measurement is 78 tons, and the delivery warehouse is Yinshan Cold Storage in Maying Township, Wucheng County, Texas. Qichacha showed that the cold storage did store dried chili peppers. The delivery contact is Shan Yongning, who is the legal representative of Tianjin Trading Market. Southern Weekend reporters called the contact number on the delivery note, but the number could no longer be reached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that You Zhihui traveled more than 700 kilometers to Dezhou, Shandong Province, so there was little point in taking the transportation fee to transport it back to Jiangsu. To this end, You Zhihui contacted several local pepper purchasers to deliver the goods together. The purchasers would calculate the price after inspecting the goods and take them away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the problem lies in the acceptance process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The warehouse handover party asked You Zhihui to send a truck to pick up the goods on the delivery day, but refused to provide the product warehousing information. As a result, You Zhihui was unable to verify whether the goods were the goods agreed in the contract, and also refused You Zhihui to bring the purchaser into the warehouse for inspection. goods. The warehouse transfer party even wanted to buy You Zhihui&#39;s dried chili peppers at a very low price. You Zhihui&#39;s application for re-inspection to the trading market did not help, and the settlement failed in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the electronic disks that Wang Deyi has come into contact with cannot clearly introduce the flow of customer funds, cannot truly present the total trading volume and physical delivery volume data of the trading venue, and are also unable to inform the number of customers with physical delivery and investment speculation. number of clients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, frequently changing prices do not actually encourage delivery, and investors all hope to earn the difference through spreads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buying and selling standardized contracts is also one of the characteristics of futures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission has a detailed definition of standardized contracts: apart from terms such as price, delivery location and delivery time, other terms are relatively fixed. After the contract is concluded, traders are allowed to exit the market through reverse operations and hedging and liquidation without actually performing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other terms refer to the quantity of traded commodities, trading margin, quotation unit, delivery quality standards, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have compared the text of the (Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate) with the strong wheat futures contract of the Zhengzhou Commodity Exchange, and there is no essential difference between the two.” Wang Deyi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the trading model and transaction details of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray all point to &quot;futures&quot;, the lawsuit is still difficult to fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a large number of effective judgments on the Tianjin trading market, the courts in Tianjin did not determine it as illegal futures. The basis is that since the State Council issued Document No. 38 in 2011 and Document No. 37 in 2012, it has not been closed, banned or suspended due to illegal futures activities or futures transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tianjin Second Intermediate People&#39;s Court once accepted the case of dispute between Dong Yumei and the Tianjin Exchange Market sales contract. In the second-instance judgment, the Tianjin Exchange submitted evidence showing that after 2012, the Tianjin Leading Group for Cleaning Up and Rectifying Various Trading Places organized an annual review of the supervision of trading places, and the Tianjin Exchange was listed in the &quot;List of Trading Places that Passed the Annual Supervision Review&quot; 》No. 14. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter called Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings, hoping to interview the relevant person in charge. The person who answered the call claimed to be a staff member of the general office and said that he could not convey the interview request. Later, Southern Weekend reporters went to Shouguang Vegetable Building, the company&#39;s office on Haoyuan Road, but were intercepted by the guard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the Tianjin trading market, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings also has the same type of commodity trading platforms in Sichuan, Shandong and other places. Among them, the exchanges of the Beichuan Qiang Autonomous County were canceled in 2021. The two in Qingdao operated to 2023. During the recent visit of the southern weekend, the southern weekend found that its team had withdrawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Southern Weekend reporters visited the two trading platforms of Qingdao, and learned from the mouth of security and front desk personnel that the staff of the Qingdao trading market were taken away by the police in May. Qingdao Huihai in September The office of evacuating Qingdao Kangda Wealth Center. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Picture &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/c91925dd3e.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;774&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/c91925dd3e.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; &lt;/p&quot; >; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters visited the two trading platforms of Qingdao, learned from the mouth of security and front desk personnel that the staff of Qingdao trading market were by the police in May 2023 by the police. Take it away, Qingdao Huihai withdrew from the office of Qingdao Kangda Wealth Center in September. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Figure &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Do not speculate on the land, do not plant the disk&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The spot trading market of agricultural products carries the reform of futures experts and local governments How much does this industrial innovation play a role in industrial innovation for more than ten years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Southern Weekend reporters went to Shouguang Land Logistics Park to Shouguang&#39;s largest agricultural product logistics park. I asked more than a dozen agricultural wholesalers to understand the Shouguang fruit and vegetable disk. Most people waved their hands after listening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I see that no one knows this market you said.&quot; Zhen Ling was born in Heilongjiang. He was born in 1980. He has been engaged in pumpkin wholesale in the logistics park for more than 20 years. Ling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She sat in the huge trading hall and brushed the drama, and from time to time, she responded to customer news. Her customer source is relatively fixed. At about 12 noon, there are not many inquiries on her. She told the southern weekend that the biggest role of the logistics park is to be able to complete the product classification and transfer, and vegetables from all over the country will be transmitted here and then sent to all parts of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhen Ling, who recognizes the experts of pumpkin, can watch the pumpkin market for more than 20 days. &quot;It has been seen for a month.&quot; Farmers are gambling, watching the day, maybe a big water someday, a frost, the things in the ground are destroyed. No one dares to predict what happened after half a year, and it is not predicted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the price fluctuations of agricultural products will also form a fluctuation law. In the past two years, the market is very poor, and it should almost rise in the third year. You don&#39;t have to predict, everyone can understand. As a first -level wholesaler, Zhen Ling never afraid of price fluctuations, &quot;we can earn money with rising and falling.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhen Ling will also deal with pumpkin farmers. For pumpkin growers, whether the market is expensive, this species will be planted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are special agricultural products in each county in Shouguang. Farmers will pull the fruit and vegetables of their greenhouses to the county wholesale market sales, and wholesalers will also go to different counties as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gaoming&#39;s family lives in Sun Jiaji Town in the southwest of Shouguang. This is also the birthplace of the winter warm vegetable greenhouse. Shouguang &quot;Caiwang&quot; Wang Leyi lives in Sanyuan Zhucun in Sun Jiaji Town. Sun Jiaji Town is based on planting cucumber and bitter gourd, and the greenhouses of every family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Out of the understanding of agricultural products, Gaoming&#39;s &quot;sacotics&quot; has been more than ten years. He has many times in Jinxiang to stock garlic and garlic, and sell it again when the price is good, which is equivalent to the &quot;two roads Trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It has heard of Shouguang Vegetables and fruit plates. Many people in the village have done transactions on the garlic disk, but this shift of the electronic disk is not necessarily farmer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Make money fast, lose money fast, the market is different from reality, and farmers will not watch this.&quot; Now the &quot;savings&quot; market is not good, and Gao Ming also started a large shed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After being found by the public security, Qian Moyou established a contact with the people who had done Shouguang Fruit and Vegetables in the past. Most of them were people like him without agricultural background. &quot; Stir -frying is not planted. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (at the request of the respondent, Qian Moyou, Dong Hang Ge, You Zhihui, Zhen Ling, Gaoming is a pseudonym) &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花大价钱建雕塑，地方的“面子”与里子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261078]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;In Zhongjiang County, Sichuan, there are nearly 2,000 sculptures stored in an &quot;unfinished&quot; scenic spot. They have been neglected for many years and have been hidden in the weeds. middle. After peeling off the cocoon, the truth emerged: the scenic spot illegally occupied agricultural land, the construction side&#39;s capital chain was broken, and the developer&#39;s legal representative was still running around while on probation. Sculpture is the &quot;face&quot; of a place, but it should also be the lining that shapes the humanistic connotation. Jingzhou, Hubei Province spent 170 million yuan to build the giant Guan Gong statue, Jianhe County, Guizhou Province spent 86 million yuan to build the 88-meter-high Miao goddess statue, and Lushan County, Henan Province spent 7.152 million yuan to build the Cowherd and Weaver Girl statue, which netizens called &quot;ugly and expensive&quot;... Spending a lot of money to build a sculpture, and the &quot;grandeur&quot; behind it is bound to be amplified by public opinion.</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年两院院士增选结果揭晓，共133人当选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261082]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 17:35:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 22, the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Chinese Academy of Engineering announced the list of elected academicians for the 2023 academician election. Among them, China The Academy of Sciences has 59 new academicians and the Chinese Academy of Sciences has 74 new academicians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern+ reporters combed through the list and found that a total of 8 &quot;big names&quot; in Guangdong were newly elected as academicians of the two academies. The specific list is as follows: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Prevention and Treatment Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ning Tsinghua University, Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Hongping Guangzhou Institute of Geochemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zheng Hairong Shenzhen Institute of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chinese Academy of Engineering&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Enhou South China University of Technology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Qingquan Shenzhen University&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xing Feng Guangzhou University&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Chao Guangdong Drug Experimental Technology Center (National Drug Laboratory Guangdong Branch)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The full list is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/a93bd531fc839694def7c5514999c0d6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;3199&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/a93bd531fc839694def7c5514999c0d6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259312&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ce99d370bd12e6ef5a6ed31a3a0d1733.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;3277&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ce99d370bd12e6ef5a6ed31a3a0d1733.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259311&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国最后的狩猎部落，在大兴安岭饲养驯鹿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261075]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:20:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>