<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[上班要不要强制穿工服，这是一个问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, &quot;Does your company require you to wear work clothes at work?&quot; Hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A netizen attended a class reunion. A total of ten people came. It turned out that three classmates who worked in different financial institutions were wearing almost identical work clothes. Nowadays, different units have different requirements for dress code. Some require employees to wear work clothes while others do not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This seems to be a small problem, but it is not. For example, in September, the U.S. Senate was in an uproar over whether members should wear formal attire when entering the Capitol. In the end, the U.S. Senate revised the dress code: allowing senators to wear casual attire such as hoodies and shorts. This move attracted criticism from mainstream media such as The New York Times and The Washington Post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Institutions, companies, and organizations around the world are faced with a multiple-choice question when it comes to employee attire: Should they uniformly dress? What are the considerations of whether to do it or not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/TQRExQi6pPp7lbrXzwLPQr6NFmeV6iqB9PvTA67a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/TQRExQi6pPp7lbrXzwLPQr6NFmeV6iqB9PvTA67a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Realistic Considerations of Uniform Dressing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;work clothes&quot; are actually people from the same institution or organization wearing uniform styles of clothing to identify them. identity, indicate their profession, and demonstrate their responsibilities. Generally speaking, work uniforms are uniform, rigorous, and depersonalized, and are distinguished from employees&#39; personal attire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From a company&#39;s perspective, employees often have practical considerations when wearing uniforms. First of all, this is a need to shape the corporate image. Employees are uniformly dressed and neatly organized, which will leave an initial impression that the company is rigorous, serious, and positive; uniform work uniforms generally have the company&#39;s logo on them, which can play a role in promoting the company&#39;s image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, for those positions that face customers directly and have more communication with customers, such as the financial industry and the lawyer industry, uniform attire of employees can bring customers A professional look and feel helps to dispel customers&#39; doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Furthermore, for workers, wearing uniform professional work clothes can play a role in psychological suggestion, help them enter the working state, and improve their work performance. execution ability. At the same time, wearing work uniforms can also restrain the employee&#39;s personal behavior, reminding him that his words and deeds represent not only his personal image, but also the image of the unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also some special professions, and uniform dress is to reflect the authority and seriousness of the profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, our country has put forward uniform dress requirements for some public authorities, including the public security department, national security department, judicial department, court system, procuratorate system, Customs system, tax system, national quality inspection department, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, this time the U.S. Senate relaxed its dress requirements, which attracted criticism because public opinion was worried that this would undermine the seriousness of Congress. The New York Times wrote this: With the United States so divided right now, one of the last signs of harmony in the Senate is the dress code. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While it does not erase the deep differences beneath the surface, it does remind each senator that their goal is still to pursue majority consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also uniform attire for some professions, which are determined by the characteristics of the profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, doctors’ white coats were first used to promote disinfection habits in surgical operations. The blood stains on the white coats serve as reminders; in addition, clean and tidy clothes White coats can also help doctors prevent static electricity during treatment. Many medical devices are very precise instruments, and the impact of static electricity on the equipment may mislead the diagnosis and treatment results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When doctors enter the operating room, they usually wear blue or green surgical gowns, which is related to &quot;persistence of vision&quot;. During the operation, when the doctor sees the patient&#39;s red blood and shifts his gaze to the doctor&#39;s white robe, a &quot;complementary color afterimage&quot; will appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As long as the doctor looks at the complementary color of red - such as blue or green, it can immediately alleviate the effect of &quot;complementary color afterimage&quot; and reduce visual fatigue, so the surgery Most servers use blue-green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2F2m5ab8kKdYI9MV0kEF1gEN4PdH8eXeiBZXTEV2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2F2m5ab8kKdYI9MV0kEF1gEN4PdH8eXeiBZXTEV2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Relaxing the dress code is not necessarily a bad thing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some units and institutions require uniform dress for reasonable reasons, but this does not mean that uniform dress is suitable for everyone Unit does not mean that uniform dress has advantages and disadvantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some people who have experienced the 1970s and 1980s may be deeply impressed by the &quot;uniform dress&quot; everywhere in that era. At that time, there was a saying that &quot;law enforcement must wear uniforms&quot;, and all public institutions would wear uniforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, it reflects the sense of honor of the profession and &quot;style&quot;; on the other hand, it regards work uniforms as the &quot;hidden benefits&quot; of the unit. Some units treat employees Clothing for all seasons is provided, but the finance department is asked to pay for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So much so that later on, some industries and personnel that did not have administrative functions at all also wore uniforms, and they were similar to those of law enforcement departments, &quot;a fox pretends to be a tiger,&quot; It undermines the seriousness of law enforcement agencies, wastes finances, and has a negative impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, starting in 1986, the State Council rectified uniform dress. In 1988, 1991, 1992, and 2003, the State Council successively issued regulations on the issue of uniform dress. The relevant notice criticized those departments that arbitrarily unified the uniform dress code, which &quot;not only affects the seriousness of the uniform dress code, but also leads to increasing financial expenditures.&quot; Later, the State Council also made clear regulations on uniform dress departments and personnel. It can be seen that it is not good to dress uniformly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Uniform dress will bring some workers a feeling of restriction, rigidity and lack of freedom. Therefore, many employees are opposed to uniform dress. A British survey showed that 61% of people looking for a new job in 2017 said they would have a negative view of any company that enforced a dress code. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to combat the monotonous uniform dress, Western workplaces gave birth to the employee activity Casual Friday (&quot;casual Friday&quot;) - employees voluntarily set Friday as casual clothing On this day, at least on this day, I can control the autonomy of dressing and be free to be myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another study suggests that the majority of the UK workforce would feel more productive if dress codes were more relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Those large companies that value creativity, such as Microsoft and Facebook, often do not impose dress code requirements for their employees. Although professionals may dress in the same way, for example, programmers love plaid shirts, and Zuckerberg wears the same casual clothes every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only do these technology companies not require employees to dress, they also make great efforts to improve the working environment, making the workplace casual, relaxed and free, thus Stimulate employees&#39; imagination and creativity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In short, it is difficult to generalize whether employees should dress uniformly. Some professions emphasize seriousness, some focus on the impression they bring to customers, some professions have special professional attributes, and some professions are more concerned about how to maximize creativity... Different demands also apply to clothing. There are different requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For workers, uniform attire is not that big a problem if the company provides free work uniforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南开段峰：“拿着金饭碗讨饭”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261413]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In June 2022, Duan Feng’s team realized the interventional brain-computer interface in the sheep brain for the first time; a year later In May 2023, led by Duan Feng&#39;s team, the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army General Hospital (301 Hospital) and Shanghai Xinwei Medical Technology Co., Ltd. jointly completed the world&#39;s first &quot;non-human primate (monkey) interventional brain-machine&quot; &quot;Interface Test&quot; was a success. This research was considered by many media to have overcome the shortcomings of invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces and created the third new paradigm of brain-computer interfaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Feng, 46, is currently a professor, doctoral supervisor at Nankai University, and director of the Tianjin Key Laboratory of Interventional Brain-Computer and Intelligent Rehabilitation. Due to Duan Feng&#39;s outstanding achievements in the fields of brain-computer interfaces, artificial hibernation and intelligent aircraft, he was selected as Southern Weekend&#39;s 2023 Scientific and Technological Person of the Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the Southern Weekend Science and Technology Innovation Conference&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/298bbbf676.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/298bbbf676 .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the Southern Weekend Science and Technology Innovation Conference &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of the China Academy of Communications, brain-computer interface (BCI) technology is a revolutionary human-computer interaction. Its mechanism of action is to bypass peripheral nerves and muscles and directly interact with the brain. Establish a new communication and control channel with external devices, which has the effect of monitoring, replacing, improving/restoring damaged or impaired natural central nervous system output and input. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a multidisciplinary cutting-edge technology that can not only assist in the diagnosis and treatment of some neurological diseases, partially or fully realize the compensation of certain human body functions, and is even expected to cure some mental diseases. Medical care is considered to be its most promising field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three main implementation methods of brain-computer interface, non-invasive, invasive and vascular intervention. The non-invasive brain-computer interface mainly refers to the collection of EEG signals in the cerebral cortex without surgery; the invasive type requires implanting electrodes deep into the brain, requiring surgeries such as craniotomy and bone drilling; the vascular interventional type mainly involves the electrode holder. Implanted into the corresponding inner wall of blood vessels to collect EEG signals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, most research on brain-computer interfaces is in the basic research stage, and some clinical results have also been achieved. In June 2022, researchers at Johns Hopkins University completed the world&#39;s first human trial of a bilaterally implanted brain-computer interface. A subject who had been paralyzed for 30 years successfully controlled machinery through EEG signals, completing Deliver cakes and eat independently; in China, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital launched brain-computer interface and deep brain stimulation methods in 2020 to treat refractory depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the participation of star companies such as Meta and Neuralink owned by &quot;Silicon Valley Iron Man&quot; Elon Musk, attention on brain-computer interfaces has been unprecedentedly high in recent years, and Duan Feng will also establish it in 2023 The company is trying to transform the results of brain-computer interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, since he returned to China after studying in Japan in 2009, he has been on the road of &quot;integration of industry, academia and research&quot; by focusing on teaching and research on one hand and entrepreneurship on the other. For this reason, he often stumbled. &quot;1 billion in 10 years, whether to do it or not&quot; has become his &quot;touchstone&quot; to test whether investors are sincere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Southern Weekend’s interview with Duan Feng:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Want to build an “industry-university-research integration” platform&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From an academic background, you received a bachelor&#39;s and master&#39;s degree from the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University, and studied precision mechanical engineering at the University of Tokyo, Japan, and received a master&#39;s and doctoral degree. degree, and chose medical rehabilitation equipment to start a business. Is it because you have always been interested in machinery? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>; When I took the college entrance examination in 1998, the major I wanted to study most was actually electronics. I filled out the application form and was transferred to the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University, where I majored in internal combustion engines and obtained postgraduate qualifications in my senior year. Studying in Japan is also an accidental choice. During my master&#39;s degree, my supervisor sent me to cooperate with two engine companies. At that time, the machinery industry was in recession, and one company went bankrupt. It was very embarrassing. At that time, I thought about changing careers and prepared to study abroad. It happened that the University of Tokyo in Japan not only waived the application fee, but also provided scholarships, round-trip air tickets and accommodation. The conditions were very good, so I chose precision manufacturing related to machinery among the majors they admitted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you later turn to brain-computer interface? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;I have studied intelligent service robots and unitized flexible production lines in Japan. My professional field has shifted from power machinery to robot control, and further Go to brain-computer interfaces. I first heard about the concept of brain-computer interface in a lecture at the University of Tokyo. I thought it was very interesting at the time, but I had limited energy and could not study it in depth. The biggest reason is that I want to copy Japan’s “industry-university-research” model in China. When I was studying in Japan, I encountered many companies that came to colleges and universities to invite students to dinner to identify talents, provide scholarships to students, and provide funds for scientific research projects to teachers to achieve the integration of &quot;industry, academia, and research.&quot; At that time, this model was relatively common in China. Rare. After graduation, I returned to China and entered Nankai University. After completing my teaching tasks, I could delve into the fields I was interested in, and then started to build a company to industrialize the research results. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you start your business at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;I learned about the market while teaching at the university. Specifically, it is to find companies to cooperate to develop things that are urgently needed by the market but there is still half a step in technology development. At that time, a friend introduced some assistive device products in cooperation with small medical device companies, which are types that rely on external force to move the limbs, but they are not independent movements. I hope to make devices that can be independently controlled by people to drive body movements, but I don’t want to sell products because it requires a series of issues such as device registration, quality inspection, and commercial promotion, so I anchored the technology research and development on the front end of the product. When I first returned to China, my monthly salary was only 3,800 yuan. After deducting 2,000 yuan for rent and 1,500 yuan for my children’s kindergarten tuition, I only had 300 yuan for living expenses every month. I think most entrepreneurs should have more money than me. Because I had no money, I had always pinned my hopes of raising money on finding partners or investors, so I took many detours and went through a process of company registration, cancellation, re-registration, and cancellation again. Many times it was dismantled. There was a difficult period when the east wall was repairing the west wall. At first, I considered making some small rehabilitation electrical stimulation equipment. A company talked to me about cooperation and asked me to do front-end research and development. It claimed that after the product was launched, the company would have its own sales channels. I believed it, but after finishing it, I found that this was not the case. Damn, there&#39;s nothing behind it. Some companies also asked me to invest in technology and promised equity. As a result, we advanced money, spent time, and invested a lot of energy. After the technology was formed, the &quot;partner&quot; ran away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to solve the entrepreneurial start-up fund? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;I earned it by selling technology. It is to help companies develop what they need and then sell it for money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Experiencing these things, the impact on you is What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;I am also reflecting and summarizing. Whether I am doing scientific research or doing industry, I just ask myself whether this is the case. If you really want to do what you want to do without anyone&#39;s help, then just do it. When I did not place my hopes on others and relied on my own efforts and persistence to do what I wanted to do, many people who helped me came to me on their own initiative. Some brought money, some brought resources, Others brought some new concepts and ideas, and gradually the matter became a success. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Among the people who took the initiative to find &quot; Liar&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When you have experienced some &quot;stepping into pitfalls&quot;, it will be easier to evaluate people&#39;s risks. Now come and talk to me. Yes, you can tell whether it is suitable or not in just a few minutes. I will not accept investment from others casually now. When someone comes to talk to me, I usually ask a question, &quot;1 billion in 10 years, do you want to do it?&quot; If you don&#39;t want to, then don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. In my case, if it works, it works, if it doesn’t work, it doesn’t work. There is no middle ground. This 1 billion is not just a thought, it is a scientific estimate. I do vascular interventional brain-computer interface experiments. Each electrode is ground out bit by bit by hand. It takes 10 days of grinding 24 hours a day to make one. The cost of consumables, labor costs, etc. in these 10 days add up. The total cost is at least 100,000 yuan; another example is the large animal monkey used for experiments. It costs 200,000 yuan to buy a monkey and 300 yuan to raise it for a day. This cost is very high. &quot;1 billion in 10 years&quot; is only used to test whether investors have the patience and sincerity to accompany the product&#39;s growth. It does not mean that someone must spend 1 billion. If the other party does not have a basic understanding of how much time it will take, how much money it will cost, and the possible return on investment, and they come and say that they are familiar with people from a certain local government and have connections in a certain park, they will talk about it with boastful words, or they will start talking about equity without saying anything. , we need to do due diligence, these are not the partners we would choose. We prefer to cooperate with people who have feelings and ideals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;No matter whether it is intrusive or non-intrusive, I am not optimistic about it&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Research on brain-computer interfaces has been very hot in recent years. What are the pros and cons of invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Non-invasive brain-computer interface is relatively safe because it is non-invasive. It mainly collects nerve discharge signals that converge on the surface of the scalp. Since this signal collection must pass through the skull and layers of tissue cells, and there are many interference signals in the scalp, the collected EEG signals are not very stable. The action EEG signal is okay, but over time, or when it recognizes finer movements, it won&#39;t work. Invasive brain-computer interfaces implant electrodes into the brain by opening the skull. If you want to collect a certain signal, you need to implant electrodes into the corresponding brain area. Usually, within half a year, the signals collected through the invasive brain-computer interface are more accurate, and the effect of human-computer interaction is also better, such as controlling the robotic arm to grab objects, and the degree of completion is also relatively high. But it’s hard to tell after half a year, because the electrodes are harmful to the brain, may lead to rejection and suppuration, scar tissue can easily accumulate around the electrodes, and the circuits will also generate a certain amount of heat, which can easily cause inflammation, which is harmful to the human body. The damage is also relatively large. Therefore, its sustainability is very poor, and the EEG signals collected later will become weaker, or even no signals can be collected. This is also a fatal shortcoming of invasive brain-computer interfaces. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In September 2023, Neuralink’s invasive brain The machine interface has begun recruiting human clinical trial subjects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The intrusive approach will cause great harm, but there are still many companies to deal with. What is a person? Are they silicon-based organisms or carbon-based organisms? What are these electrode materials? People and these materials are fundamentally incompatible. I did an invasive brain-computer interface on mice, and all the mice died. The monkeys in Musk&#39;s previous experiments also died. This direction is problematic in terms of long-term safety. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why are you doing this &quot;world&#39;s first African &quot;Human primate (monkey) interventional brain-computer interface trial&quot;? How were the animal types selected and what was the testing process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;The trial&lt;span>; will be carried out starting in June 2022. It was originally to verify the feasibility of the interventional brain-computer interface. Although there have been some relevant reports internationally, whether they are true or false cannot be known until verification. In terms of details, such as verifying whether the sensor works and whether it can last for more than half a year in the animal&#39;s brain. For vascular interventional brain-computer interfaces, the blood vessels of animals that are too small, such as mice, are too thin for electrode wires to enter. Although the blood vessels of sheep are thinner than humans, they are relatively thick, and the price is also cheap. Basic movements can be distinguished. Come out; after the experiment is successful, we will test the monkey again, and let the monkey&#39;s active intention control the mechanical arm to grab food. Because monkeys are a species similar to humans, there will be no problem with it. Then we will feel more at ease when we do human experiments. . The overall process is rather tortuous. Finding partners and venues such as hospitals and laboratories is not a problem, because everyone knows that this is a very new research, and it will be easy to publish papers and get projects later, and it also has certain market prospects. The difficulty is that the early stage of this experiment was during the epidemic. Many engineers and students were often blocked and needed to find various ways to coordinate personnel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In January this year, the American Synchron company announced its The &quot;vascular interventional&quot; brain-computer interface clinical trial successfully allowed four paralyzed subjects to control external devices and complete operations such as texting and emailing, personal finance, and online shopping. How do you understand some media describing your research as &quot;creating the third new paradigm of brain-computer interface&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is recommended not to interpret it out of context. This &quot;pioneering&quot; and &quot;world&#39;s first&quot; should be viewed together. When I conduct experiments on sheep, I actually mean to create the third new paradigm of brain-computer interface in China, because no one in China has done relevant research; the world&#39;s first case means that I am the first person in the world to conduct experiments on monkey species. People who do this type of experiment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the success of this experiment, we will bring you What are the impacts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a mental point of view, it has no impact at all. I think it is very dull. According to our plan, this trial will soon enter the clinical stage, that is, it will be tested on humans, but it is still in the ethical review stage of the hospital. But I do get some emails from volunteers. What impressed me deeply was that there was a woman who wanted to save her husband who was lying in the ICU and hoped that her husband could participate in the clinical trial of brain-computer interface; there was also a grandson who wanted to save his grandmother, and the child wanted to be a volunteer; there was also a blind person Ask me to regain my sight... These letters are very touching, but our experimental ethics have not yet passed and we cannot recruit any subjects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some scholars believe that &quot;the development of brain-computer interface We are currently in a bottleneck period, and there is an urgent need for new principles and new technologies to drive research in related fields into the next period of rapid development.&quot; What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The current research on brain-computer interface technology is indeed in a bottleneck period. There are many problems about brain-computer interface. Global problems are not unique to China. Whether it is a non-invasive or invasive track, there are too many players. If they could achieve results, they would have been done long ago. There are too many smart people and many wealthy capital parties. At present, everyone is in a state of relative stagnation. To some extent, it shows that there is a problem with this road, and I suggest you consider changing the track. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Change track? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether it is invasive or non-invasive, I am not optimistic about it, because I have done it, and there are many domestic companies or institutions. Did. In China, the current focus of the industry is still non-invasive. Everyone is crowded onto this track and there is a traffic jam. But I don’t follow any industry. I am currently focusing on vascular interventional brain-computer interface technology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I hope more people can do research in a down-to-earth manner&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people are currently focusing on the industrialization of brain-computer interfaces in rehabilitation medicine. Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is a huge demand for patients in this field and the number of patients is also large. With some auxiliary equipment, partial or complete disablement of limbs can be achieved. Sports, so the market potential is relatively large. In addition, the technical process is not difficult, and some low-threshold products are relatively easy to make. As long as companies can raise funds and obtain corresponding certifications and licenses, they can quickly realize cash. If product prices drop further in the future, for example, a product worth 100,000 yuan becomes 20,000 yuan, then the demand will be even higher. There are two main chains in rehabilitation medicine, one is the innovation chain, and the other is the industrial chain. The industrial chain is to make high-end technologies low-end and turn them into products that are sinking. After sinking, they can be universally applicable to more people. After they are universally applicable to more people, there will be more data in scientific research, and there will be more After the data is collected, it is fed back to the innovation chain to form better technology and better products. What I am currently building is such a double-chain circulation platform. Therefore, we did not rush to make specific products, but calmed down and started working on the electrodes. After the electrode automation is completed, it can serve many products. My entrepreneurship was a relatively stupid situation, equivalent to begging for food with a golden rice bowl. The position I give myself is not to do specific, low-end, repetitive things, but to make the company a platform and a core system for brain-computer interface applications in rehabilitation medicine. This platform will also be open in the future. , allowing more people, companies, and institutions to do things together on this platform. As long as they don&#39;t fool me and want to do things down-to-earth, they are all welcome. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The current overall ecology of China&#39;s brain-computer interface industrialization What is it like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the concept of brain-computer interface is overheated at this stage, and some irresponsible media use gimmicks to gain attention. Change the concept. For example, the flashing pictures are actually brain electrical signals induced by vision, which is a conditioned response. However, in media reports, it is described as controlled by &quot;thoughts&quot;. It seems very fantasy, but it is actually very simple. As far as brain-computer interface companies are concerned, there are actually not many people who can really endure loneliness and do low-level R&amp;D, because low-level R&amp;D is too expensive and there is no cash return in the short term. I sincerely hope that more people in the industry are willing to do basic research in a down-to-earth manner. Today’s investors don’t blindly follow investments because they don’t have much money. Maybe because there are so many people speculating on concepts, there are not many people who really have the patience to accompany the growth of innovative companies. I am not willing to accept investment from such investors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, the domestic brain-computer interface corresponds to In product development, what are the urgent problems that need to be solved? What type of talent is most in short supply? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the ideal brain-computer interface product in the future should be realized through vascular intervention. In order to achieve this goal, it is urgently needed Solve the problem of electrode stability. After the stability is guaranteed, we can then find ways to realize automated production to reduce the cost of the product. Judging from the professional fields involved in talents, more cross-field and compound talents are needed. For example, there is overlap in at least two or more fields in materials, processing, machinery, circuits, medicine and other fields. The most important thing is that these people can calm down and do things in a down-to-earth manner. They will not go to this company where the salary is high today, or to make money in that field tomorrow. People without feelings cannot do good things. Under this premise, you must have good understanding and the ability to think independently and explore. Both are important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to brain-computer interface, you have other research Simultaneously? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We are currently also developing intelligent aircraft that can take off vertically and artificial hibernation of rats. In the future, we hope that artificial hibernation experiments can be combined with interventional brain-computer interfaces to use special stimulation signals through electrodes in blood vessels to affect the entire brain, or to modify the brain in this way to make people hibernate. This technology can be used in the future It is used in some medical treatment fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[风波过后，脱口秀行业复苏在望？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant -east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text -align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data-style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 18px;&quot;>;Open mic performance Sharp decline&amp;nbsp;Actors are looking for other opportunities&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; In May of this year, the talk show industry went through a series of rectifications. Among all cities, Shanghai has been most affected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Informed sources revealed to reporters that since the inventory operation in May , the cultural tourism department of Huangpu District, where most of Shanghai&#39;s talk show clubs are located, has strengthened supervision of performance content, and has become more rigorous in spot checks of performance videos every week. Actors must perform performances strictly in accordance with the approved content. If there is any discrepancy between the performance video and the submitted content, the performance organization will be fined 50,000-100,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This has led to two changes in Shanghai talk show performances. First, there are fewer individual performances or flagship shows for actors, because such performances require high content integrity and it is difficult for actors to delete passages; second, most clubs no longer hold &quot;open mic&quot; performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Open Mic&quot; is designed for new actors to practice as well as experienced actors A talk show where actors try out new jokes. Due to the unstable quality of the performance content, the open mic tickets in most clubs are relatively low, such as 19 yuan, 39 yuan, etc. Actors are not paid for speaking on the open mic. The main purpose is to polish the content and practice skills. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to the reporter’s understanding, the registration form for most open microphones is Actors submit their manuscripts in advance to the agency for approval, and then sign up one to two days before the performance based on their actual situation. Due to factors such as actors&#39; personal creative habits and time, the content and lineup of open mic performances are somewhat uncontrollable. It is common for actors to temporarily revise and adjust new jokes before going on stage or to be unable to go on stage due to unexpected circumstances and need to be replaced by other actors. Therefore, under the current cautious environment, most talk show clubs in Shanghai no longer hold such forms of talk show performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shanghai open mic performances dropped sharply, resulting in no new actors on stage Chances are, veteran actors are unable to update their creative content. Some full-time actors will choose to go to open mics in other cities to try out new jokes, and Hangzhou has become their first choice. &quot;Xie Haihan&quot;, the manager of Ersansan Talk Show Club, told reporters that four or five contracted actors in his club have chosen to develop in Hangzhou. Currently, there are at least 10 talk show clubs in Hangzhou. But this does not mean that actors can make money in Hangzhou, but that they are more &quot;famous&quot; in Hangzhou. &quot;Everyone is willing to go to Hangzhou, mostly because of the open mic. It is difficult to earn performance fees because the market is not that big now, which leads to oversupply.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259815&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space : normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;233 Talk Show Club host &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data -style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot; , Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;From increment to stock&amp;nbsp;Downside and up of the market&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans -serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;During interviews with reporters, many talk show practitioners mentioned Yes, in fact, the talk show market had been quietly declining even before the public controversy in May this year. The manager of a Shanghai talk show club told reporters that the current box office level of his club has returned to the state of 2017 and 2018. The number of weekly performances has been reduced to about 1/3 (when the performances were at its peak), and the attendance rate is almost the same. Cut in half. And this situation seems not only due to the industry earthquake half a year ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;233 manager &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot; told reporters , in the past two years, the club&#39;s box office has not shown an upward trend, so it began to expand its business to second- and third-tier cities such as Nanjing and Fuzhou. &quot;The size of the entire Shanghai (market) has actually reached its limit. If we want to increase our performance, we must either expand the city or increase the unit price. But now everyone&#39;s ticket prices are falling overall, so it is not particularly easy to raise (tickets). price), you can only expand the city.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He mentioned , the current number of performances in the club has not changed much, but the attendance rate has dropped significantly. &quot;An attendance rate of 60 to 70 percent is considered relatively high. Our theater used to be able to accommodate about 300 people, but now it is basically about 100 people, and there are 60 or 70 people. It is better on weekends. There may be 200 people.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; compared to Next, the box office situation of 233 Club in Fuzhou is relatively stable: &quot;Because the competition is not that big, there are only two (clubs) in the local area.&quot; Che Hongjun, the manager of Gaoxiao Comedy, told reporters, &quot;For some second and third tier For cities, they don’t have as many forms of entertainment as Shanghai and Beijing, and talk shows are relatively new there.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline : 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to the vigorous observation of talk show actors, the golden period of the talk show performance market began in 2019: &quot;After the talk show variety show was broadcast, Talk shows took off directly offline. &quot;In 2020, during the COVID-19 prevention and control period, all performance industries were affected, and relatively small talk shows &quot;took advantage of the opportunity&quot; to seize the market share of other types of performances. In addition, talk shows and variety shows ’s phenomenal popularity has boosted the rapid growth of offline performance traffic.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/27/6VOahMXiiui9rwAiMcfXtnAuyHgcSUwGKG2d9NMx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;797&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27 /6VOahMXiiui9rwAiMcfXtnAuyHgcSUwGKG2d9NMx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259814&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant -numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The talk show actor is vigorous.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font- variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; &quot;>;&lt;span>;In 2022, with the saturation of the market and the consumption of resources, the decline of talk show performances has begun to show, and the industry has begun to usher in a bottleneck period. Dali wrote on Xiaohongshu: “Every year when online programs are broadcast, there will be a significant increase in the box office of offline performances, but this phenomenon will no longer exist in 2022. When online programs are broadcast, the number of tickets sold for performances It has not improved. It’s not that online programs don’t contribute to the performance box office. In fact, they do. It’s just that at this time, the natural flow of box office (talk show performances) is declining, and the boost space of online programs can no longer slow down its decline. Therefore, the two The forces are hedged.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Gao Xiao Comedy Host Renche In an interview with reporters, Hong Jun said that the current talk show market has almost no growth, and everyone is &quot;rolling up the stock.&quot; Some clubs may start a &quot;price war&quot;, &quot;some brands have begun to explore prices of 50, or even lower.&quot; But on the other hand, he still believes that &quot;the industry is moving upward&quot; because &quot;everyone is also focusing on quality, especially now that special performances are more popular, where one person talks for an hour or a 45-minute main show. The quality of the performance is very high. When the tide goes out, everyone starts to fight hard.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Talk show actor Dali also wrote on his Little Red Book: &quot;In the future, actors can no longer rely on 15 minutes of business performance jokes for a lifetime. Many actors are now holding special shows. In a way, that&#39;s a good thing.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; In a period of rapid growth in the industry, there have been a large number of clubs and performance companies who only want to make quick money and reap dividends but do not pay attention to content. A few actors can put together a platter to sell tickets; and a large number of audiences come to watch talk shows. I came to &quot;chasing stars&quot; after watching online programs, but I don&#39;t know much about comedy itself. But in today&#39;s cold environment, with the withdrawal of this group of people, the industry has slowly entered a settling period after undergoing a reshuffle. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Many club managers said in interviews with reporters , due to the overall poor box office situation, they prefer to leave performance opportunities to actors with better content and stronger ticket-taking capabilities. &quot;In the past, if an actor&#39;s jokes reached 30 or 40 points, he would have commercial opportunities. Now if his jokes are lower than 60 or 70 points, your performance will be very few, and many people will no longer be able to get performances. In the past two years, everyone If you are all in the limelight, there will be no survival of the fittest. It is indeed difficult now, but I think this is the way stand-up (comedy) should go.&quot; &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot;, the manager of Ersansan said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data -style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot; , Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;Where is the future? Necessary online traffic and healthy industry ecology&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font -variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible ;&quot;>;&lt;span>; &quot;I didn&#39;t take off my sex this year, but I once dreamed that I did it, and the result was not very good.&quot; On November 3, Zhou Qimo, who once won the championship of a certain talk show and variety show, posted this on Weibo , he imagined an experience in which he participated in the show&#39;s breakout competition and was eliminated, and finally concluded: &quot;The roots of talk shows are still offline.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;And when online programs are absent and completely return to offline Are talk shows getting better? In interviews with reporters, almost every practitioner affirmed a point of view: boosting the traffic of online programs is still necessary for the talk show industry, although there are very big differences in the creation of online programs and offline performances. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Che Hongjun mentioned in an interview, &quot;Competition The format of the stand-up comedy will be very internal for the actors&#39; creation. Five minutes is too small, and they need to quickly empathize with the audience. The topic will be very limited, and special performances are the ultimate form of stand-up comedy.&quot; But he still believes that the industry needs online Traffic will help break the circle, because with the increasing variety of offline performances and entertainment forms, the art of talk show is facing more fierce competition. &quot;Our competitors are not talk show peers, our competitors are all forms of mass entertainment: watching movies, KTV, short videos... everything is your competitor.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data -style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple- system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px ; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;It still needs the promotion of online traffic.&quot; The talk show actor vigorously told reporters, &quot;Many friends around me I also agree with this view. Online programs can prevent the offline market from falling too fast. If there is no traffic boost, the offline talk show performance market will be relatively bleak by the end of 2024.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font -family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In fact, many clubs and actors are trying to create online IP. The &quot;Gaoxia Comedy&quot; club, initiated and derived from the &quot;Dankou Comedy Club&quot; of Fudan University, produced the variety show &quot;Dankou Comedy Competition&quot;, which was broadcast on Station B in October; many clubs insist on doing podcasts to promote their products And maintain fan stickiness, such as Owl Comedy&#39;s &quot;No Joking&quot;, Comedy United&#39;s &quot;Xi Tan Lu&quot;, and Ersan San&#39;s &quot;A Few Words&quot;; more actors are also trying to use self-media to create personal IP and help Offline ticket sales. However, most people have not been able to achieve stable business conversion through online channels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/No32mZOtGmh9sap3X4dsPbSOUUN9XgrmNnopc5dP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1066&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/No32mZOtGmh9sap3X4dsPbSOUUN9XgrmNnopc5dP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259817&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; &quot;High Laughter Comedy&quot; Club Homemade Variety show &quot;Dankou Comedy Competition&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/QcmAdcyT2b6LEHhInNxJclB8fhfjsVtwnbWQ1ExT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/QcmAdcyT2b6LEHhInNxJclB8fhfjsVtwnbWQ1ExT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259813&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Comedy United Box Country&quot; actors Offline performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;From the perspective of industry ecology, domestic talk shows The industry has risen and developed with the popularity of related variety shows such as &quot;Post-80s Talk Show Tonight&quot;, &quot;Tucao Conference&quot;, &quot;Talk Show Conference&quot; and so on. And when an industry&#39;s system and practitioners&#39; upward path are deeply bound to a company or a program, there are bound to be great risks - and facts have proven this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aQFCDTjRkI4imCOJvI6cAxM5hXJEmyQrutwCuUeb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aQFCDTjRkI4imCOJvI6cAxM5hXJEmyQrutwCuUeb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259816&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Tonight&#39;s Post-80s Talk Show&quot; 》. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;A talk show actor said in an interview with reporters, Rather than the emergence of the next hit show, what she hopes to see is a healthy ecosystem for the industry: &quot;Different companies can let a hundred flowers bloom, with mutual competition and mutual cooperation. Each company has something to gain.&quot; Whether it’s actors or programs (online IP), it’s just like other industries.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武汉市卫健委：暂停武汉普仁医院出生医学证明签发资格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261446]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 11:13:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 28, the Wuhan Municipal Health Commission of Hubei Province issued a notice regarding the Wuhan Puren Hospital reported by netizens. Regarding issues such as surrogacy and false paternity tests issued by the Wuhan Ruiboxiang Forensic Laboratory, the Wuhan Municipal Health Commission, together with the public security, judicial and other departments, stationed at the hospitals and identification institutions involved to conduct investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Wuhan Puren Hospital’s qualification to issue birth medical certificates has been suspended, and a special inspection will be conducted on the hospital’s fertility services and birth medical certificate processing. The Wuhan Ruiboxiang Forensic Appraisal Institute has been instructed to stop its forensic appraisal business and accept investigation and handling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the Wuhan Municipal Health Commission will seriously pursue accountability in accordance with laws and regulations based on the investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在巴黎十年被抢近50次：移民导致社会治安恶化，法国社会治理失败]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261430]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a female Internet celebrity said: After living in Paris for ten years, she was stolen, robbed, and blackmailed 47.5 Second-rate. Why use decimals? Because three of them were stolen and she took them back by herself, each time was only counted as half, which means it was actually 49 times. It&#39;s jaw-dropping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My relatives and friends in China studied and worked in Paris in the mid-1990s. After retiring, I visited Europe again and felt that France had changed a lot in the past 30 years: the urban appearance and infrastructure of Paris had not changed much, and there were still antique and cultural relics buildings that were hundreds of years old. However, the composition of residents has undergone great changes, and the social atmosphere and cultural customs are completely different from those 30 years ago. The personal experiences of relatives, friends and female internet celebrities are quite similar: with the increase in immigration, France&#39;s security has significantly deteriorated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for the high immigration crime rate: France has many immigrants from Africa. Due to different religious beliefs, cultural traditions, and customs, these immigrants and their descendants have educational disadvantages that affect their social status and economic status. The status is at a lower level. The desire for a wealthy material life like Europe, but difficulty in supporting it financially, will of course lead to an increase in illegal and criminal behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The large influx of immigrants and illegal immigrants into France is a reverse sequelae of &quot;colonialism&quot;. It can be said that France is being reverse colonized. From the 17th to the early 20th century, France occupied a large number of colonies in Africa and became the world&#39;s second largest colonial empire after Britain. The two world wars caused huge losses in France&#39;s population. In order to make up for the shortage of soldiers, France recruited hundreds of thousands of local young people from colonial French Africa to join the French army and fight against Germany. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, a large number of colonial soldiers stayed in France and became early immigrants. The French movie &quot;Indigènes&quot; has a vivid description. Many black soldiers asked: We fought for France, why can&#39;t we stay here? The French government and people were speechless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through these early immigrants, their relatives and friends in Africa learned about the development and wealth of France, and a large number of subsequent immigrants and illegal immigrants continued to pour in. Official data: There are currently more than 8 million black people in France. Taking into account illegal immigrants, the actual number may reach 10 million, accounting for 15% of France&#39;s total population of 66 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The changes in the demographic structure have greatly changed France’s traditional religious beliefs, cultural concepts, and living customs, intensified ideological conflicts, and brought about increased crime rates, social unrest, and opposition between ethnic groups and classes. Street demonstrations, vandalism, looting and burning have become commonplace for more than ten years and can be called a wonderful sight in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The turbulent social environment not only affects the economic development of France, but also affects the personal and property safety of everyone living in Paris. In this chaotic environment, it is common to lose a wallet or mobile phone, and with such a high crime rate, it is impossible for the police to investigate and ordinary residents to guard against it. In desperation, they adopted the method of raising the threshold for filing a case: making serious crimes such as robbery a misdemeanor, treating misdemeanors as illegal, and simply ignoring the violations as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States has also learned this trick. In 2014, California passed a bill making theft of less than $1,000 a misdemeanor, which can be compensated through community service. Use this method to avoid conflicts between police and robbers and reduce conflicts between police and black people. This set of legal concepts and judicial practices gave birth to the &quot;zero-yuan purchase&quot; movement in Europe and the United States: large groups of people (mainly immigrants) rushed into stores, took things and ran away. Store owners were unable to stop them and the police were unwilling to intervene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to security issues, there is also a seemingly unrelated change in life details: French bread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When relatives and friends stayed in France in their early years, they were deeply impressed by French dining. I particularly appreciate French bread: in France, bread is not only a diet, but also a culture. In order to make fragrant and delicious bread, French bakers are very particular about dough mixing, ingredients, fermentation and baking. They often start work early in the morning to ensure that fragrant and hot French bread comes out of the oven as the sun rises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he visited Paris again after the COVID-19 epidemic, he was surprised to find that not only had France changed in terms of society and security, but even French bread was different from what it was 30 years ago. It was hard, tired, tasted bad, and had serious crumbs... Later I learned that many ordinary bakers are new immigrants who lack French culture and cooking traditions. For them, bread is no longer a national glory, cultural heritage, It has time-honored customs and exquisite taste in life, but it is just a job, without emotions, and it will not invest too much energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This relative and friend who likes to travel said: Nowadays, it is in former French colonies such as Laos and Vietnam in Southeast Asia, and French bread is made slightly more authentic than in Paris. There are also stricter labor disciplines, certain requirements for employees, and traditional French bread baking techniques are followed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the French have 150 days off per year (116.5 days per year in most states in the United States), and work an average of 1,490 hours per year (1,791 hours in the United States). Probably because there are too many new immigrants, grassroots jobs are done by immigrants as much as possible. The French natives with higher incomes are living more and more easily and are less and less willing to work. Bakers who once had a considerable social status I am too lazy to pursue my career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is like: instead of carrying out new technological and productivity innovations and trying to reverse the decline, a company that is already in decline cuts working hours, increases wages, weakens performance appraisals, and abandons management... What will be the consequences? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;France&#39;s &quot;traditional loss and cultural ebb&quot; problem is neither limited to social security nor catering. The culture and art that the French were once so proud of, and indeed once reached the world&#39;s pinnacle level, are also facing the same crisis. The former French actor Depardieu entangled a group of French entertainers, scolded Hollywood for engaging in cultural aggression, and even burned the American flag to vent his anger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hollywood did not carry out &quot;cultural aggression&quot; against France through force or unequal treaties, but people (including the French) no longer wanted to consume French movies, dramas, and games. The French should really think about themselves: they have problems in every aspect, including their ideas, ideologies, cultural concepts, artistic creations, international politics, economic and trade relations, social governance, and even baking bread. What is going on? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deterioration of social security caused by immigration reflects the French government’s failure in social governance. The cultural shock and ideological collision brought about by the immigration issue reflect deeper hidden dangers. The internal cause of France&#39;s social governance failure and cultural ebb is that the spiritual power of contemporary French people has dissipated, traditional values ​​have been abandoned, and national culture has been lost. The French live a lazy, leisurely and happy life, as comfortable as riding a slide, which confirms the old saying &quot;to do good is to climb, to do evil is to fall&quot;. This state of life is worth pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, I also hope that everyone will think about what Elon Musk, who is still working hard in middle age, said: I don’t want to use the power of human nature to make money. Just like the interpretation of gravity in &quot;Jupiter Ascending&quot;: Up is hard, Down is easy. Social and personal success require a high-spirited spiritual core. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一座湖南县城“利剑出鞘”：八百公职人员进退公租房]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261401]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the morning of November 14, 2023, a tenant in Runzhong Community moved. Southern Weekend Photo by reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the morning of November 14, 2023, a tenant in Runzhong Community, Lianyuan, Hunan, moved. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;National supervision makes public rental housing more &#39;sunshine&#39;.&quot; A banner hangs on the main entrance of Runzhong Community, November 2023 Since then, there has been a sudden increase in the number of residents moving out of the community, and pickup trucks carrying furniture have been coming and going. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moving is a common thing, but recently it has become a hot topic in Lianyuan, a county-level city in Loudi, Hunan. This stems from a centralized rectification campaign to crack down on illegal occupation of public rental housing by public officials. In addition to Runzhong Community, the phenomenon of large-scale relocation has also appeared in Runzeyuan Community, Huimin Community, and Runyuan Community. According to locals, these four communities are public rental housing communities in Lianyuan City, and those who have moved are basically Lianyuan’s public officials and their relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A statistical table obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that 878 households of public employees are living in the above four public rental housing communities, plus 4 households living in public housing units. There are a total of 882 households of public servants, including 28 households with public servants at the rank of full-time clerk and above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many Lianyuan public officials said that those on this list will be vacated before the end of November. &quot;This is also the first time in decades that such a large area of ​​residents has been evicted.&quot; A staff member of the Lianyuan City Housing Security Service Center (hereinafter referred to as the Housing Security Center) told Southern Weekend reporters that this action is in line with the Hunan Provincial Inspection Team Request for rectification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Don&#39;t replace the current rules and regulations with past practices, and you must not compete with the people for benefits.&quot; On October 20, the Secretary of the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee held a meeting to schedule Public rental housing operation management and service work. &quot;Lianyuan Online&quot; public account announced that the meeting emphasized that public rental housing is affordable housing, and all relevant departments must unify their thinking; a leading group and a special work class must be established to conduct in-depth research, analysis, and identification of existing problems, loopholes, and weaknesses. , establish a list of ledgers by category, and increase rectification efforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, the main entrance of Runzhong Community. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/27/edfd4a5f6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 27/edfd4a5f6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, the main entrance of Runzhong Community. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“With such a large-scale eviction, how can the housing insurance center have the ability?”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In mid-November, Southern Over the weekend, reporters visited Runzhong Community and Runzeyuan Community, where many public officials live. Red banners were hung on many fences and walls to crack down on illegal use and subletting of public rental housing. In the two communities, there are announcements from the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center on the front and back of each building: &quot;The municipal party committee and the city government are cleaning up and rectifying the illegal use of public rental housing. Relevant units, organizations and individuals are welcome to report illegal rentals to our center. Once the situation of public rental housing (including the actual occupancy situation by lending, subletting, reselling and other methods) is verified, the unit, organization and individual who reported it will be rewarded 500 yuan/time.&quot; The announcement date is October 31. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There have been fewer people moving in the past two days. Many people have moved away a few days ago.&quot; On the afternoon of November 13, a resident of Runzhong Community told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;Public rental housing, the full name of public rental housing, refers to limited construction standards and rent levels. Affordable housing for rent for urban lower-middle-income families with housing difficulties, newly-employed workers without housing, and migrant workers with stable employment in cities who meet the prescribed conditions. According to the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Public Rental Housing&quot; issued by the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development in 2012, the lease period of public rental housing generally does not exceed 5 years. After the expiration of the period, if the conditions for renewal of the lease are not met, the rental period must be vacated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The origin of the concentrated evacuation of Lianyuan City, according to many public officials, was the arrival of the 11th Inspection Team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee to work in Lianyuan City 2 During the month (September 7, 2023 - November 7, 2023), some people reported that public officials illegally occupied public rental housing and sublet and resold it, resulting in poor households who really needed a house without a house to live in. &lt;p>; The Notice also mentioned that the 11th Inspection Team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee issued a handover letter to Lianyuan City on October 17, 2023, reporting that there was a problem in public rental housing in Lianyuan City that public officials competed with the people for profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This notice requires each unit to carefully conduct an investigation into the public rental housing situation of the unit&#39;s staff&amp;nbsp;(including family members), and on October 23, 2023 Submit the &quot;Statistical Form of Public Rental Housing Rented by Public Employees&quot; to the Municipal Housing Insurance Center before 17:00. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Many people brought this matter to the inspection team to report it. The inspection team felt that this was a common problem. According to an investigation, eight to nine hundred households had public officials (residing in public houses). Rent a house).&quot; Lin Min (pseudonym), a staff member of the housing insurance center, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The phenomenon of public officials illegally occupying public rental housing is not an isolated case. Public information shows that in May 2021, an inspection by the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Committee of Qingchuan County, Guangyuan City, Sichuan Province found that local public officials used 412 public housing units in violation of regulations, including 275 public rental housing units in violation of regulations, involving 145 public officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Further forward, in 2019, the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Committee of Anhua County, Yiyang City, Hunan Province also discovered such a phenomenon. 4 public employees sub-leased public rental housing, 5 public employees sub-leased public rental housing, and 28 public officials did not meet the conditions for renting and did not withdraw in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to public information from the Lianyuan City Media Center, on the evening of October 25, 2023, members of the 11th Inspection Team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee met at the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee Standing Committee It was once again emphasized at the meeting that we must confront the issue of public rental housing, which is a matter of strong public response and concern, and push forward the rectification of the problem steadily and solidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, before the arrival of the inspection team, Lianyuan City also tried to rectify this problem. According to a report by Hunan Daily in early 2023, the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center carried out a special clean-up and rectification operation for illegal use of public rental housing by public officials from January 9 to 18. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In January, more than ten households with serious non-compliance of public officials were reported, including those with cars and houses under their names. Then again Some people were replaced, and a few households were finally cleared.&quot; Lin Min said that according to Lianyuan City&#39;s practice, such special clean-ups are organized every two or three years, but the intensity of the clean-ups is relatively small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;How can our housing insurance center have the ability to move out with such great efforts now? If the inspection team hadn&#39;t come and the municipal Party committee secretary personally arranged the move, who would have moved? &quot;According to Lin Min, the rectification of public rental housing involves many cadres, and it is difficult for the municipal housing insurance center to implement it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a public employee moved out of Runzhong Community. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/27/8c9a7b4242.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/27/8c9a7b4242.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a Public employees moved out of Runzhong Community. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Too many vacancies, is it a waste? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Are public employees eligible to live in public rental housing? Nie Chen, an associate professor at the School of Public Administration at Beihang University who has long studied housing security, believes that it is normal for some qualified public officials with lower incomes and housing difficulties to live in public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;After the abolition of the welfare housing allocation system in 1998, most provinces and cities across the country no longer &lt;span>;have units built&lt;/span>; to provide housing to employees. It is true that some civil servants have low wages, heavy family burdens, and cannot afford a house, so they meet the conditions for applying for public rental housing.&quot; said Wang Cailiang, director of the China Construction Management and Real Estate Law Research Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But regarding the situation in Lianyuan, a person familiar with the situation told Southern Weekend reporters that most of the public employees who moved into public rental housing were moved in through lottery, and a small number of them moved in through &quot; &quot;Apply the note&quot; to get the accommodation. &quot;Some people buy houses in Loudi, but they don&#39;t have houses in Lianyuan; some people have houses in Lianyuan, but they want this house; and some are helping friends or relatives to approve notes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The hardest-hit area is Runzhong Community, where most public officials are located. It is close to the city center and has a more convenient location.&quot; The person familiar with the matter said. Southern Weekend reporters compared the public rental list of Runzhong Community’s three computer lottery results with the public rental housing statistics table for public rental housing rented by public officials in Lianyuan City. They found that a total of 1,826 households were occupied in Runzhong Community’s three lottery draws. There were 669 public servants in the community, accounting for 10% of the community’s residents. The total number is about 37%; 522 of them are on the lottery results announcement list, and the remaining 147 households are not on the lottery list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter also obtained a copy of Lianyuan City&#39;s &quot;Statistical Table of Housing Check-out of Public Rental Housing for Leading Cadres of Zhengke and above&quot;, which shows that many units have 28 cadres at the department level have checked out at the end of October 2023, and the furniture is still being cleaned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Why are there such a large number of public officials living in Runzhong Community? The above-mentioned insider revealed that after the completion of Runzhong Community, during the public lottery in 2017 and 2018, due to some special reasons, &quot;as long as you participate in the lottery, you can get a house.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Runzhong Community built more than 2,300 houses at one time, but no one lives in them, but it requires an occupancy rate of 90%. If the housing insurance center cannot complete it, it will Being criticized. Because you have to build so many houses, it must mean that there is such a huge demand.&quot; The person familiar with the matter said that when allocating rents, the housing security department reported the low occupancy rate to the Lianyuan Municipal Government, and then the Lianyuan Municipal Government A meeting was held to discuss relaxing the conditions, and public officials who do not have housing in Lianyuan can apply for the lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 24, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the relevant person in charge of the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center to verify this statement. The other party said that it was &quot;not needed&quot;. declined to be interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another staff member of the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center told Southern Weekend reporters that Runzhong Community is located in Jianzhong Village and Hujia Village, Lantian Street, and construction started at the end of 2012. Construction, including low-rent housing and public rental housing, was called the &quot;Under Construction Low-rent Housing and Chengdong Public Rental Housing Project&quot; at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Information from the official website of the Lianyuan Municipal Government in 2013 shows that the Jianzhong low-rent housing and Chengdong public rental housing projects are Lianyuan City’s “Twelfth Five-Year Plan” housing security One of the key affordable housing construction projects implemented within the plan. The project covers an area of ​​188 acres, with a total planned construction area of ​​140,000 square meters, a total investment of 180 million yuan, and a total of 2,076 housing units planned to be built. After completion, it will become the largest housing area, the most complete functions, and the most livable environment in Lianyuan City. A good residential community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A property bidding document for Runzhong Community in 2021 mentioned that the total construction area of ​​the housing in the community is 140,000 square meters, with a total of 30 buildings, including 2,218 residential units. 742 non-residential (service buildings). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The panorama of low-rent housing in Jianzhong (top) released by the &quot;Lianyuan Online&quot; public account, the panorama of Runzhong Community published in &quot;Lianyuan Yearbook (2019)&quot; (bottom) .Information picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1223&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;The panorama of low-rent housing in Jianzhong (top) released by the &quot;Lianyuan Online&quot; public account, and the panorama of Runzhong Community published in &quot;Lianyuan Yearbook (2019)&quot; (bottom). Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Low-rent housing refers to the government providing social housing to families who meet the low living security standards for urban residents and have housing difficulties in the form of rent subsidies or in-kind rent allocation. Social housing. Nie Chen told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;In a sense, low-rent housing is public rental housing. It caters to people with lower incomes, and the rent is lower than public rental housing. In 2014, low-rent housing and public rental housing were merged, and now they are basically Called public rental housing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nie Chen analyzed that from 2010 to 2015, the country promoted public rental housing and low-rent housing on a large scale. At that time, it set a goal: to solve 1540 problems by the end of 2012. To solve the housing problem of 10,000 low-income families with housing difficulties, the coverage of affordable housing should reach 20% in 2015. &quot;At that time, various places had goals to achieve and built a large number of public rental housing.&quot; However, during the actual investigation, Nie &lt;span>;Chen&lt;/span>; found that some areas, including Beijing, Shanghai, and Baotou, Inner Mongolia, had a shortage of public rental housing. Due to remoteness or other factors, fewer people apply for rentals, resulting in vacant public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There is a trend now that the conditions for public rental housing are gradually relaxing, and there is even a phenomenon of converting into affordable rental housing, expanding the scope of security.&quot; Nie &lt;span>;Chen&lt;/span>; said that the rent of affordable housing is generally not higher than 90% of the rent of market rental housing of the same quality in the same location. &quot;But it cannot be directly converted into commercial housing because the government has strict control over public rental housing.&quot; &quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that in October 2020, the Lianyuan City Discipline Inspection Committee and the Lianyuan City Supervisory Committee notified the Jianzhong Integrity Committee Collusive bidding issues in rental housing construction. In November 2012, Liang Mou, the former deputy director of the Anti-Corruption and Bribery Bureau of the Lianyuan City People&#39;s Procuratorate, and Zhang Mouxian (an active participant in a gangland organization headed by Tan Mouping) worked to obtain low-rent housing and urban housing in Jianzhong, Lianyuan City. For the construction project of the 14th bidding section of the Donggong Rental Community, four companies including Hunan Lianyuan Xiangzhong Engineering Company were contacted to collude in bidding, and finally won the project. The relevant judgment shows that Liang and Zhang Xian made illegal gains of more than 1.29 million yuan from the project. In August 2020, Liang was expelled from the party and dismissed from public office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to Runzhong Community, there are also many public officials in Huimin Community and Runzeyuan Community. A public official in Huimin Community said that Huimin Community has gradually relaxed conditions for public officials because there are too many vacant houses. Many public officials also said that the application conditions for public rental housing complexes in Lianyuan were previously loose, and migrant workers who did not have a house in Lianyuan could participate in the lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The salary of public employees is not high, and many of them meet the conditions (lottery).&quot; Lu Ke (pseudonym), a deputy section-level public employee who lives in public rental housing ) said that the permanent urban population of Lianyuan City is less than 300,000, and it is difficult for poor households who have paid social security and do not have a house to live in public rental housing. &quot;We should take care of the low-income population first. If there are still vacancies, the conditions must be relaxed, otherwise it will be a waste of public resources.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Cailiang believes that the lottery, The two check-in methods of approval note treat the Lianyuan case separately. &quot;Public rental housing is affordable housing developed from the past affordable housing. It mainly solves the problem of a large number of working-class people with low incomes who cannot afford market-oriented housing. If such behavior as granting notes still exists, it is an abuse of power. .” For those who meet the application conditions and move in through lottery, temporary withdrawal may be suspected of breach of contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In November 2023, banners cracking down on illegal use of public rental housing were posted in Runzeyuan Community in Lianyuan, Hunan. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023, In Lianyuan, Hunan, banners are posted in Runzeyuan Community to crack down on illegal use of public rental housing. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Patching” and “one size fits all”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 1, 2023, &quot;Lianyuan City Public Security Bureau&quot; New regulations were released, proposing more detailed requirements. Nie Chen told Southern Weekend reporters that regulations for the management of public rental housing are generally formulated by local governments based on local economic conditions. However, the state has unified regulations that tenants must meet two conditions: &quot;low income&quot; and &quot;poor housing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lianyuan&#39;s new rules and regulations show: Lianyuan City&#39;s urban subsistence allowance, low-income, and lower-middle-income families with housing difficulties, newly employed workers without housing and those in urban areas Migrant workers with stable employment who meet local public rental housing admission conditions should be included in the scope of public rental housing security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, lower-middle-income urban households with housing difficulties refer to households whose per capita annual disposable income is lower than the per capita disposable income of urban residents in the previous year and whose household savings are low. Households with housing difficulties of 180,000 yuan (including provident fund) and no real estate in cities at the county level and above; newly employed workers without housing refer to workers who have been working for less than 5 years and are employed locally and whose families have no local housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Min analyzed that the limit on per capita annual disposable income of a family and the limit on working less than 5 years are enough to exclude most public officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;More than 20 public employees who have served less than five years have not been given notice of retirement, and the rest are all the same.&quot; Lin Min recalled that the housing security center held an internal meeting According to the requirements of the government, all public employees who have worked for five years will be dismissed. &quot;It is communicated to the top and bottom that all of them should quit first, and those who meet other conditions for moving into public rental housing can then apply for the next round of lottery.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lu Ke also told Southern Weekend reporters that except for a few college graduates who had worked less than 5 years, all the public employees who lived in public rental housing in his unit were vacated. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A grassroots enterprise staff member who was asked to vacate a public rental house because he had worked for more than 5 years wrote in the mailbox on the official website of the Lianyuan Municipal Government: &quot; (I) originally had no relatives or real estate in Lianyuan. I am a low-income person who fully meets the conditions. I cannot compete with the people for benefits. I sincerely ask the leaders to consider people from other places as appropriate and not to apply one-size-fits-all. Grassroots workers are also people.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the new regulations were introduced, were public officials really not competing with the people for benefits by staying in public rental housing? Southern Weekend reporters randomly interviewed two households in Runzhong Community, both of which were non-public servant families. At that time, they applied for public rental housing through regular lottery channels. One of them said that his brother and mother also applied for public rental housing in this way, and had never been unable to apply for public rental housing before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Min believes that later people reported that there was no public rental housing to apply for, which was a new problem in the new stage. &quot;Some people did not need public rental housing at the time, but later their children got married and needed houses again, and some &lt;span>;had family changes.&quot; In addition, in recent years, Lianyuan has no longer New public rental housing. Due to national policy adjustments, in principle, no new public rental housing will be built after 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 8, 2023, the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center issued an announcement to accept applications for public rental housing waitlists from that day to November 20. Those who meet the new regulations can apply for public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a public employee moved out of Runzhong Community. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a Public employees moved out of Runzhong Community. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to multiple public officials, on Thursday, November 9, 2023, when the inspection team was about to leave Lianyuan, the urban management A public employee of the bureau who was about to retire organized several people to go to the office of the inspection team to express their demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The person who took the lead did some renovations (in the vacated public rental housing) to see if (the government) could compensate some money.&quot; One person Officials from the Urban Management Bureau said that dozens of people were sought, involving multiple units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A public official who stayed at Runzeyuan told Southern Weekend reporters that his family also followed him to report the situation. &quot;Originally, the first notice was given to move before December 10th, but after they went (to report the situation), they issued a notice the next day that they must move before November 30th.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A public official from the Lianyuan Municipal Development and Reform Commission recalled that on the morning of Friday (November 10), the unit organized a meeting and required them to sign a commitment letter and must move out of the public rental housing before November 30. Another public official who is engaged in teaching also said that the school held an emergency meeting that morning. &quot;The leader asked us to sign a commitment letter. If we don&#39;t move by the end of the month, we will fail the annual assessment and we will not get any performance pay.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Our unit has more intensive meetings, and they are held on Saturdays and Sundays.&quot; The aforementioned public official from the Urban Management Bureau said that there are 10 or 20 people from the Urban Management Bureau. Reflecting on the demands, &quot;Most of the houses in our unit have been renovated, and there are quite a lot of complaints.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As far as Lin Min knows, among the public employees who live in public rental housing, those who spend the most on decoration spend more than 200,000 yuan. Regarding whether compensation will be provided for decoration, Lin Min said that the public rental housing contract clearly stipulates that &quot;repair and throw away&quot; will not be compensated for decoration. &quot;Because it is not a rough house. The bathroom, kitchen, and lighting fixtures are all installed. Once it meets the delivery standards, you can basically move in. This is a national subsidy to poor households. Your decoration is somewhat contrary to the government&#39;s rental.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that the resale of public rental housing in Lianyuan City is relatively common. &quot;I heard that a house of more than 50 square meters can be sold for as high as 50,000 to 60,000 yuan.&quot; Lin Min said that the reason why many people renovate public rental housing and resell it may be due to a deep-rooted local concept. To. “We in Lianyuan have a thought that if the government gave me this house, it means that this house is mine. I never worried that I would not be able to live in this house. I didn’t expect that the inspection team came and asked us to move. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Following this, rents in some Lianyuan areas close to public rental housing have also increased. &quot;The rent for a two-bedroom house on Xingfu Road used to be less than 4,000 yuan a year, but now it has increased to 5,000 yuan.&quot; A public official who lives in Runzhong Community told Southern Weekend reporters that according to public rental housing The price is just over 2,000 yuan a year. Two other public officials who were dismissed also confirmed: &quot;Suddenly more than 800 households moved out, and the supply of (nearby rental housing) must be tight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;On November 14, a Southern Weekend reporter consulted a staff member of the housing insurance center as a &quot;tenant unwilling to check out.&quot; The other party said that if they think they meet the conditions for living in public rental housing, they can submit materials and request re-examination. The application deadline was 12 noon that day, and eighty or ninety households who were unwilling to check out had already submitted materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A public official who submitted materials said that he received a notice on November 18 and still had to vacate. As far as he knows, only one public official who is paralyzed and has family difficulties has passed the review and can continue to rent public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎是新冠的变异？张文宏等专家解读误区]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261440]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Currently, as winter begins in various places, respiratory diseases have entered a period of high incidence. How should we prevent and treat it? What are the misunderstandings about respiratory diseases? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Healthy China&quot; column of the main station invited Professor Zhang Wenhong of Huashan Hospital Affiliated to Fudan University, Liu Qingquan, President of Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine Affiliated to Capital Medical University, and Vice President of Beijing Chaoyang Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University. Three experts, including Tong Zhaohui, director of the Institute of Respiratory Diseases, explained in detail the common misunderstandings about respiratory diseases on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Myth 1: Respiratory viruses are complicated this winter, and superinfection is scary? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Wenhong said that many people are afraid of superinfection. In fact, sometimes multiple viruses or bacteria are detected because very sensitive detection methods are used, so don’t worry too much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui said that although many pathogens have been detected, it does not mean that every one is pathogenic. The doctor will comprehensively analyze which bacteria are the patient&#39;s pathogenic bacteria based on the patient&#39;s clinical condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Qingquan said that from the perspective of traditional Chinese medicine, superinfection is a combined disease or comorbidity. &quot;For example, after having a fever for 7 days, it was discovered that it was influenza. About 10 days later, the fever returned, and this time it was mycoplasma. This is actually not a superposition, but a situation of poor maintenance and subsequent illness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Myth 2 : Mycoplasma pneumonia is a mutation of the new coronavirus? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui said that humans discovered mycoplasma as a microorganism at the beginning of the 20th century, and it was not determined to be a pathogen until the end of the 20th century. The new coronavirus was only known to everyone at the end of 2019, and there is no difference between the two. It doesn&#39;t matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are children particularly susceptible to mycoplasma infection? Tong Zhaohui said that children&#39;s immune systems are not fully developed and their resistance is not as good as adults&#39;, so they are more susceptible to infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Myth 3: Once you have a cold or fever, you need to get an infusion quickly? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui said, &quot;Infusions will heal a cold and fever quickly.&quot; This is actually a misunderstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with influenza, colds and fevers have lower temperatures and milder symptoms, and are often upper respiratory tract symptoms. If you have a fever or cough after catching a cold, just take fever-reducing or cough-relieving medicine at home. Pay attention to getting more rest, drinking more water, and supplementing your nutrition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for influenza, some influenza may cause pneumonia or even severe pneumonia. At this time, you may need to be hospitalized, and the resident doctor will determine whether you need infusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Wenhong also said that infusion is generally limited to hospitalized critically ill patients, or some drugs cannot be taken orally and can only be administered through infusion. For the common cold, oral medications work better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Myth 4: Mycoplasma pneumonia can be cured at home? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui said that in most cases, whether it is a virus or mycoplasma, if it is limited to the upper respiratory tract, most of it can heal on its own, and a small number may develop pneumonia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Wenhong said that generally speaking, mycoplasma pneumonia can be improved by taking some symptomatic drugs at home, but it is necessary to pay attention to whether it develops into a serious condition. For example, if your child&#39;s condition improves after taking medicine, you can observe it at home; if your child still has a high fever after taking antipyretics and is sluggish and unwilling to eat, you should seek medical attention as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Myth 5: Increased exercise and sweating in winter can improve immunity? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Qingquan said that from the perspective of traditional Chinese medicine, excessive sweating will damage a person’s yang energy. During winter sports, your body will feel slightly warm and you may sweat a little. It&#39;s okay to work up a sweat, but it doesn&#39;t have to be every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Wenhong said that everyone is encouraged to maintain a certain level of exercise. &quot;Even if you are very busy today, it is good to walk 5,000 steps.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special reminder: Please pay attention to the weather conditions in winter and wear a mask as appropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[OpenAI忙宫斗，AI大模型和应用忙上新丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/27/5c1572c356.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 27/5c1572c356.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-to-late November 2023, OpenAI experienced a constant reversal of personnel turmoil, and Sam Altman was re-appointed as OpenAI CEO It&#39;s over for now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plot is complicated and confusing, and it really attracted enough attention. Can a star company and a star CEO really influence the development process of AI in the human world? You might as well take a look at the efforts of more companies in upgrading and applying large AI models. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New large model&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 21, Anthropic, an AI start-up from San Francisco, California, launched &lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. anthropic.com/index/claude-2-1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Claude 2.1 AI model&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; supports the input of up to 200,000 Tokens, exceeding the OpenAI large-scale Model GPT-4 Turbo has 128,000 Tokens, which can handle longer text content, and also has a new system prompt word (System Prompt) function. Anthropic claims that the accuracy of Claude2.1 is twice that of Claude2.0, which enhances the ability to understand text content, especially when processing higher-accuracy documents such as legal documents, financial reports, and technical specifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as OpenAI cooperates with Microsoft, Anthropic and Google stand together. In early November 2023, Anthropic announced that it would use Google&#39;s chip Cloud TPU v5e to support its large models and use its cloud computing services. Google promised to invest US$2 billion in it in October 2023, with an initial investment of US$500 million. Dollar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Inflection AI, a company co-founded in March 2023 by Mustafa Suleyman, co-founder of Google’s DeepMind AI research group, Karén Simonyan, chief scientist of DeepMind AI, and Reid Hoffman, co-founder of LinkedIn, in November &lt;a href=&quot;https://inflection.ai/inflection-2&quot;>;&lt;strong>;A new generation of large model Inflection-2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>; was released on the 22nd, calling it the world’s second-generation large model. Language Model (LLM). Inflection-2 performs FP8 mixed-precision training on 5,000 Nvidia H100 GPUs, with approximately 10^25 FLOP computing capabilities. It is in the same training computing category as Google&#39;s PaLM 2 Large model, and has been tested on MMLU, TriviaQA, HellaSwag and GSM8k. In most AI benchmark tests, it is better than PaLM 2, and in some tests it is second only to OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone is benchmarking against OpenAI, and OpenAI is certainly not idle either. On November 6, OpenAI released customizable &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/introducing-gpts&quot;>;&lt;strong>;GPTs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>; at its first developer conference , allowing ChatGPT Plus users and OpenAI’s enterprise customers to create customized versions of ChatGPT. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Users do not need to master programming knowledge. They can build a GPT with exclusive functions in GPT Builder by relying only on dialogue and a specific knowledge base. This will be more in line with the user&#39;s specific needs and usage scenarios, and will greatly The application threshold is lowered. This service will bring new changes and opportunities in vertical industry artificial intelligence, software applications and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, this &quot;involution&quot; of computing power, data, and models belongs to enterprises. For users, the use value and application scenarios of large models are more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, in office, smart terminal, social media and other scenarios, users can easily get started directly through the built-in large model application, making commercialization faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;AI application implementation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since August 2023, various mobile phone brands have announced plans to access large models. On November 8, Samsung Electronics released a large AI model developed by Samsung Research Institute&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.samsung.com/kr/%ec%82%bc%ec%84%b1%ec%a0 %84%ec%9e%90-%ec%82%bc%ec%84%b1-ai-%ed%8f%ac%eb%9f%bc%ec%84%9c-%ec%9e%90% ec%b2%b4-%ea%b0%9c%eb%b0%9c-%ec%83%9d%ec%84%b1%ed%98%95-ai-%ec%82%bc%ec%84 %b1-%ea%b0%80&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Samsung Gauss&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;. It consists of Samsung Gaussian language, Samsung Gaussian code and Samsung Gaussian image, and is planned to be integrated into various products in stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, Elon Musk’s AI company xAI released a large model on November 4&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.ai/&quot;>;&lt;strong >;Grok-1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;, with real-time access to X (formerly Twitter), and Internet browsing and search capabilities to obtain more of the latest news on specific topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, the Google DeepMind team published a paper in Science titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adi2336&quot;>;Learning Skillful medium-range global weather forecasting&lt;/a>; paper introduces their new machine learning weather forecast model Graphcast, which can generate 10-day forecasts in one minute on a single Google Cloud TPU v4 device, and supports forecasts including tropical Cyclone tracks, atmospheric rivers and extreme temperatures. At present, the source code of this model has been made public. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The weather forecasting method (MLWP) is more accurate and efficient than the traditional &quot;Numerical Weather Prediction&quot; (NWP) method. In July 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06185-3&quot;>;Pangu meteorological model developed by Huawei Cloud&lt;/a>;, in the medium and long-term global weather forecast surpass traditional numerical prediction methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the MLWP model can also be extended to other geographical spatiotemporal predictions such as ecology, energy, and animal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, &quot;Nature Medicine&quot; published a paper on the research results of Alibaba Damo Academy and more than ten medical institutions around the world&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature .com/articles/s41591-023-02640-w&quot;>;Large-scale pancreatic cancer detection via non-contrast CT and deep learning&lt;/a>;, for the first time it has been proven that &quot;plain scan CT + AI&quot; technology can effectively detect early stage pancreatic cancer on a large scale Pancreatic cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pancreatic cancer is a digestive tract tumor with a very poor prognosis. It has the characteristics of difficulty in early diagnosis, low surgical resection rate, and easy recurrence and metastasis after surgery. It is also known as the &quot;King of Cancers&quot; because of its early diagnosis. Symptoms are vague, lack specificity, and are easily overlooked. CT is the most widely used and most sensitive examination method for detecting pancreatic cancer. However, the contrast of plain CT images commonly used in physical examinations and hospitals is low, making it difficult to identify early pancreatic lesions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team built a deep learning framework—Pancreatic cancer early detection model PANDA (Pancreatic cancer Detection with AI), which uses AI to amplify and identify subtle pathological features that are difficult to detect with the naked eye in plain CT images; internal Test evaluation shows that PANDA can achieve 90% pancreatic cancer lesion sensitivity and 99.9% lesion specificity in more than 20,000 clinical cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using AI to accelerate the popularization of early cancer screening, early detection and early treatment, the quality of patients’ lives can be guaranteed to the greatest extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attached are three recent major developments in the field of biomedicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New progress in biomedicine&lt;/h4>; &lt;h5>;Eli Lilly&#39;s weight loss therapy was approved by the US FDA&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 8, Eli Lilly announced that its glucose-dependent insulinotropic peptide ( GIP) and glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) receptor dual agonist Zepbound (tirzepatide) &lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.lilly.com/news-releases/news-release-details/ fda-approves-lillys-zepboundtm-tirzepatide-chronic-weight&quot;>;Approved by the US FDA&lt;/a>; for the treatment of patients with obesity or overweight and weight-related comorbidities (blood pressure, dyslipidemia, type 2 diabetes, obstructive sleep disorders apnea or cardiovascular disease) to lose weight and maintain weight stability. Zepbound is the first approved drug that simultaneously activates two intestinal hormone receptors (GIP and GLP-1), directly targeting the root cause of excess weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The obesity indication approved for Zepbound this time is mainly based on the results of two Phase III clinical trials, one of which targeted 2,539 adults with obesity or overweight and weight-related problems (excluding diabetes). Injecting Zepbound as a dietary and exercise aid, the highest dose group (15 mg/week) lost an average of 48 pounds (approximately 22 kg) in 72 weeks, while the lowest dose group (5 mg/week) lost an average of 34 pounds (approximately 15 kg) , the placebo group was 7 pounds (about 3 kilograms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comment: Zepbound is a GIP/GLP-1 receptor agonist injected once a week. Eli Lilly announced the first new Chinese evidence in the field of Zepbound obesity treatment on October 3, 2023. And has submitted a registration application for long-term weight management indications in adults in China. As of now, there are no GLP-1 drugs officially approved in China for the treatment of obesity or overweight. China has a huge weight loss market, and the market competition in the field of weight loss indications is fierce, which provides more information for individuals seeking effective weight loss treatments. multiple choice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;The world’s first CRISPR gene editing therapy was approved&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 16, the US biopharmaceutical company Vertex (VRTX.O) and the Swiss gene editing company CRISPR Therapeutics ( CRSP.O) announced that the UK Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has granted it &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vrtx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/vertex-and-crispr- therapeutics-announce-authorization-first&quot;>;CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing therapy Casgevy (Exa-cel) Conditional Marketing Authorization&lt;/a>; (CMA, applicable to drugs that meet significant unmet medical needs, valid for one year, updated annually Once), for the treatment of patients 12 years of age and older with sickle cell disease (SCD) with recurrent vaso-occlusive crises (VOCs) and transfusion-dependent beta-Mediterranean patients who are unable to obtain human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-matched hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Anemia (TDT) patients. This is the world’s first CRISPR gene editing therapy approved for marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Casgevy is an autologous, ex vivo CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing therapy that modifies the patient&#39;s hematopoietic stem cells in vitro so that red blood cells can produce high levels of fetal hemoglobin (HbF, a hemoglobin that carries oxygen ). Results from two global clinical trials of CASGEVY in SCD and TDT showed that treated patients had no serious VOCs or independent blood transfusions for at least 12 consecutive months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The above approvals open the door to further applications of CRISPR therapies in the future, with the potential to cure many genetic diseases. In addition, another American biotechnology company Verve&amp;nbsp;(Nasdaq: VERV)&amp;nbsp; announced its development of a single base editing therapy VERVE-101 based on the modification of the CRISPR system at the American Heart Association on November 12, confirming that gene editing therapy A single infusion of the drug significantly reduced LDL-C levels in people who were at high risk for early heart attacks due to inherited high cholesterol. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;Half natural, half synthetic yeast cells&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 9, &quot;Cell&quot; reported on the international cooperation project as a cover story &lt;a href =&quot;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(23)01079-6?_returnURL=https%3A%2F%2Flinkinghub.elsevier.com%2Fretrieve%2Fpii%2FS0092867423010796%3Fshowall%3Dtrue&quot; >;The latest achievement of the &quot;Saccharomyces cerevisiae Genome Synthesis Project&quot;&lt;/a>; (Sc2.0 project): the design and synthesis of all 16 yeast chromosomes and a new chromosome of specially designed tRNA has been completed. The researchers crossed yeast cells containing different synthetic chromosomes and then looked for individuals carrying two synthetic chromosomes in the offspring. After a long hybridization process, the research team gradually integrated all the chromosomes they had previously synthesized (6 complete chromosomes and 1 chromosome arm) into the same cell. The resulting yeast strain accounted for more than 31% of the synthetic DNA and had a normal morphology. ; Later, a newly synthesized chromosome (chromosome 4, the largest of all synthetic chromosomes) was transferred using chromosome replacement, thus obtaining a yeast cell with 7.5 synthetic chromosomes, with the proportion of synthetic DNA accounting for more than 50%. The synthetic yeast cell Survival and replication capabilities are similar to wild yeast strains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/53090e4628.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/53090e4628.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;▲ VOLUME 186, ISSUE 24&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sc2.0 project initiated by the international scientific community aims to complete the design and chemical reconstruction of complete Saccharomyces cerevisiae The genome, and ultimately the yeast strain synthesized, will be a milestone in humanity&#39;s ability to use and understand eukaryotic genomes. On November 8, the results of the Sc2.0 project were published online in Cell (2 articles) and its sub-journals such as Molecular Cell (1 article) and Cell Genomics (7 articles). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Yeast is the first eukaryotic organism to have its entire genome sequenced. The large-scale design and reconstruction of its genome is a direct test of the authenticity, completeness and accuracy of the current knowledge base in the genome field. The above series of research results are not only a milestone for Sc2.0, but also a key step in the field of synthetic genomics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国人口第一县”两年关停95所幼儿园， 并非只因人口减少]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261432]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73753&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70548&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/103ceb5c9a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111456433091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 2023, No. 1 Institute in Hefei, Anhui The kindergarten is playing the game of &quot;Little Rabbit Transporting Carrots&quot;. In recent years, news of kindergarten closures has appeared in many places. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Pictures&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/103ceb5c9a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259802&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In September 2023, a kindergarten in Hefei, Anhui Province was playing the &quot;Rabbit Transporting Carrots&quot; game. In recent years, news of kindergarten closures has appeared in many places. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the news that &quot;China&#39;s most populous county has closed 50 kindergartens&quot;, the closure of kindergartens has become a directly related factor to the decrease in the birth population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Linquan County, Fuyang City, Anhui Province, with a registered population of 2.293 million in 2022, is known as &quot;the most populous county in China&quot;. In August 2023, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement that 50 local private kindergartens had ceased operations, accounting for 24.5% of the total number of private kindergartens in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A decrease in the number of births is considered to be the main reason. A set of government public data has been repeatedly mentioned in online communication. Linquan County has 58,243 children in kindergarten in 2023, a decrease of 9.2% from the previous year. This is the fourth consecutive year of decrease. This is consistent with the national trend of decreasing the number of kindergartens and the number of kindergarten students in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, another set of data did not attract attention. In June 2023, the Linquan County Development and Reform Commission stated that in 2022, the county will build, renovate and expand 9 kindergartens, effectively expanding the number of public kindergarten places by 2,070; simultaneously handing over 7 community supporting kindergartens, adding 2,610 places, completing the annual target tasks 103.5%. According to the plan, the county will add 1,890 new public kindergarten places and 2,000 kindergarten places in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, the founders of many closed private kindergartens in Linquan said that the main reason for the closure was the impact of local public kindergartens. “Their environment is better and their fees are higher. Cheap&quot;. However, they have not received policy support and their living space has become narrower. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are fewer children and the policies are not supportive&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the 50 private kindergartens that have terminated their operations in Linquan County, 12 private kindergartens have applied to terminate their operations, and the other 38 private kindergartens have no actual enrollment. , school-running behavior, the school-running license has expired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chengdong Street Yifan Kindergarten founded by Chen Min (pseudonym) belongs to the category with expired school license. Yifan Kindergarten was opened in 2006. Chen Min recalled that there were only more than 20 students at that time. It later gradually developed to its peak, with nearly 230 students enrolled around 2017. &quot;It has been running for more than ten years, and it has feelings.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Min said that the direct reason for the closure of Yifan Kindergarten was that the Linquan County Education Bureau interviewed and informed it that the current kindergarten operating standards had been improved, but the hardware facilities and site area of ​​Yifan Kindergarten did not meet the standards. , if it continues to open, enrollment will need to be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If we are given few places, we will definitely not be able to cover the rent, so there is no need to do it.&quot; Chen Min did some calculations and believed that if we continue to do it, there is a high probability of losing money. The number of students enrolled in Yifan Kindergarten has been declining in recent years, while new public kindergartens continue to be built in the surrounding areas. &quot;Public kindergartens have a good environment and low tuition fees.&quot; Chen Min believes that even if the Education Bureau does not stop it, it will have to take the initiative to close it down in two years. After struggling for several months, Chen Min decided not to apply for a license renewal and shut down. Before the closure, Yifan Kindergarten had three large classes and one middle class, with a total of 110 students and 12 teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teaching land of Hongyang Kindergarten in Huangling Town is a private house built by the principal himself. The number of students enrolled has always been around 80. &quot;But the number of small classes will be reduced from 2022 summer vacation.&quot; The principal of the kindergarten said that before the closure, they had a total of three classes, with more than 20 students and two teachers in each class. Since the kindergarten&#39;s operating license is about to expire, applying for license renewal and acceptance requires reinvestment to improve the environment and facilities in the park. She does not want to invest anymore and simply closes down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She believes that the gradual closure of private kindergartens is the general trend. &quot;Young people are unwilling to have children, so the state has increased investment in preschool education and supports public kindergartens.&quot; And she can clearly feel that after the development of public kindergartens, it is difficult for private kindergartens to recruit students. When asked whether the kindergarten had received a request from the County Education Bureau to limit enrollment, she said: &quot;How should I put it, you can&#39;t recruit many people even if I ask you to recruit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaotang Town Kindergarten founded by Yang Hui Jiyangzhuang Kindergarten is one of the 12 private kindergartens that voluntarily applied to terminate its operation. &quot;For various reasons, the funds could not be transferred, so the application was stopped.&quot; Yang Hui believes that the primary reason is that the number of students enrolled is small. In the past, Yangzhuang Kindergarten could enroll thirty or forty children, but in 2022, only 10 children were enrolled in small classes. &quot;It will be less every year, and it will be very few by 2022.&quot; At the same time, the school required &quot;two teachers and one childcare&quot;, that is, each class must be equipped with two teachers and three childcare workers. The income was far lower than the expenditure, and Yang Hui began to go into debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Hui mentioned that another reason is that it is very difficult for private kindergartens to recruit qualified teachers. Yang Hui said that in recent years, more and more kindergarten teachers have been recruited, and all of them have joined public kindergartens, and the supply of kindergarten teachers exceeds the demand. In addition, teachers’ salaries are not high, and young people of appropriate age are more likely to choose to work outside the home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, the Linquan County Education Bureau and the County Party Committee Propaganda Department declined an interview with Southern Weekend reporters. A local official told Southern Weekend reporters that as the number of public kindergartens in Linquan County gradually increased after 2017, the living space of private kindergartens became smaller and smaller. &quot;The impact of population decline is only the beginning of the phenomenon, and it is not the fundamental reason (the closure of private kindergartens).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There will be 45 fewer private kindergartens in 2022&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend Reporter Checking the public data of the local government, it was found that the number of private kindergartens in Linquan County has been decreasing year by year since 2019, and there has been a cliff-like decline for two consecutive years in 2022 and 2023, with a decrease of 45 and 50 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the number of public kindergartens has shown an increasing trend from 2019 to 2021 (data is missing in 2022 and 2023), growing from 160 to 221 in three years, and surpassing the number of private kindergartens in 2020 quantity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned officials said that the increase in the number of public kindergartens is mainly due to central policies. On November 7, 2018, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Several Opinions on Deepening the Reform and Standardized Development of Preschool Education&quot;, which clearly requires provinces with a low proportion of children in public kindergartens to gradually increase the proportion of children in public kindergartens. , in principle, the country will reach 50% by 2020, ensuring that the coverage rate of inclusive kindergartens (the proportion of children in public kindergartens and inclusive private kindergartens) reaches 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is also because of the implementation of this policy that we have been able to obtain funds from above and have continued to expand some public schools in recent years.” The official said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Fuyang Daily&quot; report, as early as the beginning of 2020, the Fuyang Municipal Education Bureau formulated the &quot;Fuyang City Preschool Education Deepening Reform and Standardized Development Plan&quot;, proposing to promote the universal, universal, safe and high-quality development of preschool education. We will vigorously develop public kindergartens and build, renovate and expand more than 50 public kindergartens every year. In principle, each town (street) should have one public kindergarten for every 15,000 or more people. By 2020, the city&#39;s gross kindergarten enrollment rate for the three years of preschool will reach 90%, and the coverage rate of inclusive kindergartens will reach 80%, of which the proportion of children in public kindergartens will in principle reach 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, the official WeChat public account of the Propaganda Department of Linquan County Party Committee announced that the county had successfully completed the above-mentioned &quot;985&quot; target tasks for preschool education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;985&quot; goal has further requirements in the &quot;Fuyang City&#39;s &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; Preschool Education Development and Improvement Action Plan&quot;: by 2025, the proportion of children in kindergartens in public kindergartens in the city will reach 70%. %above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that while Linquan County is increasing the proportion of public kindergartens, some places are also building more private kindergartens. On October 18, 2023, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement stating that the study approved the establishment of three private kindergartens in Tupei Township, Guanmiao Town, and Huangling Town. The three new kindergartens are all non-profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned official said that this is the process of natural replenishment in the market. He mentioned that among the 50 private kindergartens that will be closed in 2023, some were newly registered in 2021 and 2022. &quot;It shows that while private kindergartens have discovered that there is a market, the government is also looking at where there are vacancies to supplement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After market elimination&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the closure of the six private kindergartens contacted by Southern Weekend reporters, most of the original students were diverted to surrounding public kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The village party secretary of Zhangmiao Village in Tubei Township told Southern Weekend reporters that after a kindergarten in the village was closed, students were diverted to public kindergartens in several nearby villages. &quot;Public kindergartens charge cheaper, (in this village) The public kindergarten has enrolled more than 90 students in 2023. In the past, it enrolled only a few students, about 30 or 40 people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A parent interviewed in Qizhuang Community, Xingtang Street, also believes that one of the advantages of public kindergartens is that they are cheap. According to his understanding, there is a public kindergarten equipped with a school bus, and the tuition for a semester is more than 2,000 yuan if lunch is provided. If you go to a private kindergarten, the tuition fee will be 4,000 to 5,000 yuan under the same conditions. However, the national chain private kindergartens are more expensive, with tuition fees You get seven to eight thousand yuan per semester. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his opinion, there are not many local students, but now parents pay more attention to education. Parents, whether in rural areas or county towns, tend to send their children to public kindergartens or kindergartens in farther urban areas. The hardware facilities and teaching staff are better. For example, public kindergartens have larger student activity areas, more teaching aids, picture books, and more interest courses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most of the local private kindergartens are in private houses. The house built by my family has a small courtyard as a playground, and there is nothing.” The above-mentioned parents believe that most of the local private kindergartens that have been closed down are local private kindergartens. “Basically, those that have been eliminated by the market, those with better student sources and up-to-standard software and hardware will be converted into public ones, and all will be taken over by the government.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Yang Hui, it is a helpless choice for private kindergartens to withdraw from the market. Yangzhuang Kindergarten has been closed for more than three months. His kindergarten building and playground are abandoned and cannot be rented out. &quot;I am exhausted every day, and I have no choice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reluctantly closing the kindergarten, Yang Hui is working hard to keep his private elementary school. The primary school was founded by his father in 1994 and has a history of nearly 30 years. As a rural primary school, when the surrounding public village primary schools merged and closed down, it still attracted many students to attend due to the quality of its schooling. It was regarded as the &quot;central school&quot; of the surrounding villages. At its peak, the primary school enrolled nearly 600 students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Hui said that the current requirements for running schools in Linquan County have increased. The Education Bureau will give him 18 primary school enrollment places in 2022 and 20 in 2023. The school&#39;s enrollment has now dropped to just over two hundred students. Yang Hui did not dare to close down because the investment in primary schools was greater than that in kindergartens, and the losses caused by closure would be greater. But he had no idea about the way out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新内阁成立不到三月，三成员辞职，日本政坛怎么了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261385]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, three Japanese political affairs officials and deputy ministers have died in explosions. A scandal broke out and he was forced to resign. A local opinion poll showed that after the scandal broke out, the approval rate of the cabinet led by Japanese Prime Minister Kishida Fumio fell to 21%, setting a new low since Kishida became prime minister in October 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new cabinet was reorganized in September this year, and three people resigned in less than three months. For Fumio Kishida, he is currently facing a severe political crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is a period of unstable governance.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng, a professor at the Institute of International Relations at the China Foreign Affairs University, told Southern Weekend reporters that other factions within the party will also I&#39;m ready to replace him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/n33bJRcdIjL91WToVBPr9WcziXEwzahoqY4Kijl0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height= &quot;1225&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/n33bJRcdIjL91WToVBPr9WcziXEwzahoqY4Kijl0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023 local time, in Tokyo, Japan, after the cabinet reshuffle, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida attended a press conference in the Prime Minister&#39;s Office. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Many senior officials were forced to resign&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;Kanda Kenji, 60 years old, is a member of the House of Representatives of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was the Japanese &quot;Bunshun Weekly&quot; that first broke the scandal of the then Japanese Deputy Minister of Finance Kenji Kanda. According to reports, a company under his name defaulted on taxes, and between 2013 and 2022, the company&#39;s land and properties were seized by the tax department four times. The report also stated that as a tax accountant, Kanda Kenji himself violated relevant industry regulations and failed to participate in necessary training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kanda apologized for the relevant scandal and admitted that the reports were true. Since he was &quot;too busy to get involved&quot; in overseeing the company&#39;s tax details, the work had been left to an accounting firm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the scandal broke out, it triggered domestic public criticism of Kanda. Japan&#39;s opposition parties put pressure on the ruling party to remove him from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 9, during his defense, Kanda also stated that he would &quot;continue to perform his duties.&quot; However, on the 10th, he changed his words on whether to continue to perform his duties and said, &quot;No.&quot; Comment&quot;. Resigned on the 13th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In just a few days, I changed my words three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is generally believed that Kenji Kanda was essentially replaced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In response to rising prices in Japan, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida proposed an economic countermeasure, an annual supplementary budget of over 17 trillion yen. Previously, the leader of the Cadet Party, Kenta Izumi, said that the Cadet Party would not participate in the deliberations on the budget unless Kishida replaced Kanda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the day of his resignation, Kenji Kanda admitted that he resigned because he &quot;did not want his scandal to affect the debate in Congress.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first senior figure in Japanese politics to resign due to a scandal in recent times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 31, the then Deputy Minister of Justice Kakizawa Mitaru resigned due to suspicion of violating the Public Office Election Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kakizawa is a member of parliament elected from Koto Ward, Tokyo. Previously, Koto Ward Mayor Kimura Yayoi and her team were arrested by Tokyo for allegedly violating the public office election law. Search by the District Prosecutor&#39;s Office. Kakizawa admitted that he made suggestions to Kimura regarding illegal campaigning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the scandals that broke out in Kanda and Kakizawa were due to tax evasion and other illegal issues, while Taro Yamada, then administrative officer of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, was involved in &quot;extramarital affairs&quot;. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 56-year-old Taro Yamada, who is married and has children, is also a senator of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Just one month before Kanda resigned, on the evening of October 19, the media photographed Taro Yamada spending the night with a young woman in a hotel in Tokyo. , which lasts about three hours. After the news came to light, Taro Yamada admitted to having an extramarital affair and apologized, but denied paying the woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, the scope of negative public opinion spread wider and wider. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 26, Taro Yamada resigned, becoming the first senior government official to resign after Kishida Fumio reorganized the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Japanese politics have long been unclean.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng emphasized that the financial sector provides money to support politicians&#39; campaigns, and once politicians gain power, they will Opening up the financial circle, formulating laws that are beneficial to them, and promoting policies that are beneficial to them, this is the collusion of money and power politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Corruption scandals captured by the media as collusion between the financial and political circles are, in most cases, immediately exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chou Yongsheng added that for those in power, this will make them disgraced, or their approval ratings will continue to decline. For them, the media is actually called the &quot;fifth power constraint.&quot; Sometimes it is helpless, and sometimes it can be settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023, in order to save the sluggish support rate, Kishida reshuffled the cabinet again, replacing the existing 19-person list with 13 people, including the Foreign Minister , Defense Minister and other important positions, and declared that this is a &quot;cabinet that transforms change into strength.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three members of the new cabinet, which was established less than three months ago, have resigned, but the public is not surprised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Japanese public is accustomed to scandals in the political world. Ordinary people have developed a &#39;political apathy&#39; and do not pay much attention to the personal integrity and moral character of politicians. Great trust and expectations.&quot; Sun Wenzhu, associate researcher at the Asia-Pacific Institute of the China Institute of International Studies, said that the public does not approve of this open &quot;fertile politics&quot;, but there is a lack of restraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Disapproval rate hits record high&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I must apologize to the Japanese people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, regarding Kanda’s dismissal due to tax arrears, Fumio Kishida publicly stated that he attaches great importance to the responsibility of appointment and will continue to do his best to perform his duties to restore the trust of the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many public opinions believe that the forced resignation of many senior executives was a &quot;double blow&quot; to Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Affected by factors such as the domestic economic downturn, the push to discharge nuclear contaminated water into the sea, and the frequent scandals involving many ministers, the support rate of Kishida&#39;s cabinet continues to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 12, the results of a joint public opinion poll in Japan showed that the approval rate of the cabinet led by Kishida was 27.8%, a decrease of 7.8% from the October survey results. percentage points, setting a new low since the establishment of the Kishida cabinet in 2021. The disapproval rate reached 68.8%, a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Qifang, associate researcher at the Institute of International Strategic Studies at the China Institute of International Studies, believes that the Japanese people are generally disappointed with the performance of politicians. There is a &quot;domino&quot; resignation effect this time. The people can be said to be &quot;voting with their feet&quot;, and the cabinet&#39;s support rate will naturally decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She added that, in fact, Abe’s support rate has been relatively low since the late period of his administration. It is not Kishida Fumio&#39;s personal deciding factor, this is also the &quot;mess&quot; left by his &quot;predecessor&quot;. Kishida obviously failed to take over this stall, so it is a continuous decline process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Japanese political arena, &quot;the cabinet support rate falls below 30%&quot; is regarded as entering &quot;dangerous waters&quot;; once it falls further below 20%, it means The cabinet is close to being dissolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Qifang said that at the beginning, the Japanese people did not have particularly high expectations for Kishida Fumio, thinking that he might not be decisive or particularly innovative. Facts have also proved that many of Kishida Fumio’s ideas have not been translated into very practical policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Liberal Democratic Party, Moriyama, the Liberal Democratic Party&#39;s general affairs chairman, publicly pointed out that the successive resignations of high-level officials were &quot;an extremely abnormal situation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moriyama leads the Moriyama faction, one of the smaller factions within the Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu believes that the so-called &quot;abnormality&quot; is not only to maintain the authority of the Liberal Democratic Party as a whole, but also to be some kind of euphemistic accusation against Prime Minister Kishida Fumio, thus putting himself The Pai clan had a certain cut with Fumio Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This incident further exposed that money issues and style issues have become chronic diseases in Japanese politics.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Early this month, the Kishida cabinet launched an economic stimulus plan of over 17 trillion yen, the main content of which is tax cuts and extended subsidies. The Japanese government estimates that the plan will increase the Japanese economy by 1.2% annually over the next three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Kishida’s “spending money” failed to achieve the expected goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, the Japanese Cabinet Office released third-quarter GDP data. Japan experienced negative quarterly GDP growth for the first time. In addition, Japan&#39;s private consumption declined in the third quarter, net exports fell by 0.1%, and corporate investment also declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;New economic strategies have not been recognized by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A Japanese poll shows that more than 60% of the people &quot;disapprove&quot; of the government&#39;s comprehensive economic countermeasures. The reason is that since 2020, Japan’s income tax and resident tax have increased year after year. The economic policies formulated by the Kishida cabinet today are not truly “beneficial to the people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It turns out that prices in Japan have not risen for decades. Zhou Yongsheng pointed out, &quot;Because Japan&#39;s imported goods are expensive, it promotes domestic inflation and causes prices to rise rapidly. The Japanese people cannot stand the sudden price increase, and they are skeptical of Kishida&#39;s ability to govern.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What worries the public even more is that the Kishida cabinet has announced plans to significantly increase the defense budget between 2023 and 2027, with a total investment of up to 43 trillion yen. Many people are worried that the Kishida cabinet will use methods such as increasing taxes and misappropriating financial funds to revitalize earthquake-stricken areas to increase defense capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Yongsheng believes that people&#39;s concerns are &quot;not unreasonable.&quot; The biggest pressures Kishida&#39;s cabinet currently faces are pressures from domestic economic growth, financial constraints, and mounting debt. Japan&#39;s fiscal budget had to rely on the issuance of government bonds to expand its fiscal budget, causing its debt burden to become further heavy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The financial flexibility of the Kishida cabinet is actually getting smaller and smaller, and coupled with the need to significantly expand armaments, the financial pressure is even greater. .&quot; Zhou Yongsheng believes that armaments are purely a money-burning and money-consuming industry with no benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu believes that Fumio Kishida has been in office as president of the Liberal Democratic Party for two years, and the Liberal Democratic Party will usher in another presidential election in the fall of 2024 at the latest. Judging from the electoral strategy, it is likely that he will take the initiative to dissolve the House of Representatives before the intra-party election and lead the Liberal Democratic Party to win a majority in the House of Representatives to gain points for his re-election. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pressure of governing under the “yellow light”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of the outside world, reorganizing the cabinet cannot bring the Kishida regime back to life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;First of all, the current life of the Japanese people is in a state of instability, which directly affects people&#39;s livelihood and leads to a decline in support rates. This has a great influence on whether Kishida can continue to work in the future. Governance is a very big threat.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng said, &quot;Secondly, Kishida has improperly hired officials in governance, and has hired corrupt people one after another. This is also a blow to his own image and the image of the cabinet.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is noteworthy is that this year, despite opposition from the international community, Japan insisted on discharging nuclear contaminated water from the Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant into the sea, causing huge controversy at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu pointed out that in terms of diplomacy, Japan is still essentially strengthening its all-round binding with the United States and relying on U.S. support to highlight its &quot;sense of presence.&quot; What the Japanese people really need to improve Sino-Japanese relations has yet to see practical action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many media reports said that if Kishida wants to be re-elected as president of the Liberal Democratic Party next fall and achieve long-term governance, he must choose the time to dissolve the House of Representatives and hold an election and ensure that the Liberal Democratic Party Achieved good results in the general election. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But the cabinet&#39;s low support rate, the low support rate of the Liberal Democratic Party, and the resignation of &quot;Domino&quot; to resign from the government officials, and the &quot;yellow lanterns&quot; for a long time for Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, from the perspective of many interviewed experts and scholars, this status quo will not force Kishida to step down immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The pressure of Kishida Wenxiong is how to win the election of the Liberal Democratic Party&#39;s president next year, and the might dissolve the election of the House of Representatives in advance to achieve continuing governing.&quot; The so -called &quot;political performance&quot; is of little significance for the Japanese people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhou Yongsheng said that in the past, in addition to Abe and Koizumi, the cabinet in Japan was almost changed every year. Kishida has been in power for two years. If there is no big leakage, it is likely to continue in power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At present, Kishida has decided to abandon the plan to dissolve the House of Representatives during the year, go all out to promote the government&#39;s comprehensive economic countermeasures, and strive to gradually boost public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The probability of the Liberal Democratic Party will still maintain the status of the ruling party. Let the presidents recognized by each factional valve. &quot;Sun Wenzhu thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But the Japanese people&#39;s disappointment of politics and the &quot;cold sense&quot; of politics cannot be reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend Intern Bao Jingzheng also contributed to this article) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访央行原副行长李东荣：数字化金融不会改变金融功能属性和风险属性]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261417]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-27 20:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 10, 2023, the &quot;Three Ding&quot; Plan of the State Administration of Financial Supervision landed: Financial Control Group&#39;s supervision Responsibilities for the protection of functions and financial consumer rights and interests are officially planned at the People&#39;s Bank of China. The pedestrian system is one step ahead of the modern central bank system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking back in the past, 45 years ago, the PICC and the Ministry of Finance were officially approved by the Ministry of Finance, and since 1984, the functions of the central bank have been specially exercised. Since then, the central bank system has been continuously changed and improved with the pace of economic reform and social development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, the four major state -owned banks have transformed into the leading benchmark of the global banking industry, and smart finance has become the forefront of strategic competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The once -chaotic Internet finance is now incorporated into the regulatory track and is growing in an orderly manner into an innovative force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the financial power has become a new goal, how does the financial industry continue to change the history as the mirror? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Researcher researcher of the New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend interviewed Li Dongrong, the former vice president of the People&#39;s Bank of China. In the past 40 years of financial career, Li Dongrong has served as the Vice President of the Guangdong Branch of the Guangdong Provincial Branch. . In June 2015, Li Dongrong was responsible for the establishment of the China Internet Finance Association and served as the first president for 7 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In an exclusive interview with the Southern Weekend, he described the achievement of my country&#39;s financial reform and opening up with &quot;thousands of sails on the side of Shenzhou, Wanmuchun in front of the sick tree&quot; The difficulty of the road before financial reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/puprtsgfe1mmmnasbf2yhyywkxzlbfgvr.png&quot; 0 &quot;widt =&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;436&quot; height = &quot;660&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/puprtsgfe1mmmnasbf2yyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyrbfgvr.png&quot; data-key = &quot;259778&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Li Dongrong, former vice president of the People&#39;s Bank of China, the former president of the China Internet Finance Association &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (interviewee/picture) &lt; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Banks cannot just count &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; account &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; When accounting &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekend Weekends : &lt;/Strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In the nearly 40 years of financial career, what financial reform and opening up has you experienced or witnessed? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I was fortunate Financial work conferences have experienced and witnessed financial reforms and development with the reform of the banking system as the main characteristics at this historical stage. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Before reform and opening up, what are the main major financial systems in China feature? Why must we reform? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; For a long time before the reform and opening up, my country has implemented a highly centralized planned economic system. It is compatible with the fiscal unified revenue and banks. In 1969, the PIFC and the Ministry of Finance were co -deployed by the Ministry of Finance. At that time, the main characteristics of the national financial system were that the Bank was a state -owned bank that managed finance and a national bank that operated the banking business. Banks only apply for mobile fund loans, the institutional business is single, the credit concentration, and the scale is not large. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 4, 1979, Comrade Deng Xiaoping pointed out at the symposium with the principals of the party committees of the provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities. The role of to the bank. To become a lever for the development of economic innovation technology, banks must truly run the bank into a bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Comrade Deng Xiaoping outlined the main problems facing my country&#39;s economic and financial at that time at that time, and timely pointed out the direction for my country&#39;s financial reform at the beginning of reform and opening up, and became an important guidance for my country&#39;s financial system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; &quot;Turn to state banks into a real commercial bank&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family : Kai style, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; How do you understand&quot; the bank is really done into a bank &quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; can be divided into two main lines to summarize. One is to make state -owned banks as real commercial banks; the other is to handle Chinese bank Real central bank. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; bank? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In the early days of reform and opening up, due to the reasons such as the burden and management of historical, the four major state -owned professional banks generally face the unclear governance mechanisms and unclear unclear governance mechanisms are unclear. Unreasonable, high proportion of non -performing assets, and outstanding problems such as increasing interest and increasing interest. The Asian financial crisis in 1997 exacerbated its impact on the four major banks, highlighting the urgency of accelerating the reform of the state -owned banking system. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You have gone through the process of transforming state -owned banks to commercial banks, especially injecting the four major banks with foreign exchange. How is the difficulty to overcome it? ? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; The State Council established a pilot group leading group of the shareholding system of wholly state -owned commercial banks. He was the director of the office, and the Central Huijin Company was established at that time. According to the deployment of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, since December 2003, the Central Huijin Company used foreign exchange reserves to inject capital with the Bank of China and the Construction Bank of China. Later, they also injected capital with Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China, and promoted their listing in mainland China and Hong Kong, and gradually realized the transformation of state -owned professional banks to joint -stock commercial banks. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I was transferred to the State Administration of Foreign Exchange in early 2002. Under the leadership of the Party Committee of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Party Group of the Foreign Exchange Administration, Guo Shuqing, then director, led us to participate in and witnessed the preparation and launching foreign exchange capital capital of the Central Huijin Company. In the process of participation, I am proud of the correct decision -making decisions of the Party Central Committee and the strong implementation of the financial system. It was this series of important and timely decisions that laid an indispensable foundation for the China Banking system at the time and the rapid rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How to fulfill the obligation of good investors? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I remember that in order to truly fulfill the duties and obligations of the investor, we pay attention Establish a party group to strengthen the construction of the party&#39;s grass -roots organizations; on the other hand, actively organize learning, learn from the advanced experience of corporate governance in the international market, explore the establishment of corporate governance mechanisms that meet China&#39;s national conditions, and select comrades from all units to dispatch politics and excellent business quality from all units. As a dispatched director, and the dispatch directors to conduct politics, business and other aspects of the directors, and improve the ability of the directors to perform their duties. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Since then, state-owned banks have continued to change to commercial banks, you What are the key factor? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Looking back, the reason why my country&#39;s wholly -owned commercial bank&#39;s stock reform can succeed, based The party&#39;s leadership of the reform and development of financial undertakings; the second is to establish a market operating mechanism on the basis of the national conditions. The Party Central Committee and the State Council are far -sighted, trial, and correct decisions. Established the Central Huijin Company, especially the use of national foreign exchange reserves to inject capital injection to pilot banks, and promote the final completion of stock reform and listing in wholly state -owned commercial banks. Later state -owned banks rejuvenated and became real commercial banks. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Historical practice shows that today China&#39;s banking system has a considerable scale in both the employment institutions, the total amount of deposits and loans, and the amount of funds. The trend of intelligence has well supported the development of the real economy and serving the people&#39;s lives of the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;&lt;strong>; Pedestrian &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Real Central Bank &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Another main line you mentioned just now is to run the People&#39;s Bank of China into a real central bank. How do you know and witness in the process of transition? Is there something particularly impressive? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In order to adapt to the new situation faced after reform and opening up, to do a good job The pace of banking system reform. In 1978, the Central Committee decided to leave the national financial management from the financial part of the financial part. Since then, the pedestrian system has been reforming. Until December 25, 1993, the State Council issued a decision on the reform of the financial system and pointed out that making the People&#39;s Bank of China into a real central bank is the primary task of deepening the reform of the financial system. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I worked at the Guangdong Branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China at the time. From June 20th to June 26th, 1991, experts and scholars from the People&#39;s Bank of China, various professional banks, other financial institutions, relevant legal departments, financial and legal circles gathered in Zhuhai, and solicited opinions and opinions and opinions and opinions on the drafting content of the bank law. suggestion. In 1995, the version reviewed and approved by the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress was divided into the People&#39;s Bank of China Law and Commercial Banking Law. They more objectively and accurately reflect the direction and status of my country&#39;s banking system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How to deepen and improve functional positioning? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; As the functional positioning is becoming increasing Monetary policy tool box. The credit fund management system has been changed from the original unified loan to the difference, and soon transition to the &quot;unified plan, divide funds, real loans, and integrate with each other.&quot; The transformation of the Lord laid the foundation for the macro -control model of the subsequent asset -liability proportion management. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In November 1997, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council held the first National Financial Work Conference to determine the policy of further deepening the reform of the financial system and emphasized that the People&#39;s Bank of China should be held into a real central government. Banks, fully reflect the three characteristics of issued banks, banks and national banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After that, the bank separated the financial supervision functions, and established the Securities Regulatory Commission, the Insurance Regulatory Commission, and the CBRC to concentrate on the implementation of the implementation of monetary policy and macro -prudential policies, and maintaining financial stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Reform has been continuing. In 2023, according to the reform plan of the State Council&#39;s institutional institution, the daily regulatory responsibilities of the People&#39;s Bank of China on financial groups such as financial holding companies and relevant financial consumer protection duties were included in the State Administration of Finance and Administration; People&#39;s Bank of China (Municipal) Central Sub -branch. This reflects the direction and measures of further construction of the Chinese modern central bank system during the new historical period. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Department &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Technology is the reform &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Important driving force &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You just mentioned the intelligent trend of the service means of the Chinese banking system. In recent years, no technology and not finance have become consensus. As the deputy governor of the central bank in charge of science and technology, what do you think that in the financial system reform so far, what role does technology have played? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The 45 years of reviewing the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up are 45 years with the advancement of global science and technology and follow the pace of scientific and technological progress. It can be said that it is the important driving force of technology that allows my country to continue to adapt to the reform and development of the economy and provide more adaptive and effective financial services to the society. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body _gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In the early days of reform and opening up, did financial technology be applied? At this stage, what are the characteristics of China&#39;s fintech? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; As early as the mid -1980s, the People&#39;s Bank of China led the establishment Prepare, &quot;Seven Five -Year Plan&quot; foundation, the size of the &quot;Eighth Five -Year Plan&quot;, and the overall goal of &quot;Nine Five&quot; basically achieved electronic goals. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this stage, the financial industry mainly relies on technological methods such as computer technology and network technology to improve the efficiency of traditional financial business and reduce operating costs. The first is to operate electronic. The second is system networking. The third is the unified standard. Bank card is a successful case of standard unified standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Benefiting from reform and opening up and technological progress, the road of financial electronic construction in my country has realized the historic breakthrough of &quot;from scratch, from manual to electronics, from single -machine to networking&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under the guidance of the top -level design, my country&#39;s financial information construction has begun to enter the fast lane. The construction of financial information and financial standardization is also closely linked to international financial supervision. I was fortunate to participate in and witnessed many major financial information incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Which event makes you most impressive? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The application and promotion of financial IC cards. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the growth of bank card management funds and the continuous development of information technology, the magnetic strip card has gradually become a criminal attack due to its weak computing processing capacity and easy copying of information. object. Technical experiments and global practical experience show that after the completion of the financial IC card migration in Britain, France and other countries and regions, the risk of bank card fraud has decreased significantly. On the contrary, countries and regions that have not carried out financial IC card migration in time may become the security depression of global bank cards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the rapid development of the bank card industry in my country and the completion of financial IC card migration in neighboring countries and regions, some pseudo card fraud activities have gradually penetrated into my country. Accelerating the application of financial IC cards has become a top priority to improving the level of risk prevention and control of bank cards in my country and ensuring the security of the people&#39;s payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Looking back at the application and promotion of financial IC cards, you What is the biggest experience? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Looking back at this difficult journey, I deeply realize that the significance of the financial IC card promotion and application is not only from security protection. In the angle, reduce the loss of fake card fraud, protect the people&#39;s money bags, and also play an important role in promoting the development of mobile finance, inclusive finance and green finance, and promoting the upgrading of the domestic industrial chain. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the one hand, it lays the foundation for improving the acceptability and convenience of people&#39;s financial services; on the other hand, the People&#39;s Bank . For example, build an experimental environment and pilot to verify the application of the national secret algorithm on the financial IC card. This provides application scenarios and contributes to the technological development and progress of critical areas in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Remediation &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Mutual Gold &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Risk &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; >; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Internet finance has grown brutal but also represents a trend. Participate in the special rectification of Internet financial risks, what do you have to perceive? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; 2015, with the consent of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, ten ministries and commissions such as the People&#39;s Bank of China issued the &quot;Guidance on Promoting the Healthy Development of Internet Finance on the Health Development of Internet Finance Opinion&quot;. The documents clearly need to strengthen the self -discipline of the Internet financial industry, and require the People&#39;s Bank of China to build the China Internet Finance Association in conjunction with the relevant departments to give full play to the positive role of industry self -discipline mechanisms in regulating the market behavior of employment institutions and protecting the legitimate rights and interests of the industry. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I accept organizational arrangements, responsible for the establishment of the China Internet Finance Association and participating in the special rectification of Internet financial risks, and witness the process of the industry from chaos and regulatory development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; as an industry self-discipline organization: China Internet Finance Association to Internet finance specifications for Internet finance What are the main principles? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In April 2016, the State Council issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for the Special Rectification of Internet Finance Risk&quot;, which was jointly rectified by the 17 ministries and commissions such as the People&#39;s Bank of China. The illegal and illegal acts in the field of Internet finance have promoted the orderly development of Internet financial norms. At the beginning of the establishment of the Internet Finance Association, it was invested in the special risk rectification work according to the deployment of the State Council and the People&#39;s Bank of China. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 2016, the state has actively promoted the digital transformation of banks while organizing the development of the Internet financial industry&#39;s risk and guiding the development of the industry. As an industry self -discipline organization, the association mainly carried out work through four aspects and establishes self -rhythmic constraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First, strengthen the construction of basic systems and self -discipline rules. Through the establishment of statistical monitoring, reporting, registration disclosure, information sharing, financial advertising monitoring and other business systems and system platforms, it provides basic services for the unified industry standards, standardized operations, and preventing risks. Monitoring information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second is to formulate and promote the implementation of relevant standard rules. To prevent Internet financial risks and financial consumer protection as the starting point, promote regulatory policy implementation and ensure the implementation of policy implementation through standard rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Third, to carry out statistical monitoring and risk early warning. Cooperate with the National Bureau of Statistics to promote the implementation of the relevant statistical system, cooperate with the financial regulatory authorities to continuously monitor the relevant risks areas, grasp the bottom number of risks, and issue risks on activities such as virtual currency, cash loan, first token issuance (ICO), illegal or illegal financial advertising and other activities. Early warning prompts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fourth is to cooperate with the country to carry out the infrastructure construction of the financial industry. In accordance with the overall planning and regulatory requirements of the national credit market development, the association organized various participating units to prepare through all aspects, and obtained the first domestic business institution permit for personal credit reporting business in February 2018, and was listed in the same year. . This provides a new channel for personal credit inquiry for various financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Treatment of service entities &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Economy &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; and risk -proof level &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; system &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the Internet financial risk is gradually clearing, the financial industry that is accelerating digital transformation should be even more What risks to prevent? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Digital finance will not change the financial functional attributes and risk attributes, but the attributes of digital technology them The openness and interaction of the coming will inevitably make the modern financial field getting fast and convenient, and will directly face the impact of multiple risks such as business, technology, network, and data. The hiddenness, suddenness and diffusion of risks during this period will be more prominent, thereby putting more new challenges to modern financial supervision and social stability. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The digital transformation of banks in my country presents a rapid development trend, which is manifested as: First, technology -driven is more prominent. Second, demand leadership is more common. Third, industry integration is closer. Fourth, risk management is more urgent. Therefore, in the process of transformation of the banking industry, on the one hand, we must actively face and embrace the opportunities and challenges brought by the application of new technology. At the same time, we must firmly establish awareness of risk prevention and strengthen safety construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What are your suggestions for the reform and opening up of the financial industry? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Thousands of sails on the side of Shenzhou, Wanmuchun in front of the sick tree. China&#39;s financial reform has gone through 45 years and has made great achievements that have attracted worldwide attention. Looking back, I have four deep feelings: First, we must always adhere to the party&#39;s leadership and use the correct ideological policy to guide financial reform and opening up. The second is to always adhere to the people -oriented, financial products and services supply, and cannot be separated from the reasonable needs of the people at any time, and pay attention to protecting the legitimate rights and interests of the masses. The third is to always adhere to the laws of the market, based on the national conditions of the country, and to deal with the relationship between serving the real economy and preventing risks in a realistically. Fourth, we must always adhere to the development of technology -driven financial development and achieve the improvement of the quality and efficiency of financial services and financial supervision. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking forward to the future, financial reforms are still on the road, and there is a long way to go. As long as we continue to work hard in the correct direction of reform and opening up, China&#39;s financial industry will continue to pioneer and compose a new chapter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>