<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[刘润“翻车”后左支右绌：“商业战略大师”到底是门什么生意？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The famous business consultant Liu Run &quot;overturned&quot; and broke the circle due to what happened on October 28, 2023 A statement from an annual speech given. Liu Run said in his speech that it took three years for brand discount MAMA stores to open 2,500 stores across the country, with total revenue exceeding 1.7 billion. This set of data has been questioned by many parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xintong, the founder of Discount Niu, posted a video on Douyin, saying that according to the public statement of the founder of Discount MAMA, the brand should have 20 to 30 stores in September this year, and the annual turnover should be It&#39;s less than 100 million. Some netizens questioned in the comments, &quot;1.7 billion, 2,500 stores, each store sells about 680,000 yuan a year on average? And where are these 2,500 stores mainly opened?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Run repeatedly explained, saying that &quot;there are explanations in the speech and in the full text&quot; &quot;these 2,500 stores include self-operated stores, co-branded stores and stores supported by the supply chain&quot; &quot;this number has been confirmed by Xing Yunfei himself&quot; &quot;. MAMA founder Xing Yunfei also responded that discount MAMA has 4,000+ stores nationwide supported by direct operations, joint operations, and supply chain hosting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Run even published a report titled &quot;Liu Run: 2,700 stores, 1.7 billion, discount MAMA&#39;s data. Is it fiction?&quot; &quot;The article, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter if you use my traffic, but you have misled many sincere entrepreneurs&quot; caused more dissatisfaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After much hesitation, Liu Run finally issued an apology letter on Weibo on November 2, admitting several mistakes. The storm is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Liu Run&#39;s mistake in his annual speech was very obvious. As he finally admitted, the so-called &quot;2,500 stores&quot; were not opened by MAMA, but most of them were MAMA &quot;services&quot; business partners. If business partners such as upstream and downstream supply chains and co-branding are included in the stores opened by brands, how many more &quot;unicorn&quot; companies will China need to add? What&#39;s even more ironic is that according to the water injection standard for cooperation, the data given by Xing Yunfei is more than 4,000, indicating that the &quot;2,500&quot; mentioned in Liu Run&#39;s speech is also very inaccurate. Could it be a compromise of &quot;fuzzy processing&quot;? There should not be such low-level data errors in the annual speeches of business consulting professionals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You shouldn’t make simple mistakes, and you shouldn’t admit it in time when you are wrong. People can not escape from doing wrong. If you can change your past, there is no greater good. Admit it openly when you are wrong and then give a reasonable explanation. This is the most basic principle of crisis public relations. Liu Run did not do this. It may not be because he does not understand, but because the &quot;Internet celebrity&quot; business model of establishing a personality and generating traffic caused deformation of his actions. Business consulting business cannot do this, but &quot;Internet celebrity&quot; traffic business must do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the rise of the Internet, a group of Internet celebrity &quot;business consultants&quot; or so-called &quot;business strategy gurus&quot; have emerged. Their resumes are as bright as a crucian carp crossing a river. Liu Run is one of the representative figures. However, the business model of these &quot;business consultants&quot; is very different from the traditional business consulting industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;business consultants&quot; who are active online are IP-based and media-based, and are keen on the &quot;to C&quot; business of mass communication, rather than the &quot;to B&quot; business of traditional business consulting agencies serving enterprises. For example, Liu Run&#39;s title includes strategic consultants for many large companies, but it is difficult for the public to understand how much he has contributed to the strategic optimization of these companies, and how much he and his business team have gained from these corporate consulting services. revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Run’s most eye-catching business achievement is the huge income that expensive online courses and even more expensive offline courses have brought him. The prospectus of Thinking Creation, the parent company of &quot;Get&quot;, Liu Run&#39;s main sales platform, shows that Liu Run has appeared in &quot;Get&quot;&#39;s major procurement contracts for four consecutive years starting in 2017. From 2017 to 2020, Liu Run received a total of 58 million in online and offline course revenue. Liu Run’s IP has become a high-quality “obtained” asset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to evaluate Liu Run&#39;s career using traditional business consulting standards. What is certain is that Liu Run is a very successful Internet content producer and an &quot;Internet celebrity&quot; with high IP value. The &quot;business consultants&quot; who are active on the Internet today are basically in this situation. It is difficult to see how successful their consulting business is. The content dissemination channel of paid knowledge is the main source of revenue. Of course, traditional business consulting also earns training fees, but this is not how the courses are sold, and the audience is not so &quot;taught but not differentiated&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The service targets of traditional business consulting organizations are very limited. Small and medium-sized organizations are usually only responsible for a few long-term customers, and large organizations only have dozens or hundreds of long-term customers. Their services require constant performance appraisal from customers, and every &quot;golden idea&quot;, every special report, and every training class must be of practical help to business operations. The traffic of &quot;business consultants&quot; in the hundreds of thousands or millions means that the audience is huge and the actual performance is difficult to measure. No one can count how many &quot;students&quot; who bought courses have gained business benefits from the wise words of the &quot;business consultant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this kind of content creation and dissemination must be classified as a business consulting industry, it can only be said that the training branch of the business consulting industry is moving toward a &quot;sinking market.&quot; The audience is huge, the good and the bad are mixed, and the specific scenarios vary widely. It is impossible to provide customized services like the traditional business consulting industry. The communication effect is the goal of this sinking market. This &quot;sinking market&quot; competes for traffic, not service performance. Therefore, the primary means of competition is presentation skills rather than actual performance in furthering the commercial interests of the audience. The macro narrative is gorgeous, the micro is chicken soup for the soul, new concepts and golden sentences fly together, and the words are not surprising, all in order to attract more fans and gain more traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The behavior patterns of &quot;business consultants&quot; and &quot;business strategy masters&quot; are closer to other &quot;Internet celebrities&quot; who do traffic business than to traditional business consulting agencies. Like all internet celebrities, they must always give top priority to maintaining their personality and traffic base. Traditional business consulting agencies have neither such &quot;traffic pressure&quot; nor room for prevarication and confusion - customers are all experts and are not easy to fool. Even if you fool around for a while, it will be in vain if there is a performance problem in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the &quot;business consultants&quot; who are active on the Internet are not the networking of the business consulting industry, but the Internet celebrityization of business culture communication. “Internet celebrity” itself is not a derogatory connotation. Used correctly, it can improve the efficiency of information dissemination and help popularize knowledge and ideas. However, if used incorrectly, it will become the starting point for a decline in industry standards and a decline in professional ethics. Liu Run made low-level mistakes first and refused to admit his mistakes later. He can be classified as the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an emerging industry in the Internet era, &quot;business consultants&quot; must be tolerant and willing to see results, but they also need to be vigilant and learn from each experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident is a warning to the &quot;business consultant&quot; industry. There is nothing wrong with spreading business culture, but don’t overly elevate your industry positioning. Most of them are content producers who disseminate business knowledge to the public. Why bother with the &quot;sheep head&quot; of &quot;business consulting&quot;? Micro business scenarios vary widely, and market segments are diverse. Even if you have the power to penetrate the universe, how many users can you provide consulting services to? The bluff of forcibly creating IP and selling characters goes against the spirit of business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For consumers who pay for knowledge, this incident is also a reminder. If two to three hundred yuan of course money can buy you the secrets of getting rich that can change your destiny, how can there be any poor people in the world? Consume rationally and choose carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also those large companies that have so many &quot;strategic consultants&quot; that they can&#39;t even remember them. They should cherish their famous products. If you don’t want to be fooled, don’t let others use it to fool others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“双11”当天全国快递业务量达6.39亿件，是平日的1.87倍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260454]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 10:58:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Monitoring data from the State Post Bureau show that from November 1 to 11, 2023, postal express delivery companies across the country collected a total of There were 5.264 billion express parcels, a year-on-year increase of 23.22%, and the average daily business volume was 1.4 times the usual business volume. On November 11, a total of 639 million express parcels were received, which was 1.87 times the daily business volume and a year-on-year increase of 15.76%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bian Zuodong, deputy director of the Market Supervision Department of the State Post Bureau, said that this year’s peak season for express delivery business mainly presents two peaks, which are more stable, supporting consumption recovery, economic improvement, and user experience is more convenient. Big features. This year&#39;s express business peak season will continue to form two peaks on November 1 and November 11, sharing the pressure of the industry at a single peak and making the operation more stable. Postal express delivery is deeply integrated with e-commerce, modern agriculture, modern manufacturing, etc. During the &quot;Double 11&quot; period, the entire network&#39;s collection volume hit a record high, reflecting the vitality of my country&#39;s consumer market and a vivid portrayal of the economic recovery. Postal express delivery is deeply integrated into the e-commerce industry chain. A large number of pre-sale goods are pre-stored in the express cloud warehouse, making delivery services faster and more accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that this year’s express delivery business peak season will start on November 1 and end on the eve of the Spring Festival in 2024. In order to do a good job in ensuring service during peak seasons, the State Post Bureau has formulated a guarantee plan based on full situation analysis and service capability assessment with major e-commerce platforms and delivery companies, and comprehensively deployed and implemented it, coordinating e-commerce platforms and delivery companies to continue to play &quot; The core mechanism of &quot;staggered shipment and balanced promotion&quot;. At the same time, we will carry out in-depth investigation and rectification of potential safety hazards to ensure production safety, delivery safety, and information security in an all-round way, and prevent casualties in the industry; adhere to the standardization, recycling, reduction, and harmlessness of express packaging, and encourage e-commerce express shipments to be sent directly with original packaging , Reduce excessive front-end packaging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During peak business seasons and under low-temperature, rainy and snowy weather conditions, front-line couriers work for long hours, with heavy loads and high pressure. To this end, the postal management department continues to strengthen the care and care work of grassroots employees, safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the courier group, and issues consumer tips, calling on users to give more tolerance and understanding to the courier group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[圣药丨本草物色]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260208]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/2fb4OeDpmkRFUzm2iHSIuYWuvkT2mgksjEEbRgMo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2fb4OeDpmkRFUzm2iHSIuYWuvkT2mgksjEE bRgMo. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257540&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Boiled donkey hide gelatin. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donkey-hide gelatin, known as the &quot;Three Treasures&quot; along with ginseng and deer antlers, has unquestionable unparalleled popularity. It is widely rumored that the famous doctor Ye Tianshi, who once used Wutong leaves as a medicine introduction, said that donkey-hide gelatin is a product of flesh and blood and is the most nourishing. The so-called products of flesh and blood, that is, animal medicine, were highly regarded by Ye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donkey-hide gelatin is the glue produced in Adi, and the named region is a classic label for authentic medicinal materials. Tao Hongjing broke the topic: It came out of Dong&#39;e, so it was named donkey-hide gelatin. Li Shizhen refined and extended: Ajing is located sixty miles northeast of today&#39;s Yanggu County, Yanzhou Prefecture, Shandong Province, which is the ancient Dong&#39;a County. There are official residences that prohibit it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talented scholar Cao Zhi moved to fiefdoms many times during his lifetime, and Dong&#39;a was his last stop before King Chen. After his death, he was buried in the local Yushan in accordance with his last wishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called official residence prohibits it, which reveals the qualification of donkey-hide gelatin as an official tribute tribute. There is a &quot;Shui Jing Zhu&quot; that can be endorsed: (Dong&#39;e) On the west side of the north gate of the big city, there is a big well on Gao Shang. It is as big as a wheel and six or seven feet deep. It is used to cook glue every year and pay tribute to the heaven. &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; calls donkey hide gelatin. Therefore, it has the name of Ajing in the secular world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Shizhen&#39;s description, the Ajing water used for cooking glue was injected with Jishui. Use it to boil glue, and use it to stir the turbid water to make it clear. Therefore, Geji water is clear and heavy, and its nature tends to be downward. The so-called heavyness lies in the richness of minerals it contains. It is said that each pound of Ajing water is about 3 pounds heavier than ordinary well water and river water. It seems that boiling glue is like making wine, and living water with natural texture plays a considerable role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; mentioned by Li Daoyuan is the &quot;Shen Nong&#39;s Materia Medica&quot;. The origin of &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; is recorded in it, which shows the antiquity of donkey-hide gelatin production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the raw material of boiled glue, &quot;Famous Doctors&quot; says that it is made from boiled cowhide. In other words, donkey-hide gelatin in this era was originally cowhide. Li Shizhen pointed out that those using cow, buffalo and donkey skins were the top ones, followed by those using pig, horse, mule and ostrich skins, and those using various old skins, shoes and other items were the bottom. Most of the ancient recipes used cowhide, but later generations used donkey skin. As for the reason for this change, Chen Zangqi explained that all kinds of glues are mainly responsible for wind, antidiarrheal, and tonifying deficiency, and donkey skin is the most important for wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the replacement of cattle and donkeys should also be related to the fact that cattle are the main livestock power in farming and even military resources, so they are strictly controlled by the government. Qin law had strict laws that stipulated that those who killed cows and horses would die. Although later dynasties no longer required beheading, they still had to bear criminal responsibility. For example, Tang law stipulated that even if you kill your own cattle, you will be sentenced to one year in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The donkey, with its trimmed tail and drooping back, and its giant ears and two gongs, is regarded by the Central Plains people as a rare animal of the Xiongnu. According to Gu Yanwu&#39;s &quot;Rizhilu&quot;, since the Qin Dynasty and above, donkeys have not been seen in written records, even if they exist. Be an unusual animal. &quot;The donkey is an object. It was named after the Han Dynasty. It was filial to the martial arts and found its way into the forest. It was filial and spiritual and was honored. However, its species mostly came from outside the fortress.&quot; Probably during the Han Dynasty, donkeys &quot;entered the fortress with their tails attached.&quot; &quot;They are all our animals.&quot; From the appreciation of Shanglin&#39;s strange beasts, they can be used as livestock for transportation. They are resistant to extensive diseases and easy to drive. They are strong in disease resistance and have early maturity and longevity. They also win in the cost-effectiveness trade-off and win the favor of both the government and the private sector. The poet&#39;s descriptions of &quot;riding a donkey into the sword gate in the drizzle&quot; and &quot;the poetry of the sky and the sea are carried on the back of a donkey&quot; vaguely reveal the relationship between donkeys and literati. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to the use of donkey skin as medicine, it should be after its mass breeding. In addition to the use of donkeys for servitude, eating meat and sleeping on their hides is an appropriate meaning in the title, and tanning and making rubber are also included in the title. As for the uses of glue, Tao Hongjing pointed out that there are three types of glue: clear and thin glue used by painters; clear and thick glue called potting glue and used for medicinal purposes; turbid and black glue not used for medicine, but can be used to glue things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called donkey skin is the most popular, which is the conclusion of the Tang Dynasty. As late as the Northern Song Dynasty, the donkey hide gelatin made from black donkey skin and boiled in well water was recognized as the best. In the view of strict medical practitioners, outside Dong&#39;a, there is only donkey gelatin but no donkey-hide gelatin. However, due to the exclusivity of tributes and the official ban on Ajing, ceiling-level real glue is extremely rare. Most of the goods sold among the people are forged horsehide, old leather, saddle boots, etc., which smell foul and cannot be used as medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although counterfeit medicines have been condemned, they have never disappeared. As a doctor with a benevolent heart, Li Shizhen is considerate and considerate. The yellow color is as transparent as amber, or the light and black color is as black as lacquer. The true one does not have stinky skin, and the summer moon is not wet and soft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prototype of Mr. Bai Qiye, played by Mr. Chen Baoguo in the drama &quot;The Mansion Gate&quot;, is Le Jingyu, the young master of Tongrentang. Mr. Lelao came to Jinan that year and founded Hongjitang. The donkey-hide gelatin he produced was known as the Nine Tips and Nine Roasts: peeling off the hair at the winter solstice, starting from the awakening of the stings, using copper pots and silver shovels, burning mulberry firewood, nine tips and nine moxibustions, and taking the ointment at nine days. There are ninety-nine processes, complicated but not many. The vernal equinox is exposed to the sun and the beginning of summer becomes glue. This is the path of Gongjiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shizhen’s explanation is more concise: When making all kinds of glue, from October to February or March... all raw skins are taken, soaked in water for four or five days, washed and scraped extremely clean. Boil, stir it from time to time, and add water constantly. When it is rotten, filter the juice and boil it into glue, pour it into a pot and wait for it to solidify. The glue that is close to the pelvic floor is called jiaojiao, and the glue that is salty and bitter is better when fried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the time line of glue making, &quot;Qi Min Yao Shu&quot; also said that it takes February, March, September and October to cook glue, and the remaining months are not enough. The reason why it is not successful is that if it is hot, it will not coagulate, and it will not make cakes; if it is cold, it will freeze and become sticky, and the glue will not stick. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is the preparation complicated, but also the preparation of the medicine is quite difficult. Tao Hongjing said: Whatever is used, it must be burned with fire. Lei Jiao, known as Thunder God, said: For any use, first soak it in pig fat overnight, take it out, dry it with willow wood and grind it before use. Li Shizhen divided and conquered it: the current method is to stir-fry pearls, stir-fry with flour, stir-fry, stir-fry with clam powder, stir-fry with grass ash, turn into ointment with wine, or hydrate the ointment, each should be based on its own prescription. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most famous effect of donkey-hide gelatin is to harmonize blood, nourish yin, remove wind and moisturize dryness. As Li Shizhen said, donkey-hide gelatin basically only replenishes blood and fluids, so it can clear the lungs, nourish yin and cure various syndromes. In addition, he pointedly mentioned that dysentery is often caused by excessive heat, and donkey-hide gelatin is an important medicine for the large intestine. Those with heat and toxin retention can be relieved; those without heat and toxin retention can be safe. From this, he regarded donkey-hide gelatin as a holy medicine and made it a god. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This classic classifies donkey-hide gelatin as a top-grade medicine, that is, it is a royal medicine that &quot;maintains life and responds to the sky, is non-toxic, and does not hurt people if taken for a long time.&quot; Although not all top-quality products are the best, donkey-hide gelatin is indeed comparable to ginseng and licorice, and is worthy of its god-like existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安机关公开通缉缅北果敢自治区电信网络诈骗犯罪集团重要头目明学昌、明国平、明菊兰、明珍珍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260458]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 11:12:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Currently, the situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar is severe, the social harm is serious, and the people have reacted strongly. Investigation by the Wenzhou City Public Security Bureau in Zhejiang Province revealed that Ming Xuechang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen are important leaders of a criminal group involved in telecommunications network fraud in the Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar. The criminal group headed by Ming Xuechang has organized and opened fraud for a long time. The den is open to armed fraud and carries out telecommunications and network fraud criminal activities targeting Chinese citizens. The amount of fraud is huge. Under the severe and high-pressure situation of the public security organs, it still does not restrain or stop, and continues to organize and carry out illegal and criminal activities. At the same time, it is suspected of intentional homicide. , intentional injury, illegal detention and other serious violent crimes, the circumstances are extremely bad and the consequences are extremely serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been found that the criminal facts of Ming Xuechang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen are clear and the evidence is conclusive. The Wenzhou Municipal Public Security Bureau of Zhejiang Province has decided to issue a public reward for their arrest. The public security organs urged the four criminal suspects Ming Xuechang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen to recognize the situation clearly, step back from the brink, voluntarily surrender themselves, and strive for leniency. At the same time, we hope that all walks of life and the general public will actively report the crime and assist in the arrest of criminal suspects. For those who provide effective clues and assist in arrests, the public security organs will reward RMB 100,000 to RMB 500,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/UqJ0oPL9FmeNfZXTGzKDetP4S9YwiER5nzweN11E.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height= &quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/UqJ0oPL9FmeNfZXTGzKDetP4S9YwiER5nzweN11E.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0UqEd83ptsiPSLyHQF2FwQgTl0WWin9CYMduHlQK.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0UqEd83ptsiPSLyHQF2FwQgTl0WWin9CYMduHlQK.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/ctLXwsz1T06nEjNSwQzzRA7OzcOlWR1HqUU45BMM.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/12/ctLXwsz1T06nEjNSwQzzRA7OzcOlWR1HqUU45BMM.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/12/i056fcAa0u8aVFd1wraLjlR5IVKJxPD9uk9lUrN0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/i056fcAa0u8aVFd1wraLjlR5IVKJx PD9uk9lUrN0. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257999&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[温州市永嘉县桥头镇一民房坍塌，4人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260448]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 09:33:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to the &quot;Wenzhou Yongjia County People&#39;s Government Information Office&quot;, at noon on November 11, Yongjia County A house collapsed during renovation in Yantou Lane, Qiaotou Town, trapping four people. As of about 6:20 on the 12th, the fourth trapped person had been found and confirmed to have no vital signs. At present, the investigation into the cause of the house collapse and the aftermath are in progress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[倒卖出生证明牵出案中案，被吊销执业证书者还可以行医吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260446]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 09:00:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[歌圩上的农民运动会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260357]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/IU6vqPyyCNOJj84Sm0I6IpAzUwtJVETByd7X0n8H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/IU6vqPyyCNOJj84Sm0I6IpAz UwtJVETByd7X0n8H. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fragrant pig race April 28, 2014, Yiwei Town, Tiandong County, Guangxi&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhuang people have a tradition of worshiping gods. There are three great creation gods in their folklore. In addition to the Thunder King and the Dragon King, there is also the old man Buluotuo who knows all things. In addition, the worship of nature has also derived many objects that can be sacrificed, such as mountain gods and land gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/1iVkwdpPF7uR7KbJCyujFW4UrAg8u1HXgC9756tT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/1iVkwdpPF7uR7KbJCyujFW4UrAg8u1HXgC9756tT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257434&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Firecracker competition on April 10, 2011, Baiyu Town, Tianyang County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In order to worship the gods, people gathered together to perform ritual songs and dances. With the development of the times, the original sacrificial singing and dancing gradually turned into a group singing fair activity. During March and April of the lunar calendar, or between August and September, when the weather is suitable in spring and autumn, people put down their farm work and sing in open places. Young men and women use singing to choose their spouses, and middle-aged and elderly people compete with each other and enjoy songs. Everyone and every family can enjoy the song fair, and the large-scale national event has shifted from &quot;entertaining gods&quot; to &quot;entertaining people&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GDYjtAsOE2zGApnmHjnfaJ4JE5nRHMctRyY5jdT2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GDYjtAsOE2zGApnmHjnfaJ4JE5nRHMctRyY5jdT2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stilt walking competition on April 28, 2014, Yiwei Town, Tiandong County, Guangxi &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song fairs are generally popular in Zhuang areas. In 1983, the People&#39;s Government of the Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region made a decision to designate the third day of the third lunar month as the Zhuang Song Festival. However, in Tiandong, Tianyang and other places in Baise City, there were dozens or even hundreds of song fairs a year at their peak. In recent years, due to young people going out to work, the number of song fairs has gradually decreased. In some areas, after the old singers quit, there are no young and middle-aged singers to take over, and the song fairs can only be suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0FCrEwFra4rmiU3HYTcLRlG1AzO0FG0iiSntiKPu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0FCrEwFra4rmiU3HYTcLRlG1AzO0FG0iiSntiKPu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wrestling match on Little Tomatoes, April 4, 2017, Baiyu Town, Tianyang County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to make the song fair continue better in the present? Tiandong County, Baise City, advocates &quot;one town, one section&quot; in 10 towns in the county. This time, the festival shifted from celebrating broad festivals to focusing on its own life. The song fair is not only for singing folk songs, but also for various folk entertainment activities, such as throwing hydrangeas, touching Easter eggs, grabbing fireworks, etc. Competitiveness is secondary, but more importantly, it is interesting and attracts participation. It allows towns and villages to discover their own special activities and stimulates people&#39;s enthusiasm for participation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VthFdlQoy2VQMB9yYQIoHT6aU7PDl1PemJtLI3Hl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VthFdlQoy2VQMB9yYQIoHT6aU7PDl1PemJtLI3Hl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bare-hand corn shucking competition on March 11, 2012, Naman Town, Tianyang County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yiwei Town is rich in fragrant pigs. Since 2014, the town has held fragrant pig races at the Gewei in the third month of the lunar calendar. The fragrant pig runs in front, and the owner leads it behind with a rope. The pigs just ran, but the people were much more excited. The audience&#39;s shouts and laughter flooded the whole street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tiandong County is the hometown of mangoes in China. Xiangzhou Town, where large-scale mango planting is carried out, came up with a mango-themed competition. Women used spoons to hold the mangoes, transport them back and forth, and first remove all the mangoes in the baskets. The one who reaches the finish line wins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AiLlc8Dxd1Dsn9JkuwvuFGbBLYfoMQktFnwZB7qu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AiLlc8Dxd1Dsn9JkuwvuFGbBLYfoMQktFnwZB7qu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257437&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gyro playing competition on March 17, 2014, Lihu Yao Township, Nandan County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some towns use small tomatoes as their main crops and hold tomato picking competitions. The couple picks tomatoes in a relay, and the one with the shortest time wins. The most beautiful scene is the wrestling on Little Tomato. The wrestling pool is filled with small tomatoes, and the wrestlers compete with each other. If they are not careful, they will slip on the small tomatoes and be covered in red juice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/QMw69502wrbjPndaL0P4PMLBXEo5BZF2gqd9B7Hj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/QMw69502wrbjPndaL0P4PMLBXEo5BZF2gqd9B7Hj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nose sticking competition February 8, 2016, Pingma Town, Tiandong County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the transformation of the song fair is the revitalization of rural industries. In the past, there was no industry in the village, and people left their hometowns to work. When song fairs returned along with the industry, young people returned to their hometowns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/SxEUJDkgni4wP7RSZqJbhhSuKLoaDGFs9UHaZaev.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/SxEUJDkgni4wP7RSZqJbhhSuKLoaDGFs9UHaZaev.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Women&#39;s water tug-of-war on May 1, 2016, Xinhua Town, Leye County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kQPdSkYUSNH0vrBx2gzRlDduMbOOhhXya3rF12Jm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kQPdSkYUSNH0vrBx2gzRlDduMbOOhhXya3rF12Jm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257439&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bare-handed duck snatching competition November 6, 2016, Sicheng Town, Lingyun County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/cetBGjwPMYQKSUIL4WHKKwJVpyagQMI89zUfzz6X.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/cetBGjwPMYQKSUIL4WHKKwJVpyagQMI89zUfzz6X.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257435&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wife-carrying competition March 11, 2012, Naman Town, Tianyang County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VLeCLDY8DyJjcigp0gSQxwWQLP8YzMm3l3Ym9Pom.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VLeCLDY8DyJjcigp0gSQxwWQLP8YzMm3l3Ym9Pom.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257446&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mud field volleyball match on November 11, 2017, Baihuatun, Sicheng Town, Lingyun County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/m61ybgRdMq3Gau6MvZTxDZZqmTwwlgbMKMefNpnp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/m61ybgRdMq3Gau6MvZTxDZZqmTwwlgbMKMefNpnp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257441&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Walking competition in sneakers on January 21, 2017, Nawangtun, Linfeng Town, Tiandong County, Guangxi &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xie Peixia/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/yfasEbdr89SaJp7jkLZaYKYJm6WRcLeRJ3nkrVZg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/yfasEbdr89SaJp7jkLZaYKYJm6WRcLeRJ3nkrVZg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mango themed sports meeting on August 4, 2012, Xiangzhou Town, Tiandong County, Guangxi &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xie Peixia/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/IVDTLNBebhu6MjnCi95xS4NEvs69WSDUgDuECPNa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/IVDTLNBebhu6MjnCi95xS4NEvs69WSDUgDuECPNa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Autumn Polishing Competition February 18, 2013, De&#39;e Town, Longlin County, Guangxi &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xie Peixia/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eCbF5Ir9YjDdiutet6awa1YRKQb7Ycj2LInEBhWo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eCbF5Ir9YjDdiutet6awa1YRKQb7Ycj2LInEBhWo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pole Climbing Competition January 30, 2023, Longlin County, Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xie Peixia/Picture)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[浙江温州一处楼房垮塌，有人员被困]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260440]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 22:24:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765547162&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;A building collapsed in Wenzhou, Zhejiang, and people were trapped.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/8087253e3270835011765547162/sampleSnapshot /sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/8087253e3270835011765547162/B3qOFQgNxDQA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640 &quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/8087253e3270835011765547162/B3qOFQgNxDQA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 11th, A building collapsed in Qiaotou Town, Yongjia County, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, and people were trapped. On-site rescue was underway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7abc43256d6e42c52d765584dd8e2345.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4096&quot; height=&quot;3072&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7abc43256d6e42c52d765584dd8e2345.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257960&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/28117402f14f581f61b1f25ff2928406.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;4096&quot; height=&quot;3072&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/28117402f14f581f61b1f25ff2928406.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/93b4c598e8a28f9dab0fb5722e973c0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 2737&quot; height=&quot;2128&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/93b4c598e8a28f9dab0fb5722e973c0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[甘肃平凉一小学校长奸淫多名学生被执行死刑？当地回应：属实]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 22:26:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a notice titled &quot;Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Gansu Province&quot; has attracted attention on the Internet. Zhang Longji, the principal of a primary school in Jingning County, Pingliang City, was shown raping and molesting many students in public. He was executed on November 7. On November 11, local government office staff confirmed to Nandu reporters that this notice was indeed issued by the Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court, which had previously heard the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3b8ad1bc0bbb52159853539a5c14831e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1135&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3b8ad1bc0bbb52159853539a5c14831e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257973&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Court Notice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement of Pingliang Intermediate Court, Zhang Longji, male, Han nationality, was born on February 24, 1979 in Jingning County, Gansu Province, with a university education. From 2010 to June 2019, when he served as the dean, principal and teacher of a primary school in Jingning County, he used corporal punishment and other means to form a mental coercion on primary school students who lacked sexual defense ability. He used opportunities such as explaining exercises and students to hand in homework to He repeatedly raped five young girls aged 8 to 12 in his dormitory, and molested 17 children aged 8 to 14 in public in the classroom or in his dormitory. The Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court found Zhang Longji guilty of rape and sentenced to death and deprived of political rights for life; he was found guilty of child molestation and sentenced to ten years in prison. He was punished for several crimes and decided to execute him and be deprived of political rights for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the verdict of the case was pronounced, Zhang Longji appealed, but the appeal was rejected by the Gansu Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court and the original death sentence was upheld, which was approved by the Supreme People&#39;s Court. On November 7 this year, Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court followed the execution order issued by the President of the Supreme People&#39;s Court, identified Zhang Longji, took him to the execution ground, and executed him by injection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters learned that Article 236 of the &quot;Criminal Law&quot; stipulates that anyone who rapes a girl under the age of fourteen shall be treated as rape and shall be severely punished. Anyone who rapes a woman or rapes a young girl with multiple persons, if the circumstances are abominable, or in public in a public place, shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than ten years, life imprisonment, or death. On May 25 this year, the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate jointly issued the &quot;Interpretation on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in the Handling of Criminal Cases of Rape and Molestation of Minors&quot;, reaffirming the judicial philosophy of adhering to the word &quot;strict&quot; and severe punishment. The relevant severe and aggravated punishment clauses have been further clarified and refined to ensure that the punishment is suitable for the crime, the punishment is worthy of the crime, and the punishment is sufficient to control the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次误杀，引来一次次误杀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260434]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The new Korean film &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot;, in some The plot setting is very reminiscent of Bong Joon Ho&#39;s &quot;Parasite&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/8a8a72b85cc0cbc139587fdc901c0d35.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1282&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/8a8a72b85cc0cbc139587fdc901c0d35.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257924&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;played by Kim Seo-hyung The heroine Wen Jing is a low-level domestic worker who takes care of an elderly couple with limited mobility. The latter comes from a wealthy family, and the old gentleman Li Taijiang is also a highly respected writer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an accident, Wen Jing accidentally killed the hostess. In order to cover up the truth, she took her elderly mother with dementia to the Li family, pretending to be the hostess, and planned to get away with it. At the same time, it also allows the mother who has been in the nursing home for a long time to be &quot;parasitized&quot; gracefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/eb640bc40cca98a7758e85cfccacdc9e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;486&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/eb640bc40cca98a7758e85cfccacdc9e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same disparity The two classes of &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot; and &quot;Parasite&quot; also involve the sharp social topic of &quot;parasitism&quot;, but the human background and expression concepts of &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot; and &quot;Parasite&quot; are completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Parasite&quot; is about the struggle between evil and evil. Neither the Pu family, who is in the upper class, nor the Jin family, who is the lower class, is a good opponent. The Pu family are polite on the surface, but in fact they regard the Jin family as servants and ants, and dislike their &quot;strange smell&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/a679d19de46b185c21598113a7968e1b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/a679d19de46b185c21598113a7968e1b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金家看He seems pitiful, but he is very good at trying to flatter people. He relies on his cleverness and pretense to obtain better living conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, the Park and Jin families both live under the law of the jungle, but one is grabbing profits from the open side, and the other is picking up leftovers in the dark. They are two incompatible factions, hostile to each other and never sincere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/436e5a804ed3734422f69bb5544669d8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/436e5a804ed3734422f69bb5544669d8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Plastic Greenhouse &quot;Different, the film never reveals the snobbishness of the Li family from beginning to end. On the contrary, Li Taijiang cares deeply about Wen Jing. No matter in terms of attitude or treatment, no one can find any fault. The same goes for Wen Jing. She doesn&#39;t covet or hate the old couple of the Li family. Although the old lady often behaves inappropriately towards Wen Jing because of Alzheimer&#39;s disease, she can always repay evil with kindness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Jing accidentally killed the old lady, which was purely accidental. She did not call the police and surrender because she wanted her son to have a complete family after he was released from prison; the reason why she took her mother to the Li family for &quot;parasitism&quot; was not for gain, but because Wen Jing, as a &quot;stupid person&quot;, was the safest thing she could think of. A way to cover up the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e1b4e2f73fd7691d777ffc33dcc4e323.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e1b4e2f73fd7691d777ffc33dcc4e323.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257926&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Full movie Looking at it, you will find that this is a silent killing between &quot;good and good&quot;. They do not hate each other, but they slip into the quagmire of sin by accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Wen Jing kills the old lady, the film is attached to the dark absurdity of the Coen brothers, and the plot is full of ups and downs, making people caught off guard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Wen Jing was disposing of the old lady&#39;s body, Li Taijiang went home, but due to his blindness, he could not see his dead wife&#39;s body on the floor. As a result, Li Taijiang was humming a ditty leisurely while cleverly missing Wen Jing and his deceased wife. This scene arrangement revealed a hint of thrilling and a hint of paradoxical absurdity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ed9007d788d0b02592c3f1a292fb9e63.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;453&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ed9007d788d0b02592c3f1a292fb9e63.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257927&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following plot , similar bizarre plots were staged one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blind Li Taijiang became more and more suspicious of the &quot;wife&quot; next to him, especially when he touched the latter&#39;s hands and face, he became more convinced of his suspicions and called an old friend to identify and confirm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My old friend didn’t take Li Taijiang’s suspicion seriously. Firstly, it was too outrageous to suddenly suspect that the person next to him was not his wife; secondly, Li Taijiang also suffered from Alzheimer&#39;s disease, and it was normal to be inaccurate in recognizing people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/b7e45b737e959efb6d8eb6dba6dda637.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/b7e45b737e959efb6d8eb6dba6dda637.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257932&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this premise Next, Wen Jing escaped another disaster. But can she always have good luck and survive until Li Taijiang&#39;s death, relying on her old mother&#39;s replacement? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ending was unexpected again. Li Taijiang suddenly came to his wife&#39;s room, strangled the sleeping &quot;wife&quot; by the throat, and eventually strangled her to death. He himself hanged himself in the bathroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sudden double death has already been explained clearly in Michael Haneke&#39;s masterpiece &quot;Amour&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/865919357072f605e6e51c99884b3b0f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/865919357072f605e6e51c99884b3b0f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257929&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old writers cannot Taking care of his deceased wife, he could not face the gradual dementia in his old age. In order to prevent the dignity of his life from collapse, he decided to die with his wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Taijiang never imagined until his death that his wife had already died in Wen Jing&#39;s hands; and what Wen Jing also didn&#39;t expect was that his old mother would become the hostess&#39;s &quot;scapegoat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gears of death did not stop. Wen Jing’s son, whom Wen Jing missed so much, was released from prison early. However, the latter and a group of teenagers came to the plastic greenhouse where they used to live, drinking and talking nonsense. What they didn&#39;t know was that there was a corpse hidden in the cabinet of the greenhouse. This corpse was Li Taijiang&#39;s late wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2969590142efb878d9fdebbe840a1fc6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2969590142efb878d9fdebbe840a1fc6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Jing came suddenly He went to the shed and planned to destroy the body and eliminate traces of it. Wen Jing&#39;s son and his friends hid in order to avoid Wen Jing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the gasoline was poured on the greenhouse, it quickly caught fire. Wen Jing finally breathed a sigh of relief. She thought that after destroying the evidence, she would be ushered in a new life, but what she didn&#39;t know was that her son was hiding inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot; is very meaningful. On the surface, it points to the plastic greenhouse in the wasteland where Wen Jing ended up, but its deeper meaning is a mixture of Wen Jing&#39;s kindness and evil, her tragedy and the death she caused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/fc74edd0909394f1dafc9bf6d83a9c30.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/fc74edd0909394f1dafc9bf6d83a9c30.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257931&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first feature film The curtain is a plastic greenhouse in the dusk, like a huge coffin, making people unable to breathe. Crows flying through the sky add to the atmosphere of death, while the gloomy color of the sky makes it difficult to tell whether it is the morning light that symbolizes hope or the dark night that represents despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this plastic greenhouse, Wenjing accepted a girl with the same fate, Chunnan, and temporarily escaped the harm of her sexual predator; but it was also here that Wenjing tore away the scars of Chunnan’s past. , sprinkle salt on its wounds. Not to mention, Wen Jing hid and destroyed corpses in this greenhouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d39cd3457c0176fc3e5e0b374c75ffaf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;449&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d39cd3457c0176fc3e5e0b374c75ffaf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257930&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, Li Cangdong&#39;s &quot;Burning&quot; uses the action of the rich to &quot;burn down their warehouses&quot; to show the tragedy and anger of the lower class and the arrogance and indifference of the upper class. Then, in &quot;Plastic Shed&quot;, &quot;burning the barn&quot; is replaced with another symbolic meaning: the person in the film is driven by the subconscious to take revenge on the entire society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why it is said to be subconscious is that, as mentioned above, we have never seen Wen Jing&#39;s humble anger, nor have we glimpsed Li Taijiang&#39;s superiority. They are so harmonious that it is hard to believe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/131b5d3e8d52c620c2598b92b46145e5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/131b5d3e8d52c620c2598b92b46145e5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Plastic Greenhouse 》The most interesting part is this. It constantly uses editing techniques to cover up part of the truth and hide the true emotions of several characters, making us think about what caused this series of tragedies. We can only watch as the gears of their fate begin to turn and slide step by step into the abyss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This can&#39;t help but remind people of the Korean film &quot;The Next So Hee&quot; that caused a lot of discussion in the first half of the year. In this movie, how did So Hee, who was lively and optimistic by nature, lead to suicide step by step? This becomes the question that detective Wu Youzhen keeps searching for in the second half of the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the school where she graduated to the company where she worked, from her native family to the social environment, Wu Youzhen discovered that it was not a certain person who &quot;killed&quot; So Hee, but the entire Korean society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7ca121b2f95e1fa4be552b9b0d8e0e08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7ca121b2f95e1fa4be552b9b0d8e0e08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257934&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Plastic Greenhouse &quot;In &quot;Chun Nan&quot;, a mentally retarded girl was abandoned by her mother since she was a child. The inaction of welfare institutions left her pathologically dependent on sexual predators; the upper-class writer Li Taijiang gave up the desire to live due to the torture of the disease. Heading towards a tragic death; the heroine is quiet and simple, but she eventually becomes a murderer and destroys all traces of her body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These characters in the film obviously just long for a touch of warmth and freedom, but in the rigid system, their humanity is distorted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c6b5027565afc4d9f42fce6a3aa9060f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c6b5027565afc4d9f42fce6a3aa9060f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a new director Lee Sol Hee&#39;s debut film did not cause much response in South Korea. It only had a score of 7.1 on Douban and only a few viewers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But whether it is its completion or the expression of the theme, it is calm, powerful and well organized. In the generally sluggish momentum of Korean movies this year, it is a niche masterpiece that should not be missed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:25:14 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[裴宜理：研究中国革命，如此复杂，如此迷人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260431]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/i8KBYscFjFPs8YglDmRNV4A1OQY9MjMa33O656xl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/i8KBYscFjFPs8YglDmRNV4A1OQY9M jMa33O656xl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pei Yili looking at files in Jiangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（ Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among American scholars who study China, Elizabeth Perry has a special life experience: she was born in Shanghai in 1948, and her parents were both Shanghai Saints. Professor at John&#39;s University, but her family left China shortly after she was born due to changes in the current situation. She later joked that maybe she had been closely associated with the word &quot;revolution&quot; since she was born, so she has been interested in the Chinese revolution throughout her life. &quot;Without the revolution, I would probably have grown up in China. I have always been curious about the Chinese revolution, and wanted to know why the revolution happened and what consequences it would bring to China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili also spent his youth in China. She survived the surging global &quot;revolutionary&quot; wave of the left-wing movement, which further strengthened her future academic ambitions. After China&#39;s door opened, she became one of the first foreign scholars allowed to enter China for fieldwork and research. Her research interests mainly focus on modern popular resistance and grassroots politics, spanning the fields of political science and history. She has written Generous and award-winning, the American Historical Review commented that she &quot;combines a social scientist&#39;s love of order with a historian&#39;s eye for great stories.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili has taught at the University of Arizona, the University of Washington and the University of California, Berkeley. Since 1997, he has taught in the Department of Government of Harvard University. In addition to her teaching work, one of Pei Yili&#39;s greatest characteristics lies in her participation in public affairs. She once served as the director of the Fairbank Research Center at Harvard University and the president of the Association for Asian Studies. Since 2008, she has served as the president of the Harvard-Yenching Institute, cultivating a group of outstanding students and scholars for China studies. Our interview took place in the office of the Harvard-Yenching Institute. The office is small, and the black-and-white photos that mark important moments of this academic institution in the past century hung on the wall exude a deep sense of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Since I became president, I have spent half of my time at Harvard-Yenching Institute and the other half as a professor at Harvard.” Pei Yili is still active in teaching, every Wednesday at 1:30 p.m. At 3:30, she is open to students. Each student had to make an appointment with her in advance and explain their questions succinctly. After learning that she had given me more than three hours of interview time, her students all expressed their envy that I had such a &quot;luxury&quot; opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili has a hearty personality and is quick to talk. During the interview, he burst out laughing from time to time. Even if he fell into a gloomy look when recalling the twists and turns of his family&#39;s experiences, he would immediately ignore this emotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China has undergone too many changes in the past hundred years. This may be what attracts Pei Yili, a political scientist who studies China. &quot;Studying their successes and failures is exciting and fascinating.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/QbYnyZoZXxiMPOUMUeZHcmbriNWr2fsheyj1zA8Q. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/QbYnyZoZXxiMPOUMUeZHcmbriNWr2fsheyj1zA8Q.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pei Yili&#39;s parents&#39; wedding photo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Birth under revolutionary fire&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Were you born in China?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&quot;Why were you born in Red China?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the time I was a girl, for a long time, every time I followed the whole family back to the United States, whether at the airport or the dock, Immigration After the officer opened her passport, there was always a conversation like the one above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I would say that when I was born it was not red, just a little pink.” More than half a century later, Pei Yili was sitting in his office at the Harvard-Yenching Institute, recalling the past and couldn’t help but He let out a hearty laugh. Then, her expression became solemn. &quot;Yes, my parents both lived in troubled times in China; without the revolution, I would probably have grown up in China, so our family does have constant ties with China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili was born in a He has a strong religious family, and his parents are both missionaries of the Episcopal Church. Her father, Charles Perry - Pei Yili later learned that his Chinese name was Pan Xuesi - had studied Chinese and Japanese at Harvard University in his early years and had a special liking for East Asia. In 1931, Pan Xuesi traveled across the ocean and arrived in Shanghai to teach at St. John&#39;s University. St. John&#39;s University was founded in 1879, formerly known as St. John&#39;s College. It is sponsored by the Episcopal Church in the United States and is the earliest church university in China. After the September 18th Incident broke out, Pan Xuesi made a special trip to Northeast China. &quot;He also wrote a very interesting diary about his travel experience in Manchuria. He was very interested in this period of history.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Pan Xuesi met his future wife Kai Rui (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Note: the Chinese name is Kong Kaili&lt;/span>;) in China. Both later taught at St. John&#39;s University. Interestingly, Pei Yili never heard his parents communicate in Chinese when he was a child, &quot;because his father only knew Mandarin and his mother only knew Shanghainese.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mEjKBtDqsDC3yeb1YmoZRw1ZwdF5aOBW6lYCyaBM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;672&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/08/mEjKBtDqsDC3yeb1YmoZRw1ZwdF5aOBW6lYCyaBM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bae Yi-ri and her father as a girl&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili’s parents got married in the summer of 1937. Because Pan Xuesi has been interested in Japanese culture for a long time, he chose to go to Japan for his honeymoon. &quot;When they were on their honeymoon, they heard the news about Japan&#39;s invasion of China, but they didn&#39;t dare to confirm it, so they went to the U.S. Embassy in Tokyo to ask whether the rumors were true. The embassy staff may not want to take responsibility and did not tell them the truth. They just said : No, there is no problem in China now. You can go back to China! So they boarded the ship from Nagasaki back to Shanghai as originally planned.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili said that his father liked water sports when he was young and was very fond of boats. The performance is very clear. Not long after their ship left Japanese port, my father became acutely aware that something was not quite right. He said to his wife: &quot;Strange, why is the waterline of the ship so low?&quot; He ran to the bottom to find out what was going on, and found that the bottom was full of Japanese soldiers with live ammunition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the soldiers Pei Yili&#39;s parents met back then were the regiments that had been reinforced from Japan after the Battle of Songhu began - they inadvertently became witnesses of history. As soon as these soldiers on the same ship arrived in Shanghai, they joined the war of aggression against China and became a link in the brutal machine. What awaited the young couple who returned from their honeymoon was Shanghai burned by the war. &quot;My mother later recalled that when the ship entered Shanghai, she could smell the smell of dead people everywhere. This was something she had never experienced...&quot; The parents returned to their residence at St. John&#39;s University and discovered that they were married. The chapel has been attacked by the Japanese army, the home has been ransacked, and all the wedding gifts have been stolen by Japanese soldiers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the current situation, the mother left Shanghai and returned to the United States for a while with her newborn son, while the father chose to stay at St. John&#39;s University. In 1941, the &quot;Pearl Harbor Incident&quot; broke out, the Japanese army invaded the concession, and Shanghai fell completely. Except for those who have returned to China, the rest of the foreign teachers at St. John&#39;s University were imprisoned in concentration camps, including Pei Yili&#39;s father. He was not released back to the United States until two years later when the U.S. and Japanese governments exchanged detainees. When his grandmother picked him up at the New York port, she could no longer recognize her emaciated son. But before long, Pan Xuesi hoped to return to China again. &quot;With the help of the U.S. Navy, he returned to China as he wished and helped the National Government fight the Japanese.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1945, after World War II ended, his mother also returned to China. For this family, this was a brief peaceful time in China - Pei Yili, who was born in Shanghai in September 1948, was the fruit of this life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1949, the Chinese Communist revolution had reached a decisive moment. &quot;My mother took me and my two brothers and left China first, but my father once again wanted to stay.&quot; A few months later, the situation became even more turbulent. Pan Xuesi had no choice but to bid farewell to the country where he had lived on and off for 18 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to the United States, Pan Xuesi returned to the university where he once studied and taught for several years, but the distant East has always been a place he has never forgotten. In 1951, their family moved to Tokyo, and Pan Xuesi taught at Rikkyo University, founded by the Anglican Church. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Thanksgiving night in 1959, the whole family was sitting together to eat and celebrate this traditional American holiday. Suddenly, they heard the dog barking in the yard. My father went out to check, but an accident happened unexpectedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two young Japanese students came in drunk. They both practiced karate... It only took a few minutes to beat my father to death... There was no plan to attack me. My father&#39;s, they were completely drunk at the time and didn&#39;t know who my father was.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This American, who had a strong interest and concern for the East throughout his life, ended his life in a sad way life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her father died, her mother used her understanding of the world to deal with the tragedy - although her way of handling it may not be understood by most people: instead of asking for a heavy sentence for the two Japanese students, she Instead, he interceded for them. As a result, one of them was released and the other was sentenced. During his sentence, his mother not only visited him frequently, but also went to the court to fight for a commutation of his sentence. The young man only stayed in prison for two or three years before regaining his freedom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother and her family lived in Japan for several more years until they returned to the United States in 1962. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/5p8loEN1xkHBDkKV03QuMmhVUAu8H61h4WBf7px0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/5p8loEN1xkHBDkKV03QuMmhVUAu8H61h4WBf7px0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1981, Pei Yili took a photo with the interviewee in Songjiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;Political Awareness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Popular protests were one of her later academic interests and directions. Her initial perceptual understanding of this came from her early experience in Japan. In the early 1950s, the Communist Party of Japan and the Socialist Party of Japan would organize labor protests every May Day. That day, Pei Yili&#39;s father happened to pass by. When the protesters saw the American, they started knocking on his car window. The car was surrounded by crowds... After his father returned home, his family found that almost all the car windows were broken, and The shocked father was almost shaking. After calming down, the father tried to explain to his daughter what &quot;May Day&quot; was and what those people were protesting... This made little Pei Yili become very interested in this form of popular protest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 11, 1960, nearly 6 million Japanese took to the streets to protest against the new Japan-US security treaty. The US Embassy in Japan was surrounded by nearly 200,000 Japanese protesters. Among this huge crowd of protesters was 12-year-old Pei Yili. She skipped school, took to the streets, and participated in demonstrations against the Japan-US security treaty. In Pei Yili&#39;s understanding, the essence of this event is not &quot;anti-American&quot; but in support of peace. &quot;People seem to be very happy to have an American child participating.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a sense, this is her The first time she participated in a &quot;mass movement&quot; was also the first time she experienced the power of mass movements - the bulletproof car in which the then US Ambassador to Japan Hagerty was also surrounded by demonstrators, and the ambassador himself had to sneak in through the back door. Eisenhower, who was scheduled to visit Japan on June 19, had to postpone his visit indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a child, Pei Yili also curiously observed that in some protests, the expressions of the people were very similar to the rituals of celebrating religious festivals. For example, during religious festivals in Japan - similar to China, people will take part in a procession with a sedan chair in which a god sits and then moves around in a kind of snake dance. &quot;I liked this kind of ritual so much that I often attended Japanese folk festivals in our neighborhood. Part of my interest in political protest in Japan also came from this kind of folk ritual.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This early experience, later It became a unique perspective for her to observe political activities. For example, during her investigation into Anyuan, Jiangxi, one of the birthplaces of the Chinese revolution, she discovered how Li Lisan wisely used traditional techniques to achieve the purpose of mobilizing workers to participate in the revolution: On May 1st, International Labor Day, Li Lisan organized a workers&#39; march. &quot;In the procession, there was a large sedan carried by eight people. Generally speaking, in this kind of local celebration, the sedans are carried by the gods of the earth and other folk religions, but this time, inside the sedan was a statue of Marx. Like.&quot; This detail was used by Pei Yili to analyze the relationship between national political mobilization and traditional culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1965, 16-year-old Pei Yili entered William Smith College. She was quickly thrust into another turbulent political environment. Pei Yili later concluded: &quot;Although my intuitive interest in popular protest comes from my experience in Japan, my left-wing thoughts come more from my college days.&quot; She was very active in college and participated in sailing clubs, drama clubs, Political Club...but &quot;politics&quot; was her more enduring interest and more devoted concern. She remembers riding the bus to Washington with college classmates to march in front of the Pentagon to protest the Vietnam War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also during this time that the seemingly weak connection between her and China, where she was born, became stronger in some way. William Smith College is small, but it has a &quot;Mao Zedong Thought Study Group&quot;, of which Pei Yili is a member. She studied Mao Zedong Thought with her classmates and developed a strong interest in Chinese politics. Soon, she became determined to learn Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there were no Chinese classes at her university, so she could only start learning Chinese by herself with the help of a tape recorder and a few tapes in the library. She asked the school if she could get credits for self-study in Chinese. The school’s answer: We don’t have Chinese classes, how can we evaluate your learning level and give you credits? Unwilling to give up easily, Pei Yili proposed to the school: &quot;If I learn by myself to a certain extent, I can ask a Cornell professor to test me. If I pass, can I get credits?&quot; The school had no choice but to agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili later contacted a professor at Cornell University, who said: You should study by yourself for three months through tapes and language books, and then come to Cornell to take my test. Three months later, Pei Yili successfully passed the exam. Interestingly, she later went to Taipei to study Chinese for a period of time. The Chinese teacher in Taipei grew up in Beijing. She was very surprised by the American student’s accent. One time she couldn’t help but ask: “Where does your accent come from?” Are you here? Is your teacher in the United States from the Northeast?&quot; &quot;I deny it. I want to say that my teacher is a &#39;recorder&#39; and not a Northeastern, but at that time I didn&#39;t know how to say the word &#39;recorder&#39;!&quot; Recalling this incident , Pei Yili was overjoyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese name &quot;Pei Yili&quot; was given while studying in Taipei. Much later, when she was looking at her father&#39;s book and saw the Chinese stamp on it, she discovered that her father&#39;s Chinese name was &quot;Pan Xuesi&quot;. &quot;So my surname should be Pan instead of Pei.&quot; Speaking of this matter, Pei Yili showed a trace of regret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WA5K5OwMwAXvSYgB2p4r65LJ0k64mD4kkdoi24OA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WA5K5OwMwAXvSYgB2p4r65LJ0k64mD4kkdoi24OA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pursuit The Origin of the Chinese Revolution&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When he was studying for a doctorate in political science at the University of Michigan, Pei Yili&#39;s original idea was to use China&#39;s &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; as the topic of his doctoral thesis, but he was opposed by a supervisor. The teacher thinks the time is not yet ripe. She instead determined to explore the origins of the Chinese revolution using perspectives and methods that were different from the prevailing views at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“How to understand the peasant revolution is an issue that has been ignored by many scientific scholars who pay attention to peasant issues.” When explaining the motivation for her research, she said, “Peasants entered world history in the face of revolution. This fact of the stage has fueled the development of many social science theories that attempt to explain the causes of peasant rebellions. Anthropologists, historians, sociologists, and political scientists have all come up with their own answers to this important question.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At this time, Pei Yili has revealed her &quot;academic ambition&quot;: she decided to examine the relationship between rebels and revolutionaries through the study of a region. The plan had to be concentrated in an area that had both a tradition of peasant rebellion and a pre-1949 Communist base. She chose this area in Huaibei. Huaibei was also the center of the famous White Lotus Sect, a loose folk religious organization that launched many rebellions in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, China’s door was still locked. Like other scholars, she chose to go to the National Palace Museum in Taipei to look at archives. During this period, she also went to Japan to collect information in a library in Tokyo. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I was so young and naive at the time, and had no idea how difficult this topic was—otherwise I would never have been stupid enough to choose this direction for my thesis.” There was another hearty laugh. Although she was fortunate to receive help from many people, including several American historians who were doing research there who gave her a lot of advice, Professor Albert Feuerwerker, another famous scholar of Chinese history at the University of Michigan, was also careful She was told the location of various Ming and Qing archives, but, &quot;I had no idea that the original sources on this subject were so scattered and their types were so different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another barrier was language. Although she systematically studied Chinese, including classical Chinese, for two years when she was a graduate student, she had never received special training in reading Qing Dynasty documents like those historians from the United States. So when she saw the Qing Dynasty archives at the National Palace Museum in Taipei for the first time, she was almost overwhelmed by despair: &quot;I will never be able to understand these archives!&quot; In her reply, the instructor said in a tone that could not be flinched: &quot;You have to completely Do research on original archives, and you have to read everything.&quot; Pei Yili also knew that the instructor did not understand classical Chinese and had no idea of ​​the difficulty of reading and sorting out Ming and Qing archives, but she still followed his advice. There was no way out now. She found that after really getting into it, she was completely capable of reading those files. &quot;We can see almost all the original documents you know in Taipei back then. For example, you can take the memorial written by the governor of Guangdong and Guangxi to Xianfeng, which contains the instructions of Emperor Xianfeng, &#39;I understand.&#39; When you feel this way , it doesn’t matter how obscure the file content is.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relying on solid work, Pei Yili completed her doctoral thesis. In 1980, the monograph &quot;Rebels and Revolutionaries in North China&quot; based on the thesis was published at Stanford University. This monograph is regarded as the representative work of the third generation of overseas Chinese scholars. Pei Yili dedicated his first book to his parents, &quot;Without them, I would not be engaged in Chinese studies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/08/XDBAeBrYfBKDdVmYZ9OQbRemzezD2UyCKWonhdJJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/08/XDBAeBrYfBKDdVmYZ9OQbRemzezD2UyCKWonhdJJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Return to China&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Were you born in China?&quot; Every time I return to the United States, I enter the customs Shi&#39;s cross-examination once made Pei Yili feel like a &quot;second-class American.&quot; This scene did not change until 1972, the year President Nixon visited China. Pei Yili remembers very clearly that when she returned from a trip to Japan that year and entered the United States, as usual, the immigration officer opened her passport and asked this question as expected, and Pei Yili answered in the affirmative as usual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I was waiting for the next question: &#39;Why were you born in Red China?&#39; But unexpectedly, this time the other person&#39;s reaction was: &#39;Oh, that&#39;s amazing! Can you speak Chinese?&#39; I said : &#39;Yes, I will say a little bit.&#39; He said: &#39;Our country needs people like you.&#39; That was the first time I was happy that I was born in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中After the thaw in U.S. relations, the National Committee on Us-China Relations began to send delegations to visit China one after another. Each delegation was accompanied by a scholar who studied China to help members understand China. In June 1979, Pei Yili was selected to join the delegation of big city mayors in the United States. She visited cities such as Shanghai, Beijing, Nanjing, Guangzhou and Hangzhou, and saw the Great Wall, the Forbidden City, and the West Lake with her own eyes... She was extremely excited. &quot;I get up early every day and go to the park to talk to the local people. I like this feeling very much.&quot; But on the other hand, she felt that the China she saw was not the China that was filled with revolutionary and romantic imagination before. Pei Yili also went to Shanghai to find their old house at St. John&#39;s University, took many photos of the campus, and brought them back to the United States to show his mother. Not surprisingly, my mother was extremely shocked and also extremely sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few months later, Pei Yili came to China again. This time she was a visiting scholar and was given the opportunity to study in China for a year - she was also the first group allowed to enter China for fieldwork. One of the foreign scholars who studied it, Zhou Xirui and Huang Zongzhi came to China at the same time as her, and they later became the backbone of overseas Chinese studies. She also experienced the &quot;voucher era&quot; under the planned economy. &quot;We treated each other as comrades and often quoted Chairman Mao&#39;s quotations in debates on academic and political issues.&quot; But behind the revolutionary upsurge, she gradually discovered Another side. For example, as a foreigner, she can sit on a soft sleeper, which ordinary Chinese people cannot enjoy; there are very few restaurants open to the outside world, but &quot;visiting scholars&quot; like her can enjoy &quot;special offerings&quot; in special areas of restaurants, which ordinary Chinese people cannot enjoy. Not enough, and can&#39;t afford it. In the spring of 1980, accompanied by Professor Cai Shaoqing of Nanjing University, Pei Yili went to Anhui for her first investigation. The field visits in Guoyang and Mengcheng gave her a more personal experience of the real life in rural China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year, when Pei Yili came to Shanghai for a meeting, she met Zhang Zhongli, then president of the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences. Zhang graduated from St. John&#39;s University in his early years and happened to be her father&#39;s student at that time. After meeting, they introduced each other to the work they were doing. After hearing Pei Yili&#39;s work plan for the next book, Zhang Zhongli joked: &quot;You are from Shanghai - I saw your father holding you on campus many years ago. Why not write the story of Shanghai?&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Under Zhang Zhongli’s suggestion, since the 1990s, Pei Yili’s research focus has shifted from the distant countryside of Huaibei to the world metropolis of Shanghai, and his research focus has also changed from the study of peasant revolution issues to the study of the labor movement. She completed the monograph &quot;Shanghai Strike: A Study of Chinese Workers&#39; Politics&quot;. In this book, she also used a lot of pen and ink to write about Du Yuesheng and Huang Jinrong, figures who are no strangers to us, and explored their roles in the labor movement. Some real characters. This book won the 1993 Fairbank Medal of the American Historical Association. The American Historical Review commented that she combines &quot;a social scientist&#39;s love of order&quot; with &quot;a historian&#39;s eye for capturing exciting stories.&quot; When writing this book, Pei Yili conducted a detailed investigation and analysis of the working class involved, including British American Tobacco. When she was about to finish the book, she suddenly realized that the British American Tobacco Company&#39;s factory in Pudong was the concentration camp where her father was imprisoned. &quot;I did not expect that the object of my research was to some extent closely related to the history of my own family. So I later wrote in the first sentence of the preface to the English version of &quot;Shanghai Strike&quot;: &#39;To me For me, writing this book feels like coming home.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nmo7yEYcHen9ErQmaxrlIictm9QBHdxe28utFf3H .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nmo7yEYcHen9ErQmaxrlIictm9QBHdxe28utFf3H.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;257459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pei Yili and Nanjing University Professor Zhou Xiaohong visited the Anhui History Museum&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cannot forget the &quot;big problem&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact, both the early interest in peasant revolution and the later shift to urban workers The study of movements, those revolutions that changed the fate of countless people, has always been a major issue that Pei Yili is concerned about. In an interview, the famous historian Zhou Xirui mentioned this detail: In 2007, when Pei Yili was elected president of the Asian Studies Association, he said, &quot;We cannot forget the Chinese revolution, these big topics, and how to understand China. How did the big change happen?&quot; Zhou Xirui later gave Pei Yili one of his monographs and asked her for advice. Pei Yili wrote back to him, saying once again: &quot;We should think more about China&#39;s big problems.&quot; - This is actually Pei Yili&#39;s expectation for contemporary scholars doing Chinese studies, and it is also her constant warning to herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to academic research, Pei Yili also actively participates in public affairs and social activities. In 1999, not long after arriving at Harvard University, Pei Yili became the director of the Fairbank Center for China Studies, a major center for overseas Chinese studies. Before her name, there are a series of famous scholars such as Fairbank, Schwartz, Kong Feili, Vogel, etc. Since 2008, Pei Yili has become the head of another important academic institution-the president of the Harvard-Yenching Institute. As one of the most famous academic exchange institutions between China and the West, Harvard-Yenching has had seven presidents since its founding in 1928. From Ye Lizui, Reischauer to Du Weiming, each of them is a highly respected scholar. Pei Yili’s status and influence in the academic world are evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The focus of Pei Yili&#39;s research is &quot;Chinese Revolution&quot;, which may be a bit &quot;non-mainstream&quot; in the Western academic circles of China studies. Therefore, when she was interviewed by reporters after being elected, she also expressed her feelings: &quot;For a long time, there were only a dozen or so people in the United States who specialized in studying the Chinese revolution. In recent years, there have been more and more people studying the Chinese revolution. Mao Zedong , the &#39;Great Leap Forward&#39;, the &#39;Cultural Revolution&#39;, the Anti-Japanese War... have all become popular.&quot; She joked: &quot;Otherwise, a guy like me who studies obscure topics probably wouldn&#39;t be the new president of Harvard-Yenching!&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;After the door between China and the United States opens and China reintegrates into the world family, commercial and economic revival and prosperity may be the most obvious and direct result. But what Pei Yili feels more is its huge significance in knowledge and academic exchanges. Over the past century or so, from the Qing Empire to the Republic of China, and then to the People&#39;s Republic of China, too many changes have taken place in this land. This may be what attracted Pei Yili to study China, &quot;They are so Complex, yet so fascinating.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>