<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[1840年以来的中国与美国（中）丨倬彼云汉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259193]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp3iVUJbVg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;962&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp 3iVUJbVg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The international landscape under the &quot;containment policy&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1949, the Kuomintang retreated to Taiwan. During this period, the United States conducted an in-depth review and determined its national policy: How to prevent and block the joint front between the Soviet Union and China? How should the so-called &quot;free world&quot;, that is, Europe and the United States led by Britain and the United States, face the socialist lineup? Will countries advocating a capitalist free economy and countries pursuing a socialist planned economy coexist peacefully, or will they be in constant confrontation? This was something the U.S. government was very concerned about at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, President Truman adopted a containment policy after consulting Marshall, Eisenhower and MacArthur on the above issues. On February 22, 1946, George F. Kennan, Charge d&#39;Affaires of the U.S. Embassy in Moscow, sent the famous &quot;Long Telegram&quot; to the State Department. Kennan&#39;s suggestion established the United States&#39; plan for the postwar world: the &quot;Strategy of Containment.&quot; From the Truman era to the Nixon era, various diplomatic measures were taken in this direction. During the Nixon era, Kissinger planned the &quot;Engagement&quot; policy. However, from the overall principle, &quot;connection&quot; is only a means, trying to break out a gap in the &quot;containment&quot;. Therefore, the &quot;containment policy&quot; can be said to be the highest principle for the United States to deal with world affairs for decades. Until recently, this policy evolved into a frantic situation that was not anticipated at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back from 1947 to the present, for more than seventy years, most of the Western world has been ruled by this &quot;containment policy&quot;: the United States hopes that it should take on the role of &quot;free world&quot; and &quot;free economy&quot; defender&quot; responsibility. All possible &quot;gaps&quot; must be plugged as much as possible - extending from the North Sea to the Sea of ​​Okhotsk, and from Berlin to Sakhalin. This long front was dominated by the Soviet Union, and China, as an unspecified &quot;partner&quot; - which side China&#39;s &quot;partner&quot; status was on, was not stated in this cable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the implementation of this policy, the United States decided to use the three important figures mentioned above as the main executors. The first step was for Marshall, as Secretary of State, to preside over the &quot;Marshall Plan&quot; (officially known as the &quot;European Recovery Program&quot;) aimed at promoting European recovery, and at the same time use US dollars to assist Greece and Turkey - these two countries are The Soviet fleet entered the Mediterranean Sea from the Caspian Sea and the Black Sea. In the East, after Japan surrendered, MacArthur wanted to build Japan and South Korea into &quot;the democratic fortresses of the East&quot; and personally preside over the defense of the Eastern Front. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Truman retired, Eisenhower took over, and the three maintained this situation for decades. One of the episodes was that Truman could not stand that MacArthur &quot;would not be ordered by the king&quot; and recalled this warrior from South Korea. However, Marshall and Eisenhower faithfully implemented this policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first step of this policy in the East was that the U.S. Seventh Fleet began patrolling the Taiwan Strait, allowing Kinmen and Matsu, the two remaining bases of the Kuomintang Taiwan authorities, to be isolated on the coast of mainland China. preservation. Qingdao was originally a naval base for the US military stationed in China, but the Americans withdrew before they were actually involved in the battlefield on China&#39;s mainland. Otherwise, the US military stationed in Qingdao will echo the US military stationed in South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This decision triggered a series of changes in East Asia. The United States strengthens its bases in the Philippines and uses Japan and Ryukyu as important strongholds in the United States&#39; eastern defense line. Together with Taiwan, it forms the &quot;first island chain&quot; to contain mainland China. This policy has been maintained for a long time, implemented vigorously, and has far-reaching influence until today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the United States has refused to communicate with mainland China. Even though the &quot;Republic of China&quot; was forced to withdraw from the United Nations in 1971, the United States still maintained relations with it until 1978, when Beijing and Washington formally established diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Cold War began, defending Taiwan became one of the tasks of the United States. As far as the Taiwan authorities are concerned, without the &quot;reassurance&quot; of the United States - the United States has drawn its defense line in the Taiwan Strait - the construction of this base in Taiwan would not have been possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The grievances and grievances between Taiwan and the mainland on the other side of the Taiwan Strait cannot be resolved to this day. How will these disputes be resolved in the future? How can we &quot;reunify&quot;? How can the results of Taiwan&#39;s construction, Taiwan&#39;s talents, Taiwan&#39;s economic foundation, and the mainland&#39;s economic construction support each other? This depends on the wisdom of us Chinese people, thinking about how to take into account the Chinese blood. Of course, the DPP and I have different ideas regarding the words &quot;Chinese blood.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the two sides of the Taiwan Strait have supported each other in economic construction, and this has not stopped since the 1970s. Mainland China&#39;s economic construction is about twenty years later than Taiwan&#39;s, because it experienced thirty years of bumps caused by trying various policies. From the time when Deng Xiaoping came to power to today, the cooperation and communication between the two sides has been carried out by the Straits Affairs Committee of both sides as the &quot;bridge&quot;, and by foreign heads of state such as Lee Kuan Yew as the &quot;middleman&quot;. Before Hong Kong and Macao returned to China, they were natural points of contact between the two sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second very important thing is the institutional reform of Taiwan initiated by Chiang Ching-kuo. He declared: &quot;We, the Chiang family, will no longer be involved in politics.&quot; Later, Lee Teng-hui changed Taiwan&#39;s basic law. But paradoxically, the U.S. government continues to promise to &quot;defend Taiwan with all its strength.&quot; This statement has become a rare example in the history of international relations. People familiar with international affairs once described this arrangement as &quot;intentional ambiguity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Chinese history, from the Spring and Autumn Period to the Warring States Period, the Jin State was the de facto leader of the &quot;Five Hegemons&quot;. Jin took possession of the cognac of its ally Weiguo. The hegemony of the Jin State was already declining at that time, and its interior was eventually divided among the three families of Korea, Zhao, and Wei. Chinese history entered the &quot;Seven Heroes&quot; era of the Warring States Period. At that time, those who really had the strength to compete for hegemony were the two marginal powers, Qin and Chu. The two hegemons Wu and Yue that appeared in the gap were just short-lived. The two marginal powers, Qin and Chu, competed. In the end, Qin unified China and became the predecessor of the &quot;Chinese Empire&quot;. The process of Qin&#39;s unification of the Central Plains and the system it established actually restricted the form of the Chinese Empire for two thousand years, and it was only changed in 1911. Here, I use this example from Chinese history to foresee possible future changes in the hegemony of the United States over the past few decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the establishment of U.S. hegemony, East Asia has encountered many crises: a Korean War and two Vietnam Wars - Japan and South Korea have become de facto &quot;dependencies&quot; of the United States, and Okinawa&#39;s status has become unclear. white. And these are all the consequences of the &quot;containment policy.&quot; The United States was so hegemonic that it could do the same thing in other countries that the Jin State obtained the cognac of the Wei State - Cognac was a stronghold in the eastern half of the Central Plains at that time, and the Jin State could not command the northern half. This situation is very similar to the &quot;island chain&quot; situation in East Asia. Paradoxically, the Zhao State, which was separated from the Jin State, finally took away the Cognac. We cannot predict whether the United States will transform Taiwan into an &quot;extension&quot; of Japan and South Korea in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at the situation in Europe. After the &quot;Marshall Plan&quot;, the United States established NATO and the European Union, focusing on the three countries of Britain, France, and Germany—the past enemy Germany—to guard the heart of Europe. Decades later, the European Union now feels that the United States was there to protect them, but now the United States has become their master. The United States spent a lot of effort to defend Europe. The &quot;Marshall Plan&quot; really rebuilt a world full of flowers and flowers from the ruins. Today&#39;s Germany has a prosperous economic foundation that is different from the United States we see today - Britain and France were defeated, and Germany came up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, the United States divided Germany into two: half occupied by the West and half occupied by the Soviet Union - just like North Korea was divided into South Korea, South Vietnam and North Vietnam. Berlin is an independent city, and a &quot;Berlin Wall&quot; was built in the middle. During the first Berlin Crisis in 1948, the Soviet Union blocked Berlin. The United States airdropped food, hamburgers, hot dogs, milk, eggs and even paper and other daily necessities for several months. The planes never stopped on the runway. That&#39;s a staggering expense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 25, 1963, Kennedy gave a speech in Berlin - &quot;As a free man, I am extremely proud to say: I am a Berliner.&quot; After becoming president, Kennedy also said: We Don&#39;t forget that Churchill and our old President Roosevelt once proposed that human beings should have &quot;four freedoms.&quot; (The &quot;Atlantic Charter&quot; signed by Roosevelt and Churchill actually has two &quot;versions&quot;: one is a long &quot;treaty&quot;, and the other is a short slogan of the &quot;Four Freedoms&quot; - freedom from fear, freedom from want , freedom of speech, freedom of belief.) It is our unshirkable duty to be the guardians of the world and safeguard these &quot;four freedoms.&quot; Back then, Kennedy swore an oath based on the &quot;Four Freedoms&quot;: Our mission is long and arduous. Don’t ask what the country can do for us, ask what we can do for the country. After President Roosevelt implemented the New Deal, the country fulfilled its responsibilities to its citizens and maintained their minimum standard of living. The responsibility of our government is to realize the &quot;four freedoms&quot; on American soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These declarations are very touching, and Americans are indeed working very hard in practice. The boundaries drawn at the time still exist today - the recent conflict between Ukraine and Russia was caused by the US &quot;containment policy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I said above is to explain the cultural background of Kennan’s “containment policy”, the United States’ expectations of itself, and its efforts. From then to now, for more than seventy years, the hegemony of the United States has been presented under the discourse system of &quot;containment policy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was also the Cuban Missile Crisis. The Soviet Union wanted to set up a missile base in Cuba, but the United States would not allow it. Kennedy and Khrushchev confronted each other and refused to give in. Eventually the Soviet Union gave in and withdrew its missiles from Cuba. The United States still occupies Guantánamo Bay in Cuba and refuses to give it up until death: it is a prison without legal control. The spies and prisoners the United States interrogates here are not protected by any human rights laws and are forced to water and whip. , electric shock and other torture, and the body was thrown away after death. I often use the word &quot;paradox&quot; to describe this kind of behavior: the United States claims to safeguard the &quot;four freedoms&quot;, but in fact there is always such a &quot;scar&quot;, but it turns a blind eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, mankind’s first artificial satellite was successfully launched by the Soviet Union. The United States spent a lot of money and tried hard to maintain the balance of power in space. Finally, in 1969, during the Nixon era, American astronauts landed on the moon for the first time. The year before, 59 countries, including the United States, the Soviet Union, and the United Kingdom, jointly signed the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons. Restricting new countries from developing nuclear weapons is a good thing for the world. As for countries that already possess nuclear weapons, it is unknown whether someone will use nuclear bombs first. Until the Reagan era, the arms competition between the United States and the Soviet Union continued, and even developed to the point where satellites could be used to carry nuclear bombs into space. The United States crushed the Soviet economy with its huge space arms race. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The previous description of U.S. foreign policy in history is used as a background to illustrate that U.S. foreign policy is the most important &quot;medicine&quot; in Sino-U.S. relations and is also intended to maintain the hegemonic thinking of Western culture and &quot;Containment&quot; thoughts. This is a very important principle for us to understand the complex chess game of the world since World War II. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chinese in the United States under &quot;McCarthyism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since World War II, many Chinese students have studied in the United States, including me. We come here to study because the curriculum and equipment of American schools are among the best in the world. At this stage, the United States is indeed recruiting a large number of foreign students, and we take this opportunity to learn skills. Of course, Chinese people like to return fallen leaves to their roots. Most of the hundreds of international students who came to the United States through the &quot;Geng Geng&quot; funds in the early days returned to China, and their main jobs were either in education or industry. At that time, China&#39;s scientific and technological development was not yet mainstream, and scientific and technological talents were roughly distributed in the above two categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, with the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party, China was divided into two and the straits were blocked. This became a big problem: under the &quot;containment policy&quot; stance of the &quot;containment policy&quot;, the United States would not allow students from mainland China to They return to the mainland. The most important example is Qian Xuesen. At that time, American physics was at the forefront of the world. If China wanted to develop modern technological weapons, Qian Xuesen&#39;s participation would definitely make a contribution. I believe Qian Xuesen did his best in inventing missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;Iron Curtain&quot; began to fall, the United States began to be suspicious of &quot;left-leaning&quot; people in the United States. This incident occurred during Truman&#39;s term. &quot;McCarthyism&quot; not only wanted to block those intellectuals who chose to return to China or Eastern European countries, but also wanted to eradicate &quot;left-leaning&quot; elements in the country. The so-called &quot;left leaning&quot; is defined as &quot;liberal elements&quot; - anyone who is not &quot;right&quot; is labeled as &quot;left&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person mainly responsible for this matter is the Pacific International Society. Their surveillance network is very wide and covers all the bases for China research-Pittsburgh is okay because it is not a big base. Such a situation has made Chinese people all over the United States fearful. One day, agents from the FBI or CIA will check your correspondence and check your tax payments. Everyone was in disbelief and fearful. When I came to Pittsburgh in 1970, I saw the remnants of this phenomenon. An old overseas Chinese named Yu - he changed his name to &quot;Lin Pan&quot; when he came here because he bought the Lin family&#39;s &quot;birth certificate&quot;; our current dentist belongs to the Yu family. The old gentleman came to my office to talk. He closed the door first, then gently talked to me about their fears, and asked me in a low voice: &quot;When will this situation end?&quot; Because they have many children from their hometown who want to come out. But the &quot;Iron Curtain&quot; has dropped; there are still dozens of fellow villagers who died in foreign lands, so they have to be cremated first and wait until one day to take them back to their hometowns. Recently, Quanzi also visited the location where the ashes are stored, and there were indeed dozens of jars there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, &quot;McCarthyism&quot; was subsided, and Taiwan resumed exchanges with the United States. I returned to Taiwan in 1962 and spent the next two or three years working in the History Department of my alma mater, National Taiwan University, arranging courses according to the modern scale and direction. My main job was to liaise with academic institutions and sinologists in the United States. My supervisors are Mr. Wang Shijie, president of Academia Sinica, and Mr. Li Ji, director of the Institute of History and Philology. This job is very difficult, and many people question my position: If we go to Taiwan, will it increase the United States&#39; suspicion of me? I said: &quot;I can&#39;t answer your question, but I went back, and I have no problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until 1971, after Nixon launched &quot;ping pong diplomacy&quot; with mainland China, that there were a large number of overseas Chinese Young people and international students returned to the mainland; subsequently, a large number of international students came from the mainland as well, more than ten times more than those from Taiwan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1956, Mr. Yang Zhenning and Li Zhengdao proposed the &quot;law of non-conservation of parity&quot;; subsequently, Ms. Wu Jianxiong proved this theory through experiments - these three are world-famous physicists. Because Mr. Yang&#39;s father was still in the mainland, he went back as soon as Sino-US relations loosened, and has never cut off contacts with the mainland since then. He also worked very hard to introduce the research situation of modern physics in the United States to China and help domestic scholars. For decades, he has helped many students study abroad based on his original intention and done his best for the development of physics in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had the honor to work with him and Liu Zunyi to help Mr. Yu Jizhong establish the &quot;Chinese-English Teaching Foundation&quot; in mainland China. The purpose is to help university teachers go abroad for as short as half a year or as long as one year. Further education. As long as they put forward the visiting unit, goals, plans, time, as well as an invitation letter or commitment from the United States, as well as a letter of recommendation from the school, we will try our best to prioritize them in a professional direction. It is a very pleasant job for me to see so many outstanding scholars lining up, ready to make further efforts. Unfortunately, there are too few people and we cannot satisfy everyone&#39;s wishes. Because of this work, Mr. Yang meets with us once a year. In addition to our lectures to various schools, I also had the opportunity to ask for advice from him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, we visited the Chinese University of Hong Kong at the same time, and we would often drink tea and chat together. With such a friendship, I admire him greatly: he is old but still childlike, smart but not overbearing. He has reached the pinnacle of his specialized knowledge and is very knowledgeable about general affairs. The most admirable thing: He is completely frank with juniors of my age, which makes me feel like I am sitting on a spring breeze when talking to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[再获雨果奖，中国科幻文学更进一步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259145]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of October 21, the 2023 Hugo Awards were announced at the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, with a total of 17 Hugo categories selected Awards and Category 2 non-Hugo Awards, Chinese writer Hai Miao won the Best Short Novella Award for &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot;. This is also the first time that the Hugo Awards are announced and awarded in China. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对李春生涉嫌受贿一案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259201]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on October 24 that the former deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress Li Chunsheng&#39;s suspected bribery case was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate of Hunan Province. Recently, the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chenzhou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Chunsheng of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant, and listened to the opinions of the defender. Prosecution charges: Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County in Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security and director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province and director of the Provincial Public Security Department, and deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress. , deputy director and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers and status, to seek benefits for relevant units and individuals in business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc., illegally accepting property from others, the amount is particularly huge, and should be legally accepted He will be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访经济学家吴晓求：“要把A股市场从融资市场转变为投资市场”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259197]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the Chinese capital market for more than thirty years, with more than 200 million investors and more than 5,300 listed companies, there is no A market that touches the nerves of all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Political Bureau meeting of the CPC Central Committee proposed “activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence.” The China Securities Regulatory Commission and other departments subsequently launched a package of policies for “active capital markets”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges are the product of reform. They later underwent two historic reforms: shareholding split and registration system. But for a long time, every investor has suffered from short-term bullishness and bearishness. What loopholes have been left behind by the share-trading reform that once inspired the Long Bull market? How to fix blockage? What loopholes have arisen from the registration system? How to fix it quickly? How can the positioning of China&#39;s capital market mature through changes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of the 45th anniversary of the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial industry, Wu Xiaoqiu, former vice president of Renmin University of China and director of the China Capital Market Research Institute, emphasized in an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend that the establishment of the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges and the split of shares Reform and comprehensive registration-based reform are three monuments in the more than 30 years since the establishment of China&#39;s capital market. While they have achieved great success, they have also left some loopholes. These loopholes are the important institutional constraints that have caused the capital market to stagnate over the past decade. At present, regulatory authorities have realized and stepped up efforts to improve system design and plug loopholes. In the longer term, the main function of China&#39;s capital market is to transform from financing enterprises to a wealth management platform for investors, and from a financing market to an investment market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiaoqiu is the youngest professor of economics in the history of Renmin University of China and the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in China. He has been engaged in securities teaching and research for more than 30 years. He led the compilation of the first edition of China Securities Practitioner examination materials. He is also the promoter and witness of many major reforms in the capital market, such as the share-trading reform and the registration system reform. He has made many suggestions for active capital markets. Among them, his consistent assertion that &quot;the time is not ripe for the implementation of the T+0 trading system&quot; is in line with the China Securities Regulatory Commission. The current stance is consistent. The &quot;Phaseically Tightened Securities Lending and Strategic Investors Placement and Lending of Shares&quot; notice issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission on October 14, 2023 is also related to the loopholes in the shareholding reduction rules and systems that Wu Xiaoqiu has been paying attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;569&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Xiaoqiu: former vice president of Renmin University of China; currently dean of the National Institute of Financial Research and China Capital Market Research Institute of Renmin University of China, national first-class professor, and executive director of the China Society for Finance and Banking . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Engaged in the economy&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Financial and Capital Market Research&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Forty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Years”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are a college student in the &quot;New Third Class&quot; (1977-1979). If the college entrance examination and reform and opening up had not been resumed, how would your life trajectory have evolved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I never went to high school. Before college, he worked as a carpenter and later as a secretary in the county commerce bureau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination and reform and opening up changed the destiny of my life, just as it changed the destiny of thousands of my contemporaries in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee was held in December 1978, but the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977. Putting the resumption of the college entrance examination before the Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee, I think this is to prepare for reform and opening up in terms of ideology, talent, and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination is a reform in itself. It is equivalent to a fundamental adjustment of the talent training system during the ten-year &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; period, bringing order to things. Looking back on the past, without reform and opening up, a key move that determines the fate of contemporary China, China would not be what it is today, and neither would I be what I am today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you apply for the national economics major of Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I initially applied for the philosophy major at Jiangxi University because I like philosophy. When my father found out, he asked me to change my major. He believes that he should study at Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics. The major in national economic planning is very good and the economy may still be very important in the future. This change is also a &quot;decisive move&quot; for me personally. I later thought about my father&#39;s decision. He foresaw the future development direction of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my first year of college, I got to know Sun Yefang, Yu Guangyuan, Xu Dixin, Song Tao, Dong Fuzhen and other seniors. They are monuments in my mind. The dream of a scholar and the dream of an economist have been with me since I was in college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the postgraduate entrance examination in 1983, I ranked second overall and was admitted to the National Economic Planning major of Renmin University of China. For the National Economic Planning major, Renmin University is a palace. Later, I studied for a Ph.D. and stayed at the school to teach after graduation, and I never left. I first did economic research for about 10 years. From 1993 to 1994, I officially switched to financial research and capital market research, which now has a history of almost 30 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;If you don&#39;t emancipate your mind, you can&#39;t find the right path to development&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of his studies (1983-1986), reform and opening up developed from rural areas to cities, urban economic system reform began, township enterprises began to sprout, and opening up to the outside world continued to expand. During this period, which reform events impressed you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four things that impressed me deeply: The first time was attending an economic system reform seminar in Chaohu, Anhui. In 1985, the central government issued the &quot;Decision on Economic System Reform&quot; and launched the economic system reform that combined planning and market. It was a historic decision. I was a second-year graduate student at the time, and my supervisor, Mr. Hu Naowu, and I attended this seminar. That was my first time to participate in a national, high-level forum. It touched me greatly and expanded my horizons. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time was in 1985, when I participated in the Second Youth and Middle-aged Economic Forum held in Tianjin. The young people participating in the forum were active in thinking, participating in various debates, thinking about China&#39;s future, and exploring the focus of reform. I was writing an article about corporate bankruptcy. Bankruptcy is a thing of the market economy. There was no such thing as bankruptcy in China under the planned economy at that time, only &quot;shut down and transfer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time in 1985, I participated in a forum held in the Great Hall of the People. That forum was hosted by Mr. Dong Fucheng, and my speech attracted the attention of Li Chengrui, then director of the National Bureau of Statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth time was in 1986, when I participated in another discussion meeting on economic leverage in Leshan, Sichuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was only in my twenties at the time. It can be seen that that era gave young people many platforms and opportunities to speak freely at high-level forums held in the Great Hall of the People. This activates your mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those were sparkling days, full of youthful dreams and pursuits of young people everywhere. Only when the mind is liberated can academics prosper and the country develop. Without emancipating our minds, we cannot find the right path to development. Everything must be explored, discussed and even debated before you know which is the right path. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Cracking the mystery of China&#39;s special economic phenomenon&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During your doctoral studies (1987-1990), the basic line of &quot;one center, two basic points&quot; and &quot;science and technology are the primary productive forces&quot; were proposed. In the meantime, what are your views on China&#39;s economic reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most important thing when studying for a PhD is to learn advanced theories, study the Chinese economy, and how to solve the mystery of the special phenomena of the Chinese economy at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book that had the greatest impact on me at that time was &quot;The Economics of Shortage&quot; by the Hungarian economist János Korny. In the mid-to-late 1980s, many people read this work. &quot;Shortage Economics&quot; is a book that describes the basic characteristics of socialist economic operations under the traditional planned economic system. It is rich in strong theoretical logic, including soft budget constraints, paternalism, etc. Inspired by his thoughts, I started writing &quot;Theory of Compact Movement&quot; in 1987. &quot;The Theory of Tight Operation&quot; and my doctoral thesis &quot;Analysis of Socialist Economic Operation&quot; were published in 1991 and 1992 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did this book receive such special attention at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The real value of these two books is their attempt to explain the characteristics and laws of socialist economic operation under the traditional system. Because of these two books, as well as articles and papers published in People&#39;s Daily, Guangming Daily, Economic Research and Journal of Renmin University of China, I was promoted to professor by Renmin University in 1993. That year, Renmin University made an exception and promoted five professors, and I was the youngest among them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Transforming securities research and taking a road less traveled&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1994, you were transferred to the Department of Finance and Economics as a professor in the field of securities research in finance. The following year, you became the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in my country. Since then, you have been closely associated with China&#39;s securities industry. The relationship has been developing for thirty years. Why focus on securities research from now on? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was already studying finance at that time, so I offered to be transferred. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two opportunities: one is to alleviate poverty. In the early 1990s, I was about to become a professor and still lived in a Tongzi building with only 800 yuan in savings. At that time, someone gave me an idea, saying that you write a best-selling book, we will be responsible for selling it, and then give you a share. I thought of stocks and bonds. So I edited the &quot;Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, which contained about 5 million words in two volumes. It was a great seller as soon as it was launched. Later, I was given some money, and I got out of poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because I am the editor-in-chief, people ask me to speak. This forced me to really learn securities knowledge and securities investment. This has begun to deviate from the direction of my economics research, which is entirely the study of capital markets and finance. At that time, people did not think it was a science, and even thought it was a bit &quot;crooked&quot;. An important scholar among my predecessors once talked to me. The core idea was that I should return to the mainstream track of economic research such as economic operation analysis, macroeconomics, macroeconomic management and inflation theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The path of securities research was a sparsely traveled path at that time. There were few professional researchers, a lot of noise, and very little rational research. But in my opinion, the more in-depth securities research is, the more valuable it is. I am one of the few people left who has done research in the early stages and is still doing front-line research now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then president of Renmin University, Mr. Huang Da, was a professor in the Department of Finance, so I applied to go to the Department of Finance. I taught a course on securities investment. At that time, there were not many securities investment courses offered in colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I first entered the stock market both for making money and for research&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There was a movie called &quot;Stock Crazy&quot; in 1994, which tells the story of the various crazes caused by mass speculation in the stock market in the early days of the stock market. Was the stock market back then really like in the movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; (The craze for stock trading) has indeed begun. The stock market has begun to enter people&#39;s lives, more and more people are investing in the stock market, and various theories, methods and stock reviews have begun to appear. Because I wrote &quot;The Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, I also started doing research on it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a research expert on securities investment, what will happen to you? Is stock trading practical? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was only after 2000 that I really entered the stock market as an investor. After entering, I found that practice was more profoundly helpful to my theoretical research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the difference between securities research and stock trading? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My goal in entering this market is not only to make money, but also to do research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set two goals for myself at that time: first, not to lose money, and to see through practical operations whether what I learned theoretically would work in practice; second, to establish a direct perceptual understanding of the research object. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, I understand the rules of securities investment and the market better. When I write textbooks, I will be more enriched and my writing will be more vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period, I presided over the compilation of the first set of teaching materials for the securities practitioner qualification examination in China. The first edition consisted of six volumes. The general structure of the later textbooks compiled by the China Securities Regulatory Commission did not deviate from this edition. It plays a very important role in the qualification examination for securities practitioners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have the expectations of making money been met? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I also wanted to catch the bull market and make a fortune. The first one I remember was buying Sichuan Changhong, and one day I suddenly discovered that it was going up quite well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;The loopholes left over from the split-share structure reform must be closed &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾说过中国资本市场有三座丰碑：沪深交易所建立、股权分置改革、试点注册制。你参与推动了哪些？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我参与了股权分置改革、参与推动了注册制试点。股权分置改革启动是2005年5月。但理论准备从2001年国有股份减持失败开始，我们就开始思考怎么进行股权分置改革。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2001年的国有股减持为何失败？它给后来的股权分置改革提供了哪些启示？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时监管机构认为国有股减持可以按市价减持，但因市场反应太大被匆匆叫停。后来分析总结，国有股按市价减持，既缺乏逻辑，也缺乏理论支持，所以必然会失败。作为这个失败的结果，我们当时就在反思如何推动股权分置改革。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在那段反思的时间，学界组织了许多讨论，我可能是参加次数最多的人之一，无论是参加证监会主持的小范围讨论，还是大范围的讨论，我几乎每场都参加了。其中，印象比较深刻的一次是2004年某一天，时任证监会主席尚福林给我打电话，单独和我讨论股权分置怎么改。后来，我也多次到他办公室参加讨论，小范围的大概十个人，大范围的二三十个人，大家讨论后就形成了两点共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一点就是必须推动股权分置改革，不推动改革，中国资本市场是没有未来的。这个也是我强调的；第二点就是股权分置改革究竟应该用什么办法去改革，这个路径的设计非常困难，我们慢慢考虑到对价改革是合适的。对价改革也只是个方向，对价多少是合适的，这个变得更难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我清晰记得在证监会开会时，时任证监会副主席屠光绍问我，你觉得对价的比例是多少合适？我说30%或者说七折，因为存量增发的价格就是按流通价的七折。这就为股权分置改革的对价提供了参照。后来实践证明，各上市公司股权分置改革的对价方案都在七折附近波动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2005年股权分置改革启动初期，沪深股市并没有太大反应。大牛市似乎是2005年之后才起来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。 2005年5月启动了股权分置改革，当时沪深股市从2001年起已经低迷了4年多，市场反应冷淡。后来市场慢慢知道这个东西不得了，越来越多的人预感到这是一个大牛市的机会。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们当时就判断，在股权分置改革过程中，沪深股市漫长的熊市会发生逆转。改革完成之后，会为资本市场的长期健康发展奠定良好的基础。从今天角度来看，股权分置改革的大方向是正确的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;股权分置改革大概用了两年时间。它还有哪些不足之处？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从2005年5月到2007年3月，95%的上市公司都完成了股权分置改革。它是一座丰碑，但它也的确还有缺陷，这个缺陷就是对大股东、实际控制人的减持缺乏有效的约束。这个政策漏洞对后来沪深股市十多年来徘徊不前产生了重要影响。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最近也讲，严重制约中国资本市场发展的，最重要的是资产供给端的制度设计，其中，资产供给端主要是存量资产的减持规则，就是实际控制人、控股股东没有财务约束的减持标准，导致了市场很难有成长性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你认为，现在这个漏洞补得怎么样？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2023年8月27日，证监会政策里已经有某些修补了。这是股权分置改革遗留下来的一个漏洞，我们必须要把它补上。因为它严重损害了资本市场资金供求关系的生态链，使资金供应关系严重失衡。目前看大的漏洞正在修补，至少知道漏洞在哪里。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;注册制改革效果喜忧参半”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提及的中国资本市场第三个丰碑是注册制改革。为什么要启动注册制改革？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2007年之后，我参与的理论研究，或者说政策制定，主要就是注册制改革。为什么要进行注册制改革？因为核准制是有重大缺陷的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，核准制最大的问题就是对企业上市的选择权没有交给市场，而是交给了发审委，交给了有形的手。第二个问题是定价没有市场化，所以才有上市之后20个涨停板的奇怪现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三个问题是监管主体和审核主体没有分离，证监会既审核又监管，这个当然是有问题的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于核准制至少有这三个方面的问题，我们想要把这三个缺陷改掉，就要进行注册制改革。根据市场化原则，交易所采取灵活性的制度，同时对拟上市企业不拘泥于一定要盈利。相对于核准制要求拟上市企业必须连续三年盈利，注册制的一个最大创新就是对拟上市企业主要高科技企业允许其过往三年有亏损，但是要具有可持续经营能力。这是个重大转变。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年是全面注册制改革元年。作为注册制改革的推动者和政策参与者，你对目前的改革效果满意吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;喜忧参半。喜的是有一些独角兽企业、高科技企业，通过这个机制成为上市公司，虽然它短期是亏损的，但是它具有可持续经营能力。注册制改革天然服务于专精特新和高科技性创新企业，天生地和高科技企业具有耦合关系。只有在注册制下，科技和资本市场才是耦合的，我们未来仍然会朝这个方向努力。这对我们推动高科技企业的发展，对我国产业结构的转型和产业的升级迭代，改善上市公司结构，提升中国资本市场的投资价值，我认为是有重要价值和重要意义的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;忧的是注册制中对亏损的界定标准的泛化，这个是很严重的误解，损害了市场信心，也不符合注册制的本来含义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么会出现这种漏洞？这个漏洞的危害有哪些？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;注册制改革如同股权分置改革一样，也出现一个漏洞。坦率地说，当时没人意识到。就像设计一个航天器一样，百密一疏。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;注册制的漏洞就是把市场化功能泛化了，或者说把上市公司不严格要求盈利的指标泛化了。以至于后来有些上市公司抓住这样一个漏洞，搞一个所谓的高科技企业，打着所谓“破解卡脖子工程”等等旗号，找几十个研究人员，搞个两三年就开始要申请IPO了。这对市场信心损害巨大。它们不符合注册制的基本精神，也超出了一个公众市场、交易所市场、社会公众投资者所能承担风险边界的要求。这类企业的融资主要应该由PE、VC去完成的，是不可以直接IPO的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我把这个漏洞定义为：在注册制条件下，关于不盈利要求的泛化理解。这是很严重的认知误区，对后来股票市场徘徊不前有密切关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这个漏洞目前在修补吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我曾经向证监会明确提出，对拟上市公司不盈利的要求不能泛化。从最近的IPO情况看，证监会和交易所也已经特别关注对财务指标都是负值的企业的上市诉求，特别是对于净资产是负的、现金流是负的、利润是也负的，这些主要财报指标都是负的，这种企业是不能上市的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;修补完漏洞，注册制改革就完成了么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;远远没有。注册制改革是全方位、全链条的改革，发行制度市场化改革只是它的历史起点、逻辑起点，后面还有交易、并购、信息披露、监管、退市、违规违法行为的处罚、法律模式等等诸多方面的调整，都要纳入到和注册制改革相适应的模式之中，不断地完善。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;双峰模式是理想的妥协&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2022年，你提出中国金融体系的“双峰模式”。背后有哪些深层次的观察和思考？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;坦率地说，我最早提出的是“单蜂模式”。 2002年前后我曾认为，未来的中国一定是资本市场占主体的金融模式。 20年过去了，我发现“单蜂模式”在中国挺难的，实现不了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管如此，在近20年里，中国资本市场的规模扩张还是比较快的。它从过去的两三万亿市值，到今天的八十多万亿市值，在金融体系中的比重明显提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，我终于意识到，中国的商业银行在中国经济生活中的作用巨大，中国只能实行双峰模式——银行体系和资本市场共同主导。这是一个理想的妥协，也是现实的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;资本市场为何难以成为主导？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;资本市场的发展并没有改变中国经济对货币信贷的依赖。从资本市场自身看，20年来上市公司的股票价格没有什么上涨，市场指数也没涨起来，只有市值在扩张。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，近20年上市企业的数量从1000家已经增加到5300多家，几乎中国最大的、最好的企业都已经实现了IPO，包括很多国企央企和“独角兽”企业。某种意义上说，中国股市便利企业融资的功能已经实现了，但它自身却是一个摊饼式的扩张，不断往外扩张，没有精耕细作，企业获得融资后的单位产出率很低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么我们的指数没有成长？很重要一个原因，还是要回到我刚才说的那两个漏洞，特别是第一个漏洞即减持规则对成长带来了巨大的抑制作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中国股市&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;何以&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;尚不成熟&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们的资本市场发展已经超过了30年，三十而立，它能算是一个成熟的市场吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中国资本市场在实践中在改革中慢慢找到了基本方向，但还是一个不成熟的市场。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个不成熟之处在于制度设计上的漏洞比较多。第二个不成熟之处在于始终没有深刻理解资本市场对中国意味着什么，对金融改革意味着什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去我们常说设立股市的主要目的是便利企业融资，这是不正确的定位和认知。证券市场表象上是融资，实际上是投资。你没有投资功能的不断加强，融资是难以为继的，人家用脚投票会走的。走了还融什么资？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，我们要把中国资本市场从为企业融资提供便利，定位于融资的市场，转变成为投资者的财富管理平台和投资的市场。由融资市场转变为投资市场，这是我们未来的方向。实现这个目标要有一个较长的时间。制度效应要发挥作用，相应的制度安排出台也需要时间。我们现在的制度安排正在堵漏洞，正在向这方面靠近。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A股牛短熊长，主要问题也是制度设计漏洞和没有真正理解资本市场对金融改革的意义？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;造成中国资本市场有这种现象，既有深厚的文化和法律背景，也有中观层次上规则的错位，比如之前提到的股权分置改革和注册制改革出现的两个漏洞。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然也有部分原因是我们的企业家并没有深刻理解上市对他们意味着什么。本来上市是手段，但这些企业创始人突然发现原来上市能这么容易发财，比他辛辛苦苦做实体经济容易得多，这就腐蚀了他们过去的创业初心。他就会把上市作为目的，实体经济也不做了，想个办法赶紧套现走人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要纠正这个错误导向，只有通过制度改革去引导——只有把企业做好，你才能够套现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对此你有哪些具体建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;要实现资本市场功能与导向的根本转型，首先是整体宏观制度设计的转型。在资产供给端方面，制度设计要有利于市场功能的转型，有利于把有透明度和成长性的资产引入市场，有利于吸引越来越多的新增投资者，新增资金进入市场。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，我们应该对所有上市前的股东减持股份有一定的约束，特别是对控股股东、实控人，包括二股东、三股东等等，怎么用财务指标约束减持，要有创新的制度设计，要让所有的股东把注意力、努力放在如何把公司做好、创造利润、提高分配上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，我们要持续改善资本市场的生态环境，无论是机构投资者还是个人投资者，在这个市场中，可以获得与其风险相匹配的收益，市场才会成长起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;股市持续不向好，需要我们拿出正确的应对办法&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;中央7月末明确提出要“活跃资本市场”，这释放了什么信号？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;应该说监管层看到了问题所在。中国没有一个领域能像资本市场涉及范围如此之大。资本市场至少有2亿投资者，背后可能就是2亿个家庭，差不多中国有一半人与资本市场有关系。第二，全球资本市场虽然都经过了疫情，但主要经济体中中国的资本市场表现不好。我们要更加重视其背后反映的问题。第三，活跃资本市场，也是提振市场信心的重要举措。需要我们拿出正确的应对办法。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对于活跃资本市场，也有不少专家提议A股从T+1切换到T+0。但监管机构一直说机会不成熟。你怎么看？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;交易上的改革没有实质意义，T+0无益于市场的成长， T+0改革的逻辑基础不清楚。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是T+0的最大利好给了证券公司，T+0会直接导致券商佣金的增加，由此带动券商股的上涨。而我们改革目标不是让券商风生水起，活跃资本市场的本意也不是佣金的增加，佣金增加反而意味着资本市场资金的漏出。至于有些人所说T+0对市场价格有纠错机制，我认为还需要多做实证研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是T+1为基础的交易规则是在中国资本市场诞生初期，在交易规则多次试错的背景下作出的选择，历经三十多年实践已经非常成熟，更适合中国国情。我非常喜欢T+1制度。上午买的股票，为什么一定下午就要卖呢？既然下午要卖，那你上午就别买。逻辑是很清楚的。如果说买错了，那明天卖也是一样的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，T+1制度也不是中国独有，国际上也是很成熟的。不见得有些国家用T+0，我们也用。从我个人来说，不太喜欢T+0，因为这个制度会把人们搞得癫狂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末：你对中国股市有信心吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴晓求:中国股市好起来的前提是中国经济要好起来。我一直说中国经济只要想搞好，是一定能搞好的。从本质上说，中国经济基础是好的。只要发挥市场的主导作用，适应历史的趋势，遵守市场规律，尊重企业和企业家精神，推动改革开放，走市场经济之路，中国经济就一定能搞好，怎么可能搞不好？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当下中国经济的问题，主要不是周期性因素带来的。我一直坚信，只要把过去45年改革开放中被证明是成功的经验坚持下去，进一步完善，中国经济就能继续保持良好趋势，中国资本市场也就有了成长基础。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部：已缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259195]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在今天（24日）上午国务院新闻办公室的举行“权威部门话开局”系列主题新闻发布会上，公安部有关负责人介绍，今年8月以来，全国电信网络诈骗案件发案数、造成财产损失数同比分别下降24%、20.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照公安部统一部署，各地公安机关持续强化打击力度，深入开展“云剑”“断卡”“断流”“拔钉”等专项行动，截至今年9月底，缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名；联合最高人民检察院挂牌督办一批重大案件，公开曝光一批典型案例；围绕境内打击，持续组织开展区域会战、专案攻坚、集群战役，密切与各部门协作配合，严厉打击引流推广、转账洗钱、技术开发等犯罪团伙，坚决切断犯罪关键链条，坚决遏制电信网络诈骗犯罪高发态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部坚持关口前移、防范为先，采取多种防范措施，最大限度预防案件发生。指导各地公安机关建立分级分类预警劝阻机制，推动“厦门经验”在全国落地生效。今年以来，累计向各地推送预警指令3.1亿条，各地自主产出预警信息1.3亿条；会同工业和信息化部建成12381涉诈预警劝阻短信系统，累计发送预警提示短信、闪信6.4亿条；会同中央网信办建设推广国家反诈中心App，累计预警提示1578.5万次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部联合中央宣传部开展主题为“预警劝阻别忽视，财产安全要重视”的“全民反诈在行动”集中宣传月活动。其间，国家反诈中心发布《2023版防范电信网络诈骗宣传手册》；会同相关行业主管部门督促金融机构、电信业务经营者、互联网服务提供者对本行业从业人员及服务对象深入开展反诈宣传；联合中国老龄协会举办全国老年人防诈反诈知识竞赛；联合教育部启动“反诈宣传进校园”活动；联合中国电影集团在全国农村地区和中小学校园组织反诈优秀影片公益展映活动，持续掀起全民反诈、全社会反诈的新热潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[情侣住酒店被偷拍勒索：应大力查办暗黑产业链丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259191]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;情侣住酒店一年后收到亲密视频，到店拆开吊灯发现摄像头竟然还在，令人细思极恐。住酒店被偷拍，酒店应该承担什么责任？偷拍屡禁不绝，背后的产业链又该如何铲除？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据广西电视台日前报道，南宁胡先生近日收到一年前和未婚妻住酒店时的亲密视频，到店后发现吊灯里隐藏的两个摄像头竟然还在。而酒店经理称，他们也是受害者，排查其它房间没有异样，只愿退还房费。这一报道在网上引起了极大关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;住酒店被偷拍的新闻屡屡出现。在某搜索引擎搜索“酒店偷拍”可以搜出几千万条相关信息。近期的新闻，除了上文中提到外，还有江苏连云港、湖南娄底等地都有出现。几年前河南郑州某酒店负责人甚至声称80%的酒店都有偷拍摄像头。其实，偷拍不止出现在酒店，服装店试衣间、写字楼厕所，甚至连动车洗手间里都发现了隐藏的摄像头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些隐藏的摄像头，严重侵犯了他人的隐私，毫无疑问是违法犯罪行为。如果是酒店私自安装了摄像头，酒店当然要承担责任。但如果是其他人在酒店不知情的情况下偷偷安装的，酒店需要承担责任吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的情况确实不少。据业内人士称，坏人可以伪装成客人住酒店，每次只要十几分钟就可以把摄像头装好，然后以各种理由换房间，一次就能偷装几个房间。在连云港酒店发现摄像头案件中，警方抓获的犯罪嫌疑人是无业人员，并非酒店员工。最高检2022年发布的一个指导性案例中，犯罪分子也是在多家酒店的客房内偷偷安装摄像头偷拍的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种情况下，难道真的像南宁那家酒店的经理所称，他们也是受害者，不需要对客人被侵害承担责任？当然不是，旅客入住酒店，当然是把酒店房间视为私密场所，对自己在房间里的隐私具有合理期待，酒店应该对客人的隐私尽到合理的保障义务。客人被偷拍，被侵犯隐私，与酒店没有尽到安全保障义务有脱不了的关系。而南宁这家酒店，一年多后摄像头还在，可见其多么疏于管理。出现偷拍事件，酒店除了要停业整顿，也要对客人进行赔偿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;酒店有义务保障客人的隐私。其实，现在市面上已经有专门针对针孔摄像头的便携式检测仪器，酒店只要给保洁或者保安人员配备一套，就可以在短时间内查出大多数隐藏的摄像头。这样做需要的成本并不高，关键是反偷拍要像打扫卫生一样，成为酒店行业标准，成为每家酒店都要做的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;酒店偷拍之所以屡禁不绝，还因为其背后有一条黑色的产业链。犯罪分子偷拍视频，并不是为了刺激，而是会把这些偷拍的视频放到暗网等非法网站去售卖。一些网站、社交账号打着“酒店偷拍”等旗号，吸引用户付费观看隐私视频。整个偷拍的黑色产业，每年可能有上千亿元规模。在前述最高检发布的指导案例中，犯罪分子就通过非法网站、即时通讯软件等发布信息贩卖偷拍的隐私视频。 2021年，辽宁警方也打掉了一条利用隐蔽摄像头在酒店偷拍、直播获利的黑色产业链。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了到暗网售卖，还有人利用拍到的隐私视频敲诈勒索。 2022年底，湖南娄底一名女子在酒店被偷拍后，就有人把视频发给她然后勒索钱财。这次广西南宁的胡先生收到偷拍视频，对方也很可能并不是好心提醒他被偷拍了，也有很大的可能是要对其敲诈勒索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于偷拍行为必须加大打击力度。在各种通讯账号都实行实名制的当下，警方要找到犯罪分子应该并不太难。对于发信息敲诈勒索的，警方可以通过发信息的账号找到勒索者，然后顺藤摸瓜，查清勒索者是如何获得视频，以及客人的联系方式等隐私信息的，将整个链条都打掉，同时也可以查清酒店是否存在泄露客人隐私的问题。毕竟，就算犯罪分子偷偷安装摄像头，没有酒店的内鬼，也很难知道客人的联系方式，是没有办法敲诈勒索的。只找到偷拍摄像头的，警方也有手段找到安装者。连云港酒店的摄像头、天津某写字楼女厕的摄像头，警方都很快就抓到了犯罪嫌疑人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对猖獗的偷拍，一方面警方要加大对黑色产业链的打击力度。对偷拍偷录设备也要加强管理。现在网络上随处可以买到各种微型隐蔽摄像头，还有各种摄像头破解、漏洞利用等教学视频，这些都助长了偷拍的泛滥。酒店行业也应该制定标准，把反偷拍摄像头等纳入行业的日常管理中，尽最大可能保护客人的隐私安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“毛孩子”上幼儿园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258991]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVAPLvRo1Tt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVAPLvRo1Tt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;两位“学员”参加幼儿园的敏捷性游戏课程&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;秋日的一个下午，三只不同种类的宠物狗在训犬师的指导下参与游戏，平衡板、滑板、数字识别、玩具分拣……这些适应性和益智类游戏是北京萌兽派宠物酒店（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以下简称“萌兽派”&lt;/span>;）开设的宠物幼儿园教学体系的一部分，此外还有游泳、嗅闻和脱敏等课程。幼儿园的托管时间是每天早八到晚八。除了上课，狗狗们还能享用营养配餐、午休、洗澡、毛发护理和按摩等服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“胖虎”今年两岁半。它的“家长”是一对95后夫妻，平时热爱旅游，每个月都会把“胖虎”送来宠物酒店寄养几天&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参加游戏课的三只狗依次进入教室，它们分别是小柴犬、贵宾犬和萨摩耶。课程开始，看到正在用相机拍摄的陌生人，三个学员马上给出了不同反馈：小柴犬专注于训犬师的口令；贵宾犬则一边不停狂吠一边试探着靠近陌生人，课程一度无法进行；萨摩耶也注意到了相机的存在，以一种友善的姿态试图靠近，当训犬师发出指令，它立即回到游戏中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“胖虎”参加幼儿园的益智类游戏课程&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“胖虎”在幼儿园体验萌兽影院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“狗狗也有自己的性格，你看它们三只就截然不同，这跟体形没关系，首先是基因决定的，另外跟它的成长经历有关。贵宾犬警惕性非常强，它其实不是要攻击你，只不过是吓唬你——&#39;你别过来，不要伤害我，我很凶的，你听我叫得多厉害&#39;，但其实这恰恰反映出它的胆小和敏感。其他两只都能专注在自己的事情上，这说明它们社会化做得比较好，能规范自己的行为，不去影响别人，面对新鲜事物时表现得非常自信和勇敢。”萌兽派创始人李晨分析着学员们的表现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萌兽派开设幼儿园将近五年，中间经历了新冠疫情，业务几乎停滞。从2023年年初开始，李晨发现宠物寄养和参加幼儿园的需求出现了“井喷式的爆发”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王姐和9岁的“咖啡豆”在萌兽派。今年是咖啡豆来幼儿园的第五年&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“年轻的养宠群体对幼儿园的接受度突然高了起来。他们不会以牺牲自己的生活方式（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;社交、出差、旅行等&lt;/span>;）为代价去养狗——我有我的生活，你有你的生活。我尽我所能让你的生活丰富多彩，送你去上学，让你每一天都过得充实快乐，并不需要每天只是在家等我。我在外出的时候也会很坦然，不用心怀愧疚，总觉得狗这一辈子只有一件事情，就是在家等我。”李晨认为随着社会的进步和养宠群体思想的变化，现在宠物主们关注的不再是自己的宠物吃的是不是进口狗粮，还会关注宠物的心理健康——你今天是不是快乐。狗狗也需要有自己的精神世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幼儿园的口号是“让狗做回狗”，在很多课程的设置上通过训练帮助它们恢复作为动物的本能，比如嗅闻、捕猎和游泳，增强狗狗的信心和体能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;三三妈带着她收养的4只老年犬到萌兽派参加生日会&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据李晨介绍，目前幼儿园的家长以80后和90后为主，他们并非都是家境优渥的中产或白领，但很舍得给“毛孩子”花钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只是年轻人，有些老年人也不惜重金为“毛孩子”打造健康舒适的生活，李晨称之为“隔代亲”。她接待过一对退休夫妇，每年定期要去外地探望女儿，离京的两三个月，他们就把领养的两只“串串儿”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;杂交品种的狗&lt;/span>;）放到李晨这里。“在他们眼里，宠物跟家人是一样的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;3只哈士奇在餐厅等候&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;咖啡豆是一只泰迪犬，今年9岁。王姐记得第一次上完幼儿园，店员把它送下来，转身走了，咖啡豆还追着人家跑。“狗的反应特别真实，从那时起我就知道他们肯定对豆豆好。”今年是咖啡豆来幼儿园的第五年，从最初谁也不能碰，见人就狂吠，转变成现在时常扮可爱博得周围人的关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王姐和丈夫是丁克族，她把咖啡豆“当作儿子养”，从不吝惜在它身上花钱。每逢店里搞活动，王姐都想着再续点费。李晨看到她卡上充足的余额，总劝她要理性消费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小程之前爱旅游和买包，现在她把这些钱存下来都花在九万身上，每月大概四五千。每周带九万出去玩，让小程从一个宅女变成了熟知宠物友好场所的户外达人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;3岁的“十五”享用宠物生日蛋糕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三年前，小程的儿子出生，她觉得养狗和养孩子各有各的好，但养孩子肯定更辛苦，而九万带给她的只有开心快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于网上流传的一些不文明养犬的新闻，小程认为不应该是养狗与不养狗的对立，而是文明养狗与不文明养狗的对立。“养狗的人首先要做好自己：牵绳、捡屎、错峰遛狗、避让行人——尤其是老人和小孩。我也理解有些人天生就怕狗，那就互相离得远点，多等一趟电梯的事，大家相互理解。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“奶瓶儿”（上）游完泳，在宠物餐厅享用加餐。三年多前，“奶瓶儿”被现在的主人从路上捡回了家&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在萌兽派创建之初，李晨把二层一个将近300平米的空间设计成了视听室，满足主人和狗狗一起看电影的需求，对会员免费开放。这个规划当时受到一些股东的质疑，他们认为从收益率考虑，这是一种浪费。但李晨有自己的想法，虽然有一些宠物主题的电影会做包场，但影院里的音响都是给人设计的，不适合狗狗的听觉系统。“我希望能给主人和宠物提供一种多元化的选择，哪怕是满足一些非常小众的需求，但在别的地方没有办法体验得到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这只哈士奇正在做惊吓测试——筛选、淘汰容易对跑动、尖叫、过度热情的人有过度害怕、攻击或过度兴奋问题的狗狗。这个测试模拟了治疗犬在服务场所可能遇到的情景，最大化地减少安全隐患。通过测评的狗狗经过培训，有机会上门服务特殊人群（老人、孤独症儿童等）&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六年来，李晨身边一直能听到一些争议，主要是质疑她把相对高端和小众的服务当作噱头，形式大于内容。“其实我们大多数的服务是非常刚需的，有一些可能相对超前一点，但它是科学的，我相信也符合未来的发展趋势。宠物服务面对的是不同客户的需求，因此要提供不同的选择，没有一个统一的标准答案，也不需要有。”李晨说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年新冠疫情期间，萌兽派协助北京朝阳区政府做宠物集中转运，第一时间将店内改成宠物方舱，缓解了疫情期间的宠物安置问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“九万”在幼儿园上游泳课&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晨对南新园社区那次大规模转运记忆犹新，120多只宠物，大部分是狗，也有猫、兔子、乌龟和小鸡等，一车车地往回拉，转运了整整两天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照常规操作，接寄养是要对宠物进行测评的：年龄、基础病、有没有攻击性……但那次没得选，时间紧迫，主人在现场把自己的联系方式和宠物基本信息写在一张纸条上，工作人员把纸条和宠物放在一起拍张照片，就算完成了登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;萌兽派宠物酒店一层的寄养房间都带有独立的院子。为避免分离焦虑，有些主人会带上宠物在家的玩具或坐垫帮它们尽快适应新环境&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到店里，李晨和店员再对不同类别的宠物分区管理，尽可能给主人们发去宠物的最新照片和视频，安抚他们的情绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“刚开始并没有建立信任，有的主人看到视频说，虽然长得像，但从神情能认出来，这不是我的狗。没关系，我们给他再拍10个视频，让他再找一找感觉或者表情，判断是不是自己的狗。头三天我们每天都会接到主人们的电话，有质问的、有痛哭的、有谩骂的。到第四天大家才开始相信——你们真把我的狗安置在你那了，于是开始给我们网购食品和物资，以表谢意。”这次经历让李晨对人性有了更深的体察和认知。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;幼儿园的照片墙&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隔离期满，这120多只宠物在逐一做过核酸后，完好地回到各自的主人身边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做宠物酒店以来，李晨阅狗无数，也见证了很多感人的故事：游泳课上，本来狗狗不敢下水，当主人“掉进”水池，它却奋不顾身地跳水相救；家有孕妇或小孩的，遛狗时狗狗宁可自己不上厕所，也要确保主人在自己的视线内，不让陌生人靠近……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[烈犬伤童事件后，“失焦”的多地捕狗风波]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259173]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;一位广州居民在遛狗，路边有标语“遛狗牵狗绳，文明不掉链”。图文无关。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;一位广州居民在遛狗，路边有标语“遛狗牵狗绳，文明不掉链”。图文无关。视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可不能说我们打狗，我们真没打过。”2023年10月20日，说起近期捕狗舆论，张勇有些紧张，特别强调他们是文明执法，全程都用执法记录仪记录，并进行台账登记。“得保证都是活的，不能有损伤。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位呼和浩特市赛罕区城市综合执法局宣传股股长担心的舆论，是罗威纳犬咬伤崇州4岁女童事件带来的连锁反应。一个烈犬咬人的视频席卷全网，进而在多地出现捕狗行动，网传有小区物业成立“打狗小队”，保安带着棍棒、捕网巡查；安徽亳州、河南郑州、江苏泰兴、山东青岛等地的城管部门陆续发布捕捉流浪狗的视频，网友们开始激烈讨论是否应当扑杀流浪狗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;争议案例也随之出现。一只生活在重庆对外经贸学院的流浪狗，被保安驱赶致死。10月20日该校通报称，有学生在归寝途中被流浪狗追赶，学校保安在驱赶中存在不当行为，已对涉事保安作停职处理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，在此次事件后，多地均针对无主犬、烈性犬、不戴牵引绳的行为进行专项整治。但与此同时，各类谣言也正在网络平台不断流传。其实，在不少地方，捕捉流浪狗都是常态化开展的一项工作，抓捕后的流浪狗将送到流浪动物救助中心收容，不会进行打杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;物业该负什么责任&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;罗威纳犬咬人事件后，女童所住的恒大西辰绿洲小区多处挂上标语：“文明遛狗牵好绳，管住嘴巴勿伤人”“牵紧&#39;文明绳&#39;，做养犬文明人”……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月20日，住在受害女童楼上的一位妈妈告诉南方周末记者，女童被咬伤的当天，愤怒的业主便已在业主群里议论：“出这么大事，保安在哪？”“为什么外来的狗进来都不知道”。压力之下，物业开始每天巡逻，捕捉没有拴绳的狗。这些工作会一一发到群里，向业主报告，附上抓捕视频和照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种紧张氛围很快传染到了其他小区。10月17日，媒体报道成都市府河御景小区成立“打狗小队”，视频中保安带着棍棒、捕网巡查，物业工作人员表示：“凡是流浪狗，没人管的，没套绳的，整个小区整改”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月18日下午，成都市三都汇朝外小区则以物业的名义挂上了“小区将对未拴绳的猫犬进行捕杀”的横幅。“捕杀”二字一下引起小区宠物主的担忧和指责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据该小区住户李明了解，“捕杀”的想法其实出自小区的妈妈群。娃妈们出于担忧，在群里提议“流浪犬只处理办法：首先是尽可能地打死或捕捉，其次是驱离小区再报警通知社区”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但反对扑杀的一方在18日晚上接连拨打政务服务便民热线12345投诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次日早上，物业出面表示横幅言辞不当，已经撤下。“物业现在已经不敢接电话了，街道不让他们强行扑杀，早上警告了他们。”李明说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者多次拨打该小区物业及所在街道办电话，均未接通。20日，成都市住建局物业事务服务中心回复媒体称，该中心没接到通知称有小区成立打狗队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市京都律师事务所律师常莎曾接触过狗伤人案件，她认为，小区物业对业主具有安全保障的义务，因此小区内出现无主狗，物业要承担驱离或管理责任，否则要为流浪狗伤人承担过错责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是另一方面，物业公司不具有执法权，因此对于有主人的狗，物业不能对其采取强制的管理措施，比如直接抓捕。非紧急情况下，物业只能采取劝说或者交给有执法权的城管、公安处理。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;多地整治，谣言同行&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在成都小区业主争议扑杀流浪狗与否的18日晚间，河南省郑州市金水区城管部门针对未拴绳养狗行为连夜执法，并进行了直播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;捕狗争论开始波及全国多地，形成执法行动。在郑州这次直播中，一位牵着法国斗牛犬的年轻人被追着跑了老远。根据直播录像，尽管城管人员一再强调不会伤害狗，只是带回去登记调查，但这位年轻人在一番交涉未果后，又尝试抱着黑狗逃跑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这段视频成为此次网络风波的又一传播点。同样在郑州养法斗的市民小真告诉南方周末记者，法斗在郑州的确是禁养的，平常不能办狗证，但执法并不严，“以前偶尔会查的”。同时，全国许多城市允许法斗饲养，包括北京、上海、西安、大连、哈尔滨、南京、杭州、长沙等。得知前述年轻人需要缴纳罚款5000元，法斗爱好者群里纷纷向其发红包，说要帮他把狗要回来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;武汉市小动物保护协会会长杜帆介绍，当下城市的犬类管理主要依据各地自行制定的条例，这样的行政管理条例效力不高，因此很多人不办狗证，也不按规定养狗。（详见&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/258846&quot;>;《多专家谈罗威纳犬咬伤女童：“关键在管理人，其次才是管理狗”》&lt;/a>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，城市里犬只管理的职权划分并不清晰，目前大部分城市由公安主管，有的归城管主管，而犬只管理还涉及工商、食品安全、治安管理等多个部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在罗威纳犬伤童事件后，多地发布专项管理行动，安徽亳州、江苏泰兴、河南沈丘、四川射洪等地均针对无主犬、烈性犬、不戴牵引绳的行为进行专项整治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其中，谣言与事实夹杂。南方周末记者发现，呼吁不要捕杀流浪狗的视频中，时常出现数十只狗的尸体照、被摔死画面等，但都没有时间标注，仅从画面背景看，公交车及建筑物应该是数年以前的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博热议话题“小狗不觉得自己是在流浪”中，许多网民将一张被捕后仍在咧嘴“微笑”的小狗照片认做是重庆对外经贸学院涉事黄狗，配文“被抓时还在笑，它以为它要有家了”，并以此表示哀悼。但原图作者辟谣称微笑小狗拍摄于4月，与重庆的并非同一只狗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有些失焦了。”江苏省动物学会理事周威发现，随着事态发展，网友讨论逐渐变成爱狗还是不爱狗、扑杀还是不扑杀这样的对立问题，并未深入细节讨论。比如，许多视频标题里说“捕杀”流浪狗，但目前大部分视频仅仅呈现了“捕捉”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;城管常态化工作&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者通过检索发现，许多捕狗视频是由各地城管、公安的官方账号发布，如青岛市西海岸新区综合行政执法局便连续发布3条视频，介绍捕捉流浪狗是其常态化开展的一项工作，抓捕后的流浪狗将送到流浪动物救助中心收容，不会进行打杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因发放牵狗绳、狗嘴套而引发关注，被网友认为文明执法范例的四川省射洪市综合行政执法局则向南方周末记者表示，他们自2021年设置犬只管理办公室，配备专业的捉狗设备及车辆，日常有5个工作人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在呼和浩特市赛罕区，据城市综合执法局介绍，该局从2020年接手流浪狗捕捉工作，仅在2023年就接到1100多条相关的举报信息，已捕捉流浪狗三百多只，举报内容大都为犬吠扰民，尤其是凌晨及早上。该局宣传股股长张勇称，队员接到举报电话，就得及时与当事人联系，处置完毕后需要回复对方，如果逮不住，一周之内队员至少还得去3次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听起来这并不是容易的工作。张勇称，他们为此专门制定长效机制，分为白班和晚班进行值班，“机动中队参与捕狗的有38人”。他们要巡查赛罕区管辖的1025平方公里，而当狗翻越栏杆、进入树丛，执法人员很难追上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是，流浪狗嗅觉灵敏，常年装流浪狗的执法车辆往一个地方一停，“这块就不会有狗出来了”。张勇说，他们曾有队员开着自己的车转悠时看到流浪狗，打电话叫来执法车，车辆还没到，流浪狗便开始躁动，“它能闻到车上的味道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛罕区每位捕狗队员都被狗咬过，还有的在抓狗过程中摔断腿。他们采用的工具是捞网，不同大小的狗采用不同型号的捞网，最大的要用拇指粗细的纤维绳网，“它们牙口很好，细的绳子一口咬断”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四川省射洪市综合行政执法局、青岛西海岸新区综合执法管理局均回复南方周末记者称，用来捕狗的工具主要为捞网。在网上流传的捕狗视频中，执法人员大都采用捞网，仅有一则出现车牌号为浙江台州的捕狗视频采用弯状夹钳。周威认为捞网是目前捕狗中比较合适的工具，本身质地较软，能困住犬只又不会带来太大伤害。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张勇称，流浪狗被捕后将送往公安部门管理的留检所收养，留检所在对狗进行检查后，交给城管队员回执单，上面会清楚写明接收数量和状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者致电呼和浩特市公安局犬类留检所，对方回复称，该所建有50亩的犬舍，目前能将接收的流浪猫狗养至自然死亡。此外，该所对外开放领养，可以在开放日前往参观、领养或捐赠物资。至于目前留检所的流浪猫狗数量，该工作人员说暂时无法提供详细数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;位于四川射洪的流浪毛孩子菩提护生园，则是一家民间运营的流浪猫狗基地，在深山里包下一块山头，分区域喂养流浪猫狗。2021年，该基地开始接收城管部门捕捉的流浪猫狗，每年20-30只，“零零星星地送过来，都是被投诉扰民以后被抓的。”该基地负责人任女士介绍，城管部门提供部分狗粮费用，猫狗送达之前会提前做好传染病检查，有伤病的则先到宠物医院医治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任女士说，射洪自10月20日起开展捕捉流浪猫狗的专项行动，仅一天便送来11只流浪狗。她有点担心短时间送来的猫狗太多，基地无法负荷。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;更精细、专业、科学&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月20日，郑州被抓的法斗已被带回老家领养，而郑州城管对媒体称该案还在走流程，罚款还未确定。关于法斗为何禁养的话题却在养狗圈里热烈地讨论，家养法斗多年的毛静从中看到城市在养狗方面的管理问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毛静称，上海的禁养名单中没有明确标注法斗，但法斗长期被视作斗牛犬的一种，在上海各区面临不同的管理办法。2014年她养第一只法斗，当时在杨浦区四平街道顺利办理犬证；2016年，毛静准备养第二只法斗，在同一区的江浦街道办理犬证时被驳回，毛静打电话申诉后才得以通过，“办理人员不太了解这个犬种”。2019年上海表示全市允许养法斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在郑州法斗事件后，她特意对比了郑州和上海的禁养犬名单，发现上海明确禁养英国斗牛犬，但不禁养法斗；而郑州明确禁养法斗，但不禁养英斗。毛静说两种狗的体型、烈性不一样，相较之下英斗体型能长到60-80斤，“这样即使不咬人，撞人一下可能也比较严重”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们国内其实没有通行的犬类标准认定。”周威说，在早期引进国外犬种时，可能存在对犬种的习性认知不高或者翻译问题。“其中体现管理滞后性。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国的宠物行业在十余年里跨越式发展，人与动物如何在城市共处的问题不断凸显。《2021年中国宠物行业白皮书》显示，2021年全国城镇宠物狗和宠物猫总数超过1.12亿只。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周威认为，目前在犬类管理方面，需要一套从源头开始，更为精细化、专业科学化的管理机制，比如在繁殖时就应该注意其品种基因以及如何训练的问题，而现在上游繁育阶段缺乏监管，到了养宠阶段才开始卡紧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜帆也持类似观点，他认为许多狗伤人事件可以追溯至源头：“为何被禁养的烈性犬仍然可以在市面上贩卖？”由此他建议从犬只出生到贩卖、饲养建立系列的监管机制，厘清部门责任主体和管理权责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周威则建议，当下破题可以从科普教育开始，例如给校园、物业提供专业的培训服务：如何应对小区内的烈犬，如何正确地安置和捕捉；可以给养狗人提供培训：如何科学认识及管束所养的宠物犬，等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜帆所在的武汉市小动物协会与当地公安部门达成合作，每月25日左右从留检所选择部分被捕捉的流浪狗向社会开放领养，呼吁“以领养代替购买”。杜帆说此前的两次领养活动举办顺利，全部留检狗狗被领养成功，“目前在准备第三次”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末记者高伊琛对本文亦有贡献，文中李明、毛静为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美经济工作组举行第一次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259175]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to He Lifeng, Vice Premier of the State Council and Chinese leader of China-US Economic and Trade, and Janet. Following the consensus reached by Yellen during her talks in Beijing in July, the China-US Economic Working Group held its first meeting via video on October 24. The meeting was chaired by officials at the deputy ministerial level of finance from the two countries. The two sides had in-depth, candid and constructive communication on issues such as the macroeconomic situation and policies of the two countries and the world, bilateral economic relations, and cooperation in responding to global challenges. China expressed its concerns. Both parties will continue to maintain communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“第一学历歧视”？别用这样的观念轻易否定企业丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259163]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, many media launched reports related to &quot;first degree discrimination&quot;. It is worth noting that on September 29, the Ministry of Education responded to a netizen’s question about “Whether the first degree after graduation is a junior college or a bachelor’s degree?” The concept of “first degree” is not used in the relevant policies and documents of the national education administration department regarding the learning experience of scientific and cultural education and skills training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an objective point of view, graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees from prestigious schools generally have some advantages in the job market. Needless to say, this may be &quot;first degree discrimination&quot; The realistic background in which relevant issues have received attention. But is similar recruitment behavior “merit-based” or “discriminatory”? It may not be possible to generalize, but the issues of corporate operational autonomy and employment autonomy that run through it are also important aspects worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, for graduate students from 985 universities, does the recruiting unit or human resources specialist make a clear employment choice based on the prerequisite of &quot;undergraduate degree from a prestigious school&quot;? This is actually hard to say. Especially as a for-profit organization, the company will ultimately look at whether the applicant&#39;s abilities and talents match the company&#39;s employment needs. It may also be that the company&#39;s interviewer confirms the match between the applicant&#39;s abilities and the company&#39;s needs through a comprehensive, complete and systematic assessment. . And graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees who have been blessed by famous schools may have shown certain advantages in this link and finally got the opportunity, but it may not necessarily be simple and crude academic qualifications that win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the recruitment process of the employer is that the human resources specialist will screen the resume before the interview. Only after passing the preliminary screening will he be qualified to participate in the initial interview hosted by the human resources department and even the professional interview hosted by the leader of the hiring department. interview. If some companies clearly stipulate in black and white that they will not recruit students with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; or are suspected of academic discrimination, if master&#39;s and doctoral graduates with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; can pass the resume screening, in this sense, 985 As a stepping stone, colleges and universities have already been used in the preliminary screening stage. The stepping stone is just a stepping stone. Next, it depends on whether the job seeker has real ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it should be noted that there is no need for society to over-amplify the halo blessing of the so-called &quot;first degree&quot;. Today, there are so many students graduating from 985 with undergraduate degrees. In the face of the severe employment situation, some Ph.D.s from Peking University have gone to compete for urban management personnel, and some have Ph.D.s from Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine to work as school doctors in middle schools. Undergraduate program 985 really does not have as dazzling aura and powerful blessing as some people imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, objectively speaking, students from undergraduate 985 colleges generally have some advantages in the job market compared to non-985 colleges. This itself also has a reasonable side. If this advantage does not exist, then the motivation for students to work hard to get into a good university may not exist, and there will be no difference between a good university and an average university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, on the surface, students have gained some advantages with the blessing of diplomas from 985 colleges, but the actual logic is the other way around: the ranking of college entrance examination scores and the distinction between prestigious schools and non-prestigious schools are Ranking of students’ intelligence and abilities. In this sense, it is generally the outstanding students who make the 985 colleges and universities successful, not the other way around. Therefore, the 985 diploma has an important signaling function and constitutes an important reference for employers to screen resumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are people with high scores and low abilities, and there are also people with low scores and high abilities; there are people who make mistakes in the college entrance examination, and there are also people who perform exceptionally well in the college entrance examination. However, firstly, it depends on whether it is a high probability or a small probability; secondly, In the end, everyone has to accept the test of the market and the employer. It depends on the real talent and hard work, whether it is a mule or a horse drawn out for a walk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enterprises are profit-making organizations, and they will ultimately look at whether the candidates’ abilities and talents match the company’s employment needs, and whether they can create higher value for the company. The HR and employing departments may take a high look at job seekers with 985 undergraduate degrees, but that’s all. Next, it depends on whether the job seekers’ performance in the interview meets their expectations for talents. Especially in free competition industries, companies have no incentive to leave more capable non-985 undergraduate job seekers and instead use incompetent 985 undergraduate job seekers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there are two people, one has a non-985 degree + 985 graduate school, and the other has a 985 degree + 985 graduate school, and the company does not admit the former but admits the latter, does it become &quot;first degree discrimination&quot;? I&#39;m afraid not so. Job seekers and employers are two-way choices. Reaching a consensus respects the rights of both parties and improves market efficiency. By extension, if job seekers themselves are very capable, but they want to go to a high-paying unit but not to a low-wage unit, does this constitute discrimination against the latter? Even if it is, it is efficiency discrimination and should be justified. Just as when people get married, they would rather find someone with good family conditions than someone with poor conditions. This cannot be said to be discrimination against the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, under the severe employment situation, the key to giving students more and better job opportunities is to inspire entrepreneurs’ confidence and expectations for the future, so that they dare to invest real money Pay attention to expand investment and create more and better jobs. This requires respecting entrepreneurs&#39; autonomy in business operations and employment, and not denying the right of enterprises to &quot;select the best&quot; at every turn and weakening entrepreneurs&#39; motivation and confidence in investing and making bets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If companies are not allowed to show their recruitment preferences, there are only two consequences: First, companies hide their preferences in the short term but write them down in their hearts. This is nothing more than making job seekers do more useless work, which is detrimental to job hunting. Is it really good? Second, in the long run, companies will feel that the business environment and conceptual environment are not good, and they will be more cautious in investing and making bets. The process of job creation will be affected. What benefits will it bring to job seekers? In short, society should create a relaxed and rational conceptual environment for entrepreneurs, allowing them to use their intelligence and real money to promote our economy, which will ultimately benefit every job seeker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:01:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[触碰寻亲直播间里的伤痛 | 记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259121]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 14, 2023, Guiyang, Guizhou, four people searched for relatives The parents drove from Kunming, Yunnan, and traveled thousands of kilometers to find their son. (Southern Weekend reporter Liu Yixian/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Interview with Yang Niuhua’s abduction case (for details, see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com /content/253854&quot;>;Human trafficker Yu Huaying was sentenced to death: she abducted 11 children and even sold her own son&lt;/a>;&quot;), this was the first time I got close to parents looking for relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of July 14, 2023, Yu Huaying, a human trafficker who abducted Yang Niuhua, was tried at the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Guiyang City, Guizhou Province. Outside the court, people looking for relatives stood outside. Parents. Most of them wore white shirts with photos of their babies printed on them, and held missing persons signs with yellow characters on a red background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Looking for his son Li Xianfang&quot;, &quot;Looking for his sons An Xu and An Biao&quot;, &quot;Marshmallow dad looking for his daughter Chen Yangmei&quot;... Each missing person sign is marked with The child’s date of birth, time of loss, physical characteristics at the time of loss, etc. Behind the sign, there were mostly sad faces, as if their facial features were drooped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While waiting, some parents looking for relatives were also doing live broadcasts, introducing netizens to the progress of the trial and what was going on outside the court, interspersed with &lt;span>;&lt; /span>;Tell how your child was lost, where you went to find your child, and how you got here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I greeted several of the parents, informed the reporter of my identity, and recorded an interview video nearby. After that, as soon as I raised my cell phone to record the video, the parents next to me immediately came up to me, walked around holding the missing persons sign, and occasionally chatted. They know how to &quot;grab traffic&quot; and show their face at any possible opportunity to increase their exposure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This eagerness became more obvious after Yang Niuhua appeared. Parents looking for relatives swarmed up almost in a swarm, surrounding them from front to back, holding signs next to each other. Several times, Yang Niuhua was submerged in the family-seeking signs, and reporters could not find her at all. In the chaos, some parents thrust their missing persons tags into Yang Niuhua&#39;s hands, while others hung a backpack with missing family information on her body. Yang Niuhua understood the mood of these parents looking for relatives and did not refuse. These parents travel around all year round and appear in various hot scenes, striving to let their children see themselves and see that &quot;Mom and Dad are always looking for you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of the day when the trial ended, I knocked on the door of Yang Niuhua’s room, but I was surprised to find that the room was crowded with parents looking for relatives, on the beds and chairs. , the floor, and every corner were filled with people. They are all waiting in line to go to Yang Niuhua&#39;s live broadcast room to introduce their search for relatives. After Yang Niuhua successfully searched for relatives online in 2021, she attracted a lot of attention and accumulated more than 300,000 fans on the short video platform. On important days like court hearings, she is also willing to use her traffic to allow parents to go to the live broadcast room to spread information about finding relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I sat down next to an aunt in her 50s and watched the live broadcast of people coming and going in the room. It was still mid-summer in July, and this aunt was wearing a long-sleeved pullover with her child’s information printed on it, and several pieces of clothing underneath. After some conversation, she said that she was from the Buyi ethnic group in Guizhou and was born with a disability in her left foot, making it difficult for her to walk long distances. But her husband was ill and bedridden, so she had no choice but to go out alone to find the child. As she spoke, she took off her left boot, revealing that the foot was deformed and looked unbearable. It’s hard to imagine how she followed the family search team to various places in Fujian and Guizhou these days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is another &quot;marshmallow dad&quot; who impressed me deeply. His daughter was born in 2003 and disappeared in Kunming, Yunnan when she was 3 years old. When Yang Niuhua was being interviewed after the trial, he stood behind Yang Niuhua and suddenly cried uncontrollably. The sound got louder and louder, and finally he squatted on the ground and cried bitterly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For many years, &quot;Marshmallow Daddy&quot; has been doing business in a minivan, selling marshmallows while looking for children, while his wife sells balloons at home to support her life. On the homepage of &quot;Marshmallow Daddy&quot;&#39;s video account, he has been to multiple recognition sites where his family search was successful. The village supermarket in Rongjiang, Guizhou was a hot spot those days. He rushed to the village supermarket to look for his children. In order to save money, the four parents who were looking for relatives cooked their own meals along the way, setting up stoves and shelves in the open air to cook. The four of them spent more than 20 yuan a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finding relatives is difficult, and parents searching for relatives hate human traffickers. But they have different views on adoptive families. Some people support the same crime of buying and selling and believe that the person responsible for supporting the family should be held accountable. But more parents will emphasize that they just want to see their children, and they do not ask the children to return to their biological families, nor do they hold them responsible for supporting the family. A very important reason is that many abducted children are afraid of hurting the feelings of their adoptive parents and are unwilling to take the initiative to find relatives, which will increase the difficulty of finding relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Yu Huaying&#39;s child abduction case, there are still several abducted children who are unwilling to formally recognize their relatives. They are trapped in complex family relationships and do not know what to do. There are also abducted children who have recognized their parents and are not close to their parents. The parent-child relationship is empty and it is not clear where to build it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the family search live broadcast room, parents called on their children who had doubts about their parentage to go to the public security bureau to collect blood and enter it into the family search database, so that one day they can successfully identify their relatives. , &quot;If you want to come back, come back. If you don&#39;t want to come back, you can stay and support your family.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;This sentence may be full of pain and pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I wish them an early reunion with their loved ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>