<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“中国乞讨者泰国被捕”背后：残酷的人口贩运链]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261387]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Facial disfigurement, physical disabilities... In recent days, several Chinese beggars have appeared on the streets of Bangkok. Putting Thailand at the forefront of public opinion has also launched a new round of crackdowns on illegal begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, Aung Munna, deputy director of the Bangkok Metropolitan Police Department in Thailand, announced at a press conference that from November 10 to 20, the Bangkok police arrested six Chinese beggars. , and all six of them had varying degrees of disfigurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the physical conditions, confessions and partial investigation results of the six beggars when they were arrested, the Thai police suspected that these beggars may be victims of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Begging is prohibited in Thailand, but begging on the streets has always existed. Data from the Thai Ministry of Social Development and Human Security show that from 2016 to the present, 7,151 beggars have been found in Thailand, including 2,473 foreign beggars, most of whom are Cambodians and Burmese, and 68 are Chinese citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the beggars wandering the streets of Thailand are forced to beg because of human trafficking. According to the Thai charity Der Spiegel Foundation, there are at least 1,000 trafficked child beggars in Thailand. The &quot;Global Trafficking in Persons Report&quot; released by the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime also pointed out that of the 36,488 victims of human trafficking detected in 2020, 0.7% were for exploitative begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in Thailand responded, “The Embassy has taken note of the relevant reports and has sent consular officials to conduct consular visits to the parties. China has always required Chinese citizens coming to Thailand to abide by Thai laws. , respect local customs, and also attach importance to safeguarding their legitimate rights and interests. We believe that the relevant departments of the Thai government and the police will find out the truth as soon as possible and handle it appropriately in accordance with the law.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who is behind the scenes? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The arrest of a Chinese beggar was inseparable from the report of Thai Internet celebrity Guntouch Pongpaiboonwet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guntouch is active on Facebook. He has long been concerned about social issues in Thailand and has 730,000 fans. On November 19, 2023, Guntouch learned that a woman wearing a student uniform and a deformed face was begging in the Pin Klao area of ​​Bangkok. He suspected that international human trafficking might be involved, so he reported it to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, the Thai police arrested the female beggar. When she was arrested, she was carrying a backpack, a chair, a money box and a key card. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Thai vendor who has been operating a store in a shopping mall for more than ten years told the police that she only started to find beggars wearing student uniforms begging nearby this year. &quot;The arrested Chinese beggars are not alone. She appears early in the morning with other beggars and doesn&#39;t leave until evening.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports stated that the female beggar told the police that she went to Thailand to beg on November 10. She said that she was divorced and had two sons to raise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the woman was arrested, another Chinese woman claimed to be the beggar&#39;s translator and came to the police station to release her on bail, but was refused by the Thai police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman is not the only illegal beggar arrested by Thai police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of November 20, Thai police arrested a total of six Chinese beggars in Bangkok. According to the Thai Immigration Bureau, the six beggars entered Thailand on different flights from mainland China, Hong Kong, Malaysia and Laos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the investigation continues, more details are emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thailand police investigation found that these beggars began to enter Thailand on tourist visas in June, and one of them was applying for a private university in northern Thailand. If your tourist visa is converted to a student visa, you will be able to extend your stay in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, beggars daily beg in crowded shopping malls and tourist attractions, earning about 10,000 baht (approximately RMB 2,000) per person per day. The police investigated the bank account of one of the women and found that the monthly flow was as high as 2 million baht (approximately RMB 400,000). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to comprehensive media reports, the six arrested beggars were around 40 years old, and all had facial scars and disabilities in their limbs. One of the beggars told the police that his facial injuries and hand disabilities were old childhood injuries caused by the explosion of flammable items, while the others refused to provide relevant information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, there are inextricably linked relationships between these beggars. Thai police found that two of the beggars lived in the Wang Thonglang area, and the rest lived in different hotels in Bangkok. This is inconsistent with the previous arrest of a woman who said she had no fixed abode. Meanwhile, some beggars share the same Thai translation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Thai police suspect that these beggars may be victims of international human trafficking, and that there may be Thai support behind the begging gang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, one beggar has been deported from Thailand, and the remaining beggars are still detained at the Immigration Bureau. Major General Panta, deputy director of the Thai Immigration Department, said that the investigation into the gang involved is being expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Thailand’s campaign against illegal begging continues to deepen. Media reports said that Thai police arrested four more beggars in Bangkok, from Laos and Cambodia. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Countries of origin, destination and transit of human trafficking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Begging is illegal in Thailand. As early as 2016, Thailand introduced the &quot;Begging Control Law&quot; in an attempt to eliminate illegal beggars on the streets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this law, foreign beggars who beg in Thailand will be deported, while domestic beggars will be forced to receive vocational training or be sent to reception centers. Those who attempt to profit from organizing street begging will face up to three years in prison and/or a fine of up to 30,000 baht. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in order to combat street begging, Thailand has carried out many street cleaning operations in recent years. According to reports, in May 2023, the Pattaya police in Thailand arrested 37 Cambodian beggars, including 19 adults and 18 children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Thai officials, strict measures against street begging are to prevent illegal begging from breeding many criminal problems such as human trafficking and child labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in fact, Thailand, known as the &quot;Land of Smiles&quot;, has long been plagued by the dark trade of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, the U.S. State Department released the &quot;Trafficking in Persons Report&quot;, which ranked Thailand as the third lowest ranking, which means that the Thai government did not fully comply with the minimum standards in responding to and eliminating human trafficking, and No significant effort was made. Meanwhile, the U.S. State Department noted that Thailand is a source, destination and transit country for men, women and children subject to forced labor and sex trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thailand is located in the center of Southeast Asia and is a destination for illegal immigrants from many neighboring countries seeking high-paying jobs. The United Nations International Organization for Migration estimates that there are nearly 5 million immigrants in Thailand, of which about 1 million to 2.5 million do not have legal immigration status. Lacking legal protection, these illegal immigrants are extremely vulnerable to work exploitation, human smuggling and trafficking, and transnational crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, the &quot;Golden Triangle&quot; connecting Thailand, Myanmar and Laos has been a hotbed of illegal activity, with Thailand a convenient location for traffickers to transport victims to other countries. Reports indicate that sex trafficking victims from Bangladesh, Pakistan, Vietnam and North Korea transit through Thailand to Western Europe, Singapore, Russia and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also difficult for the Thai people themselves to escape the nightmare of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that as of July 2020, more than 120,000 Thais are still working abroad. &quot;Many Thais prefer to seek easier but illegal jobs abroad, which makes them easy targets for human traffickers and easy to be exploited by unscrupulous employers,&quot; said Samann, a senior fellow at the Institute of Asia Studies at Chulalongkorn University in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Thomson Reuters Foundation estimates that at least 522 Thai workers died in South Korea from 2015 to 2022, about 84% of whom were illegal immigrants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to change the status quo, in 2018, the Thai police teamed up with social workers and non-governmental organizations to set up a special working group to combat human trafficking. At the same time, the Thai government is increasing its financial budget every year. In 2022, the Thai government will allocate 440 million baht to prevent and combat human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from official data, the problem of human trafficking in Thailand seems to have improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the U.S. State Department released the latest version of the &quot;Trafficking in Persons Report&quot;, and Thailand&#39;s ranking rose to the second level. This is the second consecutive year that Thailand has ranked second. Thailand&#39;s Minister of Social Development and Human Security Waravutt noted that Thailand has been committed to improving to Level 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in 2022, the Thai government investigated 253 cases of human trafficking and identified 444 victims of human trafficking. The vast majority of these 444 victims are from Thailand (344) and ASEAN countries such as Laos, Myanmar, and Indonesia. Another 11 are from China, Uganda, Tanzania, Uzbekistan, Kenya, and other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the data released by the Thai government may be just the tip of the iceberg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. State Department pointed out in the 2023 &quot;Human Trafficking Report&quot; that fraud companies located in Cambodia, Laos, Myanmar and the Philippines often use Thailand as a transit country to lure fraudsters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Myawaddy, located on the border of Thailand and Myanmar, is one of the main gathering places for fraud parks, across the river from Mae Sot, Thailand. Mechel Moore, CEO of the Mae Sot Anti-Human Trafficking NGO, told reporters that since August 2022, the organization has helped at least 452 victims of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that behind human trafficking in Thailand, there are often government officials, who facilitate human trafficking by accepting bribes. In 2022 alone, 35 government officials were investigated by the Thai government for their involvement in human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马航MH370乘客家属索赔案今天开庭审理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:52:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Malaysian Airlines flight MH370 is a Boeing 777 aircraft formerly operated by Malaysia Airlines. It was flown by Malaysia on March 8, 2014. Contact was lost en route from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing. There were 239 passengers and crew on the flight, including 154 Chinese passengers. On January 29, 2015, the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced that MH370 had crashed and 239 people on board were presumed to have died. Today (November 27), this air transport damage liability dispute case was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that more than 40 family members of passengers have filed lawsuits, and the cases will be heard in Beijing Chaoyang Court from November 27 to December 6. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attorney for the passengers’ families said that there are five defendants in this case, namely Malaysia Airlines, also known as the old Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia International Airlines Co., Ltd. also known as the new Malaysia Airlines, Boeing Company of the United States, and Aircraft Engines Manufacturers: Rolls-Royce in the UK and Allianz in Germany. The claims of the more than 40 passengers&#39; families are different, but they mainly focus on two points. One is to find out the truth about the missing incident of flight MH370 through case trial, and the other is the issue of compensation. It is understood that the biggest difficulty in the trial of this case is to ascertain the truth of the incident. &lt;p>; . The current inability to produce evidence, insufficient evidence, or incomplete evidence is a huge hole left in the trial process of this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the amount of civil compensation filed by the passengers’ families is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. Because each family’s situation is different, the amount is also different. A large part of the compensation fee is mental damage solatium. , the highest is 30 to 40 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also understood that in addition to the family members of more than 40 passengers who filed the lawsuit in Beijing Chaoyang Court, the family members of more than 110 other passengers have reached settlements with the five defendants and signed settlement agreements. The amount received ranged from 2.5 million to 3 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人民银行等八部门联合印发《关于强化金融支持举措 助力民营经济发展壮大的通知》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261389]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:37:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party and the requirements of the Central Financial Work Conference, comprehensively implement the &quot; The Opinions of the Central Committee and the State Council on Promoting the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; adhere to the &quot;two unwavering principles&quot; and guide financial institutions to establish the concept of &quot;equal treatment&quot; and continue to strengthen financial services for private enterprises. Recently, the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the China Securities Regulatory Commission Eight departments including the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Finance, and the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Financial Support Measures to Support the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;), proposing that 25 specific measures to support the private economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; clarifies the goals and priorities of financial services private enterprises. In terms of total amount, by formulating annual service targets for private enterprises and increasing the weight of services related to private enterprises in performance appraisals, we will increase financial support for private enterprises and gradually increase the proportion of loans to private enterprises. Structurally, we will increase support for key areas such as technological innovation, &quot;specialization, specialization, specialization, green and low carbon, and industrial base reengineering projects, as well as for private small, medium and micro enterprises.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; emphasizes the need to proceed from the characteristics of private enterprises&#39; financing needs and strive to unblock diversified financing channels such as credit, bonds, and equity. Banking financial institutions should increase their support for first-time loans and credit loans, actively carry out industrial chain and supply chain financial services, proactively provide fund continuity services to private enterprises, and not blindly suspend, suppress, withdraw or cut off loans, and at the same time, Promote development and prevent risks. Optimize the registration mechanism for private enterprise debt financing instruments, give full play to the role of private enterprise bond financing support tools, and expand the scale of private enterprise bond financing. Encourage and guide institutional investors to actively and scientifically allocate private enterprise bonds and increase investment in private enterprise bonds. Support the listing financing and mergers and acquisitions of private enterprises, give full play to the supporting service role of regional equity markets and equity investment funds for private enterprises, and expand the scale of equity financing for high-quality private enterprises. Increase the supply of foreign exchange facilitation policies and services, and support private enterprises in &quot;going out&quot; and &quot;bringing in&quot; by improving the level of facilitation of current account receipts and payments, improving cross-border investment and financing facilitation policies, and optimizing cross-border financial foreign exchange special services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; proposes that monetary policy tools, fiscal incentives, insurance guarantees and other measures should be comprehensively used to enhance the enthusiasm of financial institutions in serving the private economy. Strengthen departmental cooperation, improve credit information sharing, financing guarantees, convenient bill discounting, accounts receivable rights confirmation, taxation and other supporting policies and mechanisms, and enhance the private economic and financial carrying capacity. Financial institutions should strengthen publicity and interpretation, and proactively push financial support policies, financial products and service information to private enterprises. Local financial management, development and reform, industry and information technology, finance and taxation, federation of industry and commerce and other departments have strengthened communication and coordination, strengthened supervision and guidance, and improved policy effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the People&#39;s Bank of China and other departments will guide financial institutions to promptly implement the requirements of the &quot;Notice&quot; and formulate specific implementation rules. At the same time, they will strengthen statistical monitoring and policy effect evaluation to ensure that the policy benefits private enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/dc1c48c7099df8f07e8e225042aef088.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;760&quot; height=&quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/dc1c48c7099df8f07e8e225042aef088.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259746&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Website screenshot&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融业“百模大战”正酣，如何在合规中突围？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261381]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The financial industry is entering a big model moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2023, China Merchants Union Finance and Sun Yat-sen University jointly developed and launched the first 13 billion parameter open source large model in the consumer finance industry-&quot;China Merchants Union Smart Deer&quot;. This is the fourth public large-scale model of the consumer finance industry after Du Xiaoman, Masha Consumption and Ant Financial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, traditional financial institutions are also accelerating the application of large models. Some large technology companies are looking to cooperate with financial institutions. The “battle of hundreds of models” in the financial industry is in full swing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How effective is the implementation of large-scale financial models? What are the challenges? What impact will it have on the future financial ecosystem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center investigated various mainstream financial institutions, tested the apps of various financial institutions, and reviewed the speeches of guests at major professional forums in 2023. They found that in the second half of 2023, financial institutions will accelerate Lay out large-scale models, and the main application areas are intelligent customer service, investment strategies, risk control, investment consulting and investment education, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But currently, cooperation between technology companies and financial institutions is the mainstream model. In this cooperation, financial institutions are not only worried about the business effects of large models, but also have concerns about data security and compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that large models in the financial industry are still in the trial and promotion stage, but the trend is irreversible. A researcher at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center put forward three suggestions for this: promoting &quot;industry-university-research&quot; collaboration, accelerating legislation, and paying attention to talent training. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Financial large models are blooming everywhere&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is special about financial large models? The authoritative international artificial intelligence magazine &quot;Nature Machine Intelligence&quot; believes that large models refer to &quot;deep learning pre-training algorithms&quot; with parameter scales reaching more than 100 million levels. General-purpose large models require huge computing resources and data volumes, and require extremely high technical teams and financial support. They are key projects for major domestic and foreign technology companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vertical domain model focuses on specific industries, fields or scenarios. Therefore, large models in vertical fields have relatively low requirements for computing power and algorithms, but have higher requirements for data in specific fields. Financial large models are typical large models in vertical fields. As a modern high-end service industry, the financial industry has the characteristics of huge data volume and rich scenarios, which is naturally consistent with the large model&#39;s demand for massive high-quality data. Therefore, the financial industry has become one of the first scenarios where large models have been implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2023, domestic financial institutions will accelerate the layout of large models. In addition to banks, insurance companies and leading securities firms have gradually joined the &quot;Battle of Hundreds of Models&quot;. It is worth noting that consumer finance companies have also begun to compete in the battle for large models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incomplete statistics from researchers at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center show that among the 19 systemically important banks, more than half have announced that they have released large models or are in the process of intense preparations. Consumer finance companies such as Masha Consumption, Ant Financial and China Merchants Union Financial have also successively released large financial models and claim to be in a leading position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/TAZxT7BMDWTBFDbso4wRVgvJjAFCEpyPES4cNKpx.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height= &quot;425&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/TAZxT7BMDWTBFDbso4wRVgvJjAFCEpyPES4cNKpx.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different financial institutions What are the similarities and differences between large models? Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that from industry practice, except for a few leading financial institutions such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China that are developing large models of the financial industry, other small and medium-sized financial institutions generally choose to cooperate with large cloud vendors. Pilot a certain business scenario. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further research by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that smart customer service has almost become a standard feature of financial institutions, such as the &quot;smart teller&quot; of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, the &quot;Bank&quot; of China Construction Bank, and the &quot;digital employee sisters&quot; of Bank of Communications. &quot;Jiaojiao&quot; and &quot;Xiaojiao&quot;, Jiangsu Bank&#39;s &quot;Smart Xiaosu&quot;, etc. In addition, different financial institutions use AI technology in the fields of investment, risk control, investment consulting and investment education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development models, cooperation with third parties is still the mainstream model for financial institutions to develop large models. Financial institutions currently mainly cooperate with technology giants such as Baidu, Tencent, Alibaba and Huawei, as well as universities such as Tsinghua University and Peking University, as well as financial technology companies such as Hundsun Electronics and Yuxin Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with independent research and development, cooperative research and development is relatively cost-effective. Xu Dongliang, CTO of Duxiaoman, said that training a general-purpose large model with a scale of hundreds of billions costs tens of millions per time. Earlier, some institutional media reported that GPT-4’s training time was close to 100 days, and the training cost was as high as 63 million US dollars. In other words, training can be carried out up to three times a year, and each time costs about 450 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can small and medium-sized financial institutions implement large models? Huawei released a report titled &quot;Digital Finance: Leading Intelligent Change and Building the Future of Digital Finance Together&quot;. It is recognized in the industry that when the number of large model parameters reaches 62 billion parameters, there will be a surge in capabilities. At present, many open source large models have directly supported parameter sets of tens of billions or even 62 billion, significantly lowering the threshold for AI training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/Qx8S0ybfmS8cDHVoJ4Gt1pUK81Mbjh3UMzQCeRDZ.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height= &quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/Qx8S0ybfmS8cDHVoJ4Gt1pUK81Mbjh3UMzQCeRDZ.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a technical perspective See, pursuing large model parameter scale is not the best choice for small and medium-sized financial institutions. Although in theory, the larger the parameter scale of a large model, the stronger its capabilities, but the purpose of developing large models is to empower business and serve customers, not to show off skills. Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that small and medium-sized financial institutions do not need to &quot;roll out&quot; technology. They can choose billion-level, tens of billions, or even billion-level large-scale model pilots for a certain business scenario, giving full play to the organizational flexibility advantages of small and medium-sized financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Under the cooperation model, the two parties have great differences&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;With the support of AI, the digital transformation of the financial industry is accelerating, but large models have a negative impact on financial business. The empowerment needs to be further verified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that under the cooperation model, financial institutions are mainly concerned about three issues: first, efficiency; second, security; and third, compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of efficiency, digital and intelligent overall solutions that integrate the front, middle and back offices are the core demands of financial institutions. In the recent Financial Street Forum, industry experts also discussed this issue. When Zhai Chenxi, former vice president of Tianfeng Securities, served as a judge for the finals of the third global financial technology application scenario competition, he pointed out that the biggest problem faced by financial institutions is that no one does the integration, resulting in inconsistent data interfaces in the front, middle and back offices, and data cannot be shared. This leads to an increase in internal communication costs to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center tested a number of financial institution apps and found that even in the customer service business where large models are most widely used, there are still many problems. For example, inaccurate answers, repeated answers, etc. Some can only accept &quot;yes or no&quot; answers and cannot understand synonymous expressions. In addition, financial institution apps use intelligent customer service to over-market, such as using robocalls to frequently harass customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Dongliang pointed out at the Financial Street Forum that when implementing large-scale financial model scenarios, five key issues still need to be addressed: first, how to choose the basic model; second, how to use the financial institution’s own business data Integrating into large models; the third is how to control model defects such as hallucination problems; the fourth is how institutions can build competition barriers when every institution will deploy large models in the future. The fifth is how to ensure the safety and compliance of the model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to security, financial institutions have large amounts of market data, transaction data, and customer data. The importance of data security and privacy protection is self-evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Jifeng, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, once pointed out at the 2023 INCLUSION Bund Conference that the security issues of large models are mainly the collection, use and disclosure of personal information without consent. Privacy issues may occur during the training process or during use, and the generation ability of large models diversifies the ways of &quot;privacy leakage&quot;, making privacy protection more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of compliance, although cooperating with cloud service providers and purchasing their model training services is a shortcut for financial AI training, the financial industry is a highly regulated industry, and data involving key businesses is often subject to compliance pressure. And it is difficult to upload to the public cloud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jun, senior vice president of Bairong Yunchuang, also said that there are two main trends in data compliance. One is external risks, including whether data use is in compliance with laws and regulations, hackers and criminal gangs Malicious attacks, etc.; the second is internal risks, especially data leakage risks caused by operational risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; that will be implemented from August 15, 2023 balances technological development and regulatory needs and reflects the equal emphasis of legislators on encouragement and supervision. concept. It is expected that the implementation of the &quot;Measures&quot; will bring more legal protection and institutional innovation to the development of China&#39;s generative artificial intelligence service field. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ecological co-construction is the way out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How can large-scale financial models that are still in the trial and promotion stage move toward industrial-level R&amp;D applications? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hundsun Electronics’ survey found that 67% of financial institutions prefer cooperation at the application layer, and the application areas they are most concerned about are investment advisory assistants (56%), compliance and internal control (44%), and investment research (25%) ), while customer service accounts for only 10%. This is partly due to the deep application of AI in the customer service field, but more importantly, it reflects the expectations of financial institutions for large models to empower core businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As financial large models move toward industrial-level research and development, ecological co-construction should be emphasized. This point has been repeatedly echoed in the opinions of experts at major professional forums in 2023. For example, the 2023 China Intelligent Finance Forum even launched the &quot;Financial Large Model Ecological Plan&quot; on-site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Dongliang believes that the industrial application of large financial models requires the joint construction and participation of scenario users (financial institutions), model providers, training tool providers and other parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talent is the key. At the Financial Cloud Special Session of the 2023 Tencent Global Digital Ecosystem Conference, Tencent Cloud Vice President Hu Liming pointed out that leading financial institutions are now recruiting algorithm PhDs. Although they can leverage cloud vendors, in the end financial institutions must have independent use and innovation Ability to lead the construction, optimization and continuous addition of new application scenarios for large AI platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Cunchao, Director of the Third Department of the North Research Platform of the R&amp;D Center of the Agricultural Bank of China, also said that in the in-depth application of large models in the financial industry, especially in-depth applications embedded in financial scenarios, data is the core and security is the prerequisite. , computing power is the foundation, scenarios are the driving force, talents are the key, and collaboration is the guarantee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the application of large models is an irreversible long-term development trend and a key strategy to accelerate the transformation of digital finance and promote high-quality financial development. However, this is a holistic, It is a systematic and long-term project, so we cannot rush for quick success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, compliance and data security cannot be ignored. In the process of digital finance transformation, financial institutions need to be alert to compliance risks and balance the relationship between innovation and security. In data governance, clear boundaries and clear rules are the basis for consensus among all parties. Otherwise, differences will be amplified and development will be hindered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center put forward three suggestions: First, promote &quot;industry-university-research&quot; collaboration. Strengthen peer and cross-sector exchanges and cooperation, formulate standards, standardize processes, and create and share together. The second is to speed up legislation. The European Artificial Intelligence Law has been implemented, and the draft of the Chinese version of the Artificial Intelligence Law is also under review. The third is to attach importance to talent cultivation. Talent reserves restrict the implementation of AI development, because not only early-stage R&amp;D requires professional talents, but later-stage operations and maintenance also require talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[该在小学阶段把体育变主科吗？不要忘掉强身健体的初衷丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261373]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The official website of the Ministry of Education shows: Representatives of the People&#39;s Congress proposed &quot;About changing the physical education subject from a minor subject to a main subject, and providing free distribution to primary school students&quot; Physical Education Textbook Suggestions”. The Ministry of Education responded: There is no priority among the subjects prescribed in the national curriculum plan. Each subject has its own unique educational value and cannot be substituted for each other. At the same time, each subject cooperates with each other to educate students collaboratively to ensure the achievement of training goals. Physical education and health courses are an important part of the basic education curriculum system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the reply from the Ministry of Education, &quot;there is no distinction between primary and secondary subjects&quot; avoiding the distinction between major subjects and minor subjects; the statement that &quot;each subject has its unique educational value&quot; is also correct. However, it is still necessary to discuss the common understanding of what is a major subject and what is a minor subject. As far as primary schools are concerned, the main subjects generally recognized by the public are nothing more than Chinese, mathematics and foreign languages, and the minor subjects are nothing more than physical education, art and music. There are two specific criteria for classification: first, teaching time, the main subject generally has more teaching time than minor subjects; second, the main subject will have a closed-book examination, and the results will be included in the total score of the mid-term, final and entrance exams to become an outstanding student or to be promoted. The standards of a good school. The latter criterion is more commonly used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Compulsory Education Curriculum Plan and Curriculum Standards (2022 Edition)&quot; stipulates that the proportion of total class hours in nine years is 20%-22% for Chinese, which is very high, 13%-15% for mathematics, and 13%-15% for foreign languages. 6%-8%, physical education and health 10%-11%, more than foreign languages, science or physics, chemistry 8%-10%, according to the Ministry of Education, this proportion, &quot;higher than the United States , Australia, Germany, Russia, South Korea, Japan, Finland, the United Kingdom, Canada and other countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, from the perspective of teaching time, physical education is already the main subject in the compulsory education stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the primary promotion from primary school to junior high school is mainly based on interviews and admissions to the nearest &quot;good junior high school&quot; and admission by lottery, there is no unified examination for primary school to junior high school. In this sense, it seems meaningless to talk about major subjects and minor subjects at the primary school level. Because there are no exams. However, there are also some good schools that conduct the so-called &quot;secret test&quot; or resume + interview to obtain good students. Of course, the test is still on traditional cultural subjects or main subjects such as language and mathematics, and will not test physical education. In this sense, primary schools Stage physical education is a minor subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, junior high school is very different. Physical education must be included in the total score of the high school entrance examination. The original intention is to make children pay attention to sports. The score is not low. Under one physical education subject, there are many test items, which is essentially equivalent to taking several tests. In order to get high scores or even perfect scores, schools and parents force children to take exams, which increases the academic burden instead of reducing it. &quot;Junior high school students in the gym&quot; have even become a strange sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially parents in urban areas spend a lot of money to hire private tutors for their children, which has led to a skyrocketing fee for various sports coaches. This essentially requires junior high school students to be trained according to athlete standards. Extensive training and overtraining have resulted in a large number of sports injuries for children, such as knee meniscus injuries, which is detrimental to children&#39;s physical health, growth and development, and is contrary to physical fitness. The positioning of fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because mass sports and competitive sports are completely different things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Popular sports are suitable for everyone. They are designed to allow the body to have necessary activities, to allow muscles to exercise, move the muscles and bones, and strengthen the body. Even if you participate in some ball games or track and field events, the level of It is also amateur-level; at the same time, exercisers can breathe fresh air outdoors, establish a connection with nature, and repair their body and mind; it is also often a social activity that meets the need for interactive connections with others and helps promote mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competitive sports are played by a very small number of people with athletic talent. They are essentially a breakthrough in the limits of human physical ability. Among many competitive sports, many commercially successful industries and profit models have emerged. Including selling tickets + selling broadcast rights + advertising endorsements, etc., the income of top sports stars is very high; large-scale events such as the Olympics are participated in by countries and regions, and they have a higher meaning. Athletes winning medals are regarded as bringing glory to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the sports for students in ordinary primary and secondary schools should be a type of mass sports, which allows students to go outdoors more and strengthen their bodies. It is best to have their own favorite projects and get the benefits from sports. Fun and spiritual joy, under the blue sky and sun, soothing the body and mind and cultivating the spirit, this is something everyone can do. Children who are talented in sports and are interested in making a career in competitive sports can enter specialized sports schools to bring out their talents and potential. Being physically strong is only a very basic requirement. In short, the two types of schools have completely different requirements for student physical education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If physical education is included in the total score of mid-term and final exams at the primary school level and becomes the so-called &quot;main subject&quot;, it will only be counterproductive. Working hard to train in events you don’t like in order to get high scores. Overtraining and improper training often lead to sports injuries. Physical education classes will become hard labor, and children will not feel the joy of sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, recess has this tendency. It was originally intended to allow children more time to exercise, but many schools insist on making it ritualistic, pursuing uniformity and grandeur. Instead, children view recess as a daunting prospect. Sports activities should be relaxing and fun, so that they can exercise the body and mind. Fun, meaningful physical activity is itself a natural medicine for maintaining and promoting mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, many children have psychological problems. One of the reasons is that families and schools force children to take exams in knowledge education, and parents neglect character education and values ​​education for their children. The second reason is that children generally need to Strengthen the cultivation of physical and mental repair mechanisms and habits. In fact, what children now lack is not physical activity time, but physical activity time that is fun, meaningful, can release their nature, and can soothe the body and mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the high school entrance examinations in ordinary junior high schools, it is the right direction for various places to change the physical education examination from a merit-based examination to a standard examination in 2022, so that children do not need to work hard on the physical education examination items, consume too much or even Destroy your own body just for high scores; only specialized sports schools need to select the best to stimulate the talents of good talents and continue to work towards challenging the limits of human physical fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川两县禁止“私熏腊肉”：尊重民众传统权利，或可推无烟熏制丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261371]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, two counties in Bazhong, Sichuan have banned citizens from smoking bacon privately and required them to smoke bacon at designated centralized smoking points. Officials The response was to prevent air pollution. To ban a traditional food preparation method and folk custom that has lasted for more than a thousand years on the grounds of environmental protection is to ignore the traditional rights of the people and is even suspected of rent-seeking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tongjiang and Nanjiang counties in Bazhong, Sichuan, have recently issued notices prohibiting self-smoking of pickled products in urban areas. Those who need to smoke must go to designated centralized smoking points for smoking. Violators may be fined. There is a service charge for curing bacon at centralized smoking sites, and of the two centralized smoking sites announced in Tongjiang County, one clearly states that it only smokes meat products purchased from the company. The officially designated centralized smoking point is suspected of administrative monopoly and profit transfer, which has attracted great attention on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau responded that smoking bacon during the winter festival is a local custom, but the smoke produced during smoking seriously affects the ambient air quality. In order to improve the urban ambient air quality, Eliminate safety hazards and therefore set up centralized smoking points. The response also stated that the statement in the original notice that a centralized smoking site only smoked meat products purchased from the company reflected lax control and work errors. After consultation with the company, the smoking site was opened to the public. The staff of the Nanjiang County Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau also told the media that they have paid attention to online discussions, and the leaders are meeting to study. The results will be announced to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not only the counties of Tongjiang and Nanjiang, but also the Bazhong City Baya District, Economic Development Zone, Enyang District and other places have previously designated 10 bacon smoking points. In October, due to the high incidence of bacon, the prevention and control of air pollution was not in place, and the main person in charge of the local area of ​​the local area was interviewed and the district was notified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; bacon has a long history. It is said that there are bacon in the war of Huangdi Chi You, and there are bacon records in classics such as &quot;Zhou Yi&quot;, &quot;The Analects&quot; and &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Sichuan smoky bacon also has a history of one or two thousand years. Initially, making bacon was to extend the saving time of meat, but now, bacon has become an important folk custom. For many Sichuan people, bacon is the taste of home and the taste of the New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many places in Sichuan have their own signs of bacon products, such as Qingcheng Mountain bacon, Guangyuan Qingchuan bacon, Liangshan Crown Ningligat, Beichuan bacon, and Dazhou bacon. They are all famous local specialties. In 2013, the former Ministry of Agriculture approved the protection of the geographical indication of agricultural products in the &quot;Wanyuan Old Breast&quot; of Dazhou, Sichuan. However, with the increase in haze, many places in Sichuan have prohibited the use of traditional methods to smoke bacon, and many local specialty products face the dilemma of disappearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Smoked bacon is a custom that has been inherited for thousands of years, but it is now reasonable to be stopped because of &quot;polluted air&quot;. Is this reasonable? Even though smoked bacon does cause air pollution, the public is tolerant of this. Is it necessary for the official to be prohibited? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How big the impact of smoked bacon on air quality requires scientific assessment. Is it a matter of smoked bacon to pull the air quality of the entire city? Or in fact, there are other more important factors in air pollution. Summites are just a scapegoat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, how much pollution can concentrated smoking reduce it? According to the official statement, the concentrated smoke points have been built with special smoked houses, equipped with corresponding environmental protection equipment to reduce pollution. So, how much pollution can concentrated smoking be reduced? Can environmental protection equipment really play a role? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Also, just prohibiting to smoking meat in the urban area, how much can it play in environmental protection? In the county seat, many people&#39;s hometown is in the countryside, and the city is not allowed to smoke, so it will be polluted when they return to the rural areas of their hometown? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Forced centralized smoking, and charging service fees will undoubtedly increase the cost of citizens smoked meat. Although the officially claims that centralized smoke point only charge costs, because the centralized smoke is specified, there is no market competition at all. In the process of formulating fumigation points, it is also a question of public concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If you use traditional methods to smoke the bacon, it is indeed seriously polluted, and it is not impossible to manage appropriately. However, management is not forbidden to smoke the meat on the same way, nor can it be determined in a specified way. In fact, not only large smoked enterprises can build special fumigation houses, increase environmental protection facilities such as flue gas filtration to reduce pollution, and small smoke -free environmentally friendly bacon fumigation machines have already existed. As early as 2018, smoke -free and environmentally friendly bacon smoked machines appeared in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the testing of the Chongqing Ecological Environment Testing Center, using this environmentally friendly smoked machine, the particulate matter concentration in the air is reduced from traditional open smoked 400 mg per cubic meter to about 3 mg. Lowed from 40 mg per cubic meter to about 0.6 mg. Such a small smoked machine only sells only 20,000 to 30,000 yuan. Ordinary merchants can buy smoked bacon services for customers, and even some people or partnerships to buy one, it is completely possible. Although the smoked machine requires a certain cost, the sealing machine can reduce the diffusion of smoke. To a certain extent, it can reduce the use of wood. In summary, it is not much more expensive than traditional open smoked methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chongqing also named the name of environmental protection in 2015. A paper banned by citizens from smoking bacon, which has also caused a lot of controversy. After the successful development of smoke -free environmental protection fumigation machines, the demand for smoking bacon was met, and air pollution was greatly reduced. The two were beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, environmental protection is a very important task of the government. However, environmental protection should not be at the expense of public life and traditional customs. Once, some places were banned from heating in rural coal in winter, and natural gas or electricity was used to heal. However, even if there are government subsidies, the cost of heating is still much higher than that of coal burning, and farmers are overwhelmed. In some places, even the farmers&#39; firewood stoves are not allowed to burn firewood and can only use gas. In some places, people are prohibited from burning paper money during sacrifice, and traditional funeral items such as paper houses and horses are prohibited. These have caused great controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The environmental protection government has KPI, but it cannot override above the folk customs and people&#39;s livelihood. After all, talents are the standards of all things. The government&#39;s environmental protection policies and measures must fully consider the lives of ordinary people, and should not be rudely interfered with the living habits of the people and interrupt the traditional folk customs for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: // feedx. run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[扶持招商引资企业？四川通江指定集中熏肉点，是什么来历]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261361]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-26 21:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/11/26/d36424a746.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/mdias/image/23/11/ 26/d36424a746.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259734 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; January 18, 2023, Shiyang Village, Mianyang, Mianyang, Sichuan, villagers, villagers There are more than 2,000 pounds of sausages and bacon hanging at home, and the flavor of the flavors welcomes the New Year. It has nothing to do with pictures and texts. Visual China &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 15, 2023, Tongjiang County, Bazhong City, Sichuan Province issued a notice saying that urban areas are prohibited from smoking waxy products, smoked bacon, sausage, etc. It is necessary to send it to the centralized fumigation point in two specified places. On the evening of November 23, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau issued an apology announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, the apology is only a statement of &quot;smoking meat products limited by the company&quot; in the announcement, and has not revoked the regulations that prohibit residents from fuming meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters found that the practice of &quot;fixed-point smoking bacon to prevent air pollution&quot; has been implemented in some areas of Sichuan for many years, and the necessity and effectiveness have always been controversial. The notice of Tongjiang attracted attention, partly because the centralized smoke point designated by the government also associated with enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Their charging standards are not low.&quot; Qian An is a native of Tongjiang County and engaged in information from the media in the local area. He learned from the government that both companies are local investment promotion projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; The price of meat smoke is questioned &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The first announcement caused was released on November 15. According to the announcement, with the peak period of smoked waxy products, smoked smoke and dust will pollute the air and have hidden fire safety hazards. In order to respect the tradition and facilitate the citizens, at the same time protect the ecological environment and ensure smoked safety, it will prohibit the farmer&#39;s market in the county urban area. The residential communities, corridors, balconies, roofs, and non -designated locations such as Yanpo, roadside, and ditch are fumigated; it is forbidden to build smoked facilities in the county area without authorization in the county area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The announcement lists the address and contact information of the two designated fumigation points. Industry) Purchasing meat products &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;It&#39;s too far.&quot; After receiving the news that prohibit private smoking, the first response of a resident of Tongjiang County is inconvenient because there is Old people and children need to take care of them. After that, he noticed that one of the concentrated fumigation points did not allow his own meat. He believed that he had suspicion of bundling sales and forced trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The expression of&quot; smoked in the original announcement is limited to the meat products purchased by the company &#39;&quot; In the announcement of the apology, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau amended the regulation, saying that after negotiating with the enterprise, the fumigation point was simultaneously opened to the society. The announcement also explained that the centralized smoked point is located outside the smoked control area, and it is equipped with relevant environmental protection equipment such as spraying, filtering, and charging costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters dialed the contact number of the two centralized smoke points announced by the Southern Weekend, asked the charging standard, and did not receive a reply. According to Yangguang.com, the price of the first concentrated fumigation point is divided into two types. It has its own marinated meat and is charged at about 1.6 yuan to 2 yuan per catty; Charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Qian&#39;an learned that the processing fee for the smoked bacon in the Bashan animal husbandry is 3.5 yuan per catty, and the packaging fee is calculated. &quot;Light smoke is 3 yuan, 5 pounds, and a pig sometimes two or three hundred pounds of meat. If you smoke once, it will be nearly thousands of dollars, which is very expensive.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text -rign: left; &quot;>; Tongjiang&#39;s resident population is about 500,000, of which the county has a population of about 200,000. In response to residents&#39; reflection of the specified smoked point distance, apology announcement mentioned that the first centralized smoke point set up 5 stools to collect points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Winter folk custom smoked bacon. Visual China&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dc3db80ae8.jpg&quot; &quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;941&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dc3db80ae8.jpg =&quot; 259735 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Winter folk custom smoked bacon. Visual China &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;If you want to support our business&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to the notice from Tongjiang County, the first concentrated smoking point is located in Wizhou The streets of Chengdong Village, the street, covers an area of ​​2,000 square meters. There are smoked houses, management houses, oil fume purification equipment and related supporting facilities. The construction area is about 600 square meters. , Development of equipment, put into use on November 25. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters inquired about industrial and commercial information and found that the mobile phone number left at the smoked point is the registration phone of the Golden Henan Building Materials Business Department of Longquanyi District. The company is registered in Chengdu, and its main business is building materials and hardware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;We are a company, and meat is one of the business.&quot; On November 24, the reporter from the Southern Weekend called the number, and the other party replied that the smoked point just just now Jianjian, not fully put into use, as far as its scale is concerned, it can meet the requirements of nearby residents; they provide on -site services, and residents can also go with meat by themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Many people call to run and scold me, scold when they come up.&quot; Cyber ​​violence caused great trouble for yourself. &quot;What may be misunderstanding of them (netizens), it is another company that you can buy their meat (smoked), right?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot; A concentrated smoking point is located next to the Gakeng Power Station of the Industrial Park. It is a smoked point for self -built waxy products for Basan Bashan Husbandry Co., Ltd. (referred to as Bashan Animal Husbandry). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Bashan animal husbandry is a local leading agricultural and animal husbandry enterprise and has been listed on the New Third Board. The company&#39;s official website shows that Bashan Animal Husbandry was established in May 2011. It is headquartered in Tongjiang County Industrial Park. It is dedicated to the development of Qingyu pig breeding and the development of the entire industrial chain. Cold chain logistics, marketing, and brand creation of the entire industry chain standard and system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Why specify these two companies to smoke meat as residents? Qian&#39;an consulted the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau and provided recording to reporters in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Qian An said, Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau replied to specify that the smoked point belongs to the government investment promotion project and is an investment enterprise. &quot;(Bashan animal husbandry) This enterprise has made outstanding contributions to the local economic development. Our local government also wants to support our local enterprises emotionally, and now the company is not easy to develop.&quot; In the recording The staff said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters did not inquire about the public bidding information of centralized smoking points in Tongjiang County; The call of the bureau did not connect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Smoked bacon is a tradition in Sichuan and Chongqing, with a history of more than 2,000 years. In recent years, it has faced questioning of polluted air. As early as 2015, after the Sichuan Dazhou Environmental Protection Bureau said that after &quot;the main reason for the poor air quality&quot;, the local area set a centralized smoke point in the central urban area. At that time, the media explained that concentrated smoking was not replaced by concentrated pollution. The biggest benefit was that it facilitated the government to find problems and standardized management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Che Zhenming, a professor at the School of Food and Biological Engineering of Xihua University, believes that the smoked bacon of family, small scale, and small workshops will not have much impact on the environment on the environment. . He told Yangguang.com that because the air was flowing, especially in such a city that was not densely populated in Pakistan, even if there were some pollution, it would quickly dissipate. However, if industrialized and large -scale smoked bacon is carried out, the impact of the prevention and control of air pollution needs to be taken seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: // feedx. run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南周口联通以断网逼用户换光猫？是否涉嫌诈骗罪，主管部门应严肃调查以正视听丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261355]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-26 20:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recently, the engineer who has been exposed and fired by Henan Zhoukou Company and the forced user to replace the light cats extensive attention. Zhoukou Unicom stated that provincial and municipal companies have set up special work classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Henan TV City Channel Program, a fired Unicom engineer broke the news to the show. In order to force users to replace the light cat, Zhoukou Unicom will first stop the user&#39;s broadband account in the background. Will lie that &quot;light cat damage&quot; requires users to replace the equipment and charge 299 yuan. After changing the light cat, restore user network services from the background. The Unicom engineer said that when installing the new user, Zhoukou Unicom will also use the old light cats replaced by other users to install the new user. After the new user uses it for a while, the engineer will come to the door to use the &quot;light cat model to pass the old old model. Re -loading new cats for users on the grounds of matching. The engineer also said that starting in June 2023, Zhoukou Unicom asked the engineer to complete the terminal change task for 10 households per month. He was unilaterally lifted the labor contract by the company because he failed to complete the task without any compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It seems that the engineer chose to break the news of Unicom&#39;s &quot;shady&quot; because of dissatisfaction. This incident involved two different issues. One is a labor contract dispute. Whether the marketing tasks are arranged for technical positions are reasonable, and whether the employee is legally dismissed on the grounds of failure to complete the task. This problem can be resolved through a labor dispute resolution mechanism to resort to labor arbitration or court. Regardless of whether the engineer is a formal employee who directly signed a labor contract with China Unicom, or sent by a labor dispatch company to Unicom, its legitimate rights and interests should be maintained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; and another problem is also more related to the public interest, that is, whether Unicom has technical means to force users to change the light cat. If this problem is true, it is very harsh and suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the news of the dismissal engineer, Zhoukou Unicom will first stop the user&#39;s broadband in the background in order to force the user to change the optical cat, so that users cannot get on the Internet, causing the illusion of network failure. After the user reported the barrier, it was lied that the light cat was broken. It was necessary to pay for the user to replace the new light cat. After changing it, the broadband was replaced. For new users, the old light cat will be deliberately used when installing the machine. After a period of time, the user will be required to change the Internet for reasons such as light cats, otherwise it will not be able to surf the Internet normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is undoubtedly a serious allegations. Relative to ordinary users, operators have absolute technical and information advantages. Broadband fails, and ordinary users cannot know what the specific reason is, and can only rely on operators. If the operator relies on the advantages of information to fraud, it is very bad to charge users, charge users, or achieve other goals. The deputy director of Zhoukou Unicom&#39;s office said that if the Internet is disconnected privately to induce users to replace the terminal and malicious charges, it is illegal operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If this is true, I am afraid it is not just as simple as illegal. First of all, this violates the service contract with the user and is a breach of contract. Users signed a broadband service contract with telecommunications operators, and operators have the obligation to do their best to provide stable broadband communication services. If a failure occurs, it should be repaired as soon as possible. If there is no failure, the illusion of faults through technical means to achieve their own goals, which hinders the user&#39;s smooth access to the Internet. It will undoubtedly have serious malice and is a fraud. In addition, it also charged the user&#39;s cost of changing cats. Although the amount of each household is not much, there are many users and a lot of total. Deception of other people&#39;s property with fraud can constitute a crime of fraud if it meets a certain standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, whether this allegations are true, it remains to be investigated by relevant departments. The communication control system of the operator&#39;s background is very complete. Each operation will leave a record in the log, so it is not difficult to find out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to media reports, on the consumer complaint platform, there is indeed a complaint of &quot;mandatory replacement of light cats&quot;, and some of them are directly named by the Unicom branch in Henan Province. Some netizens who claim to be an old employee in the communications industry said that this behavior is the default &quot;hidden rule&quot; in the industry. If the customer resolutely does not change the terminal, the company will reduce the network speed. In fact, this behavior not only exists among telecommunications operators, but also exists in Internet companies. An Internet giant providing mailbox services has &quot;interfered&quot; users who collect their emails with other mail clients, so that they have a certain chance to receive garbled mail to induce users to download their own mail clients. This is even a successful marketing case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; No matter what the reason, telecommunications operators want users to update their light cats and other communication devices, and they should use incentives to attract users to voluntarily update. For example Quickly wait. It is difficult to complete the goal by relying on the KPI indicator to the engineer. If the pressure of the index is too large, the engineer may &quot;take a different approach&quot; and complete the task through unsatisfactory means to damage the interests of consumers. Some telecommunications operators have been intentionally cut out of bad &quot;competition&quot; methods such as rival fiber optic fiber. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; No matter how fierce the market competition is, it should not be completed by harming the interests of consumers. In response to the Zhoukou Unicom incident, the Henan Provincial Communications Administration has been involved in the investigation and conducted a first interview with Zhoukou Unicom. The management department should find out the relevant situation as soon as possible. If there is indeed the situation in the news, the Unicom should be severely punished to protect the interests of consumers and prevent operators from relying on asymmetric information and technical advantages to fraud consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[监督“八小时之外”：红黄橙三色如何管住干部]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261351]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-26 19:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection published entitled&quot; &quot;&quot; &quot;Eight hours&quot;, also to be managed! &quot;(Picture source:&quot; China Discipline Inspection and Supervision &quot;)&quot; SRC = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 26/dfe4ccb610.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1427 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/dfe4ccb610.png &quot;&quot; Data-key = &quot;259713&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>; On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection published entitled &quot;Eight hours&quot; &quot;In addition,&quot;, you must also manage it! 》 Article. (Image source: &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision&quot;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Three color of red, yellow and orange has one more use. In Wucheng District, Jinhua City, Zhejiang Province, it has become a kind of &quot;eight hours away&quot; in supervision cadres. means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In May 2023, a scientific -level cadre in Wucheng District was managed by the &quot;red code&quot; management because of the mistakes in the style of life. The cadre had an improper relationship with others and was reported by the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong, director of the Cadre Supervision Office of the Organization Department of the Wucheng District Committee, introduced that the cadre has left the original post after the incident, and his position has also been reduced from a full post to deputy position. Its archives information has been given &quot;red code&quot; in the cadre supervision and management system and has become a key supervisory object. Unless the &quot;red code&quot; in the system is lifted, the cadre&#39;s position and position cannot be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This mechanism is the &quot;red, yellow and orange three -color management&quot; system, and is an important part of the eight -hour supervision and management measures for leading cadres in Wucheng District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since 2015, in Guangdong Province, it has been introduced to the supervision and management of the &quot;eight hours&quot; activity supervision and management of leading cadres. Some agencies have also formulated embodiments. On September 12, 2023, the website of the State Commission of Discipline Inspection of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection published entitled &quot;&quot; Eight hours &quot;, and it must be controlled! The article &quot;article emphasizes the importance of&quot; eight hours of activities &quot;in supervision leading cadres. Six days later, another article published an article entitled&quot; Refine and Manage and Management &quot;Out of the&quot; Eight hours &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of Peng Xinlin, director of the International Anti -Corruption Education and Research Center of Beijing Normal University, this is an important means to strengthen the construction of a clean and clean government and the struggle for anti -corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 3 circles, 21 articles are not allowed &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In 2023, two cadres in Wucheng District were given the code for &quot;drinking&quot;. manage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A cadre of a disciplinary committee went home to drink on his working day, and was temporarily spot -discovered by the disciplinary inspection and supervision department. He was reminded to talk and give &quot;yellow code&quot; for violating the provisions of &quot;unable to drink during working days&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another cadre had a mouthful in the community after drinking the alcohol, and the other party called the police. Because of his behavior of harming the image of party members and cadres, he was commanded and paid for the &quot;orange code&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Specifically, during the eight -hour supervision process, the &quot;red code&quot; assigned serious consequences, or cadres suspected of violating the law and discipline; Cadres; for those who only involve minor disciplinary violations, they will give &quot;orange code&quot;. According to the color of the code, cadres will be handled by different degrees of disciplinary committees, reminders and conversations, and inquiries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The source of inspiration for this mechanism is actually a traffic signal light, which was first applied to the management of village cadres.&quot; Qian Hong said that there is a &quot;three -color management&quot; interface in the local organization department&#39;s cadre supervision and management system, which can be viewed. The situation of the cadre of the code. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As for 8 hours, what behaviors of cadres are not allowed, and the &quot;Eight Homes&quot; activity supervision and management measures in &quot;Leading Cadres of Wucheng District, Jinhua City&quot; are listed in detail. The Commission Organization Department jointly issued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are 21 behaviors that are not allowed, divided into social circles, living circles, and rest circles. Each circle is 7. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The non -allowed behavior of the social circle does not talk about the principles of party spirit, and discusses the policies of the Central Great Political Political Politics; Invincible, engage in collusion between government and business collusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first behavior that does not allow the life circle is to condone, acquiescence spouses, children and children&#39;s spouses violate the regulations for business -oriented enterprises and engage in profit -making activities. The behavior of incorrect sexual relationships with others is the same as blindly comparing and pursuing low -level fun. In addition, it is not allowed to violate family ethics, disrespect, or support parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public funds, public funds, public funds, public funds entertainment, and private use of public buses are not allowed by leisure circles. In the leisure circle, there is also a non -allowed to use power to act as a protective umbrella for illegal activities or evil forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To what extent will be &quot;coded&quot;, it is necessary to study and judge according to the actual situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong takes the &quot;Participating in the Management Services Banquet&quot; as an example. The banquet of participating in the management service object is not reported, and the lowest must be given yellow code; if the money is still produced by the management service object, it is Orange code; if you still use your authority to provide the other party with some economic activities during this period, you must warn or seriously warn the above, and give the red code. &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Qian Hong&#39;s view, no matter what kind of code mechanism, it is not a punishment system in nature, but a cadre management system. There is no punishment system for fault, but no more place. Taking the problem cadre as a key object to manage, so that party members and cadres are more standardized. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong also noticed that there is&quot; eight When you are hourly supervision, you may infringe your personal privacy and affect your normal interpersonal communication. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When we published a document, I explained to you that the supervision of the activity of leading cadres &#39;eight hours&#39; activities will protect personal privacy within the legal scope and not affect my legitimate interpersonal communication and amateur life. For example, eating a meal with friends and relatives and going out to play, this situation is not the scope of our supervision. &quot;Qian Hong told the Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the promotion of the promotion &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The implementation of the code system, one day in August 2023, Qian Hong received a &quot;anger rushing rushing into &quot;Lady. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She went to report her husband, a township -level cadre in a township in Wucheng District. Both of the couple were over half a year old. She previously suspected that her husband had an improper relationship with other women, but had no evidence. This time, the husband looked at her mobile phone while the husband was sleeping and confirmed the fact that her husband was derailed through chat records and transfers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong asked her why she went to the Organization Department to report it first. Her answer was that in July 2023, the Organization Department of the Wucheng District Party Committee led a promotional activity of &quot;double -entry&quot; event. She knew that there was an opinion to find the Organization Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Double advance&quot; refers to the situation of the District Party Committee Organization Department to fully understand the &quot;eight hours&quot; of party members and cadres, and extend the supervision and management of cadres from the &quot;unit of the unit&quot; to the &quot;community courtyard&quot; backyard&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, the concept of &quot;eight hours of supervision&quot; was mentioned as earlier 20 years ago, and later became a popular saying. &quot;Zhuang Deshui, deputy director of the Research Center of the Integrity Construction Research Center of Peking University, introduced early. This concept appeared more in the speeches and reports of some leaders. Later, some places introduced some related ban and specifications, but they were mostly advocated and lacking specific execution agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that around 2001, the Central Organization Department had launched a pilot on cadre living circle and social circle inspection in Huzhou, Zhejiang. In 2004, the Organization Department of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee formulated and issued the &quot;Opinions on Promoting the Life Circle and Social Circle Inspection of Leadership Cadres&quot;, stipulating that officials in the spare time to play mahjong gambling, neighborhood relationships, and circle of friends will all become inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier, the &quot;eight -hour foreign supervision&quot; rose to the level of the rules and regulations is Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2014, after the eighth inspection team of the Central Committee inspected Guangdong, it was recommended to strengthen the daily management of party members and leading cadres and the supervision of the &quot;eight hours away&quot; activities. In August 2015, the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection, the Provincial Party Committee Organization Department, and the Provincial Human Resources and Social Affairs Department jointly issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Supervision and Management of Eight Homes&quot; activities to strengthen party members and leaders &quot;to the&quot; eight hours outside &quot;matters and supervisors responsible persons The supervision mechanism is clearly stipulated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Subsequently, Guangdong selected 147 pilot units including Shenzhen Yantian District in the province to explore the supervision and management of trial leadership cadres &quot;eight hours away&quot; activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2017, the then Secretary of the Yantian District Committee of Shenzhen City wrote in the &quot;Learning Times&quot; that Yantian District established a list of &quot;three laps&quot; (negative) report, community supervision, contact with cadre family members, eight, eight, eight, eight, A series of supervision mechanisms, such as selection and appointment and integrity assessment, and other hours. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that in the past six years, including Wucheng District, Jinhua City, Zhejiang, Zhejiang Pinghu City (county -level city -level city -level city -level city), Jiangxi Fengxin County, Hubei Zhijiang City, Henan Province, Qixian County, Henan Province The “Eight -Hour External Supervision Implementation Measures” formulated by Yuxian District, Mianyang City, Sichuan, and Jianning County, Fujian Province, has many similarities with the relevant mechanisms of Yantian District in the specific content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;contact system with the family members of the cadres&quot; in Pinghu City is mainly responsible for the supervision room of the Organization Department of the Pinghu Municipal Party Committee. . &quot;Qian Ke, deputy director of the cadre supervision office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dan Ke remembered. In a &quot;home visitor&quot;, a family complained that &quot;the other half&quot; was basically not eating at home from Monday to Friday. The family visitor group asked him if he was eating in the unit. The cadre said that he sometimes worked overtime or sometimes paid. The home visitor team immediately asked what entertainment there was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;For this situation, we will verify more channels. If some entertainment may affect performance, we will take further measures.&quot; No other discovery of the cadre&#39;s entertainment was found to have a separate conversation, and no other treatment was made. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mobilization of community forces to supervise cadres eight hours of activities is also a common method in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pinghu City has three types of &quot;eight hours of supervision and observation points&quot;: Class A is located in municipal organs and departments, category B is located in towns and villages, and Class C is located in community and village -level units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the introduction of Qianke, about 90%of Pinghu City leading cadres live in the main urban area. They set up two community supervisors in each of the densely living communities in the 21 cadres. Generally Social persons with high political quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Community supervisors are the role of an information collector. They only need to collect and feed the information. As for the authenticity of the information, the basic verification work is responsible After the implementation of the mechanism, a supervisor had reported to the town street supervision point that a cadre living in the community caused neighborhood disputes due to illegal stacking of debris in the corridor. Finally, the town street supervision point was verified and confirmed, and the organization department gave reminders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A deputy department -level cadre in a province in Northwest China expressed the recognition of the community supervision mechanism to reporters in the southern weekend. P>; In his opinion, the community security can also consider hiring community supervisors. &quot;Although they do not necessarily live in the community, which leader drinks too much every day before returning, they are clear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4 >; &quot;One vote veto&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In the process of exploring the supervision of leading cadres &quot;eight hours outside&quot;, in order to ensure the effectiveness of supervision, the supervisory department will be used for the selection and appointment of cadres in many places. The leadership team of the unit performs accountability and the unit assessment is linked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the relevant implementation measures issued by Youxian District, Mianyang City, Sichuan City, required the situation of party members and cadres to be &quot;other than eight hours&quot; and fulfilling supervision and management responsibilities in the relevant implementation measures. Important content of excellent and annual assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are similar regulations in Wucheng District, Jinhua City. Qian Hong introduced that the results of the eight -hour overseas supervision and party discipline were connected to each other, which would directly affect the promotion of the level of leading cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong for example, saying that it must not be promoted within one and a half year and a half of the party&#39;s severe warning, and it must not be promoted within one year within the party&#39;s warning. In addition, the results of the party discipline will also affect the cadres&#39; annual bonuses to varying degrees. Once they are severely warned, the bonus will be directly zero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the implementation measures of various places, internal party supervision is the primary supervision method. Party committees at all levels are responsible for the supervision and management of party members and cadres in the region, the system, and the unit. He is the first responsible person to accountability to the leadership team and cadres who are inadequate to perform their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ganke said a case: a cadre of a unit in Pinghu City was included in the &quot;red list&quot; because of the issue of eight hours. When the information collection of supervision information is not timely, the cadres of the unit are not reminded to be in place. Therefore, the organization&#39;s officer was also handled and included in the &quot;yellow list.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;Red and Yellow List&quot; is similar to the code mechanism of Wucheng District, and included in the &quot;Red List&quot; means that the cadre has been investigated and punished by the Discipline Inspection Commission. There are many tendencies, and the organization department needs to intervene early to understand the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You must not wait for the disciplinary commission to file a case and report it by the public security.&quot; Qian Hong said that the party group of the unit did not perform the main responsibility of the main body, and finally there was a problem. It will be affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In terms of cadre supervision, it involves the problem of integrity and self -discipline and life style. We deducting points are very powerful, which is almost equivalent to one vote. The question, we will deduct it to the last gear. &quot;Qian Hong told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, how to measure the effect of eight hours of overseas supervision, the relevant measures in various places did not give a clear explanation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gan Ke said frankly. At present, whether the eight -hour supervision has been effective, it depends on whether leading cadres can be self -standards outside eight hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the final analysis, it is not to deal with cadres, but to protect cadres, not to make small problems into big problems, and stifle big problems in the bud stage.&quot; Qian Ke said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, the supervision of the &quot;first leader&quot; has always been a difficulty in anti -corruption. 《中国纪检监察报》在一篇探析“&#39;八小时之外&#39;怎么管？”的文章中即指出，对一把手的监督常常因为上级监督太远、同级监督太软、下级监督太难，而面临监督无效的困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“的确是这样的，这方面稍微难一点，最终还是上级管下级的。”钱宏坦言。干可一也发现，跟监督一般干部相比，如何监督“一把手”八小时外活动还存在一些特殊性，“单从应酬角度来说，&#39;一把手&#39;会涉及跟一些客商、兄弟单位的交流，有时会参加一些应酬。在这个过程中怎么区分这个应酬是因公还是因私，确实有一定难度。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“往往是他们监督别人可以，但让他们自己接受监督就比较难了。”庄德水回忆，曾有干部向他表露一种“比较悲观”的态度，认为八小时外监督没有用，“很多东西不可能被有效监督，真正的腐败都是在桌子底下的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些基层干部也担心政策的持久性与有效性。 “就怕严格执行一段时间就松掉了，（时间长了）上有政策，下有对策。”钱宏说，即使现在，有些问题也给八小时外监督带来了困扰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他举例说，有些干部会避开监管部门重点关注的场所，去更私密的场所；虽然有社区监督，但有些干部可能在好几个社区甚至其它城区都有房；在家庭监督方面，有些干部本来夫妻关系就不好，各过各的，互相也不管对方；社会监督的力量仍然薄弱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“总体上我们主动掌握线索的手段还是不够，信息甄别效率还不够高。”作为同行，干可一也有同感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国人民大学反腐败与廉政政策研究中心主任毛昭晖看来，八小时外监督可以成为基层正风肃纪的一种监督方法，但受制于人力、物力和资源、手段，目前还无法成为一项常态性工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毛昭晖的建议是，“八小时外监督若想取得更好的效果，应该切实引入社会监督，包括舆论监督、媒体监督。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“每一个蚌里都可能藏着一颗奇妙的珍珠”——第十届乌镇戏剧节青年竞演]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261257]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/IGoaZnhErhcYd1kqBeoNHzM1QQUoZ05K1v0a0Mwo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/IGoaZnhErhcYd1kqBeoNHzM1QQUoZ05K1v0a0Mwo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《蚌与珍珠》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（乌镇戏剧节组委会提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月20日到26日的白天，在乌镇西栅的蚌湾剧场门口，永远排着等待看戏的队伍，最长时可绵延至河边。 9月，乌镇戏剧节青年竞演比赛（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以下简称“青赛”&lt;/span>;）线上预约的免费票在开票伊始便被抢空。 This is one of the most important units of the Wuzhen Drama Festival and the only competition unit. Among the works of the 18 groups of young drama people, the best drama award, best personal performance award, and special attention award of the town award will be determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蚌湾剧场外的围栏前立着一块指示牌，显示本场青年赛能进ⅩⅩⅩ位观众。剧场内，18组青年戏剧人的作品轮流上演；剧场外的一面石墙上临时挂了屏幕，供无法入场的观众观看直播，烈日下，总有五六排热心观众席地而坐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年至今，乌镇戏剧节办了10年，青赛也比了10年。蚌湾剧场得名于此处最早的地名，黄磊觉得不错，“蚌湾里面有好多的蚌，每一个蚌里都可能藏着一颗奇妙的珍珠。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌镇戏剧节发起人之一、在北京电影学院任教多年的演员黄磊对传统艺术教育抱有“深刻的感激”和“深刻的关于不足的反思”，一些在学校无法实践的构想，他带到了乌镇戏剧节。 This year, two days before the opening of the tenth Wuzhen Drama Festival, in the handwriting letter of the Youth Championship, Huang Lei wrote, &quot;In the beginning, when the Wuzhen Drama Festival was only a small idea, the youth was already in this festival.主人公，一切的缘起与目标皆是为了青年们。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青赛面向有志于从事戏剧行业的青年，规则很简单：乌镇戏剧节3位发起人一人提一个道具，组成该年度命题——利用这3个道具，在20-30分钟内，不超过5个人，排演一出原创戏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年5月，乌镇戏剧节发起人黄磊、赖声川、孟京辉为青赛出题：世界名画，火车票，马。 “3个道具的根本目的并不是考验你道具如何使用，是考验你怎么利用环境，找有效的舞台支点，把单位时间内戏的能量密度发挥到极限。”青赛评委李博说。 8月，超过500份作品交上来；9月，18组入围作品公布；10月中旬，在乌镇戏剧节展演的分组抽签名单出炉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蚌湾剧场舞台很小，布置简单：顶灯，幕布。观众围成一个半圆，包裹住舞台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青赛的小舞台这些年来已经走出了不少戏剧人。 2013年，陈明昊执导的《巴巴妈妈》夺魁，今年他凭借在《漫长的季节》中的表演被大众熟知；2015年，吴彼以《静止》获得最佳戏剧奖，今年他既是青赛的评委，也是赖声川新剧《长巷》的演员。吴彼曾说，乌镇是他事业最大的转折点，“你们可以没有成本，什么都没有，但尽情去做你们想做的事，而且给大家一个舞台，这么多人来看。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/M6Z6ezjdpK9vyrDYsgTZsLoWe4HSqc0pmODUU6Bw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/M6Z6ezjdpK9vyrDYsgTZsLoWe4HSqc0pmODUU6Bw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259261&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌镇戏剧节青年竞演单元评审李博&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李博以选手身份参加了前三届青赛，作品都进入三甲；第四届起，他成为青赛评委之一，负责从几百个作品中选出18组入围作品；再从18组中选出6组决赛作品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20岁出头时，李博在北京电影学院表演系念书，在象牙塔里享受自由和浪漫；后成为大学老师，“一直觉得没有目标和出口，因而非常迷茫。”参加乌镇戏剧节对他来说有方向性的意义，他说，这是一个能让更多人了解他戏剧理念的途径。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在乌镇的10天里，我在蚌湾剧场度过了相当久的时间，从这些青年剧作中，能看到对男女情爱消逝的展现，母女、父子间的牵绊带来的隐痛，个体对世界撕裂的思考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;获得最佳戏剧奖的《五楼九楼》故事设定在一架故障电梯中，五楼的男生和九楼的女生在半个小时里，反思了自己的亲密关系，一个觉得自己困住了男友，一个可能被女友困住。他们都想要逃走，拿假想的火车票去北方看极光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/YTBsOeV8Us98w43JUFXAKA3juucRsaCWN6MX13mP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/YTBsOeV8Us98w43JUFXAKA3juucRsaCWN6MX13mP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259258&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《五楼九楼》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（乌镇戏剧节组委会提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;获得特别关注奖、最佳个人表现奖的《蚌与珍珠》，主角是控制欲极强的母亲，在心理医生的帮助下，揭开了自己少女时期受侵害的创伤。结尾，女儿给母亲拍照，母亲回眸，变成一幅《戴珍珠耳环的少女》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样获得特别关注奖的《我和刘红梅在车站》从头至尾只有一个演员，“我”离开了大城市回到家乡成为游乐园旋转木马项目的工作人员，几次遇见“她”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在家乡过了一辈子的姥姥&lt;/span>;），15岁的她要偷偷下河游泳；二十多岁的她想去北京上海，火车票丢了急得直哭；82岁的她单薄、沉默、老态，时间在她身上加速流转；最后，“我”带着6岁的“她”摸遍了旋转木马。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fU6jjhR6Sz0KwolNzteM4YohY6FGSerkhP5iORe0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fU6jjhR6Sz0KwolNzteM4YohY6FGSerkhP5iORe0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《我和刘红梅在车站》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（乌镇戏剧节组委会提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;戏剧节期间有一晚，李博在枕水雕花厅排队进场看孟京辉的新戏，听一位观众吐槽某部青赛的戏。李博觉得挺有意思，这恰恰体现了青赛标准的多元化，“确实那个戏观众褒贬不一，但是10年来青赛舞台上它是唯一以这种方式演的独角戏。我们要鼓励，没准将来会形成独特的风格。年轻人的戏就该做很多探索，如果把戏做得都非常工整，就是赖老师了，对吧？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Uzl3RRMgJu8UzwrzdxTezjUAsrdeAxd7cscXsI7f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Uzl3RRMgJu8UzwrzdxTezjUAsrdeAxd7cscXsI7f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;本届青赛决赛入围作品《打开打不开的窗》 剧组谢幕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者张宇欣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在决赛名单出炉后和戏剧节结束后，李博两次接受了《南方人物周刊》采访。以下是李博的口述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;青赛是一个学校，允许你有可爱的瑕疵&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;10月26日我们商量6个入围剧目，要拍一个评委商量决赛名单的官方照，我们都正襟端坐，拿着评戏的单子。后来是谁说到了一个观点，程耳导演第一个站起来了，说，不行，这舞台这么难得，这个戏一定要是戏剧的语言才行。后来全都站起来了，争执：什么是对舞台的敬畏、什么是话剧的语言、小剧场到底该怎么演、对3个道具到底该怎么用、表演超时了该怎么办……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;报名的有五百多个作品，我们要照顾各种各样的题材、风格、表达。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;青赛是一个学校，允许你有可爱的瑕疵。不过当时以瑕疵为优点入围的戏，到了青赛舞台上几乎都走样了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有个戏，8月20号报名截止，我看他们8月19号录的，再不录来不及了。录像在一琴行，第一个镜头还在晃。他们演的是轻喜剧，演员要绝对松弛，恰恰他们可能就是照着不入围来演的，现场碰出了很多有灵性的、高级的喜剧台词，耳导他们组就把这戏给提上来了.我正在外地开会，真是无聊，就戴耳机一边看录像。他们呈现得既松弛又好玩，我看得特别高兴。演员忘词了嘎嘎乐，我也嘎嘎乐。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;后来宣布入围，组委会打电话，签确认函，设计海报，到乌镇，安排三次公众排练，接受一次采访，再有几次排练，接着三轮演出。他们开始认知到原来这是个比赛，紧张了。一紧张人就变得不自由。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;官方微博把决赛名单公布出去，有一条留言说，这6个戏个个扎实，恭喜他们。这个评价是对我们工作最大的鼓励，有的戏可能看上去很好很丰富，但是很飘，一咂摸没味道；有的看上去四平八稳，但是整个呈现有年轻人很难得的稳重。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今年是我做了7年评委、见到作品整体水平最高的。今年决赛6个是真的能选出6个，我们最后是在取舍。恰巧碰到我很喜欢的戏，有的评委特别不喜欢，我们两个就一直争辩，但这是学术上的，不涉及个人。在单位工作，我往往会回答“是”“对，您说得对”，但在乌镇戏剧节不存在这个问题，我跟赖老师也争过。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今年道具是一匹马、世界名画、火车票。除了表演、文本以外，最重要的还是看3个元素怎么用，因为这个比赛是由3个元素撑起来的。我们在评判时，如果两个戏呈现都差不多，我们就看道具了。 3位老师每个人给一个道具，就是为了防止把旧作拿来改编。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对道具的使用，特别考验一个剧组的专业程度。比如咱俩打架没打出胜负来，突然出现一把刀，谁都想去抓刀，这个刀引起了戏剧的转折，改变了戏剧的走向，这是比较普遍的用法。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对道具，只提一下，这是最简单的；还是它对戏的转折起Key role?还是它作为一个意象、象征，贯穿整个戏，始终在你脑海当中徘徊？这是完全不同的三个层级。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今年道具里难的是世界名画，因为我们中国人很少有看画展的经历.有的戏是戏仿《戴珍珠耳环的少女》，有的是家人把她的作品当成世界名画，有的是演员去模仿《呐喊》，都挺可爱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《我和刘红梅在车站》，我们几个评委全体通过进决赛。我想它进决赛和道具的使用应该有分不开的关系。马的意象是贯穿通篇的。我们学表演，道具作为舞台支点也好，推动剧情发展的关键物品也好，怎么也要在舞台上出现一下，但这个戏里没有出现。剧本提到旋转木马的游戏，“我”在舞台上一圈一圈走，像旋转木马一样，碰到“我”的姥姥，每走一圈“我”看到不同阶段的刘红梅，都发生了不同的事情，关乎着刘红梅的命运。最后“我”又回到了工作岗位，给其他小朋友来开旋转小木马。这么清新，这么自然。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fn6iCX3PjfK5PEwyTNT8zLsIN7JTjdJqDHwyIQ9o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fn6iCX3PjfK5PEwyTNT8zLsIN7JTjdJqDHwyIQ9o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259260&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;剧目《然后潮汐，太阳，月亮》演出结束&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者张宇欣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不用玩酷、玩炫，踏踏实实把精力放在故事上&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那天我在朗读会上还说，微博140个字就能获得鸡汤，快手抖音一分钟能够达成你所有的欲望，为什么有人会在剧场里消耗两个小时的生命，去看戏？首先这个戏一定是有温度的。第二，你戏里聊的东西，是抖音快手微博不常看的，要带领观众去关注到生活里面我们不曾关注的人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;到现在为止，在历届青赛里选出一部戏，我觉得最好的是2016年的《嘎玛》（记者注：当年的青赛题目是一滴血，一个旅行箱，一颗流星。《嘎玛》主角是一对母女，多年来，阿妈放不下离家修行、成为活佛的阿爸，活佛已死，阿妈坚信活佛可以在49天内转世回到家中，寄希望于女儿嘎玛怀孕；嘎玛怀的孩子却是格桑花转世，孩子也夭折了。母女二人打算各自去朝圣，在去神湖的路上最终和解），上海戏剧学院两个研究生做的，是青赛历史上唯一一次最佳个人表现奖和大奖全给了一个团队。在舞台上演信仰，一般都往复杂里演，但那个戏讲得特别简单，一把椅子，两个女孩，其中一个女孩演了两个角色（念念不忘丈夫的阿妈，和格桑花转世的孙女），就那么简单，却讲得那么通透。她们磕完长头之后往远处一看，一个冷光打过来，哗，那是一片湖。响起藏族的音乐，感觉我们就在雪域高原里。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从第一届到现在，所有得大奖的戏，都是以小见大，踏踏实实讲生活。你从西栅随便抓一个人，10岁以上90以下，坐那儿都能看懂。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;青赛的舞台离观众很近，真，是最重要的。你的戏剧内核是通过一个小事儿，还是假模假式地通过一个哲学事件告诉我们？我特别不喜欢拿腔拿调、煞有介事地非要告诉我们点什么，或者强行灌输什么。包括评委投票，这种戏结果都不好。年轻人的戏剧不用做那么复杂，上来探讨To be or not to be，对不起，您真没那功力，有时候想的跟演出来的是两回事儿。我还是希望能把故事讲清楚：有起承转合、人物性格、矛盾冲突、主题立意，哪怕没有立意，都很难得了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你看刘添祺的《鸡兔同笼》（记者注：青赛最佳戏剧奖获奖作品）多简单，儿子去监狱里边看他爸，两个人有一段谈话。小戏里有大世界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我还是觉得年轻人不用玩酷、玩炫，踏踏实实的，把精力放在故事上，故事怎么架构、怎么展开；表演一定要收敛。我特别讨厌短视频里能刷到的那种撒泼表演，但是很多人可能受了影响，觉得我们的戏一定要“起”。我跟青赛的选手讲，内心波涛汹涌、外表平静如水的戏最难演。马龙·白兰度、罗伯特·德尼罗、阿尔·帕西诺碰到让他信仰崩塌的事儿，有一个在嚎叫吗？他的情感是蓄水池，要出来多少就出来多少。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在舞台上我们也需要学习这个。表演呈现一定要含蓄、克制、隐忍，千万不要因为观众的呐喊、叫好而把这个戏演飞了，从而喧宾夺主。有的戏呼声特别高，但我们就觉得有点讨好观众，演了一次，知道哪个包袱在哪个地方，第二次就拼了命演，甚至都没有控制、没有节奏了。 《我和刘红梅在车站》就特别稳，不迎合观众。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;独角戏不好演，一个人要诠释很多人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们看报名录像，有大量独角戏。很多像是我们上学那时候做的——一个人在单位时间里面遇到了一个困境，通过人和人、和自然环境的斗争，把问题推向一定的高潮。但我们应该给来乌镇的观众看新东西、真东西。我们这次选的有3个独角戏，像《我和刘红梅在车站》，都不是传统意义上的独角戏表演了，更多的时候是在说话、在流露，在特别平淡的状态里，但内心是有内容的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我觉得乌镇的蚌湾剧场、青赛就是中国年轻戏剧人的一块实验田，你只要有能力，可以把你自己实验的东西放在舞台上，观众是宽容的，我们评委也是宽容的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/mzOLwjXxuTifmIoAYAslcXEBXGJc6iobwlg9OBsw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/mzOLwjXxuTifmIoAYAslcXEBXGJc6iobwlg9OBsw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蚌湾剧场外，所有本届青赛作品的海报贴在灰石砖墙上&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者张宇欣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;如果不做戏剧，我们当然能理解&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我33、34、35岁那三年作为选手参加青赛，是很难忘的，也很值得。第一年我做了12个剧目里面唯一的喜剧；第二年我做了唯一的肢体剧，没有台词；第三年我做了唯一的蒙太奇戏剧，靠光来解释表演。现在我依然当老师，但肯定排不出那三年那样的东西了，人的经历越来越丰富，胆子越来越小。尤其在大学里工作，想象力就没有那么天马行空。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;投青赛第一年，我们在学校每天晚上排到两三点，排着排着学生要放弃，说这么些评委，规格肯定高，入围不了。我说，当老师这么多年我也做科研、也投奖，不收报名费的比赛肯定是好比赛。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我教书是在公办的二本院校，学生从招生上和北电中戏的就有差距了。我第一届一块儿比赛的学生，“成活率”是很高的，有一个在开心麻花，一个在大连市话剧团，一个现在是带货主播，做得也非常好，我看过他的直播，他的直播技巧和表演是挂钩的，他会现挂、砸挂，与其说在看他直播，倒不如说在看他演一场戏。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我在大学也排戏，也排乌镇的戏，一个脑子有时候得分成两种ideas.中国的大学其实都一样，大学的教育有大学的特点。所以年轻人拿到乌镇戏剧节的道具，可能很兴奋，因为终于有机会能做一个真正喜欢、有生活质感的喜剧、悲剧或者荒诞剧。咱说句特别不好听的话，乌镇的戏也不是说你在乌镇演了以后就能天天演，就这么10天，拿了大奖，（持续）上演的机会也很小。有的戏很稚嫩，但是因为它的场面足够宏大，一直在演。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我还是鼓励年轻人都应该去戏剧节看戏、比赛。全国的戏剧爱好者凑到一个地方，一起聊聊戏，这种珍贵是你在脑海里边一辈子都挥之不去的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;乌镇戏剧节的目标非常明确，抓住5%的人，这戏剧节就能manage.我们是没有办法像一些电影节那样，有一个链条式的、推波助澜的辅助，给钱拍，上映、上线。戏剧还是小众，全国的银幕数量肯定比剧场的数量多得多。但我们就是为了深深地给他们打上一针强心剂。每一年乌镇青赛的观众里都有往年入围的选手，今年没投、投了没中的，回乌镇看戏。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;每个人都有自己的人生选择，如果不做戏剧，我们当然能理解，因为能够活着就不错。如果要做戏剧，那就做出一个好的来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[考研人数八年来首降：高校招生计划扩张时代正在走向尾声丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, the official website of the Ministry of Education announced matters related to the 2024 National Master’s Degree Admissions Examination. According to statistics, the number of applicants for the national postgraduate examination in 2024 is 4.38 million, a decrease of 360,000 or about 7.6% from the 4.74 million applicants for the postgraduate examination in 2023. This is also the first time in eight years that the number of applicants for the postgraduate examination has increased compared with the previous year. fall back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why has the number of postgraduate entrance examinations declined? The outside world has summarized some possible reasons: some graduates turned to the public entrance examination, striving to get an iron job in one step, and withdrew from the postgraduate entrance examination track; some graduates no longer regard the postgraduate entrance examination as a choice, thinking that it is just a matter of paper. A postgraduate diploma may not necessarily lead to a good job, so it is better to enter the job market in advance to save opportunity costs; the postgraduate recruitment policies of major universities have changed. &quot;The number of places for professional masters has increased and the number of places for academic masters has decreased&quot;, which has reduced the cost-effectiveness of postgraduate studies, and some prices Sensitive candidates give up in the face of high tuition fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that these reasons all stem from the rational choices of candidates as &quot;economic people&quot;: studying has increasingly become an investment, and the consumption attribute of higher education is also strengthening. If the candidates believe that studying for graduate school cannot improve the competitiveness of the job market and cannot bring good economic returns in the future, then the candidates will rationally consider &quot;whether studying for graduate school is worth it&quot;, thereby reducing the &quot;supply&quot; of the higher education market. There is a rumor going viral that a famous postgraduate entrance examination teacher successfully predicted the decline in the number of people taking the postgraduate entrance examination. In fact, this also shows that his &quot;preaching&quot; over the years has achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a statistical point of view, the change in candidates&#39; attitudes has also taken several years, which is essentially a &quot;reverse incentive&quot; brought about by changes in the job market. Statistics on the number of applicants for postgraduate entrance examinations over the years show that this number declined in 2014 and 2015, but has shown an upward trend since 2015, reaching a peak in 2023. The year-on-year expansion of postgraduate enrollment and the increase in the number of graduates have made the job market supply unable to keep up with the employment demand of graduates. This imbalance in supply and demand has naturally been transmitted to the upstream higher education market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be admitted that in reality, only a small proportion of people go to graduate school to satisfy their personal enthusiasm for knowledge or for scientific research. Most students go to graduate school for employment, which can be subdivided. Further studies to postpone employment, and &quot;gold-plated graduate school&quot; for better employment. Unfortunately, both of these options are facing great challenges amid a weak job market. Of course, students are not fools and will also adjust their life strategies according to social reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key factors that affect the supply and demand of the job market are the economic cycle and industrial structure. The feedback from the job market also determines the cost-effectiveness of graduate school. None of the three parties, students, employers, or universities, can answer the question of “is graduate school worth it” alone? In the face of sluggish demand in the job market, both employers and candidates have begun to take action to answer this question: companies have reduced the scale of school recruitment, while candidates have seen a decline in the number of applicants. What is worth asking is, how will universities respond? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this century, the number of postgraduate students enrolled in China has increased year by year, from 220,000 in 2003 to more than 1 million in 2020, and now accounts for about 10% of undergraduate graduates that year. Major universities have expanded their enrollment of master&#39;s degree students so rapidly over the years. On the one hand, they are of course adapting to the growing needs of the job market. On the other hand, they can also apply for more funds for themselves, charge more tuition fees, and improve various evaluation indicators. In short, it is to strive for more benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;reverse incentives&quot; in the job market, the sluggish fertility rate is destined to continue to reduce the number of postgraduate entrance examinations in the future, and the phenomenon of &quot;the merger of primary and secondary schools&quot; will sooner or later spread to higher education. field, this will be a more decisive factor in the future than &quot;candidates choose not to take the exam&quot;. In other words, the decline in the number of people taking postgraduate entrance examinations is an irreversible trend. In the future, colleges and universities may face a new enrollment gap of one million levels every year and have to face the severe situation of &quot;competition for existing students&quot;. This is a serious issue that colleges and universities need to deal with urgently. challenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reducing enrollment for master&#39;s degrees and expanding enrollment for associate&#39;s master&#39;s degrees&quot; and &quot;extending the academic system for associate&#39;s and master&#39;s degrees&quot; are the response plans that some colleges and universities have come up with. In this way, they can not only maintain the original enrollment scale, but also increase enrollment. Collect tuition fees. But the question is, when colleges and universities make a fuss about the academic system and quota of associate and master&#39;s degrees, can they really &quot;ensure the quality of training and improve employment competitiveness&quot;, or can they just &quot;charge one more year of tuition&quot; or even &quot;delay one year&quot;? &quot;Employment&quot; itself is quite debatable and deserves reflection. Some candidates&#39; doubts about the cost-effectiveness of master&#39;s degrees may be one of the reasons for the decrease in the number of postgraduate students this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the principles of organizational behavior, &quot;organizations will work hard to create jobs for themselves, and employees of organizations will work hard to create jobs for each other.&quot; Since an organization has been established, it will do everything possible to maintain its existence, especially The public sector eats up financial resources. Public universities have long relied on taxpayers&#39; money to operate and do not need to directly face market competition. Naturally, they will find ways to maintain their existing graduate spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, changes in supply and demand in the job market and the impact of declining fertility rates will be transmitted sooner or later. The arrival of the enrollment gap has become an irreversible trend. The decline in the number of postgraduate entrance examinations this year is a timely warning to major universities. Comply with the needs of the job market, comprehensively consider social needs, adjust the recruitment plan for graduate students, and better serve the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>