<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[硬核军训是怎么炼成的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/A72oqQdD8BybPWTNg0BalhXWNoO5Mh57DFsDOpHt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;612&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/A72oqQdD8BybPWTNg0BalhXWNoO5Mh 57DFsDOpHt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guangxi Guilin University of Electronic Science and Technology 2023 freshmen military training demonstration&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Special Warfare Mode&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The alarm sounded, orange-red and white smoke staggered and dispersed, and the air was filled with sulfur smell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than forty students wearing camouflage uniforms and holding model Type 95 rifles approached in batches from one side of the green field to the other. There are scattered fire rings made of cardboard boxes and obstacles covered with camouflage nets along the way. The advancers either suddenly fell down or rolled out of their guns to avoid the explosions flying from the opposite side. Every time he stopped neatly, he was still in the shooting posture, with the muzzle of the gun pointed at the &quot;enemy camp&quot; ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this military training exercise, students acted as a special operations force of our country. Their mission at the moment is to board a strange border island to rescue the hostages held by terrorists. More than 20 people, including &quot;hostages&quot; and &quot;robbers,&quot; were stationed under a camouflage awning on the other side of the playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While advancing, we encountered stubborn resistance from the enemy. Many special forces &quot;fell&quot; and 7 &quot;sacrificed&quot;. Medical soldiers wearing white armbands rushed into the smoke-filled battlefield in groups of four. The two in front held guns for cover, and the two behind carried the wounded onto stretchers for treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The robbers were equipped with more heavy firearms: a mortar and two rocket launchers. We only have one rocket launcher. When the battle was lost, the special forces issued a request for support. Subsequently, simulated armored vehicles and tanks manufactured at a 1:1 ratio were driven onto the playground one after another. With the support of solid barriers and mobile turrets, the special forces team successfully reached the enemy camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rescue soldiers and tanks have surrounded the enemy camp layer by layer, but the robbers are still guarding the &quot;door&quot;. Our demolitions use directional blasts to blow up the stronghold. There was a loud noise and white light shot out. The hostages were finally rescued after rescue soldiers rushed in and engaged in close combat with the robbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the military training meeting of Guilin Institute of Aerospace Industry (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guihang&quot;&lt;/span>;) on September 27 The finale of the parade ceremony: the performance of the special warfare phalanx. Long after the performance ended, the applause and cheers of more than 5,000 freshmen in military training echoed throughout the playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The flame of excitement burned in Instructor Zhang. As the instructor of the special operations phalanx and the planner of the special operations performance, he also participated in the &quot;rescue operation&quot; and played the role of a special forces commander. Instructor Zhang’s skin was dark, his face was covered with sweat, and the gray and green colors of his camouflage makeup blurred together. He spoke breathlessly and in an uplifting tone. When he asked questions to the team members who were resting on the floor, he always received resounding answers and hearty laughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Instructor Zhang is a militia member of the Guilin Garrison Area. After retiring from the armed police, he worked as a special warfare training instructor at a military training summer camp in Guangdong for four years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from conventional military training, special warfare training imitates the training of our country&#39;s special forces, selecting the most elite &quot;soldiers&quot; and adding subjects such as tactical movements, weapon operation, and wilderness survival. It is more intense and difficult. Instructor Zhang firmly believes that &quot;this kind of education method can truly temper students&#39; bodies and spirits.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The educational concept of &quot;barbaring one&#39;s body&quot; is sometimes accompanied by more voices of incomprehension. Once upon a time, there was a young man who came from Zhejiang for training, and he always practiced gun-holding movements perfunctorily. In order to urge him, Instructor Zhang couldn&#39;t help but said some harsh words: &quot;If you can&#39;t hold a gun well, then you don&#39;t need to eat.&quot; As a result, his parents scolded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m not denying him food, I just want him to experience setbacks and growth. Training is not the purpose. The important thing is to let students learn the valuable qualities of self-improvement, self-reliance, and self-confidence.&quot; Instructor Zhang remembered that when he first joined the army At that time, because I was not holding the gun properly, I was ordered to do the same thing by the squad leader for a whole morning. After that, he practiced diligently and became a model in the army&#39;s tactical training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in Guihang, Instructor Zhang rarely has the trouble of not being understood - the special team members are tougher than he imagined. Among Guihang&#39;s 5,000 freshmen participating in the training, more than 80 students from various military training camps passed the selection of height and physical fitness, and finally completed the study and performance of tactics, shooting and other projects. Even if you wear protective gear, rolling, climbing and other actions will inevitably cause arm and leg abrasions. But most people are enthusiastic. Instructor Zhang recalled that a classmate from the Sixth Battalion of the special operations team had a serious muscle strain. After a day of rest, his symptoms improved and he immediately returned to the team for training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real battlefield will not leave opportunities to lax soldiers. All the training of the special operations team are highly simulated battlefields. The human ladder construction training is to restore the scene of three people fighting together. Gun training simulates a quick response to an enemy attack. &quot;The simulated gun is relatively heavy, and the students are naughty and occasionally deliberately distort the movement of the gun.&quot; Instructor Zhang will seriously teach him: &quot;When encountering a real attack, the gun must be drawn within 1 second or even 0.1 seconds. The movements must be crisp and clear, and the eyes must be clean.&quot; You have to be keen, otherwise you will be a lamb waiting to be slaughtered.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 10% of the people who initially signed up to join the special forces team dropped out. &quot;Special warfare training requires very high physical fitness. Carrying a 1:1 scale simulated rifle that is almost as heavy as a real gun (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;95 (The weight of the rifle is 3.25kg&lt;/span>;) to complete tactical actions, some people are not physically fit enough to do the standard.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only the special operations team has the opportunity to come into contact with the simulated gun, and students from other companies will start to purely Yu signed up to join the special training team out of curiosity about firearms. Instructor Zhang does not encourage such people to stay because &quot;they are not interested in the special training itself. They just want to take pictures with tanks and armored vehicles. They cannot accept the hard training and cannot keep up with the pace.&quot; In his opinion, only the students themselves are active With participation and cooperation, hard-core training and realistic performances will not be in name only. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/csZ7etnCAfokT74q9Qot5lJZJSRMp9TKLcAYgcqG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/csZ7etnCAfokT74q9Qot5lJZJSRMp9TKLcAYgcqG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254439&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Special warfare phalanx display during Guihang military training exhibition&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;National Defense Enthusiasts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As night falls, the mountains surrounding the campus gradually disappear, the singing of the Mid-Autumn Festival Gala rehearsal is endless, and the lake is full of students running around it. It’s an ordinary Tuesday night at the Huajiang Campus of Guilin University of Electronic Science and Technology (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidian&quot;&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the lively playground and stage, in the quiet square, more than 20 members of the Patriotic National Defense Education Association are conducting their daily training. This is a club composed of enthusiasts of national defense knowledge and military training in Guidian. They often participate in the school&#39;s national defense education activities and usually maintain at least two hours of tactical training a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to wearing camouflage uniforms, the team members also wore simulated guns, tactical helmets, marching bags, protective gear, and military boots, just like troops going out to perform missions. They are all students participating in this year&#39;s military training for freshmen. At this time, two weeks have passed since the end of the Guidian military training camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its establishment in 2019, the Patriotic National Defense Education Association has selected students who are determined to participate in tactical training for a long time from each new military training class and regularly conducted daily training on infantry combat skills. The core personnel who have undergone long-term training will assist the instructors in completing the tactical training for new students in the second year of military training. In the 2023 Guidian freshmen military training, 150 students from the tactical company were assigned to provide guidance to 30 members of the 21st and 22nd level associations. The person in charge pointed out that this kind of small class teaching can improve the efficiency of training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of the participants in the association have the idea of ​​joining the military or the police. Lin Yu, who served as the gunner of the anti-tank team in this military training, applied for the police academy as her first choice in the college entrance examination. Joining the tactical team satisfied her childhood desire to operate firearms. Shen Hong serves as an industrial infantryman responsible for demining. His father was a soldier. Shen Hong&#39;s favorite TV drama character is Li Yunlong. He believes that this tactical training has given him a lot of knowledge and strengthened his ambition to join the army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fend off the enemy from the front.&quot; As the squad leader issued the order, the members of the seven-person platoon quickly completed squatting, turning over, and crawling from the stance of marching with guns, with their guns pointing forward. After hearing &quot;defend the enemy from the rear&quot;, the members who were running forward suddenly turned around, slid sideways and lay down, with their guns pointed at the rear. This is an individual soldier action exercise, the association’s most basic training program. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yilong, chairman and founder of the association and a preparatory class for the children of border guards in 2019, is supervising the training of members. He reminded the squad leader to take the members to a venue without glass ballast to prevent scratches caused by the huge friction with the ground. When Lin Yu fulfilled the command to &quot;lie down while running&quot;, his movements were not coherent enough. Huang Yilonglue jokingly urged the squad leader to correct Lin Yu&#39;s actions. He explained to a reporter from Southern People Weekly, &quot;She slowed down first and then lay down. It was too slow. Now she is dead in the actual combat state. You can see that other people slid down directly from the high speed. She almost slowed down.&quot; If I go on to 0, I will still be afraid.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about the essentials and operational significance of various military actions, Huang Yilong always speaks very quickly. He can talk about the &quot;three-point running and shooting position change&quot; in team operations and the obstacle breaking training of the engineering chemical defense team like an encyclopedia. Huang Yilong grew up in a military compound and liked to study various military tactics on his own. He started participating in military clubs in high school. This hobby continued into college and became an ambition. &quot;After graduation, I will either join the army or plunge into research in the military field. I will not be so comfortable doing other jobs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plan for the 2023 Guidian military training and the tactical confrontation performance of the red and blue squares is Huang Yilong and the leaders of the training units jointly completed the planning. &quot;Our first tactical display in 2021 will be more conservative, with only infantry and pure attackers. This year, with armored vehicles, blasting tubes and other equipment, we can display more complex tactics, and we have designed offensive and defensive confrontation, engineer barbed wire breaking obstacles and other links.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Huang Yilong, the military training exercises in Guihang, a ten-minute drive from Guidian, also made reference to this tactical confrontation model. &quot;Guihang&#39;s Military Enthusiasts Association is a fraternal association with us and shares some promotional materials and equipment resources. At the beginning of their association&#39;s establishment, we helped them organize some training. This year, we also seconded guns to Guihang&#39;s freshmen military training. Give it to them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the next step in the development of the association, Huang Yilong hopes to form a mutual aid community with more military hobby societies in local universities to exchange more experiences in tactical training. In addition, he plans to enrich tactical training projects. &quot;In the beginning we only had simple training on advancing, kneeling and sliding, and fending off enemies. Later we went up the mountain and carried out infiltration and counter-infiltration operations in the forest. There may be new development directions in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/VpLyIkjRdB9o98kmFtnycQIKGic5OP5m1r3hIaR3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/VpLyIkjRdB9o98kmFtnycQIKGic5OP5m1r3hIaR3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guidian Patriotic National Defense Education Association conducts woodland infiltration and counter-infiltration training near the school&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Resources and Culture&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It takes about 50 minutes to drive from Guilin North Railway Station in the direction of Yaoshan Scenic Area to reach Guihang and Guidian. They are only one stop apart on the route of bus number 13. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both schools are surrounded by mountains, covering vast areas, far away from the bustling city, and seem to be specially designed for Qing Dynasty. Unless it is a holiday, there are few vehicles passing by on the mountain roads surrounding the school. In the nearby Yaoshan Scenic Area, there are dense forests and gentle slopes. The surrounding environment provides the school with a suitable place for field training and simulated jungle combat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guihang chose Yaoshan for training. The person in charge of the school&#39;s armed forces department explained, &quot;With more than 5,000 people training, safety is the first priority. In addition, we must also meet everyone&#39;s needs for exercise, so we walked to the mountains where there are few cars.&quot; The members of the special operations team used trees and grass to For cover, they wore gas masks and simulated woodland infiltration, jungle manhunts and other activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The supply of military training equipment benefits from cooperation between universities and between universities and military institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guidian’s imitation armored vehicles and rocket launchers are all seconded from Guilin Military Expo Park. Staff of the Military Expo Park revealed that Guidian’s national flag guard team will also come to the Military Expo Park to perform. The simulated guns and gas masks were loaned from the Army Special Warfare College. You Jiangjiao, chief of the Comprehensive Section of the Guidian Armed Forces Department, said that over three days, nearly 10,000 military training students took turns to experience shooting simulated guns. Guidian, the current deputy minister of the Armed Forces, once worked at the Army Special Warfare Academy. In order for the performance to go smoothly, he took the initiative to help the students borrow 55 marching bags from a unit in Qifeng Town. Some of the simulated mortars, tanks, firearms and other equipment used in Guihang&#39;s military training are provided by the school&#39;s military associations, and some are seconded from the Guilin Garrison District. Guidian, Guilin and other universities will also lend some equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, real gun and live ammunition shooting in military training in colleges and universities has gradually been replaced by simulated gun shooting. You Jiangjiao pointed out, &quot;Shooting with real guns is too dangerous. The real guns borrowed by the school are mainly disassembled for students to learn.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers from the armed forces departments of the two schools believe that the school&#39;s emphasis on military training Investing more resources will help enhance students’ national defense awareness and promote military recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As part of national defense education, military training is also a window for ordinary students to understand the life of the army. The person in charge of the Guihang Armed Forces Department once conducted a post-training survey on the students of the school. He found that the previous military training, which had a single form and lacked equipment support, made many students question the meaning of military training: &quot;If the military training showed students all about going forward and standing in military postures, they would also find military life boring like this. It is difficult to yearn for the army. Military training adds activities such as tactical training and enriches the form to more comprehensively reflect the real life in the military camp and allow students to understand the specific needs of national defense. This can inspire their enthusiasm and belief in joining the army.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Li Ming, a retired soldier from the Guilin Garrison District, has a military dream that was cultivated by the military training experience he witnessed in his childhood. His parents are teachers at Guilin Forestry School. Since elementary school, Li Ming has often observed the military training of this technical secondary school after school. At that time, the use of firearms accounted for a large proportion of military training courses, and Li Ming, who was watching from the sidelines, was always clamoring to play with firearms. When Li Ming was in junior high school, instructor Chen often came to this school to train students. He often played with Li Ming, who was unwilling to do homework, and taught him a lot of military knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day, Instructor Chen accidentally broke his arm while demonstrating a certain movement. Other instructors quickly rushed forward to check the wound and sent Instructor Chen to the infirmary. This scene deeply inspired Li Ming: &quot;I am an only child born in the 1990s. I can only cry alone when I am injured. When the instructor is injured, his comrades are a solid backing. We study with peace of mind, and the soldiers are also our backing, protecting everyone and the children. The safety of my home.&quot; Li Ming determined to be a soldier who can become the backing of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, he is also an instructor at Guihang Military Training. He hopes that the seeds that instructor Chen once planted in his heart will also be planted in the hearts of Guihang students. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Is hard-core military training suitable for more people?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The resources of the special operations training model cannot benefit everyone who participates in military training. Among the more than 5,000 freshmen participating in the training at Guihang, except for more than 80 members of the special operations team, other students rarely have the opportunity to come into contact with simulated firearms. Courses on square formations such as split formation and prisoner boxing are still based on formation training. For safety reasons, those who drive armored vehicles and tanks are instructors who have obtained driver&#39;s licenses. Students can only take photos with these models or sit on them to experience them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A classmate of the split company felt a little regretful that he did not have the courage to sign up for the special operations company: &quot;Although it is more difficult, I can also learn a lot of military skills and experience more military life. It&#39;s a pity that I I wear glasses. During the selection, the instructor said that the movements may break the glasses, and those wearing glasses cannot participate. In addition, there are height requirements, and those with martial arts and dance foundations are given priority. I don’t seem to be good enough.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Wang Zhipeng, a lecturer in the Military Teaching and Research Office of Xi&#39;an Jiaotong University, said that the emergence of special training models in military training is to meet the military training needs of different types of students: &quot;In recent years, colleges and universities have expanded their enrollment, and the number of participants has continued to increase. The physical fitness and adaptability of students have There are differences, and some high-intensity training may not be suitable for all students. Similar activities are also held in the national student military training camps organized by the Ministry of Education and the National Defense Mobilization Department of the Central Military Commission to provide students with good physical fitness and deep national defense sentiments. A platform for growth, experience and advancement.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the threshold of student quality, special warfare training itself also has higher requirements for resources such as venues and equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest headache for instructor Zhang, who is in charge of Guihang’s special training, is the lack of softer training venues. During special training and movements such as rolling and lying down, the hard cement floor will aggravate the students&#39; scratches. However, the plastic badminton court on Guihang South Campus cannot be used because it is close to classrooms for other grades. The playground with a 400-meter track in the North Campus needs to be shared by 7 camps. Instructor Zhang sometimes felt a little crowded, so he had to take the team to a corner of the playground for training. They had only rehearsed the full tactical display with ample space once. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guidian’s way of solving the problem is to make full use of the roads on campus. You Jiangjiao pointed out, &quot;By clearing the electric vehicles parked on the road to one side, the area of ​​the training venue can be increased, and the separated teams can train here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Universities such as Guihang and Guidian, It has a military-industrial nature, and it is more convenient to communicate with the local military region and borrow resources such as simulated firearms during military training. But in general colleges and universities, it is relatively difficult to borrow. Xi&#39;an Jiaotong University&#39;s approach is for the school to purchase its own military training teaching aids. The special training team always has more than 40 model guns, and other students can only get 2-3 guns per company on average. The average price of a model gun is a few hundred yuan. If it is to ensure that every student participating in the training has one like a special training team, it will also be a big expense for a school that provides military training for five to six thousand freshmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhipeng believes that the implementation of the compulsory content required by the &quot;Military Course Syllabus for General Colleges and Universities&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;such as light weapons shooting, battlefield medical treatment First aid, etc.&lt;/span>;), so that more ordinary students can have the experience of hard-core military training, it is necessary to &quot;increase resource investment, strengthen policy supply, and create a professional team of national defense education teachers. At the same time, teaching must incorporate the latest technologies VR, The introduction of informatization and intelligent equipment such as drones into military training will enhance the four flavors of military training, namely fun, military flavor, war flavor and technological flavor, and improve student participation and educational effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Yu, Shen Hong, and Li Ming are all pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国常会审议通过《人体器官捐献和移植条例（修订草案）》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259053]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang presided over the executive meeting of the State Council&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;State Council&#39;s Notice on Cancellation and Adjustment of a Group of Decision on Fine Matters&quot; and &quot;Regulations on Human Organ Donation and Transplantation (Revised Draft)&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Premier Li Qiang chaired an executive meeting of the State Council on October 20 to review and adopt the &quot;State Council&#39;s Notice on Cancellation and Adjustment of a Group of Fine Matters&quot; Decision&quot; and &quot;Human Organ Donation and Transplantation Regulations (Revised Draft)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting pointed out that strictly regulating penalties and fine standards is an important measure to optimize the business environment and reduce operating costs. It is necessary to continue to reduce fines and reduce fines that violate legal authority, do not meet the needs of economic and social development, and can be managed in other ways. It is necessary to strictly regulate the discretionary power of administrative penalties, intensify efforts to rectify arbitrary fines, improve collaborative governance and joint punishment mechanisms, seriously investigate and punish behaviors such as the administration of fines and excessive fines, increase exposure to the society, and prevent all types of benefits. The effect of corporate policies is weakened or offset. Efforts should be made to strengthen interim and ex-post supervision, improve supervision methods, standardize supervision procedures, improve supervision efficiency, and effectively strengthen supervision in key areas such as production safety, life and health, and product quality, so as to provide strong support for promoting high-quality development. According to the meeting&#39;s deliberations, it is planned to cancel and adjust 33 fines in administrative regulations and departmental rules as a package. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting emphasized that human organ donation and transplantation are acts of great love and charity in the world, related to the lives and health of the people, bioethics and social justice, and are an important symbol of the development of national medicine and the progress of social civilization. We must put people and life first, further regulate human organ donation and transplantation, ensure the quality of medical care, protect human health, and safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of citizens. It is necessary to take this revision of the regulations as an opportunity to strengthen legal protection, establish a full-process traceability and supervision mechanism, strengthen the construction of the organ donation work system, strengthen the ethical review of organ procurement, crack down on and investigate organ-related crimes in accordance with the law, and better protect the organ donation and The transplantation industry is developing healthily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other matters were also considered at the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列进攻加沙有多难？丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258963]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/xR91tMnZtrplBiQuvhY8Iwfs2YUaEY5bS0FgMwuo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xR91tMnZtrplBiQuvhY8Iwfs2YUa ​​EY5bS0FgMwuo. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 13, 2023, Israeli troops assembled on the Israeli side of the Gaza border &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, due to the escalation of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict caused by attacks launched by Hamas, Israel was attacked after Quickly mobilize and assemble a large number of troops, preparing to enter the Gaza Strip from the ground to completely eliminate the armed forces of the Hamas organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the Israeli army has an absolute strength advantage and there is no suspense about victory or defeat, the Israeli soldiers will undoubtedly face a very complex battlefield. Militants who have been lying in wait for a long time are waiting for the Israeli army to enter. They have a large number of Tunnel bunkers were available and large quantities of anti-tank weapons and explosives were prepared. What’s even more troublesome is that not only do a large number of local civilians in the Gaza Strip have nowhere to go, Hamas forces also control many hostages taken from Israel, which makes offensive operations more inconvenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, 2023 local time, Israel gave residents in northern Gaza 24 hours to leave their homes and go to the south to escape the fighting. Therefore, there are constant rumors from the outside that Israel will soon launch a ground attack on Gaza. However, in my personal judgment, Israel&#39;s full-scale offensive will not begin anytime soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the sudden incident, even though Israel&#39;s mobilization efficiency was very high and 300,000 reservists were recalled within one day, the reorganization, equipment distribution and familiarization of these troops, as well as pre-war mobilization, still took time. In addition, fire sweep before ground troops enter is also necessary. According to local news, in addition to dispatching its air force to attack hundreds of targets every day, Israel&#39;s artillery is also constantly shelling targets in northern Gaza at half-minute intervals. The purpose of these attacks is not only to destroy Hamas targets that have been discovered, but also as a psychological warfare method to constantly tire and disturb the enemy, forcing local civilians to flee as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This type of attack is a typical pre-war softening method for urban warfare, just like the use of shock bombs in anti-terrorism operations, leaving the opponent confused and unable to accurately judge the time to launch a real ground attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to tactical strikes, Israel has also implemented a siege policy on the Gaza Strip, cutting off water, electricity, and communications. This was not only intended to punish the local population but was also intended to affect Hamas&#39;s military communications. Since Hamas is an organization that is inseparable from civilians and military, its communications rely heavily on civilian networks and mobile phone base stations. If its power and network communications are cut off, it will not only be difficult for Hamas armed personnel to charge their electronic devices, but they will also need to add additional communications. Means to ensure smooth communication during wartime. The delay in entering after cutting off the water and power grid is actually to wait for Hamas to activate the backup communication means to conduct subsequent electronic reconnaissance, and to master the frequency band, communication habits and encryption methods of Hamas&#39;s backup communication, so that the Israeli military can launch attacks on the ground Then interfere or locate the communicator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, the newly mobilized troops and active units still need to conduct some necessary pre-war drills to become familiar with the intended battlefield environment and continuously improve the combat plan. Intelligence and reconnaissance units also need to conduct necessary pre-war reconnaissance to further grasp the real-time battlefield situation and enemy conditions. Whether it is technical reconnaissance, human reconnaissance or fire reconnaissance, it requires a lot of time and resources to complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the above technical laws of war, Israel&#39;s full-scale attack on the Gaza Strip will require at least 2-6 weeks of pre-war preparation time. All current information about launching a ground attack is likely to be interference signals released by Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Israel launched its ground attack, it certainly faced many challenges, of which the outside world was most concerned about Hamas’s tunnel warfare methods. There may be an entire city&#39;s worth of tunnels and bunkers beneath the surface of Gaza, where Hamas can constantly evade Israeli ground fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Gaza is actually not as strong as the city fortresses such as Bahmut and Mariupol in the Russia-Ukraine conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern war machines are extremely destructive. Only modern industrialized reinforced concrete structures can withstand artillery attacks to a certain extent. Ukraine is an industrialized country, and most of its buildings are built with modern construction techniques and can easily be transformed into fortresses that can withstand artillery fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the houses in the Gaza Strip are brick-concrete structures. Judging from the experience of blasting operations, brick-concrete structures are actually not very resistant to attacks by modern weapons. Large-caliber machine guns can even penetrate brick-concrete structures directly. For the exterior wall of a structural house, the fragments of the internal wall that explode while penetrating can even become anti-personnel shotguns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, using wall-breaking bombs for blasting operations can easily open new attack channels on the opponent&#39;s wall. The main reason why urban street fighting is terrifying is that the defender can concentrate its firepower in the killing traps set by itself. However, if the attacker can bypass the killing traps, the traps will be useless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the issue of tunnels, although tunnels can hide the traces of Hamas on weekdays, there are actually many means of detection and destruction of tunnels during wartime. To deal with tunnels in plain areas, you generally only need to control the ground first, then detect them through technical means, and destroy them with weapons such as cloud bombs. At the same time, you can also use cement trucks to grout all the detected entrances and exits. If Hamas cannot gain a foothold on the ground and simply takes shelter in the tunnels, the Israeli army can easily destroy the tunnels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel also has a capability that has not been seen in past wars, which is the world&#39;s first-class design and manufacturing capabilities of cruise missiles, drones and unmanned combat robots. Israel was the first country to use cruise missiles in war, and it is still the leader in the research and development of this technology. Even the U.S. military is purchasing Israeli-made cruise missiles to equip the army. Although Israel suffered heavy losses from Hamas drone attacks in previous attacks, in future operations, Israel&#39;s loitering bombs, drones and combat robots may attack in full. Even though Hamas has learned to use drones to deal with tanks, it does not have the corresponding anti-drone and loitering missile capabilities. The ground attack will inevitably be accompanied by the reconnaissance and surveillance of a large number of drones and the attack of loitering missiles. This is Russia and Ukraine. A capability that neither Russia nor Ukraine has on the battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In any case, Israel’s ground attack will be a joint attack of sea, air, ground and unmanned systems, which will undoubtedly give the outside world an opportunity to peek into new tactics for urban combat in future wars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王培军：我所喜看的九部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258957]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/20/Tl3bAwVIiWDjuln3lIIiPIfXFnKQo1vmQZXWH3OU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/Tl3bAwVIiWDjuln3lIIiPIfXFnKQo1v mQZXWH3OU. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254699&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the movie &quot;A Chinese Ghost Story&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last verse of &quot;Vajra Prajnaparamita Sutra&quot; says: &quot;All conditioned dharma, such as A dream is like a bubble. It is like dew or lightning. It should be viewed as such.&quot; Thirty-three years ago, when I was in college, I went to Mingjiao Temple with my classmates and bought this Diamond Sutra. I didn&#39;t realize at all at that time that the names of the movies that modern people love to watch were already mentioned here, and the profound meaning contained in the word &quot;movie&quot; was also revealed in these few sentences. Life is like a movie, and movies are literally &quot;like dreams, illusions, bubbles, shadows, like dew and lightning.&quot; Movies are just the shadow of life, and life is just a shadow like a movie. Most people like to watch movies, just like children who like to watch the shadows of everything and are endlessly curious about them. I can&#39;t count how many movies I&#39;ve watched, but I know the movies I watch many times because I like them. Even if you watch a good movie, if you watch it too much and you are overly familiar with it, you will definitely get bored and will not want to watch it again. This is just like delicious food, if you do not exercise restraint and eat too much to its upper limit, you will definitely get bored. , sometimes even vomiting after eating, vowing never to eat again. This is the opposite of things. Everything in the world has this dialectic. But how many times do you watch it before you get bored? The number of times you get bored is obviously a measure that can be used to detect the quality of a movie and how much you like it. The following nine movies are ones that I have watched many times but have grown tired of and do not want to watch again in the near future - of course because they are good to watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/90EHlvLkm3J5RX3wvb61RptQMwpAiWtefgYq1Zz1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/90EHlvLkm3J5RX3wvb61RptQMwpAiWtefgYq1Zz1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254703&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A Chinese Ghost Story&quot; 》Part 1 (1987). The first time I watched &quot;A Chinese Ghost Story&quot; was the third part, which was in the mid-1990s. There is only one scene that I remember now, that is, Shifang&#39;s master grew his own long ears to cover his eyes because he couldn&#39;t beat the grandma. I watched it again later, and all I remember is still this incident. I watched the first part six or seven times, maybe more. &quot;A Chinese Ghost Story&quot; is based on the &quot;Nie Xiaoqian&quot; chapter of &quot;Strange Stories from a Chinese Studio&quot;. This is a well-known story that many people are familiar with when they were young. After being rewritten in the movie, it can be said to be &quot;beyond all recognition.&quot; But it is undoubtedly more exciting than the novel, and much better than Pu Liuxian. Although &quot;Nie Xiaoqian&quot; is famous in &quot;Strange Stories from a Chinese Studio&quot;, it is not the best chapter. I think Wang Zuxian is indeed very beautiful in this movie, and it can also be said to be the most beautiful time in his life. Some places are very poetic, such as Nie Xiaoqian hiding Ning Caichen in a water tank, in order to give Ning Caichen The scene where they had to kiss each other to take a breath was actually the highlight of the film. The tension of the atmosphere and the romance of the situation are all combined into one, and the cleverness of its conception can only be achieved by the so-called &quot;intelligent literati&quot;. But if we talk about Nie Xiaoqian&#39;s beauty, the most beautiful part is not here, but the part where she says, &quot;Ghosts are as good and bad as people, and many people in the world are more harmful to people than ghosts.&quot; Her words are so smooth and beautiful. , also complement each other. Generally speaking, the beauty of a woman&#39;s expression is to smile first, and to think secondly. Laughing and laughing wildly will inevitably impair the beauty. Therefore, the ancients had the precept &quot;laughing will not cause stagnation&quot;, &quot;smile&quot; refers to the gums, and laughter It&#39;s not beautiful when you see your gums. The same goes for crying. If you can look beautiful even when you cry, then you are truly a beautiful person. The shot of Nie Xiaoqian talking and crying at the same time is absolutely beautiful. It can also be said to be the most beautiful shot in the film. The so-called &quot;pear blossom brings rain in spring&quot; is nothing more than that! In the TV series &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, the character who plays sister Lin who loves to cry cries so much that it&#39;s hard to watch, which often ruins the scene. I have to say that this is also a failure in the drama &quot;Red&quot;. One night not long ago, I accidentally heard someone singing &quot;Flower Sacrifice&quot;. I was curious, so I searched for Wang Zuxian again and found that she was already very old. Therefore, I remembered the famous saying of the ancients: &quot;Beauty has been like a famous general since ancient times. See you grow old!&quot; Yes, everything in the world cannot withstand the flow of time. On the contrary, movies are illusory and unreal, they can remain unchanged forever, and they can allow us to relive the time that has passed! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/3jyQAmXsfn8k8ngBMz8RKYLtcTMqOszICqJy04Yn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/3jyQAmXsfn8k8ngBMz8RKYLtcTMqOszICqJy04Yn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254701&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《青蛇》（1993）。这是徐克电影的最佳作之一，编剧是李碧华。我写过一首七绝，论及此片：“清羸洗马多情骨，放诞文君绝世姿。如此风流能合传，徐君才调妙堪思。”“清羸卫洗马，放诞卓文君”，是清代冯班所写的一联，我觉得对得很好，所以借用了。我一直认为，才子（亦包括书生）佳人的搭配，是最不易见好的。其故不易知，也可能是同色调的在一起，不能互起烘衬的作用所致。才子与佳人，当然是同色调的人物了。反之却不然，比如以土行孙配邓婵玉、王矮虎配一丈青，就妙不可言，可使人一见不忘。近人吴昌硕有一画，画的是朱栾实与兰，他并为之作诗云：“如以昆仑奴，侍立美人侧。”兰是国香，朱栾皮甚粗，将之同写于一幅，相形而得奇趣，这就是深知其事的要义了。爱情的故事，其本质是一个搭配的问题，女角男角配得好，故事就出色，配得不好，就容易落套。才子佳人的搭配，是最易于落套的一个搭配，所以写才子佳人的故事，从来吃力不讨好，这是连贾府中的老太太也能批判的事。 《青蛇》也是才子佳人式的故事，但是却很好，所以能如此，也可能是有了小青的旁衬之故，这大概也是电影所以名《青蛇》之故。但不管怎样，电影故事的主体，其实是一种如张继青版《牡丹亭》的“妩媚入骨”的调子，也许可以说，电影里的《青蛇》，就像戏里的《牡丹亭》，是可以作“妩媚入骨”四个字的注脚的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/03yYLvvBIobhX8CwXQhUSOs9VUAfBZok6PUU5WxS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/03yYLvvBIobhX8CwXQhUSOs9VUAfBZok6PUU5WxS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254704&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《新龙门客栈》（1992）。 《青蛇》中的张曼玉和王祖贤，为彼此之互衬，表现固佳，若就其本人而言，也还不能算她们的最佳之作。张曼玉所饰的至于极致的角色，无疑是《新龙门客栈》中的那个放诞的老板娘金镶玉。其性情之跳脱不羁，语言之泼辣流利，表情、身段之变化多姿，皆捉搦不住，而又自然入微，无不熨帖，这应该是一般观者都能赏会的。不过金镶玉的为人，只是市井中的俗人，虽然不讨厌，但也谈不上多么可爱。她与周淮安也不匹配，她最后烧掉客栈，骑马追周而去，似乎是她可以取代邱莫愁的位子，与周结合；但其实这只是电影的一种省事的了结法而已。从做文章的角度说，此客栈非得烧掉不可，而邱莫愁也是舍死无他法，不如此收拾，文章便是庸手了。金圣叹批《水浒传》第五回的“鲁智深火烧瓦官寺”，有几句说得好：“文如工画师，亦如大火聚，随手而成造，亦复随手坏。”电影也是文章，亦正同此理。但我于此片所最欣赏的，还不是这些，而是电影中把各路各色的不下数十百人，一股脑儿全塞进那个小客栈，让其在狭仄的空间中，尽数表现，而又各具面目，千变万化，人人不同。人物彼此之间，钩心斗角，层出不穷，杀机四起，而复争风吃醋，风光旖旎，点染其间，有“笙箫夹鼓、琴瑟间钟”之妙，其关系则纷繁复杂，其危机则一触即发，其文情则如火如荼，极“做戏”之大观，而所有的这些人物，中心则是金镶玉，仿佛金镶玉乃是一个机括，此中之人之事，一切由她操纵、斡旋，实在她也只是电影借之以串戏的一根线索，就像傀儡戏的“吊线”，拽之通体皆动。不仅此也，客栈中的人物、头绪虽多，但却丝毫不乱，乍看如风吹乱叶，细绎之则脉络井然，“草蛇灰线”，恰似苏轼评画诗所说的：“交柯乱叶动无数，一一皆可寻其源。”这真是可为击节叹赏的。至于电影中的对白之妙，犹是余事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/mJ7ZrWlcCdzDNl6PCQqTwkIziYEOGguGVBesjr8n.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1571&quot; height=&quot;2098&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/mJ7ZrWlcCdzDNl6PCQqTwkIziYEOGguGVBesjr8n.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254713&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《笑傲江湖之东方不败》（1992）。就打斗动作而言，此片较之《新龙门客栈》，要更为精彩。就林青霞所饰的东方不败而言，较之张曼玉饰的金镶玉，那也要美得多。而电影中令狐冲的飒爽豪气，任盈盈的缠绵情意，以及一班要退出江湖、归隐牛背山的华山派弟子的同心之约，所有这些，都使得此片较之《新龙门客栈》，色调更为温暖，也更为好看。所不及于《新龙门客栈》的，只是人物的内心，没有那么的多变，也没有那么微妙，而稍显粗线条。但此片中的好几个镜头，借古人的批点文章之法，可说都是值得加双圈的，有的并可加“名句、千古不能有二”的批，如东方不败在水中举着酒壶仰首而饮的那个镜头，令狐冲抱着东方不败在月光下御风而行的那个镜头，就都是。蓝凤凰与任盈盈坐在屋顶上的那一段，声口之妙，则可谓不让唐传奇、《聊斋志异》中的佳处。只是任盈盈的饰者，脸型似乎不对，看起来稍显老，而且说的是方言，不但不美（蓝凤凰说方言，却又不见其不美），也不合小姐的身份了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/AUMphw2CHIOe3CFfP9re5ZJiHmz3mIHKFeu8ASdu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;662&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/AUMphw2CHIOe3CFfP9re5ZJiHmz3mIHKFeu8ASdu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254702&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《功夫》（2004）。周星驰的电影，在我大多都是乐看的，而之所以推此为最，是因为其中最后一场打斗戏，可以说是中国打戏的登峰造极之作了。周星驰甚喜戏仿，他的这一场把那些斧头帮的黑衣人打得满天飞的戏，应该是仿《黑客帝国2》（The Matrix Reloaded）的。多年之前，我在电视上看《机械师2》（Mechanic: Resurrection），有一处镜头，是那个杀手从缆车俯身一跃而跳到滑翔伞上，儿子在旁看到了，激动地说：“我玩的游戏中，也有这个动作的，原来是从这来的。这是编程的人对这个电影的致敬！”我之听说“模仿就是致敬”，这是第一次。但《功夫》之仿《黑客帝国》，是否即是致敬，我还不能肯定。但无可疑的，是《功夫》的这一场戏，比起《黑客帝国》要打得好看得多。中国的打戏，所尚的不是“拼命努力”，“拼命努力”，从不是中国艺术的高境，中国人要的是举重若轻，好整以暇，要谈言微中，手挥目送，要不挂相、不着相，优哉游哉，痕迹俱泯，而“力小而任重”，“举鼎绝脰”，从古就是绝大的笑枋。一切事情都是如此。所以《功夫》中的这场打戏，虽然打得别人满天乱飞，但周星驰本人的神情，却也并不吃力，其大体的氛围，是轻妙好看的，而反视《黑客帝国》中的尼奥（Neo）与一大堆的黑衣特工的那种打法，用尽吃奶气力的样子，也就高下显然了。这是一比即可知、无须多说的。假如人类确是从古猿进化而来，那么中国人是必进化得更久远的一种人类，中国文化亦然，它已脱尽生野气，这包括精神的和物质的诸方面，当然也包括武打。至于《功夫》的主旨，我觉得是同于龚自珍《尊隐》的：日之昏之世，豪杰生于下，“丑类寙呰，诈伪不材，是辇是任”，“如是则豪杰轻量京师，而山中之势重”。也就是说，末世时的高手，都是隐在民间的。所以电影开头的官方警察局，就是最窝囊无用的，后面接着出场的鳄鱼帮、斧头帮、贫民窟里的裁缝、苦力和油炸鬼、两个瞎子、包租婆、包租公、火云邪神，一个比一个不起眼，而一个比一个功夫高，而电影中最高的高手，却是那个最为无用的小时被乞丐用两分钱一本的《如来神掌》骗了的阿星，而那本只值两分钱的《如来神掌》，也才是真正的天下第一的“武功秘笈”！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/fKJX1gYlMOy8NqtUWf3ignbptbgVdaFqILnIZymI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;652&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/fKJX1gYlMOy8NqtUWf3ignbptbgVdaFqILnIZymI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254705&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《冷山》（Cold Mountain，2003）。这是以美国南北战争为背景的一个爱情电影，男主角英曼（Inman）是一名士兵，为了他所爱的艾达（Ada），而当了逃兵，要回到他的家乡。当然最终历经艰险，回到了爱人身边，但最后也被打死了。这是有点类似于《十年归》的奥德修斯式的一个故事，其故事的本身，在西方是说不上新鲜的。电影是据美国的一本畅销小说改编的，据说，那是小说作者的祖辈的一个真实发生的事。我之喜欢这个电影，主要不是在于故事，而在于人物，而那个萦绕于电影中的哀伤的音乐，也起了相当的作用，因为它使得电影具有一种抒情长诗的调子。英曼是裘德·洛（Jude Law）所饰，艾达是妮可·基德曼（Nicole Kidman）所饰，二人也很般配，看起来使人愉悦。我也乐见年轻人在般配的爱情中成为眷属。毛姆（WS Maugham）说过，一个人谈恋爱的最大年龄，不应超过三十五岁，我觉得是有道理的。爱情的故事，必须是要有点华美的才好看，而要有华美，首要的条件是青春年少。同时，在爱情的故事中，也还要有一种一往有情痴，才能够动人。 《说文解字》心部“情”字云：“情，人之阴气有欲者。”与“性”的为“人之阳气”不同。性受之于天，谓之天性，所以是不变的；情起于人事，谓之人情，所以是易变的。情有七情，包括喜、怒、哀、惧、爱、恶、欲，无时不在变中。但人世间的事，有时候很怪，凡易变的就以不变为佳，不易变的又以变为佳。所以文章以新变为好，爱情则以不变为好，这也就是“难能可贵”，——因为“难能”，所以“可贵”。英曼与艾达的爱情故事，所以能打动人心，其故在此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/LXqVl4OWvfbzFMXAMCfThxewWcdHMRuVXZTTC0sB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2025&quot; height=&quot;3000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/LXqVl4OWvfbzFMXAMCfThxewWcdHMRuVXZTTC0sB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254706&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《人工智能》（AI Artificial Intelligence，2001）。斯皮尔伯格（Steven Spielberg）的电影中，这一部是相对不被注意的，但却是我特别喜欢的。这是一个机器人小孩执著地寻找被爱的伤心的故事，看这部电影，有一种儿时读安徒生《海的女儿》时的那般的怅惘，仿佛心的某处被琴弦轻轻触碰了一下，而生起的如缕的渺茫的哀伤。其实电影的故事，与《海的女儿》并非一类。斯皮尔伯格真是一个鬼才。按理说，机器人是机械制造的，精密、高端、有效，没有肉心，所以机械是无情的；而他却偏在情字上做文章，使得机器与人类情感中最柔弱的那一部分，生发故事。这可说是一种相当别致的巧思，整部电影亦以别致取胜。那个小孩也演得很好。另外，在《冷山》中饰演英曼的裘德·洛，在此片中饰一被制造作轻佻的青年男子的机器人，亦惟妙惟肖，与英曼的形象大反，简直辨认不出，这也是可以一提的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/3a5V5aE0HHpcnUndKkWzvFtLwyKFH9ZSvTYYwepR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;615&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/3a5V5aE0HHpcnUndKkWzvFtLwyKFH9ZSvTYYwepR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254707&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《星际穿越》（Interstellar，2014）。这是与时间有关的一个电影。时间是宇宙中的一个谜，也是宇宙中最迷人、最伤脑筋的一件事，它从古就引起哲人的沉思、诗人的咏叹，却又是不能定义，也捕捉不住的。 “人生不满百，常怀千岁忧”，人生不过百年，一百年也就是31.5576亿秒，但是我们所思想的，有时则在一百亿个31557600秒之外。宇宙中的每一秒，都如电光石火，稍纵即逝，一百年中的每一秒，亦是如此。所以以弗所的赫拉克利特（Heraclitus）说，“你不能两次踏进同一条河流”（Upon those that step into the same rivers different and different waters flow）。 “时间枯萎了青春的娇妍，时间摧残了美人的眉黛，它饱餐自然真理的珍馐，万物都在等待着它那镰刀来割刈”。诺兰（Nolan）执导的电影，2010年的《盗梦空间》（Inception），也是我很喜欢看的；但看了两遍之后，就不想再看了。这是所有以新奇取胜的电影（也包括其他作品）的通病，无可避免。但《星际穿越》就不同了，它的内容要丰富得多，而它的场景是那样宏大、浩瀚，有时是诗意的，透射着一种深邃宇宙中才有的庄严和神秘。在所有的科幻片中，这是我看的遍数最多，也是最喜欢的一部。有一年我读刘光第诗，里面有一联，是写下西陵峡的：“大波颓作阱，长舸立如锥。”立刻想起在Miller星球上，那一望无际的浅浅的水，几分钟后，就变成绝壁悬崖一样的巨浪打过来，那么大的飞船，霎时像一只长形的小盒子，被那个巨浪掀立起来。这个镜头堪称天才的手笔之一，惊心动魄，这当然也不是晚近人的诗所能摹写于万一的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/D0X5B75SkBgJM91PU5UhoRWzkST9YxnNd3rTVL3C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;1733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/D0X5B75SkBgJM91PU5UhoRWzkST9YxnNd3rTVL3C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254700&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《深蓝》（Deep Blue，2003）。这部电影可以说是一篇史诗的巨制，一部沉思翰藻的杰作，亦是最足以见出西方伟大精神之所在的作品。西方在庄严伟大上，确是要远胜过中国的，犹之中国的风神隽逸，亦非西方所可及。对于这部电影，我认为除了去看，是不用再说别的什么了。孔子的“予欲无言”，我看了这个电影，亦大有同感。也就是说，批评有时是多余的，欣赏即可。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我本来很想凑足“十部电影”，但想来想去，也想不出另外的一部，只好姑且算了。后来一转念，记起汪容甫的《释三九》，说“积而至十，则复归于一，十不可以为数，故九者，数之终也”，九是最大之数，“九部电影”正是恰好的数，又何必要凑到“十”呢？况且六十四卦的爻，不是也以“九”为名，说初九、九二、九五等等吗？其实不仅是“九”，就是“十九”，也是一个大数，古历法即以十九年为一章，阴历的生日，过十九年始与阳历生日合，所以《庄子》中说“今臣之刀十九年矣”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多地马拉松乱象频现：利益链不能冲击比赛公正性丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259047]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，各地马拉松赛事出现一系列组织问题甚至“事故”，引发关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月15日开跑的青岛海上马拉松赛出现了现场混乱的情况。有网友在社交媒体上表示，赛事现场补给不充足、人员分流不到位、领取完赛奖牌排队太久……现场甚至出现群众高喊“退钱”的情况；同样于15日进行的临沂马拉松赛也出现了争议一幕：冠军选手在冲过终点线时，被两名拉线员用横幅阻挡。不过好在工作人员及时赶到，冠军最终顺利通过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最大的争议，发生在同一天的大连马拉松赛场。中国选手尹顺金在最后冲刺阶段被一辆引导车挡住去路，导致冲冠失败。此事在社交媒体引发热议，赛事主办方专业性也遭受质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对近期马拉松赛事的频发乱象，10月19日中国田径协会发布《中国田径协会关于进一步加强全国路跑赛事竞赛组织工作的紧急通知》指出，近期，部分路跑赛事发生竞赛组织方面的问题，引起社会的广泛关注，造成一定的负面影响，要求强化赛事组织各方责任，严格执行比赛规则，排查安全隐患，做好服务配套，提高办赛质量，及时上报突发事件与情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马拉松赛事组织方面的各项问题由来已久，并非最近才爆出来的新闻。马拉松赛事组织问题，至少牵涉到两个层面的问题，一是赛事本身的硬件设施、办赛条件，牵涉到主办方的专业性；二是赛事能否保证比赛的公平性，尊重多个民事主体在赛场内外的合法权益。这两个层面的问题，都时刻考验着各地马拉松的赛事组织水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从专业性来说，此次青岛与临沂两地马拉松出现的状况，就是主办方在硬件设施不达标、软件配套不完备的情况下“带病办赛”，以至于让观众吐槽、让选手受累。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专业性不足，自然会影响比赛的公平性。如果说临沂马拉松的“拉线员用横幅”还可解释为专业能力不足、最终并未影响冠军队员比赛成绩的话，那么大连马拉松出现的情况就难免让人朝着另一方向解读了。大连这辆引导车的“诡异转向”实在是不专业得不像话，不少网友合理怀疑这是主办方的盘外招，目的是为了保证特定运动员可以拿到比赛成绩，赛事的公平性因此遭遇质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;细审这些马拉松赛事里的争议，一旦赛事的专业性与公平性出现问题，运动员就是首当其冲的受害者，现场观众也会大喊“退钱”，本地市民也难免受害。试问，主办方与运营公司能否承担责任，赔偿他们的各项损失？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以此次大连马拉松而言，运动员尹顺金遭遇引导车这么一挡，损失的不仅是他一个人的比赛成绩。赛事办到这个份上，花钱买票的现场观众也会感觉看了场假马拉松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在目前这种“各地政府牵头主办、运营公司商业开发”的模式下，各地马拉松赛事已经逐渐形成了一套利益分配链。当地政府有了知名度，主办方拿到了广告赞助费，甚至比赛成绩也传出“内定”疑云。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;舆论场上有声音就质疑说，近些年来“非洲选手包揽国内马拉松赛事前三名”的情况屡见不鲜，背后可能涉及一套灰黑产业链：有“聪明人”瞄准了马拉松赛事的巨额奖金，于是前往非洲寻找优秀选手，以“中介代理”的名义派这些非洲选手参赛。非洲选手只能拿到一部分奖金，“聪明人”却可以凭借剪刀差从中获取巨额收益，甚至不无与主办方勾结、以“盘外招”保证非洲选手拿冠军的手段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“引导车挡人”，就有不要人认为有盘外招的嫌疑，目的就是阻挡中国优秀马拉松运动员，保证非洲选手拿到冠军。如果这种嫌疑成立的话，那么涉事主办方岂止是专业性与公平性不足的问题，往深了说甚至涉嫌违劳务欺诈，这对马拉松赛事的伤害将是空前的。如不深入调查，何以杜悠悠之口？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马拉松毕竟还是一项体育运动，不是什么纯粹为了圈钱挣钱的文旅项目。马拉松为谁而办？当然首先还是要为运动员而办，保障赛事的公平性，提升组织的专业性；其次则是为现场观众而办，至少要对得起他们进场观赛的票钱，不至于让人看了一场“假跑”；最后，马拉松赛事需要服务本地市民，尊重市民的需求。如果做到这些，各地举办的马拉松赛事才算得上是没有背弃体育运动的初心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国马拉松信息平台统计，自2023年1月1日至6月30日，全国共有133场路跑赛事在中国田协备案，其中全程马拉松61场、半程马拉松及其他项目72场。中国田径协会发布的《2019中国马拉松大数据分析报告》也显示，全国337个城市（4个直辖市+333个地级行政区），2019年已有300个城市举办了马拉松规模赛事，占比高达89%。马拉松赛事已经到了“全国开花，无地不办”的程度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各地政府热衷办赛，希望借此提升城市形象。不过，屡屡爆出的赛事组织问题显示，各地政府与主办方是时候思考“马拉松为何而办，为谁而办”的问题了，不能再让这项古老的运动变成草台班子唱戏，也不能如此屡屡不把运动员与观众放在心上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[体验分娩的痛，准爸爸我只坚持了3秒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259045]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[狗伤人引发热议，人宠还能和谐共处吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259033]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/20/ckPdktfabP9rKiAV9t3O7w0hZJr34cRkHUaAXyyS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/ckPdktfabP9rKiAV9t3O7w0hZJr3 4cRkHUaAXyyS. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Yantai, Shandong, citizens walk their dogs on the beach&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, a girl in Chongzhou, Sichuan was bitten by an unleashed ferocious dog in a community and was seriously injured. She is still in the intensive care unit. The owner of the ferocious dog Criminal enforcement measures have been taken. This incident brought the existential conflict between humans and dogs to the focus of social attention, and triggered widespread discussions: how to defend yourself when vicious dogs attack, what legal basis are there for pets to hurt people, and how to raise dogs in a civilized manner... &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; Several attorneys and canine behavior experts were interviewed about these hot topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Private or sue? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;One late night in February 2021, He Qing (pseudonym), who lives in Chaoyang District, Beijing, was walking his dog in the community when he was suddenly attacked by an unleashed German Shepherd (commonly known as the &quot;black dog&quot;). &quot;back&quot;) fell to the ground. Hei Bei bit He Qing&#39;s left cheek, tearing a hole and causing blood to flow out. At this time, the owner of Heibei arrived in a hurry and immediately sent her to the hospital with He Qing&#39;s husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the break between treatments, He Qing’s husband asked the owner of the black back to write a handwritten statement of the situation, explaining the time, place and process of the incident, and attaching a signature. This written record became the key to subsequent legal proceedings. evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the black-backed owner admitted the fact at the first time, she later regretted it, denying the fact that her dog bit He Qing, and claimed that He Qing was bitten by her dog (Bichon Frize). ) bitten and refused to pay any expenses including medical expenses. Helpless and angry, He Qing decided to use the law to protect her legitimate rights and interests, filed a lawsuit with Beijing Chaoyang Court, and hired lawyer Wang Yandong from Beijing Lianggao Law Firm as her attorney. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Wang obtained key video records such as community and hospital surveillance as evidence, and submitted them to the court together with the defendant&#39;s handwritten description of the situation and other evidence. In the end, the court ruled that the plaintiff He Qing won the case, and the defendant had to pay the plaintiff a total of more than 15,000 yuan, including medical expenses, transportation expenses, nutrition expenses, and mental damage solatium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Wang specifically mentioned the 5,000 yuan moral comfort payment, &quot;The amount of compensation in this type of infringement cases is usually not very high, but if the infringing party does not recognize the liability or has a very bad attitude, it will cause The victim suffered psychological trauma. I specifically added a claim for emotional consolation to the lawsuit, because my client is a woman, and the injury was to such an important part of the face, which required stitches and long-term surgery. The process of repair and plastic surgery, and the psychological impact of this trauma on a woman cannot be ignored. In the end, the court supported our petition, and this mental comfort payment brought great psychological comfort to my client.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/FxiNfrPjgMQuTgQP3r9vteVtryDT34HY4Zwxxa2q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/FxiNfrPjgMQuTgQP3r9vteVtryDT34HY4Zwxxa2q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nantong, Jiangsu Province, the police distributed promotional materials to encourage the public to raise dogs in a scientific and civilized manner&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;One and a half years after the incident, He Qing obtained the court judgment in August 2022 and received corresponding compensation. There are still scars on her face. She and the defendant ignored each other when they met in the community. Since the black back raised by the defendant is a prohibited dog in the &quot;Beijing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;, it was sent away after the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Lawyer Wang, in reality, there are not many people like He Qing who end up in the litigation process because raising animals causes damage to the parties. “If the other party does not regret it midway, but actively apologizes, Negotiating compensation will most likely not lead to litigation. This is because the economic and time costs of going through judicial procedures are relatively high. Many parties drop out or stop litigation because they are tired of litigation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When encountering such incidents , should the two parties resolve it through negotiation or resort to public power for judgment? Lawyer Du Jiahong, a partner at Beijing Xinglai Law Firm, believes that when criminal liability is not involved, it mainly depends on whether the two parties have reached an agreement on the understanding of the infringement (including the cause of the infringement and the damage results) and the handling results. &quot;It causes a tenth-level disability, but if the offending party has a good attitude and actively compensates, the two parties may reach an agreement. However, if they cannot reach an agreement for several thousand yuan, they may also file a lawsuit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Wang suggested When such infringement occurs, evidence must be obtained as soon as possible and the evidence must be fixed first. &quot;When the infringement first occurs, the resistance and alertness of the relevant party may not be very strong. Regarding some facts, he may admit that this The infringed party must fix the evidence for later use in defending rights. The focus of filing a lawsuit in court to defend rights is the evidence. If the evidence is not fully fixed in the early stage, once the infringer retorts or does not admit the facts later, it will be This causes greater difficulties in safeguarding rights. There are many ways to obtain evidence, such as video, recording, signing a written agreement recognized by both parties, etc. When necessary, relevant surveillance can be obtained through the public security organs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/hYIaK5IAlfTdL03KKUiscAchU02wgNux3iprwdDw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/hYIaK5IAlfTdL03KKUiscAchU02wgNux3iprwdDw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254736&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A golden retriever is undergoing a scare test - screening out dogs prone to excessive fear, aggression or over-excitability of running, screaming, over-enthusiastic people. This test simulates the scenarios that therapy dogs may encounter in service facilities, minimizing safety hazards&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A dog bites a person&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;it is essentially a tort&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At present, our country’s laws regarding animal-related injuries To deal with harm, we mainly refer to Chapter 9 &quot;Liability for harm caused by raising animals&quot; in the Tort Liability Section of the Civil Code. Articles 1,245 to 1,247 of this article clarify the liability for harm caused by raising animals. General regulations, liability for damage caused by failure to take safety measures for animals in violation of regulations, and liability for damage caused by dangerous animals that are prohibited from being raised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“A dog bites a person essentially because of the inappropriate behavior of the animal’s breeder or manager (not tying the leash, not closing the door, etc.), causing damage to other people’s rights to life, health, and body rights. Such illegal behavior should bear corresponding liability for compensation. However, if it can be proved that the damage was caused intentionally by the infringed party, its liability can be reduced,&quot; said Lawyer Wang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to lawyer Du, according to data provided by the China Judgments Network, three years since the official implementation of the Civil Code on January 1, 2021, only 100,000 judgments have been made nationwide on animal damage liability disputes. &quot;This data may not be completely accurate, but the number of such cases nationwide in three years is in the order of thousands, which shows that the number of cases is relatively small. What is this concept? Taking the Beijing area as an example, according to China According to the Judgment Documents Network, there have been more than 30,000 marriage and family dispute cases in the past three years,&quot; said lawyer Du. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this does not mean that the probability of such incidents happening in reality is small. &quot;(It&#39;s just that) most of them will be resolved through negotiation or mediation.&quot; Attorney Du shared a mediation case she has handled. In a community in Beijing, a mother and daughter were playing on the lawn. The mother turned her back to answer the phone. When the daughter saw a puppy not far away, she broke away from her mother&#39;s hand and wanted to see the dog. As soon as the mother let go and before the girl took a step, the puppy rushed towards the girl and scratched her right arm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The examination fees, medical fees, vaccination fees, nutrition fees, transportation fees, etc. incurred by medical treatment total about 4,000 yuan. The dog owner did not want to pay compensation. He believed that the main cause of the injury was the failure of parents to take good care of their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the dispute occurred, Lawyer Du intervened in the relevant mediation. &quot;I would like to tell the dog owner, first of all, you did not put a leash on the dog and lead it, which is a violation of the Beijing Dog Breeding Management Regulations. Unless the offended person was intentional, he should bear full responsibility. Secondly, the little girl was not separated from her mother at the time. The scope of care was that the little girl was suddenly jumped three or four meters away from the dog. The little girl was not exposed to a dangerous environment due to her own reasons, but was harmed due to the dog&#39;s pounce behavior in a relatively safe state. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/GqQFhDEKTz7b1rnqn5pxiC9tixWO2rqxvUrqSIaa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/GqQFhDEKTz7b1rnqn5pxiC9tixWO2rqxvUrqSIaa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing, citizens holding dogs walking in the rain&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the end, the dog owner fully compensated the medical expenses and also paid the mother’s lost work wages. After the incident, the girl was frightened and did not go to school for a week, and her mother accompanied her all day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to lawyer Du’s recollection, the incident took place in a high-end community, and the two parties finally negotiated the amount of compensation in a friendly atmosphere. “These few thousand yuan may not be very large in the eyes of the parties involved. The number, but this mother hopes to establish a correct value for her children - what is right and what is wrong, one day you bully others, you have to compensate. When you are bullied, you must take up the weapon of justice, the law. At the same time, she also Teach children not to actively provoke animals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Du also mediated an animal injury dispute that had entered into litigation. A medium-sized dog without a leash bit a small dog that was on a leash while walking. Because the owner of the small dog kicked the medium-sized dog while protecting his own dog, he was also scratched. The infringed party filed a claim of nearly 10,000 yuan. Finally, through the mediation of lawyer Du, the two parties reconciled, and the infringing party compensated several thousand yuan, most of which was used for the medical care of small dogs. &quot;For this type of tort liability incident, the losses caused to people and property fall within the scope of rights protection. Therefore, it is not just dog bites that require compensation, but also dog bites.&quot; Lawyer Du analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/RlFJGgpVB32COdu2c1JWfWyZvxXIbVVF871eKyvY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/RlFJGgpVB32COdu2c1JWfWyZvxXIbVVF871eKyvY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254738&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guangzhou, Guangdong, citizens walking their dogs encountered a robot dog&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Zheng Jie/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Humans and pets coexist harmoniously&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to avoid being attacked by dogs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Qi, a canine behavior expert and senior pet trainer, divides people&#39;s defense against dogs into two situations: one is when walking normally and seeing loose dogs, pedestrians should try to avoid interacting with dogs. Look at each other, keep walking normally (don’t tiptoe, don’t shout loudly, etc.), don’t approach or drive it away, and avoid irritating it; if we encounter the situation where a girl in Chongzhou is actively attacked by a dog, we should use the effective tools around us in time - Use bricks, wooden sticks, umbrellas, etc. to drive away dogs. Wu Qi watched the live video circulated on the Internet, and he pointed out that the mop in the cleaning lady&#39;s hand played a key role in driving away the attacking black Rottweiler. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wu Qi, there are some emergency treatment methods when encountering a dog attack, such as quickly taking off your clothes, wrapping them in one of your hands, and using this hand to block the attraction. Dog attacks, this can maximize the protection of important parts such as the neck and head. If a man with certain strength is attacked, you can try to use a leash to strangle the dog&#39;s neck to make it feel suffocated and loosen its mouth, or use your fingers to dig its eyes to temporarily lose its ability to attack. &quot;In an emergency like this, the focus must be on human life safety. We drive the dogs away within a reasonable range, but we should not be overly defensive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to prevent such an incident from happening again? Obviously not everyone can solve this problem by just carrying a stick around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/T9RgDrhnPcaH1n0vRvboqP9lTulrw4JYrt5rP4IO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/T9RgDrhnPcaH1n0vRvboqP9lTulrw4JYrt5rP4IO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hangzhou, Zhejiang, citizens queue up to apply for certificates with their pets at the dog approval window&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Wu Qi himself has more than 30 years of experience in raising dogs and has been engaged in pet training for 17 years. He said that the vicious dog injury incident in Chongzhou was &quot;a murder caused by a dog, which caused anxiety among parents with children. Dog parents are also anxious, and it has even turned into a confrontation between dog owners and non-dog owners.” Wu Qi believes that understanding between groups should be enhanced and barriers eliminated. “First of all, we must know that this is not a dog problem, but a problem of individual uncivilized dog owners. As pet owners, while we enjoy the right to keep pets, we must try not to infringe on them. Others - In addition to keeping the dog leash in accordance with regulations and cleaning up pet excrement in a timely manner, if you take your dog in an elevator and encounter a lot of people or people who are obviously afraid of dogs, you should take the initiative to avoid it and wait for the next one; when walking your dog Keep a distance from the elderly and children, and keep the dog calm... In addition, we need to know more about our dog and take it to do some necessary obedience and socialization training. We must invest time and energy and take it to the suburbs to be pet-friendly. Run in the park green space to release their energy. Daily walks and socialization should also allow them to gradually transition from an environment with relatively low pressure to an environment with many people and high pressure.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In Wu Qi’s view, keeping pets is a way of life for modern people. It can liberate people from stressful work conditions, add a living atmosphere to the family, and is also a manifestation of love for life. People who don’t own pets should be understanding. Pet owners must learn correct and scientific pet-raising concepts and management methods. People who do not keep pets but like small animals must also learn the correct way to interact with small animals. They must obtain the owner&#39;s consent before touching pets and understand the preferences of pets. , Are there any places that are sensitive and inappropriate to touch? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/qyKoggwme4hCUczK1wXYBRIq6jYbtCfgebgLo62R.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/qyKoggwme4hCUczK1wXYBRIq6jYbtCfgebgLo62R.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Dogs and owners waiting to be evaluated as therapy dogs. Dogs that pass the assessment will be trained and have the opportunity to come to serve special groups (the elderly, autistic children, etc.)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Incidences of dogs attacking people appear to be troubles and potential threats brought by dogs to humans, but in fact many dogs with social functions have been silently serving humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The PFH (Paw For Heal) therapy dog ​​charity project founded by Wu Qi selects and professionally trains ordinary companion dogs from families, and allows them to serve special groups after passing strict evaluation. For example, the elderly with dementia, autistic children, physically disabled people, patients with depression, and youth groups on campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Therapy Dog has been established for more than ten years and has served more than 100,000 people in more than ten cities across the country. So far, there has not been a single incident of a dog hurting anyone. In addition to therapy dogs, there are also guide dogs, etc. &quot;Other working dogs are silently helping humans.&quot; Wu Qi regards creating a harmonious social environment with pets as the key to resolving conflicts. &quot;Including these dogs in the family, their companionship brings indescribable happiness and joy to people.&quot; Comfort.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人类的智商正在逐年下降？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258947]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In 1978, in order to write a book to refute the so-called &quot;white people are superior to other races&quot;, American scholar James Flynn The study of human IQ began. His original plan was to just flip through the information and quote a few pages from the book. However, after reviewing a large amount of literature, Flynn was surprised to notice that Americans&#39; performance on IQ tests continued to improve over time: According to records from 1932 to 1978, the average American IQ increased in 46 years scored 13.8 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The apparent increase in IQ scores over several generations seems unlikely to be caused by genetic evolution. Flynn therefore suspected that this must be caused by changes in environmental factors, meaning that IQ is influenced more by the environment than by genetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To test his conjecture, Flynn expanded his research to 14 countries, including all races. The results found that IQ scores in 14 countries have improved over time over the past half century. Among them, East Asia has the fastest growth, and the average IQ in East Asia is higher than that in Europe and the United States. The IQ of humans around the world is increasing over time. This discovery was called the &quot;Flynn effect&quot; by later scholars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flynn himself believes that there are no genetic differences in intelligence between races, and that intelligence is affected by environmental factors such as education, economy, and social culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, various countries have followed up and conducted studies, all of which have confirmed that the Flynn Effect does exist. However, by the end of the twentieth century, the Flynn Effect suddenly failed in developed countries. Statistics from the University of Vienna in Austria found that between 1962 and 1975, the growth rate of average IQ slowed down significantly; and between 1975 and 1991, it directly stagnated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, scholars thought this was a normal phenomenon: the average IQ in developed countries may have reached the upper limit and will no longer increase with the improvement of education and medical care; but the IQ in developing countries is still rising, and finally Countries will reach a level close to each other. However, as I continued to record, I found that the average IQ in developed countries has not stagnated, but has begun to regress! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, a joint survey by Finland and Denmark found that since the mid-1990s, the IQ test scores of recruits in the two countries have been declining at an average annual rate of 0.25%. In fact, as early as 2008, a British scholar discovered that the average score of 14-year-old British teenagers on thinking tests at that time was only equivalent to that of 12-year-old children in 1976. They believed that &quot;the intelligence of British young people has regressed greatly. It is almost certainly due to the popularity of televisions and computer games, as well as too frequent exams in schools.&quot; But this reason is far-fetched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The famous scientific journal &quot;Nature&quot; published a paper in 2016: A research team discovered a gene that is highly related to academic qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They first studied high-educated people and low-educated people, and found that there was a significant frequency difference in this genotype between the two groups. This genotype was then used to predict the future education level of the child, and the results were verified more accurately. Exactly how this genotype affects brain development remains unclear. However, another large study of more than 100,000 people in Iceland showed that this gene may affect the age of childbearing, thereby indirectly affecting the level of education. However, how it affects the age of childbearing is still unknown. It is very likely that Still an indirect effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, regardless of the mechanism of action, the research team discovered a serious problem:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This genotype has been eliminated from generation to generation among Icelanders. In other words, the educational level of the new generation may continue to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because people with a high level of education will delay the age of marriage and childbirth, the number of children will decrease, and they will even end up not getting married and having children, and they will eventually eliminate themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although analyzed on a ten-year basis, the influence of genes is still very small and almost negligible: the continuous decrease of this &quot;reading gene&quot; among Icelanders is speculated to cause the average IQ of Icelanders to drop every ten years. The annual decrease was 0.04. If all genes related to education conform to this rule, then this number is only 0.3 - which seems to be nothing compared to the improvement in IQ brought about by acquired environmental improvements such as education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, environmental improvements such as universal education have limits. The elimination of genes from generation to generation is eternal, so that the research team also warned: &quot;If this situation continues for centuries, the consequences will be very serious.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research in Iceland has not yet been carried out. It has been verified in other groups, but the problem suggested by the study is very general:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humans around the world, especially those in areas with higher education levels, are likely to face this problem - it seems that smart people are constantly Self-elimination. Of course, the concept of &quot;higher education level&quot; seems to require further analysis: is it longer years of education, higher academic qualifications, or both? Is it the values ​​instilled in them during their education that affect their desire to have children and their fertility rate? This requires further research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为A股做空制度打补丁，限售股融券制度为何引争议？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258955]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Amid the storm of public opinion, regulators patched the A-share short-selling system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission announced that it would gradually tighten securities lending and strategic investor placement share lending. Securities lending is currently the most important short-selling system in the A-share market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the newly listed company Jindi Shares (603270.SH) was the subject of intense public controversy. On the first day of listing in early September, Jindi shares were shorted by large amounts of securities lending. Later, after verification by the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the loaned shares came from a company&#39;s core employee management plan, commonly known as the &quot;strategic investment plan.&quot; Because they are held by insiders, these strategic investment shares are usually regarded as &quot;restricted shares&quot;, and their biggest feature is that they are not negotiable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Science and Technology Innovation Board was launched in 2019, allowing some restricted stocks to be included in the scope of securities lending, and will be fully implemented on the main board in 2023. The original intention of the policy is to &quot;bring down&quot; the price of new shares by expanding the source of securities and strengthening the power of short selling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, even if all the shares of the above-mentioned asset management plan were lent for short selling, Jindi shares were still issued and listed at a high price-earnings ratio of nearly 84 times. The closing price on the first day increased by more than 121 yuan compared with the issue price of 21 yuan. %. However, the stock price fell by nearly 30% in the following two weeks. Not only did securities lending fail to curb speculation in new stocks, it was also blamed by investors as the culprit of the decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar situations are not uncommon in new stocks. Southern Weekend reporters used financial statistics from Caihui. As of the last trading day in September, 66 of the 189 listed companies that had IPO&#39;d this year had lent their shares through strategic investment plans on the first day of issuance, changing &quot;restricted sales&quot; to &quot;tradable&quot;. &quot;. More than half of them have a price-to-earnings ratio of more than 50, which is a high-priced issue. Kweichow Moutai, which has the largest A-share market value, has a price-to-earnings ratio of only 32. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that the contradiction does not lie in the securities lending business itself, but in the fact that the scarce securities sources are concentrated in the hands of a small number of people, resulting in no securities to borrow in the market, especially for new stocks. Even more so, because most of the securities are locked in the restricted shares of the original shareholders. We originally wanted to use the securities sources of strategic investors to solve this problem, but this resulted in the restricted shares in the hands of major shareholders being circulated in disguise, and the policy &quot;fighted&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When short selling can only be participated by a small number of people, the supply and demand of securities sources are out of balance, and the inflated issuance price makes short selling a profit-free transaction, the price discovery function of A-share IPOs cannot be said to be effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/gmI5x7bPY8ZlBNBJIduTMJzG8XDVyCpzWSM2ZBBy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/gmI5x7bPY8ZlBNBJIduTMJzG8XDVyCpzWSM2ZBBy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254697&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The listing of Jindi Shares triggered a controversy over strategic investment in restricted stocks and securities lending. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Since it is a restricted stock, why do we need to let it circulate?&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to characterize the strategic investment and asset management plan of Jindi Shares is the main disagreement in the market. “No issues such as detours by relevant entities to reduce holdings or collusion in conveying benefits were found,” is the conclusion of the China Securities Regulatory Commission after verification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The essence of borrowing is to bet on the subsequent trend of stocks. Once the stock price falls, investors can buy the stock in the market at a cheaper price and return it to the lender. The difference between the borrowed stock and the actual purchase of the stock is the investor&#39;s profit. The cost depends on the interest paid to the lender, that is, the rate. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned securities lending of 4.7 million shares of Jindi Shares was divided into 7 financings, each with a term of 27 days, and the number of financings were 390,000 shares (financing rate 21.6%), 1.413 million shares (fee) 22.6%), 160,000 shares (23.6% fee), 2.477 million shares (24.6% fee), 20,000 shares (25.6% fee), 80,000 shares (27.6% fee), 160,000 shares (24.6% fee), 160,000 shares (27.6% fee), rate 28.1%). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yuan Yuwei, a senior hedge fund manager currently living in Paris, told Southern Weekend reporters that the annual rate of 28% is relatively high in the current market. “The price of each ticket changes every day and is not fixed. As a rule, the larger the ticket, the cheaper it is. The lowest rate can be around 5%, while small tickets are basically between 5% and 10%, and there are also 20%.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The executives of Jindi Shares are lending the restricted shares in the above-mentioned asset management plan to investors in exchange for interest income on the securities. The higher fee rate means that the market is flocking to the source of the stock. In other words, there are many investors who want to short the stock price of Jindi, and the stock price may be artificially high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Jindi Shares announcement, the number of strategic placements is 4,700,871 shares, accounting for 8.58% of the issued number. It is called Jindi Shares Asset Management Plan (including Plan 1 and Plan 2), with a sales restriction period of 12 months and a total amount of 102.3 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What surprised Yuan Yuwei was that the source of the stock&#39;s securities was the shareholding of core executives. According to the company law or securities law, these restricted shares, whether held directly or through an asset management plan, can only be sold after the lock-up period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is also the focus of controversy for Jindi Shares. In the stock forum, which has more than 480 pages and nearly 38,000 shareholder discussions, more than half are asking the same question: Is the refinancing of Jindi Shares reasonable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since it is a restricted stock, why let it circulate? The major shareholders even earn interest (rate) by doing so, which is strictly prohibited abroad because it violates the rights of the secondary market. Rights.&quot; Yuan Yuwei said that in the U.S. and European capital markets he is familiar with, restricted stocks mean that they are not tradable. Not only the buying and selling of stocks, but also the profit from restricted stocks are strictly restricted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is also the focus of this regulatory adjustment - &quot;Adjust and optimize the securities lending system&quot;, &quot;cancel the lending of special asset management plans established by executives and core employees of listed companies through participation in strategic placements, and moderately restrict other strategies Investors’ lending methods and proportions in the early stages of listing.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The price of new shares is artificially high, is it possible to lock in profits through securities lending? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for stocks to have similar operations to Jindi Shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, 66 of the 189 listed companies that have IPO&#39;d this year have lent shares through the Strategic Investment Plan on the first day of issuance, with a total amount of 5.932 billion. If ranked by the amount of securities lending, Jindi shares ranked fourth among 66 listed companies with 221 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to Jindi Shares, Surbana Security (688651.SH) suffered more than 90 million yuan in securities lending on its first day of listing on July 26. The company responded to investors by calling it &quot;a strategic Investors lend”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market’s doubts about Jindi shares are not unreasonable. Since there is a serious information asymmetry between the actual controllers of listed companies and ordinary investors, the restricted stock system can tie the interests of directors, supervisors and senior executives to those of listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Information asymmetry may lead to the problem of controllers running away in advance. That is, after the company goes public, the business situation deteriorates and the performance changes dramatically, and they throw the mess to the market. This phenomenon occurs in A The stock market is not uncommon.&quot; Huang Jianzhong, a former investment banker and associate professor of the Department of Finance at Shanghai Normal University Business School, explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He pointed out that if directors, supervisors and senior executives are allowed to cash out in advance, the above situation will become more serious. Therefore, under the current registration system, not only the interests of major shareholders are required to be bound, but also the sponsoring securities companies must also participate in the investment. The essence is to serve the interests of the bound listed companies and securities companies, and make the securities companies responsible for running away early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued relevant systems for the full implementation of the registration system, and the refinancing business was further liberalized. It not only broadens the scope of underlying securities and lenders, but also adjusts the original &quot;fixed term, fixed rate&quot; model to a market-based declaration method. Lenders and borrowers can independently negotiate the refinancing term, rate, extension or early settlement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The major shareholder of Jindi Co., Ltd. joined the scope of refinancing lending through its identity as a strategic investor. According to the latest data from the Securities Finance Corporation, there are currently 3,293 listed companies on the Shenzhen and Shanghai stock markets that have entered the two financing lists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If a listed company simply borrows securities, it cannot be considered to be reducing its holdings, because its operation process is for the listed company to give the securities to the securities and finance company, and the securities and finance company to the securities and finance company. The company will then be financed by the securities company to the investors who borrowed the securities. After two hands were passed in the middle, different securities will be mixed together, so it is difficult for the lender to reduce its holdings through manipulation.&quot; Professor of Peking University Law School and securities law expert Peng Bing explained to Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is also the focus of regulatory verification. It is guaranteed that Jindi shares and the final investors are not related transactions, excluding the possibility of cooperative arbitrage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Huang Jianzhong is more worried about is that the prices of new shares are generally artificially high, and major shareholders of listed companies cooperate with external institutions to carry out arbitrage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The stock price and price-to-earnings ratio of Jindi Shares are relatively high. If the issuance of new shares is accompanied by a refinancing policy, there may be problems in order to meet listing requirements and support high valuations, thereby packaging performance. Actual Controller They know the actual situation of the company best. If they lend stocks, it involves insider trading. If the performance changes after half a year, the hidden problem will be even greater.&quot; Huang Jianzhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Bing is also worried about this. &quot;Because major shareholders understand that the inflated stock price will eventually fall, they circulate restricted shares in the market to lock in the profits from the borrowing part in advance.&quot; At this time, the price of new shares increased. The higher the value, the more beneficial it is to major shareholders, because more people will borrow securities to short-sell after the listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the policy gap opened by refinancing does not make it possible for major shareholders to directly reduce their holdings, it may increase the motivation of major shareholders to falsify their performance, because even if the stock price of the restricted shares in their hands falls, the major shareholders You can still lock in some profits in advance by lending stocks through refinancing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Allow some people to short-sell first&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to Peng Bing’s observation, the average premium level in the US primary and secondary markets is between 10% and 20%, but the price of domestic new shares can double or triple on the first day. &quot;In the past, the phenomenon of A-shares flocking to speculate in new stocks was largely due to the stipulated price-earnings ratio of 23 times. Under the registration system, pricing was relaxed but the speculation was still hot, which is not normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A report from Huachuang Securities shows that as of September 24, the total turnover of the A-share market in 2023 was approximately 159.3 trillion yuan, and the sales volume of securities lending was 943.3 billion yuan, accounting for approximately 0.3% . From 2019 to 2022, China&#39;s securities lending balance/total market value increased from 0.02% to 0.11%. However, compared with the United States, the total securities lending balance is still significantly lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main means of checking and balancing stock price speculation in the United States is short selling. The A-share securities lending system also has the same effect, but the effect is not obvious. Part of the reason is that the supply of securities sources is insufficient, resulting in an imbalance of long and short forces. Only a few people to participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Commission income and interest on securities borrowing are the main sources of income from the securities lending business. The greater the customer&#39;s transaction volume and the higher the transaction frequency, the higher the securities firm&#39;s income. Brokerages are naturally more willing to lend their securities sources to private equity funds and quantitative funds that use high-frequency trading strategies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Customers who have opened the two-financing business can directly inquire about coupons from the brokerage firm where they opened an account, but not every customer can get the coupons. &quot;The first is to look at the transaction size, and the second is to look at the turnover rate.&quot; Feng Ruifeng, who works in the self-operated department of a large securities firm in Shanghai, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Feng Ruifeng’s securities firm as an example. In addition to opening a margin account, he is also required to hold more than 3.5 million yuan in trading funds before he can lock the securities, that is, the underlying securities source is locked in advance, and the rate is based on the securities source. The specific situation will be determined later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The greater the stock price fluctuation, the higher the fee rate. Because the policy allows securities lending to conduct T+0 transactions without overnight positions, for those stocks with large price fluctuations, the T+0 strategy is naturally The more room for profit there is, the more people will borrow bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Golden Emperor shares were lent to 35 individual investors and 89 private equity funds, with the number of institutions far outnumbering individuals. Feng Ruifeng judged that in addition to the 89 private equity funds, the other 35 individual investors are most likely hot money predators with funds comparable to small private equity funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon in A-shares to pay a high price but still not get the coupons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the U.S. stock market, as long as there are securities in the market, I can basically get them if I pay for them. I have almost never encountered a situation where I can&#39;t find a source of securities.&quot; Yuan Yuwei said frankly that if the brokerage firm where he works does not have a source of securities, , you can also find other brokers for lending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also differences between China and foreign countries in terms of the limit on the number of accounts to be opened. The two financing accounts are used for credit transactions, and there is a certain proportion of leverage. In order to control investors&#39; trading risks, current regulations stipulate that a single investor can only open a credit account with one securities company. Yuan Yuwei told Southern Weekend reporters that there is no restriction on this in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The threshold for retail investors to open margin trading and securities lending accounts is also quite high. According to the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Margin and Securities Lending Business of Securities Companies&quot; issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission in 2015, &quot;the average daily securities assets in the last 20 trading days are not low.&quot; &quot;500,000 yuan&quot; is the primary condition for opening a margin financing account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, data from China Securities Settlement shows that as of the end of August this year, the number of personal margin financing accounts opened in A-shares was 6.6126 million, and the number of individual investor accounts in A-shares during the same period was approximately 221 million. Those who can participate in short selling Retail investors only account for 2.99% of the total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the securities source pools of each securities firm are not the same, if the securities firm where the customer opens an account does not have the securities source he wants, and the customer cannot open an account with other securities firms for securities lending, this will objectively increase the risk. It makes it more difficult to borrow money. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Stock sources&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Why are they scarce? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At present, the source of securities for A-share securities lending transactions mainly comes from securities firms’ own stocks and refinancing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of securities firms’ own stocks is quite limited. &quot;This part of the securities source is basically for large customers, and customers who have deep business relationships with securities companies generally get priority.&quot; Feng Ruifeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Refinancing is currently the main source of securities by borrowing securities from other institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with overseas markets such as the United States, A-share securities sources lack two important sources - individuals and major shareholders of listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After U.S. stock investors sign an account opening contract with a securities firm, they will be prompted whether to activate the &quot;Stock Income Enhancement&quot; function. To simply understand, it is to lend the stocks in the personal account to short sellers in the market and obtain Interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most investors in the United States will sign this contract, which to a certain extent expands the source of securities borrowing and also enhances the liquidity of individual stocks.” A senior executive of a foreign hedge fund Chen Kaixuan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After lending to the market, although the stock will fluctuate in the short term, it will not affect the long-term trend, and investors can also earn additional interest income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more important source of securities comes from major shareholders, that is, restricted stocks. This is also the main source of bonds in the U.S. capital market, but it is subject to strict restrictions on holding reductions in the country and has not circulated in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former regulator told Southern Weekend reporters that if restricted shares are fully circulated, the problem of stock supply will be solved. After the market is fully valued, new shares will no longer be scarce, and the actual controllers of listed companies will not be able to pass The number of new shares of a company is artificially controlled to artificially increase the price. But on the other hand, it will also break the myth of A-share speculation, thereby affecting the premiums in the primary and secondary markets. &lt;br>;&lt;br>;“Only by maintaining a high premium for IPO listings can the new stock issuance market have a large amount of funds gathered in the ‘new’ place.” He said that full circulation obviously has a destructive effect on the price of new shares. Once the price of new shares in the secondary market is lowered, it will further reduce the price in the primary market and the value of the shares in the hands of early investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why are there no sales restrictions on U.S. stocks?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“In the United States, the main method of corporate governance is to decentralize and dismantle the control rights of listed companies. The more dispersed the ownership, the less investment in small and medium-sized enterprises. People&#39;s protection is often better. Rather than restricting the sale of the actual controller&#39;s shares.&quot; Zhang Wei, deputy dean of the City University of Singapore Law School, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. stock market also has a sales restriction system. The biggest difference from A-shares is that it is not a regulatory order, but the result of a game between brokers, exchanges and listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Kaixuan’s institution is a strategic investor in multiple listed companies. He explained that this system is called a lock-up period. Generally, the actual controller of a listed company and a securities firm sign a business agreement. There are restrictions on the sale of holdings between 90 and 180 days after the company goes public. The reason is also to prevent the original shareholders from immediately reducing their holdings and cashing out after listing, causing the stock price to fluctuate sharply. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SEC (U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission) does not require listed companies to sign a restriction agreement, but it has formulated regulations to explain which shares can be called restricted shares and exceptions to the restriction . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legal basis for the U.S. sales restriction system is called Act No. 144, which specifically stipulates the implementation details of the sales restriction and divides restricted stocks into two categories: restricted securities and control securities. , the former mainly involves private placement issuance, and the latter refers to the stocks in the hands of the actual controller of the company, and is also the target of the A-share sales restriction system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Controlled securities are the so-called &#39;old stocks&#39; in China. The SEC only restricts underwriters (brokerages) from short selling within 30 days after the IPO. They generally also subscribe for a part of new shares, but for investors through their own There are no restrictions on the lending of stocks by brokers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;144 actually stipulates which restricted stocks can be circulated in the market with exceptions. For example, the New York Stock Exchange and Nasdaq are 6 months. After the 6-month lock-up period, the number of shares that shareholders can sell every three months. It cannot exceed 1% of the issued shares of the same type or the average weekly trading volume within four weeks, whichever is greater, and must be reported to the China Securities Regulatory Commission in advance. There are special regulations for corporate executives, directors and other insiders who are aware of inside information. If they reduce their holdings by more than 500 shares or the transaction volume exceeds US$10,000, they must report to the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Wei explained that there are certain misunderstandings about Decree No. 144 in China. In the U.S. stock market, the focus of supervision and prevention is insider trading. Regulation 144 has designed a channel for the circulation of a series of restricted stocks. &quot;The so-called here The restriction does not prohibit resale, but requires registration in advance. What US law regulates is not the &#39;reduction&#39; of company controllers, but the transfer of stocks without (re)registration, requiring them to make public disclosures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for the actual controller to sell off immediately after listing. For example, in Alibaba&#39;s IPO, old shares accounted for nearly 62% of the total issuance. After the listing, the major shareholder Yahoo sold 120 million shares at once, accounting for 4.9% of the total equity at the time, cashing out more than 8 billion US dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also Peter G. Peterson, the founder of the well-known private equity fund Blackstone. He mentioned in his memoir &quot;Blackstone&#39;s Choice&quot; that brokerages did not consider the founder After the listing, he cashed out US$1.85 billion in one go and used the funds to found the Peterson Institute, a well-known think tank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, only companies that are truly popular in the market dare to confidently transfer a large number of old shares during the IPO stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Feng Ruifeng and Chen Kaixuan are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[把海底捞顶上热搜的“棉花娃娃”，养它带起一门10亿大生意]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258933]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, some netizens posted on the Internet platform saying &quot;Haidilao Is it discriminatory against people who bring cotton dolls?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The netizen pointed out in the post that when he and his friend each brought a cotton doll to Haidilao for dinner, they asked for the baby to sit in a baby chair in the store. The waiter looked incomprehensible. At the same time, during the meal, the two of them also experienced service that felt like they were being left out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This move has caused many netizens to wonder: What is this cotton doll? Is the brain circuit normal for asking a &quot;rag doll&quot; to sit in a baby seat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, cotton dolls have become a popular subculture among young people. Many young people do regard cotton dolls as &quot;babies&quot;. keep. What kind of existence is a cotton doll? Why is it so popular among young people? Does this subcultural market have a future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/ni51QRY50TXv8muNPN90kKaOc7DZwdJjwf7SagHV.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/ni51QRY50TXv8muNPN90kKaOc7DZwdJjwf7SagHV.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254709&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;From support object to “raised as a baby”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cotton doll refers to a body length ranging from 10 to 40 cm, with a main body made of cotton , dolls made of polyester fiber, etc. Cotton dolls were first used as a support item in the Korean entertainment industry. In 2015, a Korean brokerage company took the lead in cartoonizing the images of entertainment stars and making cotton dolls, which became a support item for fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Afterwards, cotton dolls became widely popular in the fan circle, and fans began to DIY cotton dolls based on their idols, which could be used as support items or as collections for fans. idol peripherals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After that, Cotton Dolls spread from the Korean entertainment industry to our country and developed completely new. Domestic cotton dolls not only exist as fan products, they have also formed an independent track - many &quot;baby mothers&quot; design unique cotton dolls themselves, start groups on the platform, and then let manufacturers make them after the group is successfully formed. After the goods are delivered, the &quot;baby mother&#39;s&quot; journey of raising a baby begins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Using the classification of baby circles, cotton dolls are divided into two categories: &quot;with attributes&quot; and &quot;without attributes&quot;. &quot;Having attributes&quot; means having prototypes, or celebrities, or some authorized film and television characters. They are more products of the fan economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;No attributes&quot;, that is, there is no prototype. The cotton doll is the original creation of the &quot;baby mother&quot; and can be &quot;customized&quot; according to her own preferences. The domestic cotton doll circle is dominated by cotton dolls with &quot;no attributes&quot;. Many young people &quot;raise cotton dolls as babies.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Cotton Beauty Doll&quot; Weibo Super Chat, established in 2019, now has more than 1.46 million &quot;baby mothers&quot; and more than 3.7 million posts. Read More than 28 billion times. The super chatty posts are mainly about cotton dolls with “no attributes”. According to the &quot;2021 Cotton Dolls Player Insight Report&quot; released by Weidian, the main trading platform of Cotton Dolls, in early 2022, among the army of Cotton Dolls players, the post-00s generation accounted for the highest proportion, reaching 43%, followed by the post-95s generation, which ranked second. Reaching 26%, the online transaction volume of Cotton Dolls exceeded the 1 billion yuan mark that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It can be said that cotton dolls have formed a spectacular subcultural phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/ZwnTwoNo1EJJ17WDBbQr3mWMky2SR5TfFDQSfCSe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/ZwnTwoNo1EJJ17WDBbQr3mWMky2SR5TfFDQSfCSe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254710&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;The healing feeling of “raising a baby”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generation Z users account for 70% of Cotton Doll players. Why are the younger generations obsessed with it? A cotton doll? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As far as those cotton dolls with &quot;attributes&quot; are concerned, they are mainly an extension of the rice circle culture. For example, cotton dolls based on idols are like the incarnation of idols, which can satisfy fans&#39; emotional projection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But for those DIY, &quot;attributeless&quot; cotton dolls, the fun lies in the emotional healing of &quot;raising as a baby&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although those DIY cotton dolls have different facial features and shapes, they have one strong thing in common, they are very cute. &quot;Cute&quot; is mainly used to express those people, things and things that can inspire people&#39;s extremely strong and profound emotions, including liking, admiration, being fascinated by them, persistence, excitement, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, everyone has the love of &quot;cute&quot;. Austrian zoologist Konrad Lorenz put forward the idea of ​​&quot;larval retention&quot;. He pointed out that it is human nature to like anything with larval characteristics, and these cute animals have big eyes, big heads, short noses, etc. Characteristics, which can also explain why young children, kittens, and puppies are more likely to arouse people&#39;s affection. In the same way, cotton dolls that retain the characteristics of juveniles are very kawaii, full of cuteness, and enchanting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, &quot;cute&quot; has an emotional healing function. From a psychological perspective, a series of things that are non-aggressive, peaceful and non-controversial, can soothe the soul and give people a continuous and long-lasting sense of comfort, can help people resolve sentimental emotions such as loneliness and depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The process of &quot;raising&quot; cotton dolls as babies by the young Generation Z is like the emotional investment of the little prince in the rose in &quot;The Little Prince&quot;. The little prince put up a screen for the rose, covered it with a glass cover, got rid of the caterpillars, and listened to her complaints. He devoted time, emotion and energy; the same goes for every young man who raises cotton dolls, buying clothes and clothes for his own dolls. I changed clothes, confided my feelings to him, took him to travel everywhere, took him to Haidilao to celebrate his birthday...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Like a rose to the little prince It is unique, and every cotton doll that receives the emotional investment of the &quot;baby mother&quot; is also unique to the &quot;baby mother&quot;. Therefore, it is normal to not understand the young people who brought cotton dolls to eat Haidilao in the news, but there is no need to rush to ridicule and deny them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is also worth mentioning that unlike many subculture products whose prices remain high, the prices of cotton dolls are often very affordable. Some &quot;non-attributed&quot; cotton dolls cost between tens of yuan and a hundred yuan, and baby clothes will be more expensive, but &quot;baby mothers&quot; can also buy their own fabrics and DIY, which is the fun of many &quot;baby mothers&quot;. The popular healing system has contributed to the further popularity of cotton dolls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/EUBdRoG12f2usOU3EaPTW5rC8JcQQXcw191ZHCjB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/EUBdRoG12f2usOU3EaPTW5rC8JcQQXcw191ZHCjB.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254711&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Specialization is the way out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared to industries such as blind boxes and figures, the market space for cotton dolls has yet to be Dig further. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The current cotton doll track is mainly divided into two types: &quot;with attributes&quot; and &quot;without attributes&quot;. The new trend in the &quot;attributed&quot; track is that more and more regular troops are joining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, many &quot;attributed&quot; cotton dolls were privately created &quot;secondary creations&quot; by fans, wandering on the boundary of infringement, such as not directly saying that they were infringement. A certain star or an image in a play is the prototype, but the fan base knows that it is the prototype. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, many film and television producers take the initiative to use cotton dolls as part of their derivatives, officially producing cotton dolls with &quot;attributes&quot; for sale to the public. Not only new IPs have launched Cotton Dolls, such as the previous &quot;Shanhe Ling&quot;, &quot;You Fei&quot;, &quot;Canglan Jue&quot;, &quot;Menghualu&quot;, &quot;Hunting Crime Illustrated Book&quot;, etc., some old IPs have also come to share the pie, such as &quot;The Legend of Zhen Huan&quot; &quot;&quot;Pleasant Goat and Big Big Wolf&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the emerging market of cotton dolls, this kind of formalization is necessary. It can not only expand the circle, but also help to mature the cotton doll industry chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, &quot;attributeless&quot; cotton dolls are still the mainstream, and their business model is mainly &quot;DIY design + spontaneous group building + small amount of customization&quot;, which is essentially Small workshop model. The top priority of this model is to improve the specialization of every link in the cotton doll industry chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Small workshop does not mean shoddy manufacturing and petty fuss. For cotton dolls that emphasize individuality, &quot;small workshop&quot; is an integral part of it. kind of ecology. However, cotton dolls can be &quot;niche&quot;, but the design of cotton dolls, the production of dolls, and the production of baby clothes should all be more professional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past, many cotton dolls made in a group style were of poor quality, rough details, and incorrect goods, etc. This would discourage &quot;baby mothers&quot; enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;my country is the largest toy producer in the world, and its toy production capacity goes without saying. It is hoped that some large toy manufacturers can intervene in the cotton doll market and provide professional, standardized and systematic cotton doll customization services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The toy market is already a red ocean of competition. Cotton dolls may be a new blue ocean, it depends on who can seize the opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国籍女子在美酒驾致人死亡：死者在国内的父母如何伸张正义？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258921]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news that &quot;a Chinese woman died while driving drunk and speeding in the United States&quot; has attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jimu News, this incident occurred in Bellevue, Washington, USA. The woman involved and the man killed are both Chinese citizens. After the incident, the woman involved refused to provide any information related to the deceased to the local police in the United States. She was also charged with vehicular homicide. Friends of the deceased told reporters that the woman involved concealed the incident from them, resulting in them not knowing that the deceased had been killed for many days. Not only that, the woman involved was suspected to have returned to the country before the US police issued an arrest warrant on October 9. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on U.S. media reports, local court indictments, and information released by the deceased’s former friends in the United States, a timeline of this case can be established. At 3:45 a.m. on September 30, the woman in question drove a Porsche 911 drunk and hit a concrete guardrail in Bellevue at a speed of 90 miles (144.84 kilometers per hour). The vehicle rolled over and was damaged. The man in the passenger seat died at the scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the police and firefighters arrived at the scene at 4:10 a.m., the woman involved refused to disclose any information about the deceased, and there was a &quot;strong smell of alcohol in her breath and speech.&quot; Since the woman involved also suffered minor injuries, she first went to the hospital for treatment and took an alcohol blood test three hours later. The police investigated the case in the following days. The local court issued an indictment on October 6, accusing the woman of &quot;driving to kill&quot;, and the police also issued an arrest warrant on October 9. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the deceased’s former friends, they discovered on October 13 that the woman in question had left Seattle before the U.S. police issued an arrest warrant and was suspected of having returned to China. WeChat chat records show that the woman involved first said, &quot;Go to the police station and ask, I can&#39;t contact him&quot; and &quot;Are you telling the truth?&quot;, and then said, &quot;It&#39;s really okay, he is safe now&quot;; finally After the death was confirmed, he said, &quot;His family should know the truth,&quot; &quot;I want to return to China to find his parents,&quot; and &quot;I was seriously injured and need to return to China to rest.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The facts that can be determined in the entire case are: the woman involved was drunk and speeding, causing the death of the man in the passenger seat; the woman involved concealed the death information of the deceased after the incident; the woman involved did not arrive at the scene He has lost contact with the case and is suspected to have returned to China. At the same time, he has deleted all the content on social media. Facts that are still unclear in the case include: what is the relationship between the deceased and the woman involved; whether the deceased knew about the woman&#39;s drunk driving in advance; whether the deceased himself was drunk, and how did he get into the car? This will all affect the distribution of accident liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the indictment in the King County Superior Court of Washington State, the woman involved needs to pay a bail of up to 2 million US dollars, and her passport should be confiscated. If the woman in question has indeed returned to the country, then she should have taken advantage of the gap in the police investigation to return to the country with her passport before the arrest warrant was issued. Without paying bail, there was a time lag with the police and an information gap with the deceased&#39;s friends. , completed the &quot;run away with a bucket&quot; in a short period of time, which is also consistent with the information spread online that the woman involved &quot;continues to report that she is safe on social media.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, the WeChat conversations between the woman involved and the deceased’s friend were also contradictory. She said, &quot;I want to go back to China to find his parents,&quot; and in a follow-up conversation, &quot;If you have the ability, you can go back to China and tell his parents this in person, or you can give his parents my contact information. This is the best way.&quot; &quot;In this case. Judging from this, the woman involved should not have taken the initiative to contact the parents and friends of the deceased in the days after the incident. Then, the statements of &quot;he was seriously injured&quot;, &quot;needs to return to China to rest&quot;, and &quot;find the parents of the deceased&quot; are probably untenable. It is inevitable that people will suspect that they are to cooperate with the real purpose of &quot;buying time to avoid arrest and return to China as soon as possible to protect themselves&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the woman did violated moral standards and violated the laws of both China and the United States. Drunk driving requires criminal liability. The criminal code of Washington State shows that &quot;driving to kill&quot; is a Class A felony, with the maximum penalty being life imprisonment and a fine of $80,000; Article 133 of the &quot;Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;violation of traffic and transportation management regulations, resulting in a major If an accident causes serious injury or death to a person or causes heavy losses to public or private property, he shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years or criminal detention.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not the first case of &quot;committing crimes in the United States and then escaping back to the country.&quot; In the 2015 &quot;Case of Murder of a Chinese Girl Studying in the United States&quot;, the suspect fled back to the country right after the incident, but the Chinese and American police brought the suspect to justice in accordance with the &quot;China-U.S. Criminal Judicial Assistance Agreement.&quot; The circumstances of this case are different. Judging from the current situation, even if the parents of the deceased initiate a criminal private prosecution in China, they will still face a series of difficulties in evidence collection procedures, case determination, and accident liability division. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general, the woman involved refused to provide any information about the deceased to the police after the incident and did not make efforts to deal with the aftermath, which was unkind; she concealed information about the deceased’s death from the circle of relatives and friends of the deceased, and even created “ &quot;It&#39;s very safe&quot; and pretending not to know is unjust; it is illegal to create a time difference and information gap through technology and use it to fly back to the country to evade charges. No matter from the perspective of emotion, reason, or law, the woman involved could get away with it so easily, which undermines fairness and justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the parents of the deceased have the right to continue criminal private prosecution, strive to continue to seek public relief under the framework of the &quot;China-US Criminal Judicial Assistance Agreement&quot;, and give justice to the deceased. It is also necessary for the public sector to take action to pursue the legal responsibility of the woman involved based on the personal principle, so as to prevent the perpetrators from going unpunished and maintain social fairness and justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>