<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《坠楼死亡的剖析》： 一部重在“关系”的电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/o9fOt7ZSGsFEBUHXLJ0AP8ZJyY9J2ZooYQNktZA0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/o9fOt7ZSGsFEBUHXLJ0AP8ZJyY9J2 ZooYQNktZA0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Palme d&#39;Or award-winning work &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; at the 2023 Cannes Film Festival is like a juggler throwing three balls at the same time. The execution is dazzling. It is both a strong plot thriller about an unsolved case and a family film about a broken marriage. In terms of scene presentation, it is also a legal drama in which all dramatic conflicts occur in the courtroom. Director Justine Trier is indispensable for being able to accomplish these three missions at the same time. The Cannes jury awarded her the grand prize undoubtedly in recognition of these visible advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the surface text, &quot;Analysis of Death from Falling from a Building&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Falling from a Building&quot;&lt;/span>; ) also hides some more complex and even theoretical intellectual issues. How can we distinguish between truth and falsehood when we cannot grasp the whole story? When truth and narrative come into conflict, can we persist in our pursuit of the former, or will we be conquered by the emotional power of the latter? From &quot;Battle of Solferreno&quot; to &quot;Sibyl&quot;, director Trier has been obsessed with exploring the complex relationship between text and reality. However, in &quot;Falling&quot;, which seems to be a straightforward commercial genre film, she has pushed her reflection on &quot;narration&quot; to the extreme. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A famous bisexual female writer who is stuck in the quagmire of an unhappy marriage is seizing a rare opportunity to be interviewed by a girl from the literature department, and flirting with her ambiguously while drinking. But noisy music was playing upstairs at this moment: her husband - a man who had just resigned from his university teaching position and tried to write full-time like his wife - was aware of his wife&#39;s schedule and deliberately did not want his wife&#39;s (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Interview and Flirtation&lt;/span>;) plan succeeded. The interview had to be interrupted, and the girl and the son of the family left one after another to avoid the embarrassing and noisy situation. When the visually impaired son came home from a walk, the guide dog that led him first discovered the shocking fact: the music was still playing, the sun was still shining in the Alpine sky, but the child&#39;s father had blood all over his head. He fell into the snow and died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it suicide, accident or homicide? The medical examiner could not find sufficient evidence to prove or rule out any of these possibilities, so the only person present at the time of the incident, the deceased&#39;s wife Sandra, was accused of being a suspect and had to be investigated. In the next two hours of this film, we have to work with the judge, lawyers, jury and son Daniel who was unable to witness the scene to find the truth through our own eyes and clues provided by all parties. In this process, the relationship between Sandra and her husband Samuel will be cut into pieces and dismantled by a cold scalpel like the latter&#39;s corpse, and will face the most severe inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the overall setting, we can see the organizational structure of the entire film. This is an intricate network intertwined by various relationships. Everyone is trying to determine their position in the relationship with others, but they are often lost in the flow and change of relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WuQb9pbuocxqaNObwipCMpp2z5OhCYABfe8cm7ws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;705&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WuQb9pbuocxqaNObwipCMpp2z5OhCYABfe8cm7ws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;where The most eye-catching thing is naturally the relationship between Sandra and Samuel. Through the few words and fragments of evidence in the court, we can piece together some aspects of this relationship before Samuel&#39;s death: it was due to the uneven shouldering of family responsibilities between the two parties, the imbalance in the sense of worldly success, and the social and cultural differences between the two parties. Differences in background, different emotional appeals, and fundamental differences in personality and attitude towards life, gradually fell apart. We seem to be watching another &quot;Marriage Story&quot; or &quot;The Kramers&quot;. Neither party has made an unforgivable mistake. Everyone has their own reasons and difficulties. Even so, the two people who still love each other will still move forward. Resent and hurt each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But beneath the surface, the film also constructs a more subtle relationship: the relationship between the audience and the heroine. The legal drama format, which occupies most of the film, firmly places the audience in the position of the jury in the court. Through the guidance of facts, reasoning and emotions, we pour empathy into one of the prosecution and defense parties. And together they share the same hatred against the other party. As the truth continues to be revealed and lies continue to be exposed, our trust relationship with all parties is also undergoing subtle adjustments: at first, we will instinctively resent the inference of Sandra&#39;s guilt and the prosecutor&#39;s lawyer who questioned her; As the trial progresses, we discover that Sandra is not as honest as we first thought. As a result, the emotional balance shifts slightly: every word Sandra says from now on will be more questioned in our hearts. At the same time, every difficulty issued by the prosecutor, even including the various questions they raised before, It also makes more sense in our hindsight. The strategic game between the prosecution and the defense in the film is certainly exciting, but the psychological game between the director and the audience, based on the latter&#39;s emotional identification with the heroine, is closer to the focus of the entire film and allows the film to retain suspense. The secret to keeping it until the very last moment—and even until after the film is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At its true core, the film sets up ambiguous and complex relationships between texts of different materials. The entire film adopts a realistic audio-visual and narrative strategy, but whenever the prosecution and defense raise speculations and memories that cannot be verified by facts during the trial, the camera will start from the perspective of son Daniel sitting in the auditorium. It presents a &quot;psychological image&quot; with a highly subjective fantasy color. Sometimes it is a picture of the father committing suicide, and sometimes it is a picture of the mother punching the father in a rage. As these images accumulate, they finally become &quot;reality&quot; near the end of the film: Danielle testifies in person, reciting a suicidal monologue from his father&#39;s lifetime on the witness stand. However, the father&#39;s voice never appears in the flashback sequence shot by the director, and the son&#39;s narration also adds a bit of ambiguity that is indistinguishable from truth to falsehood because of this carefully placed misplaced detail. We can&#39;t help but wonder: Is this monologue his son&#39;s true memory, or is it a narrative he made up to the judge in order to save a family that is at risk of complete collapse? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film does not reveal the answer to us until the end. But the truth may not be very important. The judge was obviously emotionally moved by Daniel&#39;s words, and the situation was reversed. Sandra was acquitted, and Daniel also re-accepted this mother whom he might not trust, but loved enough. The most intriguing aspect of &quot;Falling&quot; is precisely related to its complex emotions towards &quot;narration&quot; itself: on the one hand, it retains ontological doubts about all narratives, but on the other hand, it unconditionally believes The emotional animal nature of human beings, thereby believing in the infinite power of narrative itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about &quot;narration&quot; confirms the significance of this film being able to exist independently from similar marriage stories; as for the truth of the entire case, it may only be grasped by that language that does not understand the language but is insightful. In the hearts of Border Collie Guide Dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 23:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当家中老人失能失智：关切老龄化引发的三大社会问题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259216]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued the &quot;About Organizing and Carrying out Central Financial Support for the Central Financial Support for the Disabled Elderly People with Economic Difficulties&quot; &quot;Notice on Care Services&quot; stipulates that the recipients of assistance are tentatively designated as elderly people who have been included in the scope of minimum living security, have been assessed as completely disabled, and have voluntarily moved into a nursing home. The amount of assistance is the difference between the actual charges for staying in a nursing home after deducting the minimum living security allowance and two subsidies for persons with disabilities that the elderly have received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from a few years ago, there are more than 40 million disabled or semi-disabled elderly people in China, many of whom are also suffering from dementia, such as Alzheimer&#39;s disease. As the population ages, this number will only continue to increase. Data from the Ministry of Civil Affairs shows that as of the end of 2022, there were 280.04 million elderly people aged 60 and over in the country, accounting for 19.8%; among them, there were 209.78 million elderly people aged 65 and over, accounting for 14.9%, a year-on-year increase of 0.9 and 0.7 percentage points respectively. Increases of 12.68 million and 9.22 million. Due to China&#39;s sluggish fertility rate, the number of newborns has almost halved in six years, and the rate of social aging is quite fast. This has led to many social problems that require our serious concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the age and physical and mental conditions of the elderly, we can sort out the specific problems they face according to the timeline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, when the elderly are still &quot;younger elderly&quot;, their physical condition is generally better, and their ability to live, work and study has not significantly declined; there are also a few elderly people who have always been in good health and mentality. These two types of elderly people do not need or need the care of young adults for the time being and do not pose any social problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as we get older, our physical functions and mental abilities will continue to weaken. A considerable number of elderly people will be driven by the instinct of seeking life and hating death, and they will turn to health regimens that claim to help health and longevity. They are particularly keen on health care products and health care equipment. It is not uncommon for people who used to be very frugal and spend two cents of a penny to suddenly turn into buying and selling or even spend a lot of money; there are also a considerable number of elderly people who long for the warmth and affection of family. Although I have no children or my children are not around, I feel extremely lonely. Under the meticulous care and emotional attack of the sales staff, it is very refreshing to spend money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;elderly economy&quot; is essentially a careful hunt for the elderly and &quot;defrauds the elderly economy.&quot; The public prosecutor and the law should show their teeth and carry out a powerful crackdown to protect the legitimate rights and interests of the elderly. Children should also care about their parents&#39; mental and emotional needs, make more phone calls and spend more time with them; if possible, try to live with their parents so that parents can enjoy the rewards of raising children in their later years, so as to avoid the situation of &quot;the children want to be raised but the parents don&#39;t wait&quot; regret. In this regard, some young people may make reasonable remarks, such as &quot;small family&quot;, &quot;independent space&quot; and &quot;border&quot;. If you have never accepted or asked for a large amount of financial support from your parents as an adult, and you have repaid your parents for their upbringing financially and emotionally, you may have the confidence to say this. But it is unjustifiable if you receive a large amount of financial support from your parents as an adult and then refuse to fulfill reciprocal responsibilities. According to natural law and customary law, parents have the right to assert their own rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, now is the era of smartphones and mobile Internet, and many public transportation services, government services, and convenience services have become online and digital. A considerable number of elderly people have been left far behind in this era and have become &quot;digitally disabled groups&quot;. They do not use mobile phones or use simple-function elderly machines, cannot understand how to use those apps, and do not know how to make electronic payments. On the one hand, the government and enterprises should reserve non-digital service channels for the elderly and provide them with guidance in a conspicuous way; on the other hand, the platform should demonstrate social responsibility and launch an &quot;aging-friendly&quot; APP version to make the operation quick, simple and convenient. Older people get started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children should have patience and love for their digitally disabled parents, teach them to use the apps they need, or provide regular guidance and help, just like your parents patiently taught you ancient poems over and over again when you were a child. Like arithmetic, this is about feedback and feedback. In addition, parents should be alert to prevent telecommunications and network fraud, and should &quot;not give any personal information, do not give money, and do not cooperate with the other party in any operation.&quot; They should inform themselves when they have questions or before making major financial decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, as body functions and organs continue to age, the vast majority of the elderly will experience a stage of disability, semi-disability or even dementia. The resulting need for medical care will have a negative impact on the lives of their children. constitute a great challenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national elderly care strategy is &quot;9073&quot;, that is, 90% of the elderly are provided with home care, 7% are provided with community care, and 3% are provided with institutional care. A 2023 Beijing survey found that more than 99% of the elderly in Beijing choose home care, while less than 1% choose institutional care. Therefore, except for some completely disabled elderly people who are supported by the government, the vast majority of disabled elderly people still rely on their children to take care of them. Children generally have to contribute both money and effort, and the most important part is contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disabled elderly people can only eat three meals a day in bed or in a wheelchair. If they lose the function of their hands or have dementia, they need to be fed, just like parents feeding themselves when they are one or two years old, and they must also help with defecation. , wipe your body or take a bath regularly; use a wheelchair to push outdoors on sunny days, so that the disabled elderly can enjoy the sunshine and breeze, feel happy and refresh their spirits; lying in bed for a long time, you must turn over regularly, otherwise the blood circulation will not be smooth, which will lead to vascular embolism or bedsores. ; If dementia is superimposed, it will be even more troublesome. Some elderly people will have delusions, become violent, and even smear feces all over the house, making it difficult to clean up. The odor will also attract complaints from neighbors... Disability and dementia For the elderly, it is generally impossible to hire a nanny to take care of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, as the mainstay of the family, you are in middle age, you have seniors and juniors, you have unlimited responsibilities on your shoulders, everyone relies on you and you have no one to rely on, this kind of pressure It&#39;s unprecedented. If you add a mid-life workplace crisis, it will be even more stressful. Therefore, as aging intensifies, this social problem will become more serious. But it is obviously difficult to solve this problem with a &quot;socialized&quot; system solution that transfers costs to society, unless robots are smart enough to replace human care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aging, two kinds of disability, and three major problems are all social problems that require serious consideration and treatment by the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[探访“山地之王”：高仙芝的高原足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259129]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 20:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/23/9f8Kpn5eNv9GuiP2GOXSS097RDqjQpFK5sNsyUlf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/9f8Kpn5eNv9GuiP2GOXSS097RDqjQp FK5sNsyUlf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254965&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aerial view of the Pamir Mountains&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-August, I set off from Kashgar and cycled along the Karakoram Highway to Pakistan-occupied Kashmir. Since my country’s Khunjerab Port does not allow cycling to pass customs, I need to take a transit bus in Taxkorgan County, check the bicycle as luggage, and continue riding after arriving at Khunjerab National Park on the Pakistani side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Khunjerab Pass is 4,783 meters above sea level. On one side of the border with my country is the wide-open and wide-open valley terrain of the eastern Pamir Plateau. The climate is arid and the vegetation is sparse. It is rare to see a tree at the foot of the mountain. Surrounded by a courtyard wall - it is a family of Tajik herders; entering Pakistan, it quickly transforms into a valley terrain with surging rapids - this is a canyon cut by the Hunza River in the southeastern part of the Pamir Plateau. It collided left and right in the mountain knot formed by the intersection of the Karakoram Mountains, Himalayas and Hindu Kush Mountains, and fell rapidly. From the border line of Khunjerab Pass to the entrance of Khunjerab National Park where Pakistan conducts border inspection, it is a short 40-kilometer journey, and the altitude drops by about one thousand meters; from the border inspection to Sost, the Pakistani port ), a distance of about 38 kilometers, and the altitude has dropped by nearly a thousand meters - which is naturally great news for cyclists. By the time I rode all the way downhill to the Ganish village in the eastern part of the Hunza Valley, the altitude had dropped to about 2,400 meters, which was only half of the Khunjerab Pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far south of Ganish, I saw a pedestrian rope bridge flying north and south over the raging Hunza River, and a warm current suddenly surged in my heart - more than 1,200 years ago , Gao Xianzhi, a famous general in the Tang Dynasty, used a similar rope bridge in the lower reaches of this river to block the way of the fierce enemy troops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/xWctTRMmRc2MxiLpdWwLNYWZpCV4uwzyTRNSw53W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/xWctTRMmRc2MxiLpdWwLNYWZpCV4uwzyTRNSw53W.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A pedestrian rope bridge over the Hunza River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;Kashmir&#39;s &quot;Great Game&quot;: Smoke and dust flying to the west of Jinshan Mountain&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Gao Xianzhi rushed to the rope bridge, the prospect of the expeditionary force he commanded was not good: facing a surrendering enemy The fortified city, as well as a large number of enemy reinforcements coming all the way, while our own army has been on the march for more than three months, traveled more than 1,500 kilometers, and faced the extremely harsh geological and climatic conditions in Congling (&lt;em>; After continuous fighting in the wind and snow, the lone expeditionary force advanced deeply into the enemy&#39;s territory. They did not understand the language, had no siege equipment, lacked logistical supplies, and could not get reinforcements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a difficult situation may have been encountered by Alexander the Great during his legendary expedition to Asia and Europe. However, Alexander stationed his troops to the west of Congling and never crossed over. Gao Xianzhi&#39;s mission was precisely to cross the Congling to regain the lost territory. What&#39;s more, his military strength, animal power and material resources were far less than Alexander&#39;s expeditionary force. This may be why Gao Xianzhi later He was called the &quot;King of the Mountains&quot; by one of his rivals, Sahib jibal al-Sin. Sahib is the Turkic word for &quot;master&quot; , jibal is &quot;mountain&quot; in Arabic, and al-Sin is of China)&lt;/span>; reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi is a descendant of the Goguryeo royal family. His ancestors were the Fuyu people who emerged in the Hunjiang River Basin and the middle reaches of the Yalu River in Northeast China. &quot;Gao was their surname&quot; and established the Goguryeo regime during the Western Han Dynasty, which lasted seven hundred years. For a long time, it once occupied Liaodong to the southwest, and then crossed the Yalu River to the southeast and entered the Korean Peninsula. After the Goguryeo regime perished under the military attacks of the Sui and Tang dynasties, the Tang Dynasty moved the defeated Gao royal family to the Central Plains and Longyou. Gao Xianzhi followed his father Gao Sheji into the army and became a border guard in the Tang Dynasty. He grew up in the Hexi Corridor. He grew up in a military camp, and when he was a boy, he was transferred to the Anxi Protectorate with his father, which is today&#39;s southern Xinjiang, Pamir Plateau and Central Asia Hezhong region. He rose to prominence in his twenties and was promoted to general, the same level as his father. Later, he was further recognized by the leader of the Qiang people and the governor of Anxi, Meng Lingjin, and was promoted to deputy governor of Anxi and commander of the four towns. The horse envoy is equivalent to Fumeng Lingjin&#39;s deputy and the military chief of the entire southern Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sixth year of Tianbao&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (747 AD)&lt;/span>;, Gao Xianzhi received an edict from Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, appointing him In order to serve as a military envoy, I made my fourth expedition to Congling after the failure of my three predecessors to recapture Xiaobolu - the Pakistani-controlled Kashmir where I rode to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fKtCWOawnzDSfDbU6a8InBuv60cCYamb90OjqJHx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fKtCWOawnzDSfDbU6a8InBuv60cCYamb90OjqJHx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254967&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cycling in Hunza, Pakistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (Gilgit-Baltistan) is divided into two parts, Gilgit and Baltistan. The origin of the division can be traced back to the Greater and Lesser Bulu. The original name of this place was Boloristan, which means &quot;mountain country&quot;, where &quot;stan&quot; means &quot;country&quot; in Turkic language. Today, there are five &quot;stan&quot; countries in Central Asia, including Kazakhstan, and Pakistan in South Asia; Bolor means plateau and mountainous area - this place name is famous in the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty and is translated as &quot;Bolu&quot;. It is the junction area of ​​the four kingdoms of Tang, Tubo, Tianzhu and Dashi, and is divided into the western and western regions. Xiao Bolu in the Sa Valley and Big Bolu in the upper reaches of the Indus River in the east - the goal of Gao Xianzhi&#39;s expedition was Xiao Bolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Big and Little Bolu were originally one country, and their territory included most of today&#39;s Pakistan-controlled Kashmir and the northern part of Indian-controlled Kashmir. It was a must-win place for Tubo in its Western Region strategy. At the beginning of the seventh century, Tubo annexed the ancient Shangshung Kingdom in the Ali region and unified the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. From then on, it began to implement its Western Region strategy based on the Ali region, and launched a nearly two-year-long war with the Tang Dynasty around Bolu, that is, the Kashmir region. The &quot;Great Game&quot; between Tang and Tibet for centuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/BPoP6sb1xhgMaISzFXsrbGNTYIjafKo87zl8Qs4z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/BPoP6sb1xhgMaISzFXsrbGNTYIjafKo87zl8Qs4z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hunza Valley&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tubo is backed by the Himalayas. It borders the Tang Dynasty in three directions: north, east and south. Why do we have to choose Kashmir to decide the outcome? Tubo initially launched the main attack on Datang on the Hehuang and Jiannan fronts, but failed to open up the situation. After occupying the Ngari region, Tibet tried to seize southern Xinjiang via the northern Qiangtang Prairie and across the Altyn Mountains. After being blocked again, they had to turn to expand northwest along the Shiquan River/Indus River Basin, intending to bypass the Himalayas and enter through the Ladakh region. Kashmir eventually joined forces with the Western Turks in the north to deal with the Tang Dynasty. In short, Tubo was like a lion trapped on a high platform. It was attacked head-on by the Tang army in Qinghai, Sichuan, Yunnan and Xinjiang. It was unable to get down to the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. In the end, it had to choose to go down the mountain from Kashmir, where there was no Tang army, and take a detour. Congling attacked the western border of Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Belu Kingdom, located on this expansion route, became a &quot;soft persimmon&quot; that Tibet fought against with all its strength, and soon split into two countries: the Belu Homeland became a Tubo vassal state, known as &quot; The Great Burud&quot; was roughly located in today&#39;s Baltistan area; another royal family moved westward to the Hunza Valley and established the &quot;Little Burud&quot;, which was roughly located in today&#39;s Gilgit area, relying on the Hunza River and Gilgit The Te River&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(called Suyi River in ancient times)&lt;/span>; and the Indus River line up with deep valleys and natural chasms to resist the Tibetan invasion. King Xiao Bolu did not hesitate to send an envoy to ask for help from the Tang Dynasty, saying that Bolu was the gateway to the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty. If it fell, all the countries in the Western Regions would fall to Tubo, and the Western Regions would no longer be controlled by the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Bo Lu, Ximen of the Tang Dynasty. If he loses it, all the Western countries will fall to Tubo)&lt;/span>;, and was finally canonized by Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty and became the Tang Dynasty Subject to the country. In the tenth year of Kaiyuan (722 AD), the Beiting Protectorate of the Tang Army sent 4,000 cavalry reinforcements to Xiaobolu to attack Xiaobolu. He repelled the attack of the Tibetan army and won nearly twenty years of peace for Xiaobolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 740 AD, Tubo instigated the Tuqishi Khanate in the northern grasslands to rebel against the Tang Dynasty through marriage, and contained the main force of the Tang army in the Western Regions in the northern Xinjiang. On this occasion, he proposed to Xiao Bolu to &quot;borrow a road&quot; and build a rope bridge on the Suyi River. The Tubo army, which successfully crossed the natural barrier of the Suyi River, immediately turned against the foreigners and occupied Xiaobolu. King Su Feng of Xiaobolu was forced to marry the Tibetan princess, and together with more than 20 surrounding small countries, they rebelled against Tang and surrendered to Tibet. The Tibetan army was able to occupy the entire Bolu and get a glimpse of Congling: they captured Lianyun Fort, the fortress of the Tang army guarding the Wakhan Valley, the main road to Congling, opening the way to the north to Central Asia to make friends with the Turks, and cutting off the capital of Anxi. The road from Hufu to the Zhaowu Kingdoms in the Hezhong region also formed a condescending military advantage over the four Anxi towns of the Tang Dynasty located in the Tarim Basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the unfavorable situation that a gap was opened in the defense line of the Western Region, the Anxi Protectorate had to concentrate all its efforts in order to regain Bolu and block the &quot;downhill&quot; channel of Tubo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/bZT8JG7NjiRBsR7Doyj7Jnnki6xEICEQfr28g9Y1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/bZT8JG7NjiRBsR7Doyj7Jnnki6xEICEQfr28g9Y1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The barren and pure river valley in Hunza region&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Recovering the Wakhan Valley: The captives should be frightened after hearing this&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the most convenient way to go from China&#39;s Pamir Plateau to Pakistan-occupied Kashmir is to go south along the Hunza Valley, or That is to say, follow the Karakoram Highway, which was historically one of the important passages along the southern route of the Silk Road to South Asia. It’s just that in ancient times, caravans used to go through the Mingtie Gaidaban, and when China and Pakistan planned and built the Karakoram Highway in the 1960s, in order to avoid the military threat of the Soviet Union—Tajikistan, which today occupies most of the Pamir Plateau, was Afghanistan, a republic of the Soviet Union, was also under Soviet hostage at the time. The Soviet army deployed an army division in the Wakhan Valley and built missile launch sites and airports. It was eyeing my country&#39;s southern Xinjiang - so it chose the east of Mingtie Gaida Ban. , far away from the Sino-Soviet border and the Khunjerab Pass with complex mountains to achieve better strategic concealment. The cost is that the China-Pakistan Highway on the Pakistani side has a large gap and is easily damaged by natural disasters such as landslides and mudslides. For example, in 2010, a landslide formed a barrier lake, causing the China-Pakistan Highway to be interrupted for five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Gao Xianzhi went on an expedition to Xiaobolu, he neither took the Mingtiegaida Ban nor the Hongqilafu Pass, because this line of mountainous terrain was already controlled by the Tibetan army at that time. If he took these passes, it would be difficult. Faced with the huge risk of being attacked from the front and rear by the Tibetan army stationed in Lianyunbao, cutting off the food route. Therefore, what he chose was to first pull out Lianyunbao, the nail that was driven into the Congling Mountains, and then go south through the Yasin Valley parallel to it on the west side of the Hunza Valley, and attack Xiaobolu in a roundabout way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lianyun Fort in the Tang Dynasty was located in Sarhad, the last village in eastern Afghanistan today. It guarded the east entrance of the Wakhan Valley, and continued eastward into the Sino-Afghan border area. desert areas. The Wakhan Valley, also known as the Penchi Valley or the Wakhan Corridor, is a valley between the Pamir Plateau and the Hindu Kush Mountains. It stretches more than 600 miles from east to west and is an important cultural passage in the history of China and India. An important part of the southern route of the Silk Road. Zhang Qian of the Han Dynasty &quot;emptied out the Western Region&quot; and went through Congling to the Hezhong area to search for the Dayue clan; nearly 120 years before Gao Xianzhi&#39;s expedition to Xiaobolu&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;(629 AD)&lt;/span>;, &quot;Tang Monk&quot; Xuanzang crossed the Wakhan Valley into South Asia after seven days and nights; the two great empires of Britain and Russia in modern times launched the &quot;Great Game&quot; in Central Asia, and finally used this As the dividing line and isolation zone between the north and the south, the valley demarcated the respective spheres of influence of the two countries, thus introducing the name &quot;Wakhan Corridor&quot;, and generously arbitrarily assigned this then Chinese territory to Afghanistan. It became an abrupt appendix at the eastern end of Afghanistan&#39;s territory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tibet defended the Lianyunbao Fortress at the east entrance of the Wakhan Valley, &quot;weaving wood into a city based on mountains and rivers, cuttings and cliffs in the valley&quot;. To the east, you can enter southern Xinjiang along the Taxkorgan Valley, and to the north you can cross The Pamir Plateau enters Central Asia. To the west, you can bypass the Hindu Kush Mountains and enter South Asia, or you can go to the Transoxiana region along the Pench River. To the south, you can rely on the Hindu Kush Mountains to protect the newly occupied Big and Little Burrows. It can be said that it is connected in all directions. , strategic location. In order to fight steadily, Gao Xianzhi must first clear out the Tubo advance position, and then go south to regain Xiaobolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was unable to go to the Wakhan Valley to visit Lianyunbao in person, so I had to first take the China-Pakistan Highway to reach the small Buludu city of Gilgit - today&#39;s capital of Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (Gilgit), and then walk along the Gao Xianzhi&#39;s march route went in the opposite direction, first going westward along the Gilgit River, then northward along its tributary Yasin Valley, and reaching the southern slope of the Hindu Kush Mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/ItRbcoHPJdl4kV2Y35bCnG8BbEqBsEmisEeqIQWS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/ItRbcoHPJdl4kV2Y35bCnG8BbEqBsEmisEeqIQWS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tashkorgan Stone City&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the old and new Tang books According to records, Gao Xianzhi commanded 10,000 infantry - equivalent to half of the mobile troops of the Anxi Protectorate - from Qiuci in the fourth lunar month of 747 AD >; (Today&#39;s Kuqa)&lt;/span>; Set out and spent more than a month along the southern foot of Tianshan Mountains via Diazhuangcheng &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Aksu)&lt;/ span>;, hold Sede&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Bachu)&lt;/span>; and go west to Shule&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Today&#39;s Kashgar)&lt;/span>;, and mobilized some border guard cavalry along the way, and then followed the Taxkorgan River Valley southward to Congling to guard the capture&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Shouchu&quot; is a small military town in the Tang Dynasty)&lt;/span>;, which is the stone city outside Taxkorgan County today - &quot;Tash&quot; means &quot;stone&quot; in Turkic language. In the first ten days of the seventh lunar month, the Tang army, together with about 20,000 vassal troops from the Western Regions, crossed the Congling Mountains and arrived at Telemanchuan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now Khorog, Tajikistan )&lt;/span>;. Gao Xianzhi divided his troops into three groups here. He led the main force of the Tang army back to the west side of Lianyun Fort. He also sent two groups of troops from Kashgar and Aksu to surround Lianyunguo from the north and east respectively. It was agreed on the 13th day of the seventh lunar month. A surprise attack was launched at the same time at day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historical records show that the Tubo army held on to the mountain and rolled logs and stones to &quot;cover the sky&quot;, making it difficult for the Tang army to succeed. Gao Xianzhi issued a strict order to his brave generals Li Siye and Tian Zhen: &quot;If we don&#39;t reach the sun, we must break the enemy!&quot;. The &quot;Old Book of Tang&quot; once wrote a biography of Li Siye, saying that he was born in the military and was &quot;seven feet long and extremely brave.&quot; Facing the intensive defense of the defenders, he and Tian Zhen held the double-edged Mo Dao and led a troop of Mo Dao soldiers. The commando team found another way and &quot;climbed first at the most dangerous place&quot;, that is, climbed up from the cliff that the Tubo defenders did not expect, and rushed into the enemy&#39;s stronghold from a high position. As expected, they captured the building before noon, which was garrisoned by more than 10,000 Tubo troops. , a fortress with a compound defense system composed of mountain fortresses and mountain foot camps, beheaded 5,000 people, captured more than 1,000 people, and won the largest tough battle of the expedition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tang army recaptured Lianyun Fort, drove the Tubo out of Congling, and regained the Wakhan Valley, the passage connecting the Western Regions. The next step was to cross the Hindu Kush Mountains, recapture Xiaobolu, and clear out the The threat of the Tibetan army to the Wakhan Valley. It was mid-August at that time. Today&#39;s Wakhan Corridor is only passable from June to August of the year. The mountains are blocked by heavy snow at other times. The climate in the Tang Dynasty was also the same. Presumably considering the weather factors, Gao Xianzhi did not delay at Lianyun Fort, leaving more than 3,000 weak soldiers behind. He led his elite infantry to march lightly and quickly, and ran for three days and nights, arriving at Darkut Pass (Darkut Pass, &lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s translation is Dakot Pass). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8kscrApbrsiJFCskX9KcLqRJ1jVIPF19O4ElMSvA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8kscrApbrsiJFCskX9KcLqRJ1jVIPF19O4ElMSvA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wakhan Corridor, with the Hindu Kush Mountains in the background. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Crossing the Hindu Kush: The vast sea is covered with hundreds of feet of ice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Pakistan and Afghanistan are bounded by the Hindu Kush Mountains in the Wakhan Corridor. This Persian name was first seen in the narrative of the medieval Arab traveler Ibn Battuta. It is literally translated as &quot;Hindu (Hindu Kush)&quot;. &quot;Hindu&quot; killer (Kush)&quot;, which means that a large number of Indian slaves captured from the hot areas of South Asia froze to death while crossing this high and cold mountain; some people also interpret it as the &quot;Mountain of India&quot;, which means crossing southward This mountain range enters the Indian subcontinent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tanjuling Pass is located in the eastern section of the Hindu Kush Mountains, but it is not a pass that runs through this mountain range - because there are two watersheds and two mountain passes. The eastern end of the Hindu Kush Mountains originates from the Pamir Plateau and has the characteristics of mountain twists and turns. It is divided into parallel north and south branches near the Tanju Ridge: the north branch is the border line between Pakistan and Afghanistan, and south of the south branch is the north and south branches.向的亚辛河谷，而南北两支之间是东西向的亚昆河谷（Yarkhun River）。坦驹岭山口是南支上的垭口，海拔为4688米，山口两侧遍布冰川，很难逾越。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么还有没有其他路呢？其实是有的。翻越兴都库什山脉北支后可以沿着亚昆河谷西行，绕过南支，再翻越著名的山杜尔山口（Shandur）向东进入吉尔吉特河谷，即可顺流而下抵达小勃律。但是这条路线直到二十一世纪的今天依然极其崎岖难行，其中亚昆河谷连铺装公路都没有，大部分路段是位于陡崖半山、仅容一辆车低速通过的简易砂石土路，骑车的话分分钟会爆胎，因此我只得寄存了自行车，雇用摩托车手载我进入亚昆河谷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/An6dIyETx5jIvnAWAGpM9XcSmAmAeJBj4xm0BGXR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/An6dIyETx5jIvnAWAGpM9XcSmAmAeJBj4xm0BGXR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;山杜尔山口，是马球发源地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以想见，一千三百年前这里的路况只会比现在糟得多。如果高仙芝率部绕行亚昆河谷，很可能需要多走一个来月，那时就是九月中下旬，吐蕃援军早已在小勃律以逸待劳严阵以待，而兴都库什山脉和帕米尔高原很快就将因为严寒而无法通行，这意味着唐军归路将被切断——我猜想这就是高仙芝决定与时间赛跑，率军冒险翻越坦驹岭山口“直下峭峻四十馀里”的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，当兵吃粮的士卒们可没有这样的战略洞察。好不容易攀冰踏雪登上坦驹岭，他们望着脚下连绵冰川，惊慌失措地质问高仙芝：“大使将我欲何处去？”——“大使”是唐代对节度使的尊称——你难道要我们从这么陡峭的冰川顶部出溜下去吗？这是要带我们去小勃律还是阎罗殿？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千年以降，英籍匈牙利裔探险家斯坦因在实地考察高仙芝行军路线后写道：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当我立在山口顶端闪光烁烁的积雪上，向那直到6000英尺下亚辛山谷尽头的峻坂下窥，对于起初唐军拒绝向前移动的原因，后来他们努力挣扎前进的艰难，以及高仙芝的勇敢，才能认识清楚！ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/QmEoteO6T3NeHWtoJELvU9xOW5FmFYpLIBb5Wihg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;668&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/QmEoteO6T3NeHWtoJELvU9xOW5FmFYpLIBb5Wihg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254973&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;坦驹岭&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，高仙芝无法用个人的勇敢来驱使士卒。他料到了人性的弱点，知道士卒不敢攀冰下山深入敌境，因此悄悄派出二十多名亲信，穿上勃律人的服装提前爬上坦驹岭等待大部队。正当唐军士卒在山顶惊疑不定时，这些冒牌货笑盈盈地迎上前来，自称是驻扎在山口对面的小勃律守军，代表阿弩越城守将前来投顺王师，还说小勃律已经切断了吐蕃援军的必经之路。这个天大的好（&lt;em>;假&lt;/em>;）消息让唐军士卒们顿感胜利在望，因此信心满满地服从将令越过坦驹岭，进入亚辛河谷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据史家考证，阿弩越城位于今天的古皮斯镇（Gupis），乃是亚辛河（Yasin River）汇入吉尔吉特河的河口，也是唐军向小勃律国都进军途中的最大关隘。我沿着从吉尔吉特到奇特拉尔的铺装公路骑车至此，正逢路边一座小学放学，三五百名披着黑色hijab头巾的女生兴高采烈地从校门里涌出来&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（当地男女生各上半天学）&lt;/span>;，一时间把公路挡得严严实实。待她们散入街巷，我才看到公路北侧由中国援建的铁索桥横跨水流湍急的吉尔吉特河，过桥后溯河上行不远就可以看到一条清澈的支流从西北方向汇入大河，那便是由坦驹岭冰川融雪涓汇成流的亚辛河。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a3WXffZ5FQu5EWQchTj2pAmrlpm6JAxX4OpDzaI8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a3WXffZ5FQu5EWQchTj2pAmrlpm6JAxX4OpDzaI8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;坦驹岭下的亚辛河谷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从阿弩越城到亚辛河源头的坦驹岭南麓，全程将近七十公里，同样是未经铺装的简易土路，我搭车花了三个小时方才抵达，而高仙芝当年率军翻山越岭走了四天。还剩最后一天山路时，喜讯传来：阿弩越城真的派使者来迎接唐军了——或许守将得知吐蕃军主力已被聚歼于连云堡，唐军又已翻越天险坦驹岭，区区一道娑夷河已无法阻挡其兵锋，因此决定向唐军开城投降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而我脑海中浮现的却是另一幕场景：唐军将士诧异地看着两伙胡人，他们都自称是阿弩越城守军，都声称是来投降的，彼此却不认识，也无法对话交流。后一伙人高鼻深目，乃是波斯人的长相，前一伙人却和自己长得差不多，操着荒腔走板的夹生“胡语”，尴尬地望着对方……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;截断印度河谷：车师西门佇献捷&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;从阿弩越城出发，沿娑夷河东行至小勃律都城孽多，距离约为一百十公里。孽多城位于罕萨河谷与娑夷河谷的交汇处，原城址已不可考，但从史书记载来看应该位于娑夷河西岸。如今这里是巴控克什米尔的首府吉尔吉特，因河而名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从孽多城沿娑夷河再下行约六十里便是娑夷河汇入印度河的河口，由此沿印度河顺流而下便是古称“五河之地”的旁遮普平原&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（“旁遮普”在印地语中即“五河”之意）&lt;/span>;——五条源于喜马拉雅山脉南麓的支流在此陆续汇入印度河，形成肥沃的冲积平原，孕育了古印度文明；由此溯流而上，穿过从河口到斯卡杜（Skardu）之间的壮观大峡谷则可进入大勃律，最终翻越喜马拉雅山脉抵达青藏高原。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喀喇昆仑公路沿着罕萨河、吉尔吉特河与印度河右侧的台地一路南下，在吉尔吉特河口附近走个漂亮的U形弯道下降至岸边，再通过一座公路桥跨过吉尔吉特河，对岸就是沿着印度河通往克什米尔印巴对峙地区的S1号公路，战略价值十分重要。而在高仙芝远征期间，如今公路桥的位置建有一座用藤条编成的索桥，乃是吐蕃欺骗小勃律“借道”所建。它“阔一箭道”，也就是藤桥的跨度达到当时的弓箭射程——约两百米左右。这座藤桥是吐蕃军由大勃律进入小勃律乃至北上葱岭的必经之路，可谓咽喉锁钥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;却说高仙芝率军抵达孽多城，效忠吐蕃的小勃律贵族坚守都城，不放唐军入城。高仙芝陷入了本文开头描述的窘境：如果不尽快拿下孽多城，一旦吐蕃援军赶到，失去退路的唐军势必陷入双方夹击，在即将来临的严冬中被围歼于孽多城下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，高仙芝并没有摆出攻城的态势——当然他也并不具备强攻坚城的人力和物力。这位远征军的最高指挥官首先派使者稳住小勃律国王，声称唐军既不打算攻城也不准备破坏藤桥，而是打算经过藤桥去攻打大勃律的吐蕃军；其次他用金银财物利诱守城的亲吐蕃派贵族，将他们骗入唐营全部斩首；而最重要的一件任务，高仙芝交给了先锋席元庆：兼程赶赴娑夷河口破坏藤桥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从孽多城到娑夷河口是吐蕃军铺设的军用公路，路况想必不错，但等到席元庆急行军六十里赶到藤桥时，太阳已经落入峡谷西侧的雪峰背后。在沉沉暮色之中，他看到对面山岭中群鸟惊飞，烟尘涌起——那是另一支大军正在全速赶来。席元庆没有耽搁任何时间，立刻指挥士卒一齐动手斩断藤条。藤桥刚刚堕入被古人称为弱水三千、极为湍急的娑夷河中，吐蕃援军的大队人马就冲到了对岸——可惜已经来不及渡河了&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《旧唐书》：及暮，才斫了，吐蕃兵马大至，已无及矣）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/PnJOz5W8HdgAwZ8xG3Di00h5CaRC2mXr2W1STqHx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/PnJOz5W8HdgAwZ8xG3Di00h5CaRC2mXr2W1STqHx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254976&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;水流湍急的娑夷河，又称弱水。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这座藤桥当年花了一年时间才建成，如今被唐军控制住了西岸，吐蕃军无法复建藤桥，也不可能徒涉渡河，只得望河兴叹后灰溜溜地原路返回了大勃律。吐蕃方的《敦煌吐蕃文书· 大事纪年》在藏历猪年的条目下如此记载：勃律国、廓地&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今青海东部）&lt;/span>;守军被唐人击败，守地失陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，吐蕃守军被歼，吐蕃援军被阻，亲吐蕃派被杀，小勃律国王苏失利突然变成了四面楚歌的那一方，不得不向高仙芝投降。国王和他的吐蕃王后被送往长安献俘，小勃律则被改名为归仁军，由一千名唐军在此镇守。收复小勃律的整个战役历时四个月，但实际作战过程不过十余日，除了连云堡的半日血战之外，在小勃律境内可谓兵不血刃而收全功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斯坦因曾如此评价：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;数目不少的军队，行经帕米尔和兴都库什，在历史上以此为第一次。高山插天，又缺乏给养，不知道当时如何维持军队的供应？即令现代的参谋本部，亦将束手无策……中国这一位勇敢的将军，行军所经，惊险困难，比起欧洲名将，从汉尼拔，到拿破仑，到苏沃洛夫，他们之越阿尔卑斯山，真不知超过多少倍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/TNvnijQcmMWhhIKM3mlemCmHXMeL1ssu3i3zKftF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/TNvnijQcmMWhhIKM3mlemCmHXMeL1ssu3i3zKftF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254975&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;罕萨河谷中的Ultar冰川与Baltit城堡&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;尾声：雪上空留马行处&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;天宝十载&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元751年）&lt;/span>;，高仙芝被调离安西大都护府。两年之后，由他一手提拔于草莽的继承者、新任安西节度使封常清出兵收复大勃律，从而彻底断绝了吐蕃经由勃律和葱岭方向进犯安西四镇的通道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，这次战役是大唐在西域的最后一次扩张。只过了两年，安史之乱爆发，中原陷入纷飞战火，濒临灭亡的唐王朝从此再无力经营西域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时的吐蕃也改变了对唐战略，由面对盛唐强兵时的绕道勃律攻其安西四镇一隅，改为利用大唐反复抽调河西精锐去内地平叛导致当地兵力空虚的机会，重新开始主攻河湟地区，夺取连接大唐西域与中原的河西走廊，再将联络中断、孤立无援的西域各镇各国分别击破，大唐的西域统治体系随之轰然崩塌。到了九世纪初，安西大都护府完全陷落，天山南北直到清乾隆年间方重新纳入我国版图，故此被称为“新疆”，取其“故土新归”之意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于高仙芝为什么在军威鼎盛之际被调离西域，那就是另一段跌宕的历史了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（本文回目取自唐代边塞诗人岑参诗句。岑参是高仙芝、封常清的幕僚，曾跟随两人转战西域，走遍天山南北。）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[制造数字人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259222]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李尚福被免去国务委员、国防部部长职务，秦刚被免去国务委员职务]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259226]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 19:19:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011391102109&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;习近平签署第十二号、第十三号、第十四号主席令.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/DQLOOyhweoEA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/DQLOOyhweoEA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据央视《新闻联播》消息，第十四号主席令说，根据中华人民共和国第十四届全国人民代表大会常务委员会第六次会议于2023年10月24日的决定：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一、免去李尚福的国务委员、国防部部长职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、免去秦刚的国务委员职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三、免去王志刚的科学技术部部长职务；任命阴和俊为科学技术部部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四、免去刘昆的财政部部长职务；任命蓝佛安为财政部部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如何让老人在“家门口”幸福养老？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259157]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;让农村老人老有所依&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据2020年度国家老龄事业发展公报，2020年我国乡村60周岁及以上人口占乡村总人口的23.81%，比城镇高出近8个百分点。据全国老龄办预测，到2035年，我国农村60岁及以上人口在农村人口中的比例将升至37.7%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者采访发现，面对农村人口老龄化、空巢化问题，各地因地制宜采取各种措施，努力让农村老人老有所依。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——弘扬农村互助文化，发展互助养老。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“王阿姨，我来看您啦，今天身体还好吧？”54岁的李玉清是北京市密云区十里堡镇庄禾屯村的邻里互助员，她经常到村里80岁的独居老人王秀兰家中探望。“每次上门，我都会帮王阿姨量量血压、血糖，问问她有没有不舒服的地方。”李玉清说，邻里互助员都配备了“邻里互助百宝箱”，里面有血压计、血糖仪等设备及一些常用药品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1246ac4b5caa9ef808c40e0c129fa4a8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1246ac4b5caa9ef808c40e0c129fa4a8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;北京市密云区十里堡镇邻里互助员为王秀兰老人（左）测量血压。新华社记者邰思聪摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;密云区民政局社会儿童福利与养老服务中心副主任张昊介绍，为保障独居空巢高龄老人的居家安全，密云区大力推进邻里互助点试点建设，将本地热心公益的“4050”村民聘任为邻里互助员，将其住所作为邻里互助点，1个点位服务周边10个独居老人，为老人提供卫生打扫、洗衣缝纫、代买代缴、代开药品等服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——做好农村养老“关键小事”，守护空巢独居老人安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国疾病监测系统的数据显示，跌倒已成为我国65岁以上老年人因伤致死的首位原因。我国每年有4000多万老年人至少发生1次跌倒，卫生间是老人跌倒的重灾区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为破解部分农村住房“不适老”问题，浙江省丽水市2021年以来对2300余户农村老人家庭进行了适老化改造，让老人起夜有夜灯、走路有辅具、洗澡有座椅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——照护服务进家门，让老人老有安养。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家住湖南省长沙县青山铺镇广福村的低保对象彭汉全双下肢行动不便，平时生活只能靠老伴照顾。当地政府为他购买了居家养老服务，根据老人需求，当地养老服务中心护理员每月提供8次以上的居家上门服务，包括理发、助餐、康复指导等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在浙江省嘉善县，当地通过探索试点长期护理险制度，精准排摸失能失智老年人需求，累计为9500多名老人提供生活照料、康复护理等服务，较好保障失能失智老人的晚年生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者采访发现，一些地区农村养老服务也面临不少现实困难。一些基层民政干部反映，由于农村人口密度偏低，开展助餐、助医等服务成本较高。农村康养服务供给不足，一些重度失能失智老人易出现照护难、生活质量差的状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;社区养老服务模式不断创新&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2021年出台的《中共中央国务院关于加强新时代老龄工作的意见》提出“创新居家社区养老服务模式”；今年5月，中办、国办印发的《关于推进基本养老服务体系建设的意见》提出，“支持物业服务企业因地制宜提供居家社区养老服务”“支持养老机构运营社区养老服务设施”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者采访发现，一些城市依托社区发展以居家为基础的多样化养老服务，让社区服务与居家养老相互嵌套、融合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在杭州市拱墅区，有8个嵌入式养老机构和580余张家庭养老照护床位，可有效满足社区老人个性化需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e443db73131a798f830e2b794e0c77db.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e443db73131a798f830e2b794e0c77db.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;杭州市拱墅区大关街道德胜社区乐龄家养老园，医护人员帮助老人进行康复性训练。新华社记者李平摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拱墅区大关街道德胜社区77岁的濮阳华老人，由于记忆力衰退，子女不放心她一个人在家，将她放在社区养老机构托养。每天早上8点左右，工作人员将她接到机构；下午子女下班后，再将她接回家，一天托养费用为80元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在湖南长沙，“养老+家政”的服务模式初见成效。记者在长沙市芙蓉区马坡岭街道综合养老服务中心看到，护理员不仅可以提供营养餐制作、助洁、助浴等基础服务，还可以提供专业的护理服务，如健康监测、康复运动、辅助用药等；既可以长期住家服务，也可以由老人或子女“点单”，提供上门服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在北京，由“养老管家”提供个性化服务在一些社区流行起来。北京市民政局将试点街道划分为若干片区，每个片区组建一个“2+N+X”的管理单元，配备2名高素质首席养老服务管家、N名专业养老护理服务人员和若干名志愿者，负责2至3个社区的养老服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者采访发现，一些城市社区养老服务尚存在一些短板，服务保障能力不足。不少老旧社区公共场地少，难以建设养老食堂、照护中心等；社区养老驿站大多为“小作坊”经营模式，缺乏有行业影响力的经营主体；养老护理人才依然短缺等。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;多方共担，让老人在“家门口”安度晚年&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《中共中央国务院关于加强新时代老龄工作的意见》提出，“构建居家社区机构相协调、医养康养相结合的养老服务体系和健康支撑体系”“推进各项优质服务资源向老年人的身边、家边和周边聚集”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/acbb9f4950eac6f42eaf4ffa3216b614.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/acbb9f4950eac6f42eaf4ffa3216b614.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;甘肃省平凉市崆峒区西郊街道综合养老服务中心，老人们正在吃午餐。新华社记者王紫轩摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“老年人哪里多，我们就把养老服务机构办在哪。”民政部等部门表示，“十四五”时期将推进老旧城区、已建成居住（小）区基本补齐社区养老服务设施，推动构建城市社区“一刻钟”居家养老服务圈，让居家社区养老服务更丰富、更便捷、更有质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浙江省老年服务业协会会长徐佳增认为，农村养老服务重点应放在失能失智人群社会服务供给上。要加强低收入群体救助帮扶，加快建立长期护理保险制度，发挥乡镇卫生院、乡村医生的网络优势，鼓励乡村医生为高龄、重病、失能等老年群体提供定期体检、上门巡诊、家庭病床等基本服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市民政局副局长郭汉桥建议，鼓励社会资本进入养老产业，培育多元经营主体，共同做大做强养老服务产业。目前，北京已探索搭建养老服务统一信息平台，畅通资源对接、供需匹配，支持和引导经营主体积极参与养老服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对养老护理人才短缺等问题，浙江省绍兴市上虞区民政局局长丁福军建议，提高护理人员待遇，提升大众对护理人员认可度。同时，引导广大社会公益组织、慈善机构、青年志愿者参与养老服务工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，要大力推进智能设备的应用和数字化管理，赋能养老服务。目前一些地方已在开展这方面的探索，如杭州市开展安居守护工程，对适老化改造对象按需安装烟雾报警器、紧急呼叫器等智能监测设备；长沙市有针对性地开展适老化改造，为部分老人配备“防走失”科技服、睡眠检测仪等智能设备，并实时将健康数据同步到云端。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1840年以来的中国与美国（中）丨倬彼云汉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259193]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp3iVUJbVg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;962&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp3iVUJbVg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“围堵政策”下的国际格局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1949年，国民党败退台湾。这一段时期，美国曾有深入的检讨，也确定其国策所在：如何防堵苏联和中国联合战线？所谓“自由世界”，也就是英美领导的欧洲和美国，该如何面对社会主义阵容？主张资本主义自由经济的国家，与奉行社会主义计划经济的国家，二者之间是和平相处，还是处处对抗？这是当时美国政府非常挂心的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1947年，杜鲁门总统就以上问题征求马歇尔、艾森豪威尔和麦克阿瑟的意见后，采纳围堵政策。 1946年2月22日，驻守莫斯科的美国大使馆代办凯南（George F. Kennan），向国务院发送了著名的“长电报”。凯南的建议，定下了美国对战后世界的规划：“围堵政策”（Strategy of Containment）。从杜鲁门时代一直延伸到尼克松时代，都在这个方向做种种的外交措施。而在尼克松时代，基辛格规划了“联系”（Engagement）政策。但是，从整体原则而言，“联系”也只是手段，是想在“围堵”之中，设法闯出一个缺口。所以，“围堵政策”可以说是几十年来，美国处理世界事务的最高原则。直到最近，这一政策演化成手忙脚乱的局面，这是当时没有预料到的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾1947年至今，七十多年来，西方世界大多是在这个“围堵政策”的统治下：美国自我期许，应该担起“自由世界”“自由经济”的“防卫者”这个责任。所有可能出现的“缺口”，都要尽量堵上——从北海延伸到鄂霍茨克海，从柏林延伸到库页岛。这一条漫长的战线，中间以苏联为主，而中国作为没有指明的“伙伴”——中国的“伙伴”身份，究竟是靠向哪一边，这个电文里没有叙述。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于这一政策的落实，美国决定以前述三个重要人物作为主要执行者。第一步是马歇尔以国务卿的身份，主持旨在推动欧洲复兴的“马歇尔计划”（官方名称为“欧洲复兴计划”European Recovery Program），同时以美元援助希腊、土耳其——这两个国家，是苏联舰队由里海、黑海进入地中海的要道。在东方，日本投降以后，麦克阿瑟要将日本与韩国打造为“东方的民主堡垒”，亲自主持东线的防守。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜鲁门退任以后，接任的是艾森豪威尔，三者维持了这个局面几十年。其中的插曲是杜鲁门无法忍受麦克阿瑟“将在外不受君命”，从南韩召回这一悍将。但是，马歇尔与艾森豪威尔忠诚地执行了这一政策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个政策在东方的第一步，是美国第七舰队开始巡防台湾海峡，使得孤悬在中国大陆海边的金门、马祖——这两个国民党台湾当局仅存的基地得以保全。青岛本来是美军驻华的海军基地，美国人却在真正卷入中国本土战场前撤离了。否则，驻守青岛的美军，将会与驻韩美军形成呼应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个决定，引发一连串东亚的变局。美国强化菲律宾的基地，将日本和琉球作为美国东方防线的重要据点，加上台湾，构成围堵中国大陆的“第一岛链”。这个政策维持之长久、执行之着力、影响之深远一直到今天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从那时开始，美国拒绝与中国大陆来往。即使1971年，“中华民国”已经被迫退出联合国，美国与其之间的关系还是维持到1978年，直到北京与华府正式建交为止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冷战开始后，防守台湾成为美国的任务之一。对于台湾当局而论，假如没有美国这颗“定心丸”——美国将防线划在台湾海峡——的话，台湾这个基地的建设不可能展开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;台湾和海峡另一边本土之间的恩恩怨怨，到今天还无法解除。将来怎么解决这些纠纷？如何才能“破镜重圆”？如何能让台湾建设的成果、台湾的人才、台湾的经济基础，与大陆的经济建设可以互相支持？这要靠我们华人的智慧，思考如何能够顾及中华血脉。当然，关于“中华血脉”这四字，民进党与我的想法不一样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，两岸在经济建设方面曾经互相支持，从1970年代至今没有停止。大陆的经济建设，比台湾晚了大约二十年，因为中间经历了三十年尝试种种政策导致的颠簸。从邓小平主政时期开始，到今天双方的合作和沟通，由两边的海峡事务委员会当“桥梁”，由外国的元首如李光耀等作为“中间人”。港澳还未回归以前，是两岸很自然的接触点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个非常重要的事情，就是蒋经国开启的台湾体制改革。他宣告：“我们蒋家人不再介入政治。”后来，李登辉改变了台湾的基本大法。但吊诡的是，美国政府继续承诺“要以全力保卫台湾”，这个说法成为国际关系史上前所罕见的一个例子。熟悉国际事务的人士，曾经用“有心的模糊”形容如此安排。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国历史上，从春秋转入战国的时代，晋国曾是“五霸”里实质上的领袖。晋国占有其盟国卫国的干邑。晋国的霸权在那时也已日薄西山，内部终为韩、赵、魏三家瓜分，中国历史进入战国的“七雄”时代。那时真正有实力竞争霸主的，是秦、楚两个边缘的大国——夹缝里出现的吴、越两个霸主，都只是昙花一现。秦、楚这两个边缘大国竞争，最终秦国统一了神州大陆，成为“中华帝国”的前身。而秦国统一中原的过程及其所建立的制度，实际上约束了中华帝国两千年的形式，到1911年方才改变。在此，我以中国历史上的这个例子，来预见美国几十年来的霸权日后可能的变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国的霸权建立至今，东亚遭遇了诸多危机：一次朝鲜战争、两次越南战争——日本和韩国则沦为美国实际上的“属地”，冲绳的地位变得不明不白。而这些，都是“围堵政策”的后果。美国如此称霸，它在别国之内可以像晋国取得卫国的干邑一样——干邑在当时中原的东半边是个据点，晋国在北半边指挥不动。这个情势，就很像东亚“岛链”情形。吊诡的是，晋国分出来的赵国最后将干邑夺走了。将来美国会不会将台湾转变成日本、韩国的“延伸”，我们无法预测。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再看欧洲的局面。 “马歇尔计划”以后，美国以组建北约、欧盟的方式，以英、法、德三国——过去的敌人德国作为重点，扼守在欧洲中心地带。数十年过来，如今欧盟已经感觉到：当年的美国是为了保护他们，如今的美国却成为他们的主人。美国为了保卫欧洲，花费了极大力气。 “马歇尔计划”真是从断壁残垣之中，重新建立了一个花团锦簇的世界。如今的德国，其繁荣的经济基础，与今天我们看到的美国不一样——英、法败下阵来了，德国上来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国在战后，将德国一分为二：一半由西方占领，一半由苏联占领——如同朝鲜与南韩、南越和北越的划分一样。柏林是独立市，又在中间建了一道“柏林墙”。 1948年第一次柏林危机，苏联封锁柏林，美国长达数月空投粮食、汉堡、热狗、牛奶、鸡蛋乃至纸张等生活物资，飞机在跑道上没有停过。那一笔开支相当惊人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1963年6月25日，肯尼迪在柏林讲演——“作为一个自由人，我无比自豪地说：我是一个柏林人。”肯尼迪担任总统以后，还曾经讲过：我们不要忘记丘吉尔与我们的老总统罗斯福曾经提出，人类应当有“四大自由”。 （罗斯福与丘吉尔签订的《大西洋宪章》其实有两个“版本”：一个是长的“条约”，一个是短的“四大自由”的口号——免于恐惧的自由，免于匮乏的自由，言论自由，信仰自由。）我们责无旁贷，要做世界的卫兵，维护这“四大自由”。当年的肯尼迪，就以“四大自由”为理由宣誓：我们的任务，任重而道远。不要问国家能为我们做什么，要问我们能为国家做什么。当年罗斯福总统实行新政以后，国家对国民尽责任，维持其起码的生活水平——我们政府的责任，就是在美国的领土上实现“四大自由”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些宣示非常动听，而且美国人的实践确实也非常努力。当初所划定的界线，今天还依然存在——最近乌克兰与俄罗斯的冲突，还是因为美国“围堵政策”所导致的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前面我所讲的，是为了说明凯南“围堵政策”的文化背景、美国对自己的期许，以及做出的努力。从那时到现在，七十多年了，美国的霸权都在“围堵政策”的话语体系下呈现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中间还发生过古巴导弹危机。苏联想要在古巴设立一个导弹基地，美国坚决不允许。肯尼迪和赫鲁晓夫对抗，彼此不相让——最终苏联让步，将部署在古巴的导弹撤回。而美国至今还占着古巴的关塔那摩监狱，死也不肯让出来：这是一个没有法律管束的牢狱，美国在此审问的间谍、俘虏的囚犯，没有任何人权法保护，被施以灌水、鞭打、电击等酷刑，死了就将尸体扔掉。如此行径，我常常用“吊诡”这两个字形容：美国号称要维护“四大自由”，实际上始终存在这样一个“疮疤”，却视若无睹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1957年，人类第一颗人造卫星由苏联发射成功。美国花钱费力，力图保持太空的均势，终于在1969年的尼克松时代，美国航天员首次登上月球。此前一年，美、苏、英等59个国家，共同签署了《不扩散核武器条约》。限制新的国家发展核武器，这对于世界而言是好事——至于已经拥有核武器的国家，会不会有人首先使用核弹，就是未知之数了。一直到里根时代，美国与苏联的军备竞争始终在进行，甚至发展到可以用卫星将核弹运载到太空——美国以巨量的太空军备竞赛，压垮了苏联的经济。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前面讲述美国历史上的外交政策作为背景，是为了说明：美国的外交政策，是中美关系中最主要的一剂“药”，也是为了维护西方文化的霸权思想、“围堵”思想。这才是我们理解二战以来的世界这个复杂的大棋局，很重要的一个原则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“麦卡锡主义”下的留美华人&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;二战以来，众多中国留学生在美国深造，包括我在内。我们到这儿来求学，是因为美国学校的课程、设备居全球之冠。这一阶段，美国确实也在大量招收外国学生，我们趁此机会来学本事。当然，中国人喜欢落叶归根。早期通过“庚款”来到美国的成百上千留学生，大多数都回到中国，主要的工作岗位不是在教育界，就是在实业界。那个时期，中国的科技发展还不是主流，科技人才也就大致分配在上面两个范围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等到战后，国共内战，中国一分为二，海峡封锁，这就成了大问题：中国大陆出来的留学生，在“围堵政策”的立场之下，美国不让他们回大陆。最重要的一个例子，就是钱学森。当时美国的物理学是世界前哨，假如中国要发展现代科技的武器，钱学森的参与必定有其贡献。我相信钱学森在发明导弹这件事上尽了力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“铁幕”开始降落时，美国开始疑忌在美的“左倾”人士。这一事件发生在杜鲁门任上，“麦卡锡主义”不仅要挡住那些选择回到中国或东欧国家的知识分子，而且要铲除国内的“左倾”分子。所谓“左倾”，其定义就变成“自由分子”——凡是不“右”的，就给他们戴上“左”的帽子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主要负责此事的，是太平洋国际学会。他们的监视网非常宽广，笼罩在所有中国研究的基地上——匹兹堡还好，因为不是大基地。如此情况，使得全美的华人都心惊胆战，不知道哪天联邦调查局或中央情报局的探员，会查阅你的来往信件，会检查你的纳税数目。大家杯弓蛇影，心怀恐惧。 1970年我来匹兹堡的时候，还看见了这种现象的遗留。一位姓余的老华侨——到这里他改名换姓为“林盼”，因为他买了林家的“出生纸”；我们家现在的牙医就是余家的。老先生到我的办公室来谈话，进来先把门关好，然后轻轻地和我谈他们的恐惧，低声问我：“这个局面何时可以终了？”因为他们有很多家乡子弟想要出来，但“铁幕”已垂下；还有那些死在异域的几十个同乡，只好先火化，等到有一天带回故乡去。最近犬子还访问了存放骨灰的地点，确实有几十个坛子在那里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到后来“麦卡锡主义”平复了，台湾恢复与美国的来往。 1962年我回到台湾，此后两三年间在母校台湾大学历史系服务，按照现代的规模、方向安排课程；余外的工作，就是奉命与美国的学术单位及汉学家联络。我的上司是“中研院”院长王世杰先生，以及史语所所长李济先生。这个工作非常艰难，有很多人质疑我的立场：我们如果到台湾去，会不会加重美国对我本人的猜疑？我说：“我不能回答你的问题，但是我回去了，我没问题啊。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一直到1971年，尼克松与中国大陆开展“乒乓外交”以后，才有大量的华侨青年和留学生回大陆；随后同样有大量的留学生从大陆过来，比从台湾来的多十倍都不止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1956年，杨振宁、李政道二位先生提出“宇称不守恒定律”；随后，吴健雄女士以试验证明了这一理论——这三位都是世界著名的物理学家。杨先生因其父亲还在大陆，中美关系一松动他就回去了，从此没有断绝过与大陆的来往。他也很努力地将美国现代物理学的研究情形引介到国内，帮助国内的学者。数十年来，他本其初衷，帮助了许多学生留学，为大陆物理学的发展尽了自己的力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾有幸与他以及刘遵义一起，帮助余纪忠先生在中国大陆设立“华英文教基金会”，目的是帮助大学的教员出国，做短则半年、长则一年的进修。只要他们提出访问单位、目标、计划、时间，以及美国的邀请函或接收的承诺，还有校内给出的推荐信，我们就尽力在专业的方向评定其次序。看见如此多优秀的学者排着队，准备作更进一步的努力，于我而言是件非常愉快的工作。遗憾的是僧多粥少，我们无法满足每个人的愿望。因为这一项工作，杨先生与我们每年碰面一次。除了我们对各校讲演以外，我也有机会向他请教。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，我们同时在香港中文大学做访问，经常会一起喝茶聊天。如此交谊，我对他钦佩有加：老而不失童心，聪明而没有凌人之势。他将专门的学问做到了巅峰，而且对一般事务非常了解。最可佩处：对像我这种年纪的后辈，他完全是坦诚相交，使我与他谈话感觉如坐春风。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[再获雨果奖，中国科幻文学更进一步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259145]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;10月21日晚，2023雨果奖在2023成都世界科幻大会上揭晓，共评选出17类雨果奖奖项和2类非雨果奖奖项，中国作家海漄凭借《时空画师》获得最佳短中篇小说奖。这也是雨果奖首次在中国揭晓和颁奖。</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对李春生涉嫌受贿一案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259201]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;记者10月24日从最高人民检察院获悉，广东省人大常委会原党组副书记、副主任李春生涉嫌受贿一案，由国家监察委员会调查终结，经最高人民检察院指定，由湖南省郴州市人民检察院审查起诉。近日，郴州市人民检察院已向郴州市中级人民法院提起公诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察机关在审查起诉阶段依法告知了被告人李春生享有的诉讼权利，并讯问了被告人，听取了辩护人的意见。检察机关起诉指控：李春生利用担任河南省新县县长、县委书记，公安部政治部副主任、人事训练局局长，广东省副省长、省公安厅厅长，广东省人大常委会党组副书记、副主任等职务上的便利以及职权、地位形成的便利条件，为有关单位和个人在企业经营、项目推进、工程承揽、职务晋升等方面谋取利益，非法收受他人财物，数额特别巨大，依法应当以受贿罪追究其刑事责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访经济学家吴晓求：“要把A股市场从融资市场转变为投资市场”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259197]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;三十多年的中国资本市场，2亿多投资人，5300多家上市公司，没有哪一个市场如此牵动各方神经。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，中共中央政治局会议提出“要活跃资本市场，提振投资者信心”。证监会等部门随后陆续推出“活跃资本市场”一揽子政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沪深交易所是改革的产物，后经股权分置和注册制两大历史性改革。但长期以来，牛短熊长煎熬着每一位投资者。曾经激发长牛行情的股权分置改革遗留了什么样的漏洞？如何修堵？注册制又产生了哪些漏洞？怎样快速修补？中国资本市场的定位又如何通过变革步向成熟？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时值中国金融业改革开放45周年之际，中国人民大学原副校长、中国资本市场研究院院长吴晓求接受南方周末专访时强调，沪深交易所设立、股权分置改革和全面注册制改革是中国资本市场成立三十多年来的三座丰碑，取得巨大成功的同时，也留下了一些漏洞。这些漏洞恰是导致资本市场过去十多年来徘徊不前的重要制度性约束。当前，监管层已经意识到并加紧完善制度设计堵漏洞。而更长远的，是要把中国资本市场的主要功能从为企业融资，转变成为投资者的财富管理平台，由融资市场转变为投资市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴晓求是中国人民大学历史上最年轻的经济学教授、中国证券投资方向首位博士生导师，从事证券教学和研究长达三十多年，领导编撰了中国第一版证券从业人员考试教材。他还是股权分置改革和注册制改革等资本市场诸多重大改革的推动者和见证者，对活跃资本市场提出了诸多建议，其中“实行T+0交易制度时机不成熟”的一贯主张与证监会目前的表态一致。证监会2023年10月14日发布的“阶段性收紧融券和战略投资者配售股份出借”通知，也与吴晓求一直关注的减持规则制度漏洞有关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;569&quot; height=&quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吴晓求：中国人民大学原副校长；现任中国人民大学国家金融研究院院长、中国资本市场研究院院长，国家一级教授，中国金融学会常务理事。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;从事经济&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;、&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;金融和资本市场研究&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;四十&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;多年”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你是“新三届”（1977-1979）大学生。如果没有恢复高考和改革开放，你的人生轨迹如何演变？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我没有上过高中。大学之前，做过木匠，后来在县商业局做秘书。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恢复高考和改革开放改变了我一生的命运，如同改变中国成千上万跟我同时代人的命运一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十一届三中全会在1978年12月举行，但恢复高考是在1977年。把恢复高考放十一届三中全会之前，我认为这是为改革开放在思想上、人才上、舆论上做准备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恢复高考本身就是改革，它相当于对十年“文革”期间人才培养制度的一个根本性调整，拨乱反正。回忆前尘往事，如果没有改革开放这个决定当代中国命运的关键一招，中国没有今天，我个人也没有今天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你当时为什么报考江西财经学院国民经济专业？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我最初填报的是江西大学哲学专业，因为我喜欢哲学。我父亲知道后要我把专业改一改。他认为应该到江西财经学院去学习，国民经济计划专业非常好，未来可能经济还是很重要的。这一改，对我个人也是“决定性一招”。我后来思考我父亲这个决定，他是预见到了中国未来的发展方向。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大学一年级，我就知道了孙冶方、于光远、许涤新、宋涛、董辅礽等前辈，他们是我心目中的丰碑。学者梦，经济学家梦，这个理想从我上大学的时候就有了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1983年考研，我以总分第二名的成绩被中国人民大学国民经济计划专业录取。国民经济计划专业，人民大学是个殿堂。后来读博士、毕业后留校任教，我就再也没离开过。先做了大约10年的经济学研究。自1993-1994年开始，我正式转入金融研究和资本市场研究，到现在差不多有30年的历史了。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“思想不解放，就找不到正确的发展之路”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;求学之初（1983-1986），改革开放从农村发展到城市，城市经济体制改革起步，乡镇企业开始萌芽，对外开放不断扩大。在这期间，哪些改革事件你印象最为深刻？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有四件事，我印象很深刻：第一次是在安徽巢湖参加经济体制改革研讨会。1985年，中央发布了《关于经济体制改革的决定》，启动了计划与市场相结合的经济体制改革，那是个历史性的决定。当时我是研二学生，我和导师胡迺武先生参加这个研讨会。那是我第一次去参加全国性的、高水平的论坛。它对我触动很大，拓展了我的视野。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二次是1985年，我参加在天津举办的第二届中青年经济论坛。参加论坛的青年们思想活跃，参加各种辩论，思考中国的未来，探寻改革的重点。我当时写了一篇关于企业破产的文章。破产是市场经济的东西，计划经济下的中国当时根本没有破产一说，只有“关停并转”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三次1985年，我参加在人民大会堂举行的一个论坛。那场论坛是董辅礽先生主持，我的发言引起时任国家统计局局长李成瑞的关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第四次是1986年，我在四川乐山又参加了关于经济杠杆的讨论会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我才二十多岁。可以看出，那个时代给了年轻人很多平台和机会，可以在人民大会堂举办的高水平论坛上畅所欲言。这样就激活了你的思想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是闪闪发光的日子，到处都洋溢着青春的梦想，洋溢着年轻人的追求。只有思想解放，学术才会繁荣，国家才会发展。思想不解放，就找不到正确的发展之路。凡事都必须经过探索、讨论甚至辩论，才知道哪一条是正确的道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“破解中国经济特殊现象之谜”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你读博士期间（1987-1990），“一个中心、两个基本点”的基本路线和“科学技术是第一生产力”被提出。其间，你对中国经济改革有何见解？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;读博时最重要的事情是学习先进理论，研究中国经济，怎么去破解当时中国经济特殊现象之谜。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时给我影响最大的一本书是匈牙利经济学家亚诺什·科尔内的《短缺经济学》。在上个世纪80年代中后期，很多人都读了这部著作。《短缺经济学》是描述传统计划经济体制下，社会主义经济运行基本特征的书。它富有很强的理论逻辑，包括软预算约束、父爱主义等。受其思想启发，1987年开始我写了《紧运行论》。《紧运行论》与我的博士论文《社会主义经济运行分析》于1991年和1992年先后出版。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这本书当时为何会受到与众不同的关注？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这两本书的真正价值是试图解释传统体制下社会主义经济运行的特征和规律。我也因为这两本书，再加上发表在《人民日报》《光明日报》《经济研究》和《中国人民大学学报》上的文章、论文，1993年被人民大学破格晋升为教授。当年人民大学破格晋升了五位教授，我是其中最年轻的一位。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;转型证券研究，走一条人迹罕至的路&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1994年，你调入财政金融系任金融专业证券研究方向的教授，次年成为我国证券投资方向第一位博士生导师，从此与中国证券业发展结缘三十载。为何从此专注证券研究方向？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时我已经在开始研究金融了，因此主动提出调任。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;契机有两个：一个是为了脱贫解困。1990年代初，我当时快当教授了，还住在筒子楼里面，只有800块钱存款。那时有人给我出主意，说你写一本畅销书，我们负责卖，然后给你分成。我就想到了股票债券。于是我主编了《股票债券全书》，全书上下两册大约500万字，一上市果然很畅销，后来分了我一些钱，我就脱贫了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为我是主编，人家就要我去讲。这就逼着我真去学习证券知识和证券投资。这已经开始偏离我的经济学研究方向，完全是对资本市场和金融的研究。那时候，人们不觉得它是一门学问，甚至觉得有点“歪门邪道”。我的前辈中有一位重要学者曾找我谈话，核心意思是让我还是要回到经济运行分析、宏观经济、宏观经济管理和通货膨胀理论等经济学研究主流轨道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;证券研究这条路在当时是一条人迹稀罕的路，专业的研究者很少，杂音很多，理性研究非常非常少。但在我看来，证券研究越是深入越有研究的价值，我也算所剩不多从早期研究到现在仍然还在一线研究的人了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时任人大校长黄达先生是财政金融系的教授，我就申请去了财政金融系。我开了证券投资学这门课，当时在高校开证券投资课的并不太多。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;初入股市既为赚钱也为研究&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1994年有部电影叫《股疯》，讲述的是股市诞生初期全民炒股而产生的各种狂热。那时候的股票市场是否真像电影里那样？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（炒股的热潮）确实开始了。股市开始进入到人们的生活之中，投资股票市场的人开始多了，各种的理论、方法和股评也开始出现了。因为我写了《股票债券全书》，我也开始在这里面做研究。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作为证券投资的研究专家，你会下场炒股实践吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2000年之后，我才真正作为投资者进入了股市。进入以后，才发现实践对自己的理论研究有更深刻的帮助。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;证券研究和炒股有什么不一样？&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我进入这个市场的目标，既是为了赚钱，也是为了研究。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我当时给自己定了两个目标：一是不能赔钱，通过实践操作看理论掌握的东西在实践中行不行；二是对研究对象建立直接的感性认识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;慢慢地，我更了解证券投资的规律，市场的规律，编写教材的时候就更充盈了，就会写得更鲜活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那个时期，我主持编写了国内第一套证券从业人员资格考试的教材。第一版有六卷本，后来证监会组织编写的教材大体上的结构没有脱离这个版本。它对证券从业人员资格考试起了很重要的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;赚钱的预期达到了吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我当时也想抓到牛市赚一笔。第一笔我记得是买了四川长虹，突然有一天发现它涨得挺好。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;股权分置改革遗留&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;漏洞，必须补上&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾说过中国资本市场有三座丰碑：沪深交易所建立、股权分置改革、试点注册制。你参与推动了哪些？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我参与了股权分置改革、参与推动了注册制试点。股权分置改革启动是2005年5月。但理论准备从2001年国有股份减持失败开始，我们就开始思考怎么进行股权分置改革。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2001年的国有股减持为何失败？它给后来的股权分置改革提供了哪些启示？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时监管机构认为国有股减持可以按市价减持，但因市场反应太大被匆匆叫停。后来分析总结，国有股按市价减持，既缺乏逻辑，也缺乏理论支持，所以必然会失败。作为这个失败的结果，我们当时就在反思如何推动股权分置改革。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在那段反思的时间，学界组织了许多讨论，我可能是参加次数最多的人之一，无论是参加证监会主持的小范围讨论，还是大范围的讨论，我几乎每场都参加了。其中，印象比较深刻的一次是2004年某一天，时任证监会主席尚福林给我打电话，单独和我讨论股权分置怎么改。后来，我也多次到他办公室参加讨论，小范围的大概十个人，大范围的二三十个人，大家讨论后就形成了两点共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一点就是必须推动股权分置改革，不推动改革，中国资本市场是没有未来的。这个也是我强调的；第二点就是股权分置改革究竟应该用什么办法去改革，这个路径的设计非常困难，我们慢慢考虑到对价改革是合适的。对价改革也只是个方向，对价多少是合适的，这个变得更难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我清晰记得在证监会开会时，时任证监会副主席屠光绍问我，你觉得对价的比例是多少合适？我说30%或者说七折，因为存量增发的价格就是按流通价的七折。这就为股权分置改革的对价提供了参照。后来实践证明，各上市公司股权分置改革的对价方案都在七折附近波动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2005年股权分置改革启动初期，沪深股市并没有太大反应。大牛市似乎是2005年之后才起来。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。2005年5月启动了股权分置改革，当时沪深股市从2001年起已经低迷了4年多，市场反应冷淡。后来市场慢慢知道这个东西不得了，越来越多的人预感到这是一个大牛市的机会。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们当时就判断，在股权分置改革过程中，沪深股市漫长的熊市会发生逆转。改革完成之后，会为资本市场的长期健康发展奠定良好的基础。从今天角度来看，股权分置改革的大方向是正确的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;股权分置改革大概用了两年时间。它还有哪些不足之处？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从2005年5月到2007年3月，95%的上市公司都完成了股权分置改革。它是一座丰碑，但它也的确还有缺陷，这个缺陷就是对大股东、实际控制人的减持缺乏有效的约束。这个政策漏洞对后来沪深股市十多年来徘徊不前产生了重要影响。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最近也讲，严重制约中国资本市场发展的，最重要的是资产供给端的制度设计，其中，资产供给端主要是存量资产的减持规则，就是实际控制人、控股股东没有财务约束的减持标准，导致了市场很难有成长性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你认为，现在这个漏洞补得怎么样？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2023年8月27日，证监会政策里已经有某些修补了。这是股权分置改革遗留下来的一个漏洞，我们必须要把它补上。因为它严重损害了资本市场资金供求关系的生态链，使资金供应关系严重失衡。目前看大的漏洞正在修补，至少知道漏洞在哪里。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;注册制改革效果喜忧参半”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提及的中国资本市场第三个丰碑是注册制改革。为什么要启动注册制改革？&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2007年之后，我参与的理论研究，或者说政策制定，主要就是注册制改革。为什么要进行注册制改革？因为核准制是有重大缺陷的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，核准制最大的问题就是对企业上市的选择权没有交给市场，而是交给了发审委，交给了有形的手。第二个问题是定价没有市场化，所以才有上市之后20个涨停板的奇怪现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三个问题是监管主体和审核主体没有分离，证监会既审核又监管，这个当然是有问题的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于核准制至少有这三个方面的问题，我们想要把这三个缺陷改掉，就要进行注册制改革。根据市场化原则，交易所采取灵活性的制度，同时对拟上市企业不拘泥于一定要盈利。相对于核准制要求拟上市企业必须连续三年盈利，注册制的一个最大创新就是对拟上市企业主要高科技企业允许其过往三年有亏损，但是要具有可持续经营能力。这是个重大转变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年是全面注册制改革元年。作为注册制改革的推动者和政策参与者，你对目前的改革效果满意吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;喜忧参半。喜的是有一些独角兽企业、高科技企业，通过这个机制成为上市公司，虽然它短期是亏损的，但是它具有可持续经营能力。注册制改革天然服务于专精特新和高科技性创新企业，天生地和高科技企业具有耦合关系。只有在注册制下，科技和资本市场才是耦合的，我们未来仍然会朝这个方向努力。这对我们推动高科技企业的发展，对我国产业结构的转型和产业的升级迭代，改善上市公司结构，提升中国资本市场的投资价值，我认为是有重要价值和重要意义的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;忧的是注册制中对亏损的界定标准的泛化，这个是很严重的误解，损害了市场信心，也不符合注册制的本来含义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么会出现这种漏洞？这个漏洞的危害有哪些？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;注册制改革如同股权分置改革一样，也出现一个漏洞。坦率地说，当时没人意识到。就像设计一个航天器一样，百密一疏。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;注册制的漏洞就是把市场化功能泛化了，或者说把上市公司不严格要求盈利的指标泛化了。以至于后来有些上市公司抓住这样一个漏洞，搞一个所谓的高科技企业，打着所谓“破解卡脖子工程”等等旗号，找几十个研究人员，搞个两三年就开始要申请IPO了。这对市场信心损害巨大。它们不符合注册制的基本精神，也超出了一个公众市场、交易所市场、社会公众投资者所能承担风险边界的要求。这类企业的融资主要应该由PE、VC去完成的，是不可以直接IPO的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我把这个漏洞定义为：在注册制条件下，关于不盈利要求的泛化理解。这是很严重的认知误区，对后来股票市场徘徊不前有密切关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这个漏洞目前在修补吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我曾经向证监会明确提出，对拟上市公司不盈利的要求不能泛化。从最近的IPO情况看，证监会和交易所也已经特别关注对财务指标都是负值的企业的上市诉求，特别是对于净资产是负的、现金流是负的、利润是也负的，这些主要财报指标都是负的，这种企业是不能上市的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;修补完漏洞，注册制改革就完成了么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;远远没有。注册制改革是全方位、全链条的改革，发行制度市场化改革只是它的历史起点、逻辑起点，后面还有交易、并购、信息披露、监管、退市、违规违法行为的处罚、法律模式等等诸多方面的调整，都要纳入到和注册制改革相适应的模式之中，不断地完善。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;双峰模式是理想的妥协&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2022年，你提出中国金融体系的“双峰模式”。背后有哪些深层次的观察和思考？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;坦率地说，我最早提出的是“单蜂模式”。2002年前后我曾认为，未来的中国一定是资本市场占主体的金融模式。20年过去了，我发现“单蜂模式”在中国挺难的，实现不了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管如此，在近20年里，中国资本市场的规模扩张还是比较快的。它从过去的两三万亿市值，到今天的八十多万亿市值，在金融体系中的比重明显提升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，我终于意识到，中国的商业银行在中国经济生活中的作用巨大，中国只能实行双峰模式——银行体系和资本市场共同主导。这是一个理想的妥协，也是现实的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;资本市场为何难以成为主导？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;资本市场的发展并没有改变中国经济对货币信贷的依赖。从资本市场自身看，20年来上市公司的股票价格没有什么上涨，市场指数也没涨起来，只有市值在扩张。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，近20年上市企业的数量从1000家已经增加到5300多家，几乎中国最大的、最好的企业都已经实现了IPO，包括很多国企央企和“独角兽”企业。某种意义上说，中国股市便利企业融资的功能已经实现了，但它自身却是一个摊饼式的扩张，不断往外扩张，没有精耕细作，企业获得融资后的单位产出率很低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么我们的指数没有成长？很重要一个原因，还是要回到我刚才说的那两个漏洞，特别是第一个漏洞即减持规则对成长带来了巨大的抑制作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中国股市&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;何以&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;尚不成熟&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们的资本市场发展已经超过了30年，三十而立，它能算是一个成熟的市场吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中国资本市场在实践中在改革中慢慢找到了基本方向，但还是一个不成熟的市场。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个不成熟之处在于制度设计上的漏洞比较多。第二个不成熟之处在于始终没有深刻理解资本市场对中国意味着什么，对金融改革意味着什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去我们常说设立股市的主要目的是便利企业融资，这是不正确的定位和认知。证券市场表象上是融资，实际上是投资。你没有投资功能的不断加强，融资是难以为继的，人家用脚投票会走的。走了还融什么资？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，我们要把中国资本市场从为企业融资提供便利，定位于融资的市场，转变成为投资者的财富管理平台和投资的市场。由融资市场转变为投资市场，这是我们未来的方向。实现这个目标要有一个较长的时间。制度效应要发挥作用，相应的制度安排出台也需要时间。我们现在的制度安排正在堵漏洞，正在向这方面靠近。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A股牛短熊长，主要问题也是制度设计漏洞和没有真正理解资本市场对金融改革的意义？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;造成中国资本市场有这种现象，既有深厚的文化和法律背景，也有中观层次上规则的错位，比如之前提到的股权分置改革和注册制改革出现的两个漏洞。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然也有部分原因是我们的企业家并没有深刻理解上市对他们意味着什么。本来上市是手段，但这些企业创始人突然发现原来上市能这么容易发财，比他辛辛苦苦做实体经济容易得多，这就腐蚀了他们过去的创业初心。他就会把上市作为目的，实体经济也不做了，想个办法赶紧套现走人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要纠正这个错误导向，只有通过制度改革去引导——只有把企业做好，你才能够套现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对此你有哪些具体建议？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;要实现资本市场功能与导向的根本转型，首先是整体宏观制度设计的转型。在资产供给端方面，制度设计要有利于市场功能的转型，有利于把有透明度和成长性的资产引入市场，有利于吸引越来越多的新增投资者，新增资金进入市场。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，我们应该对所有上市前的股东减持股份有一定的约束，特别是对控股股东、实控人，包括二股东、三股东等等，怎么用财务指标约束减持，要有创新的制度设计，要让所有的股东把注意力、努力放在如何把公司做好、创造利润、提高分配上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，我们要持续改善资本市场的生态环境，无论是机构投资者还是个人投资者，在这个市场中，可以获得与其风险相匹配的收益，市场才会成长起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;股市持续不向好，需要我们拿出正确的应对办法&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;中央7月末明确提出要“活跃资本市场”，这释放了什么信号？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;应该说监管层看到了问题所在。中国没有一个领域能像资本市场涉及范围如此之大。资本市场至少有2亿投资者，背后可能就是2亿个家庭，差不多中国有一半人与资本市场有关系。第二，全球资本市场虽然都经过了疫情，但主要经济体中中国的资本市场表现不好。我们要更加重视其背后反映的问题。第三，活跃资本市场，也是提振市场信心的重要举措。需要我们拿出正确的应对办法。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对于活跃资本市场，也有不少专家提议A股从T+1切换到T+0。但监管机构一直说机会不成熟。你怎么看？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴晓求：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;交易上的改革没有实质意义，T+0无益于市场的成长， T+0改革的逻辑基础不清楚。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是T+0的最大利好给了证券公司，T+0会直接导致券商佣金的增加，由此带动券商股的上涨。而我们改革目标不是让券商风生水起，活跃资本市场的本意也不是佣金的增加，佣金增加反而意味着资本市场资金的漏出。至于有些人所说T+0对市场价格有纠错机制，我认为还需要多做实证研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是T+1为基础的交易规则是在中国资本市场诞生初期，在交易规则多次试错的背景下作出的选择，历经三十多年实践已经非常成熟，更适合中国国情。我非常喜欢T+1制度。上午买的股票，为什么一定下午就要卖呢？既然下午要卖，那你上午就别买。逻辑是很清楚的。如果说买错了，那明天卖也是一样的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，T+1制度也不是中国独有，国际上也是很成熟的。不见得有些国家用T+0，我们也用。从我个人来说，不太喜欢T+0，因为这个制度会把人们搞得癫狂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末：你对中国股市有信心吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴晓求:中国股市好起来的前提是中国经济要好起来。我一直说中国经济只要想搞好，是一定能搞好的。从本质上说，中国经济基础是好的。只要发挥市场的主导作用，适应历史的趋势，遵守市场规律，尊重企业和企业家精神，推动改革开放，走市场经济之路，中国经济就一定能搞好，怎么可能搞不好？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当下中国经济的问题，主要不是周期性因素带来的。我一直坚信，只要把过去45年改革开放中被证明是成功的经验坚持下去，进一步完善，中国经济就能继续保持良好趋势，中国资本市场也就有了成长基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部：已缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259195]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在今天（24日）上午国务院新闻办公室的举行“权威部门话开局”系列主题新闻发布会上，公安部有关负责人介绍，今年8月以来，全国电信网络诈骗案件发案数、造成财产损失数同比分别下降24%、20.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照公安部统一部署，各地公安机关持续强化打击力度，深入开展“云剑”“断卡”“断流”“拔钉”等专项行动，截至今年9月底，缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名；联合最高人民检察院挂牌督办一批重大案件，公开曝光一批典型案例；围绕境内打击，持续组织开展区域会战、专案攻坚、集群战役，密切与各部门协作配合，严厉打击引流推广、转账洗钱、技术开发等犯罪团伙，坚决切断犯罪关键链条，坚决遏制电信网络诈骗犯罪高发态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部坚持关口前移、防范为先，采取多种防范措施，最大限度预防案件发生。指导各地公安机关建立分级分类预警劝阻机制，推动“厦门经验”在全国落地生效。今年以来，累计向各地推送预警指令3.1亿条，各地自主产出预警信息1.3亿条；会同工业和信息化部建成12381涉诈预警劝阻短信系统，累计发送预警提示短信、闪信6.4亿条；会同中央网信办建设推广国家反诈中心App，累计预警提示1578.5万次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部联合中央宣传部开展主题为“预警劝阻别忽视，财产安全要重视”的“全民反诈在行动”集中宣传月活动。其间，国家反诈中心发布《2023版防范电信网络诈骗宣传手册》；会同相关行业主管部门督促金融机构、电信业务经营者、互联网服务提供者对本行业从业人员及服务对象深入开展反诈宣传；联合中国老龄协会举办全国老年人防诈反诈知识竞赛；联合教育部启动“反诈宣传进校园”活动；联合中国电影集团在全国农村地区和中小学校园组织反诈优秀影片公益展映活动，持续掀起全民反诈、全社会反诈的新热潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>