<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[剁碎新鲜白菜凑厨余垃圾，涉事企业：正在整改]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259867]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小学老师因不堪非教育负担而自杀：当减轻乃至消除老师的非教育任务负担]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259877]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The suicide of a primary school teacher attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lv, a female teacher at Jianxing Road Primary School in Guancheng District, Zhengzhou City, left a suicide note with the completion time marked at 23:44 on October 26. The suicide note said: Mom, I&#39;m sorry, I really can&#39;t hold it on anymore... I feel like I can&#39;t breathe. I never thought that being a primary school teacher would be so difficult... School work, school activities, and leadership inspections make us graduates who directly become class teachers without training feel like we are in a cage, and the cage is shrinking little by little. We go to work every day with our last breath in mind. When can teachers only do the job of teaching and educating people? How can unhappy teachers teach positive and optimistic children? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lv is only 23 years old this year. He was admitted to the school in August to teach and serve as a class teacher. He has a &quot;normally cheerful personality&quot; and is in the best years of his life. What a tragedy for her family who loved her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, this incident has sounded a wake-up call for us. We must care and pay attention to our family members, especially their mental state and values. We should relax as a family regularly, have heart-to-heart conversations, and tell each other’s confusions. and weakness: If some problems can be solved, then help solve them; if some problems cannot be solved, then at least relieve the pressure. The &quot;normally cheerful personality&quot; may be true, or it may be that he forced himself to perform in order not to worry his family and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers within the system are regarded by many as &quot;iron rice bowls&quot;. They have a system and have a good social status, but in turn they may become barriers that restrict people: many people have passed the teacher certification examination, but find that they are not actually qualified. If you don&#39;t like or are not suitable for this job, and you don&#39;t dare to resign and look for another job, you are often worried that your family or outsiders will not understand you, and you feel that you do not cherish this hard-won opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only you know whether your shoes fit or not. Here, I would like to advise everyone, no matter what profession you are engaged in, you should respect your own intuitive feelings and don&#39;t care too much about other people&#39;s opinions. When it&#39;s time to change the track, change the track, and spend your life on meaningful and worthwhile things; holding on for dear life will only lead to greater and greater mental internal friction, consuming and annihilating your own vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, this matter will inevitably lead to a question: Don’t teachers only have a few classes a day and two three-month vacations in winter and summer every year? Isn’t it enough to be admitted to the teacher establishment? &quot;Going ashore&quot; can we not work so hard or even lie down? Why are we so busy and tired? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technically, this can be described as the dark side brought about by the popularity of smartphones and instant messaging tools. Various WeChat home-school groups and DingTalk groups allow the will of schools and teachers to reach every family and every parent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, the function of the home-school group was just that schools and teachers forwarded various educational tasks to parents, asking parents to help their children prepare for classes, check their children&#39;s homework, etc. This forced parents to invest time and resources. Go into your child’s learning. To a certain extent, the teacher is the leader of the home-school group. Their children are in the hands of the school and the teacher. How many parents dare to publicly refuse to cooperate? There is also competition among parents to please the teacher or at least not to offend the teacher. The benefit of this approach to teachers is that teachers and schools still have certain KPI performance, and parents’ input helps them achieve KPIs, so schools and teachers have incentives to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, this trick will become known to some departments, and the routine of &quot;little hands holding big hands&quot; will be summarized, which is to press down through the chain of education system-school-teacher. Ask parents to cooperate in completing various non-educational tasks, as these departments also have their own KPIs. As time goes by, more and more departments are found to be able to do this. Various non-educational tasks are handed down to parents through this chain, and occupy more and more time of schools and teachers. Parents Although it was unpleasant, the school and teachers also felt uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above sense, through home-school clusters, schools have become the third grassroots governance organization besides village committees and neighborhood committees. Each department has penetrated the tentacles of power into every student through the school-teacher transmission link. Families, and the frequency and intensity of intervention far exceed that of village committees and neighborhood committees. You may wish to recall, how many times can you interact with the village committee or neighborhood committee in a year? Many people may not even have one. But whenever you have children in primary or secondary school, you often have to complete non-educational tasks for your children that are communicated to you through the school-teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, other government departments will also second teachers to do various non-educational work offline. After all, teachers are public officials within the system and are more or less dependent on local finance, so they are easier to dispatch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Sanlian Life Weekly&quot; once published an article &quot;&quot;Squeezed out&quot; to have a teacher establishment, they regret it. The article interviewed Zhang Xiaohui, a primary school teacher born in the 1990s. She said: She was When I am a primary school teacher or head teacher, only 30% of my job is teaching, and the other 70% is social tasks. Another interviewee said: As a class teacher, you not only have to teach classes, but you also have to arrange class activities and class meetings, and connect with local communities, hospitals, fire stations, transportation bureaus and other government agencies. You will even be called up by the school leaders at two o&#39;clock in the morning. Volunteering and these heavy tasks made her feel physically and mentally exhausted, which was contrary to her original intention of becoming a teacher, so she chose to resign. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in order to reduce or even eliminate the burden of various non-educational tasks faced by schools and teachers, there are strategies to reduce the salary under the kettle. The first is to forcibly disband various home-school groups. Unless students get into trouble or get hurt at school, schools and teachers are not allowed to contact parents. In this way, various educational and non-educational burdens on parents can be eliminated at once, which is conducive to the normalization and harmony of home-school relations; schools and teachers may also be exempted from various online non-educational tasks. Second, it is explicitly ordered that other government departments shall not use teachers as temporary workers or use them for free as temporary workers. In short, a two-pronged approach will reduce the non-educational burden on teachers both online and offline, so that teachers can concentrate on teaching and educating people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[加沙的地道恐怕挡不住以色列的进攻丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259856]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/Erv2zTeF7MZqh7v93zNuSduQSLAT2P9rV1UjDIR9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Erv2zTeF7MZqh7v93zNuSduQSLAT2 P9rV1UjDIR9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 28, 2023, at the Israeli-Gaza border, the Israeli army fired artillery shells into the Gaza Strip &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Israeli-Palestinian conflict that has lasted for three weeks has entered a new stage, and Israel has begun to continuously launch attacks on the Gaza region Launch a ground attack. Major General Hagari of the Israel Defense Forces told the media that the Israeli ground forces are &quot;expanding the scope of their activities&quot; and &quot;taking vigorous actions... to achieve war goals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a video released by the Israel Defense Forces, a group of Merkava tanks can be seen running through the flat, open sand of Gaza, attacking distant buildings with their main guns. Hamas also confirmed that it was engaged in ground combat with the Israel Defense Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as predicted in my previous column, Israel’s ground operations will not involve large-scale penetration and encirclement, but will continue to slowly encroach from the edge with very cautious actions. Obviously, Israel is very aware that Hamas&#39;s army has established a very strong underground network inside Gaza. It will be a defense system full of death traps, just like the Japanese army prepared for the US Marines in the Battle of Iwo Jima. Those death potholes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To directly attack such an area, Israel may pay heavy casualties, which is of course the result Hamas hopes for. Does Israel have a way to deal with this authentic meat grinder that has been operating for many years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, compared with the era of the Battle of Iwo Jima, technological advancements have allowed today&#39;s military to use some new technological means to detect the underground world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is thermal imaging technology, which has been widely used in tunnel detection. Although the tunnel itself does not emit infrared signals, ventilation equipment must be installed in large tunnels to prevent people inside from being suffocated. At present, Israel has cut off the power supply to Gaza. Such ventilation equipment can only rely on its own generators to maintain operation. These generators and the vents of underground passages will be an identifiable thermal imaging signal. During peacetime, Hamas can still cover thermal imaging signals through some buildings and temporary facilities. However, once war breaks out, Israel will continue to destroy those ground buildings, forcing the exposure of heat sources such as vents and power generation equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another common tunnel detection method is synthetic aperture radar. This type of radar has the ability to detect underground metal objects at a certain depth, and can even detect the depth and position of underground tunnels. In 2021, the U.S. Army announced a new technology that can generate three-dimensional images of underground bunkers by simply comparing the images generated by synthetic aperture radar twice through an algorithm. Platforms including satellites, dedicated ground surveillance aircraft and drones can be equipped with synthetic aperture radar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also an advanced technology that has received high hopes in recent years, namely hyperspectral imaging reconnaissance. Hyperspectral detection equipment is an imaging method that can distinguish extremely subtle changes on the surface of objects. Different soil media, water flows and even air fluctuations can be imaged in front of hyperspectral imaging equipment. This method has been widely used in minerals and water resources. aviation wide area detection. In the military, this imaging technology can also be used to discover the opponent&#39;s bunkers, mines and hidden military forces. In recent years, hyperspectral imaging cameras have been integrated into drones and satellites. Israel has also done considerable research in this area and is at the leading level in the industry in several research directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that an almost science-fiction technology was also used in this conflict, that is, muon imaging technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1936, humans discovered the existence of a type of ray called muons in the universe, which can penetrate various materials including hard granite and marble. In recent years, with the advancement of particle mechanics, humans have discovered that the penetration properties of muons can be used to image the interior of objects. The principle is the same as X-ray photography. Nowadays, muon photography technology is widely used in engineering, geological observation and archaeological activities, such as detecting the direction of magma inside volcanoes or observing the internal structure of pyramids. Even after the Fukushima nuclear power plant accident, muon cameras were also used Find out what&#39;s going on inside the Fukushima Nuclear Power Plant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, muon imaging technology has rarely been used for military purposes in the past. The main reason is that this technology requires sensors to be deployed in at least two directions of the object being detected, otherwise imaging cannot be performed. Military facilities are often underground, and aerial reconnaissance alone cannot meet imaging conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the tunnels in the Gaza Strip are qualified for the use of muon imaging technology, because this is a small area, and Israel almost surrounds the Gaza area from three sides, allowing muon photography to be deployed in multiple directions. As for the conditions of the equipment, since this technology has been widely used in other fields, it can basically be used immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more technical reconnaissance methods on the battlefield, the better. In addition to obtaining means, the ability to comprehensively analyze and utilize reconnaissance results is also crucial. With the advancement of human science and technology, although underground bunkers have a certain degree of concealment, they are no longer impenetrable. With all technical means overwhelming them, tunnel combat alone may not be able to withstand the opponent&#39;s attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报网传抢中药事件 :村民误认为收割完毕遂进场捡拾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 11:32:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Agricultural and Rural Affairs Bureau of Zhoukou Huaiyang District issued a situation report on November 1:&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the afternoon of October 31, Qiu, a medicinal planter in Fengtang Township, Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City, Henan Province, was two-thirds of the way through the second harvest of Atractylodes macrocephala. Fault. The nearby villagers mistakenly thought that the grower had completed the second harvest, so they went into the field to pick up medicinal materials (after the second harvest of medicinal materials was completed, it has been a habit for many years for the growers to allow villagers to go to the field to pick up the leftover medicinal materials). After the growers tried to dissuade them to no avail. The police were called, and police from the local police station quickly arrived at the scene and persuaded the people to leave. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, our bureau will further strengthen the service and management of agriculture, rural areas and farmers, and effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of farmers and growers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0reZZbJvE7oiWSg0YTpVwKDlyjqmVtlnW4PGw59H.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;828&quot; height= &quot;555&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0reZZbJvE7oiWSg0YTpVwKDlyjqmVtlnW4PGw59H.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[空荡荡的国美总部，时间仿佛停留在上一个圣诞 丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259873]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 10:53:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In mid-October 2023, on the lottery page of Gome App, there were messages targeting Gome founder Huang Guangyu and current Gome Chairman Huang Xiuhong’s pop-up window included “wage arrears and payment arrears”, which attracted great attention from the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, problems such as wage arrears at Gome have already emerged as early as 2022. This company was founded in 1987 and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange in 2004. Its founder Huang Guangyu has been ranked as the richest man in mainland China on the Hurun Report three times. However, he was arrested by the police for suspected economic crimes in 2008 and will serve his sentence in February 2021. Get out of jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is happening in Gome now? After losing nearly 90% of its employees, what is left of Gome now? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With these questions in mind, on the morning of Monday, October 30, Southern Weekend reporters came to the Pengrun Building at No. 26 Xiaoyun Road, East Third Ring Road, Beijing, where the headquarters of Gome is located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/K5p3Bh6rY2sHICU8ofsDuW4qOqbhvB1f8WFvxvup.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/K5p3Bh6rY2sHICU8ofsDuW4qOqbhvB1f8WFvxvup.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pengrun Building was once the The top-level office building with the largest single area in Asia is located in Beijing, close to the Embassy District and Chaoyang Park. This is also the headquarters of Gome Electrical Appliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the sign at the front of the building, Tower B also includes Beijing Gome International Wine Trading Co., Ltd., Gome Holding Group Recruitment Management Center/Training Development Center, Gome Real Estate Holdings Co., Ltd., Gome Holding Group Co., Ltd., etc. But more companies have been removed from the signs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A resigned employee told a reporter from Southern Weekend, “The previous signboards were filled with numerous Gome companies.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/jmTRW45oYNfZihJzuY0Qnw9gnZE4DVJcgy8cqsC0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/03/jmTRW45oYNfZihJzuY0Qnw9gnZE4DVJcgy8cqsC0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest feeling when walking into the Gome headquarters is that it is &quot;empty&quot;, with only a few staff and cleaning staff. Seeing the stranger, no one came forward to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/7UkPZdL7sDW5NZkI4xwmZrSUZaQ41Ck0LoIcycDA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/7UkPZdL7sDW5NZkI4xwmZrSUZaQ41Ck0LoIcycDA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inside Gome, large and small The conference rooms, office areas, and reception rooms are all locked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 18th floor of Pengrun Building was once the place where the entire Gome received merchants and suppliers. There is no staff at the front desk now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/fjQLFxPGN4uPa7nNsGKEHOzzigLRYFzQhFlp9jia.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/fjQLFxPGN4uPa7nNsGKEHOzzigLRYFzQhFlp9jia.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the publicity room of Gome Group , densely packed with various certificates and trophies of Huang Guangyu and other company executives in the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ikXXnLPpmDJ9eag3ajTjqAn7XYSdvigRL6PFkfaL.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ikXXnLPpmDJ9eag3ajTjqAn7XYSdvigRL6PFkfaL.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/y0wyUhGJj5CLbTNALCNN32p1q3Q0xBQ275M1EAY7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/y0wyUhGJj5CLbTNALCNN32p1q3Q0xBQ275M1EAY7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employee&#39;s workstation was described by the resigned employee as once &quot;full of pits and valleys for American Americans&quot; , is now largely vacant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/LuDk4NJp90wzMcygz39J1kWhkPQHcfUl8NKEETFW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/LuDk4NJp90wzMcygz39J1kWhkPQHcfUl8NKEETFW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/Wu9kLvjWhHMxGM3rwhvlPMr6YPXPVuQKqu2Ofkhi.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/Wu9kLvjWhHMxGM3rwhvlPMr6YPXPVuQKqu2Ofkhi.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The traces of Gome employees’ past work and life still exist, but now, most of them have left here Facing the dilemma of unpaid wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/U03etLPl6TwRka0fkjmYFwWopb4k7wTSD3OlX1PB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/U03etLPl6TwRka0fkjmYFwWopb4k7wTSD3OlX1PB.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/yf2aXZHKncMy0hiXEnN3UINDg1NDlMNz2fBXRso4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/yf2aXZHKncMy0hiXEnN3UINDg1NDlMNz2fBXRso4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Huang Guangyu was released from prison, he had high hopes for the &quot;True Happiness&quot; App and invested heavily in it . Today, traces of True Joy remain in the building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/7rJDR9zJqBZQjtyAxyJPsS6tqYxFUxTIZQxJt09k.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/7rJDR9zJqBZQjtyAxyJPsS6tqYxFUxTIZQxJt09k.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/YuS01msDL9rQbfJZNWTbJ1XVu6iqrm2zgj1hdw63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/YuS01msDL9rQbfJZNWTbJ1XVu6iqrm2zgj1hdw63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/03/8vOYQplTwaEyIfRyiVkMGYh8gm2Eh3O6BO9zcYQE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 03/8vOYQplTwaEyIfRyiVkMGYh8gm2Eh3O6BO9zcYQE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(South Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, time seems to have stopped at the last Christmas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/9T4dA4sbb8xR6QTOHz0dN7MZZtXZ3X7ziHSKatG1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/9T4dA4sbb8xR6QTOHz0dN7MZZtXZ3X7ziHSKatG1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/39qV2lpb2xN3ZTiVQn2e3bPlfBhuMf9WsKIqc9ew.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/39qV2lpb2xN3ZTiVQn2e3bPlfBhuMf9WsKIqc9ew.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(pictured above) All photos taken by Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“男子炫耀在市中心养烈性犬”：何人能如此横行猖狂？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259840]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;a man showed off keeping a vicious dog in the city center&quot;, which attracted attention. A netizen named &quot;Taishan McDull Button&quot; posted on multiple platforms to show off that he was raising three large Canary dogs in a community in Lixia District, located in the center of Jinan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenshots of the man in question&#39;s social media show that in August 2021, he posted a post with a picture saying, &quot;The dog scared the pregnant woman. I also beat the pregnant woman and she stayed at the police station until 11 o&#39;clock&quot;; In January 2022, he posted another article saying, &quot;To commemorate the first snowfall in 2022, the brother and sister bit the Shiba Inu in the community to pieces.&quot; In February 2022, his accompanying picture showed that the dog he raised Large dogs eat under the &quot;Civilized Dog Raising, Scientific Dog Raising&quot; banner set up at the Wenhua East Road Police Station of the Lixia Branch of the Jinan Municipal Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since October 2023, the man&#39;s social media has turned to showing off his wealth and power, and has continuously posted &quot;(Three dogs) go out in luxury cars, stay in star hotels, and go out to eat.&quot; hotel&quot;, &quot;a day&#39;s foster care fee is higher than your salary as an office worker&quot; and other content to show off their wealth. On October 24, the man involved posted a video of a policeman knocking on the door with tools, with the text saying, &quot;You check yours and I&#39;ll take care of mine. If you have the ability, you can tear down my door and come in to arrest me.&quot; On October 25, the man involved released the surveillance video again and sarcastically said, &quot;I really worked hard to catch the dog, hahahahaha.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interaction with netizens, the man in question said, &quot;I go out every day, and I can sneak away as I please.&quot; The image of &quot;abundant&quot; and &quot;monstrous power&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident spread online, on the evening of October 30, the Lixia District Public Security Bureau of Jinan issued a notice stating that a man who had recently been rumored on the Internet to &quot;show off raising prohibited dogs&quot; had been administratively detained. &quot;Beating pregnant women&quot; and &quot;you check yours and I&#39;ll keep mine&quot; are all false information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two administrative penalty decisions issued by Jinan police also showed that the man’s behavior constituted illegal dog breeding. He surrendered on October 28 and was fined a total of 3,900 yuan; the man’s release The video &quot;The police don&#39;t dare to arrest me even when they come to my door&quot; is a stolen photo of the police investigating and punishing other people&#39;s illegal dog-raising, and then plagiarized it and put it on his own account to boast that he &quot;lacks respect for the law and openly challenges the bottom line of the law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The timeline of this case shows that the man involved has been doing this for many years and is divided into two parts: offline and online. The current report has not fully answered netizens&#39; questions, and there are still some areas left to be analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first thing to ask is, is the &quot;power and power&quot; that the man in question flaunted true? Judging from the social media content of the man in question, he clearly has the image of a wealthy young man who is either rich or noble. The pictures distributed also imply that he has a certain &quot;background&quot; and is an existence that others &quot;cannot mess with&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man in question has repeatedly posted content about his participation in activities within the system, and has also shown his status as &quot;military first.&quot; The Jinan police’s administrative penalty decision also showed that the man involved was affiliated with the Material Management Office of a military region hospital. If the man in question really has some kind of &quot;identity within the system,&quot; his employer should express its condemnation and cut him off. And if the identities the man in question brags about are fabricated, then what he says and does is also suspected of committing a crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Military hospital staff are national staff in a broad sense. According to Article 279 of the Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, whoever pretends to be a staff member of a state agency and commits fraud, thereby constituting the crime of fraud, shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention, public surveillance, or deprivation of political rights; if the circumstances are serious, he shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years but not more than ten years. imprisonment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, according to the &quot;Red Star News&quot; report, the man in question has kept these three large dogs for many years. The property management, police, and community have come to communicate with them many times, but to no avail. This detail shows that the man in question did not keep large dogs illegally for a day or two, which seriously interfered with the lives of surrounding neighbors, but it was something that people could do nothing about. Combined with his arrogant words and deeds online, the man in question has been suspected of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, which &quot;seriously affects the work, life, production, and business of others.&quot; This is a plot worthy of further investigation by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police report showed that the man involved was dissatisfied with the regulations related to dog breeding, so he turned to provoke the public, and it took ten days to be brought to justice. I would like to ask, if the man in question did not &quot;blatantly challenge the bottom line of the law,&quot; do the surrounding neighbors still have to endure it? If you think about it further, if the man in question keeps a low profile online but remains arrogant offline, can he continue to be lawless? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only are dogs not civil subjects in the legal sense, but even their social attributes in the abstract sense are completely determined by the dog owner’s dog-raising behavior. The illegal behavior of the man in question was not just raising a large prohibited dog without a leash or muzzle, but also magnified the social harm of illegal dog ownership with his arrogant and domineering words and deeds. In addition to administrative penalties, public authorities should also conduct in-depth investigations and investigate the suspects for the crime of cheating and provoking troubles. While cracking down on illegal dog-raising, &quot;dogs fighting against human power&quot; should not be tolerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“我可以不恋爱，但我的CP一定要结婚”，为什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the spring of 2021, Xu Guanwen, born in 1998, began a new and unfamiliar research. At that time, he was still a graduate student at the School of Society and Demography at Renmin University of China. A course on qualitative research methods led him to set his sights on a costume drama called &quot;The Order of Mountains and Rivers&quot;. The relationship between the two protagonists in the play leaves room for the audience to imagine intimate emotions, attracting a large number of &quot;CP fans&quot; to stop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the East Asian cultural circle, the trend of &quot;consuming CP&quot; has been around for a long time. It first appeared in the ACGN (animation, comics, games, novels) circle and refers to pairing (Coupling) between two characters, referred to as &quot;CP&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, Xu Guanwen paid attention to this cultural form twice. The first time was in high school. My deskmate selected two male characters from the Japanese manga &quot;Kuroko&#39;s Basketball&quot; - Aomine Daiki and Kise Ryota, and wrote a CP &quot;fanfic&quot; for them. &quot;Aomine Daiki&#39;s character is aggressive, while Kise Ryota is more elegant and has a wild side inside. Their roles complement each other to a certain extent, and there are certain areas that can be explored.&quot; Although the article written by the same deskmate is only a fragment It&#39;s a sitcom, but Xu Guanwen can feel a &quot;strong emotional connection&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time was when he was an undergraduate student in sociology. He was chatting with his graduate student and found that the other party was doing research on &quot;Whether Danmei literature has an impact on real gay men&quot;. He realized that, Popular culture will be related to real-life emotional practices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, thinking of the two intersections with CP culture, Xu Guanwen was once again aroused his &quot;long-standing curiosity&quot;. He started with friends around him and conducted snowball interviews with 55 CP fans, including 53 women and 2 men. Most of the interviewers were surprised at first: Why would a boy who doesn’t take CP want to learn about this issue? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the few male CP fans is a fan of the female idol team AKB48. He thinks the members are beautiful and beautiful, so he takes up the team’s CP; the other is a gay man who lives in daily life. It is difficult to find a partner and intimate relationship that meets their expectations, so they look for male CPs in Japanese dramas to project their emotional needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to make the topic selection more focused, the interviews of two male CP fans were not included in the analysis. At the beginning of 2023, this paper titled &quot;&quot;CP-eating&quot;: Creative Emotional Experience of Young Female Fans&quot; was published in the &quot;Women&#39;s Studies Series&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was originally a routine survey, but in October 2023, the paper suddenly became popular. This paper, which is full of words such as &quot;childhood sweetheart&quot; and &quot;soul mate&quot;, was forwarded and liked on social media, attracting attention and ridicule from &quot;addict experts&quot;: &quot;The paper the professor asked me to read is my first name.&quot; No matter how long I put it off, I read the paper on CP addiction with gusto, and even cried while reading it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Search for the keyword &quot;CP&quot; on CNKI and sort by the number of downloads, &quot;&quot;CP&quot;: Creative Emotional Experience of Young Female Fans&quot; ranks first in the relevant literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An interviewer tried to give an answer as to why he is keen on taking CP: &quot;What I expect to see in CP is a kind of spiritual communication and soul resonance.&quot; In real life, marriage is Contracts, contractual relationships, and love are complex luxuries. In a world that is complex and open to multiple interpretations, CP is &quot;a relatively beautiful thing constructed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/IvZpDtwHvl2xSXb2GfD8IBDuhzTTM5Wwh2X6yfJY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/IvZpDtwHvl2xSXb2GfD8IBDuhzTTM5Wwh2X6yfJY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256605&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Different CP combinations often appear among the members of idol groups. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Some emotional needs are not satisfied in reality&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Xu Guanwen does not take CP and calls himself an &quot;outsider&quot;. His in-depth understanding of CP culture is limited to 55 interviewers. When studying the craze of “eating CP” on the Internet, he paid more attention to the emotional mechanism behind it. When collecting information and designing the interview outline, the question he wanted to discuss with these CP fans was: What is their imagination of this kind of love? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, his master&#39;s thesis is about to be started. He was inspired by French sociologist Eva Iroth&#39;s &quot;Love, Why Does It Hurt?&quot; 》Inspired by this, I want to do cultural research on love. Eva Iroth discusses in the book: People are changing partners more and more frequently and faster, and there is a set of changes in emotional concepts behind this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xu Guanwen&#39;s view, &quot;romantic love&quot; seems to be imported from China. &quot;During the Republic of China, it was an ideological tool to criticize feudalism and encourage women to escape from the feudal patriarchal system. Lu Xun wrote &quot;What Happened After Nora Left&quot; and found that women did escape from the patriarchal system, but fell into the small family system. In the family, we are still restricted by the male-dominated family concept.&quot; Xu Guanwen told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;In the 1970s and 1980s, we were exposed to a new round of Western literary and artistic works, such as &quot;Titanic&quot;, and everyone began to accept it again ( Freedom of marriage and love).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guanwen feels that since the concept of &quot;romantic love&quot; was introduced to China, it has assumed the role of rebelling against the current order, often running counter to economic rational decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following this line of thinking, he decided to include the love concepts of contemporary Chinese youth groups into his research. I looked around, but found that I couldn&#39;t find a suitable research object. By chance, he saw a topic: &quot;I don&#39;t have to fall in love, but my partner must get married.&quot; The most direct question jumped out: Why are they so happy to have a love relationship with their partner? Why do they like to watch others fall in love, but don’t fall in love themselves? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He found his old friend Q as his first interview subject. The two met in a corner of the cafeteria and chatted for three hours in a pleasant atmosphere. The CP circle pays attention to &quot;enclosure and self-admiration&quot;, which refers to entertaining oneself in one&#39;s own small circle. Even if the CPs are the same A and B, if the order is reversed (such as the &quot;AB&quot; party and the &quot;BA&quot; party), it is possible I can&#39;t go together. Q rarely has the opportunity to chat with his peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The CP that Q drank was a pair of male and female CPs in a certain boy group. Xu Guanwen initially thought that Q&#39;s boyfriend liked childish boys, but after in-depth conversation, he discovered that this was not the case. Q&#39;s boyfriend in real life was burly. The reason why Q likes this couple is that they don&#39;t deliberately maintain a sense of boundaries like adult men, but interact closely like children. &quot;That&#39;s the state of interpersonal interaction that she prefers. It&#39;s simple enough and the emotions are obvious enough.&quot; Xu Guanwen analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The encounter between a CP fan and CP may be an accident. She chose to learn more about it, possibly because there are certain qualities in CP that attracted her. She got emotional feedback at that moment, Therefore, she is positive and happy at the moment. As she gradually learns more about CP, the underlying things slowly emerge. What really induces this kind of emotional feedback is that certain emotional needs are not met in reality. .&quot; Xu Guanwen told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after chasing for several years, the couple finally &quot;be&quot; (bad ending, tragic ending). As the two grew older, Q watched the latest variety shows and found that their interaction became unnatural. &quot;The sense of boundary is very obvious. Even if you don&#39;t realize it, your body&#39;s reaction is very obvious.&quot; Q couldn&#39;t let go of it for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interviewees had different reasons for taking CP. Some people are frustrated by love in real life and heal their wounds in the relatively ideal and flawless CP world; some people feel stressed in real life and escape to the CP world to vent their emotions. There are also people who have a spectator mentality. In real life, love or marriage always makes people worry about gains and losses, and taking CP can make people objectively look at the emotional direction of a CP couple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are still times when taking CP is just &quot;interesting&quot;. There are various unexpected combinations of protagonists from characters to actors, from reality to virtuality, from contemporary times to history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On video websites, Jia Ling was paired up with various male stars and edited into CP videos. Daiyu and Voldemort are also favored by netizens and are paired up as contrasting characters. Xu Guanwen interviewed a girl who was a fan of Voltaire and Rousseau. The outside world often feels that these two people have different opinions and are lifelong enemies. This girl feels that there is room for further interpretation behind the historicized relationship. &quot;The antonym of enemy is friend. Are there other possibilities (for the relationship between the two)? For example, falling in love and killing each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/02/Ibo0RTSbVtuQnLkTBpD8F4EdP3EjktaCh8wRcytR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1797&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/02/Ibo0RTSbVtuQnLkTBpD8F4EdP3EjktaCh8wRcytR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256606&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The two protagonists of the costume drama &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; It has become the target of many fans to &quot;eat CP&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;You can live without love, but you cannot live without love&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;When many people take CP, they first feel the impromptu and plump happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guanwen analyzed that behind this kind of immediate happiness, there is not only aesthetic satisfaction, but also the satisfaction of the demand gap of the current emotional state. Of course, some people put their own expectations for intimate relationships into it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(This expectation) has been very concretely presented in CP. With continuous immersion, the concrete image changes from fuzzy to three-dimensional, so that happiness can continue. Because you can continue to explore , form your own understanding, and experience happiness in the process of exploration.&quot; Xu Guanwen told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After interviewing 55 CP fans, Xu Guanwen found that the CP emotions that many people actively explore overflow the framework of conventional social life. One of Xu Guanwen&#39;s interviewers drank the CP of two male members of a Korean boy band, but he did not define the intimate relationship between the two as &quot;romantic love&quot;, but the Japanese word &quot;bond&quot;, which expresses a kind of &quot;friend or above&quot;. The emotion of “love is not full”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The couple grew up together, and were both under 20 years old when the team was formed. This interviewer grew up in a Tongzilou, a group of children who spent their childhood playing around, and shared a similar background to her CP. &quot;She said that she took advantage of this couple because she and her (young) friend were separated by two places and could not meet each other. The kind of family-like connection she expected was seen in CP.&quot; Xu Guanwen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guanwen paid attention to the comments on social media and found that many people were moved by the interviewer&#39;s words: &quot;You can live without love, but you cannot live without love.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Just like Henry Jenkins As said, the popularity of CP culture itself has a reflection on heterosexual romantic narratives. CP fans are no longer satisfied with the old romantic narratives, but hope to discover unique emotional connections.&quot; Xu Guanwen wrote in the paper . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a male, Xu Guanwen also discovered some gender differences in his research: when female CP fans romanticize male and female CPs, they often regard holding hands, hugging, etc. as evidence of the intimacy between the two. . Xu Guanwen believes that this is typical female thinking. In fact, boys and girls have different sense of boundaries when expressing closeness to the same sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Differentiated emotional models present a complex and complex ecological landscape in the CP world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You will see that CP culture itself is like a small society, with a very avant-garde side and a very conservative side.” Xu Guanwen told Southern Weekend reporters, “In Danmei CP fan works, maybe There will be some very avant-garde explorations of gender. The conservative side may be that I only consume heterosexual CP and follow the biggest mainstream (society).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The CP world is like a diverse and diverse world. There is a free emotional market, and whether this market can affect emotional practice in reality, Xu Guanwen&#39;s investigation failed to give an answer. &quot;The reality I face, and how much freedom I have to make my own (emotional) practices, varies from person to person.&quot; Xu Guanwen said, &quot;But in general, it is happy first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“刘忠林”案代理律师被控三宗罪，一审获刑16年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259844]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/mrRGzBS9fSCrOw1lSmD0jdnd5PFaXElNGDvrONZ2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;742&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/mrRGzBS9fSCrOw1lSmD0jdnd5PFaXElNGD vrONZ2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256790&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Fengman District Court of Jilin City issued a guilty verdict against Xiu Bao. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiu Bao, who is well-known in the legal circles of Jilin City, Jilin Province, may not have thought that he would also &quot;cry out injustice&quot; for himself &quot;One day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Xiu Bao was the director of a law firm, president of the Jilin Lawyers Association, and vice president of the Jilin Provincial Lawyers Association. He served as a deputy to the provincial People&#39;s Congress and was once selected as a candidate for Touching China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;It is worth mentioning that Xiubao was still the defender during the retrial of Liu Zhonglin’s case. Liu Zhonglin was sentenced to death with a suspended death sentence for intentional homicide and was imprisoned for 25 years and 3 months. He is the longest-term unjust person who has been detained for the longest period of time in public reports. In April 2018, the Jilin Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court changed the verdict and found Liu Zhonglin not guilty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Xiubao was found guilty of introducing bribes, offering bribes and fraud in two cases he had represented, and was sentenced to 16 years in prison in the first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unsatisfied with the warranty, he appealed to the Jilin Intermediate Court on July 17, 2023. According to Southern Weekend reporters, the warranty repair case file was returned from the Jilin City Procuratorate to the Jilin City Intermediate Court on September 18, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the relevant provisions of the Criminal Procedure Law, the second instance court should promptly notify the procuratorate to review the case files after deciding to open a trial. The procuratorate shall complete the review within one month. The procuratorate&#39;s review time is not included in the trial period. The people&#39;s court of second instance that accepts appeals and protest cases shall conclude the proceedings within two months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that the trial deadline for this case is November 18, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Acting bribery case of acting department official was accused of intermediary bribery&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 68-year-old Xiubao had many auras before he lost his personal freedom. &lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that he has been working as a lawyer since 1988, and later founded Jilin Baomin Law Firm and served as director. Xiubao has won many honors such as &quot;National Advanced Legal Aid Individual&quot; and &quot;National Outstanding Lawyer&quot;. In 2011, he was selected as a candidate for Touching China. In the legal profession of Jilin Province, he is the first deputy to the Provincial People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiu Bao&#39;s personal deeds have also been frequently reported in newspapers, and he has been called a &quot;civilian lawyer&quot; and &quot;workers&#39; lawyer&quot; by the media. According to People&#39;s Daily Online in 2019, Xiubao has long helped laid-off workers and vulnerable groups safeguard their rights. It has represented more than 400 lawsuits for free in cases involving farmers infected with HIV and other people in need, and has recovered nearly 30,000 laid-off workers and vulnerable groups in accordance with the law. With 200 million yuan in compensation (compensation) and social security pensions, dozens of unjust, false and wrong cases were corrected, and 13 people who were wrongly imprisoned were acquitted, including Liu Zhonglin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years after Liu Zhonglin was released, on January 24, 2022, because he was suspected of committing bribery and bribery, the Huadian City Supervisory Committee, which was managed by Jilin City, took detention measures. He was suspected of committing fraud and was criminally detained by the Panshi City Public Security Bureau of Jilin Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The repair and maintenance investigation was related to the bribery case of the first department official of Jilin Province whom we had previously represented. In September 2017, Liu Baowei, chairman of Jilin Provincial Investment Group Co., Ltd. and former secretary of the Tonghua Municipal Party Committee, was investigated. Later, in October 2018, he was prosecuted by the Jilin City Procuratorate on suspicion of accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, Xiu Bao served as Liu Baowei&#39;s attorney, and was therefore accused of introducing bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the Fengman District Court of Jilin City ([2023] Ji 0211 Xingchu No. 10) shows that the Procuratorate of Fengman District, Jilin City believed that in April 2018, Xiu Bao took advantage of the then deputy director of the Jilin Intermediate People’s Court. Due to his position, Dean Feng Qisheng asked Liu Baowei&#39;s family to contact Feng Qisheng&#39;s wife Tan Xuemei and pay a &quot;favor fee&quot; of 600,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first-instance verdict, Feng Qisheng admitted that when he was the presiding judge of Liu Baowei&#39;s case, he introduced Liu Baowei&#39;s relatives to give Tan Xuemei 600,000 yuan in favors in order to get a lighter sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Qisheng was dismissed from public office in July 2022 due to serious violations of discipline and law. His suspected criminal issues were transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from relevant parties that Feng Qisheng was sentenced to 11 years in prison by the Dongchang District Court of Tonghua City in December 2022. His wife Tan Xuemei took 5.93 million in bribes and was sentenced to 3 years in prison with a 4-year suspended sentence by the Fengman District Court in Jilin City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the case of Feng and Tan, Xiu Bao was also implicated. On December 29, 2022, the Procuratorate of Fengman District, Jilin City filed a public prosecution against Xiubao. After the Jilin City Intermediate Court designated jurisdiction, the Fengman District Court opened the case and accepted it on January 11, 2023, and a public hearing was held on March 30 of the same year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 6, 2023, the Fengman District Court made a first-instance judgment, and Xiubao’s behavior in this case was found to be the crime of bribery and the crime of introduction of bribery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the repair party insisted that it was not guilty. Xiu Bao&#39;s attorney believes that the evidence in the case cannot confirm that Liu Baowei&#39;s family paid a bribe of 600,000 yuan to Tan Xuemei. Xiu Bao has no motive for bribery and has no request for Tan Xuemei, which does not meet the standard of proof for conviction. Xiu Bao&#39;s son Xiu Zhiyu said that Xiu Bao and Feng Qisheng often argued about cases in public and were not familiar with each other in private, &quot;and Tan Xuemei is also a practicing lawyer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The crime of fraud in &quot;the money is scattered and people return&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the first instance judgment, Xiubao was also found guilty of fraud. Related to a corruption and bribery case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Procuratorate of Fengman District, Jilin City believes that from January to June 2019, Xiu Bao was entrusted by Luo to serve as the defender for her husband Yao Moulin&#39;s suspected corruption case, and Xiu Bao fabricated the need for Yao Moulin to be sentenced to probation. Luo then transferred money to his friend Cao, who later paid 1.6 million yuan in cash to the repair agent in person in three installments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, the Fengman District Court held that when Xiu Bao met Yao Moulin at the Jilin City Detention Center, he asked him to write a note to Luo Mou, telling Luo Mou &quot;Don&#39;t feel bad about money, money.&quot; It’s a benefit for the forensic investigators.” The note said, “The money has been scattered and everyone will return.” “It’s time to spend money. It is estimated that it may cost 2 million (ten thousand) to 4 million (ten thousand). You can decide the specific situation.” Later, Xiubao found Cao and lied that he wanted to smoothen the relationship so that Luo could get the money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the presiding judge and the judge who tried Yao Moulin’s corruption case both testified that in Yao Moulin’s case, Xiubao did not bribe the court investigators, and Yao Moulin’s conviction and sentencing were in compliance with laws and regulations. . Xiu Bao also admitted in his confession that he received 900,000 yuan in attorney fees in Yao Moulin&#39;s case, but denied fabricating reasons to smoothen the relationship to collect 1.6 million yuan from Luo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in Cao’s testimony, Cao said that after Luo remitted 1.6 million yuan to himself, he also remitted 1.3 million yuan to his driver, and after withdrawing cash, he together with the 300,000 yuan in his hand Yuan for repair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Fengman District Court held that for the purpose of illegal possession, Xiubao fabricated facts that would allow Yao Moulin to get a lighter punishment for his crime through smoothing relationships, and defrauded the victim Luo Moumou of a particularly huge amount of property. constitutes the crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiu Bao’s defense lawyer believes that the evidence in the case cannot prove the fact that Xiu Bao obtained 1.6 million yuan, and that Xiu Bao did not fabricate facts or conceal the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Secondly, even if he accepted the 1.6 million yuan, it would at most be a violation of lawyer&#39;s professional ethics. After Xiubao accepted the entrustment, he completed all the work of meeting with the lawyer, reviewing the papers, and holding court proceedings, and the client I am also very satisfied with the outcome of the case, so it does not constitute a crime of fraud.&quot; Xiu Bao&#39;s defense lawyer told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, according to his son Xiu Zhiyu’s understanding, Yao Moulin and Luo did not recover the 1.6 million yuan from Xiu Bao, nor did they report the case to the public security agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, the court sentenced the repairman to fraud, sentenced him to twelve years in prison, and fined him RMB 200,000. In addition, the court also sentenced the prisoner to a fixed-term imprisonment of three years and a fine of RMB 200,000 for the crime of bribery; the prisoner was sentenced to a fixed-term imprisonment of two years and fined RMB 100,000 for the crime of introduction of bribery; and decided to execute the fixed-term imprisonment of 16 years year, and a fine of RMB 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;After the verdict of the first instance was pronounced, Xiu Bao appealed to the Jilin Intermediate Court. Currently, the case has entered the second instance procedure. On November 1, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters contacted the Jilin Intermediate People&#39;s Court several times about whether the second instance of the case would be heard, but received no reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiu Zhiyu said that he hopes that the second instance can be heard in court. &quot;As long as the verdict is open and fair, and everyone understands the facts of the case and feels that my father deserves what he deserves, I think he will be relieved.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“纳卡”再得一分、强力介入中东：埃尔多安玩转地缘政治棋局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259773]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the world situation has become increasingly turbulent, and conflicts between civilizations and regional conflicts among various ethnic groups have become increasingly intensified. Back to troubled times. Amid many conflicts and turbulence, Turkey&#39;s series of actions in recent years have become increasingly eye-catching. President Erdogan has earned himself the nickname &quot;Esultan&quot; with a series of dazzling combination punches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Syrian civil war in the past few years, it sent troops to northern Syria to support pro-Turkey armed factions and occupied and controlled part of the Syrian territory. In the process of fighting for the sphere of influence, Erdogan was bold and ruthless. He not only dared to take action against the Assad government forces, but also dared to shoot down Russian fighter jets and helicopters supporting the Syrian army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2020 &quot;Azerbaijan-Azerbaijan War&quot;, Turkey supported Azerbaijan, severely damaged Armenia, and once again hit Russia&#39;s prestige in the Middle East. As a result, Turkey&#39;s status in the Middle East has been greatly improved, and many Arab people regard Erdogan as a national hero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Erdogan dares to challenge Putin mainly because of his membership in NATO. He knows that under the protection of this political and military bloc, Russia will not directly attack Turkey for secondary and smaller overseas interests. It is a good way to use the power of the West to enhance one&#39;s prestige among the Islamic community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Russia-Ukraine conflict broke out in 2022, Turkey shuttled back and forth between several parties and experienced ups and downs: On the one hand, its participation led to the negotiation of the &quot;Black Sea Food Channel&quot; and improved its status among NATO member states. status. On the other hand, it used its veto power in NATO to delay Finland and Sweden&#39;s applications to join NATO. This has further improved his status in the Middle East. In the eyes of the people, Erdogan is a contemporary hero who dares to say no to Russia as well as the United States and Europe. He is simply the reincarnation of Saladin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has given Turkey a lot of points in its competition with Saudi Arabia and Iran to become the leader in the Middle East. Originally, due to the collapse of the Ottoman Empire, the fact that the Turks belong to the Turkic ethnic group rather than the Arab ethnic group, the pro-Western line implemented by Kemalism in the past few decades, and many other factors, Turkey was once marginalized in the Middle East world. Now it has finally been &quot;Egyptian&quot; Sudan” regained many scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, Turkey will make another move in the Transcaucasus: supporting Azerbaijan and forcing Armenia to withdraw from the &quot;Naka ​​region.&quot; This not only enabled Turkey and Azerbaijan to win the geopolitical dispute, but also caused Armenia to break away from Russia, its old master that it had relied on for hundreds of years, out of consideration for its own survival. This move caused Russia to lose serious points in the geopolitical conflict in the Transcaucasus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After embarrassing Finland and Sweden for nearly a year and achieving its own political goals (Finland and Sweden agreed to weaken their support for the anti-Turkey Kurdish forces), Turkey approved Finland and Sweden’s applications to join NATO, and then Increased its influence in NATO and improved relations with the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, as the &quot;Hazra-Israeli conflict&quot; broke out in the Gaza Strip, Erdogan stood up to criticize Israel and criticized the United States and Europe, once again winning widespread support for him in the Middle East. Did he really want to revive the Ottoman Turkish Empire? How did he win so many times in a row over several years? This starts with Turkey’s political interests, cultural positioning, and geostrategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turkey’s national defense security depends on NATO, dominated by the United States, and its economic foundation mainly relies on the European market, dominated by the EU. In the modern world, it is simply impossible to allow Turkey to use force to retake the homeland of the former Ottoman Empire. Therefore, the main body of the secular and pro-Western concepts of &quot;Kemalism&quot; has not changed. Erdogan has worked hard for many years and always hopes to join the EU. When asked by the media whether he would go to the West or the East, he firmly answered: Go west and join the EU. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turkey is also a country that has great conflicts with the West culturally. As a politician, Erdogan must decide his policies based on real social foundations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early decades of the practice of &quot;Kemalism&quot;, Turkey adopted a one-sided strategy towards the West. But in the past decade or so, as the power of the Islamic world has increased, the Ankara authorities certainly cannot give up this huge resource. Therefore, they must strive for leadership in the Islamic world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the geostrategic level, Turkey has a unique advantage: as the strategic pillar of NATO in the southeast, it not only blocks the entrance and exit of the Black Sea, but also affects the security situation along the Black Sea coast and the Caspian Sea. The Transcaucasus and Central Asia have always been Russia&#39;s strategic soft belly, and Turkey has a profound influence on these two regions, whether in terms of geography, ethnicity, religion, culture, economy, etc. Turkey, which sits on the Anatolian Plateau, borders southeastern Europe to the west, Iran to the east, and the two river basins of Mesopotamia to the south. It plays a very important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Erdogan has made comprehensive use of political, religious, cultural, economic, military, geographical and other factors to combine vertical and horizontal movements and maneuvers, and has achieved many successes and expanded Turkey. geopolitical interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But behind this set of seemingly prosperous actions, Turkey has serious problems: their economic size cannot support the talents and strategies of &quot;Egyptian Sudan&quot;. Its inflation is very serious. On October 26, the Central Bank of Turkey announced that it would raise the benchmark interest rate by 500 basis points from 30% to 35%. This is the fifth consecutive interest rate increase since the Central Bank entered the interest rate increase cycle in June. Since 2022, Turkey&#39;s inflation rate has been running at a high level, reaching 85.51% in October 2022, and 47.83%, 58.94%, and 61.53% in the three months of July, August, and September 2023, respectively, and there is still an upward trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, &quot;Egypt-Sudan&quot;, as a medium-sized country in Turkey, has done too many political achievements at a loss and made a profit, and all the costs have to be borne by the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In history, many countries have adopted strategies of inciting nationalism, playing tricks at the top, and overdrafting national power. They have achieved jaw-dropping achievements in a relatively short period of time, but the results have mostly been tragic. The reason is simple: just like a person who is not in good health and has to exhaust his energy to run a marathon, triathlon, or decathlon, of course there will be no good results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Erdogan is trying his best to control the pace of the game. After achieving his goals, he may compromise with the United States and Europe. For example: when Finland and Sweden were finally approved to join NATO, he chose to keep a low profile when the US military shot down a Turkish drone (in order to safeguard its interests with the Kurdish community). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, in terms of national defense, Turkey relies on the United States; in terms of economy, with such a high inflation rate, it depends even more on the help of the European Union, and it has a large number of immigrants and workers in Europe, which has a great impact on Ankara. The economy is very important, and it is also Turkey’s long-term means of ethnic penetration, colonization, and cultural expansion into Europe. Therefore, whether it is a show, a show, or a dispute or conflict, it must be stopped in moderation and not completely fall out with the West. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Erdogan is playing a medium-scale geostrategic game with Turkey&#39;s national power and influence. His intention is to use his territory spanning Europe and Asia, and his political and cultural involvement in the two camps of Europe and Islam, to jump on several ships to expand Turkey&#39;s influence in modern Europe and the Islamic world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报女教师跳楼轻生事件：成立联合调查组，“加班数石榴”为不实信息]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259820]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, a female teacher from Jianxing Road Primary School in our district unfortunately passed away. In response to the incident, , the teachers and students of the school were deeply saddened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, the district education bureau attached great importance to it and immediately collaborated with relevant departments to set up a joint investigation team to investigate the incident and make every effort to comfort the family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, false information such as &quot;working overtime to count pomegranates&quot; appeared on the Internet. We hereby appeal to the majority of netizens to be rational and objective, and not to believe or spread rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the District Education Bureau will further enhance its care for grassroots teachers in the district, make every effort to care for the lives and psychological care of grassroots teachers in the district, and provide a good education and teaching environment for primary and secondary school teachers in the district . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guancheng Hui District Education Bureau&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 1, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/02/ac6d47e1881f43b216e87142e275f058.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;1018&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/02/ac6d47e1881f43b216e87142e275f058.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256651&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[花十几万去南极旅游，是花钱买罪受？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259372]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, &quot;The ticket price for an expedition to Antarctica has been reduced by 90,000 &quot;The post sparked heated discussions on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;You know, every November is when the Antarctic tourism season starts. Many domestic travel agencies have started selling Antarctic tour projects. The price of a trip is basically more than 100,000 yuan, and some high-end routes can be as high as 300,000 to 400,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time, the Antarctic trip has been a niche high-end project. Many people don’t know about it. This is the first time for many people to hear that it is okay. Travel to Antarctica. Is traveling to Antarctica difficult and expensive? Is traveling to Antarctica a matter of spending money to enjoy the unique beauty, or is it &quot;spending money to buy suffering&quot;? Will many people traveling to Antarctica damage the ecological environment of Antarctica? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/Ry46lJqqtjt2vMlY9w62dFLPyCkmUXDliLD7DCL3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/Ry46lJqqtjt2vMlY9w62dFLPyCkmUXDliLD7DCL3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Is it difficult to travel to Antarctica&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctica is the southernmost point of the earth. It is the last one to be discovered on the earth and the only one without humans. A continent where people live and settle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time in the past, Antarctica was a mysterious place in the world until Antarctica was discovered in 1820. Since then, Antarctica has also been mainly used as a scientific research base. In December 1911, the Norwegian Amundsen expedition reached the Antarctic Pole for the first time. In 1985, my country established a scientific research station in Antarctica for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Antarctica is also a tourist destination. In the 1950s, the world&#39;s first international tourist group of 500 people went to Antarctica, and Antarctic tourism officially appeared. 2007 was the first year for China to launch Antarctic tourism, and China’s first officially recognized Antarctic tour line was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to statistics from the International Association of Antarctic Tourism Operators (IAATO), China is the second largest source of tourists to Antarctica. In the 2017-2018 Antarctic tourism season, a total of 51,707 tourists from around the world visited Antarctica, and the number of Chinese tourists reached 8,273, accounting for 16%, second only to the United States. A total of 1,464 Chinese people went to Antarctica in the 2022-23 Antarctic season. It is expected that in the 2023-24 Antarctic tourism season, Chinese tourists will return to 80% of the pre-epidemic number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctica does not have four seasons, only two seasons, namely the warm season (November-March) and the cold season (April-October). The warm season is also the tourist season in Antarctica, because it is almost daytime and the temperature is higher, making it more suitable for tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Theoretically, as long as it is the Antarctic tourist season, everyone can travel to Antarctica, because traveling to Antarctica does not require a visa, and Antarctica does not belong to any nation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From a practical point of view, traveling to Antarctica is difficult. After all, our country does not have direct commercial flights to Antarctica. Tourists must first go to a country relatively close to Antarctica. , such as Argentina, Australia or New Zealand, and then go to Antarctica via cruise ships or flights from these transit countries. Therefore, if you want to apply for a transit country visa when going to Antarctica, you also need the help and services of a professional travel company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/bcdfUdi8XYsJEq5ytx0qk74142tITCWOEmb4Y18g.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/bcdfUdi8XYsJEq5ytx0qk74142tITCWOEmb4Y18g.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Appreciate beauty, or buy into suffering? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As you can imagine, Antarctica has breathtaking beauty. 98% of the Antarctic continent is covered with ice and snow all year round, making people feel like they are in a pure white world, which is extremely clear and translucent from the eyes to the soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Here, tourists will tremble at the miraculous workmanship of nature. They can enjoy the natural landscape of eternal daylight and interact with the masters of Antarctica - penguins, Blue whales, sea lions and various seagulls coexist harmoniously and happily...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctic tours can provide us with exclusive experiences that cannot be experienced anywhere else in the world. In order to enrich the fun of the journey, travel companies will also carry out outdoor activities such as hiking, kayaking and camping in Antarctica. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Going to Antarctica to appreciate the beauty behind it also requires paying a high cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Behind the long journey is the sound of money disappearing. Nowadays, the mainstream Antarctic tourism projects in China are to fly from China to Argentina first, and then take a cruise to Antarctica via Argentina. The departure point of most cruise ships is Ushuaia, the southernmost tip of Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The flight from China to Buenos Aires, Argentina takes about 40 hours (and you have to endure the troublesome transfer). It takes a long time to take a cruise from the Argentine port to sea. It takes between 2 and 5 days of sailing time to reach the Antarctic continent. Tourists can choose to spend only a few days in the Antarctic continent; they can also choose &quot;Antarctic Peninsula + Antarctic Circle&quot;, which will sail southward through the Antarctic Circle based on the Antarctic Peninsula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A trip to Antarctica can take about ten days if it is short, or twenty or thirty days if it is long. Depending on the aircraft cabin, cruise class and accommodation environment, the price also varies greatly. For example, the prices of various cruise companies are basically 60,000-200,000 yuan per person. Therefore, the total cost of a trip to Antarctica ranges from 70,000 to 80,000 yuan for a cheap trip to 30,000 to 400,000 yuan for an expensive trip, or even higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The challenge of traveling to Antarctica is not only the high price, but also the &quot;suffering&quot; during the journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cruise ships arriving at the Antarctic continent basically have to pass through the Drake Strait. This is the widest strait in the world and the deepest strait in the world. Due to the influence of polar cyclones, there are strong winds and huge waves all year round. The wind force is basically above level 8 all year round. When a cruise ship passes through it, the hull will inevitably shake violently, and the probability of seasickness and vomiting among tourists is extremely high, so much so that there is a saying, &quot;If you haven&#39;t fainted once in the Drake Passage, don&#39;t say you have been to Antarctica.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tourists who travel to Antarctica often have polarizing opinions about this journey. Some people think that the trip is worthwhile and it is a unique experience in life. Some people frankly say that spending money to buy the experience makes Antarctic travel &quot;so cold, so far, so expensive, and so boring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Will tourism harm Antarctica&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctica is recognized by the world It is a nature reserve shared by all mankind, and the protection of Antarctica has long been established in the form of international conventions. On December 1, 1959, the Antarctic Treaty was signed and came into effect on June 23, 1961. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Antarctic Convention&quot; aims to restrict the activities of various countries in Antarctica, the only continent on earth without a permanent population, and ensure that countries respect Antarctica. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1991, the Special Meeting of the Antarctic Treaty Consultative Countries adopted the &quot;Antarctic Treaty Protocol on Environmental Protection&quot; with a view to environmental protection in Antarctica. As one of the negotiating countries, China signed the protocol. The protocol sets out strict protection measures to protect the ecological environment of the Antarctic continent and nearby areas from damage. Later, the International Association of Antarctic Tourism Operators also issued the &quot;Activity Guide for Antarctic Tourism Practitioners&quot; and the &quot;Activity Guide for Antarctic Tourists&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the constraints of these treaties, travel to Antarctica must abide by some principles. For example, large ships cannot stay in a certain place for more than 5 hours; each trip to the island Only 100 people can log in; you cannot take the initiative to get within 5 meters of the penguins; you must clean your shoes after disembarking from the boat and returning to the boat to avoid biological invasion, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, climate disasters have already had a serious impact on Antarctic ecology. As the Earth heats up, Antarctic glaciers are melting and becoming more fragile. Research shows that from 1997 to 2021, more than 40% of Antarctic ice shelves have shrunk significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, frequent human travel activities may make the Antarctic snow melt faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Last year, a paper published in Nature Communications pointed out that black carbon pollution at tourist arrival points in Antarctica may increase these area of ​​snowmelt. The burning of fossil and biomass fuels creates black carbon, which absorbs light and heats the atmosphere. If black carbon falls on snow, it melts faster. As a result, environmentalists loudly shouted: Please reduce unnecessary Antarctic travel and protect the natural ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Embarrassingly, many domestic companies that launch Antarctic tour projects promote one of the reasons for Antarctic tours is that &quot;some Antarctic glaciers are melting at an accelerating rate and are losing their The original natural beauty. The earlier you go, the less likely you will be able to see the most primitive Antarctic continent and retain the beauty and primitiveness that is about to disappear!&quot; However, the arrival of more and more tourists is exacerbating the melting of Antarctic ice and snow and destroying the beauty of Antarctica. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This does not mean that all Antarctic tours should be cancelled. Man and nature can coexist harmoniously. However, it is indeed necessary to speed up the use of clean energy in Antarctic tourism, limit the number of tourists, strengthen the supervision of Antarctic tourism, and strengthen the implementation of the Antarctic Treaty, so as to minimize the negative impact of human activities in Antarctica on the Antarctic ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>