<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[外婆索要带孩费：“家务劳动补偿”的自然延伸？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257707]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Grandma sued her daughter and son-in-law for taking care of her children, demanding payment of remuneration from February 2018 to July 2023 192,000 yuan. Recently, the Guang&#39;an District Court of Guang&#39;an City, Sichuan Province ordered the daughter and son-in-law to pay 82,500 yuan to the grandmother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the court, because the child Xiaobao’s mother Hu and father Zhu had been working in Chengdu and were busy with work and had no time to take care of the child, they left Xiaobao in the care of his grandmother Duan. Hu said: She and her husband give her mother 1,000 yuan a month for living expenses and 2,000 yuan for child care. Hu said that he and Duan had signed an agreement on Xiaobao&#39;s custody, but the child&#39;s father did not know about it. When my grandmother tried repeatedly to get her, but to no avail, she filed a lawsuit in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that Hu and his wife had the rights and obligations to raise, educate, and protect Xiaobao, and were able to earn income through labor and had the ability to support the child. Duan had no legal obligation to support the child, so Hu The couple should pay the grandmother the necessary expenses incurred for daily care and nursing of the baby. However, the child&#39;s father, Zhu, said: The fundamental reason why the old man asked for &quot;child care fees&quot; was that he and the child&#39;s mother had a divorce dispute. &quot;The person she really wants to sue is me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a couple divorces, it is not difficult to understand why the elderly come up with unique strategies to obtain more benefits for their children. Of course, there is no problem with the court&#39;s decision. The current Marriage and Family Section of the Civil Code stipulates that both husband and wife jointly bear the obligation to raise, educate and protect minor children (Article 1058); Children and grandchildren have the obligation to support them (Article 1074), which is essentially consistent with the previously applicable marriage law provisions (Articles 21 and 28). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, statutory law and judicial practice now recognize small families, and large families only exist in the sense of customary law. Under normal circumstances, in the sense of statutory law, the elderly have neither any rights nor any responsibilities and obligations towards their small family members. Therefore, for the elderly of either party to help take care of the children is a matter of affection, not a duty. The elderly can choose to take them or not; they can take them voluntarily for free, or they can ask for compensation before or after the event. These are the rights of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time a similar verdict has been issued. There is a famous case in Nanjing. In 2010, Su married her husband Li. In August 2014, her son was born and was taken care of by her grandmother Fang. In August 2019, the two divorced. In December 2020, the court ruled that the divorce was granted, and the child was raised by Su. On October 10, 2020, Fang sued his daughter and son-in-law, who had not yet divorced at the time, demanding more than 200,000 yuan in childcare fees. The court held that Fang had no obligation to take care of the child and ordered Li to pay a total of more than 160,000 yuan in childcare fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judges have discretion and may make contrary decisions. There is a case in Tai&#39;an, Shandong. Yao married her husband Su in 2013 and had a daughter. The two divorced in 2021. During the marriage, both husband and wife worked, and Grandma Li took care of the children. In 2021, Li sued and demanded that Yao pay 100,000 yuan. The Ningyang County Court held that although the two parties are now divorced, the children still have a close relationship with their parents and ancestors, and the children should not be blamed for their elders&#39; entanglements. &quot;The children should be cared for and will not be supported,&quot; the court said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the elderly&#39;s request for childcare fees is also a natural extension of &quot;housework compensation&quot; and deserves attention and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In judicial practice, the concept of “housework compensation” often appears in divorce cases. One party works to earn money, creates wealth for the family, and provides transfer payments to those who stay at home full-time and their children; the other party stays at home full-time. According to the community property system, one person will receive half of the property upon divorce. For example, if the property is 2 million, each person will share 1 million. However, according to the idea of ​​&quot;family labor compensation&quot;, full-time earners need to provide some additional money to those who work full-time at home. The logic behind this division is that full-time stay-at-home workers contribute more to the family than full-time earners. Theoretically, because common property itself already means compensation for those who stay at home full-time, the so-called &quot;housework compensation&quot; is actually secondary compensation. Reasonable or not? There was endless debate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In actual divorce cases, one spouse who used to be a good couple can ask for additional &quot;housework compensation&quot; from the other spouse on the grounds that they stay at home full time. Then it would be more reasonable for one or both elderly people to ask for &quot;child care fees&quot; from the small family, because taking care of children is not the responsibility of the elderly in the first place. This is why when there are more and more divorce cases involving &quot;housework compensation&quot;, there are also more and more cases of the elderly asking for &quot;childcare fees&quot;. The two have both a positive correlation and a causal relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, even if it was just a matter of affection, not a duty, to take care of grandchildren in the legal sense, there were very few cases where one or both elderly people asked for &quot;child care fees&quot; from a small family. There were many reasons: or because they were The constraints of traditional extended family concepts and customary laws may be due to fear of hurting the relationship with grandchildren, or &quot;fear of being laughed at by others.&quot; But when a couple is divorcing, one party can ask for &quot;compensation for housework&quot; from the other party, and the constraints on these concepts of the elderly are invisibly relaxed and even disappear; one of the husband and wife may even secretly ask their parents for help, so that they can When an old man sues himself and his spouse, he will argue as much as possible, and &quot;the flesh rots in his own pot.&quot; This is why we are seeing more and more cases and reports like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贷中贷，“瑕疵案”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/VZjva2GziqcXupA02j2W8YDlQPOVfdpTWWeaVi6i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;982&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/VZjva2GziqcXupA02j2W8YDlQPOVfdp TWWeaVi6i. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252272&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 19, 2023, today’s Mujiangwang Village, Baqiao District, Xi’an City . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhai Xingli/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past nine years, Shaanxi businessman Hu Xufeng has been involved in 273 lawsuits. The origin of the 273 lawsuits is the urban village reconstruction project of Mujiangwang Village in Baqiao District, Xi&#39;an City that he began to develop in the 2000s. He was only 27 years old when he won this project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Huashang Daily&quot; report, on July 5, 2009, the Xi&#39;an Urban Reform Office released for the first time a list of 83 projects that had obtained the &quot;Approval of the Urban Village Renovation Plan&quot;. In terms of area, the Mujiangwang Village reconstruction project covers an area of ​​785 acres, making it the largest one on the list. Based on the average sales price of commercial real estate surrounding the project, Hu Xufeng estimated that the market value of the project around 2016 was about 4 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the project development process, Hu Xufeng pledged the company&#39;s shares due to two private loans, and therefore lost control of the company. One of them was a cumulative loan of 6 million yuan from Wang Jian, a Zhejiang businessman who has lived in Xi&#39;an. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to regain his equity, Hu Xufeng launched a lengthy lawsuit against creditors and administrative agencies, and the lawsuit went all the way to the Supreme People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the Supreme People’s Court made a judgment on the civil case involving Hu Xufeng’s party suing Wang Jian, upholding the judgment of the Shaanxi Provincial High Court, but found that the “Shareholders Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement” on January 10, 2012 was illegal. The true expression of intention of the parties does not have the effect of equity transfer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng sued the Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau based on this, petitioning to revoke Wang Jian&#39;s share change registration, but lost both cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng lodged a protest with the procuratorial organ. In July 2020, a prosecutor from the Seventh Procuratorate Department of the Shaanxi Provincial People&#39;s Procuratorate appeared in court to protest. After the protest, Hu Xufeng still lost the case in the retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Hu Xufeng’s opponent, the current shareholder of Hongrun Real Estate, applied to the Xi’an Market Supervision Bureau to change the legal representative, but was also rejected. On August 18, 2023, the Xi&#39;an Railway Transport Intermediate Court made a second-instance judgment. The Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau lost the case. The court ordered it to administratively handle Hongrun Real Estate&#39;s change application within 60 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that in this equity war that has lasted for nine years, the administrative agencies involved must make the final decision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of press time, the Xi’an Market Supervision Bureau had not responded to an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two private loans&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;International Happy City is located in the southeast of Xi&#39;an&#39;s central city, about 20 minutes&#39; drive from the city center, and close to the East Third Ring Road . Property staff said that at the end of 2022, with the opening of the subway Mujiangwang Station next to the community, the rent in the community will also increase slightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This real estate project with good market conditions is the origin of a series of lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng was born in Taibai Village, Shuigou Township, Shangnan County, Shangluo City, Shaanxi Province in 1980. After dropping out of junior high school, he went out to work. He claimed that he received advice from businessmen while working in other provinces, and returned to Xi&#39;an to do computer wholesale business and made his first pot of gold. Later, he was introduced to Xi&#39;an and started contracting projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Hu Xufeng established Shaanxi Hongrun Industrial Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Hongrun Group&quot;) in Xi&#39;an. In May 2006, Shaanxi Hongrun Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Hongrun Real Estate&quot;) was registered and established. Hu Xufeng, who is only 26 years old, has the ability to buy a first-floor office building as the company&#39;s office space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, the Xi&#39;an Municipal People&#39;s Government issued the &quot;Opinions on Accelerating the Transformation of Urban Villages&quot; (Municipal Administration [2005] No. 92), proposing to &quot;encourage social capital investment to participate in urban village transformation projects to make up for the government&#39;s Fund shortage situation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this wave of urban village (shanty town) renovation, Hu Xufeng was introduced by someone and signed a joint development contract with the Mujiangwang Village Committee of Baqiao District in March 2007. After that, Hu Xufeng injected capital to start the project. While demolishing and demolishing, he built relocation housing and built commercial housing for sale to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hu Xufeng’s statistics, from the start of the project to the borrowing from Wang Jian in 2012, it invested a total of 820 million yuan in the Mujiangwang Village reconstruction project, with the funds coming from self-raised and private loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports of the year, the renovation of Mujiangwang Village was the largest project among the first batch of urban village renovations in Xi&#39;an. As for why it borrowed money from the private sector, &quot;the main reason was that the city&#39;s urban reform at that time was characterized by incomplete materials and insufficient procedures.&quot; Hu Xufeng&#39;s explanation was that the project land was developed first without the government purchasing and storing it, and the developer did not obtain the land use rights. Unable to get a bank mortgage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng named the commercial housing he built International Happy City, and the first batch of about 100 units were sold out within three days. During the development process, in 2010, Hu Xufeng’s friend Zhu Yaojiang proposed to take a stake. Judgment No. 1377 of Zhejiang 0603 Xingchu shows that Zhu Yaojiang was born in Shengzhou City, Zhejiang Province in 1966. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng said that in his early business activities, Zhu Yaojiang provided help. When buying shares, Zhu Yaojiang introduced him to the actual investor Li Bin and introduced Li Bin’s identity as a social worker in Shaanxi Province. President of the Charity Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 14, 2010, Zhu Yaojiang lent 80 million yuan to Hongrun Real Estate in the name of Xi&#39;an Zhongsha Investment Co., Ltd., and Hu Xufeng transferred 18% of Hongrun Real Estate&#39;s shares to Zhongsha Company for free, agreeing that The shares will be returned free of charge after Zhongxia Company obtains 18% of the project income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng said that when he borrowed money from outside the country before, no creditors asked him to mortgage his equity. &quot;Most of them were mortgages for houses that we have not yet opened.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 11, 2012, Zhu Yaojiang introduced Wang Jian to lend 6 million yuan to Hongrun Real Estate. The loan materials obtained by Southern Weekend reporters show that Wang Jian was born in 1968 in Taizhou, Zhejiang. The term of this loan is 3 months. Hu Xufeng will transfer 75% of the shares of Hongrun Real Estate to Wang Jian for free. After Hu Xufeng repays the loan, Wang Jian will transfer it back to Hu Xufeng for free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the market value of the Mujiangwang Village renovation project at that time, the proportion of pledged equity corresponding to the two loans of Zhu Yaojiang and Wang Jian did not conform to normal business logic. In the subsequent lengthy litigation, Hu Xufeng compared it to a &quot;snake swallowing an elephant&quot;, but did not provide a precise explanation for the abnormal equity pledge ratio. According to Hu Xufeng, he repeatedly asked for repayment of debts, but both creditors proposed to change the cooperation method, and the debt repayment was abandoned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/lm6tN82Qv6ijldU6z94DFvOHB4Ewn60YEuvNgeSH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1038&quot; height= &quot;778&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/lm6tN82Qv6ijldU6z94DFvOHB4Ewn60YEuvNgeSH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252273&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 19, 2023, 16 years after the project was launched, many unfinished buildings can be seen at the site of Mujiangwang Village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhai Xingli/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Forged signature&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In this regard, Hongrun Real Estate, which was originally 100% controlled by Hu Xufeng and his wife, is left with only Hu Xufeng&#39;s wife Chen and Hongrun Group holding a total of 7% of the shares. In March 2013, the legal representative of Hongrun Real Estate was changed from Hu Xufeng to Zhuyaojiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hu Xufeng claimed that he only learned about the fact that only 7% of the equity was left in July 2014, more than two years after the loan agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his account, in the previous two years, he had been diagnosed with esophageal cancer, operated, and recovered. During the treatment, the capital chain of Hongrun Real Estate was broken. Although Zhu Yaojiang and Wang Jian jointly obtained Hongrun Real Estate 93% of the equity, but no further capital injection into the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng tried to restart the project. He went to the industrial and commercial department to inquire and found that on January 10, 2012, the industrial and commercial department received the application materials for registration of changes in equity interests of Hongrun Real Estate shareholders and approved the application on the 31st of that month. Registered the change of 75% of the equity of Hongrun Real Estate to Wang Jian&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the application materials, there is a &quot;Shareholders Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; signed on January 10, 2012, which is the document recognized by the Supreme Court. The content is that the Hongrun Real Estate Shareholders Meeting has studied and approved the transfer of 75% of the equity. Transferred to Wang Jian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The date of the loan agreement between Wang Jian and Hongrun Real Estate is January 11, 2012. Hu Xufeng applied for an appraisal from the Judicial Appraisal Center of Northwest University of Political Science and Law. The appraisal opinion shows that the signatures of Hu Xufeng and Wang Jian on this shareholder transfer capital contribution agreement are not their own signatures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted Wang Jian after many attempts. Wang Jian responded via text message to a reporter from Southern Weekend: &quot;The whole lies and stories fabricated by Hu Xufeng have troubled me for more than ten years and caused a lot of pressure and shadow to me and my family. At present, there are irresistible problems in all aspects.&quot; Overturning the conclusion, I don’t want to be entangled with such social liars, ruffians, and scoundrels anymore, and I don’t want to explain anything in this matter. The government department will definitely come up with a conclusion about who committed the crime in violation of the law, but before the time comes, the company will go bankrupt. Everything will be revealed during liquidation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Wang Jian refused to explain the facts about his loan situation with Hu Xufeng, equity disputes and handwriting identification. He asked: &quot;He was really rich and capable back then. Do you want to engage in such a big project?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, Hu Xufeng and his wife took Hongrun Real Estate to court, claiming that the signatures on the &quot;Shareholders Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; were forged and completed without the knowledge of Hu&#39;s wife Chen. On the grounds that the transfer of 75% of the shares violated Chen’s right of first refusal, the court requested the court to invalidate the “Shareholder Transfer and Capital Contribution Agreement” and restore the industrial and commercial registration information of Hongrun Real Estate to the state before the change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 29, 2015, the Xi&#39;an Intermediate People&#39;s Court made a verdict. The court found that the signatures of Hu Xufeng and Wang Jian on the &quot;Shareholder Transfer and Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; signed on January 10, 2012 were not signed by the two of them, and Wang Jian himself had no objection to this. The court ruled that the agreement was invalid, but rejected the Hu Xufeng couple&#39;s other claims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jian refused to accept the decision and appealed to the Shaanxi Provincial High Court. Wang Jian argued to the court that although the signatures of Hu Xufeng and Wang Jian on the &quot;Shareholders Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; signed on January 10, 2012 were not signed by the two of them, there was another agreement signed by Hongrun Real Estate on January 10. The &quot;Shareholders Meeting Resolution&quot; transferring 75% of the shares to Wang Jian has the signature of Hu Xufeng&#39;s wife Chen. Chen cannot prove that her signature is forged, so Chen knows and agrees to the agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters repeatedly asked Hu Xufeng and his wife for verification. They insisted that the signature was not signed by Chen, but &quot;because the appraisal fee was very expensive and they were short of money at the time, they only authenticated the &quot;Shareholder Transfer and Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; &quot;The signature on the &quot;Shareholders&#39; Meeting Resolution&quot; was not authenticated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 25, 2015, the Shaanxi Provincial High Court made a judgment. The court found that after signing the &quot;Shareholders Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; on January 10, 2012, Hu Xufeng and his wife confirmed the authenticity of the agreement several times at the Hongrun Real Estate shareholders&#39; meeting and external agreements on March 15, 2013. The validity of the agreement was not raised and no objection was raised. Therefore, its appeal to determine that the agreement was invalid &quot;has no factual and legal basis and this court will not support it in accordance with the law.&quot; The second-instance judgment of the Shaanxi Provincial High Court revoked the first-instance judgment of the Xi&#39;an Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng refused to accept the lawsuit, and the lawsuit eventually went to the Supreme People&#39;s Court. On May 29, 2019, the Supreme People&#39;s Court issued (2017) Supreme Court Judgment No. 171, upholding the judgment of the Shaanxi Provincial High Court. However, the Supreme People&#39;s Court found that the &quot;Shareholder Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; signed on January 10, 2012 was a pledge guarantee by changing the equity holder, and it did not have the effect of equity transfer because it was not the true expression of intention of the parties. As for both parties, &quot;whether the equity pledge in the loan relationship complies with legal regulations can be resolved through separate legal channels.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Administrative Protest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reason why the Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau became the defendant is also because of the above two signatures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng requested the court to order the bureau to cancel the change registration and re-register the shares under the name of Hongrun Group on the grounds that the bureau relied on the &quot;Shareholder Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; with forged signatures in the change registration. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case was assigned to the Xi&#39;an Xincheng District People&#39;s Court for trial. On July 8, 2016, Xincheng Court issued an administrative judgment. The court found that when the bureau reviewed the change registration application materials submitted by a third party, it did not find that the signatures on the shareholder capital contribution agreement were not made by the company&#39;s legal representative and shareholders. &quot;It was a flaw in the industrial and commercial change registration and did not affect the administration.&quot; the legality of the conduct”. Hu Xufeng lost the lawsuit. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng refused to accept the verdict and appealed to the Xi&#39;an Intermediate Court, which upheld the original verdict. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 18, 2019, Hu Xufeng filed a protest with the Xi’an Municipal People’s Procuratorate, and the Shaanxi Provincial People’s Procuratorate supported the protest. The Shaanxi Provincial High Court ordered the Xi&#39;an Intermediate People&#39;s Court to conduct a retrial. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, the prosecutor of the Seventh Procuratorate Department of the Shaanxi Provincial People’s Procuratorate appeared in court to protest. According to the official website of the court, this is the first time that the Shaanxi Provincial People’s Procuratorate has sent personnel to attend the retrial court for administrative protest cases after the internal institutional reform of the Shaanxi Provincial Procuratorate and the establishment of a separate administrative prosecution department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau argued that the law requires administrative agencies to conduct a formal review for the registration of changes in shareholder equity. The change application materials at that time were complete and met the formal requirements stipulated by the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Administrative Licensing Law, formal review is a concept corresponding to substantive review. Formal review refers to the review that the application materials submitted by the applicant are complete and in compliance with the legal form, while substantive review refers to the administrative agency’s review of the applicant. The authenticity and legality of the content of the materials provided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bureau argued that &quot;Although the &quot;Shareholder Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; was not signed by me, the content of the agreement represents the true intention of the parties, and there is evidence to prove that the facts of the agreement are recognized by both parties.&quot; In addition, although The Supreme People&#39;s Court determined that the &quot;Shareholders Transfer Capital Contribution Agreement&quot; is in the nature of an equity guarantee and does not have the effect of equity transfer, &quot;but it does not affect the outcome of the administrative case. Our bureau has fulfilled its reasonable review obligations and has no responsibility to revoke this administrative action.&quot; and obligations”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bureau emphasized to the court that administrative actions have conclusive power, and the registration of equity changes reflects the true meaning of Hongrun Real Estate’s equity transfer guarantee in appearance, and cannot antagonize bona fide counterparts. Likewise, it does not affect administrative matters. Effectiveness of behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng&#39;s litigation attorney objected, &quot;Equity transfer guarantee and equity pledge are two completely different legal relationships.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Civil Code, equity transfer guarantee means that the debtor transfers the equity to the name of the creditor. After the debtor pays off the debt when due, the creditor should return the equity to the debtor. Equity pledge can only obtain equity ownership after the debt matures through auction, (liquidation) or negotiation procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the finding in the Supreme Court&#39;s judgment that a pledge guarantee is made by changing the equity holder, it does not have the effect of equity transfer because it is not the true intention of the parties. The parties in the dispute case have argued that Each has its own understanding and expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 18, 2020, the Xi&#39;an Intermediate People&#39;s Court issued a retrial verdict, and Hu Xufeng lost the case again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the application of law to the aforementioned two focus issues in this dispute, the Small and Medium Enterprises Business Environment Research Group of the Law School of Xi&#39;an University of Finance and Economics commissioned the Civil Law Research Society of the China Law Society on August 31, 2023. Four legal experts, namely Yang Lixin, vice president, Cui Jianyuan, vice president of the Civil Law Research Society of the China Law Society, Wang Xizhen, executive director of the Administrative Law Research Society of the China Law Society, and Wang Bo, dean of the Law School of Xi&#39;an University of Finance and Economics, organized the seminar and issued a legal Opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legal opinions put forward by the experts at the meeting include: Hu Xufeng’s signature in the “Equity (East) Transfer and Capital Contribution Agreement” dated January 10, 2012 is forged. This document is a false material, and any agreement based on this false material should be revoked. Administrative decision on the registration of change of equity transfer of Hongrun Real Estate; the agreement reached between Wang Jian and Hongrun Group is an equity transfer guarantee, not an equity pledge. If the aforementioned change registration is regarded as a valid equity transfer guarantee registration, Wang Jian will act as a creditor , has no right to exercise shareholder rights and can only receive priority repayment for the equity involved in the case; Hongrun Group, as the debtor and guarantor, has the right to request Wang Jian to return the equity and change the equity registration after repaying the loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The final chapter is coming&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the dispute that lasted for more than ten years, the Mujiangwang Village reconstruction project experienced unfinished work, changed hands, and the villagers many times During the petition, Southern Weekend reporters saw at the scene that there are still 10 buildings in unfinished condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the villagers of Mujiangwang Village that around 2015, the government-funded relocation houses were delivered, and the last batch of villagers moved back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2015, the Xi&#39;an Bahe New District Management Committee changed the project subject from Hongrun Real Estate to Shaanxi Jiaxinyuan Industrial Co., Ltd. The government department advanced 140 million yuan to build some relocation houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The control of Hongrun Real Estate is still being contested by all parties. Zhu Yaojiang was sentenced by the Keqiao Court in 2017. According to the law, he can no longer serve as the legal representative of Hongrun Real Estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 13, 2017, the People&#39;s Court of Keqiao District, Shaoxing City, Zhejiang Province issued the (2016) Zhejiang 0603 Xingchu No. 1377 Judgment. Zhu Yaojiang was sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment for the crime of embezzlement and illegal absorption of public deposits. 13 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are Hu Xufeng’s witness statements on pages 22 and 33 of this judgment. However, Hu Xufeng insisted that he was traveling between Xi&#39;an, Beijing and other places at the time and had not received any inquiries or evidence collection from Shaanxi or Zhejiang public prosecutors and law enforcement departments regarding the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on September 20, 2023, the Keqiao District People&#39;s Court responded to Southern Weekend reporters that after verification, during the handling of the case, the Economic Investigation Brigade of the High-tech Branch of the Xi&#39;an Public Security Bureau transferred 46 files along with it. A set of case materials, including Hu Xufeng&#39;s witness testimony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Xufeng’s sister said that on September 23, 2023, she contacted the police officer handling the case at the time, and the other party said that a report record had been made when Hu Xufeng reported the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report refers to the fact that in August 2014, Zhu Yaojiang’s sister was arrested by the Xi’an police on suspicion of illegally absorbing public deposits. Hu Xufeng reported to the Xi’an Public Security Bureau at that time that Zhu Yaojiang was the mastermind behind the case. Hu Xufeng produced the original reporting materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Are crime report transcripts equivalent to witness statements submitted to the court? The policemen handling the case and Hu Xufeng each held their own opinions. However, (2016) Zhejiang 0603 Xingchu No. 1377 Judgment shows that Zhu Yaojiang was only criminally detained in November 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2017, Hui Xiping, then director of the Hongqi Subdistrict Office in Baqiao District, Xi&#39;an City, said in an interview with CCTV&#39;s &quot;News Investigation&quot; program that Zhu Yaojiang and Wang Jian collectively acquired 93% of the shares of Hongrun Real Estate. Later, it was discovered that the actual controller of Hongrun Real Estate was not these two people, but the aforementioned actual investor Li Bin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are different opinions about Li Bin’s life. Some media once quoted the article &quot;&quot;Luxury Monk&quot; Li Bin&quot; published in the 14th issue of &quot;China Entrepreneur&quot; magazine in 2007 to introduce his life. Southern Weekend reporters were unable to find the original text of the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned in Li Bin’s parents’ neighborhood that his father was a team worker at Xi’an Film Studio. He returned to his hometown in Mei County, Baoji City a few years ago. Li Bin also worked in Xi’an Film Production The factory worked briefly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the relationship between Hu Xufeng and Li Bin is concerned, since losing control of Hongrun Real Estate, Hu Xufeng said that he can no longer contact Li Bin. After Hu Xufeng started litigation to defend his rights, Li Bin reported Hu Xufeng to the public security agency on the grounds of gang involvement. Hu Xufeng also publicly reported Li Bin with his real name for the same reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 25, 2019, the Shaanxi Provincial Public Security Department handed over to Xi&#39;an the clues that Hu Xufeng reported about Li Bin and others&#39; suspected crimes in the form of a Director&#39;s Supervision Order (Supervision of Crime Leads No. 044) Verification by the Municipal Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xi’an Municipal Public Security Bureau confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that regarding the two people’s reports of each other, the public security organs did not find any illegal or criminal facts on both sides after a lot of work. Whistleblower”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a series of processes such as notarized delivery, convening of extraordinary shareholders&#39; meetings, and announcements, Hongrun Real Estate submitted materials for changing the legal representative to the Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau in April 2022. The bureau issued a &quot;Notice of Refusal to Registration&quot; on August 22 of that year, rejecting the application for change of registration on the grounds that the identity of the convener of the shareholders&#39; meeting did not comply with the provisions of the Company Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the processing results alone, Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau did not support Hu Xufeng&#39;s application for change of registration, nor did it support the applications of Li Bin and Wang Jian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hongrun Real Estate then sued the bureau to the Xi&#39;an Railway Transport Court. On December 30, 2022, the court issued a first-instance judgment in which Hongrun Real Estate won the case. The court ordered the Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau to re-administer Hongrun Real Estate&#39;s change application within 60 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau was dissatisfied and appealed to the Xi&#39;an Railway Transport Intermediate Court. On August 18, 2023, the second-instance court made a final judgment and upheld the original judgment. The Xi&#39;an Market Supervision Bureau lost the case again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that the bureau must re-administer the change application of Hongrun Real Estate within 60 days after the judgment takes effect. This equity war that has lasted for 9 years will come to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Note: The Xi&#39;an Municipal Public Security Bureau was interviewed about the transfer of Hu Xufeng&#39;s witness statement, and had exchanges with Wei Hua, deputy chief of the Information Section, The other party later asked for confirmation and there is a WeChat record.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陕西咸阳警方通报“女子被住建局保安踩在脚下”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 09:10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/5abd26a9848878c70264abe4914d0df2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;826&quot; height=&quot;1076&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5abd26a9848878c70264abe4914d0df2 . jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252279&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美伊“换囚游戏”，各有“算盘”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/pXNmTFP3LTBZpdcgUFIz9GGXcNd69gQQhcrdELuM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;701&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/pXNmTFP3LTBZpdcgUFIz9GGXcNd69g QQhcrdELuM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023 local time, Doha, Qatar, five people were detained in Iran The U.S. citizen was released and arrived at Doha International Airport with his family as part of a Qatar-brokered prisoner exchange deal between Iran and the United States that also freed five Iranians. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;prisoner exchange&quot; between the United States and Iran shocked the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 18, 2023, the United States and Iran exchanged five prisoners detained in the United States and Iran, allowing them to see the light of day again. The week before, the United States and Iran publicly reached a &quot;prisoner exchange agreement.&quot; The content of the agreement includes the United States unfreezing $6 billion of Iranian oil funds in South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This move caused waves in the political arena. The Biden administration has been strongly criticized by US Republicans, saying that unfreezing US$6 billion is equivalent to paying a &quot;ransom&quot; and is an &quot;appeasement policy.&quot; What puzzles the outside world is why the two countries, as &quot;old enemies&quot;, &quot;swap prisoners&quot; during this time period? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewed experts told Southern Weekend reporters that the United States and Iran have their own calculations behind this move, but it remains to be seen whether it can be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Prisoner Exchange&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Who are the arrested Americans? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before his arrest, 51-year-old businessman Siamak Namazi worked as the director of strategic planning at Dubai-based Crescent Petroleum Company. He was arrested by Iran&#39;s Revolutionary Guards in October 2015, while his 86-year-old father Bakr was arrested in February 2016 after Iranian officials allowed him to visit his son in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The British Broadcasting Corporation reported that they were eventually sentenced to ten years in prison by Iran for &quot;cooperating with foreign hostile countries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In recent years, the United States has repeatedly proposed to rescue or extradite Namazi. Because these people obviously serve the United States or have made great contributions to the United States, the United States is unwilling Give them up,&quot; said Li Shaoxian, director of the China Arab Studies Institute at Ningxia University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another 59-year-old Iranian-American businessman Emad Shaji moved to Iran from the United States with his wife in 2017. In November 2020, Iran&#39;s Revolutionary Court summoned him and informed him that he would be convicted of &quot;espionage&quot; and sentenced to 10 years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April of the following year, his daughters told the Washington Post that their father, Shaji, was in &quot;a deplorable situation&quot; in prison and that prison guards only allowed him to make a few brief, monitored phone calls. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tabaz, a 67-year-old businessman, was arrested together with eight other Iranian environmentalists in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The BBC reported that Tabaz’s organization, a member of the Persian Wildlife Heritage Foundation, has been using cameras to track critically endangered wild Asian cheetahs and was accused of using its environmental projects as a “gathering of confidential information” cover&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tabaz and his colleagues deny Iran&#39;s accusations against them. But in the end Tabaz was sentenced to 10 years in prison in 2019. He is being held in Evin prison in Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, these arrested American businessmen were released due to the &quot;prisoner exchange agreement&quot; between the United States and Iran. The names and circumstances of the other two Americans released have not yet been released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a statement after his release, Namazi expressed his gratitude and was very interested in knowing the progress of updating mobile phone equipment. &quot;When I was arrested, the iPhone 6S had just come out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side of the prisoner exchange, Iranian media confirmed on the afternoon of September 18, 2023 that five Iranian citizens imprisoned in the United States had also been released. . Of the five Iranians released, only two chose to return to Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Cavlani and Kashani were accused of violating &quot;sanctions.&quot; Afrasiabi, a political scientist living in Boston, was arrested at his home in 2021 on charges of being an &quot;agent of the Iranian government.&quot; Ansari and Hassanzadeh were accused of &quot;links to Iranian security forces.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaoxian said that the prisoner exchange matter contemplated by the United States and Iran is not a temporary decision. In fact, in the US-Iran relationship, the two sides have been fighting for each other to release their own people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States and Iran have always been &quot;old enemies&quot; and have no diplomatic relations. Qatar served as the mediator for this &quot;prisoner exchange&quot;. According to public reports, negotiations between the two parties were also conducted in Doha, the capital of Qatar. After at least eight rounds of back-and-forth between Qatar and Qatar, the United States and Iran&#39;s &quot;air-space negotiations&quot; finally reached a prisoner exchange agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2022, after Iran proposed its latest nuclear agreement plan, the United States believed that Iran had regressed and decided to withdraw from the negotiations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Iran&#39;s reason is that since the United States has withdrawn from the nuclear agreement, Iran is the official representative, so it does not need to face the United States. Face-to-face talks will not occur until the United States resumes the nuclear agreement.&quot; Li Shao said that at that time The EU agrees and agrees with the United States and condemns Iran, so it cannot continue to be the middleman now. &quot;Qatar therefore plays a very important role in this negotiation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Thaw&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The agreement, brokered by the Qatari government, represents It marked an unusual moment of cooperation between the United States and Iran and a rare agreement between two long-time enemies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This deal is an important stepping stone.” Sanan Wakil, director of the Middle East and North Africa program at Chatham House in the UK, said that the months-long negotiations have restarted the US-Iran relationship. Indirect bilateral dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bloomberg reported on September 19, 2023 that according to the prisoner exchange agreement, while the United States and Iran exchanged detainees, Iran’s previously frozen oil export payments of US$6 billion in South Korea were remitted to Qatar through Switzerland. Domestic Iranian bank account. The prisoners were released hours after the funds were unfrozen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea is a &quot;large consumer&quot; of Iranian oil, and the $6 billion that was unfrozen was previously South Korea&#39;s payment for Iranian oil. In 2010, the Central Bank of Iran opened Korean Won accounts in two South Korean banks specifically to collect payments from South Korea. At that time, Iran could withdraw the funds in the accounts at will. In September 2019, the Central Bank of Iran was included in the sanctions list by the United States, and US$6 billion in payments were frozen in the account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Iran is rich in oil and natural gas resources. For Iran, US$6 billion is a small amount of money under normal circumstances.&quot; Li Shaoxian analyzed, but for Iran in the past few years, &quot;it is definitely a timely help.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reuters reported that after Qatar and Switzerland confirmed that the funds were in the account, Qatar sent a plane to take five U.S. citizens and two of their relatives out of Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yin Gang, an expert on Middle East issues at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said that Iran is not only economically difficult, but also diplomatically. At present, Iran can accept such conditions, which shows that Iran urgently needs to ease its international status and change its international balance of payments situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, both the United States and Iran have &quot;different ideas&quot; regarding the implementation of the negotiation results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Washington Post&quot; reported that when the two sides reached a prisoner exchange agreement, Iran also specifically added the validity period of the agreement. That is, if the frozen payment is not received within two months, the prisoner exchange agreement will automatically be invalidated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The two sides have no trust at all, so they just set a deadline.&quot; Li Shaoxian said that this matter is relatively sensitive for both parties, and the United States and Iran have many different voices in the country. &quot;I think the two-month limit is considered from a realistic perspective, and it also reflects that both parties want to accomplish this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that US Republicans are criticizing the Biden administration&#39;s prisoner exchange. At the time of the move, it was stated that the unfreezing of 6 billion US dollars was equivalent to paying a ransom and may lead to more &quot;hostages&quot; being held. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although this group of U.S. citizens have been released, there is no guarantee that other Americans who decide to go to Iran despite long-term warnings from the U.S. government will get similar results.&quot; On September 18, the U.S. Secretary of State announced Lincoln warned the people at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Win or Lose&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The outside world has received mixed reviews about this prisoner exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Al Jazeera reported that Sina Tusi, a senior fellow at the Center for International Policy, a Washington think tank, said that the prisoner exchange was an &quot;important first step.&quot; She said, &quot;This creates a basis for the United States and Iran to get rid of hostile and confrontational policies, and is expected to reach a broader diplomatic agreement.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States will hold a presidential election in November 2024, and at this stage, the two sides have restarted negotiations Friendly relations are unrealistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tusi said Biden was unlikely to make concessions to Iran before the vote, which would draw attacks from Republican hawks. Iran, on the other hand, hopes to maintain its influence &quot;in case Trump returns to power.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Washington Post&quot; reported on September 19 that the prisoner exchange agreement was a signal of partial easing of US-Iran relations. It marked a breakthrough in relations between the United States and Iran, long-time enemies, although the two countries remain at odds on a range of issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Objective analysis shows that the United States has made a compromise.&quot; Li Shaoxian pointed out that in addition to US$6 billion, the Biden administration actually &quot;turned a blind eye&quot; to Iran&#39;s oil exports. Therefore, Iran&#39;s oil exports have increased significantly in recent months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;On the one hand, this move can be seen as a sign of the easing of bilateral relations between the United States and Iran. On the other hand, the United States also wants to reduce the diplomatic pressure on South Korea.&quot; Yin Gang analyzed the current relationship between the United States and South Korea Also very important. If South Korea does not pay oil to Iran, it will have great dissatisfaction with South Korea and will bring great difficulties to South Korea&#39;s diplomacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But American Republicans have different opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 18, former US President Trump publicly stated, &quot;The United States, which was highly respected three years ago, has now become the laughing stock of the world.&quot; Former Vice President Pence criticized Biden, Allowing Iran to “foment terrorism across the Middle East.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaoxian analyzed that the struggle between the two parties in the United States is now booming, and the two parties are even more sharply opposed on the Iran issue and the Iranian nuclear issue. Although Biden did not lift sanctions on Iran after taking office, his goal is to restore the nuclear agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surprisingly, on the day of the prisoner exchange, Biden issued a statement saying that the United States would impose sanctions on former Iranian President Ahmadinejad and the Iranian Intelligence Ministry on the grounds that relevant individuals and Institutions are complicit in “wrongfully imprisoning” American citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wall Street Journal commented on September 19 that the Biden administration has been trying to ease tensions with Iran, but it is clear that exchanging prisoners while imposing new sanctions on Iran will complicate the problem again. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the continued sanctions imposed by the United States, it seems to have become the norm for countries around the world to face restrictive measures in certain areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Iranian President Raisi said that the United States has no right to decide how Iran will use the $6 billion in funds that are about to be unfrozen. He emphasized that the frozen funds originally belonged to the Iranian people and the Iranian government, and the use was not determined by the U.S. government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaoxian analyzed that Iran’s nuclear technology capabilities have improved very quickly. &quot;The United States is very anxious, and Europe is also anxious.&quot; He said that under such circumstances, although the United States publicly did not lift sanctions, it gradually released its policies to whet Iran&#39;s appetite. Iran also deliberately slowed down the production of highly enriched uranium. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There have been rumors in the international community that behind the deal, Iran promised to have active dialogue with the United States in the next step on the nuclear issue.&quot; Yin Gang said that at present, the entire Middle East The situation is on the trend of easing, between Iran and Arab countries, and between Iran and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When will there be a breakthrough in the long-stalled Iranian nuclear negotiations? Will the tension between the United States and Iran gradually ease? These issues will also affect the trend of the global political landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Xu Ziyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[失落的1945——张爱玲“笔误”解谜丨云端]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/MOoJJcgGQN3BIjhiUWiurpcBJO2W25OAjeX0Mvgd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;726&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/MOoJJcgGQN3BIjhiUWiurpcBJO2W25OAjeX0 Mvgd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Manuscript of Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel &quot;Little Reunion&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I forgot again&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Ailing There are many examples of poor memory. Reading the 700,000-word &quot;Collected Letters of Zhang Ailing&quot; edited by Song Yilang and recently published by Crown has deepened this feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, Zhang Ailing’s bad memory focused on dates and numbers. The more famous &quot;public case&quot; is about the &quot;Genius Dream&quot; which gave birth to Zhang&#39;s famous saying &quot;Life is a gorgeous robe, covered with lice&quot;. Until her later years, Zhang Ailing was still bitter about the &quot;unfair treatment&quot; she suffered in the &quot;West Wind&quot; essay competition when she was 19 years old. However, scholars and Zhang fans have verified that she remembered everything wrong, whether it was the limit on the number of words in the essay, the format of the essay, or even the awards. , and maybe I didn’t read the specific terms of the essay advertisement clearly back then. The number of words in the competition was limited to 5,000, but she mistakenly thought it was 500; when she finally won the third honorary award, she wrote it as a &quot;special award&quot;; she even recorded the more than 1,500 words of her award-winning article as more than 490 words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was looking through old magazines at home not long ago and accidentally found the July 2004 issue of &quot;Yin Ke&quot;. In this issue of Zhang Ailing&#39;s album, there was published a letter she wrote to the Chinese Embassy in Washington on June 4, 1966. Letter from the British Embassy. At the time, Eileen Chang was interested in applying for a position as a writer-in-residence at a university and required proof of academic qualifications. Due to the loss of her documents, she wrote to the University of Hong Kong to request a replacement. However, the Registrar of the University of Hong Kong only certified that she had &quot;two ins and two outs&quot; and did not mention that she had received a certificate for her excellent academic performance. Scholarships and other honors, several negotiations failed. At that time, Hong Kong was still under British rule, so she wrote to the British Embassy in Washington for help. To explain his situation, there is this paragraph in the letter of more than a thousand words: &quot;...I immigrated to the United States in 1955, married an American in the 1960s, and obtained American citizenship. My mother has been naturalized as a British citizen, and she was a British citizen in 1958. Passed away in London...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had never read this letter before, and I was very interested. But I was really surprised when I read this: She and Laiya registered their marriage in August 1956, the second year after arriving in the United States. On August 14th and August 18th, she also wrote to Kuang Wenmei, why did it suddenly become the &quot;60s&quot;? Her mother Huang Yifan died of illness in London on October 11, 1957. On October 24, she accurately reported in a letter to Song Qi and his wife that her mother had &quot;died two weeks ago&quot;, but the letter to the embassy read &quot;1958&quot; in black and white. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/J7ek9M46hhsAvN7cc670HxW3bYAzesTK5Rxozede.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;1593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/J7ek9M46hhsAvN7cc670HxW3bYAzesTK5Rxozede.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The photo that her mother took with her when she left China returned to Zhang Ailing after her death. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This letter was translated into Chinese by Chen Ziyu, and Su Weizhen wrote the introduction. Neither of them discovered it, so it was also There is no &quot;clerical error&quot; noted in the letter. Indeed, no one would have thought that in 1966, Zhang Ailing was 46 years old and was only middle-aged. No matter how bad her memory was, she would not have mistaken the year of her mother&#39;s death and the year of her remarriage. Moreover, she wrote a formal letter to an official agency. inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, when I saw so many &quot;I remembered wrongly&quot; and &quot;I forgot again&quot; in the collection of letters between Zhang Ailing and Song Qi, I was no longer surprised. Zhang Ailing lives largely on royalties in the United States, but she can&#39;t even figure out whether Crown Publishing&#39;s fixed royalties for a certain period of time are US$2,000 for half a year or a year. What&#39;s even more outrageous is that before leaving Hong Kong for the United States in 1955, with the help of Song Qi, she advanced all the royalties for two scripts from the Telecom Company, but she forgot all about it five years later. Only after being reminded by Kwong Wenmei did she remember that she had done so. This is the case. It is simply unbelievable that a person who is most afraid of owing money or favors would forget such a sum of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few days, I have been browsing a collection of essays by book reviewer Liu Zheng, and I came across an article titled &quot;Zhang Ailing Remembers Wrongly&quot;, which records the errors in words, sources, plots, and mistakes in Zhang Ailing&#39;s works. , a total of 22 cases, which is eye-opening. Regarding citation errors, I also read in Chen Zishan&#39;s &quot;Cong Kao of Zhang Ailing&quot; that Zhang Ailing quoted Lu Xun&#39;s translation of the Soviet writer Shuxue Jianke (also translated as Zuoqenko) in 1926 in &quot;Talk about Eating and Painting Cake to Appease Hungry&quot;. The short story &quot;Women of a Noble Family&quot; in 2000 was mistakenly written as &quot;Baozi&quot;; while &quot;Baozi&quot; written by Zhang Ailing was actually translated by Lu Xun as &quot;Meat Buns&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both Chen Zishan and Liu Zheng are sharp-eyed and knowledgeable, but they still respect Zhang Ailing. Liu Zheng said: &quot;In terms of human relations and physics, as well as in choosing words and sentences, Zhang Ailing can be said to be a very thoughtful person. However, she did not seem to care much about whether the quotations were accurate. In addition, it was very difficult to check the information at that time, so Zhang Ailing She doesn’t have the habit of collecting books, so it’s normal to have some misremembering when quoting. To put it into perspective, Zhang Ailing obviously doesn’t have a ‘photographic memory’, maybe she just has a poor memory; what she left behind There are really not too many clerical errors.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zheng explained that he had no other intention in writing down these when he was studying, but just for fun - Zhang Ailing would also remember it wrong! At the end of the article, a sentence from Sontag&#39;s novel &quot;The Volcano Lover&quot; was quoted: &quot;Genius, like beauty, everything, well almost everything, will be forgiven.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, He attributed the clerical errors to memory and unverified information. On the contrary, Zhang Ailing said in &quot;Contrast Notes&quot;: Freud, the master of psychological analysis, believed that there is no clerical error or an occasional wrong word, it is all what he thought in his heart and revealed it inadvertently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it was also in &quot;Contrast Notes&quot; that Zhang Ailing left another famous &quot;clerical error&quot;: the well-documented &quot;cool party&quot; in Shanghai on July 21, 1945 The photo taken with Li Xianglan was annotated as &quot;Meet the movie star Li Xianglan at a garden party in 1943.&quot; As if following the Freudian line of thinking mentioned by Eileen Chang, two scholars have tried to analyze whether Chang Eileen&#39;s &quot;clerical error&quot; of &quot;one or two years&quot; was just due to poor memory, or there is another meaningful reason behind it. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1945&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cooling Party/1943 Garden Party&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Comparative Notes - Looking at Old Photo Albums&quot; is Zhang Ailing&#39;s last work This work is also her only autobiographical collection of pictures and texts. &quot;Picture 41&quot; in the book is a photo of her and Li Xianglan that has been treasured for nearly 50 years. She wrote: In 1943, she met Li Xianglan at a garden party and wanted to take a photo together. She was too tall and the two of them would complement each other if they stood side by side. , someone asked her to sit down, and Li Xianglan stood aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/iEioqzjAsX9CGyu33WRvaDrFnNz5X5Lb1h9JvdFX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;693&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/iEioqzjAsX9CGyu33WRvaDrFnNz5X5Lb1h9JvdFX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1943, Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan (right) took a photo in Shanghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The book &quot;After Yun&quot; mentions clothes made from the quilt cover of my grandmother&#39;s bed. This is the one. It was taken down by my aunt and saved. Although the tailor said that &#39;chen silk is like rotten grass&#39;, the tailor did not frown, took it without saying a word, and made it according to Yanying&#39;s design. The beige thin silk was sprinkled with light The ink dots hide a dark purple phoenix, which is very picturesque. I have never seen a similar pattern elsewhere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;1943&quot;, this year is ridiculously wrong, the correct time and place is: July 1945 On the 21st, a &quot;cool party&quot; hosted by &quot;Magazine&quot; was held at No. 2 Xianyang Road, Shanghai. The basis is &quot;Magazine&quot; in August 1945, which published the article &quot;Records of Enjoying the Cool Coolness&quot;. In addition to this picture of Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan, there is another group photo: Li Xianglan and Zhang Ailing maintain the same posture, and Zhang Ailing&#39;s aunt is also seen. Zhang Maoyuan, his best friend Yan Ying, an unidentified Ms. Chen, and two men in long gowns - Chen Binhe, the president of the Shenbao Press during the Wang puppet period, and Jin Xiongbai, the president of the Pingbao Press. According to Shao Yingjian, a Chinese scholar who studied in Japan and is now a researcher in Japan, in the book &quot;The Legendary Literature and Rumor Life of Zhang Ailing&quot;, Xianyang Road was the name of the current Shaanxi South Road from 1943 to 1945. It was older. The name familiar to Shanghainese is &quot;Yalpe Road&quot;. No. 2 Xianyang Road was the garden of Jin Xiongbai’s private residence at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, when &quot;Contrast&quot; was published, it was the year before Zhang Ailing&#39;s death. In her declining years, she had to study the skirt that she had changed from her grandmother&#39;s old quilt cover, from the texture, color, pattern, Patterns, origins, styles, designs, and tailors are all fresh and clear in my memory. Why do I remember the wrong time and place when I took the photo? What kind of information does this 1943, this &quot;clerical error&quot; reveal? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shao Yingjian believes that if you understand Zhang Ailing’s life, this mystery will not be difficult to solve. For Zhang Ailing, 1943 to 1945 were the most glorious days in this life. She wrote &quot;Legend&quot; and &quot;Rumors&quot; in just two years, and she rose to the top of the literary world when she was just starting out. &quot;In the database of the brain, this is a A perfect file, with no details, displayed in its entirety on the screen of memory.&quot; - This statement is very tempting: in the stage of life when the fire is burning, the oil is blooming, and the flowers are blooming, the memory is mixed and unclear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for what Shao Yingjian pointed out, Zhang Ailing wrote &quot;cooling party&quot; as &quot;garden party&quot;, in my opinion, it does not seem to be a clerical error, just like some people say that going to a &quot;theater&quot; or &quot;cinema&quot; to watch a movie is not a mistake. substantial difference. But researcher Shao focused on the difference between the two words and found his answer - interestingly, he also made a &quot;clerical error&quot;. After checking several versions of &quot;Contrast Notes&quot;, Zhang Ailing wrote &quot;Garden Party&quot; Rather than a &quot;garden party&quot; - he found out from the old &quot;Declaration&quot; that on July 8, 1944, the Wang Puppet &quot;Shanghai Press Association&quot; held a party in the central square of Hartung Garden, attended by thousands of people from all walks of life. &quot;Citizen Garden Lecture&quot;, the program includes red star singing and movie card screening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although he did not specifically mention the red star singing that night or the celebrities attending the meeting, Shao Wen determined that the red star was &quot;most likely&quot; the popular Li Xianglan, and Zhang Ailing, who is already a celebrity in the maritime literary world, &quot;naturally&quot; should also Be present. He deduced from this that it was on this occasion that Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan met for the first time: &quot;...the first tangible and tangible meeting was at this garden party. The impression on them was profound and indelible. As the years passed, As time went by, the subsequent impressions became shallow and flat, leaving only this scratch. How many years later, in Zhang Ailing’s brain inventory, all the fate with Li Xianglan was merged into this time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;He further said that when Zhang Ailing stood on the balcony of her apartment (Eddington Apartment, today&#39;s Changde Apartment), she could see a corner of Hartung Garden. Hartung Garden can also be regarded as Zhang Ailing’s neighborhood. Zhang Ailing also mentioned this legendary garden twice in her 1944 serial &quot;Serial Set&quot; in Vientiane. &quot;Although the scale of Jin Xiongbai&#39;s private garden and Hartung Garden are not the same, there are some similarities: they are both Western-style houses with flower beds and lawns. Just based on the background of the photo and the Western-style cushion chairs, in Zhang Ailing&#39;s memory, , unknowingly, the garden of Jin Xiongbai&#39;s private residence was replaced by Hartung Garden, and the &#39;cooling party&#39; also turned into a &#39;garden party.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s right. One thing is certain: Zhang Ailing has never mentioned and has not seen any information showing that she has been to the &quot;garden party&quot; in Hartung Gardens. Therefore, Mr. Shao&#39;s discussion based on assumptions has a strong reasoning component and is more like a It is a imaginative fiction. The mystery of forgetting is complicated and confusing, and a convincing analysis comes from Professor Wong Sham-cun, Chairman of the Department of Comparative Literature at the University of Hong Kong. In a wonderful essay, she spent six and a half pages discussing the photo of Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan taken three weeks before Japan surrendered, and put forward a meaningful &quot;maybe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“I don’t remember a thing in this year”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Picture 50” in “Contrast Notes” is a picture of Zhang Ailing leaving Hong Kong in 1955 In the photo before America, the makeup is exquisite, the side face is lowered and the eyes are downcast. Eileen Chang described taking a boat from Hong Kong and passing through Honolulu. The customs officer was a skinny Japanese young man who clearly filled out her entry form: height 6 feet 6 and a half inches and weight 102 pounds. She laughed at the young man&#39;s carelessness and made a Freudian slip by writing 5 feet 6 and a half inches as 6 feet 6 and a half inches. &quot;I am thin and look very tall. That is the shocking record of this customs officer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /26/g8ajGWryb6p5fYU92Aa3zTiqI33SZTgtDdLC5XE5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;1738&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/g8ajGWryb6p5fYU92Aa3zTiqI33SZT gtDdLC5XE5.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Contrast Notes&quot; contains photos of Zhang Ailing before she left Hong Kong for the United States in 1955. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Picture 41&quot; in &quot;Contrast Notes&quot;, Zhang Ailing was &quot;careless&quot; and mistakenly recorded as &quot;1943&quot; &quot;Year&quot; frame with Li Xianglan is considered by scholars to be the most important photo of her in Shanghai. Professor Huang Xincun has a paper &quot;Mottled Light and Shadow: Zhang Ailing&#39;s Japan and East Asia&quot;, and his analysis starts from this photo. Taken on July 21, 1945, just three weeks before the end of World War II and Japan’s surrender, “Its strange composition and uncoordinated visual style are also impressive. Viewers who are familiar with the background of the photo even regard it as a depiction.” On the eve of the collapse of the Japanese Empire, a visual allegory of the crumbling Japanese-Chinese combination.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Huang’s analysis of the photo focuses on the different expressions of Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan, the strange composition of the photo, and their different dressing styles, especially It’s Zhang Ailing’s perverse sitting posture, her downward gaze away from the camera, and all the details. She said, &quot;Zhang Ailing&#39;s facial expressions and body may imply resistance or contempt, but more importantly, she obviously knows how to turn the gaze of the camera lens on her into a help to deepen her own image.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;What I am more interested in is how did Zhang Ailing, her aunt, and Yan Ying go to this &quot;garden party&quot; three weeks before Japan was defeated? Japan unconditionally surrendered on August 15, and the current situation suddenly changed. Hu Lancheng, who had been an important member of the Wang Puppet Government, was wanted by the Nationalist Government and fled hastily. How did it bring shock and panic to Zhang Ailing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suddenly it occurred to me that I should review &quot;Little Reunion&quot;. What happened in the long summer of 1945 is described in the book. Moreover, at the beginning of Chapter 8, what Zhang Ailing wrote about Jiuli was simply an annotation in advance for her subsequent &quot;clerical error&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;From this time until the end of World War II , for more than half a year, there was a kind of chaos in her heart, which was sealed with a layer of white wax, which was a sense of calm and security on the surface. What happened during this period was always regarded as the previous year or the next year. &quot;...I don&#39;t remember a single thing in this year. It can be called a lost year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When she first met him, she knew that he was going to flee after the war, but she became confused when things happened. , also because this was her &#39;lost year&#39; and she was devastated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despondent, she banished 1945 in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Maybe Zhang Ailing herself doesn&#39;t want to believe that this photo was taken on the eve of Japan&#39;s defeat.&quot; Huang Xincun wrote a sentence in the &quot;Notes&quot; of the paper that is heart-stopping. Yes, there is no 1945, only 1943, only the previous year or the next year. Although &quot;Contrast&quot; was published in 1994, half a century after those unbearable and chaotic days, she still remembered that there was a kind of Freudian error. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Psychology has a lot to say about memory and forgetting. Whether Zhang Ailing left defective memories a year before her death was due to retrograde amnesia caused by damage to the hippocampus of the brain, or active forgetting of emotional memories, it is no longer a question. Of course, exploring the secrets involved is not to &quot;disenchant&quot;. As Huang Xinchun said, it is only to &quot;restore a historical Eileen Chang&quot; and &quot;a more complex Eileen Chang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subconsciously shielding the unbearable past and deleting the dark aspects on the memory chip. Isn’t it true for us, many ordinary &quot;people&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I strongly agree with this statement: What ultimately constitutes a person&#39;s life is not experience, spirituality, or any events, but the memory, description, and interpretation of all these experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matsuo Basho has a haiku: The temple bell/stopped, but the lingering sound in the flowers/continues to echo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[二十届中央第一轮巡视完成反馈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257717]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the deployment of the Party Central Committee, the first round of inspection and feedback work of the 20th Central Committee has been completed recently. Feedback from this round of inspections is carried out through a combination of centralized feedback and &quot;one-on-one&quot; feedback from the inspection team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, the Central Inspection Leading Group held a centralized feedback meeting on the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee. The meeting conveyed and studied the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the Central Committee’s first round of inspection reports, informed the common problems discovered during the inspection, and made arrangements for rectification during the inspection. Liu Jinguo, secretary of the Central Secretariat and deputy leader of the Central Inspection Leading Group, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From September 20th to 22nd, 15 central inspection teams conducted &quot;one-on-one&quot; meetings with the party groups of 30 medium-sized enterprises, 5 party committees of medium-sized financial enterprises, and the party group of the State Sports General Administration during this round of inspections. feedback. According to the Central Inspection Work Arrangement, each Central Inspection Team notified the principals of the inspected party organizations of the outstanding problems discovered during the inspection, and reported the inspection situation to the leadership team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feedback pointed out that in recent years, centrally managed enterprises and financial enterprises have faced the complex and severe external environment and the impact of the epidemic. They have withstood the test and bravely shouldered heavy responsibilities. They have been successful in winning the battle against poverty and promoting high-level scientific and technological self-reliance. It has made important contributions in building a new development pattern, promoting high-quality development, coordinating epidemic prevention and control, and economic and social development, and has made new progress in building a sports power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The feedback seriously pointed out the outstanding problems existing in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance and sports. Some fail to implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, do not have a deep understanding of the responsibilities and missions they shoulder, and have gaps in their performance of duties; some do not coordinate development and safety, have weak risk awareness, and have insufficient prevention and control mechanisms; some implement party management The responsibility for party governance is not in place, the pressure transmission is decreasing layer by layer, the implementation of the strict tone is weak, the integrity risks of key positions such as &quot;top leaders&quot; are relatively prominent, the problem of &quot;depending on the enterprise to take advantage of the enterprise&quot; is common, the &quot;four styles&quot; problem is prominent, and it violates the eight central regulations Mental problems still occur; there are weak links in the construction of some leadership groups and cadre talent teams, and the political functions of grassroots party organizations need to be strengthened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The feedback requires that the inspected units should thoroughly study Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, conscientiously study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the inspection report, and fully implement the deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s leadership, firmly establish and practice a correct view of political performance, completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, adhere to functional positioning, focus on main responsibilities and main businesses, and promote high-quality development. It is necessary to resolutely implement the political responsibility to prevent and resolve major risks, establish bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking, comprehensively sort out and investigate hidden risks, plug leaks and fill gaps, resolve risks and recover losses, and effectively safeguard national interests. It is necessary to conscientiously implement the &quot;two responsibilities&quot; of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, strengthen the effectiveness of supervision of &quot;top leaders&quot;, intensify the investigation and handling of corruption cases, seriously correct the &quot;four styles&quot; problem, deepen the use of cases to promote reform, use cases to promote treatment, and integrate We dare not, cannot, or do not want to be corrupted. It is necessary to thoroughly implement the party&#39;s organizational line in the new era and effectively strengthen the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feedback emphasized that inspections and rectifications should be more serious and tough, and the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere should be passed on and carried out consistently. The inspected party organization must resolutely shoulder the political responsibility for rectification. The &quot;top leader&quot; is the first person responsible for rectification. Other members of the team must conscientiously perform &quot;one post, two responsibilities&quot;, strictly compare feedback opinions, and establish a problem list, task list, and responsibility list. Combining the problems found during the inspection with the theme education inspection issues and the problems that were not rectified in the last inspection, rectify the system and rectify the whole body, practice the &quot;two maintenances&quot; with practical actions, and reflect the loyalty and responsibility with the rectification results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The feedback requires that the responsibilities of all parties for rectification should be consolidated and efforts should be made in the same direction to solve the problem. Discipline inspection and supervision agencies must strengthen daily supervision of rectification, focus on key issues, focus on specific people and specific matters, strengthen on-the-spot inspections, grasp the real situation, and seize examples of those who deal with perfunctory or false rectifications and seriously hold accountable them. The organizational department should strengthen research and guidance based on the inspection situation, and promote the solution of outstanding problems in the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. Relevant functional departments must comprehensively make full use of the inspection results, strengthen daily supervision of common and deep-seated problems reflected in the inspection, deepen reforms in key areas, optimize policy supply, and improve systems and mechanisms. Inspection agencies must strengthen overall coordination and supervision, establish and improve rectification work mechanisms, and report important situations to the Party Central Committee in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the Central Inspection Team has also received clues about problems reported by some leading cadres, and has transferred them to the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission, the Organization Department of the Central Committee and other relevant parties for handling in accordance with relevant regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访胡歌：如果不做演员，生活里的我应该什么样？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257715]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Throughout September, Hu Ge’s work was fully scheduled. He had just attended related activities at the Venice Film Festival, and then flew back to Beijing to attend the premiere of the movie &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/i696A6YUsdAgCij7tPH3N2q1voWbuMVhpkbNsLQz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/i696A6YUsdAgCij7tPH3N2q1voWbuMVhpkbNsLQz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Ge (left) and &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; director Liu Jiayin at a business dinner at the Shanghai International Film Festival in June 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to promote this low-cost literary film, Hu Ge traveled to seven cities in nine days, non-stop to Group after group of viewers shared their feelings about the male protagonist Wen Shan. He said: &quot;When I meet a character I like, I am not playing him, but becoming him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film&#39;s director Liu Jiayin expressed his &quot;jealousy&quot; of Hu Ge: &quot;This character is obviously mine. But I feel like you understand him better than I do. Now I understand that the extra thing is yourself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan is nearly forty years old and was once a failed entrepreneur. The screenwriter, because he believes that &quot;ordinary people can also be the protagonist&quot;, has never been able to write a script that satisfies Party A. Over time, he gradually lost confidence in himself and gave up this career. The character that he could not write became a part of his heart, transforming into a boy named Xiao Yin, who often jumped out of his mind to talk to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wen Shan was in school, he liked to go to funeral parlors and zoos to take notes on his life, which later became a habit. After his life fell into embarrassment, he accidentally found a new job - writing articles for clients to commemorate their deceased relatives and friends. After completing an article, he could get 4,000 yuan, which could just cover his room and board expenses in the suburbs of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan always wears baggy clothes that have been washed too many times. He is habitually hunched over and has long hair that covers his eyes. He cuts his nails frequently because of typing all the time. He likes to buy large buckets of mineral water and directly Lift it up and drink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first glance, there is not much connection between the frustrated Wen Shan and Hu Ge himself, except that the latter has also come into contact with many screenwriters at work. Hu Ge told the Southern Weekend reporter with some regret: &quot;This industry is sometimes quite abnormal. Unless the screenwriter is a big shot, he has almost no power of expression. Most of the time, he can only wait to be evaluated, without even a chance to refute. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hu Ge’s eyes, Wen Shan is a person who is unwilling to compromise. It’s not that he doesn’t know how to write (scripts) to gain favor, but he is unwilling to do things he doesn’t want to do. &quot;I hope to be such a person, but often I can&#39;t. I envy him very much.&quot; Hu Ge said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2023, Hu Ge suddenly disclosed the news of getting married and having a daughter on Weibo. It quickly became a hot search list and there were constant discussions on the Internet. He did not hesitate to share the joy of becoming a father for the first time: &quot;When I held my daughter for the first time, it was like holding a piece of tofu. I was afraid that I would break her if I shook her.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Get married and have children. I have considered this before, but never took action. I made this decision after playing the role of Wen Shan. This role brought me a lot of changes and influence. After playing this role, I have a lot of confidence to do it. I think it’s a choice that should be made,” Hu Ge told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty years after his debut, Hu Ge is no longer a young guy like Li Xiaoyao in &quot;Legend of Sword and Fairy&quot;, but closer to Mei Changsu who narrowly escaped death in &quot;Nirvana in Fire&quot;. Attentive viewers will find that whenever the shots of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; show a close-up of Hu Ge, the scar on his right eye is clearly visible. He has already been able to face the impact of the car accident in 2006. In the first two or three scenes after the car accident, Hu Ge used his bangs to cover the scar, but then he let it go: &quot;If I can&#39;t pass this test myself, how can I let others accept it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;After works such as &quot;Nirvana in Fire&quot; and &quot;The Pretender&quot;, the audience began to pay attention to Hu Ge&#39;s acting skills, and he decided to &quot;stop&quot; and &quot;put down some of his current work and concentrate on experiencing life.&quot; After a few years, &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; may be regarded as Hu Ge&#39;s answer. With this film, he won the Best Actor Award at the 25th Shanghai International Film Festival. At the award ceremony, he said: &quot; When an actor truly falls in love with a character, he will give himself completely to the character.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/26/m0wYwiSsUoiV4OaxXvNhtGAIoiNsQ4VHZX5MklBS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 26/m0wYwiSsUoiV4OaxXvNhtGAIoiNsQ4VHZX5MklBS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Ge rests at the closing ceremony of the 25th Shanghai International Film Festival district. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One afternoon in mid-September 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend interviewed Hu Ge via online connection , the original interview time was only half an hour, but Hu Ge said: &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, I am willing to chat more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Hu Ge&#39;s self-report:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;He has me in him The Firmness That Is Not Possessed&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; talks about ordinary people, allowing many viewers to see themselves in it. (I) traveled to seven cities to do road shows, and the audience was willing to share their own experiences of facing the death of relatives and friends when communicating. This is where I can most empathize. This script has many intersections with my own life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, my mother passed away, and I wrote the eulogy myself. So when I first read the script, I was not Wen Shan, but one of his clients. I still haven&#39;t fully recovered from this experience, and it will take me a long time to accept the end of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this, I had never thought that there were people like Wen Shan in my life. In our traditional culture, we seem to be very shy about talking about death and the end of life. Therefore, when a loved one passes away, it is usually difficult to find someone to share and talk to. This script gave me a warm feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan has another meaning to me. In current terms, he is an &quot;i person&quot; (Editor&#39;s note: a result of the MBTI personality test that has become popular in recent years, and &quot;e person&quot; ” In contrast, the two are approximately equivalent to introverts and extroverts respectively), introverts. He is not good at expressing himself or getting along with others. To be honest, the real me may be such a character. But he has a firmness that I don&#39;t have, and he won&#39;t change his choices because of external evaluations and so-called worldly standards. This is something I envy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw in him a part of myself that I couldn’t achieve, my ideal look, and I really wanted to be him. Even though he is not a person with a strong sense of presence, he is still very dignified at heart. This kind of axis is a kind of courage, persistence and courage to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am an i person at heart, but I don’t look like me. This may have something to do with my career and environment. As an i person, Wenshan is more able to stick to his own choices, but I often can&#39;t. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a screenwriter, Wen Shan seems not to be that successful, not because of ability, but because of choice. He insists on his own aesthetic and is unwilling to change his creative direction. Throughout his career, he had almost no opportunity to express himself, and his works were always rejected by others before he could complete them. But what is rare is that he never said that he must seek the approval of others. This is an inner persistence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The turning point in Wen Shan’s life came when he got the job of writing eulogies for others by chance. Although this job is completely different from being a screenwriter, they are both creating with words. At work, Wen Shan found a sense of identity. This did not mean that everyone praised him for writing well, but that he used his kindness and sincerity to influence others through constant communication. For example, Mr. Wang in the film re-understood his deceased father through Wen Shan&#39;s eulogy. This is the meaning of Wen Shan&#39;s work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/pf6D5BNM6E4lSzTB57y1Lxai5d60id3WlXYJbTCa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/pf6D5BNM6E4lSzTB57y1Lxai5d60id3WlXYJbTCa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影《不虚此行》中，客户王先生的儿子对胡歌饰演的闻善（右）袒露心中的秘密，闻善由此发现这家人彼此之间无言的爱。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（片方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我并不认为《不虚此行》主要表达的东西是死亡，它借着死亡讲的是我们怎样书写人生。闻善从一个编剧到写悼词的人，他在用笔创作人物，书写别人的故事。回过头看，我们在用每天的生活书写自己的人生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一个阶段人会变化，但和具体的年龄无关，反而和经历有关。 2019年，我的母亲去世了，接着我们又经历了三年的疫情，看到了很多生离死别。这个过程中，我想不仅仅是我，很多人都会对生命有更多的思考。 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;大部分人都是主角&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;什么叫普通人？普通人并不是通常理解的特别平庸的人，而是相对于那些带有主角光环的人而言的。后者身上往往有特别强的戏剧冲突，在生活中发生了很多奇迹。但生活中普通人才是大部分，我们生活中很难遇到偶像剧主角那样的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片强调的“普通人也能做主角”，就是说大部分人都是主角。我们对于成功的定义好像太标准化了，一切事情都变得很功利。其实每个人的轨迹都不一样，有时候把眼光和目标放得太统一了，很容易就错过人生真正重要的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于个体来说，我们原本就在自己的故事里，在自己的成长轨迹中，你当然就是自己的主角，为什么非要当自己是配角呢？ （为什么）非要把符合所谓概念中的成功的人物形象称为主角呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是一个经常容易纠结的人，内心的自我和闻善很接近，只不过因为我的各种好运气，让我的人生过得和偶像剧一样。从内心来说，我确实对自己的人生是有问号的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;闻善和我以往塑造的角色都不一样，几乎所有的角色都带有主角光环，即使带着某些缺陷，也一定有特别厉害的能力，是所谓的“悲情英雄”。我以往塑造角色都是在做加法，要在身上叠加各种能力才能抵达人物，但这一次是做减法，需要把现在身上附加的各种东西卸下来，回到最初的自己。说得简单一点，如果我不做演员的话，我在生活里应该是什么样？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次我并没有刻意设计什么动作，我塑造闻善，并不是去演这个人物，而是成为他，所以没有用一些特别外化的方式，而是先靠近人物的内心，其他的东西就是一种自然流露。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小尹是闻善内心的镜像，作为一个倾听者，闻善是孤独的，很少能够找到让他可以倾诉的对象，他不得不学会和自己相处。小尹的存在就是用了一个特别的方式去呈现孤独的人如何与自己相处，这样他至少不是寂寞的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/MC2AiDpZGMtuM4xiW492lOe04yepgJnApFZGdZ0L.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/MC2AiDpZGMtuM4xiW492lOe04yepgJnApFZGdZ0L.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影《不虚此行》中，胡歌饰演的闻善（左）和他内心的小尹（右，吴磊饰）。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（片方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真正可悲的是孤独的人还要承受寂寞，孤独却不寂寞，是一个相对理想的状态。小尹是闻善心中更积极大胆的部分，但这一面一直被压抑着，他的内心一直存在着自我对抗和纠结。小尹一直在推着闻善更加勇敢地面对现实。最后小尹消失了，代表闻善找到了自信，可以作为编剧继续创作，让小尹回到了剧本世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己的身体里恐怕不止一个小尹，经常有些小小的分裂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;演员是动物园里的大猩猩&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;闻善会经常观察周围的环境和人物，做生活笔记，片中最重要的两个场景殡仪馆和动物园，都是闻善爱去的地方，他可以静静观察周围的人和物。我自己可能也有所谓的职业病，喜欢观察遇到的人，并不是说我演了某个角色，我才要去找一些人物作为参考，而是和福尔摩斯似的，看见一个不认识的人从眼前走过，忍不住会猜测对方的职业履历和家庭关系，会想象这个人刚才在做什么，又经历过什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不习惯去给过去的角色贴标签，每一个角色对我都很有意义。都说电影电视就是遗憾的艺术，没有办法重来，但我会经常反思，每当演完一个角色，就会去想自己哪里演得不好。可能我并不是一个那么有自信的人，即使别人说如何的好，我还是会给自己挑出毛病来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看完《不虚此行》的剧本，我就开始了和导演刘伽茵长达半年的网络交流。那段时间，我一直在《繁花》剧组，基本每天都要开工，只能和刘伽茵导演通过微信沟通，我们第一次见面就是定妆那天，我都已经进组开工了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;合作过这么多导演，每一位的工作方法都不一样，和演员的交流相处也不一样，我觉得对于导演来说，如何启发演员、引导演员，是工作中特别重要的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孔笙导演会给演员特别大的空间，他可能会给你一个大的方向，然后具体的表演方式他会特别放心地交给演员。姜伟导演同时还是非常优秀的编剧，他的剧本所有的台词都无法调整，就连语气词都非常准确。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王家卫导演给我的感觉反而和之前一些媒体报道的不同，他之前的电影在拍摄的过程中可能没有特别具体的方向，但这次我感到他特别知道自己想要什么，也会表达得十分具体。当然有时候他也会让你去突破，如果能够给到他意料之外的火花，也就是更好的即兴的表演，他也会非常欣赏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时候，角色就是不同形状的瓶子，演员就是水。每次进入到不同的角色里，演员就变成了不同的样子。所以表演是流动的，水进入瓶子之后才被固定成一个形状。我觉得导演最需要的是那个流动的瞬间，从艺术上来说，这一刻才是最美好的表达，而不是那个固定的样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于演员来说，很多时候因为成名了就忘记如何平视生活。平视生活是非常重要的。忘记自己从哪里来，这是一件特别要命的事情。不演戏、不工作的时候，就是回归生活，要忘记自己的职业和身份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我很羡慕那种可以卸下自己演员身份的生活状态，所以没事的时候，我总是想往远的地方走走。我每次去青海做志愿者，就有网友说我去捡垃圾什么的。其实我就是想去洗涤一下，把身上一些不属于生活的东西洗掉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多时候大家对演员有想象，往往都带着角色滤镜，以为我们和普通人不一样。当你卸下演员这个职业回到生活里，我日常所处理的东西，无非也是今天这只猫生病了，明天那块墙皮掉下来了，浴室的热水怎么不热了……这些构成了生活，面对这些日常，我经常感到自己能力有限，比不上很多人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我常常思考演员好像是动物园里的大猩猩，一天24小时的一举一动都在大家的关注之下。很多时候大家将自己的各种好奇、审视和监督都投射在演员身上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾想过冲破这个牢笼，不在这个动物园待了，想要跑到大街上去。但你要知道，猩猩在动物园的时候有笼子隔着，跑到大街上可能会受到更多关注，岂不是要被围追堵截了？所以既然选择了这份职业，在得到很多的同时，就要承受它的压力，这是公平的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运中国第39金！体操女队实现亚运会13连冠，乌兹别克斯坦48岁老将晋级跳马决赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257719]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 21:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the women&#39;s qualifying and team competition for gymnastics at the Hangzhou Asian Games The final was held at Huanglong Stadium, and the Chinese team players appeared.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/8a89cb0d56.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/8a89cb0d56.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the evening of September 25, 2023, the women&#39;s qualifying competition and team finals of the gymnastics event of the Hangzhou Asian Games were held at the Huanglong Stadium, and the Chinese team players appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the women&#39;s qualifying competition and team finals of the gymnastics event of the Hangzhou Asian Games were held at the Huanglong Gymnasium. Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, Zhang Jin, The Chinese team composed of Yu Linmin and Tang Xijing won the championship with 161.896 points, achieving the 13th consecutive Asian Games women&#39;s team championship. This is also the 39th gold medal won by the Chinese sports delegation in this Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the Chinese team composed of Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, Zhang Jin, Yu Linmin, and Tang Xijing won the championship with 161.896 points.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/029c619686.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/26/029c619686.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252260&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023 On the evening of the 25th, the Chinese team consisting of Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, Zhang Jin, Yu Linmin, and Tang Xijing won the championship with 161.896 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team players warmed up before the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/f62058eb4b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/f62058eb4b. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252261&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team players warmed up before the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Due to competing for Olympic tickets at this year&#39;s World Championships, three all-around masters Ou Yushan, Qiu Qiyuan, and Zhang Qingying, as well as two individual masters Zhou Yaqin and Huang Zhuofan, went to the Antwerp World Championships. In the Hangzhou Asian Games, two senior players who participated in the Tokyo Olympics, Zhang Jin and Tang Xijing, led Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, and Yu Linmin, three teammates with less experience in the international arena, to participate. Among them, Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, and Zhang Jin participated in the all-around competition and competed in all four events in the qualifying round. Tang Xijing participated in the uneven bars, balance beam, and floor exercise, and Yu Linmin competed in the vault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Yu Linmin competed in the vaulting competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26 /a9a52bf896.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/a9a52bf896.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;252262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Yu Linmin competed in the vaulting competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Jin performed in the floor exercise event.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/26/4b9181b8b2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ 4b9181b8b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252263&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Jin performed in the floor exercise event middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Tang Qian competed in the uneven bars.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 26/011ce52486.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/011ce52486.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Tang Xijing competed in the uneven bars competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the Asian Games gymnastics event was held in the Huanglong Stadium. Some spectators raised the North Korean flag and shouted in support of the North Korean team.&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ad42324924.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ad42324924.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252265&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9, 2023 On the evening of March 25, during the Asian Games gymnastics event in the Huanglong Stadium, some spectators raised the North Korean flag and cheered in support of the North Korean team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Chinese team competed in four categories: vault, uneven bars, balance beam, and floor exercise. After all four competitions ended, the Chinese women&#39;s team won the championship with 161.896 points. , achieving the 13th consecutive Asian Games women’s team championship. The Japanese team and the North Korean team won the runner-up and third place respectively, with scores of 157.229 points and 156.829 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the North Korean team won the third place in the women&#39;s team finals of competitive gymnastics with 156.829 points.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/26/0a3916b339.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/0a3916b339.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252266&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the North Korean team scored 156.829 Won the third place in the women&#39;s team finals of competitive gymnastics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, although Uzbek player Chusovitina&#39;s left leg was bandaged, she still showed high-quality performance in the gymnastics competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games. Action.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/cc88658e26.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/cc88658e26.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252267&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, although Uzbek player Chusovitina’s left leg was bandaged, she still showed high-quality movements in the gymnastics competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 48-year-old Uzbekistan veteran Chusovitina participated in the vault and balance beam competitions, becoming a highlight of the game. She ranked Ranked fifth in the qualifying round and advanced to the vault finals. Chusovitina previously told the outside world: &quot;I cannot end my career before winning a medal on behalf of Uzbekistan. After the Asian Games, I will also participate in the 2024 Paris Olympics. Desire is my biggest motivation. I just Why should I stop doing what I love?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, after the vault, Chusovitina raised her hands above her head to gesture to the audience. My heartfelt regards.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/c8d03ea78a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/c8d03ea78a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252268&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 25, 2023, at After the vault, Chusovitina raised her hands above her head to express her heartfelt greetings to the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原江苏连环龙卷风，两地同日遭袭致10死8伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257689]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网暴可能涉及哪五种罪名？组织“水军”从重处罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/bEFnVbHqKIkc7ECKYwZPIu1A4KbsUEWnZlWHGkCB.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1264&quot; height=&quot;948&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/bEFnVbHqKIkc7ECKYwZPIu1A4KbsUEWn ZlWHGkCB. png&quot; data-key=&quot;252210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, the &quot;Two High Schools and One Ministry of Education&quot; jointly issued the &quot;About Punishment in accordance with the Law&quot; Guiding Opinions on Internet Violence and Crime&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When cyber violence occurs, victims often feel confused: the subject who commits cyber violence is usually an unspecified person. Moreover, if there are many people and there are many people, will there be a situation where &quot;the law does not punish everyone&quot;? How does the law identify those who play a major role in cyber violence? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 25, 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Illegal Crimes of Internet Violence in accordance with the Law&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guiding Opinions&quot;), pointing out that cyber violence For illegal crimes, we must &quot;correct the erroneous tendency of &#39;the law does not punish the public&#39;&quot; and focus on cracking down on malicious initiators, organizers, malicious promoters and those who refuse to change despite repeated admonitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The guidance is clear: when the targets are minors and disabled people; organize &quot;trolls&quot; and &quot;thugs&quot; to implement; fabricate &quot;sexually related&quot; topics; use generative AI technology to publish illegal information; If a network service provider initiates or organizes any of these five situations, cyberviolence perpetrators must be severely punished. According to Yao Jia, a professor at the Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, this represents the attitude towards controlling illegal and criminal acts of online violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Category of cyber violence for the first time&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Cyber ​​violence refers to the behavior of insulting others, spreading rumors and defamation, and invading privacy in cyberspace. It is not a legal concept, so when it comes to online violence, what are the crimes related to it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This issue is listed in the guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three categories related to the perpetrators of cyber violence: creating and spreading rumors on the Internet, derogating others&#39; personalities and damaging others&#39; reputations. If the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of defamation; those who resort to wanton abuse, malicious slander, and disclosure privacy and other methods, openly insulting others, and if the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of the crime of insult; organizing &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and if the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of the crime of infringing on citizens&#39; personal information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, there are malicious marketing and hype behaviors carried out through cyber violence incidents, which are subject to the crime of illegal use of information networks; network service providers who do not act on the information discovered about cyber violence crimes may be liable to This constitutes the crime of refusing to perform information network security management obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yao Jia&#39;s view, this guidance classifies online violence for the first time, &quot;at least it makes it a lot clearer&quot; and also emphasizes which behaviors may constitute crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, &quot;After the guidance is issued, cyber violence will certainly not be completely solved.&quot; Yao Jia believes that in practice, cyber violence incidents may involve the intersection of multiple behaviors, and judicial agencies, Law enforcement agencies should strengthen the identification of causal relationships and corresponding damage in cyber violence. In addition, the responsibilities of other social entities also need to be clarified. For example, when cyber violence occurs on campus, the school should also be an important player in participating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the guidance, the boundary between online violence and freedom of speech is also proposed: to report and expose other people’s crimes or violations of laws and disciplines through information networks, as long as they do not intentionally fabricate facts or knowingly If the facts are fabricated and spread intentionally, they should not be considered as defamation. Commenting and criticizing other people&#39;s words and deeds, even if the views are biased or the speech is extreme, as long as it is not wanton abuse or malicious slander, it should not be considered an insult or crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Clear standards for public prosecutions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Criminal Law stipulates that, except for cases that seriously endanger social order and national interests, crimes of insult and defamation are “dealt with upon complaint.” crime. In other words, most of the time, this type of crime requires the victim to collect evidence to file a lawsuit in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, among the 587 criminal defamation cases concluded by courts across the country, 271 cases, accounting for 46%, were not accepted, and only 79 cases were judged, accounting for less than 14%. Among them, only guilty verdicts were 43 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a set of data provided by Zhou Jiahai, deputy director of the Supreme Law Research Office, at a press conference on the afternoon of September 25, 2023. He said that in recent years, there has been a significant increase in the number of criminal cases involving insults and defamation, but the proportion of guilty verdicts is very low. Zhou Jiahai believes that this is due to the difficulty faced by private prosecutors in collecting evidence. On the other hand, it is also related to the lack of detailed guidance and &quot;too high a threshold&quot; for public prosecution standards in criminal cases of insult and defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defamation case of a woman who picked up a courier in Hangzhou in July 2020 is a rare case that has been converted from private prosecution to public prosecution. It was listed as one of the top ten legal supervision cases of the year by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as Zheng Jingjing, the victim’s attorney, saw this guidance, she noticed the clauses detailing the circumstances of “seriously endangering social order” in the crime of insult and defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the situations is that &quot;the general public is arbitrarily targeted, and relevant information is widely disseminated on the Internet, triggering a large number of vulgar and malicious comments, seriously damaging the order of the Internet, and having a negative impact on society.&quot;—— This situation is almost completely consistent with the defamation case involving the courier woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference, Li Wenfeng, deputy director of the Legal Policy Research Office of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, said in response to reporters&#39; questions that the guidance did draw lessons from the Hangzhou woman who was defamed while picking up express delivery when stipulating the prosecution standards for insult and defamation cases. case experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Jingjing recalled that when she represented the case, according to the judicial interpretation on the criminal offense of online defamation issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate in 2013, more attention was paid to whether the determination of &quot;seriously endangering social order and national interests&quot; It may cause crises in real life, such as mass incidents, public disorder, etc. Finally, the court used the blanket clause of “other situations that seriously endanger social order and national interests” as the legal basis for transferring private prosecution to public prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the release of the guidance, there are more detailed guidelines for the application of public prosecution procedures to crimes of online insult and defamation. In addition to the above-mentioned situation, there are three other specific situations that cause bad social impact: serious consequences such as mental disorder or suicide of the victim or his close relatives; insulting and slandering multiple people or spreading insulting and slanderous information multiple times; organizing and instigating Personnel spread a large amount of insulting and slanderous information on multiple online platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中秋节临近，广州的这条“灯笼街”充满中国人的节日浪漫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>