<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《关于依法惩治网络暴力违法犯罪的指导意见》出台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 15:34:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Although the Internet is a virtual space, it is by no means an illegal place. Those who wantonly publish abuses and insults against individuals on the Internet Cyber ​​violence that spreads rumors, defamation, invades privacy and other information must be subject to due legal sanctions. On September 25, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, and the Ministry of Public Security jointly held a press conference to officially release the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Internet Violence and Crime According to the Law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions&quot; have a total of 20 articles, mainly covering ten aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, clarify the applicable rules for the crime of online violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; provide guidance on the nature of online violence in accordance with the criminal law and relevant judicial interpretations. Specifically, those who openly insult others or fabricate facts to slander others on the information network, if the circumstances are serious, will be convicted and punished for the crimes of insult and slander; organize &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and the circumstances are In serious cases, they will be convicted and punished for the crime of infringing on citizens&#39; personal information. In addition, the crime of illegal use of information network can be applied to malicious marketing and hype behaviors carried out through cyber violence incidents; the crime of refusing to perform information network security management obligations can be applied to the behavior of failing to perform information network security management obligations in accordance with the law for discovered cyber violence information . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to clarify the rules for handling illegal online violence. For online violence, we should adhere to multi-dimensional and joint governance and improve the connection mechanism between administrative law enforcement and criminal justice. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that the implementation of online insults, slander and other online violence does not constitute a crime. If it complies with the provisions of the Public Security Management Punishment Law and other provisions, administrative penalties will be imposed in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to clarify the policy principles for punishing cyber violence crimes. The &quot;Opinions&quot; require that the spirit of severe punishment for cyber violence crimes should be reflected so that the people can fully feel fairness and justice. Adhere to strict law enforcement and justice, strictly investigate cyber violence crimes in accordance with the law, and effectively correct the erroneous tendency of &quot;the law does not punish the public&quot;. We must focus on cracking down on malicious initiators, organizers, malicious promoters, and those who persist in reforming despite repeated abuses. The &quot;Opinions&quot; also stipulate that there are those who commit cyber violence against minors and disabled people, organize &quot;trolls&quot; and &quot;thugs&quot; to commit cyber violence, fabricate &quot;sexually related&quot; topics to infringe on the human dignity of others, and use &quot;deep synthesis&quot; and other generative methods If artificial intelligence technology releases illegal information, or if network service providers initiate or organize cyber violence, they will be severely punished in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to clarify the boundaries between illegal crimes and legal behaviors of online violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that reporting or exposing other people&#39;s crimes or violations of laws and disciplines through information networks should not be considered a defamation crime as long as they do not intentionally fabricate facts or knowingly spread the facts to be fabricated. Commenting and criticizing other people&#39;s words and deeds, even if the views are biased or the speech is extreme, as long as it is not wanton abuse or malicious slander, it should not be considered an insult or crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth is to clarify the work requirements for public security organs to assist in evidence collection. According to the provisions of the Criminal Law, in cases where the victim files a private prosecution for online insult or defamation, if the people&#39;s court determines after review that it is indeed difficult for the victim to provide evidence, it may request the public security organs to provide assistance. The &quot;Opinions&quot; reiterate the provisions of the Criminal Law, and also clarify that the public security organs should promptly identify the perpetrators of online insults and slander according to the requirements of the People&#39;s Court and the specific circumstances of the case, and collect evidence and materials such as the spread and spread of relevant information and the impact caused. Network service providers shall provide necessary technical support and assistance for public security organs to obtain evidence in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth is to clarify the public prosecution standards for criminal cases of online insult and defamation. According to the provisions of the Criminal Law, those who commit crimes of insult or slander and seriously endanger social order and national interests shall be prosecuted in accordance with the law. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that in cases of online insult and defamation, public prosecution procedures will apply if one of the following circumstances occurs: (1) causing serious consequences such as mental disorder or suicide of the victim or his close relatives, and causing a bad impact on society; (2) arbitrarily using The general public is the target of infringement, and relevant information is widely disseminated on the Internet, triggering a large number of vulgar and malicious comments, seriously disrupting the order of the Internet, and having a bad impact on society; (3) Insulting and slandering multiple people or spreading insulting and slanderous information multiple times, causing social harm Those with a bad impact; (4) Organizing and instigating people to spread a large amount of insulting and slanderous information on multiple online platforms, with a bad impact on society; (5) Other situations that seriously endanger social order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The seventh is to clarify the transition process from private prosecution to public prosecution in criminal cases of online insult and defamation. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that for online insults and slander that seriously endanger social order, the public security organs have filed a case as a public prosecution case, and the victim simultaneously files a private prosecution in the People&#39;s Court, the People&#39;s Court may request the private prosecutor to withdraw the private prosecution or rule not to accept it; it has been accepted If the case is found, a ruling should be made to terminate the trial and the relevant materials should be transferred to the public security organs. The original private prosecutor can participate in the lawsuit as a victim. The victim files a private prosecution before the public security organ files a case. If, upon review, the people&#39;s court determines that the relevant online insults and defamation seriously endanger social order, the case shall be transferred to the public security organ. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eighth, support civil rights protection against online violence in accordance with the law. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that if cyber violence is committed against others and infringes on others&#39; reputation rights, privacy rights and other personality rights, and the victim requests the perpetrator to bear civil liability, the people&#39;s court will support it in accordance with the law. If the right holder has evidence to prove that the perpetrator is committing or is about to commit an illegal act that infringes upon his or her personality rights, and failure to stop it in time will cause irreparable damage to his or her legitimate rights and interests, the People&#39;s Court may, upon the right holder&#39;s application, issue an injunction against infringement of personality rights in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ninth is to clarify the rules for public interest litigation in cases of online violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that if online violence harms public interests, the People&#39;s Procuratorate may file a public interest litigation with the People&#39;s Court in accordance with the law. If a network service provider fails to perform its information network security management obligations in accordance with the law for discovered cyber violence information, resulting in the large-scale dissemination of illegal information or other serious circumstances that harm the public interest, the People&#39;s Procuratorate may file a public interest litigation with the People&#39;s Court in accordance with the law. When handling public interest litigation cases in the field of cyber violence control, the People&#39;s Procuratorate may require network service providers to provide necessary technical support and assistance in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tenth is to proactively perform duties and promote comprehensive management of cyber violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; require that when handling cases of cyber violence, information on the progress of the case should be released to the public in a timely manner in accordance with the law, clarify the truth, and eliminate the adverse effects of cyber violence, so as to reduce the harm to the victims and help the victims get out of their predicaments; carry out legal publicity and give full play to law enforcement The role of rule guidance, value orientation and behavioral norms in handling cases is to educate and guide netizens to consciously abide by the law and lead social civilization; to conduct in-depth analysis of the root causes that promote the occurrence of online violence, promote multi-dimensional co-governance of online violence, and fundamentally reduce online violence occurrence, creating a clear cyberspace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙一文止步八强，新旧交替的女子重剑队亟待历练]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257567]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/qLY0NaAvQ3TEA5d5kye3jm2Vd1xtEzLcs4MrEYLK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/qLY0NaAvQ3TEA5d5kye3jm2Vd1xtEz Lcs4MrEYLK. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, women&#39;s individual epee four in the fencing event of the Hangzhou Asian Games In the quarter-finals, Chinese player Sun Yiwen (right) lost to South Korean player Song Shiluo 12-14 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;12 to 14, on September 24, the first official competition day of the Hangzhou Asian Games, in the quarter-finals of the women’s individual epee fencing event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Sun Yiwen lost to South Korean player Song Se-ra and stopped in the quarterfinals. So far, all Chinese players in this project have been eliminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Sun Yiwen’s third Asian Games trip. She and her teammates won the women&#39;s epee team championship twice before. At the last Asian Games in Jakarta, Sun Yiwen also reached the finals of individual events, but ultimately lost to South Korean star Kang Young-mi and won a silver medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This sport pays great attention to variety, balance, game and precision.” A game lasts up to 9 minutes. If you hit at the same time, you must be 1/25 second earlier than the opponent to score. A blink of an eye is 0.75 seconds, which is enough to turn the tide or give up victory. To do this, fencers need to &quot;count one step at a time.&quot; Excellent fencers are often in a &quot;man-sword-in-one&quot; state, that is, under various circumstances, they can hit the opponent&#39;s exposed effective parts (including the torso, legs, feet, hands, arms, and helmets) at the fastest speed and the shortest route. . Behind the &quot;subconscious&quot; sword thrusts again and again is the muscle memory cultivated over many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tokyo Olympic champion Sun Yiwen is the number one Chinese women&#39;s epee player. He has always been good at &quot;stopping with stillness and attacking later.&quot; &quot;Determined, calm, and explosive&quot; is how she sums up her playing style. However, after winning the Tokyo Olympics and Xi&#39;an Games, Sun Yiwen has been trapped by injuries and will not resume training until October 2022 and systematically participate in events. To &quot;find the feeling of starting over&quot;, the road is rough. Sun Yiwen once lamented that he &quot;can&#39;t even play games anymore&quot; and was &quot;very unfamiliar.&quot; It was not until the International Fencing Federation World Cup Barcelona in February 2023 that he gradually regained his form and won two bronze medals in a row, both individual and team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Y1LICojmKJNk0KhWE9ZrblJq0W0assdjikvr0Ab1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Y1LICojmKJNk0KhWE9ZrblJq0W0assdjikvr0Ab1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 24, 2021, Sun Yiwen (right) celebrated with his coach after winning the women&#39;s individual epee final in fencing at the Tokyo Olympics&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous interviews with the media, Sun Yiwen once said that winning a gold medal is not necessary for this comeback. After reviewing the schedule performance of the last Olympic Games, she and the coaching staff found that although they won the gold medal, many problems and deficiencies were still exposed in the process. If they can be improved, the state will be better than before. &quot;There is a new coach in the team who has taught me many new ideas and moves. Now I dare to try new moves in the game and explore new areas. This is what makes me most interesting and what makes me happy.&quot; The reason why I decided to stick to another Olympic cycle is that I am still learning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Tokyo Olympics, the Chinese fencing team is facing a transitional period of replacement of old and new players and adjustment of the coaching team. Three-quarters of the athletes participating in the Asian Games have never competed in the Tokyo Olympics. The Hangzhou Asian Games is regarded as an important training opportunity for this young team to prepare for the Paris Olympics. According to the competition plan, the fencing competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games will be held from September 24th to 29th, with a total of 12 gold medals produced. On September 27, Sun Yiwen will also lead his young teammates to continue their pursuit of medals in the women&#39;s epee team competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Zhang Xin, Secretary-General of the Chinese Sports Delegation at the Hangzhou Asian Games and Director of the Competitive Sports Department of the State Sports General Administration, said, the Hangzhou Asian Games is the &quot;high school entrance examination&quot; before the Paris Olympics. Less than a year later, 32-year-old Sun Yiwen will usher in her third Olympic trip in Paris, and before that, she and the young Chinese fencing team still need to overcome many obstacles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/zSTuMc9YvjlkUYhKNhKW9jT7caOSYptFWqNxmbnw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/zSTuMc9YvjlkUYhKNhKW9jT7caOSYptFWqNxmbnw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 20, 2023, in the 2023 Asian Fencing Championships Women’s Epee Team Third Place Competition held in Wuxi, Jiangsu, the Chinese team defeated the Japanese team and won the bronze medal. Chinese team players Tang Junyao (first from left), Lin Sheng (second from left), Zhu Mingye (third from left) and Sun Yiwen took a group photo after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Behind the &quot;Duel of Swords&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Yiwen never considered himself a &quot;talented player&quot;. She attributes her gains in her career to her seriousness and stubbornness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yiwen was born in Wanggezhuang Village, Qixia City, Yantai, Shandong Province in 1992. When she was young, her health was very poor and she would catch a cold every winter. Sun Yiwen&#39;s father, Sun Hongming, is a local village doctor. Under his father&#39;s supervision and company, she has developed the habit of running and exercising since she was a child. Long-term persistence pays off. In elementary school, Sun Yiwen had become the school&#39;s top sports student. When he was 11 years old, Sun Yiwen was selected by the Qixia Sports and Competition School to focus on middle and long-distance running. Two years later, she had grown to 1.66 meters, and her best standing long jump score was over 2.5 meters. Because of her tallness, long wingspan, strong instantaneous explosive power, and being left-handed, she was spotted by Xu Zhaowei, the then head coach of the Yantai City Fencing Team, and officially embarked on the road of fencing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fencing is a project that requires very comprehensive abilities. &quot;Strength, speed, explosive power, endurance, coordination, flexibility, and thinking&quot;, none of them can be missing. The initial training was hard and boring. Morning training starts at 5:30 in the morning. Basic steps and movements last for several hours. In order to develop their endurance shortcomings, the team members also need to receive additional running training. From Monday to Friday, I run 3,000 meters in the morning and evening, and there is also a 6-kilometer cross-country race on the weekends. If you fail to complete the task within the stipulated time, you will be fined. The longer it takes, the greater the fine. After the high-intensity training during the day, there are cultural classes in the evening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a week, Sun Yiwen wanted to give up. In order to comfort and encourage his daughter, Sun Hongming rushed to Yantai from his hometown and stayed with his daughter for two days. After the initial adaptation period, Sun Yiwen, who is physically fit and good at thinking, began to gradually emerge. &quot;Every time I practice an action and I can&#39;t do it, I will carefully review it and think about why. Every time I win or lose a game, I will dig deeper into the underlying logic.&quot; At the 2010 Shandong Provincial Games, the 18-year-old Sun Yiwen represented the Yantai Fencing Team and won 8 gold medals with his teammates. After the competition, she was successfully selected for the provincial fencing team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But life was not smooth. For a long time, because there was no establishment in the provincial team, Sun Yiwen had to pay for outings by himself. Sometimes a game would cost half a year&#39;s salary of my father. At that time, his younger brother was still studying at home, and Sun Hongming and his wife were living in a very tight situation in their hometown. Due to technical and tactical breakthroughs facing bottlenecks, Sun Yiwen was withdrawn from the provincial team twice. Worried that he would not be able to get ahead by practicing fencing, Sun Yiwen once proposed to his father that he should give up fencing and go out to work to support his family as soon as possible. The father knows his daughter&#39;s thoughts well. Just like when he was a child, Sun Hongming sought psychological relief on the one hand, and actively communicated with the coach on the other. In the end, no one gave up. Fortunately, under the advice of her coach, Sun Yiwen began to try to change the gun-handled sword to a straight-handled sword. After that, her hard training finally paid off. For a time, there was no female player in the province who could match her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Sun Yiwen was selected for the national fencing team. In the same year, at the age of 21, she made her debut in international competitions and won the women&#39;s epee World Cup Grand Prix team championship. Two years later, she won her first individual championship at the Italian Fencing World Cup. However, it was the 2021 Tokyo Olympics that really brought Sun Yiwen to the pinnacle of his career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2016 Rio Olympics, Sun Yiwen, as a &quot;dark horse&quot;, won the individual bronze medal and team silver medal in women&#39;s epee. But with the end of the Rio Olympics, the national women&#39;s fencing team has also undergone earth-shaking changes. At that time, the head coach &quot;Bole&quot; Levavasseur, who had a profound influence on Sun Yiwen&#39;s thinking and technology, resigned, and the main players such as Xu Anqi and Sun Yujie retired. The burden of leading the new team suddenly fell on Sun Yiwen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/O0mKyXd6lHmdwegDkVKOPAasw1yJDwy0BEGRnrOb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/O0mKyXd6lHmdwegDkVKOPAasw1yJDwy0BEGRnrOb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Yiwen&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Sun Yiwen was used to &quot; The &quot;second intention&quot; style of play is to first use fake moves to confuse the opponent, and then attack by surprise. However, the successor head coach Yuge Oberly is good at direct offensive tactics, which is exactly Sun Yiwen&#39;s shortcoming. During the running-in period, which lasted for about a year, Sun Yiwen&#39;s performance in competitions has been mediocre. She felt as if she had returned to the state when she had just joined the fencing team at the age of 15, and everything had to start from scratch. &quot;My thoughts and thoughts at that time were completely chaotic, like a ball of knotted hemp rope.&quot; She has experienced too many ups and downs. Sun Yiwen could only encourage himself silently, &quot;This state must be temporary. There will always be low points in life. It depends on how you overcome it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, due to the postponement of the Tokyo Olympics, Held in 2016, Sun Yiwen adjusted back to his form in time during the Olympic points competition. By blending the strengths of both sets of technical ideas, she developed a new combat style. In the summer of 2021, she won the gold medal in the Tokyo Olympics women&#39;s epee individual finals, defeating Romania&#39;s Popescu, who was ranked number one in the world at the time. The only regret was that in the subsequent team competition, Sun Yiwen was injured and had to be replaced. The Chinese women&#39;s epee team eventually failed to reach the top four of the team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Tokyo Olympics, Sun Yiwen missed several major events in 2022 due to injuries. In an interview with the media in early 2022, she described her injuries this way, &quot;I now have a torn posterior cruciate ligament and water accumulation in my left leg, a knee cyst, a worn meniscus, and a long stretch from the back of my right leg to the knee. Injury. Even if I move a few times or when the weather is bad, my knee will still hurt.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike many other sports, few people can maintain absolute dominance in the field of fencing. force. In the past year, Sun Yiwen has been participating in the competition while sick due to the lumbosacral pressure on the nerves in her legs. She has been exploring how to coexist with the injury technically and psychologically. At the World Fencing Championships in Milan in July, Sun Yiwen won the bronze medal in the women&#39;s epee individual event. This was her first time winning an individual event medal at the World Championships. In a post-match interview, Sun Yiwen said that this bronze medal was a &quot;heart booster&quot; for her, letting her know that she &quot;can do it&quot; despite injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t care about winning or losing, but I have perseverance. I think I can do things that others can do. Injuries, difficulties and problems are in front of me, and I will never run away from them. I won&#39;t be afraid, I will definitely solve it. The higher you go, the more problems you will encounter.&quot; In Sun Yiwen&#39;s view, the most important lesson her 18-year fencing career has taught her is &quot;not to accept weakness. Don’t admit defeat.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(Reference materials: &quot;Blog World&quot;, &quot;GQ Report&quot;, Chao News, Dazhong Yantai Channel, Forbes China, &quot;Wonderful OK&quot;, &quot;Qilu Evening News&quot;, China News Network, &quot;Beijing Daily&quot;, Shangguan News, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从北京、广州到杭州：33年3届亚运会见证中国经济社会发展与国民精神进化丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, the 19th Asian Games opened in Hangzhou. During the lighting ceremony, a giant &quot;digital man&quot; rushed from outside the venue and lit the main torch together with the real people present, bringing this technologically full opening ceremony to a climax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s not just about digital people igniting fires. This opening ceremony can be said to be the opening ceremony of a sports meeting with the strongest sense of technology to date. A &quot;net screen&quot; with a total length of 185 meters and a height of 20 meters hangs in the air, and a 6,000-square-meter ground screen on the ground turns the &quot;Big Lotus&quot; of the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Stadium into a huge three-dimensional display screen. In addition, with the blessing of naked-eye 3D, AR and other digital technologies, the digital fireworks are dazzling, and the opening performance combines virtual and real scenes, giving it a full sense of the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the third time China has hosted the Asian Games in more than 30 years. The hosting of these three Asian Games also reflects the development process of China&#39;s economic society and national spiritual mentality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, the 11th Asian Games was held in Beijing. This was the first time that China hosted a large-scale international comprehensive sports event. It was also the early stage of China&#39;s reform and opening up. In 1983, China applied to host the Asian Games, hoping to show an image of openness to the outside world. Economically, China&#39;s development was just starting at that time. By 1990, when the Asian Games were held, the country&#39;s total GDP was only 1.89 trillion yuan, less than 360.9 billion U.S. dollars. Its per capita GDP ranked outside the 130th place in the world, and it was also the lowest in Asia. Not forward. At that time, even the preparations for the Asian Games lacked funds, so they had to launch a nationwide fundraising campaign. Tens of millions of people across the country participated and donated a total of 270 million yuan, more than one-tenth of the total investment in the Beijing Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time China hosted the Asian Games was the 2010 Guangzhou Asian Games. In the past 20 years, especially at the beginning of the new century, China&#39;s accession to the WTO and integration into the global market have made China the world&#39;s factory, and its economy has developed by leaps and bounds. Although affected by the financial crisis in 2008, China&#39;s economy quickly resumed development. In 2010, China&#39;s total GDP exceeded 40 trillion yuan, equivalent to more than 6 trillion US dollars, surpassing Japan for the first time, ranking first in Asia and second in the world. The Asian Games will be held in Guangzhou. Guangzhou has been a commercial capital for thousands of years and the forefront of reform and opening up. The Pearl River Delta is also the most active region for China&#39;s export-oriented economy and one of China&#39;s most important manufacturing and foreign trade bases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, the Hangzhou Asian Games has been more than ten years since the Guangzhou Asian Games. Over the past ten years, China&#39;s economy has nearly tripled. More importantly, the scientific and technological content of China&#39;s economy has also been greatly improved, especially in the field of digital economy, which leads the world. Hangzhou is the home base of Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba. The gorgeous digital people and digital fireworks at the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games are a concentrated display of China&#39;s high-end digital technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the attention attracted by these three Asian Games is also different. I believe older friends will have a better understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the successful bid to the preparation and successful hosting of the Beijing Asian Games, it has attracted unprecedented attention from the whole country. I remember that televisions were not yet popular in China, especially in rural areas. Black and white TVs were rare, and color TVs were even rarer. In some villages, only the village committee had a color TV for villagers to watch. Farmers are busy with farm work during the day and have no time to watch the live broadcast of the Asian Games. At night, the color TV in the village committee is crowded with farmers watching the game. Of course, more news about the game was heard from the loudspeaker broadcast in the village the next morning. Every time there was news that the Chinese team had won, it would cause a burst of carnival. The emblem composed of the Great Wall pattern, the mascot panda Panpan, and the promotional song &quot;Asian Heroes&quot; have all become the memories of a generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony of the Guangzhou Asian Games was ingenious and brilliant. The &quot;Sail of White Clouds&quot; showed a grand atmosphere of openness and pioneering. However, in terms of attention, I am afraid it cannot compare with the national participation of the Beijing Asian Games. the hot state. I came to Guangzhou from Beijing to work in October 2010, just before the Guangzhou Asian Games. Just two years ago, China just hosted the 2008 Olympic Games. All the top events in the world have been held, and the psychological threshold of the Chinese people has naturally increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, mobile networks have become the main channel of communication. Everyone has a variety of short videos and news apps installed on their mobile phones. Even payment tools such as Alipay have video reports of the Asian Games. Information about the Asian Games can be received anytime and anywhere. In such a convenient communication environment, more than 100 million people participated in the Asian Games digital torch relay event. However, with the continuous evolution of lifestyles, we can no longer see the state where everyone sits in front of the TV. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change in attention to the Asian Games is also an inevitable result of the development of China&#39;s economic society and national mentality. At the time of the Beijing Asian Games, China&#39;s economy was still relatively backward. The Asian Games was an opportunity to unite the strength of the Chinese people and show their national pride. The vigorous publicity by the official media made the Beijing Asian Games known to everyone. As for the Guangzhou Asian Games and this time the Hangzhou Asian Games, with the improvement of China&#39;s economic level, there have been countless world-class sports events held in China. Ordinary people also have more channels to access more information, and their attention is divided. Of course, this is also a good thing. Those who love sports will continue to pay attention to the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third Asian Games in thirty years is a testimony to China’s development and the evolution of the national spirit. In this sense, the opening ceremony of the Asian Games has increased technological content and attracted less attention than it did in the past, which is a reflection of its richness, development and progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“常·识”背后的南方报业融合转型密码]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, Huang Changkai, Secretary of the Party Committee and President of Southern Newspaper Media Group, wrote the monograph &quot;Common Knowledge - Southern The book &quot;Newspaper Media Convergence Comics&quot; was officially published by Nanfang Daily Publishing House. This is another professional masterpiece by the author following &quot;Communication Power - Media Integration Practice of Southern Newspaper Industry&quot;, which deeply summarizes the practice and experience of the integration transformation of southern newspapers and profoundly explains the understanding and understanding of the regularity of integration transformation of provincial party newspaper groups. Although the title of the book is &quot;Common Knowledge&quot;, it is closely combined with the extraordinary process of the southern newspaper industry in recent years to successfully explore the path of integrated development that is in line with the spirit of the central government, industry trends and with southern characteristics. It shows the southern newspaper people&#39;s perspective on media integration and transformation. Deep understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/5b8d0c05c65e1a924c997e724b8104c4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/5b8d0c05c65e1a924c997e724b8104c4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252058&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Book and video of &quot;Common Knowledge - Comics on the Integration of Southern Newspaper and Media&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Looking at integration transformation from eight sets of dialectical relationships&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;:&lt;/span >;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Without communication power, there is nothing&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the era of mobile Internet, how to promote the development of media integration is a question of the times and also of contemporary media. A must-answer question for people&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;. Media integration is a systematic project that involves &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;innovation of ideas, content, forms, methods, and means. It involves many tasks such as resource integration, process optimization, and platform reengineering, and involves all aspects of technology, operation, and management problems. . Where to solve the problem and how to solve the problem? How to focus on the key reforms that &quot;pulse one person to mobilize the whole body&quot;, innovative measures to achieve the traction effect of &quot;one child is full of vitality&quot;, and how to rectify the complex relationships between various aspects and different links? To this, we can find part of the answer just from the content structure of the book &quot;Common Knowledge&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the content structure, the book is divided into eight themes, namely &quot;Old Business and New Business&quot;, &quot;Rice Bowl and Stage&quot;, &quot;Career and Talent&quot;, &quot;Main Business and Industry&quot;, &quot;Content and Technology&quot; &quot;Removal of disadvantages and innovation&quot;, &quot;Management and construction&quot;, &quot;Big ecology and small ecology&quot;. Furthermore, the eight themes actually illustrate eight sets of major dialectical relationships that need to be accurately grasped to crack media integration. For example, &quot;Old Industry and New Industry&quot; focuses on a dialectical view of the relationship between traditional media and emerging media, and how to achieve complementary advantages, one can grow stronger than the other, and one can be better than the other during the iterative process of integration and transformation. &quot;Jobs and Stages&quot; focuses on how, in the face of the irreversible trend of the decline of traditional media, how to build a bigger and stronger self-controlled and controllable communication platform, provide a secure job, and create a stage for entrepreneurs to start their own businesses. By analogy, &quot;Business and Talent&quot; focuses on the construction of a talent team for integrated transformation; &quot;Main Business and Industry&quot; explores how to achieve positive mutual promotion between editing and operations; &quot;Content and Technology&quot; focuses on building a solid foundation for integrated transformation The technological foundation of and Small Ecology&quot; shows how for a provincial party newspaper group like Nanfang Newspaper, which has multiple sub-media, multiple ports, and multiple positions, to build an all-media communication system with misaligned development, coordination and harmony, and amplify the communication power of integrated development. and influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/3bc02f7af596f0fabf0199532b415f1d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;530&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/3bc02f7af596f0fabf0199532b415f1d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252062&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Innovative measures for the southern newspaper industry’s institutional mechanisms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see from a detailed reading of &quot;Chang·shi&quot; that the eight sets of dialectical relationships are not &quot;theories out of thin air&quot;, but stem from the successful integration and transformation practice of the southern newspaper industry. A profound summary of the Southern Style of Play. In recent years, Southern Newspapers has taken improving modern communication capabilities as its primary task, deeply implemented the &quot;three integrations&quot; and &quot;four modernizations&quot; strategies and tactics (see the book &quot;Communication Power - Media Integration Practice of Southern Newspapers&quot; for details), and built It is a micro-screen all-media communication system for newspapers and periodicals with over 457 million users on the Internet. Its seven media organizations, including Nanfang Daily, Nanfang Magazine, Nanfang.com, Nanfang Rural Daily, Southern Weekend, Southern Metropolis Daily, and Nanfang+Client, are all among the &quot; &quot;Billion Yuan Media&quot; Club, Southern+, GDToday News Network (client), Nanzhou App, Nandu App, N Video, Guangdong Learning and other new communication platforms with independent controllability and strong communication capabilities are developing well. Southern+ has exceeded 1.7 With an outstanding performance of over 100 million downloads and over 6 million daily active users, it firmly occupies the position of the most authoritative mobile publishing platform of the Guangdong Provincial Party Committee and the Provincial Government, and ranks first in the dissemination power of the self-owned client of the provincial party newspaper in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such an outstanding performance in integration and transformation stems from the correct grasp of the eight sets of dialectical relationships discussed in the book. The author&#39;s so-called &quot;community&quot; is by no means a general discussion. He focuses on a series of key problems, important themes, and major issues in the integration and transformation of media. The author&#39;s in-depth explanation of the eight sets of dialectical relationships is the answer to the &quot;need and need&quot; dilemmas of effectively solving media convergence and transformation. From it, we can also get a glimpse of the successful code of the Southern newspaper industry&#39;s convergence and transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Feel regular knowledge from “common knowledge”: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Transformation is not a career change&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The author states in his preface, &quot;The title of the book is &quot;Chang·Shi&quot;, which means both ordinary views and normal common sense.&quot; Looking at the whole book, there are many views on &quot;Without communication power, there is nothing&quot;, &quot;What kind of circle should Southern+ get out of&quot;, &quot;What kind of person should Mingji become&quot;, &quot;What kind of industry should we build&quot;, &quot;Let management and management change from a &#39;dilemma&#39; to a &#39;dilemma&#39; The in-depth discussions on a series of industry-concerned topics such as &quot;two ends&quot; can be said to have &quot;frequent golden sentences&quot;, which left a deep impression on people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Common sense is unusual. For a long time, in the face of the continuous fierce impact of new Internet media, where to go in media transformation has been the &lt;span>;most prominent&lt;/span>; problem. Practice has proved that the correct answer to this question often determines the path choice and future of a media. In this regard, the author clearly pointed out that &quot;transformation is not a change of career&quot; and emphasized that &quot;as mainstream media, regardless of newspapers, radio and television, websites, or clients, we must ask ourselves: what do we do?&quot; &quot;The southern newspaper industry must be clear about its positioning. No matter how it is transformed or integrated, the cornerstone status of media attributes cannot be shaken.&quot; In the current era of drastic changes in the industry, adhering to the strategic determination of &quot;still calm when flying through chaotic clouds&quot; is common sense, but it still requires an unusual &quot;sobriety in the world&quot;. Similar to the book, &quot;ignoring the media business is tantamount to discarding the basics&quot;, &quot;being independent and controllable does not mean starting from scratch&quot;, etc., etc., which may not seem to be profound and mysterious truths, but often require people to make clear decisions in the reality of integration and transformation. The right choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1ddee1f0902287b520469a2b18222ed6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1ddee1f0902287b520469a2b18222ed6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252061&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Four-year changes in the business structure of Southern Newspapers (2019-2022). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Common sense is also consensus. As the author said, &quot;Common Knowledge&quot; &quot;presents by no means my personal practical thinking, but the crystallization of collective wisdom.&quot; It not only originates from the integration and transformation practice of Southern Newspaper Industry, but also condenses the consensus of all employees of Southern Newspaper Industry . It is not difficult to see from the discussions in the book, such as &quot;Content production and dissemination as the basis for survival&quot;, &quot;Building new mainstream media must adhere to &#39;long-termism&#39;&quot;, &quot;The most precious assets of the southern newspaper industry are two: the first is Talent, the second is communication power.&quot; &quot;Famous journalists are not judged, but typed.&quot; &quot;Only by &#39;sinking down&#39; can the foundation be everlasting.&quot; These are not only important concepts and principles that the southern newspaper industry adheres to in its integration and transformation, but also have long been Integrating into the daily development of the group has become a consensus practiced by the Southern Newspaper industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Common sense is a regular understanding. Many &quot;golden sentences&quot; in the book are not only insights, but also reflect a deep understanding of the laws of media integration and development. For example, when talking about the essence of transformation, he pointed out that &quot;transformation is the transformation of media from a &#39;paper&#39; form to a &#39;net&#39; form; integration is the fusion and symbiosis of old and new media forms&quot;; when talking about the relationship between main business and industry, It was pointed out that &quot;by strengthening the main business, the communication power and influence can produce spillover benefits, thereby doing a good job in the main business, leveraging the industry and bringing diversified income&quot;; when talking about the relationship between technology and content, it was pointed out that &quot;where the content is spread, Technical support will follow wherever you go.” Discussions like this are undoubtedly highly inspiring to the entire industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of media integration is a big article. This year marks the 10th anniversary of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instruction to “accelerate the integrated development of traditional media and emerging media.” At such an important time point, the publication of &quot;Common Knowledge&quot; undoubtedly provides a vivid sample and reference for us to summarize the media integration transformation practices of the entire industry and accelerate the in-depth development of media integration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1f89d7f6202dd2ba9ff83a96f15f47a8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;5678&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1f89d7f6202dd2ba9ff83a96f15f47a8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252064&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Table of contents of &quot;Common Knowledge - Southern Newspaper Media Integration Comics&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/07bb486f461ce7c1189ca9b7220c0010.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;851&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/07bb486f461ce7c1189ca9b7220c0010.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252060 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;About the author. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运新项目电子竞技开赛，中国香港队小组赛战胜中国台北队]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257563]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/ef0b241597.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ef0b241597. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251859&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports events in China Hangzhou E-Sports Center kicks off. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports competition was held in Hangzhou, China The E-Sports Center starts. This is the first time that &quot;e-sports&quot; has been listed as an official event at the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2d24a1f7bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2d24a1f7bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, e-sports players of the Hong Kong team in China were competing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Glory of Kings Asian Games version group round robin tournament Group B held on the morning of September 24th In the second game, the Hong Kong team of China defeated the Chinese Taipei team 1-0. The competition venue, Hangzhou E-Sports Center in China, is the first professional e-sports venue in China that meets the Asian Games standards. The most eye-catching thing in the venue is the battle screen with 4 large screens and 4 corner screens, with a total area of ​​202 square meters. This large screen can be raised and lowered, and can be raised to a maximum of 22 meters above the ground, which can satisfy audiences at different seating positions in the venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/277ff3db5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/277ff3db5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Douping with a total area of ​​202 square meters. This large screen can be raised and lowered to accommodate audiences at different seating positions in the venue. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ 7ae897d930.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7ae897d930.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;251862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, the people watching the game in the stands danced with glow sticks. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ 4b9cc5a147.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4b9cc5a147.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;251863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, in the second game of Group B of the Asian Games version of Glory of Kings, Hong Kong, China The team defeated the Chinese Taipei team 1-0. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is understood that the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports competition will be held from September 24th to 10th On March 2, a total of 7 projects were confirmed for the competition, namely League of Legends, Honor of Kings Asian Games version, Peace Elite Asian Games version, Dota, Dream Three Kingdoms 2, Street Fighter 5, and Football Online 4, including 5 PC-side projects and 2 Each mobile game project will produce a total of 7 gold medals. According to the official ticket sales plan, e-sports ticket prices are divided into multiple tiers starting from 200 yuan, with the highest price for the finals being as high as 1,000 yuan, making it one of the most expensive Asian Games tickets and the only item that requires a lottery to purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9b0a05f6af.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9b0a05f6af.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, all the spectators were young faces. E-sports tickets are one of the most expensive Asian Games tickets, and they are also the only items that require a lottery to purchase. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking back on the process of &quot;e-sports entering Asia&quot;, within Asia, e-sports It was first popular in South Korea, and then gradually developed to China, Japan, Vietnam, Thailand and other countries. On November 18, 2003, the State Sports General Administration officially approved e-sports as the 99th official sports competition event; in 2008, the State Sports General Administration re-approved e-sports as the 78th official sports competition event; in 2013, the State The General Administration of Sports established the Chinese e-sports national team and launched extensive competitions; at the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games, e-sports made its debut at the Asian Games as a performance rather than an official event, and the Chinese e-sports delegation won 2 gold medals and 1 silver; December 2020 On the 16th, at the 39th General Assembly of the Olympic Council of Asia, e-sports was approved as an official event of the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5b099e5d1f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5b099e5d1f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, after the game, the e-sports players of the Hong Kong team of China (right) shook hands with the players of the Chinese Taipei team. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从风暴到常态：审计结果公开二十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/wZQfLtQoOm2O6lcVO2LGZLhZEhsqWbg3H242Yr6H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height=&quot;844&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/wZQfLtQoOm2O6lcVO2LGZLhZE hsqWbg3H242Yr6H. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251918&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing, National Audit Office. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of April 2023, the amount of problems discovered in the 2021 audit has been rectified to an amount of 850.111 billion yuan. , improved more than 2,900 systems, and held more than 14,000 people accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the data released by Hou Kai, Auditor General of the National Audit Office, when he made the &quot;Audit Work Report of the State Council on the Implementation of the Central Budget and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures in 2022&quot; on June 26, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When seeing the 2022 annual audit work report, Cai Chun, vice president of the China Auditing Society and professor at the School of Accountancy of Southwestern University of Finance and Economics, believed that with the improvement of auditing levels and the improvement of system construction, auditing has become normalized Serve national governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public’s impression of audit work was at least 20 years ago. On June 25, 2003, Li Jinhua, the then Auditor General of the National Audit Office, delivered the 2002 annual audit work report to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. A number of ministries and commissions, including the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Education, and the former State Planning Commission, were publicly criticized. At that time, the Internet had just emerged, and the full text of the report was made public on the official website of the National Audit Office, attracting national attention and calling it an &quot;audit storm.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiaorong, a professor at the School of Government Auditing at Nanjing Audit University, believes that 20 years ago, the public was accustomed to the government keeping fiscal revenue and expenditures secret. At that time, &quot;disclosure itself was a hot topic,&quot; but now, even if public opinion does not pay attention , auditing also functions as usual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back over the past 20 years, it is not difficult to find that with the development of society, the focus of auditing has also changed. Different periods have different priorities, and some content has become history. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Tell the truth&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 2022 audit work report has many highlights. Different from previous scientific and technological achievements transformation audits, this time for the first time it focused on basic research and key core technology tasks, pointing out that some task deployments and requirements deviated from the planned goals, and some scientific research results were suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The audit found that for 45 key tasks, from the formulation of implementation plans to the signing of task contracts, the indicator requirements were reduced step by step. Some technologies have been mass-produced in China and do not need to be tackled. The pass rate of 649 accepted projects was 96.5%, but a spot check of 135 of them found that 34 had actually not completed all tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiaorong observed, &quot;Every year we review and find problems every year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2022 annual audit work report pointed out that 41 regions collected state-owned capital gains from loss-making enterprises, levied excessive taxes, or directly and randomly apportioned fines, etc., and illegally organized fiscal revenue of 7.75 billion yuan; 49 regions passed the commitment Through methods such as bottom-up buybacks and state-owned enterprise advance financing for construction, illegal new hidden debts of 41.516 billion yuan were added; 12 regions had to allocate treasury funds from superiors&#39; over-budget quotas, obtain bank advances or external borrowings of 28.072 billion yuan to maintain basic operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of neglect of management and supervision by units affiliated to various central ministries and commissions still exists. For example, 3 departments and 29 affiliated units were extravagant and wasteful. Some spent more than 27 million yuan to rent office space, with the per capita office area reaching 137 square meters. Some exceeded the contract schedule and spent 84.5807 million yuan at the end of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar problems were named 20 years ago. The 2002 annual audit work report pointed out that the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology fabricated false project budgets, signed false construction contracts with an engineering agency, and allocated 1.35 million yuan in budget funds. The Agency then recovered it in batches and used it mainly for the payment of staff subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An audit cadre recalled that it was in 2003 that the Audit Office became known to the public. Twenty years have passed since the Audit Office was established in 1983. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 25, 2003, after the full text of the 2002 audit work report was made public on the official website of the National Audit Office, it was widely reproduced by the media. Yang Suchang, a professor at the School of Economics at Lanzhou University, still remembers the shock brought by the report, &quot;(It turns out) the problem is so serious.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problems disclosed this year include: the fiscal revenue of counties and cities is relatively &quot;watered&quot;, artificial concealment of deficits is common, and the debt burden is heavy; the problem of enterprises failing to pay basic pension insurance funds is relatively common, and relevant management departments have misappropriated 420 million yuan; the National College English Level 4 and Level 6 Examination Committee of the Ministry of Education illegally collected 224 million yuan of examination fees from various places, from which 190 million yuan was spent on related examination fees and other expenses. etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the shocking nature of the problems announced, the public called it an &quot;audit storm.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the &quot;audit storm&quot; may be traced back to 1999. According to the audit work procedures at that time, every May, the National Audit Office should issue an audit results report to the State Council on the audit work of the previous year. Based on this report, it would then draft an audit work report to be submitted to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress fully explained the problems discovered in the audit. On June 26, 1999, Li Jinhua made the &quot;1998 Audit Work Report&quot; to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, pointing out that 43 departments and directly affiliated units of the State Council had misappropriated 3.124 billion yuan of fiscal funds and other issues. The China Economic Times quoted some members as saying , saying it was “the best audit report in many years.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;After the 18th National Congress, poverty alleviation auditing became a focus&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since 2003, what areas have audit work focused on? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters combed through and found that among the 21 &quot;Audit Work Reports&quot; from 2002 to 2022, in addition to the fixed annual financial audits, resource and environmental protection, social security funds, agriculture and rural areas are the most concerned. fields, appeared 17 times, 13 times, and 13 times respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In different periods, audit work also has different priorities. Taking the &quot;three official&quot; funds as an example, the 2007 annual audit work report used 103 words, pointing out for the first time that the tax department purchased cars without and beyond the establishment, as well as the problems of insufficient strict control of entertainment expenses, conference fees, training fees and overseas expenses. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, with the formulation and implementation of the eight central regulations, the &quot;three public&quot; funds began to become the focus of audit supervision. The 2013 annual audit work report used an unprecedented 1,244 words to directly address the management and use of &quot;three official&quot; funds and conference fees, naming 22 central departments and affiliated units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, the “three official” funds and conference fee expenditures of central departments dropped by 27% compared with the previous year, and the reform of official vehicles at the department level was basically completed. However, the audit still found that 33 departments and units, including the Ministry of Science and Technology and the former Ministry of Culture, occupied vehicles from other units for a long time, or leased 122 official vehicles in disguise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For nine consecutive years, &quot;three public funds&quot; have been mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Poverty alleviation was once the focus of the report. After the &quot;targeted poverty alleviation&quot; strategy was proposed in November 2013, the following year, the audit report once again included content on poverty alleviation auditing after a lapse of ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report pointed out that after auditing 19 key counties for national poverty alleviation and development work, it was found that 15.9571 million yuan of poverty alleviation funds were misappropriated by individuals, 173 million yuan of poverty alleviation funds were falsely claimed or misappropriated, and 5 counties had poverty alleviation funds. The department in charge of work illegally included 533,600 yuan in food, drink, and travel expenses among poverty alleviation management fees and other funds, and 227 million yuan in poverty alleviation funds remained idle for more than one year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/evLOaYcG1oPhzGE1tX8YmI86cZI29BnAy3yyGxM4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1271&quot; height= &quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/evLOaYcG1oPhzGE1tX8YmI86cZI29BnAy3yyGxM4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The 2022 annual audit work report pointed out that it is difficult for local governments to coordinate, integrate and use high-standard farmland construction funds. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2015, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Decision on Winning the Battle against Poverty&quot; , proposed to ensure that the rural poor will be lifted out of poverty by 2020, requiring the key links of accurate identification and establishment of files to be lifted out of poverty through industrial support and other measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was reflected in the report of the second year. The &quot;2015 Audit Work Report&quot; mentioned that a random inspection of 1,339 poverty alleviation household discount loans of 65.6 million yuan issued in Xundian County, Yunnan Province in 2015 Among them, only 711 amounts of 34.33 million yuan (accounting for 52%) were distributed to registered poor households. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2022, the report has audited employment subsidies and employment promotion funds for two consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Some sectors have been renamed 7 times&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past 20 years, the form of audit work reports has also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One change is the report name. The 2012 annual audit report produced in 2013 was titled &quot;Audit Work Report on the Implementation of the Central Budget and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures in 2012&quot;. The following year, it was changed to &quot;Audit Work Report of the State Council on the Implementation of the Central Budget and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures in 2013&quot;. , this format has been fixed to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not simply 3 more words. Zheng Xiaorong believes that according to the provisions of the Audit Law, the audit work report is submitted by the State Council to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. In practice, the National Audit Office makes the report on behalf of the State Council. Adding &quot;State Council&quot; to the title is more in line with the spirit of the Audit Law and can better reflect the authority of the audit work report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the title at the beginning of the audit work report was adjusted from the previous &quot;Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress&quot; to &quot;Chairman, Vice Chairmen, Secretary-General, and Members.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zheng Xiaorong&#39;s view, the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress is an institution, and the latter is more specific, &quot;similar to a roll call.&quot; The change of title is &quot;I hope that when deliberation and resolution of work reports, everyone attending the meeting &quot;People&#39;s Congress attaches great importance to it and strengthens the supervision role of the National People&#39;s Congress.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public is particularly concerned about which units are named. Over the past 20 years, the &quot;roll call&quot; has gone through a process from vague to gradually clear, and the number of named units has also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2002 annual audit work report blurred some region and unit information, replacing it with &quot;a certain province&quot;, &quot;a certain district government&quot;, &quot;some airlines&quot;, etc. As for the persons who violated laws and disciplines discovered by the audit, it was not until the 2006 annual audit work report that the names of the parties began to appear. Previously, only their units and positions were named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiaorong believes that this is a sign of caution by the audit agency. Information disclosure was still sensitive at the time. &quot;After the information is disclosed, there will be unexpected results.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Another change is that after 2017, the number of units named in the report decreased. Southern Weekend reporters did not make complete statistics. In 2017, the report named 24 units, but this number dropped to 3 in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Li Yuedong, director of the Audit Department of Southwestern University of Finance and Economics, this has something to do with the changes in the audit function. &quot;Now it is more about helping the audited unit solve problems.&quot; The time for audit evidence collection is limited, and More emphasis is placed on the discovery of major problems. &quot;Some small problems may not necessarily appear in the report. Just inform them of the rectification.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiaorong added that in the past, some audited units were not very cooperative during the work process and did not report in the report. Name-calling was once a way to promote rectification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fixed sections in the audit work report have also undergone many name changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that for the first time in the 2008 annual audit work report, the chapter &quot;Disclosure and investigation of major violations of laws and regulations&quot; appeared. In addition to announcing the number of transferred clues to major violations of laws and regulations and economic crime cases, In addition to the number of people involved, the form, means and methods of the crime are also summarized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the chapter has been renamed 7 times, such as &quot;Major violations of laws and regulations and economic crime cases discovered by audit&quot; in 2012, and &quot;Major violations of laws and regulations discovered by audit&quot; in 2013. In 2014, it was “cases suspected of major violations of laws and regulations detected by audit.” In 2021, it was renamed &quot;Clues to Major Violations of Discipline and Law&quot; and remains so far. The issues mentioned include &quot;corruption of petty officials&quot;, micro-corruption at the grassroots level and &quot;supporters taking advantage of the mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 21 audit reports, the content, location and name of the chapters are not fixed as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiaorong also noticed this phenomenon. He believed that as the system gradually becomes standardized, the audit agency has discretion over the form of the audit work report, which will also affect the text form and framework of the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Breaking Barriers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Governments at different levels bear public entrusted economic responsibilities. While fulfilling their responsibilities, the government has also been given specific responsibilities. Power.&quot; Cai Chun believes that the role of auditing is to ensure the fulfillment of government responsibilities and promote the use of public power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the 2009 annual audit work report pointed out the overall large scale of local government debt, the high debt repayment pressure of some local governments, and the insufficient solvency of fiscal funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, in accordance with the requirements of the State Council, in 2011 the National Audit Office organized more than 40,000 audit agencies across the country to conduct audits on all audit offices across the country based on the principle of &quot;seeing accounts, people, and objects, and reviewing each transaction one by one.&quot; 25,590 government departments and agencies, 6,576 financing platform companies, 54,061 other units, 373,805 projects and 1,873,683 debts involved in local government debt were audited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Audit rectification was once a &quot;difficult&quot; issue. Before the revision of the Audit Law in 2021, there were no specific provisions on what measures should be taken if the audit object does not make rectifications as required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the newly revised Audit Law responded: &quot;The audit results and rectification status should be used as an important reference for assessing, appointing and removing, rewarding and punishing leading cadres, formulating policies, and improving systems; those who refuse to rectify or commit fraud during rectification will be Legal responsibilities shall be pursued in accordance with the law.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Audit Law, audit agencies are under the dual leadership of the government at the same level and the audit agency at the next higher level. In reality, the government at the same level has a greater influence on the audit agency at the same level. Liu Air Force, a staff member of the Audit Bureau of Huaihua City, Hunan Province, published an article in 2009 stating that 62% of team members in 13 local county (city, district) grassroots audit agencies were adjusted without consulting the superior audit agency in advance, resulting in dual management. Just a formality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zheng Xiaorong, before the audit results are reported to the people&#39;s congress at the same level, the government has the opportunity to intercept and screen the problems reported. &quot;Some problems cannot be investigated thoroughly, and the supervisory power cannot be extended downwards.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2010, there were many views on the issue of audit system reform. According to an article published on the official website of the Audit Office in 2013, Huang Kai, the director of the Audit Office, summarized the views of all parties into the theory of upgrading. , vertical theory, independence theory and legislative theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legislative theory that is most highly praised by industry insiders is that the audit agency is subordinate to the People&#39;s Congress and independently exercises audit supervision power over government departments. As early as 2002, Yang Suchang conducted a questionnaire survey among 62 Audit Office officials, local audit agency officials, government officials, People&#39;s Congress cadres, and audit scholars. 77% of the respondents agreed or basically agreed with the legislative audit system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The discussion on the reform of the audit system has not stopped. In December 2017, after the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, Yang Suchang was invited by the National Audit Office to discuss the direction of audit system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The answer will be revealed soon. In March 2018, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China issued the &quot;Plan for Deepening the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot; and announced the establishment of the Central Audit Commission. &quot;I didn&#39;t expect it to be established.&quot; Yang Suchang said that from a practical perspective, &quot;Under the leadership of the Central Audit Commission, the audit work is integrated with the party&#39;s leadership and supervision system.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problems found in the audit &quot;must Reporting to the Central Audit Committee, and directly”. Zheng Xiaorong believes that although the current audit institutions are still under the dual leadership of the government at the same level and the audit institution at the higher level, the Central Audit Commission has broken down the barriers formed under government management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[印度裔CEO正在“统治”世界，凭的是什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257541]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, there is a half-joking saying circulating in the field of workplace human resources (HR): Indians are using a A strange way to &quot;rule&quot; the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meaning is: Indian-origin professional managers and workplace elites are achieving greater and greater success in the world. More than 30% of the CEOs of large Silicon Valley companies in the United States are Indians. Among U.S. companies, the top ten Indian-Americans serve as chairman, CEO, president, and chief operating officer: Google &amp;amp; Alphabet, Microsoft, FedEx, IBM, Novartis Pharmaceuticals, NetApp, Barclays Group, Starbucks, and Adobe , Micron Technology and other world-renowned companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Led by this type of Indian professional managers who hold top-level positions, these companies have recruited a large number of younger, lower-level Indian elites for high- and middle-level management positions, technical positions, Key positions such as finance and human resources are increasingly occupied by Indian career elites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indians have an increasing influence in the Western world and have become the most powerful minority group in American and British societies. Many Westerners know that Indians are not easy to mess with, and the social status they have gained , the social achievements achieved far exceed those of local Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have interviewed some HR organizations to understand why they are willing to promote Indian professional managers, what employers think of Indian managers, and why Indians have achieved such achievements. The feedback received shows that Indians The advantages of ethnic-American workplace elites are roughly as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Value recognition: India was a British colony for a long time, and Indians were once ridiculed as British &quot;long-term laborers and coolies.&quot; However, Indians identify with and want to integrate into Britain and the United States. Social and lifestyle motivations are strong. Their purpose of studying hard is often to enter the British and American society, and gradually become &quot;foremen, housekeepers, and shopkeepers&quot; from &quot;long-term workers&quot;. When Indians go to Britain and the United States, they have no intention of going back. Instead, they try their best to take root there and transform from &quot;Indians&quot; to &quot;Indians.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Communication advantages: As a former British colony, high-end schools in India focus on English education. Therefore, its educational elites, despite their thick accents, have no barriers to language communication, which is a great advantage in the British and American workplaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Hindi belongs to the &quot;Eurasian language family&quot; and has many similarities with Western languages, based on Hinglish, there are also fewer obstacles for Indians to learn French, German, and Spanish. few. Therefore, the current trend of Indian workplace elites spreading from English-speaking societies to the entire Western world. The second communication advantage of Indians is that their living customs advocate chatting, chatting, and debating. Therefore, they can get along well with Westerners. Even if they have different opinions, they can chat and dare to talk. It is easier for them to get familiar with each other, which is good for promotion. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cultural diversity: India has 6 major religions, 22 official regional languages, 212 ethnic groups, and 414 tribes. Religions, cultures, and living customs vary greatly among regions and ethnic groups. Such a complex society makes Indians more adaptable to culturally diverse lifestyles. There has never been a &quot;grand unification&quot; in India&#39;s history, and its unification was all established with the help of the British. Therefore, when Indians come to the Western world, not only do they not find it weird and weird, but they think Westerners are too serious, rigid, and simple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teamwork: Indians focus on teamwork and interpersonal relationships, and their individuals usually have good interpersonal and communication skills, which are very important for senior management positions. Indians are very cooperative, and Indian executives in companies try their best to recruit Indian employees. There have even been cases of fraud: when an American hospital recruits doctors, the Indian director throws away all the resumes of non-Indian applicants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The folk rule of the Indian people is: those who are successfully recruited should give all of their 1-3 months&#39; salary (the higher the position, the higher the kickback) to the recruiter to express their gratitude for the kindness. . Almost no one in the Indian community violates this convention, forming a long-standing custom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obedience and loyalty: Corresponding to the above-mentioned Indian workplace custom of &quot;recruitment kickbacks&quot;, Indian employees are highly obedient to their superiors. Their subordinates are very good at communicating with their leaders. They will often ask their leaders: What else do you need from me? What am I not doing well? What can you do to be more satisfied? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have hired Indians, you will feel that they are generally more submissive, reliable, and secure, and leaders will gradually feel comfortable appointing and promoting them. One way of saying it is that Indian people often shake their heads slightly (to express approval and obedience) and say: I see, I see (I understand). It is known as &quot;Ah San, Ah San&quot; by Chinese people. Another theory is that Asan is &quot;Asir&quot;. At that time, the British often recruited Indians to serve as police officers in the colonies or concessions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People recruited by themselves are more capable, less likely to get into trouble, and less likely to cheat. This is also the reason why Indian executives dare to recruit subordinates of the same race. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resilience: Americans love to mock their government as useless and their president as incompetent. In the eyes of Indians, their own country and government are even worse. In order to survive in their own country, Indians have learned to persevere and make full use of limited resources to live under endless harsh conditions. This ability makes Indian employees more hardworking and hardworking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humility: As new immigrants from a backward and poor society, Indians understand and admit their limitations and deficiencies in many aspects. Therefore, they are more humble and open-minded during the learning process, making it easier for them to integrate into the local area and be accepted by the local society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Educational advantages in technology and engineering fields: As a late-developing country, India&#39;s education is similar to that in East Asia, with more emphasis on science and technology, engineering and other science and engineering courses. It is particularly distinctive in fields such as computers, engineering, and technological innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Indian Institute of Technology&quot; even boasts that &quot;those who cannot get into Indian Institute of Technology should go to MIT.&quot; This is of course bragging, but the large number of science and engineering talents it has trained have just made up for the excessive wealth in the English-speaking world. After a long period of peace, more and more wealthy young people no longer want to study hard to study science and engineering, but study &quot;literature, history, philosophy and arts&quot;. ” and other weaknesses of so-called “rich people’s disciplines”. The &quot;rich N generation&quot; in Europe and the United States learn the art of maintaining success and the method of controlling people, while the science and engineering talents from India serve as CEOs, directors, managers, technological elites... to achieve their own class jump. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dare to take risks and start a business: Indian individuals are more willing to take risks and start a business. They are more willing to set up their own companies and serve as CEOs after they grow. This entrepreneurial tendency has made them achieve great success in the business world. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Indians are moving from the business world to the political world, and the jokes about &quot;dominating&quot; the world are gradually becoming serious: British Prime Minister Sunak, Singaporean President Shanmugaratnam, Irish Prime Minister Varadkar, Portuguese Prime Minister Costa, and the President of Mauritius Roopun, Prime Minister Jugnauth, Guyana President Irfaan Ali, Suriname President Santokhi, etc. are all Indians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are currently too many Indian cabinet members in the U.S. government: Assistant to the President and Domestic Policy Advisor, Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Deputy Director of the National Economic Council, Senior Advisor to the Secretary of State, White House Chip Advisor and U.S. Commerce The department’s chief economist, deputy director of the White House Office of Presidential Personnel, senior White House staff and presidential speech writers are all Indians. However, Indians only account for 1.4% of the U.S. population. With such a small population weight, they can leverage such huge political influence. Leverage affects the national policies of the United States and even the direction of world politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The idea that Indian elites &quot;dominate&quot; the world is a joke to many people, but the trend cannot be underestimated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[有奖征集 | 鲁迅的哪些话，让你印象深刻？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257549]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In fifty-five years of life, I have left behind countless words. Sometimes it is sharp, sometimes desolate, sometimes uplifting, sometimes tender. &quot;From Baicao Garden to Sanwei Bookstore&quot;, &quot;Diary of a Madman&quot;, &quot;Young Runtu&quot;, &quot;The True Story of Ah Q&quot;, &quot;In Memory of Mr. Liu Hezhen&quot;... His writings are related to his family, country and society, and they are vivid in the Chinese textbooks of generations, and they are also stirring. in the hearts of every Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today is the 142nd anniversary of Lu Xun’s birth. Times have changed a long time ago, and life is advancing rapidly. If you read those sonorous and powerful words again, you will still feel enlightened and enlightened, and you will use compassionate gentleness to dissolve the mixed feelings. days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which words by Lu Xun impressed you deeply? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Welcome to participate in the interaction in the comment area below. &lt;strong>;We will select the person who leaves the most thoughtful message and receive a &quot;Lu Xun Reading Series T-shirt&quot; as a gift&lt;/strong>;. Wear the words on your body and turn them into the power to move forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Message deadline: October 9, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /0qsVbxH8GFKakbFx0pDTUFhMU8erUTB81TzWtMHJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0qsVbxH8GFKakbFx0pDTUFhMU8erUTB81TzWtMHJ. jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;251841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国泳队包揽亚运开赛首日全部7枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257565]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, formed by Yang Junxuan, Cheng Yujie, Wu Qingfeng, and Zhang Yufei The Chinese team won the women&#39;s 4x100m freestyle relay event in 3 minutes, 33.96 seconds, breaking the tournament record.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/2432a564ca.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2432a564ca .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023, by Yang Junxuan, Cheng Yujie, Wu Qingfeng, Zhang Yufei The Chinese team won the women&#39;s 4x100m freestyle relay event in 3 minutes, 33.96 seconds, breaking the competition record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of September 24, 2023, 7 gold medals were awarded in the swimming event of the Hangzhou Asian Games. Zhang Yufei, Wang Shun, Li Bingjie, Pan Zhanle, Tang Qianting, Xu Jiayu, Cheng Yujie, Yang Junxuan, and Wu Qingfeng won 7 gold medals for the Chinese team, breaking multiple competition records and Asian records! Many athletes from the Chinese swimming team won silver and bronze medals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Wang Shun beat Qin Haiyang to win the men&#39;s 200-meter medley. He set a new personal best time of 1 minute, 54 seconds and 62 seconds, and also broke the Asian record Record.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/a925420da0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/a925420da0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Wang Shun defeated Qin Haiyang to win the men&#39;s 200-meter medley. He set a new personal best time of 1 minute, 54 seconds and 62 seconds, and also broke the Asian record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the women&#39;s 200-meter butterfly final, Chinese star and Tokyo Olympic champion Zhang Yufei successfully defended her title with a time of 2:05.57 and broke the competition record. . This is the first gold medal for the Chinese swimming team in this Asian Games. Yu Liyan won the silver medal in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Zhang Yufei won the 200-meter butterfly gold medal, completing the first of her seven gold medal goals. At the same time, she set a new meet record in 2 minutes, 5 seconds and 57 seconds. &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/54989279d5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/54989279d5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Zhang Yufei won the 200-meter butterfly gold medal, completing the first of her seven gold medal goals. At the same time, she set a new competition record with a time of 2 minutes, 5 seconds and 57 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Zhang Yufei was in the competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/ 8e032ffdaf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/8e032ffdaf.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;251869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Zhang Yufei was in the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the men&#39;s 200-meter individual medley final, Tokyo Olympic champion Wang Shun broke the Asian record in 1 minute, 54 seconds and 62 seconds and won the championship. Qin Haiyang won the runner-up in this project. After the game, Wang Shun said: &quot;I am very satisfied with breaking the Asian record. It was the elders in my hometown who gave me strength!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Wang Shun waved after the game. &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/193302a019.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/193302a019.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Wang Shun waved after the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Qin Haiyang warmed up before the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /25/17ec106ec8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/17ec106ec8.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;251871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Qin Haiyang warmed up before the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final, Chinese star Li Bingjie won the championship with a time of 15 minutes, 51 seconds and 18 seconds, and significantly rewritten the competition record. Another player of the Chinese team, 15-year-old Gao Weizhong, won the silver medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, in the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final, Li Bingjie won the championship with a time of 15 minutes, 51 seconds and 18 seconds. 15-year-old Gao Weizhong won the silver medal.&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/ffd4af8357.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/ffd4af8357.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 24, Li Bingjie won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final with a time of 15 minutes, 51 seconds and 18 seconds. 15-year-old Gao Weizhong won the silver medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Li Bingjie, wearing a panda swimming cap, won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle event without any suspense. She broke the competition record with a time of 15 minutes, 51 seconds and 18 seconds.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afef9efb15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afef9efb15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Li Bingjie, wearing a panda swimming cap, won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle event without any suspense. She broke the competition record with a time of 15 minutes, 51 seconds and 18 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the men&#39;s 100-meter freestyle final, Chinese star and Asian record holder Pan Zhanle broke his own Asian record and won the championship with a time of 46.97 seconds. He also became the first Asian player to swim 47 seconds in this event. Chinese player Wang Haoyu won the silver medal in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the referee rang the bell at the pool to remind the swimmers entering the final lap.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/acaea8bce5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/acaea8bce5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 24, 2023, the referee rang the bell at the poolside to remind the swimmers entering the last lap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Tang Qianting won the women&#39;s 50-meter breaststroke in 29.96 seconds.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/25/70572f9fb3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /25/70572f9fb3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023 , women&#39;s 50-meter breaststroke, Tang Qianting won the championship in 29.96 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the women&#39;s 50-meter breaststroke final, Chinese team player Tang Qianting won the championship with a time of 29.96 seconds. In the morning preliminaries, she broke her own Asian record held. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Tang Qianting maintained the lead in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/afd8995c28.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afd8995c28. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Tang Qianting maintained the lead in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the men&#39;s 100-meter backstroke final, Chinese star Xu Jiayu broke the competition record with a time of 52.23 seconds and won the championship. Chinese player Wang Gu Kailai finished fourth in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the Chinese team members of the women&#39;s 4x100 meter freestyle relay posed in a heart-warming pose after the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/25/01f1d92924.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/25/01f1d92924.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023, Women&#39;s 4x100 Athletes from the Chinese team in the meter freestyle relay pose in a show of love after the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Hong Kong athletes from China won the bronze medal in the women&#39;s 4×100 freestyle relay.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/25/40fff8a813.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25 /40fff8a813.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, Hong Kong players from China won the women&#39;s 4×100 Freestyle relay bronze medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the women&#39;s 4x100m freestyle relay final, the Chinese team composed of Cheng Yujie, Yang Junxuan, Wu Qingfeng and Zhang Yufei won the championship with a time of 3 minutes, 33.96 seconds, breaking the competition record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the audience cheered for the Chinese swimming team.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/10cdff31f3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/10cdff31f3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251879&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, the audience cheered for the Chinese swimming team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Regarding the fruitful results achieved by the Chinese swimming team, some netizens joked: Are they coming to Hangzhou to wholesale gold medals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[鲁迅 不会挖矿的医生不是好作家丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257470]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 09:26:20 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鲁迅：我这一辈子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257328]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/23/RYvzS4EwCdyaokXiS3BOILQxoYZCXlcUS7N3Tpsh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;22120&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/RYvzS4EwCdyaokXiS3BOILQxoYZCXlcUS 7N3Tpsh. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251689&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>