<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[北京跳水大爷：只愿安静跳水，不想当网红]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256880]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team coach Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;1, 2, 3, jump!&quot; Coach Meng Derui gave the order, and more than a dozen adults and aunts in swimsuits jumped into the water from left to right, splashing everywhere. splash. &quot;Someone jumped, let&#39;s do it again.&quot; Coach Meng was in second place, and he heard that the rhythm of entering the water behind him was wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Diving Team&quot;) rehearsing the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump in the South Moat on September 13. Every day at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, this group of 60 and 70-year-old people come here from all directions to participate in &quot;training&quot;. They perform tuck-knee pose, swallow pose, back swallow pose, front and back somersaults...all of them are as strong as swallows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Training is over , Zhang Yuan rode an electric bike home &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting out of the water, water droplets lay on her wheat-colored skin, which was particularly bright under the sun. . Although the team has been established for less than three years, most of the team members have 20 to 30 years of winter swimming or diving experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the personal training session, Coach Meng completed a set of backward somersault half-circle pike jumps. &quot;201B, performance level, so exciting,&quot; teammates and passing spectators clapped and praised. Applause and laughter continued on the shore - some applauded, and some who failed the jump were heckled and joked, &quot;Isn&#39;t this shot painful enough?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You see, everyone is laughing so hard Mouth, everyone is here just to have fun.&quot; Mengdry said while looking at his teammates. This 67-year-old Beijinger grew up in the alleys of Di&#39;anmen. He remembered two very happy things when he was a child. One was flying a kite on the tiles of a bungalow, and the other was swimming in Shicha Sea. In the 1960s, Meng Derui, who was in primary school, studied diving at the Shichahai Sports School. His coach later went abroad to teach and also brought out world diving champions. Because of his professional background and his approachability, the team members affectionately called him &quot;Meng Jiao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For every new position, Meng Jiao explained the movements to us from head to toe and demonstrated it personally. No matter how cold the weather was, he could do a standard demonstration when he climbed on the platform. In his Under the leadership of the diving team, we adults have moved from a group of diving bastards to a quasi-professional level,&quot; said 62-year-old team member Zhang Yu&#39;an. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The team members rehearse the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Don’t want to take risks Risking your life to become an Internet celebrity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 3, 2023, Meng Jiao led the diving team to Tianjin to socialize with local diving friends. At that time, the diving master of Tianjin Lion Forest Bridge was popular all over the world. net. Some netizens posted a video of the team members arriving in Tianjin online with the title &quot;Beijing Diving Master Comes to Tianjin to Play Gym&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, it’s not a competition at all, but an exchange and learning between diving friends. We have known each other for many years and are very familiar with each other. We go there to dive there every year because there are more suitable venues for high school students in Tianjin. The environment for bridge diving - the water is deep, the bridge is high, and the water bottom is clean.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an introduced, &quot;Like the Beijing South Moat where we train daily, the water depth is about 3 meters, and the bridge deck is 5 meters away from the water. For safety reasons, law enforcement officers do not allow us to To jump from the bridge, you can only jump from the guardrail on the shore, the height is only 2 meters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop in Tianjin is the Chifeng Bridge, which is more than 9 meters high. Wang Tieshun, the &quot;Ironman of Winter Swimming&quot; in the team, was the first to take the stage. In his first jump, the &quot;Reverse Swallow&quot;, his buttocks touched the water first, and he was slapped hard, which was not ideal. He analyzed that it was due to the increase in height that there was a problem with the angle of entering the water. He immediately adjusted his posture when entering the water, and performed a wonderful dance afterwards, which won bursts of applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Brother Wang is 69 years old. Generally, when a person of this age stands at a height of 9 meters and looks down, his legs will tremble. Not only does he dare to jump, but he is also a &quot;anti-Yan&quot; who is cool and neat, so generous. People are impressed.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an said as he opened his arms in a &quot;swallow pose&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second stop was the &quot;8A-level scenic spot&quot; Lion Forest Bridge. The deck of the Lion Grove Bridge is about 6 meters above the water surface, which is an ideal height for high bridge diving. The team members just skipped here three months ago and it was a great experience. But at this time, there were already a sea of ​​people on and off the bridge, and the scene was very chaotic. Those who could jump and those who couldn&#39;t jump plunged into the water. Meng Derui saw a man walking into the water with his child in his arms, and he still has lingering fears. For safety reasons, he decided to lead his team members to evacuate immediately without jumping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training , the brothers went to a nearby restaurant to have a drink&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Someone at the scene recognized that we were from Beijing and chased us all the way. We were following the filming, but we still withdrew. Everyone comes to dive for physical and mental pleasure and to improve their skills. They don’t want to risk their lives to become an Internet celebrity and be in the limelight.&quot; Zhang Yuan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Changluo, director of the emergency department of Changsha Central Hospital, said in an interview with the media that high-bridge diving is very dangerous, and it is easy to get injured if you blindly try it without professional guidance. In addition to damage to the retina, head and cervical spine, if the diving posture is incorrect and the abdomen falls into the water first, the impact may damage the internal organs, or even cause fatal consequences such as spleen rupture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another risk comes from the complex and unpredictable underwater conditions of natural waters. Every time the diving team arrives at a new water area, they will send members to go into the water first to survey - how deep is the water and whether there are large rocks or sharp foreign objects. Wang Tieshun once found a shared bicycle and several broken beer bottles underwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Safety is the most important thing for the diving team. In addition to their own safety, there is also the safety of others. Some young people passing by also want to dive with the old men on a whim. &quot;When encountering this situation, we will first dissuade them - if you haven&#39;t practiced before, don&#39;t jump blindly. If you jump, we will also remind you: the water depth here is not enough. If your head enters the water, you must raise your head in time, otherwise it will be easy to poke vertically to the bottom of the water.&quot; Meng Meng and his team members have encountered many such young people. Some of them couldn&#39;t wait to take off their clothes and shoes, and shouted to plunge into the water. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the training, Zhang Yuan rode his electric bike home&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the years, the team members We have rescued many people who accidentally drowned. &quot;Especially in the summer of 2023, which was extremely hot, more people came to swim than in previous years. Many delivery boys came here to take a shower. They parked their cars on the shore, took off their riding clothes, and plunged in. After a while, He was dangling in the water, and when we found out, we quickly swam over and pulled him ashore,&quot; Wang Tieshun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the 1990s, Meng Derui participated in the New Year diving event at Xinjiekou Gap&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The fun and hidden dangers of natural waters&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For adults and adults, on the premise of ensuring safety, the fun of swimming in natural waters is something that cannot be achieved in indoor swimming pools. Comparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the view is wide and there are few people. You can enjoy the natural scenery while swimming. Secondly, there is the water quality. Many adults said that they cannot stand the smell of disinfected water in indoor swimming pools, which &quot;makes their brains hurt.&quot; Natural waters like the South Moat are treated gray water, which is safe and odorless. Of course, there are also economic reasons. A swim in an indoor swimming pool costs at least dozens of yuan, and you only need to prepare a pair of swimming trunks in natural waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, as Beijing’s water ecological environment has gradually improved, the water affairs department has continued to increase the openness and sharing of river and lake spaces to meet citizens’ water-related needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About two years ago, a group of swimming enthusiasts that Zhang Yuan belongs to forwarded eight officially opened natural water swimming spots in Beijing, including Beijing Bay Sunken Square, Dongzhimen Triangle, and Yongyin Canal 8. A lake and the south moat where the diving team is currently located, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The warning sign here used to be &#39;No Swimming&#39;, but now it is &#39;Civilized Water Activities, Ensure Life Safety&#39;. Recently, the relevant departments have also equipped lockers on the shore. These are welcome new features. Weather.&quot; Mendry said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Regulations on the Protection and Management of Rivers and Lakes in Beijing&quot;, in non-water source protection areas and waters where there are no &quot;No swimming, skating and other water activities&quot; signs, event personnel or organizers should take safety protection measures. activities under the premise. However, due to safety concerns, relevant managers will dissuade you from doing so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Every afternoon, the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team will train on the bank of the South Moat&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;The two movable jumping platforms currently used by the team members are made by Wang Tieshun, which is safe, easy to move without damaging the guardrails&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&quot;Some managers are afraid of being held responsible for accidents, so they set up obstacles and prevent swimming in legal natural waters. We have our own ideas about this. Many of us have been swimming our whole lives, and we often travel in groups. How could something happen so easily? Among our team members, there are quite a few people who have rescued people who slipped and fell into the water, accidentally drowned, and committed suicide. Without daily outdoor exercise, how could we have the ability and physique to save people?&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an hopes to pay attention to nature. The management of water activities in water areas should not be &quot;one size fits all&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As evening approached, Mr. Li, who lived nearby, took his children to the river to swim. The family had just moved to Dongcheng District for the purpose of studying for their children. One day I was riding by here and saw people swimming and diving in the river. The children also wanted to try it. Now they can&#39;t wait to come here to play in the water every day after school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For children, this kind of natural water area is definitely much better than the experience in an indoor swimming pool. You can have more fun here. Diving is not allowed in the indoor swimming pool, and you cannot change swimming lanes at will, because it will It affects other people.&quot; Mr. Li was a little concerned about the water quality at first, but the children swam for more than half a month and felt fine. &quot;The water quality here may have a higher microbial content, and the residual chlorine and urea in the swimming pool may be higher. . Chlorine is very harmful to the respiratory tract, especially children. If you keep swimming in it, there may be some potential harm. There is no such problem in natural waters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he spoke, a large area The water plants floated slowly, and the curious children wanted to catch them, but Mr. Li immediately stopped him, &quot;Don&#39;t touch the water plants, they will tangle you up and make you unable to move your hands and feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;Beijing’s middle-aged and elderly diving team took a group photo with the Bayi Lake diving team who came to exchange and learn. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Diving is a spirit Relief&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking back on Meng Derui, the three years he spent learning diving in the sports school were unbearable. Other children were happily playing pinball and shooting cigarette boxes after school, but he could only go to training hard. &quot;Although I was in the amateur team at the time, the training was very strict. A group of 10 jumps for each movement was counted, and five or six groups had to be danced in half a day. Basic skills such as leg presses and shoulder presses were interspersed in between. The coach was also very strict, and the movements were not up to standard. Just hit the bottom of the shoe.&quot; Meng Derui has a family with many children, and he is the sixth child. His family sent him to a sports school just to have a free place to take care of him and to exercise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Derui loves water by nature. He feels excited when standing on the diving platform, and it is indescribable satisfaction to jump into the water. Later, when he went to the mountains and countryside, he took advantage of his lunch break to go to a nearby reservoir to continue practicing. After returning to Beijing for work, after dinner, I rode my bicycle to a bridge at Xinjiekou Gap to dive. On weekends or holidays, go dancing on the high platform of the outdoor swimming pool in Gongti or Taoranting Park. It costs 10 cents for two hours. At this time, there is no urging from the coach, but an inner need - when diving, you must concentrate on thinking about the movements and not have distracting thoughts, so that you can forget a lot of &quot;messy things&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Mengdry helped take care of his grandson. Sometimes when he did not come to training in the afternoon, his teammates knew that he must have gone to pick up his grandson. &quot;At home, it&#39;s all about fulfilling obligations, being tired and worrying. Coming here to dive with everyone is the most relaxing and joyful thing of the day,&quot; Mengdry called it a &quot;spiritual relief.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the training, the team members shared their fruits, and the brothers occasionally met up to have a drink. If a team member has a birthday or someone’s grandchild is one month old, they have to find a place to celebrate together. Not long ago, Meng Jiao&#39;s wife broke her foot. Zhang Yu&#39;an immediately sent his unused wheelchair to his home and accompanied him to the hospital. Several teammates went to visit his home. &quot;The relationship between our teammates is closer than that of real brothers.&quot; Mengdry sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yuan had many hobbies when he was young and studied art and decoration in his spare time , photography and design. In terms of sports, he is involved in skating, skiing, swimming, diving, cycling, running, and mountain climbing. He knows that he is not good at everything but enjoys the process and joy of learning and mastering each sport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Zhang Yuan got acquainted with Meng Jiao and these like-minded teammates, and concentrated his energy on diving, almost without landing for three years. He felt physically stronger and more energetic than before. &quot;We seniors in our 60s have a very simple idea: move more, exercise more, get sick less, and put less burden on the country and our children.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an has many dancing friends around him, and many years of chronic diseases such as high blood pressure, hyperlipidemia, and arthritis have passed. Keep exercising and get effective control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training, Wang Tieshun rinsed his body with his own water. Almost every team member has such a homemade bucket&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One early morning two weeks ago, an 80-year-old man came for a morning tour of the moat alone. Died of sudden illness. After hearing this, the team members expressed their regrets. Zhang Yuan had his own thoughts: &quot;It is very sad that such an accident happened. But I think this old man died very happily and could immerse himself in his lifelong hobby at the last moment of his life. In this way Leaving silently is much better than struggling in the hospital bed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[和心智障碍者成为同事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nervous and scared, I pushed open the door of the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others, I don’t know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked forward cautiously, and no colleagues with mental disabilities showed up. Don’t ever encounter it, I thought silently in my heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pap tap tap~&quot; came the sound of footsteps going down the stairs, and around the corner I met the first colleague with a mental disability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl, with her high ponytails, smiling, with bright eyes, raised her hands and shook them at me, &quot;Sister...Hello, sister!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This It was an opening that I had anticipated a lot in advance but didn’t expect. I didn&#39;t know how to respond to her enthusiasm, so I forced a smile on my tight face, said &quot;Hello&quot;, and turned around to go upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who knew that this girl was just here to lead the &quot;warm greeting army&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was catching up with my colleagues with mental disabilities in the factory who had changed into work clothes and went downstairs to do morning exercises. As they filed out, each one of them greeted me: some stopped and stood to say good morning to me. ; Some ran past me quickly, leaving echoes of hello drifting through my ears; others slowly walked downstairs, shyly saying good morning to me... The nervousness turned into surprise, and I suddenly Time just smiles and nods and says &quot;hello&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they finished walking, the stairwell became quiet again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I felt their outpouring of enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I walked up the stairs, there were pictures of them hanging on one side of the wall: profiles of employees working hard; employees participating in events; female employees dressed beautifully for Women’s Day... They seemed to be telling me: look! I&#39;m not dangerous, I can work, I can be beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing the entry procedures, the ordinary employees of the factory began to introduce me to the basic information of the entire factory and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked into the production workshop. Every colleague with mental disabilities was working seriously at his or her position. There was only the sound of the machine and the trainer&#39;s voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are engaged in some simple assembly and sorting work, which is boring, but they enjoy it very much. On my first day here, I heard that one of my colleagues with mental disabilities was called the &quot;Clamp King&quot; because of his excellent work on clamps. This resounding name was well known in the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The factory is very user-friendly and will arrange work according to their characteristics and provide them with some auxiliary tools to help them complete their work more efficiently. For example, when sorting two types of parts, one large and one small, because the difference is very small, the factory will use a 3D printer to make a slot into which one type of part can be placed, so that colleagues with mental disabilities can tell which type of part it is by placing it. As I got familiar with the factory, I secretly admired it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During lunch, the employees lined up in an orderly manner when they heard the lunch bell and walked to the dining area carrying their plates. After I sat down, an employee sat next to me and started some conversation: Hello, sister, what is your name? My name is so-and-so, sister, are you here to work? Sister, you look so beautiful today. Sister, where are you from? … They spoke a little slowly and maybe a little unclear, but they were very polite. What surprised me most was that the girl with the twin tails said to me after finishing the meal: “Sister, I’ll eat and leave first, please take your time.” &quot;Then he picked up his dinner plate, wiped the table clean with paper, pushed the chair under the table, and left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They would sing their favorite songs in the lounge during lunch break, mostly catchy old songs. Some people sang seriously, some interrupted and made trouble, some sat quietly by the window and watched the scenery... The work bell rang, and they returned to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will not shout suddenly or rush to attack others. Observation is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was chatting with others that I was interning in a factory where people with mental disabilities were the main people. Others looked at me strangely: Can these people also work? Is it a welfare institution organized by the government? Before actually entering this workshop, I also had this &quot;strange vision&quot;. However, after truly understanding it, I realized that there is light and love here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Be civilized and polite, they are the best practitioners of this slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a graduate student majoring in journalism and communication)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国三大车企工人首次同时举行罢工 前十天累计损失或超50亿美元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256852]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021183175256&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;The cumulative losses in the ten days before workers from the three major U.S. auto companies went on strike simultaneously for the first time may exceed US$5 billion.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2. myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp12 51434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width= &quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the contract between the auto workers and the auto manufacturer expired on the 14th, and the two parties failed to reach an agreement, a large number of American auto workers began to strike in the early morning of the 15th local time. Analysts pointed out that the auto workers&#39; strike may plunge the operation of the auto industry into chaos, thereby affecting the US economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250950&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At midnight local time on the 14th, which is noon on the 15th Beijing time, the labor contracts of approximately 150,000 American auto workers with the three automakers General Motors, Ford and Stellantis expired, and both parties have not yet agreed. A new contract can be reached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250948&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, 12,700 workers of the United Auto Workers union went on strike at the three plants of the three major automakers in Michigan, Missouri and Ohio. This is also the first time in more than 80 years since the founding of the United Auto Workers that auto workers have staged a strike against the three automakers mentioned above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;United Auto Workers President Sean Fein said that a larger &quot;general strike&quot; has not yet been held, but said that if labor and management cannot reach a new contract, &quot;any option is possible&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Auto industry analyst Garrett Nelson:&lt;/strong>;The most optimistic estimate we have seen so far is that in terms of strike costs, the cumulative losses in the first ten days may exceed $5 billion. The automobile industry is the largest manufacturing sector in the United States. If this situation continues into October and November, economic growth will definitely be affected in the third quarter and even more severely in the fourth quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花高价找“高富帅”？婚恋网站的“结婚保”与“VIP”套路多]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256741]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Relying on the rapidly developing Internet, dating and dating websites can theoretically provide broader and more convenient dating and matching services. However, in recent years, various routines and suspected cases of &quot;pig killing plate&quot; have occurred frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Beijing Business Daily&quot; reported in April this year that Ms. Zhang spent 20,000 yuan on Baihe.com to purchase a &quot;marriage insurance&quot; matchmaking service. The &quot;matchmaker&quot; who matched the service said that she would introduce high-quality men to her, and then successively Recommended 5 men. Ms. Chen mentioned that the five men did not express sufficient communication intentions, did not introduce themselves, and could not confirm the personal information mentioned by the &quot;matchmaker.&quot; Yuyao (pseudonym), who purchased a matchmaking service at Century Jiayuan’s Beijing Anzhen store, also revealed that she signed a contract and paid nearly 100,000 yuan. The store staff promised Yuyao that they would introduce “high-quality men” and “guaranteed success.” After Yuyao connected with several male users, none of them established a relationship between male and female friends. The two women asked for a refund because they were dissatisfied with the services of the dating website, but the other party had to deduct high fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Online social networking is a loose and progressive dating model, but the services provided by dating websites are very purposeful. Men and women who register as members or even purchase paid services have clear demands for marriage and love, and they hope to pass them. Dating and dating websites find people who match their own requirements and have corresponding expectations and measurement standards in terms of appearance, income, position, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mating and dating websites will provide two services for this type of men and women. One is a free registration service. After the user registers, they will &quot;audition&quot; for opposite-sex users who are also registered on the website to find those who meet the conditions and can communicate with each other. of opposite-sex communication. However, this method is inefficient and consumes a lot of time and energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save screening costs and improve success rate and safety, some consumers choose paid services provided by dating websites. In this regard, marriage and love websites provide &quot;offline matchmaker&quot; services, which are divided into telephone customer service and emotional consultants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, a reporter from The Paper applied for a job and went undercover to enter an offline store of Jiayuan Online. After the short-term training, the store opened back-end permissions for reporters. Through the back-end, they can view the personal information of registered members of Century Jiayuan.com, including the user&#39;s browsing history and chat history. After obtaining the user&#39;s &quot;big data&quot;, the telephone customer service invites the user to the store for an interview through phone calls, text messages, etc. The reporter inquired about the statistics on the number of calls in the background of the system and found that most of the store&#39;s sales made an average of about 100 calls per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a customer comes to the store, the emotional consultant responsible for the interview will use words to guide, for example, &quot;Compared with buying a commercial house worth millions or tens of millions, it is better to spend tens of thousands of dollars to find your lover.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s worth it&quot;, and then displays the high-quality candidate information it has to induce users to sign up and pay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Paper reported: In 2017, Liu Gang, a consumer who had used the &quot;matchmaker one-on-one&quot; service, said that online membership fees are relatively low, and members are charged for sending and viewing messages, and users also pay more every year. It only costs a few hundred yuan in membership fees. Prices for high-end services range from 10,000 to hundreds of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do so many people fall into this trap? The supply and demand relationship in the marriage market also plays a driving role. Century Jiayuan has not announced the proportion of male and female paid members, but Ideal Island VIP, known as the &quot;Master and Doctoral Dating Platform&quot;, released the &quot;2023 Ideal Island VIP User Report&quot; stating that 40.2% of Ideal Island VIP users are men and 59.8% are women. Among them, women account for more than 60% of users in Shanghai, Chengdu, Guangzhou, Beijing, and Shenzhen. It is reported that after becoming the VIP of Ideal Island and searching for the opposite sex, if you need to initiate an exchange WeChat application, you need to pay to purchase a membership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a phenomenon of &quot;more boys and girls&quot; among users of dating websites, or it may be because men often bear the majority of dating expenses for both parties during the relationship, especially men at the bottom of the class who have to pay betrothal gifts when they get married. For the decision-making process of purchasing paid dating services More cautious. Some women consider more based on their age, partner&#39;s income, occupation, etc., and the need to find high-quality men through paid services is more urgent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to understand why female users are more likely to be deceived among the various service traps designed by dating websites. In 2021, Zhejiang Radio and Television&#39;s &quot;Xiaoqiang Online&quot; column reported that Ms. Lu, a Hangzhou citizen, registered as a member of Century Jiayuan in November 2019 and wanted to find a suitable partner. For this reason, she did not hesitate to borrow more than 130,000 yuan to pay the membership fee, because the contract stipulated that as long as she registered for marriage with the person recommended by the matchmaker during the contract period, the membership fee could be returned in full. However, after signing the contract, the candidates recommended by the matchmaker often did not meet Ms. Lu&#39;s standards, and Ms. Lu eventually requested a full refund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the recommended products not matching the previous promises, some users have also encountered suspected &quot;marriage trusteeship&quot; incidents. The Beijing News reported in 2017 that Xiaoqing, who had worked at Zhenai.com and Jiayuan for two years, said that marriage entrustments were common. Some sales matchmakers think that this member is useless, or that the conditions required are difficult to find, so the matchmaker will introduce their people to the other party and make it clear that they cannot establish a relationship, but just gather the number of people and go through the motions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the above incidents that the promises of &quot;full refund on scheduled marriage&quot; and &quot;marriage insurance&quot; services of dating websites are all based on so-called back-and-forth promises to allow female users to fall into their serial routine—— Brainwashing them with words to induce them to pay, and pretending to be a high-quality man as a &quot;marriage agency&quot; during the meeting. Although as early as 2017, the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the National Health and Family Planning Commission formulated and issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Further Improving Youth Marriage and Love Work&quot;, requiring the promotion of marriage and dating platforms to strictly implement real-name authentication and real-name registration, and severely crack down on Illegal matchmaking activities such as marriage entrustment and marriage fraud, but relying solely on the self-discipline of dating websites lacks the strength and breadth of normalized governance, making it difficult for users to safeguard their rights, and such routines will continue to spread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一边补贴购车，一边对中国电动车反补贴调查，欧盟为何双标？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256872]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/vRua021qrFj0ZpFrqYpZ4Wv0gH0XflmZuPMb1fs2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1062&quot; height=&quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vRua021qrFj0ZpFrqYpZ4Wv0g H0XflmZuPMb1fs2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250981&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Munich Auto Show. This year has the largest number of references for Chinese car companies in history. Not only BYD, Xpeng Motors, Leap Motors, SAIC MG, Avita and Cyrus participated in the exhibition, but also CATL, Yiwei Lithium Energy and so on. , Sunwoda and China New Aviation and other parts, software and hardware suppliers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China&#39;s electric cars, which are rapidly entering the market, have encountered &quot;stumbling blocks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the China Association of Automobile Manufacturers, in the first eight months of 2023, China&#39;s new energy vehicle exports surged 110% year-on-year. However, on September 13, 2023, European Commission President von der Leyen announced that it would launch a countervailing investigation into electric vehicles from China. The core of the investigation is whether the Chinese government provides subsidies to assess whether the EU needs to impose punitive tariffs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《电动汽车观察家》创始人邱锴俊认为，各国都在出台政策支持本国电动汽车产业发展，中国只是更早实行补贴而已，不存在正当性的问题。而且中国针对新能源汽车的“国补”政策已经于2022年终止，但有的欧盟成员国至今仍在对本国新能源汽车实行补贴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月14日，中国商务部新闻发言人回应，中国电动汽车产业快速发展，竞争力不断提升，这是坚持不懈开展科技创新、构建完整产业链供应链的结果。中方敦促欧盟从维护全球产业链供应链稳定以及中欧全面战略伙伴关系的大局出发，与中方开展对话磋商。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国电动汽车“国补”政策已经退出&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“全球市场现在充斥着更便宜的中国电动汽车。而巨额国家补贴人为地压低了它们的价格。”冯德莱恩称，这是欧盟考虑对来自中国的电动车启动反补贴调查的核心理由。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧盟委员会表示，中国在欧洲售出的电动汽车的市场份额已经上升到8%，并有可能在2025年达到15%。这一快速增长的占比是因为，中国电动车相较欧洲车型普遍存在20%左右的价格优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国政府确实给予了电动车补贴，但也很早设定了补贴的退出机制。 2022年初，财政部等四部门联合发文，明确2022年新能源汽车购置补贴政策于2022年12月31日终止，之后上牌的车辆不再给予补贴，延续13年的电动汽车“国补”政策正式退出历史舞台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;反观欧洲，近年来也出台了诸多对电动汽车产业的补贴政策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，德国对纯电动汽车根据售价给予不同的补贴，4万欧元以下车型最高补贴4500欧元。 2023年，法国普通消费者的购车补贴为5000欧元，低收入家庭的电动汽车补贴增至7000欧元。 2023年2月1日，欧盟委员会提议增加国家补助，使欧盟国家能够在电动汽车和其他绿色产品的生产领域中与其他国家竞争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“发展电动汽车这样的新兴产业，各国的产业政策都非常积极，只是存在着程度的差异。”邱锴俊表示，“早年所谓的完全自由市场，完全不干预产业发展的经济理论，在欧美其实也已经不流行了，当地也对新兴产业有很强的干预和扶持。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;对中国车企影响仍需观察&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据欧盟法规，反补贴调查最多需要13个月，意味着还需等待约一年后的“靴子落地”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在9月13日晚间，中概股新能源汽车就已集体下跌。小鹏汽车跌3.11%，理想汽车跌0.54%，蔚来跌4.64%。港股汽车股尾盘走低，比亚迪股份、小鹏汽车分别下跌3.53%、2.47%，吉利汽车跌1.52%，长城汽车、蔚来、理想汽车小幅下跌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在反补贴调查启动前，欧洲政策相对友好，对从中国进口的汽车征收关税为10%，而美国则为27.5%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邱锴俊表示，目前中国车企成本优势非常明显。若调查后被加征反补贴关税，增加幅度不大，中国车企依然具备竞争力；但如果被征收惩罚性关税，例如100%、150%的级别，打击将非常大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有远见的中国车企已准备在欧洲建设工厂，反补贴调查将可能加快他们的建厂进度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港中文大学（深圳）国际事务研究院研究员吴丹建议，中国车企应在行业协会的协助下加强协调磋商，形成共进退的立场和策略，完善涉外经贸法律工具箱，准确掌握欧盟立法信息和进展，与商务部密切合作，在中欧经贸高层对话中和欧方开展谈判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国有最好的电动汽车产业链&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;不少外国车企在中国设有工厂，所谓来自中国的电动汽车，也包含他们在内。反补贴调查也将波及在中国制造的非中国品牌车型，如特斯拉、宝马等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“外资品牌愿意在中国设厂，是用脚投票。不是因为中国有补贴，而是因为中国有最好的电动汽车产业链，拥有很好的汽车产业工人，正如马斯克盛赞特斯拉上海超级工厂的工人聪明且勤奋。”邱锴俊称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日，欧盟中国商会发表声明，中国电动汽车及上下游产业链企业不断创新，并在激烈的中国本土市场中累积出了整体产业优势，这种优势不是凭借所谓巨额补贴而形成的。中信证券的研报也指出，当前中国电动车并不以低价为卖点，竞争力来自技术积累、质量控制、用户体验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产业优势体现在了价格优势上。邱锴俊向南方周末记者举例，大众汽车旗下的ID.3车型，既在中国生产，也在德国生产，在德国售价为4万欧元，而在中国售价约1.5万欧元，巨大价差引起了德国一阵舆论风潮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据研究机构JATO Dynamics的一项统计，自2015年以来，欧洲电动汽车的平均价格从4.9万欧元上涨至5.6万欧元，美国从5.3万欧元上涨至6.4万欧元，而中国从6.7万欧元下降至3.2万欧元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/sgbOXPSp4wVLuSzSIK5Atygt7XfxqiISz85gHrFJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1086&quot; height=&quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/sgbOXPSp4wVLuSzSIK5Atygt7XfxqiISz85gHrFJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年5月23日，匈牙利德布雷岑，由中国宁德时代科技有限公司(CATL)投资的电动汽车电池厂正在建设中。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;出海之路漫长且艰难&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;此次欧盟对来自中国的电动汽车发起反补贴调查，不禁让人回想起欧盟于2012年对中国出口的光伏组件进行的“双反”（反倾销、反补贴）调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邱锴俊介绍，中国光伏产业兴起时，俗称“三头在外”，即原材料、技术、市场都在国外，中国作为主要加工地，由此发展起来。在“双反”调查中，中国光伏产业遭受了巨大打击，但也正是在这个阶段，中国光伏产业充分挖掘了内生力量，原材料、技术、市场都实现了本地化，当“双反”调查撤销后，重新占据了很大市场份额。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而电动汽车行业的发展路径与光伏行业有所不同。中国电动汽车起源于本地市场，发展到一定程度后再走出国门。中国新能源汽车目前市场渗透率为35%左右，国内还有很大市场需求，。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次欧盟的反补贴调查也敲响了警钟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴丹认为，欧盟对来自中国的电动汽车发起反补贴调查是典型的贸易保护主义，是欧盟双重标准的体现，无论在法律上还是道义上都完全站不住脚。目前，关于此反补贴调查，欧盟内部也存在巨大分歧，德法内部政治势力都是既有支持也有反对，但在现今政治环境下，德法内部的支持势力有能力推动欧盟启动调查，甚至影响调查结论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但除了面临贸易保护主义的阻碍，吴丹认为，中国汽车国标与国际标准不统一、我国新能源汽车出口认证制度尚未与国际接轨、海外消费能力下滑等因素，都制约了我国新能源汽车的国际化发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴丹曾撰文表示，在当前阶段，我国车企海外投资设厂规模远不及发达国家的传统跨国汽车制造商，中国车企想要从传统贸易模式向海外事业发展模式转变，提升配套供应链自主性和品牌影响力，还要经过漫长且艰难的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[恒大财富杜某等涉嫌犯罪人员被采取刑事强制措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256870]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mmbiz.qpic.cn/sz_mmbiz_jpg/Dm1HIR5mtBCpZsNIdQqubPCVicQZnZDBHsmns7gVm9iav5GtKbUibVljN4L3I5fNFCpHzw LxUYWrW5bEH9Kia5nIBw/640?wx_fmt= jpeg&amp;amp;wxfrom=5&amp;amp;wx_lazy=1&amp;amp;wx_co=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 0.5;&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://mmbiz.qpic. cn/sz_mmbiz_jpg/Dm1HIR5mtBCpZsNIdQqubPCVicQZnZDBHsmns7gVm9iav5GtKbUibVljN4L3I5fNFCpHzwLxUYWrW5bEH9Kia5nIBw/640?wx_fmt=jpeg&amp;amp;wxfrom=5&amp;amp;wx_lazy=1 &amp;amp;wx_co=1&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1694873788117-0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走近霍尔果斯“守关人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256824]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/FqInwUqfJtlhA5sf3cCHzxzSO15M5p9oKUr1J14C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;539&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FqInwUqfJtlhA5sf3cCHzxzSO15 M5p9oKUr1J14C. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Police monitor China-Europe trains leaving the country at night&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 10 o&#39;clock in the evening, the sun has just set, the rails and stones are still hot, and the high temperature emitted by the train engine is uncomfortable. Police officer Yue Shuang walked in the heat wave and urged police officers at all points to pay attention to train monitoring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the Horgos railway port located on the China-Kazakhstan border, and is also the center of China-Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚&lt;/span>;) One of the major passages on the west line. The four lanes of the railway freight yard were filled with trains waiting for entry and exit, and subsequent trains waiting for admission sounded their whistles in the distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/EZXRelpVvmcOYVYSip9HBnFRDsa5IZRPBoZ79QCu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/EZXRelpVvmcOYVYSip9HBnFRDsa5IZRPBoZ79QCu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Horgos Railway Port and surrounding freight yards&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is a 1,050-meter-long supervision road running through the east and west ends of the freight yard. As the deputy of the third team on duty at the Horgos Entry-Exit Border Inspection Station (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Horgos Border Inspection Station&quot;&lt;/span>;) Captain, Yue Shuang has been on this road for 11 years and witnessed the opening and development of the railway port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Horgos has a customs clearance history of more than 100 years and is my country’s closest and most convenient window to Central Asia, West Asia and even Europe. In July 2012, Yue Shuang, who had just graduated from the military academy, was assigned to the Horgos Border Inspection Station. At that time, this border town had a sparse population. Most shops were closed after 10 p.m., and “there were no people eating noodles on the street.” There is no place.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qjKUBwucyDgNE2lVo40qHUiVplDQZLmcvakaf6S3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qjKUBwucyDgNE2lVo40qHUiVplDQZLmcvakaf6S3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Before going to work, Yue Shuang checks the police appearance and discipline&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 22, 2012, the Horgos Railway Port opened for trial operation. Yue Shuang was among the first batch of policemen stationed at the scene. There were only four railway tracks, one guard bridge and a temporary structure in the vast Gobi. color steel house. According to the agreement between China and Kazakhstan, the railway port implemented a 7-day × 12-hour service model at that time, but there were only seven or eight inbound and outbound freight trains every day. Yue Shuang used &quot;boring&quot; to describe the work at that time, &quot;There was not much business volume, but it was very tiring.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change occurred in 2014, when the railway port was officially opened in February of that year. Yue Shuang still remembers that the number of trains that summer more than doubled than before, and the number continued to grow. The background of this change is that China proposed the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative in 2013, and Horgos is located in the &quot;core area&quot; of the &quot;New Silk Road Economic Belt&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WO9Y5ktr951A1xtFgbFggEZnfeaSqjKbqpjUGkbj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WO9Y5ktr951A1xtFgbFggEZnfeaSqjKbqpjUGkbj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Check the front of the truck to prevent hiding illegal items&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huo Ergos means &quot;the place where the camel caravan passes&quot; in Mongolian. It has been an important pass on the Silk Road since ancient times. Nowadays, this is the starting and ending point of the Lianhuo (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lianyungang-Horgos&lt;/span>;) Expressway and the 312 National Highway, &quot;Double West&quot; The eastern entrance of the &quot;Highway&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Western China-Western Europe&lt;/span>;) has an unparalleled position in promoting the interconnection between Eastern and Western societies. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/lAS1xailDfF88mOdOZIY1ETlBiJn5n8Vc4chJmHB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/lAS1xailDfF88mOdOZIY1ETlBiJn5n8Vc4chJmHB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Police officers climbed onto the covered bridge to monitor the train&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In March 2016, the Horgos Railway Port opened for China-Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Asia&lt;/span>;) trains, relying on its unique location advantages It has become the &quot;golden channel&quot; for international logistics land transportation - from the initial operation volume of less than 400 trains in the first year, it now passes through Central Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Asia&lt;/span>; ), the total number of trains exceeds 30,000, and the total number of train routes reaches 78, covering 18 overseas countries and 45 cities and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FmGY4SHJsZgoAPseKRsjQbHW5lTUyUHAZQdV0Dn5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FmGY4SHJsZgoAPseKRsjQbHW5lTUyUHAZQdV0Dn5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250560&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Police pre-check outbound passenger documents&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yueshuang In my memory, the initial inspection mainly relied on manpower. The police had to climb into the carriages one by one and check the bottom of the carriages to prevent criminals or prohibited items from hiding in them and illegal entry and exit. It took more than half an hour to inspect a train. Later, they formed a mature inspection process, strengthened technological means, and carried out comprehensive monitoring of inbound and outbound trains. Now it only takes about 10 minutes to inspect a train. In order to better adapt to the growing demand for customs clearance, the border inspection station has adjusted the railway port to a 365-day × 24-hour service model, so that entry and exit trains can be inspected and released at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1eF7ZbQvGlj1T8fCvN2CBPnzdGYnDZDn2hnXiIRB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1eF7ZbQvGlj1T8fCvN2CBPnzdGYnDZDn2hnXiIRB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Check the identity of the outbound truck driver&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Spring and Autumn Return Well, the most difficult parts are summer and winter.&quot; Yue Shuang said that the highest temperature in summer at the duty site is over 50 degrees Celsius, eggs can be fried on the railway tracks, and people often faint at the duty site; in winter, the lowest temperature drops to more than 30 degrees below zero. degrees Celsius, when the police inspected the car, their hands were accidentally stuck to the iron sheet of the carriage. If they tore it apart with force, bloody skin and flesh would be left on the carriage. In December 2018, the port encountered a blizzard with more than 70 centimeters of snow. In order not to affect the normal operation of the train, the police cleared the snow all night. Everyone was covered with thick ice when they returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the northwest of the railway port, about two kilometers away in a straight line, stands the sixth-generation national gate that was opened in September 2018. Hundreds of trucks leave the country from highway ports every day, transporting Chinese products to Central Asia and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Sdb8D0QuKty04rr4pXZlh6X3aDOCxCsI4vXRGoE5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Sdb8D0QuKty04rr4pXZlh6X3aDOCxCsI4vXRGoE5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Highway Passenger Transport Duty Site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Border of Horgos Zeng Qi, captain of the second team on duty at the inspection station, has witnessed the changes from the fifth generation to the sixth generation of the national gate. In his opinion, the design concept of the new national gate is more advanced. Passengers only need to scan their fingerprints and faces to clear customs in just 15 seconds; trucks adopt one-stop inspection and one-time customs clearance to improve customs clearance efficiency. From January 1 to July 21, 2023, the number of entry and exit vehicles at the port exceeded 100,000, exceeding the annual customs clearance volume of highway ports in previous years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are many potential changes that cannot be seen at ordinary times.” Zeng Qi said. In the past, export commodities were mainly fruits and vegetables, department stores and various daily necessities, but now they include building materials, machinery and equipment, precision instruments, etc. Among them, Chinese-made new energy vehicles are especially popular with countries along the “Belt and Road”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WKPqmSzsnAkezItMKQ5VwS3AhY40YNpCDOQrwJIm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WKPqmSzsnAkezItMKQ5VwS3AhY40YNpCDOQrwJIm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Vehicles of various types waiting to leave the country in front of the sixth-generation national gate&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What touched Zeng Qi most deeply was one day in May 2023. As he was getting off work, there was still a long queue of vehicles waiting to clear customs. They urgently met and negotiated with the Kazakh border inspection department and obtained the other party&#39;s consent to extend the customs clearance time. When the news came, the drivers waiting for customs clearance in front of the boundary bridge applauded in unison. They worked until about 5 a.m. the next day, and finally completed the inspection and release of all vehicles to be inspected. &quot;Seeing so many Chinese products leaving us, no matter how tiring it is, it&#39;s worth it.&quot; On August 15, 2023, the Horgos Highway Port began to implement 24-hour freight customs clearance on a trial basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is the tenth anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. With the continuous growth of port customs clearance, more and more tourists are visiting Horgos, and &quot;gold diggers&quot; from various countries are also pouring in. This border town is undergoing rapid changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Shuang once went out of the country to meet with the Kazakh border inspection department, and it was already night when he returned. He stood in the dark wilderness outside the country and looked at Horgos. It was brightly lit and bustling with traffic, making it a veritable &quot;city that never sleeps.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡适与吴鼎昌父子刘廷芳兄弟：从吴元黎旧藏《四十自述》说起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256625]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/LL1yxLVpALUNrKyeCE83Pod4zXgpgeFhBJuc4Sss.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;882&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/LL1yxLVpALUNrKyeCE83Pod4zXgpgeFhBJuc4Ss s. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250684&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Shi signed and presented Wu Yuanli&#39;s &quot;Autobiography of Forty&quot;. The picture on the right is young Wu Yuanli. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Liu Rongqian, who is far away in Canada, left me a message on WeChat not long ago: &quot;I am now eighty-six years old, so I should take advantage of the opportunity before I have dementia. &quot;I&#39;m going to sort out the relics left by my elders in the family. There are some old books among them. I chose three to give to you.&quot; He knew that I loved books, so he joked: &quot;A sword is given to a hero.&quot; It happened that a Chinese friend returned to China to visit relatives, and Liu My husband asked her to take it with her and deliver it to me when she got home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within a few days, I received three books from Nantong: one was the 1935 edition of Kang Youwei&#39;s &quot;Book of Datong&quot; by Zhonghua Book Company. The front and back covers had fallen off, and the title page had the words &quot;Wu &quot;Huansheng&quot; is printed in white. One is the 1943 edition of Chiang Kai-shek&#39;s &quot;The Destiny of China&quot; by Zhengzhong Bookstore. There is a calligraphy inscription on the title page: &quot;Brother Zhao Jinyong Huicun, brother Liang Kui respectfully presents it.&quot; Zhao Jinyong and Liang Kui were both diplomats during the Republic of China. There is also a 1959 edition of Hu Shi&#39;s &quot;Autobiography at Forty&quot; published by Far East Book Company, which is actually signed by Hu Shi. The last invoice was made by Wu Yuanli, Mr. Liu Rongqian&#39;s uncle, and the invoice was signed on May 31, 1960. Inside the book is a copy of Mao Zishui&#39;s &quot;Three Years After the Death of Mr. Hu Shizhi&quot; published in the third issue of Volume 6 of &quot;Biographical Literature&quot;. This was beyond my expectation. I have been thinking about Hu Shi’s autographed book for a long time, but I didn’t expect that it was Mr. Liu Rongqian who helped me realize my dream. These three books were all collected by Wu Yuanli. Mr. Liu Rongqian told me that after his uncle (Editor&#39;s note: Wu Yuanli) passed away in the United States, he went to California to help his cousin deal with his uncle&#39;s belongings and asked for it from his cousin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Check the &quot;First Draft of the Long Chronicle of Mr. Hu Shizhi&quot; (Supplementary Edition) compiled by Hu Songping. It says on June 1, 1960: &quot;Wu Yuanli and Liu Tingwei came to see him. Yuanli was Wu Dingchang (Da). (Quan)’s son, let’s talk about Wu Tat-quan’s autobiography &quot;Huaxi Xianbi&quot;.&quot; It can be seen that Hu Shi prepared the book a day in advance, and the gift of &quot;Autobiography at Forty&quot; was also a thoughtful and meaningful move. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Shi and Wu Yuanli did not have a close relationship and may have only met once or twice. On June 19, 1949, they met in the United States. Hu Shi did not have too many records in his diary. He only wrote: &quot;5:30 &amp;nbsp;Mr. Wu (Son of Da Quan).&quot; At this time, the Nationalist Government had withdrawn from Nanjing and Hu Shi arrived in the United States. On June 21, Hu Shi telegraphed his resignation as Foreign Minister to the new Executive Yuan Yan Xishan, who was retreating to Guangzhou. But Hu Shi should have heard about Wu Yuanli&#39;s deeds. On the morning of July 1, 1959, he attended the fourth academician meeting of Academia Sinica and served as the chairman of the meeting. At the meeting, Jiang Shuojie reported on the research status of Chinese economists in the United States and mentioned many talents in economics, including Wu Yuanli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQukqc6kLu6aOF9pBLBRSMm3uroyeMm8Jxnk6R1u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;628&quot; height= &quot;1028&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQukqc6kLu6aOF9pBLBRSMm3uroyeMm8Jxnk6R1u.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250679&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Dingchang (back row, right), Chen Shiyun (middle seat) and his wife take a photo with their daughter Wu Yuanjun (back row, left), son-in-law Liu Tingwei (back row, center), and son Wu Yuanli (front row, right) . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yuanli was born in Shanghai in 1920. He studied at Shanghai Nanyang Middle School and St. John&#39;s University in his early years, and later went to England for further study. In 1942, he received a first-class honors degree in economics from the University of London. In 1946, he received a doctorate in economics and was a disciple of Hayek. After returning to China, he served in the Central Bank. In 1949, he moved to the United States and became a professor in the Department of Economics at the University of San Francisco. Chen Yuxian divided the Chinese experts who studied Sinology in North America into five major groups. The second group was &quot;around the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China. A group of scholars who studied or taught in church universities migrated to North America. They encountered the expansion of North American institutions of higher learning after World War II.&quot; Soon, they became fluent in both Chinese and English and settled in various universities, becoming the backbone of Chinese studies in each school.&quot; Wu Yuanli is the leader in this second group. Since 1960, Wu Yuanli has served as a researcher and consultant at the Hoover Institution of Stanford University. He used the rich collections of the Hoover Library to write books such as &quot;Overseas Chinese and the Economic Development of Southeast Asia&quot;, &quot;The Role of the Chinese in the Economic Development of Southeast Asia&quot; and &quot;Taiwan: Towards an Industrialized Society&quot;. Precisely because of Wu Yuanli&#39;s superb research on China issues, he served as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense of the United States from 1969 to 1970. In 1985, Wu Yuanli won the Humboldt Foundation Research Award in Germany. In November 2008, Wu Yuanli accidentally fell and caused intracranial hemorrhage. He died at Stanford University Hospital in California on the 18th at the age of 88. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/3BQKBU2VVI5x5r8qEWYPN7BSq3FboPaO0bFfSg1A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1104&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/3BQKBU2VVI5x5r8qEWYPN7BSq3FboPaO0bFfSg1A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250683&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A group photo of Wu and Liu families. From left in the front row are Xu Yuanyue (Xu Shuxi’s eldest son), Liu’s mother Li Xi, Wu’s mother Chen Shiyun, and Wu Yuanli; in the back row from left are Liu Tingwei, Liu Tingfang, Liu Wenzhuang (Liu Tingfang’s second sister, Mrs. Xu Shuxi), Wu Dingchang, and Wu Yuanjun. Provided by Liu Rongqian. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked Mr. Liu Rongqian what special impression he had on this uncle (Editor&#39;s note: Wu Yuanli)? He said that when he was a child, he lived with his grandparents in Guiyang (Editor&#39;s note: referring to Wu Dingchang and his wife, Wu was the chairman of Guizhou Province at the time). One day the postman delivered a silver-gray box with a piece of coffee cake and a lot of dried fruits. His grandmother told him this It was sent from London by my uncle, and I still haven&#39;t forgotten the sweet taste. After the war of resistance against Japan was over in Nanjing, his uncle brought back his aunt with blue eyes and blond hair. This was the first time he saw his uncle and the first time he talked directly to &quot;foreigners&quot;. He felt strange. Later, his uncle went to the United States, and his family went to live in Taiwan. In 1962, my grandmother passed away, and my uncle returned to Taiwan to attend the funeral. In 1965, he was studying in Paris. His uncle and aunt came to see him. They saw that he was studying design during the day and working in a hotel at night. His life was difficult. His uncle suggested that he go to the United States to study economics instead. It would be easier to find a job after graduation and it would also help He lends a helping hand. He answered his uncle: &quot;I can only draw.&quot; In 1965, Liu Rongqian immigrated to Canada. A few years later, he brought his parents to live in Canada. His uncle would come to visit relatives every year. After Mr. Liu&#39;s parents passed away, he often visited his uncle in California, chatted with him, and discussed the foundation to commemorate Wu Chen Shiyun (Editor&#39;s note: Wu Dingchang&#39;s wife). When his uncle passed away, he was in Beijing and did not have time to attend the funeral. Later, he went to California to help his cousin, who did not understand Chinese, organize a house full of Chinese books and materials. Mr. Liu said that his uncle kept a low profile throughout his life, moved and spoke softly, was good at listening and asking questions, and was very caring about his younger generations. &quot;Perhaps my uncle studied in England when he was young and was influenced by the British&#39;s cold humor. He would often make people laugh unexpectedly during conversations. I remember that in Paris that year, we were sitting in an outdoor cafe. He said that Paris was very interesting. Half of the Parisians were sitting there. Watching the other half of Paris in a cafe. If I could describe my impression of my uncle in one sentence: he is a gentleman with a sense of humor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Shi and Wu Yuanli&#39;s father, Wu Dingchang, are old acquaintances and spoke highly of him. On February 26, 1931, Cao Heheng invited Ke Shaobin, Zheng Xiaoxu, Jiang Han, Yang Zhongxi and others to have dinner together. He also invited Wu Dingchang and Hu Shi. This was the first time they met. Hu Shi&#39;s diary recorded on that day: &quot;Wu Jun is a capable man. I have wanted to see him for a long time, but I have disagreed many times. Today I met him for the first time.&quot; Wu Dingchang is seven or eight years older than Hu Shi. He is an industrialist and banker and has served as the Bank of China. President, General Manager of Salt Bank, and Deputy Minister of Finance of the Beijing Government. Later, he acquired &quot;Ta Kung Pao&quot; and appointed himself as president. He invited Hu Zhengzhi as general manager and Zhang Jiluan as editor-in-chief, giving &quot;Ta Kung Pao&quot; a new life and becoming one of the most influential newspapers in the country. Therefore, Hu Shi was left with a &quot;competent&quot; impression. In November of that year, the Nanjing National Government established a Finance Committee, with Hu Shi and Wu Dingchang as members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gvp2av25spnjzLea2PNQn5ygS6DkCvKHe2kwJAk4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;479&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gvp2av25spnjzLea2PNQn5ygS6DkCvKHe2kwJAk4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Tingwei and Wu Yuanjun wedding photos. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Liu Rongqian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 11, 1933, on the eve of Hu Shi’s visit to the United States, he passed through Tianjin. Wu Dingchang went to visit specifically. They &quot;talked for more than two o&#39;clock&quot;, and Wu Dingchang &quot;advocated &#39;returning power to the people&#39; the most vigorously, and also advocated the temporary suspension of many construction projects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 31, 1934, Hu Shi and Wu Dingchang met at Wang Jingwei&#39;s official residence in Nanjing. Also present were Zhang Jiluan, Ren Hongjun, Chen Hengzhe, Tang Youren, Zeng Zhongming, etc. They discussed foreign and domestic issues. . The meaning is still not finished. After leaving, Hu Shi and Wu Dingchang talked late at night when they returned to their apartment. At that time, Sino-Japanese relations were becoming increasingly tense, and there were many different voices regarding foreign and domestic policies. Hu Shi and Wu Dingchang obviously had different opinions, but this did not affect Hu Shi&#39;s good impression of Wu Dingchang. In July of that year, Hu Shi wrote &quot;From Private School to Yenching University&quot;. When talking about private donations to build schools, he cited the example of Wu Dingchang: &quot;Those with more money can renovate a university. ... Those with less money can also subsidize a specific school.&quot; A certain part, such as Mr. Wu Dingchang’s donation to the Department of Economics of Nankai University for student aid. In this way, a small amount can add up to a large amount, making the already successful school become even more successful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Shi, Wu Yuanli and Liu Tingwei The &quot;Huaxi Xianbi&quot; mentioned was written by Wu Dingchang when he was the chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Government. It was published by Guizhou Daily in October 1940. It has &quot;when taking office&quot;, &quot;after taking office&quot;, &quot;province&quot; and &quot;county&quot;. There are seven chapters in &quot;Central Administration and Local Governments&quot;, &quot;Miscellaneous Thoughts&quot; and &quot;Postscript&quot;. Three years later, Hu Zhengzhi persuaded Wu Dingchang to continue writing &quot;Huaxi Xianbi&quot;, so there were nine chapters in the &quot;Continuation&quot;, namely &quot;Provincial Government&quot;, &quot;Counties and Towns&quot;, &quot;New County System&quot;, &quot;Counties and Townships&quot;, &quot;New Life&quot;, &quot;Public Security and Gangs&quot;, &quot;Economy and Control&quot;, &quot;Finance and Accounting&quot; and &quot;Miscellaneous Feelings&quot; were published by Guizhou Enterprise Co., Ltd. Printing Office in October 1943. Wu Dingchang ran a newspaper, and it is said that his poetry and prose were very good. Cao Juren said: &quot;I read the sequel to his &quot;Huaxi Xianbi&quot; and liked his simplicity and closeness. His female son-in-law collected his poems and distributed them to the best. After reading them, I felt that there were no empty scholars in his name. After leaving Guizhou, Wu Dingchang served as the civil servant of the National Government, Secretary-General of the Central Design Bureau of the Kuomintang, and Secretary-General of the Presidential Office. He once suggested to Chiang Kai-shek that he invite Mao Zedong to Chongqing for negotiations. In January 1949, retired Wu Dingchang came to live in Hong Kong at the urging of his son. On August 22, 1950, Wu Dingchang died of cancer in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WrMFUIDTySoVmp3a1GM2tmUVYsCQiSp4eHl8e3wK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;610&quot; height= &quot;927&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WrMFUIDTySoVmp3a1GM2tmUVYsCQiSp4eHl8e3wK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brothers Liu Tingfang (left) and Liu Tingwei (right). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Liu Rongqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Tingwei, who went to visit Hu Shi with Wu Yuanli, was not introduced in Hu Shi&#39;s diary. Liu Tingwei is the son-in-law of Wu Dingchang and the father of Mr. Liu Rongqian. He was born in 1903 and was a native of Wenzhou, Zhejiang. After graduating from Yanjing University, he studied at Cornell University in the United States and received a doctorate in entomology. After completing his studies, he returned to China and served successively as professor in the Department of Biology of Hujiang University, technical director of the Nanjing Central Agricultural Experimental Institute, technical director of the Guizhou Work Station of the Central Agricultural Experimental Institute, and technical director of the Agricultural Group of the Agricultural Society. After the Agricultural Restoration Association moved to Taiwan in 1949, Liu Tingwei served as the leader of the first group and later the plant production group until his retirement in 1965. Liu Tingwei is also a poet. His poems are highly praised by Tao Xingzhi, Xu Zhimo and Shen Congwen. He has published poetry collections &quot;Mountain Flowers&quot; and &quot;My Cup&quot;. His wife, Wu Yuanjun, was the eldest daughter of Wu Dingchang. She was born in 1912. She studied at Yenching University and was a classmate of Zhou Yiliang. She was quite talented and assisted Rong Geng in editing the &quot;Continuation of Bronze Inscriptions&quot; when they were in school. The daughter Cao Juren mentioned was Wu Yuanjun who printed a collection of poems for Wu Dingchang. Liu Tingwei and Wu Yuanjun got married in July 1933 and stayed together for the rest of their lives. In their later years, they lived with their children in Canada and the United States. In January 1994, Liu Tingwei passed away in Canada. In December 2001, Wu Yuanjun passed away in the United States. Both lived into their nineties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Shi has no direct interaction with Liu Tingwei, but he is very familiar with his eldest brother Liu Tingfang. When Liu Tingfang was a teenager, he was highly appreciated by Su Huilian, Cai Bomin, Stuart Leighton and others. Stuart recommended him to study at St. John&#39;s University in Shanghai, and later arranged for him to study in the United States. Liu Tingfang received a bachelor&#39;s degree and a master&#39;s degree from Columbia University in the United States, a bachelor&#39;s degree in divinity from Yale Divinity School, and a doctorate in educational psychology from Columbia University. After returning to China, he worked at Yenching University with Leighton Stuart and was an important assistant to Leighton Stuart in starting the cause of Yenching University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/kzPxt48fnGol2uq1muiA1nHoLJfOKkF0tqevZMwr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height= &quot;815&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/kzPxt48fnGol2uq1muiA1nHoLJfOKkF0tqevZMwr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Yuanli in his later years. In the 1940s, Wu Yuanli advocated giving rights to the poor and allowing them to develop freely. Another famous economist, Fang Xianting, advocated relying on elite planning to develop the economy and letting the elites make decisions for the poor. The debate between the two ended with Fang Xianting gaining the upper hand. Wu Yuanli retreated to the United States, and his name was gradually forgotten. It was not until 2007 that American historian of economic thought Paul Trescott rediscovered Wu Yuanli and believed that the Wu Fang debate was the earliest debate in the history of development economics. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest record about Liu Tingfang in Hu Shi&#39;s diary was on April 28, 1921: &quot;Went to Liu Tingfang&#39;s house for dinner. Liu Jun is in charge of religious studies, and his family has many books on religious history.&quot; On May 18 of the same year: &quot;In the morning, Mr. Stuart, Pastor Liu Tingfang and Mr. Huo Jinde came to talk.&quot; On June 30 of the same year, Peking University, the Men&#39;s and Women&#39;s Normal Schools, the Shangzhi Society, the New Society, etc. held a farewell party for the Dewey family at Jinyuxuan in Central Park. Hu Shi, Liu Tingfang, and Wu Zhuosheng were all there. Hu Shi, representing Peking University, translated it into Chinese and spoke it again. Wu Zhuosheng delivered a speech on behalf of the Women&#39;s Normal University, which was translated into Chinese by Liu Tingfang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1921, Yenching University wanted to improve the Department of Chinese Language and Culture. Stuart Leighton and Liu Tingfang invited Hu Shi to take charge of the work, but Hu Shi did not agree and recommended Zhou Zuoren instead. He thought it was a pity that Zhou Zuoren could not use his talents at Peking University, so he asked him to &quot;go out and do his own thing.&quot; Unfortunately, Zhou became ill, so the matter was put on hold for a year. The next year, Yanjing brought up the matter again, so on March 4, 1922, Hu Shi invited Stuart Leighton, Liu Tingfang, and Zhou Zuoren to introduce them and let them talk face to face. Hu Shi recorded in his diary: &quot;They were very satisfied with their discussion.&quot; Zhou Zuoren taught at Yan University for more than ten years until he was hired as a research professor by Peking University and could not take courses at other schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 11, 1937, Hu Shi &quot;went to eat at Liu Tingfang of Yan University.&quot; Since then, Liu Tingfang has not appeared in Hu Shi&#39;s diary. Liu Tingfang was later elected as a legislator, but due to poor health, he went to the United States for medical treatment in 1942. He died in a Presbyterian Hospital in New Mexico in 1947 at the age of fifty-six. I wonder if Hu Shi thought of his brother Liu Tingfang when he met Liu Tingwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Liu Rongqian currently lives in Montreal, Quebec, Canada, and has been inviting me to visit him. &quot;Don&#39;t forget that at my age, I&#39;m already counting down the days. Please make the trip as soon as possible.&quot; But I thought, he should go home as soon as possible while he can still move around. Liu Rongqian has lived overseas for a long time and has never been to his hometown of Wenzhou. In May 2015, he held the &quot;Unintentional Realm&quot; photography art exhibition in Hangzhou. I went to observe and learn from it, and took a quick look. Fortunately, there is WeChat, so we can communicate online at any time after we are separated. That was the closest Mr. Liu Rongqian was to his hometown. A few months ago, Professor Shen Weiwei of Nanjing University came to Wenzhou University to give a lecture and asked me to accompany him to look for Liu Tingfang’s old traces. That area is undergoing renovation of a historical district, and the small bungalow Liu Tingfang built for his mother after returning to China is no longer accessible. Professor Shen saw a corner of Liu&#39;s former residence through the bathroom window of an office building. Therefore, please Mr. Liu Rongqian &quot;make the trip as soon as possible&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贵州省委政法委原副书记刘文新被“双开”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256866]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision: Recently, with the approval of the Guizhou Provincial Party Committee, the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision Liu Wenxin, former deputy secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Provincial Party Committee, has been investigated for serious violations of discipline and law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Liu Wenxin lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his duties and missions, alienated himself from the party and the people, acted on his own initiative, acted arbitrarily and illegally, engaged in &quot;seven things&quot;, and became a destroyer of the political ecology and economic order. ; Being disloyal and dishonest to the Party, being two-faced, resisting organizational censorship, engaging in feudal superstitious activities, privately possessing and reading books and periodicals with serious political issues; Ignoring the spirit of the eight central regulations, accepting violations that may affect the fair execution of official duties Arrange banquets, travel and activities, violate the work and life security system, seek special treatment, advocate hedonism, fly first class in violation of regulations; have no organizational principles, fail to truthfully explain problems when organizing conversations, fail to truthfully report major personal matters, violate regulations Transferring work for others; losing integrity, accepting gifts and money in violation of regulations, having bad morals, living an extremely corrupt life, engaging in power, sex, and money transactions, having long-term improper sexual relations with others, whoring, gambling; playing with things, being obsessed with knives; violating regulations Allocating fees to enterprises, intervening in violation of regulations and intervening in judicial activities. Liu Wenxin has no bottom line in discipline and law, engages in power-for-money transactions, uses public power as a tool for personal gain, uses his position to benefit others in terms of project contracting, financing loans, etc., and illegally accepts huge amounts of property; in order to seek illegitimate benefits, Give property to state workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Wenxin seriously violated the Party’s political discipline, the spirit of the Eight-Point Provisions of the Central Committee, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, mass discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and being suspected of bribery and bribery crimes. After the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, they did not restrain themselves, did not stop, and did not know how to stop. This is of serious nature and has a bad impact and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and submitted to the Provincial Party Committee for approval, it was decided to expel Liu Wenxin from the party; by The Provincial Supervisory Committee dismissed him from public office; confiscated his illegal gains that violated disciplines; and transferred his suspected criminal issues to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved was also transferred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[宫鲁鸣：外教不是中国篮球的救命稻草]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256832]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/XovBvRKJkp0MMKw0YWuHZTlI7kYhKTy4v8e5uMQk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/XovBvRKJkp0MMKw0YWuHZTlI 7kYhKTy4v8e5uMQk. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250578&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;June 20, 2023, Taipan Village, Taijiang County, Guizhou, Chinese Basketball Association Vice Chairman Gong Luming watched the &quot;Village BA&quot; game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup fell on the evening of September 10 At the end of the day, the German team, which entered the final for the first time, continued to create miracles, defeating the Serbian team 83-77, and was finally crowned. Although the Serbian team failed to win the final victory in the decisive battle, in this World Cup they made it all the way to the final in the absence of several top stars, which once again proved the amazing strength of this veteran European team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some are happy and some are sad. The Chinese men’s basketball team ranked only 29th among the 32 participating teams. The coach is Alexander Djordje, the famous coach who holds the Lifetime Achievement Award of the Serbian Basketball Coaches Association. Vicky, for him and the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team, the trip to the Philippines World Cup was full of frustration and depression. The Chinese men&#39;s basketball team lost to Serbia 63-105 in the first game of the World Cup. This day happened to be Lao Qiao&#39;s 56th birthday. Before the game, many members of the Serbian team sent blessings to the legend, but after the game started, the birthday boy could only shake his head. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 16, 2022, the Chinese Basketball Association made adjustments to the head coach of the Chinese Men’s Basketball National Team and announced the selection of Djordjevic as the head coach of the Chinese Men’s Basketball National Team. His task is to lead the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team in the sixth window of the 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup qualifying period and the 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup, striving to lead the team to qualify for the 2024 Paris Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese men’s basketball team spent a lot of money to hire a world-class coach to lead the army, and naturalized NBA star Kyle Lee joined the team. The largest investment in the history of the Chinese men’s basketball team resulted in one win and four losses in this World Cup, setting the worst record in history. At the same time, he lost his Olympic ticket again and fell into the abyss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese men’s basketball team performed poorly in the last Olympic cycle and failed to qualify for the Tokyo Olympics. This time it failed to qualify for the Paris Olympics, which means that a generation of players cannot participate in the highest level during their golden period of competition. competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, when participating in the Olympic Games, the flag bearer of the Chinese delegation would be a tall and handsome Chinese men&#39;s basketball star. Now, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team, which has missed two consecutive Olympics, has even lost a standard-bearer who can guide the direction - veteran Yi Jianlian, who was unable to go with the team, announced his retirement before the last game of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball group stage. Fans lamented that since before the Olympics, Without being able to compete for eight to eight years, the glory of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team has completely faded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How should the Chinese men’s basketball team move forward? &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; conducted an exclusive interview with Gong Luming, the famous Chinese basketball coach. At the 1996 Atlanta Olympics, at the age of 39, he directed the Chinese team to reach the top eight in the Olympics for the first time. This is the best record that has not been broken so far. This group of players is also known as the &quot;96 Golden Generation&quot;. When the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team hit a trough in 2014, he was asked to come out. A year later, he once again brought the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team back to the top in Asia. This legendary guard, who is only 1.72 meters tall, is known as the &quot;fire-fighting master&quot; of Chinese basketball. In 1999, he became the head coach at the lowest point when the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team lost the qualification to compete in the Sydney Olympics. Through major changes and all-round team building, he created a young and brave golden generation of women&#39;s basketball, winning the 2001 Asian Women&#39;s Basketball Championship and the 2001 Women&#39;s Basketball Asian Championship. He won two titles at the 2002 Asian Games and finished sixth at the 2002 World Championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is the self-report of coach Gong Luming:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; I personally strongly agree with the strengthening of international exchanges in Chinese basketball. It is a good thing for the Chinese Basketball Association to hire foreign coaches, especially famous foreign coaches. They can bring us a lot of good experience in terms of confrontation, concepts, and methods. . However, some practical factors must be taken into consideration on how to properly coordinate the coaching team and how to give full play to the role of foreign teachers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The specialty of foreign coaches is high professionalism, concentration and seriousness, and their coaching level is also certain He was selected by the Chinese Basketball Association only after he has reached a certain height. There is no doubt about this. Most of them grew up in a highly professional basketball environment and believe that everyone in the team, including themselves, has sufficient professionalism. After assembling a national team, foreign teachers rarely think that the construction and management of the team and the improvement of athletes&#39; skills are also one of the priorities of the head coach. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;They are more accustomed to focusing on the court, such as the tactical system, lineup configuration, and opponents. Research, etc., and many other things, he will think that it is your athlete&#39;s own business, or that a mature professional athlete should have solved the problem long ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When foreign teachers serve as head coaches, although they will be equipped with excellent Chinese coaches as assistants, the basic Foreign head coaches rarely have in-depth and active communication with Chinese coaches. To be honest, they may not necessarily like our Chinese coaches, so we will see that the foreign head coaches are very dedicated and very courageous to carry out their work, but there are very few opportunities for Chinese and foreign coaches to formally exchange opinions or communicate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From our past experience, if a foreign teacher serves as an assistant coach, he will actively communicate with the head coach To communicate, he will actively communicate with the Chinese coaching staff the various information he has seen and collected, as well as how to deal with it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Over the years, whether it is the national team or local clubs, our basketball world has formed such a The coaching environment: Unless the Chinese coach is very proactive and actively cooperates with the foreign teacher and asks the foreign teacher for advice, he may talk more to the Chinese coach. If you don&#39;t do this and you just follow the foreign teacher, he will not actually give you any help. But if the Chinese side is the head coach, the foreign teacher will actively communicate with you about his experience, knowledge or methods. This is a very realistic thing. Such a coaching culture has been formed over the years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Another point is that even if there are no foreign teachers, the coaching staff is all local coaches. There is also an unwritten rule. I am used to following the arrangements of the head coach. To put it simply, if you don’t arrange things, I won’t do it. If the head coach has spoken and arranged for me, I will do it. If the head coach does not ask for it, then the assistant coach will not express his opinion easily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These are our &quot;basketball culture&quot;. When hiring foreign teachers, you must consider these practical factors. In fact, it is very difficult. There has been a consensus within the circle for a long time that foreign teachers can be used and the ball can be lost, but the initiative must be in our own hands. Even if we lose, we must let our own coaches know how to lose. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/O4yeTzwTaxr80Zv1c1vc6sHZGmgOxdACXvM7x0pw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/O4yeTzwTaxr80Zv1c1vc6sHZGmgOxdACXvM7x0pw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250580&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2015, in Changsha, Hunan, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team won the 2015 Asian Men&#39;s Basketball Championship. Gong Luming held the trophy high to celebrate&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;2&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;The most taboo thing about hiring foreign teachers is to treat foreign teachers as a life-saving straw and expect them to turn stones into gold and produce results in a short period of time. Can foreign teachers really save Chinese basketball? not necessarily! To this day, the best record in the history of China&#39;s men&#39;s and women&#39;s basketball teams is still led by our own local coaches. Group projects have their own particularity and complexity. It is not easy to achieve a breakthrough through a foreign teacher. This is something we must think about when building our team. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you invite foreign teachers in, you can&#39;t lose all your own things. Your own things have been accumulated over several generations and are suitable for your own personnel characteristics and specific environment. These experiences have been tested by specific practices. You can&#39;t just follow others and succeed. Making up for our shortcomings and developing our own strengths is fundamental. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some words may sound a bit outdated, but I still have to say that I always insist on paying attention to team building Ideological work. The so-called ideological work is not an empty long speech. It can be combined with many things in daily work requirements and business learning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Foreign teachers don’t care about team building, and they don’t know how to do this kind of ideological work. Before the competition, they Carrying a jersey to that station and saying that you must be worthy of the national flag on it is considered the ideological work he has done for the players. A person&#39;s mind is not that simple. Why do you play basketball? What basic quality requirements does this profession require of you? Going a step further, what is your specific understanding of the era you live in? What requirements does this specific background of the times place on yourself and the sports industry? You can&#39;t take the ball with nothing in mind. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not just the national team that lacks quality ideological work, our current professional league, there are people who can do it Is ideological education work? What social role should a professional basketball player play in today&#39;s environment? How many people can answer? We have engaged in professionalization, and players&#39; salaries have gone up, but their ideological understanding has not kept up. Athletes need guidance. Hearing people criticize the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team for &quot;male football&quot; brings disgrace to our work in basketball and football. As the old saying goes, &quot;A teacher once is a father forever&quot; and &quot;It is the fault of a son not to teach his father.&quot; From the club to the national team, have our coaches and team leaders fulfilled their responsibilities in influencing and educating young people? If a player has a problem, it must be related to management and education. No one educates him in the national team, and no one educates him when he returns home. He wanders around every day, even begging him and coaxing him, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/VGjynPqZDGsRtIwxJasuc8S7aHF3iszemchidAPX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/VGjynPqZDGsRtIwxJasuc8S7aHF3iszemchidAPX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250579&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 2, 2023, Manila, Philippines, in the 17-32nd group stage of the 2023 Men&#39;s Basketball World Cup, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team lost to the Philippine men&#39;s basketball team 75-96. Head coach Djordjevic exited after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our own coaches must actively grow. We cannot just wait for high-level foreign coaches to be our assistants. This is unrealistic and impossible to win the true respect of our peers and team members. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Don&#39;t underestimate a team, its content is not just technical things. The head coach himself needs a kind of maturity, a subtle influence, and leading by example. What kind of atmosphere your words and deeds create is very important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The coach is actually an ascetic. If you want to be a good coach, you have to focus and give up many hobbies. You usually make a group of friends, train here, and arrange what to do in the evening there, so where can you go? When you are a player, you just have to take care of yourself. When you are the coach, you have to consider the affairs of the whole team. The affairs of the whole team are not one or two things. Team formation, communication between top and bottom, communication with parents, ideological issues, technical issues, the construction of the offensive and defensive system of the entire team, and opponent research, you are too busy working 24 hours a day, do you still have time to do other things? Failure to focus simply cannot solve these problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A person must respect his or her job, this is what you rely on for survival or for your food. . When I was coaching the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team, I always ate out of a porcelain bowl, just to remind myself that you have to take good care of your own job, don&#39;t fight, otherwise you won&#39;t have anything to eat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether you are a star athlete or a coach, you should abide by your duties and not sacrifice to show your personality. The core values ​​of sports are sunshine, health and positivity. In the past, before the national team completed training or competition tasks and before the players returned to the club, we had to set requirements for them. After returning, you must reflect the level and value of the national team members, lead by example, and take the lead in all aspects. , instead of going back to being a big name. Everyone in the league still has specific technical problems that need to be solved, and we will check them when we come back. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Chen, president of Peking Union Medical College and academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering, said in his 2023 opening speech, &quot;It is necessary to Take the world as your own responsibility, have real skills, and embody the nobility of life, the nobility of industry, and the nobility of health care in simple labor.&quot; Every industry must have its own professional beliefs, and the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team relies on the accumulation of generations of people If you gain a little bit of family wealth, the whole industry needs to cherish it and make practical contributions. If the family wealth is lost, the whole industry will suffer losses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[把美术课还给孩子？一所广东乡村学校的实验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256860]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;This is not a &#39;good&#39; school!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Zhongshan taxi driver He looked determined and made a judgment. On the way, he talked about Guinan School, which is located at the foot of Wugui Mountain in Zhongshan City. The implication is that this private primary and secondary school has an average admission rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have heard too many of the same stories. Designer and school art group teacher Zhang Yaoren could only smile helplessly. What is good and what is bad? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Achievements&quot; are always the only yardstick for most people. Zhang Yaoren didn’t think so. He is thin, in his fifties, and has been at Guinan School for more than five years. Old P, as people like to call him, is from Henan. He has been in Guangdong for more than thirty years. He settled in nearby Qixi Village a few years ago. He and Shi Lei, the principal of Guinan School, hit it off on this topic: &quot;Do children in rural areas need... Need aesthetic education?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vMCE1SIISojaA1pyEdXttSCFwmE6MrnjJsd4NQjL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vMCE1SIISojaA1pyEdXttSCFwmE6MrnjJsd4NQjL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Works by Guinan School students. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Independent artist and curator Guan Yong is in his forties, has a tall figure and likes to wear Straw sandals. He has been engaged in art education since he was nineteen years old, working in kindergartens, primary schools, and art galleries in Zhuhai, Guangzhou, Macau and other places. Later, he also participated in this miniature rural aesthetic education experiment as an art director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, Guinan School had more than 40 classes, more than 1,700 students, and 3 art teachers, but there was no art classroom. In July 2018, Guinan School converted six classrooms on the first floor into art classrooms. Now, the school has eight full-time art teachers, four studios and a reading room. The teaching content involves traditional Chinese painting, printmaking, pottery, paper-cutting, etc. Guinan&#39;s campus also has a miniature art gallery that displays students&#39; works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visiting this place, Southern Weekend reporters were surprised by the art works hidden on campus. These works are displayed all over the campus. A large number of clay sculptures are dried on the ground, prints are posted on the walls, installation art is hung in the corridors, and handmade works are posted under the eaves. These works are quite childish, and the largest number are clay sculptures, including cups, plates, bottles, jars, and various clay figures with strange shapes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Up3LZQx8CNfkgURkqUALPuYpCgqb4Tv173RGEIYA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Up3LZQx8CNfkgURkqUALPuYpCgqb4Tv173RGEIYA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Student art works in the corridor of the teaching building of Guinan School. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comprehensive studio, weaving, sewing, embroidery and other handicrafts are completed here; folk crafts The studio is for students; the folk art room is filled with students&#39; prints, paper-cuts, etc.; in the comprehensive painting studio, you can see Chinese paintings, watercolors, oil paintings and other works by students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/K4RhNWazPNxMQUDqRo9O4X3j0zIZBlSXxoWguIr8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/K4RhNWazPNxMQUDqRo9O4X3j0zIZBlSXxoWguIr8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250963&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Student prints from Guinan School. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you travel through the countryside, you can also see the works of students. &quot;Children&#39;s things are natural things.&quot; Zhang Yaoren pointed to the student works along the country road and said, &quot;(In the past) many paintings on the walls were relatively stiff.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, Guan Yong and others started a rural teacher program to provide teaching support to front-line teachers from rural areas and plan to complete the training of one thousand teachers within two years. Zhang Yaoren said: &quot;We do the Thousand Talents Plan precisely because we believe that (aesthetic education) is the most important thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;If you have never done carpentry, you will do carpentry; if you have never played in mud, you will play in mud.&quot;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;Local children mostly choose to go to public schools in towns. The students recruited by Guinan School are basically the children of migrant workers. Most of these students come from Sichuan, Hunan, Anhui and other places. Their parents left their hometown and came to the Pearl River Delta. While the students are in class, their parents sell things at nearby markets, work in factories, and do odd jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaoren recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that students would leave every semester. The fathers left the worksite, and the children flew away like birds. Academic performance has nothing to do with art. Zhang Yaoren said that they did not disclose the idea of ​​​​art courses to the parents of the students. He understands the parents’ thinking. Art is useless. It’s better to do more questions: “The parents must have said that my son only scored 85 points in math. Can you not let him attend the 90 minutes of art class? He might get 90 points in the exam. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Yong has a point of view. Regarding the curriculum, the art textbooks compiled by the state are always the basis, accounting for 70% of the curriculum. The remaining 30% is carried out by the teaching team for outreach and expansion. The content of the 18 textbooks for grades one to nine was broken up and reconnected with the four studios. As the grades increase, the content offered by each studio becomes deeper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/yPaKd9OGAQgZTSxdq2wI90zCjjZziTskqh66IZUd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/yPaKd9OGAQgZTSxdq2wI90zCjjZziTskqh66IZUd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gouache painting by Guinan School students. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All the teaching materials were smashed and placed in the studio... The textbooks are relatively thin ,&quot; Zhang Yaoren gave an example, &quot;One class (textbook) says that the mud will be gone, but we asked the first-grade children to work here for four consecutive weeks making mud, and (the students) wanted to make bowls after finishing the cups. I also want to make a vessel with a handle, so that the child will have an understanding of the properties of clay, the complexity of materials, and the complexity of creation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Improving teachers&#39; aesthetic and teaching abilities is the key . Five years ago, there were only two art teachers in Guinan School, and students would take out A4 paper to sketch in class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Rural Art Teachers) Their professionalism is not deep. How come teachers who graduated from the National Academy of Arts and Central America come to our place? When the professional level of the teachers is not that high, how can Can you improve their level?&quot; Zhang Yaoren told the Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Teach you how to work. If you have never done carpentry before, do carpentry, and if you have never played with mud, just play with mud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Yong et al. People prefer to refer to entering the classroom as entering the studio. They believe that art is the vocabulary of the adult world, while children&#39;s basic art education is &quot;enlightenment of students&#39; creativity and self-expression&quot; and is more like &quot;an artistic job&quot;. He rarely talks about art theory. When he encounters a problem, Guan Yong always says &quot;get moving&quot;. What should I do if I don’t have an art foundation? Guan Yong said, then work! As you dry it, you will feel it on your hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/1EySt6Joa4v1Qfj3z416218QnPl4KnxPxxZ1Z1UV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/1EySt6Joa4v1Qfj3z416218QnPl4KnxPxxZ1Z1UV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The art studio of Guinan School. Every time students finish class, they will clean up the studio as required. Zhang Yaoren believes that this is also part of aesthetic education. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guinan School does not add additional time for art classes, and of course does not allow preemption of art classes. time, students are required to complete a ninety-minute class once a week. Forty minutes of art class is simply not enough to keep children &quot;enjoyed.&quot; There is always an appreciation session at the beginning of the course. The teacher brings the pictures related to the curriculum to the children to “look at”. In nine years, students can look at tens of thousands of pictures, and these pictures become one of the sources of their aesthetic appreciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the second grade course &quot;Paper Cutting - Transformation&quot;, students need to learn origami, binding, cutting and collage heads, and watch the works of Huang Yongyu, Komatsu Miu, Han Meilin and others; fifth grade The ninety-minute class in the first semester is titled &quot;Color Blow Molding - Vase Flowers&quot;. The teaching content includes engraving outlines and patterns. The materials viewed include the works of Davids, Van Gogh, Matisse, etc.; In the ninth-grade course &quot;Comprehensive Printmaking - Mask&quot;, students have to learn how to engrave lightness and grayscale, and watch the works of Gu Kaizhi, Wu Daozi, and Zhang Xuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various equipment in the studio, including expensive printmaking machines, as well as various painting tools, glue guns, saws, etc. According to statistics, there are more than thirty kinds of paper. These materials come from Guinan School Expenditures. Zhang Yaoren said that the school has made great efforts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Q4vVA4zYwX0QyIXfpOnDVbYEIDsoi3KyR1mlocmq.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Q4vVA4zYwX0QyIXfpOnDVbYEIDsoi3KyR1mlocmq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250956&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the art studio of Guinan School, the drawers are filled with papers of various materials. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, not every school has enough funding for materials. Some materials also come from the land. The art teacher took the students to collect leaves, soil, discarded paper, old clothes, plastic bottles, etc. Every semester, children in Guinan consume tons of soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The art teacher became the leader of the main subject&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaoren once visited some rural schools in western Guangdong, and the proportion of left-behind children in these schools accounted for more than 60%. In a central primary school in a certain town, there are only 180 students. In the context of &quot;dismantling sites and merging schools&quot;, data from NetEase Digital shows that in the forty years from 1976 to 2016, 916,000 primary schools disappeared in China, and most of them were rural primary schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many art teachers who participated in the training confirmed this statement to Southern Weekend reporters. A rural teacher in Hengyang, Hunan told a Southern Weekend reporter with sadness that her rural primary school will be merged next semester. She came in a hurry from other places with great expectations in her heart, wanting to bring something new to the children in the village. After working for four years, she watched the number of students drop from more than one hundred to more than thirty. She is a little envious of physical education classes. Campus football education is a Hengyang specialty. Almost every primary school is equipped with a football field and guaranteed physical education class hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Xiaohong, the head of the Zhejiang Zhipu Charity Foundation, known as &quot;Huabu&quot;, has been paying attention to the life growth of rural children and the mental health of children in distress for many years. She told Southern Weekend reporters that six years ago, In a county in a mountainous area, there is only one full-time art teacher in all 20 rural primary schools in the countryside. There has been some improvement over the years, but there are still problems that need to be solved urgently. For example, there are 13 establishments in schools with less than 200 students. “Obviously, this (class arrangement) cannot be arranged no matter how you arrange it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In rural schools, &quot;one teacher uses many people to use it.&quot; &quot;I am now the class teacher in charge of the first grade, responsible for reading classes, labor and skill classes, and also responsible for the quality promotion of our school,&quot; a teacher told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visiting rural schools, Zhang Yaoren found that some teachers who graduated from normal art schools had been teaching their main subjects for more than ten years and no longer taught art, while the original teachers of Chinese, mathematics and other subjects taught part-time instead. Art, music and other courses. Some former art teachers have even become subject leaders of their main subjects, and they “always have some regrets in their hearts” when talking about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Comprehensively Strengthening and Improving School Aesthetic Education in the New Era.&quot; The opinions proposed that aesthetic education should be included in the entire process of talent training in schools of all levels and types, and should run through all stages of school education. A post-80s teacher from a public primary school in western Hunan is one of the second batch of local art students. I have been teaching for thirteen years and have taught foreign language and math all over the place. In the past two years, the school responded to the aesthetic education policy, and she was able to return to her profession and become a full-time art teacher, making up for her regret at the time: &quot;It&#39;s not that art has no threshold, it&#39;s because they think it doesn&#39;t matter if they don&#39;t teach well and there will be no consequences.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Art education has always been considered a &quot;minor subject&quot;. In many cases, the class hours of minor subjects are often &quot;occupied&quot; by the main subjects. Especially in primary schools with limited educational resources, it is more common for the main subject teachers to concurrently serve as the teachers of the minor subjects. The encroachment of the minor subject class hours is &quot;natural&quot;. &quot;Many documents on aesthetic education have been issued at the national level, and it cannot be said that they are not taken seriously. Art teachers like to take art classes, and students also fall in love with art classes, but in many cases they fail to take art classes.&quot; Luo Xiaohong felt heartbroken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another mystery in scheduling classes. According to the normal schedule, for example, a Chinese teacher has twelve classes and uses the original Chinese class hours; but in actual operation, a Chinese teacher is given six Chinese classes. The remaining six periods were replaced by art, physical education and other courses, and naturally all &quot;minor subjects&quot; were taken into Chinese language classes. According to Luo Xiaohong&#39;s observations in two counties in Zhejiang, the situation of &quot;two class schedules&quot; has been intensifying in the past two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A private primary school art teacher comes from a county in Dali, Yunnan, and teaches a village primary school with 250 students. She told Southern Weekend reporters that when she came to Guinan School, she seemed to find a companion all of a sudden. For example, both choose two classes to form one big class. Her school does not take up art time, but in the public elementary school next door, the situation is completely different. &quot;Now there are exams and there are not enough class hours. The teacher has no choice but to do this in order to achieve results.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“What I painted twenty years ago, you are still painting”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters saw at the teaching site that the art teachers who came for training experienced the Guinan experience in the studio The content of aesthetic education in the classroom: understanding materials-obtaining materials-production-teacher comments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The level of rural teachers obviously varies. The first practical class involved hand-made books, and most of the teachers successfully completed the work. In the second period of the ink painting class, the quality of the teacher&#39;s ink paintings showed a certain difference. While creating, some teachers told Southern Weekend reporters that, in fact, they had not really touched ink for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Guan Yong&#39;s request, an art teacher from Ankang, Shaanxi Province used three different kinds of paper to experience ink. He couldn&#39;t help but think of the students in class. Each student was given a brush, poured a little bit of ink, and asked them to apply it on the cardboard box and A4 paper. This was his best effort to let the students experience ink. If it is a handicraft class, paper cutting may be the simplest and most convenient. Many teachers told Southern Weekend reporters that the current main teaching format is drawing classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reality of rural resource constraints still exists. An art teacher in Huaihua, Hunan Province said that the school’s resources are scarce, and some art class materials even need to be purchased out of own pocket, costing almost 20,000 yuan. “It’s really impossible to do it. The classroom is empty, there is nothing, and the drawing board No, how to teach?&quot; Zhang Yaoren said that in the schools he contacted, students need to bring their own materials. If families cannot provide them, it will be difficult for the courses to continue. &quot;The pain of materials is a scar that has nowhere to hide in art courses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Hj47ESMSaP91n0rp7AvckUqLyRfBjsQmFyoeVrM1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/Hj47ESMSaP91n0rp7AvckUqLyRfBjsQmFyoeVrM1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250960&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A fire hydrant at Guinan School decorated with student works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We cannot ensure that every student gets an art book to take home.&quot; The above-mentioned teacher from Hengyang told Southern Weekend reporters that where she lives, even art textbooks are not widely available, and they can only use teaching materials in turns.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned rural teacher from Yunnan said that some teaching content involves high-rise buildings Buildings, zebra crossings, etc. Some rural children have never left the village and have only seen them on TV. &quot;Since high-rise buildings are drawn with lines and squares, we will transform the content and consider how to return to the teaching objectives.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aq5KSZquk7pNJuHuzUjJUZccQX7cQXqiurpR8NNH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aq5KSZquk7pNJuHuzUjJUZccQX7cQXqiurpR8NNH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250961&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guinan School’s art studio decorates the walls with students’ paper-cutting work. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In rural schools, having an art classroom may be a luxury. An art teacher from Shaanxi recalled that when he first came to school, the principal said to him that you were the only art teacher in the school, &quot;just take whatever you want.&quot; He felt his shoulders sink, but soon he realized that this might mean staying away from various competitions and honors. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The training program does not reject urban art teachers. Maybe their schools have excellent resources, but they are still confused about teaching methods. A young teacher from Beijing&#39;s Haidian District asked that the textbook content requires innovation, for example, asking students to color in triangles, but teachers are limited in what they can do. Guan Yong asked, why don&#39;t you make the triangle bigger? Why not design a giant triangle and let students color it freely? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This teacher born in the 1990s suddenly understood. He was born in a normal school majoring in art education, and now teaches at a key primary school in Haidian, responsible for courses from fourth to sixth grade. According to him, there are plenty of classes and resources, and there are no problems with rural teachers taking on concurrent jobs. The school’s art teachers have all received very good professional art training. &quot;The pressure on art teachers comes from the normalization of &#39;listening to and evaluating lessons&#39;.&quot; The above-mentioned young teacher said that another problem is that the two classes a week are often separated by several days, and the content of the teaching materials is trivial, and students&#39; learning is not systematic enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reading the work, he commented that &quot;the children here (compared to the children in Beijing) are more active.&quot; Unlike many rural teachers who are surprised when they first see the campus, what he feels is not the art itself, but things other than art. At the scene, a teacher asked whether demonstrations should be conducted for children. This has been one of the teaching models for many years. Guan Yong stopped her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An art teacher in Chengzhong Village, Tianhe District, Guangzhou told Southern Weekend reporters that he is an art major and has always painted according to standards and learned painting formulas. When painting, the most important thing to consider is the formula. rather than expressing emotion. She pointed to the students&#39; works on the wall and said, &quot;The first feeling is that it is very free and unique.&quot; She recalled that her children attended the top ten middle schools in the district and participated in the school&#39;s interest classes. As a result, the content and mode of learning were no different from when she was a child. &quot;What I drew twenty years ago, you are still drawing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Art is a pinch of salt&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Guinan has no internal evaluation activities and rarely participates in peripheral art competitions. Zhang Yaoren explained that the core of art works is self-expression and inner feelings. How can this be scored? And when you look at the works in those competitions, you can often see traces of teacher intervention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, Zhang Yaoren wanted to design a logo. In the folk studio, he saw a monkey-style print. This print later became the logo. In accordance with the collection standards, Guan Yong specially made a beautiful collection certificate with the author&#39;s name and the title of the work on it. During the flag-raising ceremony, the certificate was awarded to the child and a bonus was given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/I1BvI5zZPXHpe53okfU9YdjzV0MHq6UiQ4mf1FVA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/I1BvI5zZPXHpe53okfU9YdjzV0MHq6UiQ4mf1FVA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250962&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guinan School Art Museum, where creative materials and student works are stored. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;As ordinary people, if they can be nourished by beauty, I believe their lives will be better. &quot;So it&#39;s different,&quot; Zhang Yaoren said, &quot;He might keep his house clean and try to take good care of his family; she might pick a handful of wild flowers from the field and put them on the table to turn a plain meal into a new one. It has to be slightly different...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Guinan School held a rural children&#39;s art biennial, a student at the University of Pennsylvania in the United States researched and established a data model to analyze the impact of art education on migrant children. . After analyzing the effects of the first round, a positive conclusion was drawn. Zhang Yaoren is reluctant to utilitarianize and digitize the results to demonstrate the relationship between art and academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He often said that art is a handful of salt, and life needs a little spice. As for the potential and influence of aesthetic education, Zhang Yaoren does not consider these and does not care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Art should always be about education, not works. School teachers have students’ work observations, and teachers observe and record students’ behaviors, habits, emotions, etc. in the classroom. For example, in the &quot;Final Summary Art Classroom Observation Diary&quot;, an observation diary written in the second semester of the 2020-2021 school year, each student is recorded in terms of classroom performance, regular habits, and presentation of works. One student did not perform well. A teacher wrote: &quot;In the future classroom, I will try to find a creative method suitable for this kind of children.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least from the perspective of some outsiders, occupying art classes, increasing learning time, and improving The enrollment rate is the key to changing the fate of migrant children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Lei, the principal of Guinan School, has been thinking about a question since 2017: Who are the people closest to us? &quot;Chefs, waiters, repairmen, cleaners, etc. In real life, our feelings come from them.&quot; Shi Lei said, &quot;Our students have a probability of becoming them. This is a very real problem.&quot; According to statistics, the school only has 35 % of students will enter high school, while the remaining students will enter technical secondary schools, vocational schools, etc. What if they have different feelings about life? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Lei told Southern Weekend reporters that over more than five years, the school has successively invested millions of yuan to renovate classrooms, build art galleries, buy materials, etc., and reduce the school’s enrollment scale from 2000 to 2008. The number of students has dropped to about 1,200, and tuition fees are low, so the school is losing money almost every year. Some of his colleagues came to the school to criticize him and went to see a doctor if he had a mental problem. &quot;(They don&#39;t understand) Will this help me raise my tuition fees or help me recruit more students?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to &quot;copy&quot; Guinan-style art education. Guan Yong contacted some schools in Zhuhai and almost reached the final stage, but gave up due to teacher objections. Guan Yong recalled that the teachers were unwilling to do it because they thought it would increase the workload but bring no additional income. He took the initiative to teach, but the teachers did not agree. &quot;It&#39;s so commonplace,&quot; Guan Yong said, &quot;If you don&#39;t do it, just leave.&quot; Luo Xiaohong told Southern Weekend reporters that they had donated brushes, paints, etc. to some rural schools, but after a few years, the things were still stored there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If you understand our students, you will only do more.&quot; Shi Lei said that the children of migrant workers live a busy and unstable life, and lack opportunities to relieve their emotions under the pressure of life. Would life be better if there was one more outlet in a very compact life? After nine years of reading tens of thousands of works, will the aesthetics of life improve? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Lei grew up in a school for the children of a factory. He had contact with many good art teachers and music teachers since he was a child. After a few years, he forgot all his knowledge other than language and mathematics, but he remembered the art classes and music classes in the past, and his life was also different. Thanks to the abundant gifts at that time. &quot;Others see that we have done a lot of works and painted a lot of paintings, but these are the least important in our hearts,&quot; Shi Lei said, &quot;We are not doing this for this thing, what is really important is the process of aesthetic education. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>