<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[这位董事长女儿，彻底火了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261651]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There is a stock that has hit the daily limit among A-shares today, and the story behind it is very exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This company is called Xinyada. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/0795606a1bb8f5660150c5aaba1744fd.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;823&quot; height= &quot;714&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/0795606a1bb8f5660150c5aaba1744fd.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reasons for the daily limit , I believe many people will not guess that it is because the chairman’s second daughter, a Chinese genius girl Guo Wenjing, developed an artificial intelligence APP in the United States, which is very popular in overseas markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This APP is called Pika. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to technology bloggers, Pika 1.0 has released a major product upgrade, including a new AI model that can use text to generate and edit videos in multiple styles, such as 3D animation, animation, cartoons and movies. style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Now foreign AI videos have entered the stage of the war of the gods, and it (Pika) is violently flooding the screen at home and abroad. Whether it is the ceiling level in terms of production quality, editing capabilities or ease of use .&quot; The blogger sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Full-featured&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Specifically, the new Pika 1.0 includes the following:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. A new generative artificial intelligence model that can create higher quality video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. In addition to generating a variety of new styles of video, the new feature also allows you to use AI to edit videos: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Text to video and image to video: enter a few words on Pika Line text or upload an image, and the platform uses artificial intelligence to create short, high-quality videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Video to video: Convert existing videos into different styles, including different characters and objects, while maintaining the structure of the video. For example, change a video from a live-action video to an animated video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expand: Expand the canvas or aspect ratio of the video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, change a video from TikTok 9:16 format to widescreen 16:9 format, and the AI ​​model will predict content beyond the boundaries of the original video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Change: Use AI to edit video content, such as changing someone&#39;s clothes, adding another character, changing the environment, or adding props. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Extend: Use AI to extend the length of existing video clips. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/0fe88ddf214abe95a127abaaef6e189d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;666&quot; height= &quot;911&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/0fe88ddf214abe95a127abaaef6e189d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Notable Yes, the founder of this APP is Guo Wenjing, the second daughter of the chairman of Xinyada and a doctoral student at Stanford AI Lab. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The birth of Pika is also the story of her dropping out of Stanford and becoming a CEO. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Quiting out of school to start a business&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Last winter, Guo Wenjing and several classmates from Stanford&#39;s computer science doctoral class used the winter vacation to try to use generative artificial intelligence to make movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the much-watched artificial intelligence video editing startup Runway had just reached a valuation of US$500 million. The company was hosting the first &quot;AI Film Festival&quot;, offering a US$10,000 grand prize for the best work. , they are confident that their work will win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Guo Wenjing’s team didn’t even win the award. &quot;We were the most technical team, but we had a really hard time making the movie,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/61fdbab70f2ed69ecc616433767eb482.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/61fdbab70f2ed69ecc616433767eb482.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Artificial Intelligence Breakthrough It gave people hope, but applying it to the video production process itself was very tedious for Guo, who spent a lot of time using tools like Runway and Adobe&#39;s Photoshop with mediocre results, much to her frustration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, the awards were won by professional creatives. &quot;It didn&#39;t look that good,&quot; she said of the film&#39;s disappointment. &quot;I was really frustrated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Guo and doctoral classmate Chenlin Meng dropped out of Stanford in April to start Pika to create an easier-to-use artificial intelligence video generator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Pika&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Promotional video&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Around 500,000 people have tried the software and are currently using it to create millions of new videos every week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This surge of interest sent Silicon Valley investors into a frenzy, and the four-person startup raised $55 million in three rounds of funding in a short period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first two rounds were led by former GitHub CEO Nat Friedman, and the latest round of financing was a $35 million Series A, led by Lightspeed Venture Partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This round of financing values ​​Pika Labs at between $200 million and $300 million, according to direct information from people familiar with the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Genius Girl&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Guo Wenjing was reported. Guo studied at Hangzhou No. 2 Middle School and was the first student in Zhejiang to be admitted to Harvard in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that Guo Wenjing’s mother is a top student who graduated from MIT, and his father is Guo Huaqiang, the actual controller of the listed company Xinyada Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xinyada was founded in 1996 and is headquartered in Binjiang, Hangzhou. It is the first software company in Zhejiang to be listed on the domestic main board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/e4bb5463a8aaaec64fff4b40398e735a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/e4bb5463a8aaaec64fff4b40398e735a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Wenjing was admitted to Harvard Behind the early admission, his rich resume is indispensable:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Won the first prize in the National Youth Informatics Olympiad League (Zhejiang Province Division) when I was a freshman in high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Was invited by MIT to participate in a competition and won second place in the North American Programming Invitational Competition, surpassing most of the university teams from Harvard, Stanford, and Carnegie Mellon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. In 2014 and 2015, I participated in the U.S. National Informatics Olympiad for two consecutive years and won the championship. In 2014, I also obtained the only perfect score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. She has participated in mathematics competitions in China and the United States, and obtained the highest score in the American Mathematical Olympiad Summer Camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. During his three years in high school, Guo Wenjing tried a variety of meaningful things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, learn to sail, learn to ski, learn to be a lifeguard, join the debate club of No. 2 Middle School, and go to Shanghai to participate in an all-English debate competition; I like to study social issues and actively participate in various summer camps, such as &quot;Harvard Campus Tour&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6. Tang Meijie, Harvard undergraduate alumni interviewer and Harvard University China Secretary-General, interviewed Guo Wenjing and was full of praise for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have been interviewing in China for 6 years, and she is one of the best students. Her computer skills are among the best among female programmers of the same age in the United States. She is in American universities I got perfect scores in 5 subjects in the preparatory exam. I am very fluent in English and good-looking. It is almost perfect.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[卫星视角重访西九龙：一座海上CBD的诞生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260974]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 23:02:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李永晶的2023年度书单]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261633]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73793&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70582&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/c18da79b36.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Dunhuang Past.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1485&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/c18da79b36.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260273&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Dunhuang Past&quot;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Day] Matsuoka Rang, translated by Pan Yuling and Chen Yanqing , New World Publishing House, April 2023. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I see the word &quot;Dunhuang&quot;, my first reaction is usually to read it as TONKOU; similarly, when I see the word &quot;Kumaroshi&quot; This name, I would pronounce it as KUMARAJYU, and there are several similar situations. My pronunciation is actually Japanese pronunciation, because they are almost the same as the pronunciation of &quot;Dunhuang&quot; and &quot;Kumaroshi&quot; when I learned about it more than 20 years ago, so I was very impressed. This impression originated from a documentary produced by Japan&#39;s NHK TV station that I saw at that time: &quot;Silk Road&quot;. I am ashamed to say that before that, I had no understanding of either Dunhuang or Kumarajiva. Later, I gradually learned that Dunhuang has an extraordinary status in the hearts of Japanese people. In October 2018, I went to Dunhuang for the first time due to a meeting. After transferring in Xi&#39;an, I found that I was on the same plane with a Japanese tour group, and the TONKOU images in my memory flashed back frame by frame. At that time, I secretly sighed: Japan’s “Dunhuang Fever” is indeed well-deserved. Speaking of the origin of &quot;Dunhuang fever&quot; in Japan, this book published in 1943 is undoubtedly one of the initiators. Since this book is a &quot;novel&quot;, to avoid spoilers, the content will not be mentioned here. However, readers must have realized by now that it might be a pity to read this book as a novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73794&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70583&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/30/6ddafb8163.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Killing Season.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1484&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/6ddafb8163.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260274&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;《 &quot;Killing Season: A History of the Indonesian Genocide 1965-1966&quot;, written by [Additional] Robinson, translated by Xie Kankan and Roger, World Knowledge Press, June 2023. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the six months starting from October 1965, approximately 500,000 members of the Indonesian Communist Party and its affiliated organizations were killed, becoming the leader of the twentieth century. One of the most famous massacres in human history. What was the cause of this massacre? What is the identity of the executioner who carried out the massacre? What role did the United States, Britain, the Soviet Union, and other major powers play in this tragedy? These may be some questions that our general readers will think of. The author of this book is a well-known expert on the politics of Southeast Asian countries. Therefore, although this book is titled &quot;History&quot;, it is not a general straightforward narrative, but has clear analytical features. The author carefully depicts the distribution of the huge energy that triggered the massacre along several cracks within Indonesia such as ideology, military-political relations, religious beliefs, and ethnic identity. Of course, because it involves many complex and sensitive issues such as religion and race relations, the author writes with different shades of ink, which can be said to be prudent; however, the almost rare silence of the countries involved on this incident has been overshadowed by this excellent historical research Totally shattered. The people want the truth, and that is what true learning is about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73795&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70584&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/30/bda9db9a0d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Real and Virtual.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1591&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/bda9db9a0d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260275&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Reality and Virtuality: Philosophy in the Post-Truth Era&quot;, by Jin Guantao&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, CITIC Publishing Group, July 2023. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The word &quot;philosophy&quot; in the subtitle of this book actually refers to &quot;philosophy of authenticity&quot;, and the core part of this book can be positioned as &quot;philosophy of science&quot; &quot;Epistemology&quot; or &quot;theory of knowledge.&quot; Having said that, we understand that there is a high threshold to cross in order to read this book. However, the book&#39;s argument is unusually clear because the author has a consistent model throughout. This model is very simple: authenticity R (X, M, Y) is a structure composed of subject X, control means M and object Y. The &quot;authenticity&quot; of object Y only depends on the universal repeatability of M. . So, isn’t this just a repetition of the basic methods of modern scientific research? Not so; the author realizes that authenticity should be divided into three incommensurable fields: science, individual and society, and therefore wants to establish a unified theory for this purpose. In this book, such as the theoretical blind spots of Kuhn, who was famous in the field of scientific philosophy in the 20th century, the &quot;kingdom of lies&quot; spun by humanistic intellectuals who regard themselves as academic leftists in European and American circles, and the opinions of great physicists such as Einstein on mathematical abilities. &quot;Surprised&quot;, and even the properties of gauge field theory and superstring theory, which are the most cutting-edge in theoretical physics, the author has given his own very unique and bold views, which can be said to have great philosophical ambitions. In the process of reading this book, I would often compare it with my own experience gained from studying and researching in recent years. Although the results are similar and different, they all made me think deeply. This can be said to be due to the author&#39;s strong and clear extreme thinking ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73796&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70585&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/30/5c87f2a91e.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Qiu Chengtong&#39;s Mathematics Concept.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1566&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/5c87f2a91e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong >;&quot;Truth and Beauty: Qiu Chengtong&#39;s Views on Mathematics&quot;, written by Qiu Chengtong, Jiangsu Phoenix Literature and Art Publishing House, August 2023. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I just finished reading this book, I had a &quot;delusional&quot; thought: Is there a channel for at least all junior high schools, high schools and universities in the country to Have all math teachers read this book? After years of reading, I can see that such original Chinese works that are full of vitality are extremely rare. Reading them makes me feel refreshed. This makes me sigh from time to time: Mr. Qiu is really a powerful gentleman and a great scholar in the world. This great strength is not only reflected in his courageous advancement in mathematical research, but also in his outspoken criticism of the low academic style that takes fame and fortune in the academic world. It is also reflected in his enthusiasm for cultivating students. It is also reflected in the fact that he has a secret that is not easily known to others. The psychological mechanism: &quot;Study the relationship between heaven and man, understand the changes of ancient and modern times, and become a family.&quot; This is the famous saying of Tai Shigong, and I don&#39;t know how many scholars have been inspired. I have seen criticism of him on the Internet, to the general effect that Yau Shing Tong is domineering; for some details of the story, please refer to &quot;My Geometric Life: The Autobiography of Yau Shing Tong&quot;. At that time I thought: Well, as long as the critics can point to one of the above four points, I will accept it; otherwise, please listen to your instructions. In fact, if we look at the Chinese people who have left their names in the history of human science since the 20th century, one of their teachers is Chen Shengren, Yang Zhenning is another, and the third one is Yau Shing-tung. However, in terms of being able to make decisions for real academics and scholars, there may be no one at the moment who can surpass them. Master once said: &quot;Virtue is never alone, it must have neighbors.&quot; Good readers of this book will definitely agree with this statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73797&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70586&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/30/254212bb7b.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Conquest and Culture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1622&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/254212bb7b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260277&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Conquest and Culture: A History of the World&quot;, written by&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;US] Sowell, translated by Jiang Lin, CITIC Publishing Group, October 2023. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The author of this book is a famous black economist, thinker and public intellectual in the United States, and is also labeled as a &quot;black conservative&quot; . Knowing this background, it will be easier to understand the tepid style of the book: although the author is outspoken about the evils caused by the conquest of the major Western colonial empires in the nineteenth century, such as the slave trade and the massacre of Indians, he does not High-profile accusations. His economic perspective gave him an awareness of &quot;conquest and culture&quot; from the perspective of human natural history. For example, the situation of black people on plantations in the United States in the 19th century was better than that on plantations in Latin America. The reason was that the price of purchasing slaves in the United States was relatively high. Naturally, slave owners did not want their property to suffer losses easily, so there was a trend of preferring to hire slaves. Irish immigrants doing dangerous jobs. So, how does the author view the issue of &quot;colonial conquest&quot;? It can be said that the violent conflicts in the current world are still a continuation of this helpless natural history of mankind. The pace of progress of human civilization seems increasingly slow and heavy today. Because of his special ethnic identity, the author&#39;s relatively gentle and tolerant reappearance of this period of history, as well as his quiet criticism of &quot;tribalism&quot;, make his expressions and thoughts more meaningful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The author is an associate professor in the Department of Political Science, East China Normal University)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[作为文本的茶馆丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258517]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/k7XSaOnKmcU72AMhUa66c91RrEJSV10jWfkJLuh9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/k7XSaOnKmcU72AMhUa66c91RrEJSV 10jWfkJLuh9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Di at Heming Tea House in Chengdu People&#39;s Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Hua Xiaofeng/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For relevant reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.infzm.com/contents/257991&quot; title=&quot;Wang Di: Historian in the Teahouse&quot;>;Wang Di: Historian in the Teahouse&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di’s generation in Chengdu When people meet, they like to say, &quot;I eat three flowers in my mouth.&quot; &quot;Kouzi&quot; means &quot;Jiekou&quot;. &quot;啖&quot; means &quot;to eat&quot;. Su Dongpo&#39;s famous sentence &quot;Eating three hundred lychees a day&quot; will be pronounced more accurately in Sichuan dialect. This is easy to understand. The term &quot;Three Flowers&quot; requires experienced Chengdu people to explain it in detail before they can understand it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met Wang Di, I proposed to sit in a teahouse. Wang Di said, let’s meet at Heming Teahouse in People’s Park. At Heming Teahouse, as soon as we sat down, Wang Di explained what &quot;three flowers&quot; were. &quot;When I was a child, I drank third-grade flower tea, which is the most popular tea. I went to the United States in 1991, and when I returned to Chengdu in 1997, I went to a teahouse to drink tea. The tea waiter asked, what kind of tea should I drink? I said, &#39;Sanhua&#39; &#39;. He said that the worst ones now are &#39;special flower&#39; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Special Flower Tea&lt;/span>;).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;From &quot;three flowers&quot; to &quot;special flowers&quot;, it seems to conform to a certain &quot;law&quot; of &quot;rising&quot; along time. Wang Di said that maybe the &quot;Special Flower&quot; now is the &quot;Sanhua&quot; back then, but the name has just been changed. Older Chengdu people say &quot;eat tea with your mouth in mind&quot;. At that time, there was not even the word &quot;三花&quot;. An author signed by &quot;Follower&quot; made a somewhat pessimistic prediction in a Chengdu newspaper in 1942: &quot;As long as society progresses and a replacement for the teahouse appears, it will definitely decline or even cease to exist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Wang Di wrote at the end of &quot;Teahouse: Public Life and Microcosm in Chengdu, 1900-1950&quot;: &quot;A few hours later, they will still open the door of the teahouse just like they did on the first day of the century fifty years ago. They were unloaded piece by piece, but they didn’t know that together with this city, they had entered a completely different era that, although vigorous, no longer belonged to teahouses and tea guests.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to write this Teahouses in different eras, thus &quot;Teahouse: The Decline and Renaissance of Public Life in Chengdu, 1950-2000&quot;. Wang Di was born in 1956 and has more personal experience of Chengdu teahouses during this period. These two books constitute a century-old history of teahouses in Chengdu. &quot;Although the theme of this century-old history is teahouses, it is also a century-old economic history, a century-old social history, a century-old cultural history, a century-old popular history, a century-old history of daily life, and even a century-old Chinese city&#39;s history seen from the microcosm of the teahouse. The history of character.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di&#39;s years of writing about teahouses earned him the second biennial (2018-2019) &quot;Best Book Award&quot; from the American Urban History Society. The award citation said: &quot;This book adopts a multi-disciplinary research orientation, adopts anthropological and sociological research methods and theories, and mines various historical documents, including newspapers, diaries, personal records, and oral data of teahouse culture, so that This research is very in-depth.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For media professionals, Wang Di’s works have a lot to learn from. How to think big from the micro? How to see the times from ordinary people? How to find new ideas from numerous materials? These are common problems we face. Wang Di took me to many places. The feeling of telling history on the spot is extraordinary. It allows people to see three-dimensional and rich details, and naturally compare teahouses and tea guests in time and space. Everything is emotional. The collision and fusion of opinions and rational thoughts will form complex and fresh texts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Texts, or &quot;fragments,&quot; written by specific individuals provide new perspectives on history. Everyone adds their own text to history itself, so that history will be richer and more visible, and it will continue to get closer to the &quot;reality&quot; itself. There is no overall history, only ever-expanding history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[短剧制造者：哪有什么一夜暴富？不过是流量的打工仔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The shooting scene in Xuanpingli, Dahan, Xi&#39;an. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/b7f1bda39f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/b7f1bda39f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260286&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xi&#39;an Dahan Xuanpingri shooting scene. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Short plays are popular, but what are short plays? There are many descriptions in the industry: &quot;small local drama&quot;, &quot;mini program short drama&quot;, &quot;vertical screen drama&quot;, &quot;paid short drama&quot;, &quot;one-minute short drama&quot;... These words are put together to form the legendary &quot;short drama&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a video-based novel. You have to jump to WeChat, Douyin, and Kuaishou mini programs to watch it. The first few episodes are free, and then one yuan per episode, one minute per episode, and one episode is about 100 episodes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, it is more expensive than watching a movie, and the box office is about the same as a movie. Industry insiders have speculated based on internal data released by Douyin that annual sales can exceed 30 billion. By comparison, the national movie box office in 2022 will only be 30.067 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past month, this kind of imagination has made capital excited, and stocks related to short dramas have experienced skyrocketing prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of November 22, 2023, Tianwei Video and Chinese Online have both increased by more than 140% within the month, and Gravity Media, Guangbo Shares, Jiayun Technology, etc. have increased by more than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The unfinished story of capital is that this business looks very &quot;rich&quot;, but in fact it is difficult to make money. Many industry insiders told Southern Weekend reporters that the profit rate will not exceed 10%. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;90% of the income is used to pay for advertising on Douyin, Kuaishou, and WeChat. They are the driving forces behind the short drama’s popularity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of a short drama platform told a Southern Weekend reporter that the life of short dramas is given by traffic. It can make you rich overnight, or it can make you lose money overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said, just like e-commerce and merchants, &quot;If we don&#39;t support you to go online, your goods will sell hundreds of thousands a month, but if we support you, it will be tens of millions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An industry insider explained that according to Douyin’s traffic bidding mechanism, the cost of acquiring customers for short dramas is actually the result of competition with e-commerce, live streaming, games and other industries. Short dramas can acquire customers at a lower cost. Guest, this is the fundamental reason for its rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the ability of other industries to pay for traffic is weakening, and their ability to pay for traffic affects the future of short dramas. &quot;If live broadcasts become popular again next year, or those live broadcast rewards are at the top of the list, If guys are willing to pay for gifts again, they will steal more traffic with higher bids, and this will truly end the future of short dramas.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Right now, the leaders in the industry are deploying their own apps in order to seize this period of time and keep users on their own platforms, thereby getting rid of dependence on traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late November, the wild growth of short dramas ushered in a new round of supervision, and the State Administration of Radio and Television once again launched a one-month special rectification work on online micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Major short video platforms have removed a large number of illegal micro-short dramas from the shelves and banned a large number of accounts that have illegally published micro-short dramas. The micro-short drama &quot;Black Lotus&#39; Handbook for Ascension&quot; produced by Mi Meng&#39;s team was removed from the shelves for &quot;exaggerating the bad values ​​of extreme revenge and using violence to counter violence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A short drama platform founder told Southern Weekend reporters that supervision had begun as early as November last year, and starting from March 2023, the platform will also require &quot;review before broadcasting.&quot; In the past year, &quot;Every episode will be reviewed. After review, you will be given clear instructions whether you have passed the review or not, such as too many intimate scenes, etc.&quot; The founder has also had one or two dramas abandoned due to too many revisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since a large number of companies in the industry have transformed from online novel platforms, most companies are equipped with &quot;self-reviewers&quot;. &quot;Overall, it does not have a big impact on us.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, supervision is a good thing. Now everyone is waiting for the &quot;Detailed Rules for the Creation, Production and Content Review of Online Micro-Short Dramas&quot; formulated by the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television. With it, the waste of investment caused by failure to review will be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State Administration of Radio, Film and Television has launched a special rectification work on online micro-short dramas since late November 2022, and has removed from the shelves more than 25,000 short dramas, totaling 1.36 million episodes, and &quot;small-format dramas&quot; that contain illegal content. Programs&quot; 2420. From March 2023 to the present, more than 350,000 episodes (strips) of vulgar and harmful online mini-drama have been cleared, and 429 related &quot;mini programs&quot; and 2,988 accounts have been dealt with at different levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Xi&#39;an has become a center for short dramas&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sorry, my voice is hoarse.&quot; Li Tao has to meet more than a dozen people every day, &quot;Chen Ou flew to Xi&#39;an yesterday, just to gather beautiful and beautiful people. As for Chen Ou, some state-backed companies also came to me to see if there was any possibility of cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Tao is the founder of Fengxing Studio, which was originally a little-known film and television company. Previously, it mainly produced information flow advertisements and occasionally hosted weddings. I just started filming short plays last year when I couldn&#39;t get any work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyin releases an advertising consumption list every week. Being on the list is considered a hit. In the past year, Li Tao filmed 14 short dramas, 9 of which were on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially &quot;Wushuang&quot;, which was online for 24 hours, had a top-up of more than 50 million, and consumed 100 million ads in 8 days. It became this year&#39;s &quot;King of Dramas&quot; and Feng Xing became a &quot;hot star&quot; in the industry overnight. Fried chicken&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Li Tao was doing information flow advertising before, Xi&#39;an gathered more than half of the country&#39;s information flow advertising shooting team. After the short drama became popular, Xi&#39;an also transformed from an information flow advertising production base to a short drama center. Li Tao said, &quot;Sometimes, nine out of ten hits on the list come from Xi&#39;an.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Tao moved his office to Xi&#39;an Silk Road Center at the beginning of this year. There is a floor-to-ceiling window with a 270° panoramic view, overlooking the entire Chanba Ecological Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He regards this place as his blessed place. &quot;After moving here, the drama started to explode.&quot; More and more people came to him. He added a large coffee table, prepared a complete set of tea sets, and learned Acting like a southern businessman, he made Kung Fu tea for the guests. &quot; I want to feel happy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What people who come to drink tea are most concerned about is whether there is a password for the popular product? Li Tao&#39;s answer is &quot;book&quot;. A good script plus good production equals a big hit. A good script plus poor production equals a small hit. A bad script plus good production may not necessarily lead to a hit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone re-filmed &quot;Wushuang&quot;, &quot;I just changed the character names, even the actors&#39; sentences were the same, and the result was still a hit, which shows that the script is really good,&quot; Li Tao said . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He can read dozens of scripts a week and has developed a skill. &quot;After watching the first episode, I can guess the content of the next dozen episodes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these production teams, only by making hits can they have the opportunity to select good scripts. Only by selecting good scripts can they have the opportunity to make more hits. In order to get a good script, they are even willing to advance funding for filming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what kind of book will explode? &quot;This is a metaphysics.&quot; Li Tao is more confident about how to present a good script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I found the feeling of filming a short play was during the Spring Festival this year. At 3 a.m. on the sixth day of the lunar month, he checked the surveillance on his mobile phone and found that two shareholders were working overtime in the office to edit a film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fengxing has six shareholders, all of whom have been friends for more than ten years. Li Tao felt uncomfortable, &quot;My brothers are working overtime, and I am celebrating the New Year at home. This is not going to work. I called the others and said, Let’s go to the company and work overtime together.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around four in the morning, six people were editing a film in the company. The first episode was cut out to 3 minutes, but the pace was not fast enough and the impact was not strong enough. Everyone started arguing while talking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One side believed that the story should be complete and the main line should be clearly explained. The other side believed that the pace should be fast and the impact should be strong. No one could convince anyone. The final decision was that &quot;one person would cut one version and compare it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After comparing the two versions, the controversy disappeared. &quot;The audience will definitely know what this is about through two short sentences.&quot; Li Tao explained to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The core of the short play is The rhythm, if it is very long, it will be over if you feel relaxed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Short dramas need to subvert many concepts in the past. The experience of the traditional film and television industry has become a burden for short dramas. Now, compared to mature actors in the traditional sense, Li Tao prefers actors with experience in short plays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Xi&#39;an has become a center for short dramas. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ 2f5691249b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/2f5691249b.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;260287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xi&#39;an has become a center for short dramas. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Between being happy and not happy&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wu Shuang&quot; tells the story of the male protagonist Chu Qing who helps his wife make a comeback. After the wife becomes famous, she dislikes her husband and wants to divorce. But she didn&#39;t know that Chu Qing&#39;s other identity was the supreme master of the Dragon Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This drama has never explained what the Dragon Palace is, why it has supreme power, why Chu Qing needs to conceal his identity, he has to prove his identity, why can&#39;t he just say it...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Tao’s experience is that there is no need to pursue logic and rationality. “Many themes are fictitious. You don’t need to worry about which dynasty it is, or trace whether it is from the Song Dynasty or the Tang Dynasty. It is just a costume drama, the Three Palaces and Six Dynasties.” The courtyard is a matter between the emperor and his concubines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to the short drama is to control the audience&#39;s emotions and keep them in a state of &quot;between being happy and not yet happy&quot;. A small hook must be left at the end of each episode to make everyone want to read on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first and paid episodes are the key to a short drama. Li Tao&#39;s experience is that people must be retained in the first episode, and paid episodes are usually set before the biggest suspense is solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On average, editors at Fengxing Studio edit 1.6 episodes of short dramas a day, including the first episode and paid episodes, which usually take 5 to 15 days. Editor Er Pang told Southern Weekend reporters that their requirement is that &quot;every frame must be meaningful&quot; and there is no way to add water to a short drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Tao described that a good screenwriter can stabilize the audience&#39;s emotions, set a hook every time, and untie the hook reasonably, so that the suspense is still there and the audience will not lose patience. For example, the male protagonist has been suppressed for two episodes, and his emotions are almost suppressed. A small reversal is interspersed to stabilize the audience&#39;s emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of high-reversal, high-frequency, fast-paced plot is designed to stop the brain from thinking. &quot;As soon as you think about it, I fail,&quot; a short drama producer told a Southern Weekend reporter , &quot;When you think about it later, you will wonder whether the money was worth it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Tao introduced, &quot;We meet the needs of users in minutes,&quot; which is faster and more exciting. It is denser, has more reversals and fuller emotions. He believes that short plays have created an unprecedented form of film and television. &quot;I have never seen anything so dramatic in the history of film. No matter how good the film is, it cannot be cut into one minute.&quot; Sell ​​by the minute.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the professional shooting team in Hengdian, these &quot;people on the margins of the film and television industry&quot; in Xi&#39;an have an advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They once visited Hengdian for inspection and found that they still use traditional film and television techniques to shoot short dramas. The sound and pictures are recorded separately, the picture quality is 4K, and large machines are used to shoot on site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production team in Xi&#39;an can sometimes shoot a 100-minute drama in four days. In order to improve efficiency, the picture and sound are recorded at the same time. The picture quality is 2K. All shooting machines are handheld and no large machines are used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some traditional film and television people will also come to Li Tao to communicate. He obviously feels that, &quot;From the other side&#39;s heart, they don&#39;t like short dramas, and they feel that they are doing big dramas. But this does not exist Many big teams looked down on dimensionality reduction at first, but then they wanted to do it but found that they couldn&#39;t do it. This is a very common phenomenon in short dramas.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In less than a year, this office that brought good luck to Li Tao was already overcrowded. On the day of the interview with Southern Weekend reporters, Li Tao had just found a new office, &quot;more than a thousand square meters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The protagonist is either a security guard or a delivery person”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When Wang Xiaoshu started filming short plays in 2021, no one was optimistic about the short plays. “The first batch of people who filmed short plays , taking me as an example, they may all be losers.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, he founded Jia Shu Technology, a free novel platform. &quot;The business will not close, but it is not very good either.&quot; Seeing the story experts on Kuaishou, he felt that it was very similar to online novels. &quot;If we produce novels such as Son-in-law and God of War, which we are good at, there should be a market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2021, he filmed his first short drama &quot;The Strongest Female Security Guard&quot;. He didn&#39;t use a film camera, just a camera. &quot;It&#39;s a bit too much to call it a drama. You can&#39;t imagine how crude it is.&quot; The budget was 30,000 yuan to shoot for 100 minutes. &quot;I didn&#39;t even accept weddings, saying it was too cheap.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He remembered that, including Jia Shu Technology, there were maybe four short drama companies at that time. &quot;The protagonist of the short play is either a security guard or a food delivery guy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He found a Kuaishou expert in Tongnan, Chongqing. &quot;In Tongnan, one led one by one, and there were several teams specializing in photographing security guards. Their names were all very crude, and they were called &#39;shooting jokes&#39;.&quot; &#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to film a story, Wang Xiaoshu flew from Shanghai to Chongqing Jiangbei Airport, then took a three-hour bus ride, and finally met his heroine in a remote town - a story with millions of fans. Blogger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This business is also very magical to me, and I don’t know how to shoot it.” Wang Xiaoshu asked the expert to shoot the popular content on Kuaishou again. “At that time, I can’t say that I was polishing it. , I can only say that in order to extend the time, enrich the dialogue, and add a bit of conflict.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose is to leave space for recharging. &quot;Users have to watch about 10 minutes before paying, and the whole show is only 30 minutes. It feels bad to pay. For fifty, sixty, seventy or eighty episodes, users The recharge space will be larger.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everything is very primitive, there are no actors, &quot;her grandfather, grandmother, and cousin came to help&quot;, and the venue did not cost any money, &quot;just in front of a factory that has stopped production.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was very hot in Chongqing in July, so I had to take a break after taking a photo. Wang Xiaoshu squatted in front of the factory with an umbrella and finished the photoshoot in four days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other party also suspected that he was a liar and asked him to pay the money in one lump sum. The reason was: &quot;A similar story has been published on Kuaishou. If you shoot it again, will anyone see it?&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xiaoshu actually had no idea, &quot;it was too shoddy&quot;, but he soon discovered that he was wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Middle-aged and elderly people love to watch it&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;He bought 100,000 yuan of traffic for &quot;The Strongest Female Security Guard&quot; on the WeChat public account, and then played it on the mini program after on-demand viewing. The reason why we choose mini programs is that it is much easier than promoting apps. After all, the cost for users to download and install is very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platform charges a channel fee from the recharge he withdraws. The channel fee for the WeChat mini program has risen to 5-8 yuan per 100 yuan, while Douyin only costs 1-2 yuan, but WeChat is still the big one. &quot;Short drama&quot; The audience is more accustomed to using WeChat to pay, and Douyin needs to be redirected, which will create an additional payment obstacle.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;&quot;The Strongest Female Security Guard&quot; has returned about 100,000 in almost 20 days,&quot; which gave Wang Xiaoshu a premonition that this model could work. &quot;There are still people watching this crude production, so let&#39;s make it better. You can get your money back.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The short dramas that became popular at first were all security dramas, and their audience was also summarized as the &quot;three guarantees&quot; personnel, &quot;security guards, cleaners, and nannies.&quot; However, Wang Xiaoshu discovered through the backstage that these people were not necessarily low-income groups. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After accumulating tens of millions of fans, Wang Xiaoshu made user portraits and found that half of them were over 45 years old. “Most people may think that when people get older, they stop reading. We found that when people get older, It’s very impressive to see.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After starting his business for more than four years, Wang Xiaoshu interacts with this group of people every day. He feels that the entertainment life of middle-aged and elderly people is very lacking. &quot;Young people have many activities and do not need to consume online. These dramas are not cheap. An episode costs about 60 cents, and 100 minutes costs 60 yuan. Middle-aged and elderly people have both money and leisure.&quot; Moreover, young people are very familiar with the Internet. &quot;You can find pirated copies if you search casually, and it is difficult to pay for short dramas.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entry threshold for short plays is also very low. &quot;No need to think, no need to read, no need to think, everything is placed in front of you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It completely follows the classification system of online articles, which is divided into male channels and female channels according to the gender of the audience. The consumption psychology of the two groups is also different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Female video drama consumers are all grandmothers or mothers, and the most popular themes are sadomasochism and sweet pets. Wang Xiaoshu felt that they were &quot;still very eager and longing for love.&quot; Their marriage may have been like this. They had never been in love when they were young, and they longed to be cared for. &quot;It should be said that people need to be loved throughout their lives.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More men watch short dramas than women, and the male dramas dominate. God of War is the most popular theme, followed by son-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The self-media &quot;Short Drama Study Room&quot; found based on the statistics of the streaming list released by Douyin that among the popular short dramas from January to July 2023, the theme of God of War accounted for 32.98%, ranking second. It is a female video drama with a sadomasochistic theme, accounting for only 9.42%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;God of War&quot; refers to a person with a powerful identity who hides his identity and transforms into a small person. He is bullied by the villain and finally reveals his identity to fight back against the opponent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xiaoshu said that security guards or couriers will make the audience feel more involved. &quot;In reality, these groups are not respected, but in dreams they are very powerful and have status.&quot; It empathizes with the suppression and is released from the protagonist&#39;s counterattack. &quot;Dignity is something that many men lack on a daily basis.&quot; Wang Xiaoshu believes that short dramas can satisfy them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Short plays are used to create dreams. What does a dream look like? The dream is when he threatens you with &#39;bad reviews&#39;, and you suddenly laugh and say, &#39;Actually, I am a rich second generation, I will Being a delivery boy is just about experiencing life, but has it suddenly changed?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wushuang&quot; combines the elements of God of War and son-in-law. &quot;The male protagonist conceals his identity and becomes the son-in-law, not because he is not strong enough. It&#39;s because I like that woman, and her strong identity will always be made public.&quot; Li Tao feels, &quot;People who are suppressed by their wives or mother-in-law in life can be greatly released here.&quot; &lt;p>; com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/e2488df4d8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/30/e2488df4d8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Wushuang&quot;, online for 24 hours recharge With over 50 million, he became this year’s “King of Dramas”. Picture source: Video screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Unexpectedly small profits&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After March 2022, Wang Xiaoshu suddenly discovered that the entire industry began to skyrocket. “In two or three months, the company’s revenue scale went from several to One million suddenly increased to tens of millions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyin and WeChat became interoperable at the end of 2021, and short dramas became the beneficiaries. Wang Xiaoshu said that in the past, when buying traffic from official accounts, 40% might be recovered on the first day. After Douyin allowed jumping to the WeChat mini program, “the recovery on the same day was 100%.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyin also invited short drama platforms to stream in March 2022 (that is, merchants pay to increase traffic), which brought a huge turnaround to the industry. At its peak, Douyin’s short dramas invested in Stream consumption is 80 million a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xiaoshu believes that the first year of short dramas is 2021. In June of that year, the WeChat ecosystem opened up short dramas for streaming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there had been a large number of micro-short plays before that. For example, Tencent Video’s “Please! &quot;Don&#39;t Spoil Me&quot;, the amount of the split account in the third season reached 32.49 million yuan, and it is known as the &quot;King of Drama&quot; in the split account short drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But these short plays are not paid short plays. Their commercial realization relies on platform subsidies, and the bulk of the investment is still production fees. &quot;please! The production cost of &quot;Don&#39;t Spoil Me&quot; is as high as 20 million, and the advertising cost is only a few million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Essentially, these short dramas still follow the business model of long videos. The broadcast platform splits the bill with the producer based on the click rate of 1,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paid short drama adopts the business model of online novels. The monetization path is for users to pay for on-demand viewing, but more than 90% of the income must be used to pay advertising fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This business model is completely rooted in the CPS model of online novels, that is, the copyright owner opens the promotion link to distributors, and the distributors create secondary creations of the materials and publish them through Douyin, Kuaishou, and WeChat official accounts. Attract users to recharge, and both parties will split accounts according to the recharge amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the top short drama companies have been in the novel business before, such as Chinese Online, Dianzhong, Peanuts, etc., all have their own online distribution systems. They are the core of the industry, the copyright holders, and hold the most important resource - the script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Its upstream is connected to producers such as Fengxing Studio. The copyright owner will give the other party some guaranteed fees. The part of the shooting cost that exceeds the guarantee must be borne by the producer himself, and the profit will be divided in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Its downstream is the distribution distributor. The copyright owner provides technology and content and takes 15% from the recharge. There are also short drama companies that do their own distribution. Jiuzhou Culture is a company that is famous for its castings, with a casting team of 300 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Distribution is the lowest level of the short drama industry, and it is also the most mysterious and low-key group of people. Mou Changqing is very familiar with several leading short drama platforms. He is the founder of the short drama community &quot;28 Push&quot;. The main members of this community are the platforms, distributors and producers of short dramas. , script side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Most of the well-established distributors keep a low profile and never show off their cakes because they are afraid of being poached.&quot; When he saw some media reports claiming that the short play was created by a team of e-commerce brushing orders, he believed this was inconsistent with the facts. “The mainstream short drama platforms I know of include their main distributors, and none of them used to do e-commerce brushing orders. of&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Distribution is a resource-hungry industry. &quot;Most of the good distribution is due to a good relationship with the platform.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rate of return on traffic refers to the money that users recharge after buying traffic. Mou Changqing said, &quot;If the information provider invests in streaming, if it is a private e-commerce company, it would be good if it can repay 60% to 80% of the cost on the same day, because the private sector relies on follow-up to slowly repay the cost. If the live broadcast does not repay the cost on the same day, it will lose money. &quot;The return on investment must reach 150% to make money. In comparison, short dramas can reach 130% if done well.&quot; Mou Changqing said that short dramas are also one of the few projects that can return the money on the same day. Many powerful distribution companies They all chose to do short plays, &quot;thinking they can grab this piece of cake.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Min, the founder of &quot;Short Drama Expert&quot;, has also done short drama distribution business. He and Mou Changqing have different views. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the return rate of a short drama must reach 120%. It&#39;s not easy. &quot;A drama that can achieve such a rate of return can be regarded as a &#39;magic drama&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is actually very difficult to make money from short drama streaming. Yan Min said, &quot;As long as the return rate exceeds 105%, I will continue to invest. 100 yuan of advertising, 105 yuan of recharge, and 5 yuan paid to Tencent , labor is actually a loss.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained that the core of investment is to start with volume. If you recharge 100 million yuan, the profit rate is only 1%, and you can still make 1 million yuan. There is no minimum amount. After recharging 100,000 yuan, the profit margin is 10%, and the profit is only 10,000 yuan, which is still a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyin’s streaming system can set the rate of return. For example, if you invest 100,000 first, the return rate will be 110%. Only if the user recharges 110,000 will the next round of investment be triggered. Distributors will expand their scale as much as possible without losing money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Min said that distribution is an industry with high labor costs and thin profit margins. “For a small team of fifty or sixty pitchers, no one will care about you at all. If you have more than 200 pitchers, profitable&quot;. In the entire industry chain, distributors have the lowest threshold and the thinnest profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Content is king in short plays, and the copyright owner has the highest threshold, and they are the main ones who can make money. They can only provide technology and content and let distributors bear the cost of distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The producers also bear risks. Wang Xiaoshu said, &quot;To shoot 30 dramas a month, the content cost is 10 million. If the box office is not 100 million, wouldn&#39;t it be a loss? This does not include the platform&#39;s own manpower expenses and other expenses, but only the content cost. Most platforms still lose money. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The real winner is only the traffic side&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Short dramas are already a red ocean. Wang Xiaoshu calculated an account. According to the daily consumption calculations previously announced by Douyin, the monthly short drama sales It’s about 2 billion, corresponding to about 700 new dramas. The production cost of a drama is about 300,000 yuan, and the average revenue per unit is 3 million yuan, which means it is just profitable. In fact, the hits took most of the share, and most of the short plays were less than 3 million, which means they lost money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mou Changqing said, &quot;Many media think that if you recharge 30 million, you can earn 30 million. If the return rate is set to 110%, the gross profit will be only 3 million.&quot; After deducting various costs, The profit is only 1 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Min believes that &quot;those people deliberately make it so easy, just to cut leeks and let others invest.&quot; Some bosses in traditional industries mistakenly believe that investing hundreds of thousands can generate tens of millions in income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real winner in the short drama industry is only the traffic side. Most of the revenue goes to Douyin, Kuaishou, and WeChat, leaving only about 10% of the industry’s profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producers generally need to pay for filming. &quot;I have paid a little too hard recently, and now I am a little scared.&quot; Li Qiang, the boss of Xi&#39;an Gewu Qianfan, told Southern Weekend reporters that he has already paid for a movie. The skit has more than 1 million posts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the guaranteed production fee given by the copyright owner, the purpose of their payment is to improve the quality. &quot;It makes no sense for me to earn your 108,000 or 80,000 yuan production fee. What I want is to split the account,&quot; he asked. Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;50,000 or 5 million, which one do you want?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has been in the short drama circle for less than half a year. This is the first short drama he has invested in. &quot;I see this. &quot;Definitely win&quot;, if you can&#39;t win, it&#39;s just paying for your hobby. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, Li Tao is more cautious than the newcomers, &quot;I am not willing to shoot a short drama with a production cost of more than 600,000 to 700,000 yuan.&quot; He made some calculations, &quot;If you shoot a drama with more than 300,000 yuan, you can make a profit by recharging it to 3 million. For 600,000, you need to recharge 7 to 8 million to make a profit. How many dramas can have a recharge of tens of millions?&quot; What?&quot; He hopes to make some more stable money, &quot;I can make 200,000 yuan per movie, and I can do 50 movies a year, and I will still make a good profit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Nan, the boss of Xi’an Muniu Liuma Film and Television, has released three hit movies. “Not even the third one on the list, but the first and second ones.” However, he told Southern Weekend reporters that he is in a difficult situation now. The capital chain is broken, &quot;I don&#39;t know if I can survive until next month.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the film or online drama industry, teams are often formed temporarily, but short drama production companies need assembly line production. Chen Nan has four shooting teams with more than 40 people. Not counting rent, &quot;each The monthly salary is two to three hundred thousand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Tao said frankly, &quot;I can responsibly say that less than 10% of people in this industry can actually make money, and 90% are losing money.&quot; He used himself as an example. They filmed nine After a short play, the first hit came out, &quot;But everyone only saw &#39;wolf eating meat&#39;, not &#39;wolf being beaten&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, Chen Ou announced that he was actively watching short dramas. A month later, he told Southern Weekend reporters that he was &quot;still in the learning and research stage.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 26, the famous Hong Kong director Wang Jing appeared at the opening ceremony of a short drama. This may be the first opening ceremony held by the short drama industry. You know, vertical screen short dramas Cast and crew names never appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[监察官等级首次确定工作全面完成]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261626]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;As of mid-November, 31 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) across the country and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps City For the first time, the work of determining the grade of county-level supervisors has been completed. This marks the successful conclusion of the first determination of the national supervisory officer level, which will be carried out since 2022. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Doing a good job in determining the level of supervisors is an important measure to deepen the reform of the national supervision system. It is a practical need to build a high-quality professional discipline inspection and supervision iron army. It is also important for building supervision with Chinese characteristics. It is of great significance to strengthen the official system, uphold and improve the party and state supervision system, and promote the high-quality development of disciplinary inspection and supervision work. Under the unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission took the lead in carrying out the work from top to bottom and level by level. Local party committees, disciplinary inspection commissions and supervisory commissions resolutely shouldered their political responsibilities and strictly followed the &quot;Procurators Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and &quot;Measures for the Management of Supervisory Officer Levels (Trial)&quot; and other relevant regulations to steadily and orderly advance the work of determining the level of supervisors for the first time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Each provincial-level Discipline Inspection Commission and Supervisory Committee took the initiative to report to the party committee at the same level and put forward suggestions for overall planning and promotion plans. The main leaders of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee presided over two meetings to study the determination of the level of supervisors; the Deep Reform Committee of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Party Committee will promote the determination of the level of supervisors into annual work points and monitor the whole process; the main leaders of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee issued instructions twice, requiring careful attention Organize and implement meticulously. Under the leadership of party committees at the same level, the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commissions of Hebei, Shandong, Shanghai, Sichuan, Zhejiang, Jilin, Jiangxi and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps studied and issued work guidance opinions, detailing the scope of personnel, approval procedures, disciplinary requirements, etc. The Guangdong production and hair production work template provides key reminders on links or matters prone to errors; Hainan establishes a problem ledger to study and solve existing problems one by one to ensure accurate grasp of policies, standard work procedures, and strict disciplinary requirements. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Considering the determination of the level of supervisors as an important task, the disciplinary inspection and supervision agencies at all levels conscientiously organize and implement it and advance it prudently and steadily. The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission issued 2 questions and answers on the first determination of supervisory officer levels, carefully answered inquiries from various places, promptly summarized and published the experience and practices of the completed provinces, and promoted exchanges and mutual learning. Provincial Discipline Inspection Commissions and Supervisory Committees, based on actual conditions, generally adopt methods such as issuing question and answer sessions, holding special training courses, and carrying out policy presentations to strengthen guidance and standardize procedures. The Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commissions of Gansu, Henan, Hubei, Liaoning, Shaanxi, Tianjin, Yunnan, Chongqing, Anhui and other places have established a working mechanism in which the main responsible comrades take the lead, the leaders in charge are responsible, the organizational departments organize the implementation, and the functional departments closely cooperate, and set up special work teams , take the initiative to strengthen communication and docking with the Party Committee Organization Department, institutional establishment and other departments, and work together to study and solve problems. Guizhou has selected some municipal (state) Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commissions to conduct field surveys to study and solve existing difficult problems; Qinghai has organized special dispatch meetings according to different time nodes; since November, Ningxia has insisted on &quot;daily reporting&quot; to solve policy confusion encountered and process control and other issues; Shanxi summarizes the progress of the province&#39;s work every month, provides &quot;point-to-point&quot; supervision and guidance for slow progress, and ensures that the work determined by the inspector for the first time is advanced in layers and carried out in an orderly manner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Insist on putting political standards first, strictly standardize conditions, and strictly review and control. Discipline Inspection and Supervision Committees at all levels strictly compare the conditions for serving as supervisors, conduct a comprehensive survey of institutions, personnel, establishment, etc., comprehensively consider the performance of cadres&#39; moral integrity, job grades, etc., and scientifically and rationally determine grades in accordance with regulations and laws. Together with organizations, public security, economic and credit and other units, we will review the cadres’ academic qualifications, annual assessments, party conduct and clean government, credit reports, spouses and children’s immigration abroad (overseas), etc., and will not confirm those who do not meet the conditions. At the same time, we actively explain policies, provide ideological guidance, and take the initiative to have heart-to-heart conversations with cadres to ensure the ideological stability of the team. Fujian will review and judge one by one the establishment status, job rank, length of service, assessment rewards and punishments, academic qualifications, personal matters, party style and integrity of the cadres to be included in the determined scope; Tibet will establish accounts and list specific lists according to the cadre management authority. Check carefully and confirm again and again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Taking the opportunity of carrying out the first determination work, efforts will be made to promote the construction of a team of high-quality professional inspectors. Constitutional oaths, targeted training, knowledge competitions and other forms are commonly used in various places to educate and guide cadres to faithfully perform their legal duties and obligations, continuously enhance the awareness of the rule of law, procedures and evidence, and improve the level of standardization, rule of law and formalization. Combining thematic education and educational rectification, we should deepen the internalization and transformation of the party&#39;s innovative theories, highlight practical training and practical exercises, and vigorously improve the political quality and disciplinary and legal literacy of inspectors. Beijing compiled the &quot;Handbook of What Inspections and Supervisors Should Know and Should Meet&quot; and made public examinations a necessary process for determining the level of inspectors; Guangxi organized knowledge tests on party discipline and laws and regulations; Xinjiang relied on the online learning platform of the discipline inspection and supervision system to organize learning for disciplinary inspection and supervision cadres Relevant policies: Hunan guided 14 cities and states to hold ombudsman constitutional oath ceremonies to enhance the sense of professional responsibility and honor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“In the next step, we will guide all localities to carry out the regular determination and promotion of the level of inspectors in accordance with the provisions of the Inspectors Law and the Measures for the Administration of Levels of Inspectors.” Central Commission for Discipline Inspection National Relevant comrades from the Organization Department of the Supervisory Committee said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以自伤自残来控制对方也是家暴：应确认成年人自负其责原则丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261570]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Supreme Court released a number of typical cases against domestic violence. One of the cases was: Li repeatedly threatened his wife Wang by jumping off a building and drinking pesticide in front of her at her workplace. In order to ensure personal safety, Wang applied to the court for a personal safety protection order. The court held that: Li&#39;s self-injury behavior would cause Wang to feel nervous and fearful, which was a mental violation. Wang&#39;s application met the legal conditions for a personal safety protection order. Ruling: Li is prohibited from committing domestic violence against Wang; Li is prohibited from harassing, stalking, and threatening Wang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The typical significance of this case is expressed as: &quot;The harm of mental violence is not less than the harm of physical violence. In this case, although the respondent did not commit any acts such as beating or mutilation, the applicant The person causes physical injury, but his self-injury and self-mutilation behavior will definitely make the applicant feel nervous and fearful, causing the applicant to be mentally unstable and act according to the applicant&#39;s will. This behavior is mental violence.&quot; &quot;Clearly adopted The behavior of harming oneself in order to control the other party is also considered domestic violence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, this case should establish the following rules: Either one of the spouses will cry, make trouble, and hang themselves, or threaten the other party to commit suicide. Injuring yourself to require the other party to meet your specific requirements (whether the request is reasonable or not) is an act of mind control/psychological violence/domestic violence against the other party, so the other party will receive judicial relief. Of course, it is necessary to ensure that men and women enjoy equal judicial protection, that new rules apply to both men and women, and that the principles of equal rights for men and women and equal rights and responsibilities for each party are respected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media, this case has received a lot of concern, discussion and questioning. It is necessary to ask questions: The man threatens the woman by jumping off a building or going to her workplace to drink pesticides. What is the content of the threat? The basic facts of the case only state that &quot;both parties often have disputes over trivial family matters.&quot; The content of the dispute and the positions of both parties are crucial to determining who is right and wrong. From the &quot;frequent disputes&quot; between the two parties to the &quot;self-injury&quot; of the man, the conflict has an escalation process. How is this escalation completed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of this case is: &quot;Wang&#39;s application for a personal safety protection order case - threatening others through self-injury and self-harm is domestic violence&quot;, and the set keywords are &quot;self-injury, self-harm, mental control&quot;. The logical chain from self-injury to mental control/psychological violence/domestic violence is: one party says &quot;If you don&#39;t agree to my request and don&#39;t act according to my will, I will hurt myself&quot; + this means that the other party &quot; Produce tension and fear&quot; and cause the other party to &quot;not be free mentally.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, there are two points that may deserve further discussion. First, according to this logical chain, many different types of &quot;verbal violence&quot; by one party should also be recognized as mind control/psychological violence/domestic violence, because they can also cause the other party to &quot;generate tension and fear&quot; and cause the other party to &quot; The spirit is not free.&quot; For example, one party devalues ​​the personality, dignity and achievements of the other party through habitual and persistent complaints or derogatory and insulting remarks, in order to lower the other party&#39;s self-evaluation and thereby better manipulate the other party; or one party Make ridiculous or harsh demands, make exaggerated or false accusations against the other party, force the other party to give up their rights and self-esteem, and hand over control of their property and income, in order to control the other party mentally and financially. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to the above case, some netizens asked: &quot;Both parties often have disputes over trivial family matters.&quot; So during the dispute, did the woman commit &quot;verbal violence&quot; or mental violence against the man? If the man unilaterally and continuously engages in mental control/psychological violence/domestic violence against the woman through self-mutilation, why not file for divorce? In current judicial practice, domestic violence is a very sufficient cause for divorce. From the above details, it is difficult to see the necessity of maintaining this marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this we might as well extend our thinking: In a relationship between a lover or a couple, if one party injures himself or herself, does the other party need to be held responsible for this? The answer is self-explanatory. Because self-injury persons, as persons with full capacity for civil conduct and adults of sound mind, should bear their own responsibility and bear all the consequences of their actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, a court in Inner Mongolia decided a case, which caused huge controversy. The prosecutor alleged: On September 28, 2020, E Moumou drove his wife Chao Moumou to the Tongug Nur Pastoral Area of ​​Bayanhot Town to visit their daughter in a car. The two had a quarrel and dispute over whether they needed to go to the pastoral area to visit their daughter. While the vehicle was driving, Chao suddenly opened the rear door of the vehicle and jumped out of the vehicle. He died of severe brain injury after landing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports are more specific: The man drove his wife to see their 3-year-old daughter. The two of them kept quarreling over the issue of &quot;eating hot pot&quot; on the way... The wife said that she just wanted to eat hot pot now and didn&#39;t want to see the children. The man insisted on seeing the child first. When the wife saw that her husband had no intention of turning the car around to take her to eat hot pot, she became angry and made an unexpected move: she opened the door and jumped out of the car while the car was still running. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, the court held that the man&#39;s &quot;overconfidence&quot; caused the death of one person, constituting the crime of negligent death, and sentenced the man to two years in prison and three years of probation. The problem is that the woman did not give any warning before jumping out of the car. According to the rules and legal principles established by the above-mentioned typical cases of the Supreme Court, jumping from a car is like jumping off a building or taking pesticides. It is an act of self-harm. The person should also know the consequences of his actions, and there is no reason to hold the other party responsible. Article 66 of the Road Traffic Safety Law also stipulates: Passengers... shall not act in a manner that affects the driver&#39;s safe driving. It is impossible to establish such rules and legal principles: In the relationship between husband and wife, if one party harms himself or threatens the other party to obey, if he does not die, he will exercise mental control/mental violence/domestic violence on the other party. If he dies, it will be the other way around, and the other party will be responsible. criminal responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, the only correct rule is that adults and no one else should be held responsible for their actions. To &quot;strive to make the people feel fairness and justice in every judicial case&quot;, the rules and legal principles presented in each case in judicial practice should be reasonable, consistent and systematic, so that the people can have stable expectations and Sense of fairness and justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 18:25:17 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“并案处理”应被精细化对待丨法眼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261628]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/30/LAZyzv4x2zmzMca5us0hEL7XM29DdGTculyOSKr5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/LAZyzv4x2zmzMca5us0hEL7XM29DdGTculy OSKr5. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the &quot;anti-gang and evil&quot; campaign, cases often appear to be merged. The picture shows that on October 28, 2019, the public security organs of Wuhu City, Anhui Province held an exhibition of the results of the special struggle against gangs and evil. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In criminal cases, a case often goes through its own set of proceedings alone. However, under special circumstances, &quot;consolidated case processing&quot; will also occur, that is, multiple cases will be merged together for processing. According to the relevant provisions of our country, for cases in which the same person commits multiple crimes, joint crimes, or related crimes, the public security organs, people&#39;s procuratorates, and people&#39;s courts can handle the cases together. The original intention of consolidating cases is to allow judicial staff to handle cases more efficiently, and it has produced good results in practice. For example, it can better discover the truth, ensure consistency in sentencing, and generally improve the efficiency of litigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, in anti-gang and anti-telecommunication fraud cases, there have been huge cases involving hundreds of parties and spanning several months. At this time, some merged cases have not been handled as expected. Although it produces good results, it exposes some new problems that require urgent attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Unrefined systems and practices&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the whole, my country’s handling of consolidated cases lacks clear provisions in the Criminal Procedure Law, and at the same time, the provisions on judicial interpretation are at a low level. Defects such as overly general regulations and overly general provisions make the system not only less authoritative in judicial practice, but also less operable. This will inevitably affect the rights and interests of the parties after the case is merged, the choice of procedures, and the quality and duration of case handling. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the rights of the parties concerned are not adequately protected. Case-handling agencies such as the police, prosecutors, and courts have greater decision-making power over whether and how to consolidate cases. Sometimes, some case-handling agencies will bring their own case-handling needs into decision-making. Whether and how cases can be consolidated often depends on whether it can make handling the case more convenient, and whether it will affect the rights of the parties is rarely considered. This results in that in practice, it is sometimes difficult for the same party in the same case to realize the rights that he should have had when the case was not consolidated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in some combined cases, evidence will be used universally, and some evidence that was originally used only in one case will be used in another case. Some parties often make innocent confessions in order to get rid of the accusations against themselves, but these confessions may contain information that proves the guilt of others. In the absence of consolidated cases, once the defendant obtains a not guilty verdict, he is only a witness in other people&#39;s cases. At this time, he could refuse to appear in court to accuse other defendants due to immunity from testifying by relatives or other reasons. However, when the cases are combined, he essentially has the identity of the defendant in both cases, and the evidence proving the guilt of others in the innocent confession can be used in the entire case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is that the parties’ right to choose procedures is unduly affected. With the continuous development of consultative criminal justice, our country&#39;s criminal proceedings have given parties the right to make voluntary choices in some special procedures. When certain conditions are met, the parties can choose whether to apply summary procedures and expedited adjudication procedures, and can also make a judgment on whether to appeal. However, these options will be affected when cases are consolidated. According to my country&#39;s current litigation rules, the application of these two procedural diversion mechanisms must obtain the consent of all defendants. When there are differences of opinion between defendants, some defendants who wish to have a trial as soon as possible may not be able to use summary procedures or expedited adjudication procedures. Similarly, the second instance procedure in my country&#39;s criminal proceedings also stipulates that in cases of joint crime, as long as some defendants appeal, the entire case must be reviewed and handled together. A defendant who has no intention of appealing will be forced to enter the second instance procedure because other defendants file a second instance. For these defendants who had no intention of appealing, they could have obtained an effective judgment immediately after the first instance, but the mandatory second instance procedure extended the time they had to wait for the judgment. During this time, they suffer from the uncertainty of the final verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, merging cases without an upper limit will affect the quality of case handling. In practice, sometimes large cases involving dozens or even hundreds of defendants will be consolidated. Compared with splitting into multiple cases, giant cases require coordination among more parties and take up more time in preparation and trial procedures. Case handlers have to deal with the process of determining the facts and convicting and sentencing each person being prosecuted. The balance also requires more energy than ordinary cases, and improper handling will have a negative impact on the quality of case handling and the fairness of the results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, it may delay the handling of the case. The Criminal Procedure Law does not clearly stipulate the calculation of the time limit after the merger of cases, and the judicial interpretation only provides principled provisions on the time limit for joint trials, requiring that cases that &quot;may cause excessive delay in trial&quot; should avoid joint trials. But in fact, there is no operational standard for what constitutes “excessive delay.” Some case-handling agencies are not efficient in their work and are more willing to delay the litigation time. They will use cases with long remaining periods as the basis for the deadlines of newly merged cases. This leads to the fact that when the deadline for handling previously accepted cases is approaching, some case handlers will use newly incorporated cases as a reason to extend the deadline. As a result, merging cases has become a means for some investigators to extend the time of handling cases. It is a pity that the current system for combining cases has not yet identified and standardized this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Refined systems promote refined practices&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order for merger processing to better fulfill its original value and intention, it needs to be improved within the existing institutional framework. We believe that the handling of combined cases should focus more on the protection of the rights of the parties. Large cases need to be split reasonably, the time limit for handling the case should be strictly limited, and the parties should be given more room for procedural choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, we must pay attention to the protection of the rights of the parties. Our country&#39;s merger of cases is dominated by public power, and some unreasonable phenomena have appeared in the protection of the rights of the parties. In order to change this situation, efforts need to be made from two aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, it is necessary to ensure that the parties concerned enjoy the same rights when the case is consolidated as when the case is not consolidated. The International Criminal Court&#39;s &quot;Rules of Procedure and Evidence&quot; stipulate that for cases tried jointly, the parties should enjoy the same rights as if they were tried separately. Inspired by this, it is necessary for our country to emphasize in the litigation rules that regardless of whether the cases are merged or not, the parties have the same rights and treatment in the litigation - the rights enjoyed by the parties in the division of cases cannot be limited because of the merger of cases. reduce. Regardless of whether cases are merged or divided, and no matter what other purposes are pursued, the rights of the parties to a fair trial need to be protected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, it is necessary to establish the parties’ right to apply and improve the parties’ right to object. In terms of the right to apply, in addition to being decided by the public authority, case consolidation can also be initiated upon application by the parties. This can allow the parties’ demands to be taken more seriously during the merger process. In terms of the right to object, we must take seriously the objections raised by the parties to the merger procedure and protect these objections from being expressed smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the parties need to be given more choices. In criminal proceedings, the lengthy proceedings themselves are a kind of torment and a kind of punishment. In order to minimize the burden of litigation, parties should be able to enjoy the same right to choose whether to merge cases or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, in the pre-trial conference system, the right of the person being pursued to choose when combining cases should be emphasized. Since the actual trial has not yet entered, pre-trial conferences can effectively resolve and prevent some procedural issues. However, the relevant judicial interpretations in our country do not emphasize that &quot;whether there are objections to the merger and division of cases&quot; is something that can be discussed during the pre-trial conference stage. This situation should be added to the relevant provisions of the pre-trial conference to expressly indicate the pre-trial conference This stage allows the parties involved in the case consolidation to express their opinions on the case consolidation. If the person being pursued cannot reach an agreement between the summary procedure, the expedited procedure and the ordinary procedure, it is necessary to discuss and consider the possibility of dividing the case at the pre-trial conference stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to explore a divisible system for the second instance of combined cases. In our country, not all criminal cases are indivisible at the second instance stage. The Supreme People&#39;s Court has stipulated in its judicial interpretation that in cases with multiple defendants, the criminal facts of some defendants are unclear, the evidence is insufficient, or there are new criminal facts that need to be prosecuted, and the relevant crimes are not related to other co-defendants. , the people&#39;s court of second instance may handle these defendants separately based on the circumstances of the case. The second-instance rules for case consolidation can refer to this provision. When special circumstances similar to this provision occur during the case-consolidation process, unrelated defendants can also be separated in the second-instance procedure to avoid &quot;partial appeal, full appeal&quot;. case review” thereby depriving the parties of their right to appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Again, giant cases must be split up reasonably. When the handling costs of giant cases exceed a certain limit, it may consume too much judicial resources and have a negative impact on the fairness and efficiency of judicial decisions. To this end, two steps can be taken to promote the reasonable division of my country&#39;s giant cases from concept to technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first step is to clearly establish the awareness of rational division of large cases. Article 136 of the International Criminal Court’s Rules of Procedure and Evidence stipulates that when combining cases has a greater negative impact on the fairness of the case than dividing the cases, even if they are jointly accused, they need to be tried separately. This concept of division of cases can be transplanted in our country&#39;s judicial practice. The highest judicial authority can use guiding cases or typical cases to encourage localities to conduct pilot trials of reasonable division of giant cases under the guidance of the principles of fairness, efficiency and proportionality, and gradually establish the relationship between the case-handling agencies and case-handling personnel. Awareness of reasonable division of cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second step is to improve the provisions on the reasonable division of cases system in relevant judicial interpretations based on the aforementioned work. The current judicial interpretations related to case consolidation do not stipulate whether and how cases that are no longer suitable for consolidation as the litigation activities of this department advance. Once case handlers decide to combine cases, even if unreasonably large cases arise, they rarely make adjustments to the division of cases. Therefore, relevant judicial interpretations need to be supplemented, requiring the case-handling agencies to still handle separate cases as necessary after merging the cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the time limit for handling the combined cases must be limited. In order to prevent the &quot;borrowing period&quot; of case handling, it should be prohibited to extend the case handling period by merging cases. That is to say, merging cases will not automatically lead to the extension of the case handling period. When the case handling period is insufficient, the case handling agency should apply for a legitimate extension for approval. procedures to extend the deadline for handling the case. At the same time, it is necessary to make it clear in the case-handling responsibility system that delaying litigation in the name of merging cases is an unreasonable way of handling cases, and case-handling personnel must bear corresponding case-handling responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author Liu Renwen is a researcher at the Institute of Law, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, and Qin Han is a lecturer at the Law School of Zhejiang University of Technology)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“基辛格不会有第二个，但基辛格的担忧却会不断重复”丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 15:11:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency and other media reports, on November 29, 2023 local time, former US Secretary of State Henry Kissing Gerard died at his home in Connecticut at the age of 100. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just two months ago, Kissinger was still mediating the conflict between Russia and Ukraine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 24, local time, according to the &quot;Ukrainian Pravda&quot; report, Ukrainian President Zelensky met with former US Secretary of State Kissinger during his visit to the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Andrei Yermak, director of the Ukrainian Presidential Office, posted the above news on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger visited China in July and attended the Bund Financial Summit online on September 23. Southern Weekend once published &quot;Mediating the Russia-Ukraine Conflict, Centenarian Kissinger&#39;s Achievements and Controversies | Think Tank Perspectives&quot;, and the old version is now reposted as a mark of commemoration. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is Kissinger still active?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The world today is facing huge risks, unlike any risks since the Cold War. Previous risks, whether the United States sent troops to Afghanistan or Iraq, occurred between world powers and small and medium-sized countries, and the risk of escalation is unlikely. But this time, it has become a confrontation between world powers and a strategic confrontation between nuclear powers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the Russia-Ukraine conflict and the Great Game between Russia and the West behind it have had a strong impact on the post-Cold War world order. The conflict between Russia and Ukraine marks a serious challenge to the post-Cold War world order. On the other hand, this is also the first indirect confrontation between Russia and the US and Western camps after the Cold War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Yermak&#39;s account, Kissinger told Zelensky during the meeting, &quot;Before this war, I opposed Ukraine joining NATO because I was worried that it would set in motion the war we are seeing now. process (the outbreak of the conflict). Now this process has reached such an extent that the idea of ​​​​keeping Ukraine neutral in this situation no longer makes sense.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time Kissinger has mentioned Ukraine joining NATO. On May 17, The Economist published an exclusive interview with Kissinger. During the interview, Kissinger stated that he supports Ukraine&#39;s membership of NATO. He also said: &quot;Ukraine should continue to be protected by Europe, rather than becoming an isolated country that protects itself on its own.&quot; Regarding Russia, Kissinger said, &quot;If I talk to (Russian President) Putin, I will tell him , Ukraine will be safer if it stays in NATO.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Kissinger called on all parties to sit down and carry out diplomatic negotiations. He warned that there is now a risk that the great powers&#39; military relationships dominate their geopolitical calculations. The Russia-Ukraine conflict may therefore develop into a global conflict, and diplomatic negotiations will become &quot;increasingly important.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Sino-US relations have undergone qualitative changes since the Trump era. Conflict has begun to replace cooperation and become the key word in Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the relationship between the world&#39;s major powers, represented by the relationship between China, the United States and Russia, has become very dangerous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, Kissinger became increasingly worried about Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by Xinhua News Agency on June 16, Kissinger said in an interview with the media that Sino-US relations are on &quot;a cliff&quot; and &quot;the current trajectory of the relationship must change.&quot; Later, Kissinger also said that the Cold War between China and the United States is now &quot;walking on a mountain road.&quot; Kissinger believes that China and the United States &quot;both believe that the other side poses a strategic threat. We are moving towards a confrontation between major powers.&quot; This is a process that &quot;should not continue&quot;. Once a conflict breaks out between China and the United States, it will be comparable to World War I. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Kissinger actively mediates the conflict between Russia and Ukraine and drags his old body to visit China, which is an attempt to stabilize Sino-US relations and exert his residual energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why Kissinger? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the United States, there are many influential strategists. There are also many people who are worried about the international situation and are trying to improve Russia-Ukraine relations and Sino-U.S. relations. But why Kissinger and not someone else? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Kissinger has a superstitious admiration and sense of mission for the United States. As a German Jew who escaped the Nazi regime, to hold a high position in the United States is an example of an American success story. This also makes him always grateful to the United States. He once wrote: &quot;The same generosity of spirit and lack of malice can be found anywhere else.&quot; This almost sentimental gratitude and admiration for the United States made him serve the United States at all costs in diplomacy and devote himself to Maximize the national interests of the United States. For this reason, he did not hesitate to sacrifice his personal beliefs and did not care about his personal success or failure, reaching the height of &quot;living and dying for the benefit of the country, how can he avoid it for the sake of misfortunes and blessings&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, more than half of Kissinger’s diplomatic achievements are in Sino-US relations. Kissinger is an eyewitness and operator of America&#39;s transformation from decline to prosperity. If President Nixon had not accepted his suggestion, destroyed the Sino-Soviet alliance, and shifted the strategic focus of the United States from Asia to Europe, it would have been difficult for the United States to win the Cold War in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he entered American politics, the United States was experiencing its lowest point after World War II, and was experiencing triple crises of foreign strategy, economy, and society. The United States was trapped in the Vietnam War and was unable to extricate itself; it was in economic difficulties, and the U.S. dollar lost its ability and credibility to redeem gold; domestic society was in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Kissinger left American politics, the United States had successfully transformed China from an enemy of the United States into a &quot;friendly non-ally&quot; of the United States against the Soviet Union. Although the U.S. dollar can no longer be redeemed freely with gold, it has been tied back to the oil trade, achieving an upgrade from the U.S. dollar to an international standard currency. The U.S. dollar has transformed from an intermediary in world economic and trade to a truly hegemonic currency and an international standard currency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These all make Kissinger unique and a myth and legend in the diplomatic community. His status and influence in international politics, especially in Sino-US relations, are irreplaceable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Symbol of the Times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On June 16, 2023, according to Xinhua News Agency, Kissinger said in an interview with the media that the United States is politically polarized and is currently &quot;too focused&quot; on itself. If its foreign policy fails to balance U.S. and global interests, the United States &quot;will become isolated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Sino-US relations turned from hostility to cooperation was that both countries had to deal with the threat from the Soviet Union. However, without Kissinger&#39;s insight and courage, it would be difficult for China-US relations to quickly restart in such a bad bilateral relationship. The symbolic effect produced by this overlapping interaction between individuals and times is something that no one else can possess. Kissinger has become a symbol, a symbol of an era, and is unrepeatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, it was a product of the times when China and the United States united to fight against the Soviet Union during difficult times. When Kissinger secretly visited China, it was the Soviet Union&#39;s rise and hardening period, and it was a difficult period for China and the United States. The handshake between China and the United States across the Pacific and across the ideological divide not only created a diplomatic legend, but also stabilized the world situation at the time and destined the outcome of the Cold War in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Kissinger came to China, he saw the strategic contradictions and ideological differences between China and the Soviet Union, and wanted to contact China to jointly fight the Soviet Union. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, China and the United States have become the biggest beneficiaries of the end of the Cold War. After the end of the Cold War, both China and the United States were able to get rid of security concerns, reduce security burdens, and focus on economic development. The rise of China in the world and the rise of the United States within the Western camp complement each other. It can be said that Kissinger&#39;s personal luck lies in standing at a turning point in Sino-US relations and the world structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a personal level, Kissinger is often called a realist, mainly because he puts strategic thinking ahead of ideology. This distinguishes Kissinger from the current strategic researchers in the United States who are guided by ideology. However, he did not take ideological factors into consideration. In fact, he calls his foreign policy principles &quot;liberal internationalism,&quot; which is equivalent to the neoconservatism of the George W. Bush era. It is the product of combining the emphasis on values, internationalist principles, and diplomacy based on national strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because of this kind of liberal internationalism that he offended the two US presidents, Trump and Biden. On November 25, 2020, Trump fired Kissinger from his position as an advisor to the U.S. Defense Policy Council. However, he is also dissatisfied with Biden&#39;s withdrawal from Afghanistan, believing it to be an irresponsible act that betrays the tradition of U.S. foreign policy dating back to President Wilson. One result of expressing this rhetoric is that Biden inherits Trump&#39;s approach to Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are many talents in the U.S. strategic field, and many of the younger generation of strategic people than Kissinger have also withdrawn from the stage. The young and middle-aged strategic talents in the United States are now leading the charge in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, age is a major advantage for Kissinger. Kissinger is 100 years old and has outlived all his friends and opponents. Kissinger is the only international politician in the world who is still active and influential at the age of 100. This makes Kissinger&#39;s role largely unrepeatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Can Kissinger be copied? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Kissinger is a product of his times. Times cannot be repeated, and Kissinger cannot be copied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the shape of Sino-US relations has changed. During the Cold War, the biggest external threat to China and the United States was the Soviet Union. For the sake of their own security, China and the United States have established a quasi-alliance system across the ideological divide, which is in line with their own interests. Now, as China has unprecedentedly entered the center of the world&#39;s power stage, Sino-US relations have become the most important bilateral relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the characteristics of diplomacy have changed. The realists represented by Kissinger advocate personal factors and are superstitious about secret diplomacy. This was already outdated by the end of the Cold War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger was obsessed with those passionate years throughout his life, and was intoxicated by the thrill and excitement of secretly boarding a plane from Pakistan to Beijing. In the post-Cold War era, especially in the era of highly transparent and open self-media, these individual heroic diplomatic behaviors are difficult to reproduce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Kissinger’s influence in the United States has declined much faster than in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of the new era, many Americans are also reflecting on and challenging Kissinger&#39;s past contributions and achievements. The famous international relations scholar Hans Morgenthau has long said that Kissinger, like Odysseus in Homer&#39;s epic poem, &quot;has many facades.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the United States, there are two descriptions of Kissinger: one is a liar. This person never tells the truth, always speaks ambiguous words, and almost never makes clear public comments on major events. This may be one of the secrets of his longevity in the world of international relations. Second, Kissinger is an amazing person with an excellent memory. He was an eyewitness and living dictionary of many major events. Christopher Hitchens&#39;s description of Kissinger is perhaps more accurate, calling him &quot;a stunning liar with an incredible memory.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, there is something very dangerous. Compared with Kissinger, whose main achievement was during the Cold War, current American strategists basically grew up in a peaceful atmosphere. For them, peace is no longer the primary goal of international politics, but the premise or background of international politics, which does not need to be fought for or paid for. Therefore, we can see that compared with Kissinger&#39;s concerns about the prospect of conflict, many American strategists seem not to be concerned about the possibility of conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, there will be no second Kissinger, but the crisis that Kissinger is worried about will continue to repeat itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Center for American Studies, Fudan University)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西藏阿里全体公务人员为一女子献血？应以令人信服的证据消除特权嫌疑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261624]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 14:57:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A woman in Shanghai suffered severe bleeding in a car accident in Tibet. Her relatives contacted the Ngari region through the Shanghai Health Commission and mobilized all civil servants Donate blood for it? Recently, this news has attracted great attention on the Internet, and netizens have questioned whether there is a privilege issue behind it. Although the person concerned continues to deny that any relatives are public officials, many netizens do not buy it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports from the Beijing News and other media, a woman who calls herself Xiaoyu recently posted a short video on social media, saying that she had a serious car accident while traveling by car to the Ali area of ​​Tibet during her honeymoon. Her liver ruptured, she lost serious blood, and she was injured. Danger to life. Her husband’s aunt contacted the Ngari area of ​​Tibet through the Shanghai Municipal Health Commission and coordinated with medical experts from Shanghai to assist Tibet to treat her. She also mobilized “all public servants” in the Ngari area, including police officers, fire fighters, and army officers and soldiers, to donate blood for her. In the end, more than 7,000 ml of blood was used to bring her back from the brink of death. Subsequently, she was transferred to West China Hospital in Sichuan via a medical charter flight for further treatment. After her injury stabilized, she returned to Shanghai from Sichuan to continue treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video quickly attracted a lot of attention. Many netizens question who the &quot;little aunt&quot; is. She can actually allow the Shanghai Municipal Health Commission to mobilize medical experts to assist Tibet, and can also mobilize all civil servants in the Ngari region to donate blood for her. Is she suspected of taking advantage of her privileges? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After arousing great public opinion, all parties involved accepted media interviews and responded, denying the existence of privileged interference. However, these responses failed to dispel public doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, who is the &quot;little aunt&quot;. Ms. Yu&#39;s husband, Mr. Tao, later told the media that his aunt was not a public official in Shanghai. It was after his wife&#39;s car accident that the local authorities suggested asking the Shanghai Health Commission for help. The aunt, who was usually close to him, &quot;find a way&quot; to contact the Shanghai Health Commission. Committee. The Shanghai Health Commission stated that they received a letter from &quot;relevant departments&quot; at that time, requesting Tibet-aid doctors who were in Shigatse City, Tibet, to go to the hospital involved to participate in the treatment. There was no action caused by improper factors such as personal relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that this little aunt is indeed able to contact the Shanghai Health Commission and can also get the &quot;relevant departments&quot; to send letters to the Health Commission. In the eyes of ordinary people, an ordinary citizen may only be able to call the National Health Commission&#39;s hotline at most, so &quot;little aunt&quot; will inevitably raise questions. The Shanghai Health Commission needs to provide more explanations. Which department has received the letter? The department also needs to explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Ms. Yu was later sent to West China Hospital in Chengdu, Sichuan for treatment on a medical charter flight. The medical charter flight was expensive. Her father said that they were an ordinary family and the charter flight cost more than 1.2 million yuan, which they borrowed from relatives, friends and leaders. But this statement is also questionable. Although the purpose of spending one million yuan to charter a flight from Tibet to a better hospital in the mainland was to save her daughter&#39;s life, it was not easy to raise such a huge sum of money in a short period of time. According to Mr. Yu, he &quot;driving at work.&quot; Such a unit and such a good leader have aroused the envy of many netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, what netizens are most concerned about is whether &quot;all public servants&quot; were mobilized to donate blood for her. Mr. Tao later said that his wife had just undergone surgery and was still seriously injured. He said this to encourage his wife to have the will to survive. In fact, it was the hospital staff who posted messages in Moments and groups, hoping that well-wishers would donate blood. , I also contacted the local police station, fire department and other departments, hoping to get their help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba government staff said that cadres and employees did donate blood to the injured woman, but it was not officially organized, but voluntarily donated blood after seeing relevant news. Ali Hospital staff also said that after the blood bank inventory ran low, the hospital asked employees and social workers for help, and family members also asked multiple local departments for help. Later, many people came to donate blood, including dozens of public officials. The aforementioned government staff also said that the medical conditions in the Ngari area are relatively backward and the blood inventory is already very tight. If someone asks for help, many cadres and employees will voluntarily donate blood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Shanghai tourist had a car accident in Tibet. The relevant departments in Shanghai and Ngari worked together to coordinate the treatment of Tibet experts while voluntarily donating blood to save lives. Finally, the seriously injured tourist was rescued. This should have been a touching moment. s story. However, a short video caused an uproar on the Internet questioning privileges. The reason is that the public has seen too many unfair phenomena of using power for personal gain, and has also seen too many incidents where people show off their wealth and power online and inadvertently expose corruption issues. The short video posted by Ms. Yu may also give people the feeling of showing off her &quot;little aunt&#39;s&quot; abilities (that is, showing off her family&#39;s abilities). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, no wonder the public suspects that there is privilege here. If you want everyone to believe that this is a purely touching incident, the parties involved, especially the official agencies involved, should come up with more Compelling evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[查理·芒格逝世 “我没有什么要补充的了”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/30/65rPbMhQMAk6Wb5LlOGb5rwNujlbtMcUqyWfR7Dm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/65rPbMhQMAk6Wb5LlOGb5rwNuj lbtMcUqyWfR7Dm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260229&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;May 3, 2019, Burke, Omaha, Nebraska, USA Hill Hathaway CEO Buffett (left) and Vice Chairman Munger &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;&quot;Less crazy and stupid than most people&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A month before his 100th birthday, Charlie Munger died in a hospital in California. Warren Buffett has lost his best friend forever, and the world has lost another humorous and unruly wise man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger, 99, is a partner of Warren Buffett. He has served as Vice Chairman of Berkshire Hathaway since 1978. Over the past 40 to 50 years, the two have worked together to build Berkshire from a shaky textile manufacturing company into one of the most successful multinational conglomerates in history. The group&#39;s subsidiaries have covered many fields such as insurance, rail transportation, energy, manufacturing, retail and services, and hold shares worth more than US$318 billion, about half of which are Apple shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two weeks ago, Munger was interviewed by CNBC reporter Becky Quick. Compared with the shareholders&#39; meeting half a year ago, his thinking is still sharp and he likes to use long sentences when stating his views, but his voice has become increasingly hoarse and difficult to understand. The limitations of the body cannot be overcome by the intellect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quick asked him what he wanted to do in particular, and got a negative answer. His hands can no longer feel the tension of the fishing line when different fish bite the hook like they did when he was young. He no longer insists on crossing &quot;catching a 200-pound tuna&quot; off his bucket list. &quot;It requires too much physical strength. Even if I have the chance now, I won&#39;t go there, I won&#39;t even chase them. Time will always make you give up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with when he was 96 years old, he We are increasingly aware of aging and weakness in our bodies. When asked about it by Quick, he said he no longer had a plan. He &quot;happily accepts&quot; all kinds of changes. During the interview, he was sitting in a sunny courtyard, with a row of anthuriums, also known as flower candles, placed on the lawn beside him. This kind of flower has bright color and long-lasting flowering period. From blooming to withering, it will show beige, milky white, green and yellow, each with its own characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/QlY37KH7E81EYH1sOkTaiqbGA2Cmb0CkWmOADdgm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/QlY37KH7E81EYH1sOkTaiqbGA2Cmb0CkWmOADdgm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260223&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From &quot;The Way of Munger&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by CITIC Publishing Group)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Buffett often jokes that in front of Munger, he is still a young man. Just a week before Munger&#39;s death, 93-year-old Buffett had just announced a donation of approximately $866 million worth of Berkshire stock to four family charities. This is the latest step in his commitment to donate more than 99% of his net wealth to charity. Since 2006, every year on the eve of Thanksgiving, the &quot;Stock God&quot; has donated to the above four family charities. In a letter to shareholders, Buffett said that he is 93 years old and feels very good about himself, but he is also fully aware that he has entered &quot;overtime.&quot; A week later, in the &quot;overtime&quot; game, his most tacit teammate bid farewell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger has always believed that the important reason why he and Buffett have had outstanding careers is to stay on the scene long enough, but the prerequisite for the magic of &quot;compound interest&quot; to be cast is still &quot;more than most&quot; People are less crazy and stupid”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger was born on January 1, 1924 in Omaha, Nebraska. He has loved reading since he was a child, is especially fascinated by biographies, and has a strong logical thinking ability. After graduating from Harvard Law School as a magna cum laude graduate, Munger followed in the footsteps of his grandfather and father and started his career as a lawyer in Los Angeles. Subsequently, in order to earn more income than a senior lawyer, Munger began to rely on existing client resources to carry out investments outside of his legal business and created his own investment partnership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/mp7jsMBqiHAWf10KmMJXxXhIPShRxI9hoGZ1sDuV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;959&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/mp7jsMBqiHAWf10KmMJXxXhIPShRxI9hoGZ1sDuV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260228&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 9, 1988, Munger was in California, USA&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1959, Munger&#39;s father passed away. When he returned to his hometown to take care of his funeral, he met 29-year-old Warren Buffett at a dinner arranged by a friend. The two, who were 6 years apart, hit it off immediately. At Buffett&#39;s suggestion, Munger began to focus on business in 1965. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two were each other&#39;s confidants and contributed to an important turning point in each other&#39;s lives. Buffett once said that it was Munger&#39;s ideological power that expanded his horizons and allowed him to &quot;evolve from apes to humans at an extraordinary speed.&quot; Otherwise, he would be much poorer than he is now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of his career, Buffett was a loyal follower of Benjamin Graham, known as the &quot;Father of Value Investing.&quot; Graham advocated finding company stocks that were selling for less than working capital, buying them cheap, and then selling them when the stock price rose, leaving a sufficient margin of safety. These &quot;cheap and unloved stocks&quot; he compared to &quot;cigarette butts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/DgBzqofMqcGvRNWJU3WDvArA4pJap8FglGpU91EU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1592&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/DgBzqofMqcGvRNWJU3WDvArA4pJap8FglGpU91EU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Munger&#39;s Way&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key force driving the evolution of Buffett&#39;s investment philosophy is Munger. Munger believes that Graham&#39;s investment strategy is based on the assumption that the future will be &quot;more dangerous than full of opportunities.&quot; But in fact, investing in great companies with fair stock prices is far better than investing in ordinary companies with ultra-low stock prices. Influenced by Munger&#39;s ideas, Buffett gradually moved away from the limitations of Graham&#39;s theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They found that some stocks are still very cheap even though the price is two or three times their book value, because the company may be on a growth path, have very good managers, or The whole management system is excellent and so on. Through detailed analysis of balance sheets, social and economic trends, etc., Buffett and Munger detected high-quality stocks from the vast stock market that they regarded as &quot;compound interest machines.&quot; Holding these stocks over the long term will result in excess profit returns, and these funds will be reinvested. Buffett compared this process to &quot;snowballing&quot;. &quot;You can only roll a snowball if you find the right snow.&quot; &quot;Choose a snowy place while moving forward to let the snowball get bigger and bigger.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since From 1965 to the end of 2022, Berkshire&#39;s annual compound return was 19.8%, and its total return in 57 years reached nearly 37,900 times, far outperforming the performance of the S&amp;P 500 Index during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Without Charlie Munger’s inspiration, wisdom and involvement, Berkshire Hathaway would not be able to develop to its current position.” After Munger’s death, Buffett wrote in a statement road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/O7v0oHkL2z4eLmMxBbVRqU7G2xtdZwWNS8lw4ThR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/O7v0oHkL2z4eLmMxBbVRqU7G2xtdZwWNS8lw4ThR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 6, 2023, Nebraska, USA, shareholders listened to Munger (right) and Buffett via video at the Berkshire Hathaway annual meeting Deliver a speech &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Acquiring wisdom is a moral responsibility&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;According to Forbes, as of November 28, 2023, Munger&#39;s net worth was approximately US$2.6 billion. However, compared to his difficult-to-replicate wealth and life, what benefits ordinary people more is Munger&#39;s thinking mode. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett calls Munger &quot;the best fast thinker in the world.&quot; As a stock picker, Buffett would test his ideas through Munger&#39;s questioning. &quot;He can think from A to Z in one go, and he can see the essence of everything even before you finish speaking.&quot; Behind this insight is Munger&#39;s long-trained thinking method, which he calls &quot;multiple Thinking Model”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger has spoken many times in public about the value and importance of using &quot;multiple thinking models&quot; in the business world and real life. For example, before making an investment decision, he will conduct a comprehensive analysis of the internal operating conditions of the intended company and the larger overall &quot;ecosystem&quot; in which it operates, so he can always &quot;find convincing weaknesses within 60 seconds.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Munger&#39;s estimate, he has as many as a hundred multiple thinking models stored in his mind. These models will help him collect and process information and provide decision-making guidance on this basis. These models need to borrow and combine analytical tools, methods and formulas from various traditional disciplines, including the redundant backup system model of engineering, the compound interest model of mathematics, the breakpoint of engineering, the overturning moment of physics and chemistry, and the autocatalytic model. Modern Darwinian integrated models in biology, and cognitive misjudgment models in psychology, to name a few. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/CmTkpEB3YqZ184Ju7dBlvWVXmJpC6Sg8ZqUNmcab.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1525&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/CmTkpEB3YqZ184Ju7dBlvWVXmJpC6Sg8ZqUNmcab.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260224&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Poor Charlie&#39;s Almanac&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the so-called &quot;intuition&quot; is actually the end point of a long thinking journey, which is Munger&#39;s understanding of human behavior and business systems. and other products of long-term interdisciplinary research. He advocated &quot;quick annihilation of what shouldn&#39;t be done, followed by a skilled, interdisciplinary attack on what should be done, and then, when the right opportunity comes - and only when the right opportunity comes - decisive action.&quot; He likes to regard his life as an educational experiment. &quot;A person who has mastered his major well will test the feasibility and effectiveness of this basic academic spirit and method in a very broad academic field.&quot;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Munger&#39;s view, gaining wisdom is not just to make an individual&#39;s life better, but also a moral responsibility. He made this point in his 2007 commencement address at the USC Gould School of Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his speech, he also reminded the young graduates to &quot;avoid extremely strong ideologies&quot;, &quot;especially those expressed in a very violent way&quot; because &quot;it only &quot;Instilling some concepts in people instead of convincing people to accept some truths&quot;, &quot;This is tantamount to locking the brain in a very unfortunate mode&quot;, &quot;In this way, your mind will be broken, and sometimes it will be bad.&quot; It breaks at an alarming rate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to help himself stay clear when he is inclined to support a strong ideology, Munger set an &quot;iron rule&quot; - &quot;Only if you can be better than your opponent I am qualified to have an opinion only when it refutes my own position.&quot; Of course, this &quot;iron rule&quot; is not limited to avoiding the whirlpool of strong ideologies. Munger believes that this way of thinking deserves continuous training. Only by constantly falsifying and questioning yourself can you reduce your ignorance. In his opinion, perhaps more suitable as an ideology is the spirit of &quot;accuracy, diligence and objectivity&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, catastrophic thought states include &quot;jealousy, resentment, hatred, and self-pity.&quot; Munger has experienced the most pain in the world. In 1953, shortly after divorcing his wife, his eldest son Teddy suffered from fatal leukemia. Bone marrow transplant surgery had not yet been available at that time, and Teddy soon died of the terminal illness. In the memories of friends, after visiting his son in the hospital at that time, the 29-year-old Munger would often walk on the street crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, Munger warned young people, &quot;Excessive self-pity can make people almost paranoid. Paranoia is one of the hardest things to reverse. Whenever you find yourself feeling self-pity, whether it is No matter what the reason, even if your child is about to die from cancer, you have to think that self-pity will not help.&quot; However, different life stages will always encounter very difficult problems. His advice is: Don’t have high expectations; have a sense of humor; surround yourself with the love of friends and family. &quot;The most important thing is to adapt to changes in life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a wealthy and long-lived wise man, Munger is most often asked &quot;How to become happy and wealthy?&quot; In his opinion Come on, there&#39;s more to life than just being smart about accumulating wealth. Most success in life and business comes from things that should be avoided, like premature death and bad marriages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/qxt9znRMzJc1X9gzp3gXf67kE7UzJkseFJjzmsKJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 30/qxt9znrmzjc1x9gxf67KE7UZJKSEFJZMSKJ.JPG&quot; data- &quot;>; 260225&quot;>; &lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; September 29, 2010, Munger (left), Buffett (middle) and Bill Gates participated in the event in Beijing &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also has another answer- &quot;When I get up every day, strive to become smarter than you before. Complete your task seriously and excellently. Slowly, you will make progress, but this progress is not necessarily fast. But this can lay the foundation for rapid progress ... slowly move forward every day. Finally -if you have long enough life -big Most people will get what they deserve. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; When 82 years old, Munger&#39;s friends gave him a&quot; Sissero&#39;s Beautiful Life &quot;published by Benjamin Franklin. The translation of &quot;On the Elderly&quot;. Inspired by this article, Munger wrote the article &quot;The Elderly: The Elderly: Munger&#39;s Later&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the text, Munger exceeded the summary of the wise man born in 106 BC: &quot;The best protective armor in his later years is a life that was carefully spent before it was used. The pursuit of beneficial knowledge, glorious achievements and noble lives; people who live this kind of life have been committed to improving himself from his youth, and will harvest the happiest fruit of them in his later years; this is not only because of Beneficial knowledge, glorious achievements, and noble manners will accompany him for life, even until the last moment of his life, will bring the soul supreme because of witnessing the conscience of the upright life and the memories of the past good achievements. Comfort. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Munger&#39;s life is one of the best interpretations of this. Like Benjamin Franklin, who is happy, he always has a strong curiosity and extensive interest. He is always creating, giving, and being remembered. He spent the full 99 years, just as his mantra at the Berkshire Annual Meeting: &quot;I have nothing to add.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>; ( Reference materials: &quot;Poor Charlie&quot;, &quot;The Way of Munger&quot;.) &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>