<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中美经济工作组举行第一次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259175]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to He Lifeng, Vice Premier of the State Council and Chinese leader of China-US Economic and Trade, and Janet. Following the consensus reached by Yellen during her talks in Beijing in July, the China-US Economic Working Group held its first meeting via video on October 24. The meeting was chaired by officials at the deputy ministerial level of finance from the two countries. The two sides had in-depth, candid and constructive communication on issues such as the macroeconomic situation and policies of the two countries and the world, bilateral economic relations, and cooperation in responding to global challenges. China expressed its concerns. Both parties will continue to maintain communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“第一学历歧视”？别用这样的观念轻易否定企业丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259163]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, many media launched reports related to &quot;first degree discrimination&quot;. It is worth noting that on September 29, the Ministry of Education responded to a netizen’s question about “Whether the first degree after graduation is a junior college or a bachelor’s degree?” The concept of “first degree” is not used in the relevant policies and documents of the national education administration department regarding the learning experience of scientific and cultural education and skills training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an objective point of view, graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees from prestigious schools generally have some advantages in the job market. Needless to say, this may be &quot;first degree discrimination&quot; The realistic background in which relevant issues have received attention. But is similar recruitment behavior “merit-based” or “discriminatory”? It may not be possible to generalize, but the issues of corporate operational autonomy and employment autonomy that run through it are also important aspects worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, for graduate students from 985 universities, does the recruiting unit or human resources specialist make a clear employment choice based on the prerequisite of &quot;undergraduate degree from a prestigious school&quot;? This is actually hard to say. Especially as a for-profit organization, the company will ultimately look at whether the applicant&#39;s abilities and talents match the company&#39;s employment needs. It may also be that the company&#39;s interviewer confirms the match between the applicant&#39;s abilities and the company&#39;s needs through a comprehensive, complete and systematic assessment. . And graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees who have been blessed by famous schools may have shown certain advantages in this link and finally got the opportunity, but it may not necessarily be simple and crude academic qualifications that win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the recruitment process of the employer is that the human resources specialist will screen the resume before the interview. Only after passing the preliminary screening will he be qualified to participate in the initial interview hosted by the human resources department and even the professional interview hosted by the leader of the hiring department. interview. If some companies clearly stipulate in black and white that they will not recruit students with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; or are suspected of academic discrimination, if master&#39;s and doctoral graduates with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; can pass the resume screening, in this sense, 985 As a stepping stone, colleges and universities have already been used in the preliminary screening stage. The stepping stone is just a stepping stone. Next, it depends on whether the job seeker has real ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it should be noted that there is no need for society to over-amplify the halo blessing of the so-called &quot;first degree&quot;. Today, there are so many students graduating from 985 with undergraduate degrees. In the face of the severe employment situation, some Ph.D.s from Peking University have gone to compete for urban management personnel, and some have Ph.D.s from Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine to work as school doctors in middle schools. Undergraduate program 985 really does not have as dazzling aura and powerful blessing as some people imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, objectively speaking, students from undergraduate 985 colleges generally have some advantages in the job market compared to non-985 colleges. This itself also has a reasonable side. If this advantage does not exist, then the motivation for students to work hard to get into a good university may not exist, and there will be no difference between a good university and an average university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, on the surface, students have gained some advantages with the blessing of diplomas from 985 colleges, but the actual logic is the other way around: the ranking of college entrance examination scores and the distinction between prestigious schools and non-prestigious schools are Ranking of students’ intelligence and abilities. In this sense, it is generally the outstanding students who make the 985 colleges and universities successful, not the other way around. Therefore, the 985 diploma has an important signaling function and constitutes an important reference for employers to screen resumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are people with high scores and low abilities, and there are also people with low scores and high abilities; there are people who make mistakes in the college entrance examination, and there are also people who perform exceptionally well in the college entrance examination. However, firstly, it depends on whether it is a high probability or a small probability; secondly, In the end, everyone has to accept the test of the market and the employer. It depends on the real talent and hard work, whether it is a mule or a horse drawn out for a walk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enterprises are profit-making organizations, and they will ultimately look at whether the candidates’ abilities and talents match the company’s employment needs, and whether they can create higher value for the company. The HR and employing departments may take a high look at job seekers with 985 undergraduate degrees, but that’s all. Next, it depends on whether the job seekers’ performance in the interview meets their expectations for talents. Especially in free competition industries, companies have no incentive to leave more capable non-985 undergraduate job seekers and instead use incompetent 985 undergraduate job seekers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there are two people, one has a non-985 degree + 985 graduate school, and the other has a 985 degree + 985 graduate school, and the company does not admit the former but admits the latter, does it become &quot;first degree discrimination&quot;? I&#39;m afraid not so. Job seekers and employers are two-way choices. Reaching a consensus respects the rights of both parties and improves market efficiency. By extension, if job seekers themselves are very capable, but they want to go to a high-paying unit but not to a low-wage unit, does this constitute discrimination against the latter? Even if it is, it is efficiency discrimination and should be justified. Just as when people get married, they would rather find someone with good family conditions than someone with poor conditions. This cannot be said to be discrimination against the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, under the severe employment situation, the key to giving students more and better job opportunities is to inspire entrepreneurs’ confidence and expectations for the future, so that they dare to invest real money Pay attention to expand investment and create more and better jobs. This requires respecting entrepreneurs&#39; autonomy in business operations and employment, and not denying the right of enterprises to &quot;select the best&quot; at every turn and weakening entrepreneurs&#39; motivation and confidence in investing and making bets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If companies are not allowed to show their recruitment preferences, there are only two consequences: First, companies hide their preferences in the short term but write them down in their hearts. This is nothing more than making job seekers do more useless work, which is detrimental to job hunting. Is it really good? Second, in the long run, companies will feel that the business environment and conceptual environment are not good, and they will be more cautious in investing and making bets. The process of job creation will be affected. What benefits will it bring to job seekers? In short, society should create a relaxed and rational conceptual environment for entrepreneurs, allowing them to use their intelligence and real money to promote our economy, which will ultimately benefit every job seeker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:01:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[触碰寻亲直播间里的伤痛 | 记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259121]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 14, 2023, Guiyang, Guizhou, four people searched for relatives The parents drove from Kunming, Yunnan, and traveled thousands of kilometers to find their son. (Southern Weekend reporter Liu Yixian/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Interview with Yang Niuhua’s abduction case (for details, see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com /content/253854&quot;>;Human trafficker Yu Huaying was sentenced to death: she abducted 11 children and even sold her own son&lt;/a>;&quot;), this was the first time I got close to parents looking for relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of July 14, 2023, Yu Huaying, a human trafficker who abducted Yang Niuhua, was tried at the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Guiyang City, Guizhou Province. Outside the court, people looking for relatives stood outside. Parents. Most of them wore white shirts with photos of their babies printed on them, and held missing persons signs with yellow characters on a red background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Looking for his son Li Xianfang&quot;, &quot;Looking for his sons An Xu and An Biao&quot;, &quot;Marshmallow dad looking for his daughter Chen Yangmei&quot;... Each missing person sign is marked with The child’s date of birth, time of loss, physical characteristics at the time of loss, etc. Behind the sign, there were mostly sad faces, as if their facial features were drooped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While waiting, some parents looking for relatives were also doing live broadcasts, introducing netizens to the progress of the trial and what was going on outside the court, interspersed with &lt;span>;&lt; /span>;Tell how your child was lost, where you went to find your child, and how you got here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I greeted several of the parents, informed the reporter of my identity, and recorded an interview video nearby. After that, as soon as I raised my cell phone to record the video, the parents next to me immediately came up to me, walked around holding the missing persons sign, and occasionally chatted. They know how to &quot;grab traffic&quot; and show their face at any possible opportunity to increase their exposure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This eagerness became more obvious after Yang Niuhua appeared. Parents looking for relatives swarmed up almost in a swarm, surrounding them from front to back, holding signs next to each other. Several times, Yang Niuhua was submerged in the family-seeking signs, and reporters could not find her at all. In the chaos, some parents thrust their missing persons tags into Yang Niuhua&#39;s hands, while others hung a backpack with missing family information on her body. Yang Niuhua understood the mood of these parents looking for relatives and did not refuse. These parents travel around all year round and appear in various hot scenes, striving to let their children see themselves and see that &quot;Mom and Dad are always looking for you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of the day when the trial ended, I knocked on the door of Yang Niuhua’s room, but I was surprised to find that the room was crowded with parents looking for relatives, on the beds and chairs. , the floor, and every corner were filled with people. They are all waiting in line to go to Yang Niuhua&#39;s live broadcast room to introduce their search for relatives. After Yang Niuhua successfully searched for relatives online in 2021, she attracted a lot of attention and accumulated more than 300,000 fans on the short video platform. On important days like court hearings, she is also willing to use her traffic to allow parents to go to the live broadcast room to spread information about finding relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I sat down next to an aunt in her 50s and watched the live broadcast of people coming and going in the room. It was still mid-summer in July, and this aunt was wearing a long-sleeved pullover with her child’s information printed on it, and several pieces of clothing underneath. After some conversation, she said that she was from the Buyi ethnic group in Guizhou and was born with a disability in her left foot, making it difficult for her to walk long distances. But her husband was ill and bedridden, so she had no choice but to go out alone to find the child. As she spoke, she took off her left boot, revealing that the foot was deformed and looked unbearable. It’s hard to imagine how she followed the family search team to various places in Fujian and Guizhou these days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is another &quot;marshmallow dad&quot; who impressed me deeply. His daughter was born in 2003 and disappeared in Kunming, Yunnan when she was 3 years old. When Yang Niuhua was being interviewed after the trial, he stood behind Yang Niuhua and suddenly cried uncontrollably. The sound got louder and louder, and finally he squatted on the ground and cried bitterly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For many years, &quot;Marshmallow Daddy&quot; has been doing business in a minivan, selling marshmallows while looking for children, while his wife sells balloons at home to support her life. On the homepage of &quot;Marshmallow Daddy&quot;&#39;s video account, he has been to multiple recognition sites where his family search was successful. The village supermarket in Rongjiang, Guizhou was a hot spot those days. He rushed to the village supermarket to look for his children. In order to save money, the four parents who were looking for relatives cooked their own meals along the way, setting up stoves and shelves in the open air to cook. The four of them spent more than 20 yuan a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finding relatives is difficult, and parents searching for relatives hate human traffickers. But they have different views on adoptive families. Some people support the same crime of buying and selling and believe that the person responsible for supporting the family should be held accountable. But more parents will emphasize that they just want to see their children, and they do not ask the children to return to their biological families, nor do they hold them responsible for supporting the family. A very important reason is that many abducted children are afraid of hurting the feelings of their adoptive parents and are unwilling to take the initiative to find relatives, which will increase the difficulty of finding relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Yu Huaying&#39;s child abduction case, there are still several abducted children who are unwilling to formally recognize their relatives. They are trapped in complex family relationships and do not know what to do. There are also abducted children who have recognized their parents and are not close to their parents. The parent-child relationship is empty and it is not clear where to build it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the family search live broadcast room, parents called on their children who had doubts about their parentage to go to the public security bureau to collect blood and enter it into the family search database, so that one day they can successfully identify their relatives. , &quot;If you want to come back, come back. If you don&#39;t want to come back, you can stay and support your family.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;This sentence may be full of pain and pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I wish them an early reunion with their loved ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[睡眠保单规模有多大？如何常态化唤醒？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259165]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Sleep policies are being required to be cleared within a time limit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration recently issued a special notice to clean up “sleep policies” in personal insurance within a time limit. According to the notice, for &quot;sleep insurance policies&quot; generated between January 1, 2013 and June 30, 2023, special cleanup work will last for one year starting from October 2023. According to research conducted by researchers at the New Financial Research Center of Southern Weekend, various life insurance companies have begun to look for “owners” of “sleep policies”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are there sleep insurance policies in China? How will the rights and interests of policyholders be guaranteed? What is the overseas experience in dealing with sleep policies? After studying overseas experience, researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Financial Research Center believe that the cleanup of sleep policies cannot only rely on irregular supervision by regulatory agencies, but should establish an easy-to-check national system, and insurance companies should proactively disclose the status of sleep policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; a “sleep policy”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is a &quot;sleep policy&quot;? Wang Xiangnan, deputy director of the Insurance and Social Security Research Office of the Institute of Finance, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, told a researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center that &quot;sleep insurance policy&quot; is not clearly defined. It generally refers to an insurance accident or an insurance contract that has expired but has not yet received compensation or Insurance benefits are paid upon maturity, and policies in which the validity of the insurance contract is suspended or terminated but the cash value has not yet been collected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that a similar concept abroad is &quot;unclaimed life insurance&quot;. Allstate Insurance Company (Allstate) specifically refers to the situation where the insured dies and the beneficiary fails to apply for insurance compensation. According to the U.S. government website, the United States combines unclaimed insurance income and unpaid wages, pensions, tax refunds, fund income, bond income, etc. into unclaimed funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In layman&#39;s terms, the &quot;sleeping policies&quot; that the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau requires to be cleaned up within a time limit this time are the policy owners who &quot;lost contact&quot; resulting in the policy being &quot;not claimed but not claimed&quot; and eventually being &quot;shelved&quot; by the insurance company. &quot;Insurance policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Sleep Policy&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Why did it come about&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why did sleep insurance policies come into being? A partner at Beijing Datong Insurance Sales Company told researchers at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center that there are many reasons why policy owners “lost contact”. For example, in some families, the elders bought an annuity without notifying their families, and before they could receive it, the elders passed away. This will result in no one applying for a claim; some consumers have purchased insurance, but due to changing contact information, interruption of payment, etc., the policy has expired, and they have forgotten about it and did not return the cash; many families do not keep and manage the insurance policies properly. , family members are unaware of each other’s policy holdings. It is generally difficult for insurance companies to process such policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also learned that orphan policies are also one of the reasons for the creation of sleep policies. &lt;span>;Orphan&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Insurance&lt;/span>; only refers to &lt;span>;policies&lt;/span>; where no one has taken the initiative to provide follow-up services due to the resignation of the original marketing staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the reasons for domestic sleep insurance policies, foreign sleep insurance policies are also mostly caused by the &quot;loss of contact&quot; of policyholders for various reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For policyholders, &quot;sleep policy&quot; means a &quot;sleep fund&quot; or an &quot;insurance window period.&quot; The former corresponds to the situation where the insured has matured survival benefits and maturity benefits that have not been collected; while the latter occurs when the policy is suspended due to &quot;loss of contact&quot; and arrears. This means that the insurance company has the right to terminate the insurance contract. Based on this, this special cleanup operation organized by the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration can not only revitalize the &quot;idle funds&quot; sleeping in society, but also safeguard the rights and interests of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How big are sleep policies&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The regulatory agency specifically issued a notice to clean up &quot;sleep insurance policies&quot; within a time limit. This means that the &quot;sleep policy&quot; cannot be ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How big is the &quot;sleep policy&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from Southern Weekend’s New Financial Research Center found that, so far, regulatory authorities have not released nationwide statistics. One data that can be referenced is that in August 2014, the former China Insurance Regulatory Commission issued a notice that “all personal insurance issued after June 10, 1999 and effective as of 24:00 on June 30, 2014, with a payment period of more than one year shall be invalid.” &quot;Policies&quot; carried out a special cleanup, and a total of 18.5793 million lapsed personal insurance policies were found, with a cash value of 35.083 billion yuan. The &quot;lapsed personal insurance policies&quot; targeted by this special cleanup operation specifically refer to policies whose contract validity is suspended due to interruption of insurance payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sleep policy&quot; includes more than just &quot;life insurance lapse policy&quot;. It can be seen from this that the amount involved in sleep insurance policies should also be larger. Data from various places can serve as examples. Data disclosed by the Anhui Insurance Association shows that as of June 30, 2023, the number of unpaid survival insurance policies that Anhui personal insurance companies should receive is 77,900, involving an amount of 920 million yuan; according to China Banking and Insurance News, in 2022 In 2020, 40 personal insurance companies in Zhejiang carried out the &quot;Looking for Insurance Survival Benefit Recipients&quot; activity. As of December 31, 2020, Zhejiang (excluding Ningbo) had a total of 121,300 expired personal insurance policies with an amount of 779 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from different insurance companies also show that sleep insurance is no small matter. Ping An Pension Insurance Zhejiang Branch recovered 140 million yuan in &quot;maturity survival funds&quot; for customers from April to August 2022. Xinhua Life official said that from 2021 to the present, Xinhua Insurance Zhejiang Branch has carried out activities to find survival allowance recipients. By visiting village committees and communities, seeking to find &quot;lost&quot; customers from bill-issuing banks, police stations, household registration centers, etc., a total of We recovered 2,193 &quot;lost&quot; customers, assisted them in the collection procedures, and paid 90.46 million yuan in survival benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Financial reports are not disclosed separately&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How motivated are insurance companies to clean up sleep policies? Is the &quot;sleep money&quot; lying on the account a windfall for insurance companies? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center checked the financial reports of listed insurance companies and found that each company did not disclose this separately. This means that companies treat this as a normal insurance policy in their financial reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior official from a listed insurance company confirmed in a survey by a researcher from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center that from the insurance business side, insurance companies do not distinguish between &quot;sleep policies&quot; and &quot;sleep policies&quot; in their financial statements. Normal policy. &quot;Sleep insurance policies&quot; follow the same accounting standards as other insurance policies. For example, premium income is included in asset accounts, and insurance liability reserves are included in the &quot;withdrawal of insurance liability reserves&quot; account based on actuarially determined amounts. The reserve withdrawal ratio has many rules according to the type of insurance and reserve type, and the conditions of each insurance company are different. Coupled with factors such as long coverage periods and diverse policy statuses, “sleep policy” cleanup is a complex undertaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A partner at another insurance sales company even said that insurance companies may not have the incentive to clean up sleep policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to wake up the &quot;sleep policy&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to apply for a wake-up sleep policy overseas? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Securities Times reported in May 2020 that no one claims millions of dollars in life insurance rights every year in the United States. In 2023, the website of the Association of British Insurers quoted sources as conservatively estimating that forgotten and unclaimed insurance policies across the UK are expected to involve a total of 200 million pounds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that in the United States, consumers can either log in to the National Association of Insurance Regulators (NAIC) system to inquire, or they can find third-party agencies to help with inquiries. According to the American Family Life Insurance Company (Aflac) website, different states in the United States have different legal requirements for unclaimed insurance policies. In many cases, beneficiary retroactive policies have no time limit, and once a beneficiary submits the policy, the insurance company takes a few weeks to a month to process and pay out. In addition to receiving insurance benefits, beneficiaries can also receive part of the interest income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in order to cooperate with the cleanup of &quot;sleep insurance policies&quot;, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau also guided relevant agencies to research and establish a unified &quot;sleep insurance policy&quot; information inquiry platform for consumers to inquire independently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that the cleanup of sleep insurance policies cannot only rely on irregular supervision by regulatory agencies. In addition to establishing a national unified policy query system as soon as possible, regulatory authorities and industry associations should require insurance companies Put reminders for policyholders at the forefront. At the same time, insurance companies should use financial technology to enable the tracking of sleep policies, and even use big data systems to check all policies once a year to achieve normalized wake-ups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新任中国足协主席宋凯：不能再出台“奇葩”政策]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259155]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the 22nd, the new Chinese Football Association Chairman Song Kai came to Weifang, Shandong to watch the second China Youth Football League Men’s U15 finals , and held discussions with youth training and media representatives. This was his first public appearance as chairman of the Football Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the work ideas of the new Chinese Football Association, Song Kai said that Chinese football must make up its mind to follow the &quot;Long March Road&quot; in the future, regard youth training as a top priority, and also improve China&#39;s football through greater opening up. football competitiveness and ensuring that the policies of the Chinese Football Association are reasonable and stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4c31a52c7e5b9847bbfb84f41cf49701.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4c31a52c7e5b9847bbfb84f41cf49701.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255015&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chinese Football Association Chairman Song Kai (middle) and Chinese Football Association Vice Chairman Yuan Yongqing (right) and Xu Jiren at a media symposium&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Make youth training a top priority Come and catch us.”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first stop after taking office was to inspect youth competitions. The message Song Kai wanted to convey was very clear: “If we want to revitalize football, we must first focus on youth training. In the future, the Chinese Football Association will make youth training a top priority. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Kai said that on the one hand, high-level coaches should be encouraged to engage in youth training. &quot;Poor competitive performance first shows that training is not good. We do not have good coaches for youth training, and the salary of youth training coaches is indeed very different from that of professional teams. This is a real problem that needs to be gradually changed. The Chinese Football Association must strive to adopt policy regulations and Orientation, guiding the best coaches to focus on youth training.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, a high-level and stable youth competition system must be established. &quot;When they are 12 years old, Chinese players are at the same level as Japanese and Korean players, but by the age of 16, the gap is huge. This is mainly due to the gap in the competition system. Only by participating in more high-level competitions can players continue to grow. The problem with our competition system is that it is unstable , the youth competition system must remain stable and reasonable improvements can be made, but the overall framework must remain unchanged.&quot; Song Kai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c238d83b720e76683a63f3053a1db926.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c238d83b720e76683a63f3053a1db926.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255014&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(File picture) Young players playing on the court. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhou Mi&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talking about what kind of youth training model Chinese football should adopt, Song Kai said: &quot;Currently, Chinese football youth training mainly includes professional clubs, professional sports teams, social institutions and campus football. Waiting for different routes, the Chinese Football Association must first consolidate its base areas and defend its basic market. It is unrealistic for Chinese football to completely return to the sports team model, but the policy guidance of the National Games can be used to increase the enthusiasm of provinces and cities and increase their commitment to football. support,&quot; Song Kai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the basis of insisting on practicing internal skills, Song Kai believes that the development of youth training also requires the help of external forces. &quot;With the help of external forces, including inviting in, going out and naturalizing players, this can all be discussed. There is a gap between our understanding of youth training and that of developed countries in football, so we must learn with an open mind. The internationalization of youth training is very important. According to statistics, China is now There are 137 registered foreign teachers. In the future, we will continue to improve the internationalization of youth training coaches. Youth leagues can also consider relaxing nationality restrictions and increasing exchange opportunities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1f2957ee55bb560399fe419d8ecd75e9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/23/1f2957ee55bb560399fe419d8ecd75e9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255016&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 8, East AFC U15 Men&#39;s Football Championship, the Chinese team celebrated their victory at the award ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Ziheng&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the East Asian Football Confederation U15 Men’s Football Championship held in September this year, the Chinese team defeated the Japanese team to win the championship. Song Kai said: &quot;The U15 players do give us some hope. By the 2034 World Cup, they will be in their prime. We must do a good job in this age group. All parties have suggested applying for the World Youth Championship and the World Youth Championship. The Chinese Football Association is currently considering it, and we are also discussing this matter with FIFA.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Chinese football will not work if it does not open up&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In his inaugural speech on the 16th, Song Kaiti To topics such as &quot;more openness&quot; and &quot;connecting with the AFC and relaxing restrictions on foreign aid&quot;. At this media symposium, Song Kai explained that he hopes to force Chinese football to improve its competitiveness through wider opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Kai believes that Chinese football has been in a relatively closed environment for a long time, and players lack competition. &quot;Many industries have proven that only with full competition in an open market can low-cost and high-quality products be produced. Now the AFC is relaxing restrictions on foreign aid. The Saudi League plans to increase the number of foreign aid quotas for each team to 10. Others Everything is opening up, and Chinese football cannot do without opening up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The long march of Chinese football requires players to walk together. How to let the players go on the long march? Education alone is not enough, but competition and a high elimination rate are also required . By expanding opening up, we will force Chinese players to improve their level in competition.&quot; Song Kai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/2f5472dd47520d8bf451e2f807ca9892.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/2f5472dd47520d8bf451e2f807ca9892.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For wider opening up This may lead to domestic players not being able to play football, and thus affecting the national team. Song Kai said frankly: &quot;Many national leagues, including Spain, relaxed their foreign aid policies, which caused great controversy in the country at the time. In the process of expanding the opening up of Chinese football, , there will definitely be pain, and the Chinese Football Association must remain determined. If domestic players cannot play in the Chinese Super League, they can go to lower-level leagues. The policy can only be more open and cannot go back.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Kai At the same time, he said that the Chinese Football Association must move at a steady pace in expanding its opening up. &quot;We must not rush to introduce policies. We must use one year for all parties to fully discuss, think things over clearly, and then implement them step by step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The Chinese Football Association cannot introduce any more &#39;weird&#39; policies. Policy&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Song Kai said frankly that many policies of the Chinese Football Association were previously formulated haphazardly, which caused harm to the development of Chinese football. &quot;The Chinese Football Association can no longer introduce &#39;weird&#39; policies like the &#39;National Team League&#39; and &#39;U23 Player Policy&#39; in the future. If the Chinese Football Association wants to issue new policies, they must meet social expectations. This is the first bottom line during my term. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The new Chinese Football Association will establish smoother communication channels and communication mechanisms with the media. The truth will become clearer and clearer. We hope that the media will take the lead in discussing the future policies of the Chinese Football Association. We will not issue all A policy that no one agrees with,&quot; Song Kai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/0630b7d37b470fe1489dbc794328769d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/0630b7d37b470fe1489dbc794328769d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;July 18 On the same day, the Chinese women&#39;s football team trained at the 2023 Women&#39;s World Cup Chinese Women&#39;s Football Base Camp at the Croatian Sports Center in Adelaide, Australia. The picture shows Chinese women&#39;s football players Wang Shuang (left) and Zhang Xin training. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Yibo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the development of the national team, Song Kai said that the Chinese Football Association will adhere to the combination of &quot;working for a long time&quot; and &quot;seizing the day&quot;, and try to improve the team as much as possible while focusing on long-term development. Management and construction level. &quot;Although it is useless to worry about the national team, we must build the national team well at the current level. If the team is well managed, it may be able to perform at 120%, but if it is not managed well, it can only perform at 60%. % level.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese women&#39;s football team will usher in the Paris Olympic qualifiers at the end of this month, and the Chinese men&#39;s football team will participate in the 2026 US-Canada-Mexico World Cup Asian qualifiers in mid-November. Regarding these two key competition tasks, Song Kai said: &quot;We have recently strengthened the management of the Chinese women&#39;s football team, and have also recalled overseas players. The Chinese women&#39;s football team is competitive in Asia, and we must win the Olympic qualifiers. Good. Everyone is not very satisfied with the current situation of the Chinese men&#39;s football team. Although they beat the Vietnam team, their technical content was not high, and then they lost to the Uzbekistan team. I think Jankovic is a very good coach, and the coaching staff needs to sum up their experience. Lessons learned. We must work harder.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[视频小作文与泛道德批判：真的有助于社会道德风尚的提升吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259108]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some time ago, &quot;netizens posted a video reporting that a woman had accompanied her leader to drink and lie drunk on the street many times&quot;, which triggered a large number of onlookers and Hot discussion, many people have seen it, many people immediately established such a &quot;mental position&quot;: This thing seems to be untrue, and emotions such as contempt or anger suddenly surged, and then they put the matter aside Go aside and rush to the next hot spot that is real or seems real, and you are filled with the same sense of justice or righteous indignation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on October 6, Tai’an High-tech Industrial Development Zone in Shandong Province issued an investigation report on this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is ironic is that in the so-called &quot;report video&quot;, the video shooter claimed that Zhang, a member of the Party Working Committee and Deputy Director of the Management Committee of Tai&#39;an New District, had an improper relationship with the woman. In fact, Zhang There is no such relationship with the woman (Xu), but the person who has a male-female relationship with Xu is precisely the person who shot and posted the video, Meng. The married man Meng had a relationship with the unmarried woman Xu during the relationship. Because of an emotional dispute, he created a related video through grafting and malicious editing and published it on a certain platform, in order to &quot;retaliate&quot; against the other party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng released a video containing false information and insulted and slandered others, which is obviously an illegal act that blatantly infringes on the reputation rights of others. If this is regarded as a report, then it is undoubtedly a malicious and false accusation. . The matter is far from that simple. The investigation showed that although Zhang and Xu, who both worked in the high-tech development zone, did not have an improper relationship between men and women as mentioned in the &quot;report video&quot;, they had the problem of accepting corporate banquets in violation of regulations. It is this situation that has caused differences of opinion among netizens who have been paying attention to the incident. Some netizens believe that although Zhang and Xu have other problems, &quot;one code to one code&quot; cannot change the illegal fact that Meng has violated the reputation rights of others. Other netizens believe that although the &quot;report&quot; of the video publisher Meng was untrue, it uncovered other problems. If Meng is held accountable, potential whistleblowers like this will be discouraged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This debate actually contains a rather profound social moral issue, that is, the encouragement of &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; and &quot;low-cost reporting&quot; will really help to form a clean and upright society. Environment? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pan-moral criticism&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pan-moral criticism&quot; is a very popular criticism method in the Internet era. Critics often moralize all personal grievances and social phenomena and use &quot;public opinion&quot; to moralize them. &quot;In the name of &quot;justice&quot;, they gain the moral high ground and condescendingly carry out absolute moral criticism of the target of attack. Critics often use &quot;group labels&quot; to project a certain stereotype of the public on the specific parties involved in the incident, deliberately disrupting the public&#39;s judgment of the basic facts of the incident, and then leading the public to attack the parties in order to achieve the moral integrity of the parties. &quot;social death&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Precisely because &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; can often occupy the moral high ground in the name of public opinion, after successfully arousing public sentiment, the critic himself obtains a certain kind of &quot;moral golden body&quot;, even if he himself Even if there are major moral flaws, they can often be exempted from questioning and accountability under the banner of &quot;justice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the aforementioned incident, the video publisher Meng apparently used identity labels such as &quot;leader&quot; and &quot;official&quot; to &quot;label&quot; the parties involved, Xu and Zhang, and then led the public to label &quot;corruption&quot; This impression was projected onto Xu and Zhang, disrupting the public&#39;s attention and judgment on the fact itself &quot;whether Zhang and Xu had an improper relationship between men and women,&quot; and ultimately achieved the goal of &quot;discrediting&quot; Zhang and Xu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that this farce of &quot;exposure&quot; and &quot;reporting&quot; directed and performed by Meng is a standard &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot;. Meng himself has moral problems, but he dares to make up unbridled stories. In fact, to conduct &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; of others is to believe that once one occupies the high ground of &quot;justice&quot;, one has the privilege of unilaterally criticizing others without any moral questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral sense is a social ideology that embodies the public’s pursuit of social fairness and justice. The purpose of moral criticism is to praise the beautiful and belittle the ugly, punish the evil and promote the good at the moral level, and then promote the social morality. improvement. However, this is not the case with &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot;. There are many grotesques and farces in which moral depravity stands on the high ground of &quot;justice&quot; and criticizes the moral depravity of others. &quot;Pan-moral criticism&quot; not only fails to promote the improvement of social morality, but also allows speculators to run rampant on the Internet, which not only causes the focus of public opinion supervision, but also creates a society where &quot;ruling the virtuous with no virtue&quot; Moral regression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said unceremoniously that &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; is the alienation and distortion of &quot;moral criticism&quot;. Therefore, in a society, if the public is generally keen on &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; and cannot extricate themselves, it will not only fail to improve social morality, but will lead to the regression and collapse of social morality. Netizens who believe that Meng&#39;s unjust behavior has a &quot;just&quot; result and therefore should not be punished or should be given a lighter punishment have actually been subtly influenced by Meng&#39;s &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; trap. And unconsciously accepted such an alienated network morality. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Low-cost reporting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot;, there is another problem in the incident of &quot;netizens posting videos to report that the woman had accompanied the leader to drink and lie drunk on the street many times&quot;: we Whether the society accepts &quot;video exposure&quot; as a low-cost &quot;reporting&quot; method? If this &quot;reporting&quot; method is established, should it be the same as other reporting channels, requiring the reporter to bear the corresponding responsibilities and consequences arising from the untrue content of the report? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty in defining whether &quot;video exposure&quot; behavior meets the definition of &quot;reporting&quot; is that it is not a point-to-point one-way transmission relationship between the whistleblower and the accepting agency like the traditional reporting method. Instead, they often start with a &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; and ferment into public opinion on the Internet platform, forcing relevant departments to investigate. What ultimately responds to problems is often not the traditional petition and disciplinary inspection and supervision mechanisms, but the public opinion handling mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This leads to a series of problems. First of all, because this method of &quot;reporting&quot; is not a traditional channel, it is difficult to be constrained and restricted by various regulations. Even if there are legal consequences, it is often punished for &quot;releasing false information to disrupt social and public order&quot;, and Their &quot;false accusations&quot; are difficult to pursue, which makes it possible for them to exploit loopholes in the system and corrupt the social atmosphere by evading the most important and minimizing the minor, writing essays and videos that are both true and false. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this kind of &quot;forced reporting&quot; that uses the public opinion handling mechanism conducts a moral trial on the parties in advance before the relevant departments investigate, forming invisible pressure from public opinion to interfere with the investigation. Once the investigation is carried out, The results are inconsistent with the results of the moral trial, which can easily lead to public doubts and criticism of the investigation department and damage the credibility of the relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, once those with ulterior motives find that this reporting method is more &quot;effective&quot; than traditional channels, then the mentality of &quot;let the matter go unnoticed and someone else will take care of it&quot; will inevitably spread. Trivial matters in daily life and personal grievances rise to the level of morality, and then publicity and hype form online public opinions, which in turn force relevant departments to come forward to &quot;solve&quot; the problem. There will inevitably be more and more phenomena, and a large amount of social resources are forced to invest in endless meaningless investigations. In itself, it is a huge internal friction for society. It was just an accident that Meng’s false accusation was finally revealed. Our tireless pursuit of social fairness and justice must not rely on the false accusations of online accusers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 22:25:17 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大账高企小账不绝  银保业务何以常年畸形？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259167]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As the channel business that contributes the largest premium to insurance companies, bancassurance is facing a new round of high pressure from regulations and new policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, Liu Sheng, the person in charge of the personal insurance supervision work of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, said that the regulatory authorities will consistently do a good job in the work of &quot;unifying reporting and banking&quot;; insist on catching up early and small , grasp the typical cases, continue to strictly supervise and strengthen accountability, rectify industry chaos, and effectively safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of insurance consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 22, the Personal Insurance Department of the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration issued the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products through Bank Agency Channels&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;) to all personal insurance companies, requiring all When filing products, insurance companies should clearly state the cost assumptions and fee structure in the product actuarial report, and list the commission ceiling; each insurance company should truthfully list the commission rates paid to the bank, and the actual fees such as commissions should be compared with the filing materials. Stay consistent, that is, &quot;unity of reward and action.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of the &quot;Notice&quot;, the Shanghai Insurance Association has issued an industry self-discipline convention. Following the Notice, insurance industry associations in Guangdong and other places also issued a self-discipline convention for bancassurance business. Self-regulatory conventions in various places target stubborn problems such as high fees and disorderly competition in bancassurance channels, and strictly prohibit vicious price competition, commercial bribery and other illegal activities that disrupt the order of the bancassurance market. We promise not to covertly increase bancassurance business fees through other channels and methods, and resolutely put an end to small accounts in bancassurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the pressure of supervision, it is imperative to reduce bank insurance fees. But why does the bancassurance business always suffer from the chronic industry problem of high large accounts and constant small accounts? It seems to be getting more and more popular as it becomes more banned. As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand any benefits other than those agreed in the agreement in any way from insurance companies and their personnel.&quot; Under this round of high pressure, will the chaos in the banking and insurance channels end? Will the bank insurance premium rate difference that plagues insurance companies turn into a fee difference from now on? How do bancassurance alliances develop internationally? What are some lessons worth learning from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center reviewed the development history of bancassurance at home and abroad, and used horizontal comparative research methods to find that the root cause of the &quot;big and small account problem&quot; lies in the profit distribution mechanism caused by the loose cooperation between insurance and banks. imbalance. Under this cooperation model, banks are driven by unilateral profits, and the overall business falls into a dilemma of incremental growth but no efficiency gain. Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center also visited different bank outlets as policyholders and conducted unannounced visits and found that the professionalism of bancassurance sales staff needs to be improved. Only when banks and bank employees transfer their focus on sales fees to professionalism will bank cooperation enter a new stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The stubborn problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank insurance refers to a business model in which banks mainly sell insurance on their behalf. Together with personal agents and group insurance, it constitutes the main sales channel of insurance companies. Bancassurance is the core business of life insurance companies and the leading business of many small and medium-sized companies. In order to compete for premiums,&amp;nbsp;many small and medium-sized insurance companies have always maintained high-priced large accounts and various forms of small accounts, and many large companies have been passively involved in price wars. This is what the industry calls &quot;big and small accounts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;big and small accounts&quot;? The &quot;big account&quot; refers to the handling fee agreed in the written contract between the insurance company and the bank, which is the bank&#39;s official income from the agency sales of insurance; the &quot;small account&quot; refers to the sales incentives privately given by the insurance company to bank staff, in various forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2019, when talking about strict management of violations of regulations and disciplines at an internal meeting, the president of a joint-stock bank said that the one thing he could not tolerate the most was employees receiving kickbacks from insurance companies. In fact, regulatory agencies have also cracked down on small accounting issues many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand from insurance companies and their personnel in any way other than what is agreed in the agreement.&quot; any benefit”. Over the past few years, rectification has continued, but no significant results have been achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Big accounts are high, small accounts are endless&quot; Why does it become a chronic disease? On the surface, the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is due to the strong position of banks and bancassurance cooperation due to their huge channels and strong customer resources. However, the root cause is that the interest distribution mechanism under the short-term and loose cooperation model between banks and insurance companies is insufficient. Reasonably caused. Banking and insurance are independent entities and there is no basis for equal cooperation between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reasons for the strong position of banks are complicated, but in the financial market structure dominated by banks, it does not necessarily lead to the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;. For example, in Europe, where the bancassurance business originated, in countries such as France and Italy, the bancassurance business not only accounts for a high proportion, but also makes a large contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is related to my country’s bancassurance cooperation model. Except for bank insurance companies and some giant insurance companies, the cooperation model between most banks and insurance companies is a &quot;many-to-many&quot; distribution agency model, that is, banks sign distribution agreements with insurance companies, and banks sell insurance through agency insurance companies. Products earn fees and commission income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this model, the determination of business philosophy, development of bancassurance products and insurance claims settlement are all undertaken by the insurance company, and both bancassurance and bancassurance parties only carry out superficial cooperation based on channel-level factors such as marketing channels and customer resources. cooperation. From the perspective of contract theory, it is essentially a simple principal-agent relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, outside the bank, the insurance company serves as the principal and the bank acts as the agent. The two define each other&#39;s rights, obligations and interest distribution methods by signing a cooperation agreement. The main incentive mechanism of the contract is that the bank earns handling fees from the bancassurance agency business, while the insurer transfers part of the benefits in exchange for rapid expansion of premium income, thus forming the first level of entrustment-agency between the bank and the insurance company. relation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within the bank, sales tasks are distributed layer by layer in the order of head office - branch branches - outlets, and the products are ultimately sold directly by bancassurance specialists at each outlet. According to the &quot;About Further Strengthening the Compliance of Commercial Banks&#39; Agency Insurance Business&quot; &quot;Notice on Sales and Risk Management&quot; stipulates that commercial banks shall not allow insurance company personnel to be stationed in bank branches. Therefore, relevant personnel of the insurance company can only supervise and assist bancassurance sales in the form of patrol points. A second principal-agent relationship is formed between the bank and its employees based on the sales of bancassurance products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the sales intensity of sinking channels determines the amount of premiums to a large extent. Moreover, because of the existence of a double principal-agent relationship, the two parties have conflicting goals. Specifically, banks tend to sell single payment or short-term regular payment insurance products with high commission rates, simple terms and simple benefit demonstrations. As for the compatibility between customers and products, agents are not particularly concerned. However, regular payment insurance with long payment period and comprehensive protection functions is the type of insurance that insurance companies hope to sell because of its high intrinsic value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, insurance companies compete fiercely for banking channels. The &quot;Measures for the Administration of Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; promulgated in 2019 (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;) stipulates that each branch of a commercial bank can only cooperate with no more than 3 insurance companies in the insurance agency business in the same fiscal year, that is, &quot;1+ 3&quot; mode. The quality and configuration of banks’ sinking channels have become the focus of competition among insurance companies. Therefore, the Measures have to a certain extent intensified competition among insurance companies for banks’ high-quality channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of serious product homogeneity, large accounts and small accounts have become an alternative competitive weapon. Liu Sheng commented that in recent years, the personal insurance industry has experienced severe homogeneous competition, and insurance companies generally have extensive expense management, resulting in actual expenses exceeding the level at the time of product filing, resulting in &quot;inconsistent reporting&quot;. High fees not only disrupt the market order, but are also the root cause of problems such as false fees, false insurance applications, and false surrenders. They are also the breeding ground for &quot;black agency products&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To what extent are bancassurance channel fees exaggerated? Liu Sheng revealed that as of October 20, the vast majority of banks carrying out bancassurance business have re-signed contracts with insurance companies in accordance with the requirements of &quot;unification of banks and banks&quot;. Preliminary estimates show that the commission rate for the bancassurance channel has dropped by about 30% compared with the previous average level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the results of the competition between &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the fragmentation of market share. According to statistics from Guolian Securities, judging from the scale of bancassurance channel premiums of personal insurance companies, the market share of the top ten companies in bancassurance channel premiums has dropped from 59.9% in 2017 to 52.1% in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Due to the intertwining of various reasons, the bancassurance channel has formed a status quo of &quot;high cost and low value&quot;. The bancassurance channel is also one of the channels where policyholders complain more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the intersection of history and reality, and is the product of the extensive development of the insurance industry in the past. In recent years, the insurance industry has received great attention in supporting economic and social development, and regulatory authorities have promoted deepening reforms in multiple key areas, including comprehensive system construction and core areas such as corporate governance, solvency, capital utilization, and consumer rights protection. The &quot;Notice&quot; releases a signal of reform, which will curb the industry&#39;s &quot;big and small accounts&quot; problem to a certain extent. However, whether the stubborn problem of &quot;big accounts, high prices, small accounts, and constant supply&quot; can be completely eradicated still depends on industry self-discipline, deepening cooperation between banks and insurance companies, and improving long-term incentive mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Change&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Window period&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why are the temporary management agencies stepping up their efforts to rectify the bancassurance business at this time? A researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that the insurance industry has undergone major changes under the new situation, and this is a window period for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the insurance industry is concerned, the agent team continues to shrink, and the growth rate of original premium income of the personal insurance industry is hovering at a low level. In 2022, the personal insurance industry will continue to be under pressure and enter a period of deep adjustment. That year, the original premium income of life insurance was 2.45 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 4%, accounting for 71.6% of personal insurance premiums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the public’s awareness of social security is gradually increasing The trend of aging and social aging still creates demand space for the development of the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of consumer behavior, insurance consumption has changed from &quot;should I buy it&quot; to &quot;is it good or not.&quot; The &quot;2022 China Internet Insurance Consumer Insight Report&quot; shows that consumers aged 31-40, mainly those born in the 1980s, spend more on insurance, and 75% of households spend more than 5,000 yuan on annual insurance. It can be seen that young consumers’ awareness of insurance and willingness to pay have increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an operational perspective, some small and medium-sized insurance companies have relatively aggressive product pricing strategies, and some products have risks of long-term insurance and short-term insurance. At the same time, in the context of declining long-term interest rates and declining corporate investment yields, incremental whole life insurance with the function of locking long-term interest rates will expose insurance companies to the risk of spread losses. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the life insurance version of “interest rate cuts” has been implemented. Supervision has clearly provided window guidance. Before the end of July 2023, the predetermined interest rates for new personal insurance products will be adjusted. After dealing with the interest rate loss in the short term, how to solve the fee difference loss has become increasingly urgent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of bancassurance channels is a key measure to alleviate fee differences. What conditions are met for channel purification at this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found through statistics and comparison that as of the end of 2022, the total number of agents of Ping An, China Life, China Pacific Insurance and New China Insurance was 1.59 million, down from 1.64 million in 2010 Thousands of people. The efficiency-improving reform of personal agency channels continues to show no significant results. At the same time, since 2020, major domestic listed insurance companies have been actively developing bancassurance channels, promoting the strategic transformation of &quot;new bancassurance&quot;, and have introduced a series of measures to strengthen the depth of cooperation with banks, hoping to achieve Growth in scale and value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Ping An Life as an example, financial report data shows that, From 2019 to 2022, the growth rate of new policy premiums in the bancassurance channel was as high as 19.1%, significantly ahead of the individual insurance channel and other channels. The premium growth rates of the two during the same period were -10.1% and -7.5% respectively. The proportion of the company&#39;s new premiums increased from 4.2% in 2019 to 9.2% in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This also shows that the agent channel that can best bring high intrinsic value policies to life insurance companies is still being adjusted. However, small and medium-sized insurance companies are basically unable to cultivate a large-scale agent team. In other words, the importance of the bancassurance channel has increased, highlighting the need for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks are also facing performance pressure. In a situation where interest spreads have shrunk, wealth management products have been depleted and trust products have become scarce, the agency insurance business has become a performance highlight. Take China Merchants Bank as an example. In 2022, China Merchants Bank&#39;s fund agency business revenue dropped by 46.4% year-on-year, and its proportion of non-interest income also dropped from the highest value of 13.0% in 2015 to 6.6%, while insurance agency sales revenue has remained at around 50% for two consecutive years. positive growth, and its proportion in non-interest income also increased significantly to 11.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;974&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the depth of both banks and insurance companies The window period for cooperation has arrived, and regulatory agencies and associations have the “right time, favorable location, and harmonious relationship” to crack down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that from the perspective of insurance companies’ profit models, among the “three differences”, death and fee differences account for relatively small proportions. The &quot;Notice&quot; aims to standardize sales expenses and prevent unfair competition. It is one of the important measures to standardize insurance sales behavior in a multi-dimensional and systematic manner. Following the &quot;Notice&quot;, the &quot;Insurance Sales Behavior Management Measures&quot; recently issued by the State Administration of Financial Supervision will be implemented from March 1, 2024. The &quot;Measures&quot; echo the &quot;Plan for the Construction of the Sales Ability Qualification Grading System for Insurance Sales Practitioners&quot; previously issued by the Insurance Industry Association, and aim to guide insurance companies to establish a product grading and channel grading system that matches customer needs. With the combined efforts of multiple measures, the results of this round of bancassurance channel rectification are worth looking forward to. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Overseas Bancassurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Close&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Type&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank Insurance It has existed abroad for more than 60 years. What can we learn from it? Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found out that there are two theories about the origin of bancassurance: one is Britain in the 1960s; the other is France in the 1970s. However, the development of bancassurance business in Britain and France is quite different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;New Bancassurance Era: The Beginning of Value&quot; released by Deloitte in 2023 shows that bancassurance channels in France, Italy and Spain account for 64%, 74% and 60% of all premiums respectively. %. Among Asian countries, South Korea accounts for 50%, Indonesia accounts for 48%, Singapore accounts for 30%, and India accounts for 25%. The UK bancassurance business has developed slowly and mainly relies on insurance broker channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the evolution of cooperation models in various countries, four bancassurance business cooperation models, namely agreement agency, strategic alliance, capital cooperation and financial group, have proven to be quite successful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1535&quot; height= &quot;3358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take France as an example. Banks enter the bancassurance field mainly by controlling insurance companies. Banks control insurance companies in two ways: establishing self-owned subsidiaries and acquiring other insurance companies, with the former being the main form. In terms of products, simplified and standardized life insurance or savings products are the main products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banking and insurance in Hong Kong, China also implement mixed operations, and large banks build their own insurance companies to achieve bancassurance synergy. The same is true for Taiwan, China. Bancassurance is mostly carried out in the form of a financial holding company. Its insurance product sales channels mainly include joint marketing through financial holding companies and strategic alliances, that is, business cooperation promotion through financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overseas experience shows that the development process of bancassurance is a process of banks and insurance companies jointly exploring consumer needs. It is a common choice for banks and insurance companies to choose the path of bancassurance cooperation and provide bancassurance products that meet the diverse needs of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development experience, the global bancassurance industry has experienced three stages: bancassurance, insurance banking and universal finance. They are essentially the cross-penetration, mutual integration, mutual complementation and common development of banks and insurance companies in many aspects such as product research and development, sales channels, organizational forms and business strategies, that is, the mixed operation of banks and insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the development models of bancassurance vary in different countries and regions. In other words, there is no universally applicable bancassurance development model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that my country’s bancassurance started relatively late but is developing rapidly. Data from the &quot;Insurance Yearbook&quot; show that in 2010, China&#39;s bancassurance channel premium income accounted for 50% of life insurance premium income, which was the highest in history. However, the cooperation between banks and insurance companies has always been based on the sales agreement model, and the cooperative relationship between banks and insurance companies is relatively loose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This model has obvious shortcomings. First, bancassurance cooperation is limited to the sales level, and there is a lack of motivation to jointly develop products; second, banks only act as agents for insurance products to obtain agency fees, and the cooperation between the two parties is short-term and unstable. Third, driven by short-term financial goals, both parties lacked enthusiasm in cultivating bancassurance professionals, resulting in low bancassurance service levels and frequent misleading sales problems. Therefore, my country’s banking and insurance cooperation model needs to be further deepened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Explore new ways of bancassurance cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to establish a healthy and win-win bancassurance ecosystem? The development experience of overseas banking and insurance shows that the financial legal environment and the form of organizational cooperation are crucial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the banking and insurance industries are under the unified supervision of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the regulatory coordination of the two industries will be smoother. At the same time, banks’ huge channels and strong customer resources are excellent channels for bancassurance to acquire customers. In addition, after years of market education, people generally have insurance awareness. Bank customers are naturally aware of financial management, and the question has changed from &quot;whether to buy&quot; to &quot;which product to buy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for insurance companies and banks, the customer acquisition cost advantage of the bancassurance channel will exist for a long time, and it will still be the main channel for insurance companies, especially small and medium-sized insurance companies, and it is not to be underestimated in banks’ collection business. field of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to build a new cooperation method for banks and insurance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that judging from overseas experience, the four models each have their own merits. At this stage, we can appropriately promote the development of in-depth bancassurance cooperation models. Those who have the conditions can try it at a higher level. my country&#39;s bancassurance development model has transformed from a sales agreement model to a strategic alliance model. In the future cooperation between bancassurance and insurance, the following points should be implemented: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. In terms of business philosophy, both bancassurance and bancassurance parties should completely transform the extensive operation that puts scale first, and truly shift from &quot;sales-centered&quot; to &quot;sales-centered&quot; Customer-centric&quot;. This will help both banks and insurance companies reach a consensus and shift to long-term business goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. In terms of cooperation methods, promote the transformation and upgrading of bancassurance cooperation. On the one hand, through strategic alliances between banks and insurance companies, &quot;capital integration&quot; and other methods, the constraint mechanism for the distribution of interests between banks and insurance companies will be reconstructed, and the &quot;discourse power&quot; of insurers in bank-insurance cooperation will be enhanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of laws and regulations, it is recommended to further optimize relevant laws and regulations. Objectively speaking, under the &quot;1+3&quot; model, the collaborative business relationship between banks and insurance is not stable, which increases the coordination costs between the two parties and exacerbates the inequality between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科技之手点燃梦想之火——访杭州亚残运会主火炬手徐佳玲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259159]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the lighting ceremony of the opening ceremony of the 4th Asian Para Games in Hangzhou on the evening of the 22nd, the last torch bearer , disabled swimmer Xu Jialing stepped onto the main torch stand and changed the torch &quot;laurel crown&quot; from her right hand to her left hand in front of everyone&#39;s attention - her smart bionic hand lit the main torch of this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, I only found out through the news that I was the last one.” Before the rehearsal of the opening ceremony, Xu Jialing had already worked with the intelligent bionics with the help of the research and development company Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. It took me a while to get my hands on it and I can control it pretty well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Some staff notified me before that I was the infield torchbearer for the opening ceremony, but I didn’t know which torchbearer I was.” Until I saw Sha Xiao, the chief director of the opening ceremony, in the news Lan revealed how to light the main torch, and Xu Jialing realized that she, who had been working with the intelligent bionic hand, would bear the final blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, I felt that I was very honored to be given such an important task.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1016&quot; height= &quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255023&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Beh In Chinese language, this is called &quot;control with thoughts.&quot; &quot;Actually, I am already used to life after amputation, but the smart bionic hand allows me to hold the torch with both hands and light the sacred flame. It is also very convenient in life. I can hold a water cup and twist the bottle cap.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smart bionic hand that looked very technological at the opening ceremony has actually undergone improvements in appearance design. &quot;At the beginning, we made a skin-colored version of the hand and socket for Xu Jialing. In order to make the overall visual presentation more technological, the team replaced her with a space gray hand and a carbon fiber socket. She also said she liked it very much. .&quot; revealed the intelligent bionic hand engineer team of Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My prosthesis is very cool!” Xu Jialing’s tone revealed happiness and pride. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;729&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255025&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Bei He&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, Xu Jialing’s cheerful and optimistic words often make people forget that the “cool” high-tech product we are discussing is being worn on her slightly defective left arm. superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2006, 4-year-old Xu Jialing was involved in a car accident and her left arm was no longer intact. Two years later, by chance, her mother discovered that Xu Jialing liked to play in the swimming pool, so she considered sending her to learn how to swim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coach thought that Xu Jialing might be good at swimming. Coupled with the recommendation of the local Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, Xu Jialing trained in her hometown of Ningbo for 6 years, successfully entered the Zhejiang Provincial Disabled Swimming Team, and went on an expedition with the national team. Rio 2016 Paralympic Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1019&quot; height= &quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255027&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 15, 2016, at the Rio Paralympic Games, Xu Jialing (middle) won the S9 championship in the women&#39;s 100-meter butterfly. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yang Lei&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rio, 14-year-old Xu Jialing, as the youngest competitor of the Chinese delegation at the time, won 1 gold and 2 bronze medals, which can be said to be &quot;the peak at her debut.&quot; After that, she won 7 gold medals and 2 silver medals at the 2018 Jakarta Asian Para Games. Although she experienced a trough in the subsequent Tokyo Paralympics, Xu Jialing&#39;s mentality is now very calm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When I won the gold medal in Rio, the journey may have been too smooth. At that time, I felt that it was not too difficult to stand on the podium. In Tokyo, I was not able to get on the podium even once. There will be disappointment, but it is also expected, because the state was not very good at that time.&quot; Xu Jialing said, &quot;The mentality now is more about training well and letting nature take its course.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only cheerful Optimistic, Xu Jialing often shows maturity beyond her years in conversations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the Rio Paralympics, 14-year-old Xu Jialing said in an interview: &quot;I think my life is very exciting, no worse than my able-bodied peers.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1015&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 2, in the women&#39;s 100-meter butterfly S9 final of the Para Swimming World Championships held in Manchester, England, Chinese athlete Xu Jialing won the championship with a time of 1 minute, 08 seconds and 34 seconds. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo by Jon Hupper)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years have passed, looking back on the growth process, Xu Jialing’s youth can indeed be described as “wonderful”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to her dazzling competition results, Xu Jialing also likes to travel during her limited holidays. In addition, she trains and competes with the team overseas, allowing her to leave precious memories around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jialing is currently a student in the &quot;Championship Class&quot; of Beijing Sport University. Her major is sports training. &quot;I&#39;m very happy to be back in school.&quot; Xu Jialing, who has been training for swimming for most of the past ten years, said, &quot;Studying in college can not only learn knowledge, but also better understand the major you are engaged in. I think this is The chances are good.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, lit the main torch at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Xu Jialing has become the main torchbearer of the Asian Paralympic Games. With the help of technology, she lit the main torch in the spotlight and illuminated her youth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development of science and technology, more and more devices and equipment such as smart bionic hands help people with disabilities make up for their physical deficiencies, igniting their belief in pursuing their dreams. But in Xu Jialing&#39;s view, the word &quot;equality&quot; may be as important as technological assistance to the disabled group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Personally, I don’t want everyone to look at us with a pity and want to cry. Our ability to stand on the Asian Paralympic Games, just like any athlete, is a result of hard work. The result of training. Maybe our training will be harder and it will be more difficult at the beginning, but we still hope that everyone can treat us with a normal mind.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网传“前台实名制”将落地：能有效改善网络空间的现实生态吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259112]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it has been reported online that the &quot;real-name system at the front desk&quot; is about to be implemented, causing concern and discussion. &quot;Come and Go&quot; (Wang Gaofei, CEO of Sina Weibo) quoted a media comment &quot;&quot;Real-name system at the front desk&quot;, big V should have taken off his vest long ago&quot;, which showed that the rumors were true. He also stated in a reply: The real-name system at the front desk is aimed at It is a self-media account with 1 million fans, which will be reduced to 500,000 fans in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Management of &quot;Self-Media&quot;&quot;. Among the 13 articles, there is a requirement to &quot;standardize account operation behavior&quot;: website platforms should strictly implement the &quot;one-person According to the regulations on the number of account registrations for &quot;One Number, One Enterprise and Two Numbers&quot;, individuals or companies are strictly prohibited from manipulating the &quot;self-media&quot; account matrix to publish and disseminate illegal and harmful information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current network platform implements a &quot;backend real-name system&quot;, and the front-end real-name and pseudonym are decided by oneself. If you really commit a crime on the Internet, you cannot go unpunished. The police will find you very quickly. Because the phone number used for registration itself is a real-name one; the IP addresses of Internet users are recorded in the background. However, even if real names are used in the background, as long as the person does not actively expose his or her information, the anonymity of online accounts is still quite strong, and online moral constraints are far inferior to offline ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for some people, if they want to maintain the quiet handsome man/demure lady personality that the large account has established, or if the large account exposes private information, they can just create another small account, go there Say something that the big one won&#39;t say. In this way, a person&#39;s personality can be divided into three: the offline one, a normal person in the eyes of colleagues and family members; the large one, an image with an ideal personality; the small one, another one, All kinds of darkness and nastiness appear. Seamless switching between ego, superego and id. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bigger problem with anonymity is that some self-media, in order to create topics and traffic, have no bottom line at all, and use all kinds of opposition to mobilize, engage in &quot;team building&quot;, brush up comments and hot searches, Using a small power to create a huge voice in an organized manner to create public opinion and influence the legislative and judicial process; the same party opposes dissent, and organized super-saturated attacks, harassment, and threats against individuals and institutions that disagree with their actions and values. This is It has become a public nuisance, constantly dissolving the consensus and values ​​on which society relies for survival, and greatly deteriorating the ecology of public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, can these problems be solved by allowing self-media accounts with 1 million or even 500,000 fans to have real names at the front desk? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We might as well do a model analysis. There is a group of people, each of whom has a voting right. So which one is better, anonymous voting or real-name voting, so that everyone can express their true opinions and make the results more fair? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people think it is better to vote anonymously: this way everyone can express their true opinions without pressure. But the disadvantages of anonymity are also obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, some people may be bribed or asked privately, because the final result is anonymous. Except for those who are colluding with each other, others have no way of knowing how they voted and no moral pressure can be exerted on them. , in this case, the vote he cast probably cannot be called &quot;expressing his true thoughts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, even if some people have not been bribed or accepted private requests, their voting tendencies may not be fair. For example, they may not want to let others go because they have personal grudges. Or maybe it&#39;s purely because of the &quot;Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma&quot;: No matter you vote for or against my favorite, I will always vote against it, at least without losing money. In this way, unanimously opposing it becomes an advantageous strategy. Having a significant number of people think this way can significantly skew the overall voting results. Although these voters &quot;expressed their true thoughts,&quot; they had nothing to do with fairness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it is not ruled out that there are some people who are pure in nature and will not be bribed or accept private requests under any circumstances. They will put aside their personal grudges during the voting process and do not bother to conduct sophisticated calculations of interests. There are some people who objectively judge candidates based on their own merits, but they are probably few. In addition, it does not rule out that the above two types of people will vote fairly under certain circumstances. If the candidate is too good/bad, they cannot resist their conscience by insisting on voting against/for voting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people also think that real-name voting is good and can effectively reduce the above two unfair situations of anonymous voting. Everyone&#39;s voting results will be seen by others, thus making it easier to vote for favors and vote for personal grudges. Exposing the behavior of calculated votes to the public will significantly constrain such behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But real-name voting is not without problems. First, some weak-minded people are afraid of offending others and do not dare to truly express their wishes and cast a fair vote when voting with real names; second, voting with real names will make the differentiation of factions from vague to clear. After factions or cliques are formed, conflicts will become apparent and may intensify. These two points are also the main reasons for implementing anonymous voting: to allow everyone to vote without pressure, thereby limiting the intensity of conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, whether to vote anonymously or with a real name ultimately depends on which values ​​the institutions involved prefer and which issues need to be urgently resolved. How to apply this model analysis to whether the real-name system at the front desk should be implemented and the scope of implementation? If we want to solve the two problems of organized public opinion creation and organized over-limit attacks and harassment of individuals and institutions, we should undoubtedly implement a real-name system at the front desk to expose these organized and dark behaviors of self-media to the public and accept them. The scorching heat of the moral sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if only self-media accounts with 1 million or even 500,000 fans require front-end real names, it may not be enough to curb the organized and dark behavior of self-media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there is the question of how far the front desk needs to be real-named. Is it the real person in charge or the editor of the operation? How to solve the problem of letting people without decision-making power to top the tank and deal with the real-name front desk? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, organized public opinion creation and organized over-limit attacks and nuisance have become highly evolved. The main account with hundreds of thousands or millions of fans will not be left alone at first, allowing some peripherals or fans to send malicious messages or mobilization messages through small accounts, and then instigate or patiently wait for some accounts with fewer fans to forward them, in addition to layer upon layer of forwarding. , the main account will then follow up and forward, thus minimizing the risk of the main account. This method of &quot;wearing multiple layers of cover&quot; is difficult to break the real-name system at the front desk of some self-media accounts with many fans, because small accounts and accounts with fewer fans can still do their own thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访广东省卫健委：基层诊疗“不仅要有大楼，还要有人才”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259151]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/23/9c64b58a94.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 23/9c64b58a94.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lantang Town Central Health Center, Hospital, Zijin County, Heyuan City, Guangdong Province In the lobby of the outpatient clinic building, there are promotional roll-ups by the chief health expert. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Letting high-quality medical resources sink and allowing people to see famous doctors at their doorsteps has attracted the attention of governments at all levels. The 2023 Government Work Report mentioned “promoting the expansion and decentralization of high-quality medical resources and balanced regional layout.” The 2023 Guangdong Provincial Government Work Report also proposed “in-depth implementation of a new round of grassroots medical and health service capacity improvement plans to effectively increase rural and underserved areas. Medical resources in developed areas”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To improve grassroots medical and health service capabilities, the most important thing is to fill the gaps in talent. In March 2023, the &quot;Opinions on Further Improving the Medical and Health Service System&quot; issued by the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council emphasized that we should increase support for the training of grassroots, remote areas and urgently needed professional talents, and narrow the gap between urban and rural areas, regions, and majors. The gap in talent allocation among enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to open up the &quot;last mile&quot; of serving people&#39;s health and provide more convenient, high-quality and efficient health services, Guangdong launched the &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts&quot; Grassroots Program”. The plan recruits 100 retired doctors from across the country who have senior professional titles and meet job requirements to serve as chief experts in 47 upgraded central health centers in Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the construction of the grassroots diagnosis and treatment system in Guangdong Province and the new round of implementation of the &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level&quot;, Southern Weekend reporters exclusively interviewed the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Support the horse and give him a ride&quot; to speed up the formation of service capabilities&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Guangdong is the country&#39;s largest province in terms of economic aggregate, but unbalanced development is the biggest shortcoming of Guangdong&#39;s high-quality development, which is also reflected in the grassroots health system . In recent years, Guangdong has invested a lot of money in comprehensively developing primary medical and health service capabilities. What is the current progress? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; Since 2017, Guangdong has invested 50 billion yuan in facilities, equipment, talents, etc. Comprehensively carry out capacity-building in primary-level medical and health services and consolidate the grass-roots foundation. It also regards the upgrading and construction of 47 central health centers as the &quot;number one project&quot; to strengthen the grassroots level, and plans to &quot;build it in three years and form service capabilities in five years.&quot; By the end of 2020, 47 central health centers have successfully completed the &quot;three-year construction&quot; target task. Primary medical and health institutions have taken on a completely new look, and a path of primary health and health services with Guangdong characteristics has gradually taken shape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three years to complete&quot; is just the completion of phased tasks and a new starting point. In the coming time, the ultimate goal is to continue to complete the &quot;five-year service capacity formation&quot;, reach the mid-level county-level hospital capacity, and provide better basic medical and basic public health services to the local people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hardware facilities are the foundation , grassroots diagnosis and treatment must &quot;form service capabilities&quot;, and talents are very critical. How does Guangdong solve the dilemma of building a talent team for grassroots diagnosis and treatment? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;After the hardware facilities are improved, if the relevant supporting systems still adhere to the rules and do not implement them in a timely manner Adjustment is likely to lead to a situation of &quot;only buildings but no talents&quot; and &quot;a good start but insufficient stamina&quot;, which deviates from the original intention of the provincial party committee and the provincial government to make great efforts to build a tight grassroots medical security network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To this end, the Provincial Health and Health Commission has issued corresponding support policies to &quot;support and give a ride&quot; to grassroots medical and health institutions to promote their accelerated formation of service capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Primary health and health talents are the main body of primary health care resources and the providers of basic medical and health services. The construction of primary health and health talents is important for improving the ability and quality of primary health care services. Quality is of great importance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on the three-year action plan (2018-2020) to strengthen the construction of grassroots health talents, we have also issued the &quot;Increase of Grassroots Health Talents in Guangdong Province&quot; &quot;Quality Improvement Implementation Plan&quot;, &quot;Guangdong Province&#39;s tertiary-level public hospitals and county-level public hospitals to carry out medical and health &quot;group-type&quot; close assistance action plan&quot;, &quot;Guangdong Province&#39;s 100 chief health experts&#39; grassroots plan implementation plan&quot;, etc., many measures At the same time, we have made every effort to strengthen the construction of grassroots medical and health talents, promote the reform of the incentive mechanism for training and use of doctors, and effectively improve the professional service capabilities of provincial grassroots health talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The number of outpatient clinics has increased year by year, and residents have high awareness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The &quot;One hundred chief health experts at the grassroots level&quot; has been implemented. How are the chief experts selected? ? What are the characteristics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>; The &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level&quot; is based on the actual needs of the grassroots. We will recruit 100 retired doctors from across the country who have senior professional titles and meet job requirements to serve as chief experts in the 47 upgraded central health centers in the province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After being hired, the chief expert serves as the subject leader of his unit. He is mainly responsible for guiding and improving medical staff in the diagnosis and treatment of common diseases and frequently-occurring diseases, preventive health care, rehabilitation and Capacity levels in chronic disease management, emergency response to critical conditions in specialist diseases, etc., to achieve the &quot;Three Ones&quot; - building a specialty specialty, developing more than one new business and new technology, and &quot;passing on, helping and leading&quot; to create a Specialist team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The provincial finance provides a subsidy of 200,000 yuan per person per year, every three years. The first round of the project was officially launched in December 2018, attracting more than 500 experts in the medical and health field from all over the country to actively sign up. After selecting the best from the best, the list of 100 first batch of chief experts was finally determined. Among these 100 chief experts, the average age is 62 years old and they have a total of 22 professional backgrounds in clinical disciplines. The ratio of retired experts inside and outside Guangdong Province is roughly 3:2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Just mentioned &quot; &quot;Three Ones&quot;, the first round of the plan has ended. What results have been achieved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;The chief expert assists the Central Health Center in carrying out specialist construction, and helps the Central Health Center establish and Improve relevant specialties, and at the same time, through training and guidance of grassroots medical staff, teach a group of medical staff for the central health center where they are located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Statistical results show that 65.2% of central health centers have established departments including obstetrics and gynecology, traditional Chinese medicine, pediatrics, general surgery, and gastroenterology with the help of chief experts. Internal medicine and other specialty specialties, among which central health centers that have established two or more special specialties account for 39.1%; more than half of the chief experts have developed one or more new technologies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On grassroots health In terms of the talent team, what changes has the chief expert brought to the hospital? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;The chief expert gave full play to the role of mentoring and guidance, and systematically conducted Professional technical training enables them to master advanced medical technologies and methods and improve their professional level and service capabilities. At the same time, the hospital is guided to formulate standardized operating procedures, optimize service processes, improve the efficiency and quality of diagnosis and treatment, and continuously improve the service capabilities of primary medical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The average annual outpatient volume of 47 central health centers in Guangdong Province increased from 114,000 to 149,000 in three years, with an average annual growth rate of 9.3%. Affected by the COVID-19 epidemic, compared with 2019, the total number of visits to primary medical institutions in Guangdong Province decreased by 20.2% in 2020, while the average outpatient volume of the 47 central health centers participating in the project only dropped by 1.5%, fully demonstrating that the central health centers participating in the project The medical services provided by the hospital have been fully recognized by local residents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, the Langtang Central Health Center of Zijin County, Heyuan City is one of the project implementation units. With the support of the local health administration department, the Central Health Center selected a general surgery department , two retired doctors from the Orthopedic Surgery Department serve as chief experts. Under the leadership of the chief expert, the hospital&#39;s general surgery department has established a laparoscopic minimally invasive center, and the orthopedic surgery department has carried out third- and fourth-level surgeries such as femoral head replacement and hip replacement, effectively improving the hospital&#39;s service capabilities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The chief expert also proactively invited familiar professors and scholars to the institute to conduct academic lectures and exchange activities, providing opportunities to grasp the development prospects of the discipline, cutting-edge theory, advanced technology and professional experience, and promote While improving the level of primary diagnosis and treatment, the number of outpatient visits at the central health center has also increased significantly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Has the Provincial Health Commission conducted relevant surveys, such as how satisfied are residents in the area where the planned hospital is located? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;Our survey of patients at the grassroots level showed that residents’ sense of gain from medical treatment scored 88.9. 75.9% of the respondents stated that they were clearly aware that the local central health center has provided diagnosis and treatment services by chief experts, and 92.8% of patients expressed their preference to receive diagnosis and treatment from chief experts. The survey results show that the health centers participating in the project provide better medical and health services to patients and have high awareness among the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a66f76cb29.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a66f76cb29.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Patients visiting the emergency department at the Central Health Center of Liuhuang Town, Fengshun County, Meizhou City, Guangdong Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Establishing an assessment system and carrying out professional construction are the focus of assessment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with the past, how is the new round of &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level plan&quot; different? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;First, accurately set up positions based on local realities. The new round of &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts Working at the Grassroots Level&quot; actively absorbs the work experience of the previous round and continuously adjusts and improves the implementation plan. Regarding the position setting, each central health center will comprehensively consider the urgently needed majors, departments with weak foundations, and leaders in the units. Based on the actual situation such as the establishment of the teaching team, we put forward the professional requirements for the position of the chief expert of the unit, implement on-demand appointment and on-demand recruitment, and promote accurate matching and compatibility of personnel and positions in various locations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Second, develop and improve the project management system to assist project implementation with informatization. Focusing on informatization assistance, we developed a project management system and adopted an informatization management model to achieve full-process integrated operations such as job setting, personnel registration, qualification review, interview announcement, agreement signing, personnel withdrawal, and subsidy calculation. At present, the use of the management system has basically reached expectations, and the results of project management efficiency, information electronics, and communication network have been initially demonstrated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Third, strengthen communication and coordination and establish a good communication mechanism. In order to facilitate the efficient advancement of the project, a work communication group has been established to answer problems encountered during work as soon as possible. During the registration and qualification review stages, give full play to the role of coordination and consultation, and actively communicate and coordinate with experts and relevant health centers for specific positions, understand the specific situation of experts, introduce position information in detail, and provide a more accurate two-way selection between experts and health centers. match. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;New round of &quot; What is the progress in recruiting experts for the &quot;Grassroots Plan&quot; of &quot;One Hundred Chief Health Experts&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;According to statistics, 46 central health centers (Gaozhou Second People’s Hospital have Merged into Gaozhou Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital in 2021, the number has changed from 47 to 46) 100 positions are set up in 23 professional categories, and a total of 186 people&#39;s registration information was received. After review, 144 people entered the interview stage, and finally all 100 positions were admitted, with an admission rate of 100%. Among them, 73% have a bachelor&#39;s degree or above, 48% have senior professional titles, and 17 are first-round experts. On July 1, the chief expert arrived at his post to start work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hiring experts is a two-way street In what aspects will the chief expert be assessed during the selection process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;In order to better assess the effectiveness of the experts’ work, we did this at the beginning of the project After completing the baseline survey, we can comprehensively understand the quality of medical services in the hospitals and departments where the experts work, and provide a basis for decision-making in the next step of scientifically evaluating the effectiveness of expert performance and the overall effectiveness of the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, a reference indicator system and standards for project performance evaluation are established, and the chief expert&#39;s assistance in specialty construction, teaching medical staff, and new business expansion are the focus of the assessment. The satisfaction of patients and employing units with the chief expert will be promoted to promote scientific and standardized assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;New round of &quot; The &quot;Grassroots Plan with 100 Chief Health Experts&quot; will also last for three years. How will the National Health Commission ensure that the plan meets expectations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>; We will strengthen supervision and guidance and guide all local units to follow the implementation plan and other requirements. Implement various tasks and requirements, do a good job in daily management and service of experts, and select some central health centers to carry out &quot;four no-two directs&quot; (no notification, no greeting, no listening to reports, no need to accompany reception, go straight to the grassroots, go straight to the On-site) field investigation to understand the work of the chief expert. At the same time, it guides each unit to do a good job in the annual assessment of experts, and implement expert protection and remuneration accordingly. It also conducts publicity work for outstanding chief experts and creates a good working atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Through the implementation of the &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts Go to the Grassroots Plan&quot; project, it not only meets the public&#39;s demand for medical resources, but also satisfies the grassroots doctors&#39; learning of appropriate medical technologies. It has effectively provided grassroots people with more convenient, high-quality and efficient health services, opened up the &quot;last mile&quot; of serving people&#39;s health, and allowed grassroots people to enjoy high-quality medical services at their doorsteps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层：三年会带来什么改变？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259149]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>