<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[东北亚新安全态势初现，如何推动局势缓和？| 智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the post-epidemic era, leaders of various countries have reunited, but they have not yet achieved significant results on political, economic and climate issues. Results. It is difficult for countries to unite collectively and instead prefer small-scale alliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, even in Northeast Asia, a similar new security situation has emerged, and the roles of South Korea and China in dealing with the new situation have also attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New security issues emerge in Northeast Asia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On August 13, the summit held at Camp David, Maryland, brought together the leaders of South Korea, the United States, and Japan to jointly respond to pressing international security issues situation. During the summit, the leaders announced the opening of a &quot;new era of trilateral partnership&quot; and emphasized the three countries&#39; commitment to security cooperation. They held a joint press conference to outline plans and cooperation strategies involving tripartite cooperation, the Camp David Principles and the Camp David Spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the meeting, in order to ensure the stable development of trilateral cooperation between the United States, South Korea and Japan, a cross-level and cross-field systematic cooperation foundation was established. In addition to standardizing the U.S.-South Korea-Japan summit, officials from each country, including the ministers of foreign affairs, defense, and national security advisers, also agreed to hold annual meetings in their respective fields to closely coordinate cooperation plans among the three countries. In addition, the three leaders decided to establish communication channels to facilitate rapid consultation and rapid response when urgent regional issues that threaten the common interests of the three countries arise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to strengthen strategic cooperation among the three countries in the region, the three countries agreed to establish a ministerial-level dialogue called the &quot;U.S.-South Korea-Japan Indo-Pacific Dialogue&quot; and explore new areas of cooperation within the Indo-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the leaders discussed practical cooperation measures to enhance joint operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the United States, South Korea and Japan reiterated their commitment to maintaining an international order based on norms such as sovereignty, territorial integrity and peaceful resolution of conflicts. Similarly, the three countries also agreed to support strengthening maritime security capabilities in ASEAN and the Pacific Island countries when implementing the Indo-Pacific strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, on September 13, Kim Jong-un and Putin held a summit meeting at the Vostok Cosmodrome in Amur Oblast, Russia. This time they met again after about four years and five months since April 2019. The background of the emergency meeting is that North Korea faces strong sanctions mainly imposed by the United States and Western countries. North Korea is subject to United Nations Security Council (UNSC) sanctions and suffers severe food shortages and technological deficiencies. Russia is also facing economic sanctions from the European Union and other countries, and is working hard to solve the long-standing &quot;weapons shortage&quot; problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current international situation, Russia and North Korea are considered unique partners capable of meeting each other&#39;s needs, and the two countries also intend to cooperate in the activities of the United Nations Security Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If new security issues arise in Northeast Asia, South Korea, China, and related countries will experience a vicious cycle of instability in terms of security and broader economies. Resolving the North Korean nuclear issue will also become more complicated, and regional economic development will surely stagnate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;South Korea and China promote cooperation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this context, South Korea and China are one of the major countries with the potential to control this situation. The relationship between the United States and Russia is still hostile, and the bilateral dialogues between the United States and North Korea and between South Korea and North Korea have been stagnant for a long time. South Korea and China can play a key role in mitigating and responding to new security issues in Northeast Asia through cooperation. Therefore, in order to achieve this goal, South Korea and China can cooperate in various ways and contribute to easing tensions in Northeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the trilateral summit between South Korea, China and Japan is a direct opportunity for cooperation. The trilateral summit has been held eight times since 1999. However, the trilateral summit has not been held since December 2019, with South Korea currently chairing the summit. The tripartite summit, which has been suspended for three years, may clear away the dark clouds hanging over Northeast Asia. South Korea&#39;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to host a trilateral summit within this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, South Korea and China may hold a summit summit. The summit was proposed by South Korean Prime Minister Han Deok-soo. A recent survey conducted by the South Korean newspaper Mainichi Yonhap Newspaper in collaboration with the public opinion research company Opinion and Public showed that 82.3% of the respondents believed that the South Korea-China summit was &quot;necessary&quot; to be held, while only 11.3% of the respondents believed that &quot; No need&quot;, 6.3% of the respondents were unsure. Regardless of differences in region, age or political affiliation, a majority of respondents believe a summit between the two countries is necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, while rebuilding trust between South Korea and China, it is necessary to activate various security cooperation mechanisms. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations in 1992, South Korea and China have made significant progress in various fields. The relationship between the two countries developed from a good-neighborly and friendly cooperative relationship in 1992 to a China-ROK cooperative partnership for the 21st century in 1998, and further developed to a comprehensive cooperative partnership in 2003, and was upgraded to a strategic cooperative partnership in 2008. However, after the THAAD missile defense system was deployed in South Korea in 2016, relations between the two countries became tense, resulting in restrictions on exchanges and cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the strategic competition between the United States and China and the international order have affected the security exchanges between South Korea and China. The uniqueness of North Korea-China relations and the South Korea-US alliance will also limit exchanges between South Korea and China. Additionally, the political climate may affect communications between South Korea and China, resulting in a lack of substantive agenda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from the perspective of the common national interests of pursuing stability, peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, it is necessary for South Korea and China to resume exchanges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, it is necessary for the two countries to maintain communication channels to resolve sensitive security and military issues and prevent accidental conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea and China are close neighbors, partners and indivisible. Today, cooperation between South Korea and China can jointly dispel the shadows and jointly open up a path to achieve regional stability, peace and prosperity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;(Author: Lee Chang-hyung, Director of the Korea Continental Strategic Research Institute, Korea Institute for Defense Analysis; Translator: Zheng Weihao)&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[枪械教官“大开杀戒”，“全美最安全州”响起无差别扫射枪声]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259575]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Year&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;October&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Month&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;27&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Day&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;The body of Robert Card, was found in the woods near Lisbon, Maine with an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound to the head. In the past two days, Lewiston, Maine, in the northeastern United States where he lives, has almost become a &quot;ghost town.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is the &quot;suspect&quot; in a mass shooting there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, the local police said on social media that a &quot;mobile gunman&quot; was found in Lewiston and asked people to &quot;shelter in place&quot; and &quot;stay at home and Lock the door.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the shooting on the evening of October 25, 2023, the U.S. police have been searching for Card. He carried out indiscriminate killings in a bowling alley and a bar, killing at least 18 people and injuring dozens more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, the Lewiston, Maine, police confirmed that the 40-year-old Card was a certified firearms instructor and a member of the U.S. Army Reserves. But this summer, he behaved erratically while training at the U.S. Military Academy and was admitted to a mental health treatment facility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The mass shooting is considered the worst shooting on record in Maine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Once known as &quot;the safest state in the United States&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As one of the least populous states in the United States, the state has high rates of gun ownership but relatively low levels of gun violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The number of victims in this shooting &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; almost equals the number of homicide victims in the state for all of 2022. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Why did the gunman go on a killing spree here?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Why has gun violence erupted on a large scale in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It has become the focus of attention of the international community&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Month&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;29&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Day&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Zhang Weiwei, dean of the China Institute at Fudan University who was attending the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing, spoke at the meeting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; about the issue of gun control in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;He once said in a TV program&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the Chinese people’s view of “political Tao” is the overall and long-term interests of the people, using “Tao” To manage the &quot;skills&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;If there is no concept of &quot;political ethics&quot; and only legal provisions, it will be difficult to promote &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;gun control &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; reforms in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/RSZkCUtwxkJRDLsS361ZrDduMf14vWknOe5nRcpk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 727&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/RSZkCUtwxkJRDLsS361ZrDduMf14vWknOe5nRcpk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the gun-wielding man shot in Lewiston, Maine, USA on October 25 (video screenshot). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/AP/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Indiscriminate shooting&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 25th&lt;span>;Night&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;If nothing else happens&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;A group of young people gathered in the Lewiston bowling alley&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;will spend their &quot;bowling night&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; here. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The bowling alley is located approximately 3.2 kilometers north of the Bates College campus, on the outskirts of the city center. There&#39;s also a small bar not far away that&#39;s a popular spot for local bowling leagues and young partygoers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;But soon, a gunshot interrupted the carnival&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;I heard about 10 gunshots, and I thought the first shot was the sound of a balloon popping.&quot;&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;A bowler said in an interview with the media&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;When he turned around, what he saw was not a balloon, but a man holding a weapon. man. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Robert Card appeared at the door armed with a semi-automatic rifle. The bowling alley was packed with parents and teenagers, with panicked young bowlers scrambling to hide behind the pins. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The gunfire did not stop because of the panic of the crowd and the crying at the scene, but became more intense. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Then&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Card began to face the crowd without mercy. Differential shooting. Immediately after&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;he chose to change a place&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;continue to cause tragedy in the bar&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In less than &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; minutes, the police received a large number of calls from the bar. Police phone number&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;People said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kard continued to shoot&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in the bar. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;But the Lewiston police were still a step slower. After Card fired continuously and wildly&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; drove away and fled&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;He was not caught on the spot&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dr. John Alexander, the local chief medical officer, said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This time The attack was &quot;unprecedented&quot; for the small city. About 50 medical providers, nurses, respiratory therapists and surgeons responded to the call to help treat victims, he said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After the incident&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The streets of Lewiston were empty and huge. Signs remind people to lock their doors and stay&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; indoors. The whole city came to a standstill due to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;this crazy shooting case&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;And &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a city 50 miles (80 kilometers) away from the shooting scene, schools, doctor&#39;s offices and grocery stores&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;also&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; All closed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Meanwhile&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Portland, Maine’s largest city, closed its public &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;facilities&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;The Canada Border Services Agency issued an &quot;armed and dangerous&quot; alert to officials stationed at the U.S. border. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;People are anxious and silently praying that the police can catch the murderer sooner&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;At the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;next day&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; morning press conference, Maine The commissioner of the state Department of Public Safety&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that more than one hundred police investigators&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;including&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Federal agents &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are also &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; involved, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in full swing &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; throughout the city&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Search for the murderer, leaving no corner that can be easily hidden. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Police in Maine said the suspect had recently&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;appeared&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mentally Health concerns, including &quot;hearing voices and threats to shoot at a military installation in southern Maine.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;His &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;sister-in-law Katie Card&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;accepting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the media&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;In the interview, he stated that his family had reported to the police and the army that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; was experiencing a serious mental health crisis&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Rick Goddard, a neighbor of the Card family&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;being interviewed by the media&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Shi&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; said that a few weeks ago&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; looked &quot;completely normal.&quot; Goddard lives&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;near the incident site&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and knows the Card family&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and revealed&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is where Card grew up&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;every ledge hidden behind, every&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;The&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;bush,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade is very familiar with&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Kade has received training as a firearms instructor, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is also&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Member of the U.S. Army Reserve&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Police said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade &quot;heard voices&quot; and threatened to blow up a &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;military&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;base. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;So&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;he was sent to a mental hospital, but he only stayed there&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;for two weeks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;Leaved&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is reported that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the gunman used a gun with an extended magazine and Semi-automatic assault rifle with scope. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The gunman’s firearm is very powerful.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Deputy Director of the Northeast Asia Research Center of Shanghai University of Political Science and Law&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Yang Zhen analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that the gun used by the gunman this time was an AR -15 type rifle, this model is shorter than a baseball bat, lighter than a bowling ball, cheap, simple to shoot, has slight recoil, easy to aim, and has a large number of copies, making it easy to obtain parts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is unclear how or when &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kard&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; obtained the shot Firearms used in the incident. The motive for the shooting is still unclear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Judging from the modus operandi and past experience, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The shooter&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;may have suffered psychological trauma, distorted personality, and has not received effective treatment for a long time&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;so it is possible&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Anti-social and anti-human tendencies caused by external factors stimulation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Before&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Before the gunman was caught&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;A shadow falls over &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Until&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;local time&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; year &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;October&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;month&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;27&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; on the evening of&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The state&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; held an emergency press conference&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Public Safety Commissioner Michael Sawchak said Card&#39;s body was found &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; near the Androscoggin River in the Lisbon Falls area. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It is about 10 kilometers away from the place where the shooting occurred. Card died of an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;When &quot;safest&quot; becomes unsafe&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Gunmen with military backgrounds carry out mass shootings&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is not an exception in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;For example, in 2018, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;there was &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; shot and killed in a Thousand Oaks bar. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Innocent&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;people’s &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;former Marine Corps&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;team members, and in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a church&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Sutherland Springs, Texas&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Air Force veteran who shot and killed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;26&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; people. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;U.S. Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) Agent Ferguson said the weapons used in the shooting were purchased legally and said &quot;more than three&quot; guns were found. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On the list of &quot;Top 10 Safest States in the United States&quot; by U.S. News &amp; World Report&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; ranks among the best&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;While Democrats control the governorship and both chambers of the state Legislature, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Maine has long resisted guns. Control measures &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;because &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;hunting is an integral part of the culture there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This year&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the Maine House of Representatives &lt;/span>;&lt; A measure to strengthen background checks for private gun sales was approved in June, but the proposal failed in the state Senate. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In addition&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the state House of Representatives also passed &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; a bill &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;banning&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Possess, sell, or manufacture&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;bump stocks and other rapid-fire modified devices&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, but the bill was also blocked by the Maine Senate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is worth noting that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine allows the purchase of certain Assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and no &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;similar&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; written extreme risk protection statute. These measures, also known as &quot;red flag laws,&quot; allow law enforcement or family members to seek an order from a judge to temporarily restrict someone&#39;s access to a gun if they believe they pose a threat to themselves or others. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to a 2020 RAND Corporation study, between 2006 and 2017, 45% of Maine households had at least a gun, compared to the national average of 32%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The state has high rates of gun ownership but relatively low levels of gun violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The number of victims in this shooting nearly matches the state’s homicide total for all of 2022. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Many US media revealed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that this shooting incident marked the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; 36th mass &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; shooting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; incident that has occurred in the United States this year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Based on&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;United States&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gunviolencearchive. org/&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guns&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Violence Archive data&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span>;, as of&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;On October 26, at least 35,275 people died from gun violence in the United States this year, with an average of nearly 118 deaths every day. Suicides account for the vast majority of gun violence deaths this year. This year 19,734 people died by firearm suicide&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023 is expected to be the deadliest year on record for mass shootings in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is noteworthy that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine Governor Janet. Mills is a Democratic attorney general. On October 25, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Biden had a phone call with him and expressed that the White House would provide support to Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Zhen believes that the United States is currently experiencing internal and external troubles, especially the U.S. presidential election, which has actually begun to have undercurrents of politics. struggle. Biden&#39;s move is, on the one hand, a show to the public, and on the other hand, it is an attempt to pull Janet away and help her survive the subsequent criticism and accountability. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;Confrontational Thinking&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The gun problem in the United States is an old problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Whenever a U.S. president ambitiously wants to reform the gun trade&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;, members of Congress will show very fierce opposition. In the end, the president often compromises with members of Congress, and the issue goes away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wang Yiwei, Director of the Institute of International Affairs at Renmin University of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Talked to Southern Weekend reporters&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;There is no way to completely eradicate&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;gun violence&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Just like treating every presidential election as a &quot;venting tube&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Violent shootings in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Be regarded as&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;more extreme&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;venting&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After hundreds of years of development in the United States, the gun trade has formed a huge vested interest group. These vested interests established a so-called &quot;National Rifle Association.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The association provides nearly 90% of the funding for anti-gun control activities in the United States .&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that the association also uses monetary donations to win over members of Congress to influence legislation. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;From this point of view, gun control in the United States is a dead end. The constant occurrence of shootings has plunged this dead end into an endless loop&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; .&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wang Yiwei&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;thinks&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The frequent shooting cases in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is an &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;old and persistent disease&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. The United States has had a tradition of carrying guns since the founding of the country, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and then&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;later turned into a constitutional amendment,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;now&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Plus the Rifle Association has hijacked this culture of violence&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After this mass shooting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; sought re-election In a White House statement, Biden mentioned legislation he has enacted to reduce gun violence. Biden said, &quot;While we have made progress on gun safety through the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act and the establishment of the first White House Office of Gun Violence Prevention, it is not enough.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; urged that Republican lawmakers &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; should &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; pass the ban as early as &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Assault weapons bill, universal background checks for gun manufacturers and ending&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;liability immunity, &quot;fulfilling our responsibility to protect the American people.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen believes that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The Biden administration is currently beleaguered internally and externally and is in dire straits. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“In this context, gun ban is just a disease of mustard&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;He added&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Just put on a posture and deal with it, it is unlikely that there will be a follow-up&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, they&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;We have neither the ability nor the will to completely solve this problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;However, people are still paying attention&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Why have there been so many shootings in the United States in recent years? Not only is there no &quot;cooling down&quot;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; but it is getting worse&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On October 16, 2023, the FBI released a latest investigation report. This report details the crime situation in American society in 2022. According to the report, in 2022, hate crime cases across the United States have reached 11,634. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Visible&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The phenomenon of hate crimes in American society is clearly visible to the naked eye. Visible rates are spreading rapidly. Conflicts between white people and people of color, conflicts between local residents and immigrants, and conflicts between different political factions have erupted intensively in American society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wang Yiwei&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;thinks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; At present, there are many contradictory problems in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;such as the advocating of individualism&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the culture of violence&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Oppositional thinking&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Social tearing&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Race Conflicts, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;Currently, the entire American society is in a state of division. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Now the United States continues to &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;be &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; belligerent&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Whether it is support for Israel&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;or exporting a violent war culture everywhere&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;definitely It affects the people in the country&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot; Wang Yiwei&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;analyzed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;including the so-called To defend personal freedom&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the freedom to permanently hold a gun, etc., guns are often used to resolve dissatisfaction with society, especially those who are well-trained in the military&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Military&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen believes that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in recent years, the United States has taken more aggressive actions toward foreign countries, which has not only intensified social conflicts , and worsened the financial situation. Once the financial situation is poor, it will inevitably lead to a reduction in investment in social governance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He analyzed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that the United States is a country of immigrants, and the increase in foreign aggressive behavior will lead to an increase in social conflicts. ,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to a much higher degree than other countries. Poor social governance has led to the proliferation of guns and insufficient police force, which will naturally lead to frequent shootings. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is worth noting that since 2020, the FBI has conducted The number of investigations into cases of terrorism and extremism has more than doubled. The Justice Department has established a new domestic counterterrorism unit to respond to the evolving security landscape. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The divisions in American society are still intensifying&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen judged&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that next year’s US general election will further tear apart American society and intensify class conflicts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:25:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》专访，导演邱礼涛，“我要拍巨变的年代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259584]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1部手机配8个壳：当年轻人不换手机爱换手机壳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259376]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/KBFUSLEv34V8c4MQjy4j8GEE1pNRRQ9sNwIITCv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/KBFUSLEv34V8c4MQjy4j8GEE1pNRRQ9s NwIITCv2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a certain brand’s 1,999 yuan mobile phone case has caused heated discussion. Previously, a mobile phone with 8 mobile phone cases has also become a hot search topic, and discussions about mobile phone cases have become increasingly popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, it costs thousands of yuan to replace a mobile phone, but it may only cost a few yuan to replace a mobile phone case. The dazzling array of mobile phone cases has gradually become a Mobile phone replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moreover, young people seem to be less and less fond of changing their mobile phones. An iResearch consulting report shows that 79.5% of Generation Z change their mobile phones within 1 to 3 years. At the same time, a research report from Ping An Securities stated that the time it takes for Chinese users to change their phones has lengthened from 28 months to 43 months, reaching a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A mobile phone made of iron and a mobile phone case as smooth as water. Since 2017, the market size of mobile phone cases has continued to expand, doubling in five years. Different from the &quot;one machine and one shell&quot; of the elders, contemporary young people are keen to play &quot;dress up show&quot; on their mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although a popular poll on Weibo shows that half of netizens will choose mobile phone cases with a price of less than 9.9 yuan, major mobile phone brands have embarked on a trend of skyrocketing mobile phone case prices. road. The lowest price of mobile phone cases sold on Apple&#39;s official website is 398 yuan, while Huawei&#39;s latest Mate 60 RS Extraordinary Master Edition mobile phone case, Star Diamond Smart Window Protective Cover, is priced at 1,999 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;CASETiFY, known as the &quot;Hermès&quot; of mobile phone cases, is the best-selling Hello Kitty and Sanrio co-branded model on Taobao, priced at 439 yuan. More than 1,000 people placed orders. With the blessing of the star&#39;s same style effect, Zhao Lusi&#39;s same style, TNT&#39;s same style, etc. attract star-chasing girls to donate generously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mobile phone cases have also become a fashionable item in the DIY industry. Cream glue, acrylic, and diamond stickers are all materials that can never limit the imagination of mobile phone case modifications. In many DIY shops in Guangzhou, the cost of DIYing a mobile phone case is about 30 to 100 yuan, making it a new choice for many sisters&#39; gatherings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of many people, a small mobile phone case actually provides a space for self-expression. Young people can find people who like the same anime and TV series through mobile phone cases. A close friend of the same celebrity, or some mobile phone cases themselves convey their own values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk to you about why young people are keen on &quot;wholesale&quot; mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/55373e95c3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/55373e95c3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255638&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/2d54bdaac5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/2d54bdaac5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/62e734b882.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/62e734b882.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255640&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/9d648c4144.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/9d648c4144.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255641&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/26/687c278ac1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26 /687c278ac1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26 /3314847adf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3314847adf.png&quot; data -key=&quot;255643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么钱买不来“父慈子孝”？富裕家庭面临价值观代际断裂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259531]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Youdao means that &quot;one can only know the etiquette by being practical&quot;. In the era of material abundance, the atmosphere within the family is relaxed, and &quot;the father is kind to the son.&quot; filial piety&quot;. Especially wealthy families or middle-class families with better economic conditions do not have the stress and oppression of material scarcity, and parents are able to provide their children with more choices and express their deep love.经济条件越好，亲人之间越甜蜜，这似乎是无需证明的定律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可从诸多报道的社会新闻看，这种结论却相当不靠谱。富裕或富裕中产家庭的亲情，似乎并未因金钱调剂而变得普遍美好。亲人间的隔阂不睦，仍相当普遍；父母与儿女关系紧张，似乎也没比普通家庭好。可见有些问题，并不是单单靠钱就能解决的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当代年轻的“啃老族”或所谓“职业儿女”，他们家境大多不错，父母在中产及以上——否则无以支撑家中长期的考公考研族。这种家庭的氛围可想而知。多数父母一面供养一边抱怨，儿女们烦闷不已，又无力脱离。吵得天昏地暗，家庭关系破裂的，不在少数。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为儿女结婚大出彩礼、买房买车的家长，实质也是供养。孩子都已成年，还能一下拿走父母大笔财产，这在其他国家很少见。若能换来关系融洽倒还好，现实往往是，拿钱的犹嫌不足，供养无法换来感恩，家庭关系紧张乃至破裂，倒是常见的闹剧甚至悲剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果以上只是普通中产家庭的烦恼，有钱人家（富裕或富裕中产家庭）是否好一些呢？未见得。这几年，有些富人的日子也不好过，不少海外留学生遭遇减供，直至断供。小红书短时期内出现了许多抱怨帖：生活水准降低，想买的买不起，住宿标准和旅游酒店降级。还有人抱怨父母，担心留学生活泡汤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;能供孩子在海外留学并享受高水准生活，怎么说在国内都算富人阶层。家里财务困难，不得不削减孩子开支，这大约是多数父母最后的减支手段。这些成年儿女们，没有惶恐不安，没有为父母分忧之心，而是先顾念眼前小利。这实在太没心肝了，足以令很多父母难过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，以上不能推论穷人家的亲情关系更好，而是要指出：相当多家庭有殷实的财富积累，父母给儿女付出更多，却没能换来更好的家庭关系。新一代年轻人目睹此种情形，生育信心很容易受到打击。不少人甚至认为：养孩子是完全错误的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事情何以至此呢？传统主义者见此说：孝道沦丧。从传统伦理看，很多儿女行为确实称得上不孝，可这套价值观在当代毫无市场，年轻人根本不听，父母也没底气说出来。拿出来指责年轻人，丝毫不能解决问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家庭成员冲突，本质仍是价值观冲突。传统社会几代人共享一套价值观，生活模式大体相同，现代社会则不同，父母大多代表传统价值，儿女则更新潮，隔阂不可避免。尤其这一百多年来的中国，正快速经历传统瓦解，两三代人的代沟之深，堪称史无前例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;价值观分歧不一定演变成现实冲突。成年儿女和家长之间冲突，亦是一场话语权博弈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只要儿女超越父母成就，用事实证明后浪超越前浪，父母纵有不满也只是无关紧要的唠叨。父母安然养老后，分歧最后消失，变成其乐融融的“父慈子孝”。贫穷家庭发迹之后，父子亲情大多仍很融洽，原因在这里——家庭内部平稳实现了权力的交接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但不是所有儿女都能超越父母的成就。尤其早年成功，率领家庭迈入富裕行列的父母，他们的见识能力有过人之处，累积已久的资源圈子，不是初出茅庐的后辈所能比拟。一方面，父母努力给孩子提供资源，帮其成长；另一方面，他们的成就又是后辈难以逾越的山丘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;举一个简单例子，夫妻双方是顶尖学霸，孩子能考取父母毕业的学校，其实寥寥无几。这还只是考试一环，在激烈的社会竞争中，孩子无法超越优秀的父母，已经成为常态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母自信其信奉的价值观仍行之有效，这是他们赖以成功的经验。他们给儿女提供财富支持，并输出指点批评。儿女们习惯优渥生活，对父母供养没觉得不妥（一旦父母拒绝供养，儿女必然怨恨），但同时他们有了新想法，对父母的耳提面命很容易心生反感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着年纪变大、儿女渐长，长辈话语权长期在衰落，家庭内部冲突不可避免。在多子女家庭或古典的长子继承时代，冲突不会太激烈——家长会运用财产继承权约束儿女，后者亦会自觉向父辈靠拢。当代潮流的趋势，则完全不利于父母，而有利于儿女。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;能干的父母再怎样强势，碍于法律限制，他们对儿女的约束力注定变弱。新一代儿女多是独生子女，理所当然继承家业。哪怕能力低下、言行出格，几乎不会有实质性惩戒。这助长了他们的底气。有钱人管不住孩子，并不难理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的潮流无法逆转。富裕家庭或富裕中产家庭要想缓解代际冲突，只能从根本出发，协调两代人价值观。责任落在父母身上：他们需要格外重视儿女的价值观。尤其身为企业家的父母，他们不能只给儿女提供优渥生活条件，却放任他们价值观走到对立面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企业家的工作是：判断消费者需求，发现市场间隙机会，机敏地提供产品服务，并获得超出一般工薪阶层的收益。企业家不事具体劳动，而是靠组织生产和发现机会创造财富。有时赚小钱都很辛苦，有时发大财却很容易。企业家既受羡慕，也常遭嫉恨和误解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理解企业家工作，需要长期学习和深入理解。古典企业家培养继承人，要求长期历练，并对其言传身教，考察其能力和品行。这是价值观传递的过程。当代企业家培养孩子，大多将对孩子的教育重任托付给了学校，给予全部的经济支持，而不是价值观传导。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将儿女送到海外留学，接受精英或商学院教育，以为这样能开拓眼界，超过父辈能力。结果显而易见：企业家儿女们长期脱离商业世界，往往只知消费，不事生产，最后在真实的市场竞争中显露出平庸。由于缺乏父母约束，儿女走向堕落的亦不罕见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当代欧美教育界是极左思想大本营，校园充斥着各类“进步”意识形态。反资本、反企业和反家长制、反家庭的思想大行其道。中国富人将儿女送往求学，苦心希望儿女继承家业。然而他们很可能迎来的是“不肖儿女”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经济学家米塞斯在其著作《反资本主义的心态》剖析了这一现象。米塞斯所处的时代，商人和企业家通常儿女众多，继承人通常只有一个，他们继承父辈价值观，苦心经营产业。而被家族“抛弃”的次子、孽子、私生子或近亲属孩子（如侄子），则早早失去继承权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些人生活优渥，教育良好，却对父辈的工商经营充满偏见和误解，以至于自命不凡，以为通过思索改造，就能超越父辈和执掌产业者。米塞斯把这种现象称为“侄子的怨恨”。这很大程度能解释大动荡时代，为何有些人明明可以生活优渥，却走上“逆子”道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当代企业家面临的虽不至于如此极端，价值观断裂现象却很相似。崇拜精英教育，忽略家学传承，家庭内部价值观代际断裂。更糟的是，当代企业家大多儿女稀少，家族产业存在后继无人的危机。长辈焦虑却无计可施，儿女则泰然处之，这种态度差异加剧了紧张关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[洞穴潜水圈里的门派江湖：关于金钱、性命和纪录的游戏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月16日，九顿天窗打捞现场。南方周末记者陈佳慧摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/80dc0f47c7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/80dc0f47c7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月16日，九顿天窗打捞现场。南方周末记者陈佳慧摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;享誉洞穴潜水界的九顿天窗还有另一个名字——源头，生活在广西都安县大兴镇的人们都这么称呼这个水下洞穴。它连通地下河，是南北走向、全长42公里的澄江的发源地。水面之上毫不起眼，一潭碧水卧在国道边。碧水之下，喀斯特地貌特有的洞穴向地心延伸，至于深度，目前仍未探明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幽深、神秘的洞穴笼罩着迷人的色彩，这里常年聚集着穿黑色速干衣、背着气瓶的洞穴潜水爱好者。58岁村民韦彩逢在源头附近开了一家餐馆，潜水者是常客。她想不明白，这个洞穴这么危险，为什么这些人还热衷到此潜水。她掰着指头算在此遇难的潜水者：2022年1个，2021年2个，8年前1个，再加上2023年的韩颋，已经5个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为最危险的极限运动之一，一个微小的失误就会让潜水员命丧于此，但漆黑的洞穴仍吸引着他们前仆后继。那里是胜景，也是深渊；是游乐场，也是名利场；是生命张扬处，也是死亡寂静地。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;每一口气需花费7元&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;韩颋最后一次下水前，吃的是韦彩逢店里的蛋炒饭。10月7日晚上六七点钟，韦彩逢炒了一锅八人份的蛋炒饭，连锅端到了九顿天窗。她告诉韩颋一行，吃完后要是有时间就把锅放到店门口。“韩颋每次来都到我家吃饭。他很温柔，每回来都笑眯眯的，（出了这个事）太可惜了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月7日，为打破洞潜世界纪录，46岁的韩颋（圈内昵称老猫）下潜训练，不幸遇难，遗体落在九顿天窗北洞约113米深的一处斜坡上。在此后失联的18天中，媒体跟踪报道，这位被称为“亚洲潜水第一人”的浙江人，生平开始广为人知。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩颋的意外死亡，大多数洞潜圈内人感到惋惜。但在这项充满危险的极限运动中，这一结果似乎并不意外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在都安，像九顿天窗一样充满危险的洞穴不在少数。作为广西地下洞穴探索项目的一员，43岁的魏杰经常到处寻找这种水下洞穴。他自称曾探访过约150个洞穴，其中未被踏足的洞穴占八成。国内洞穴潜水起步较晚，2010年左右才开始起步。“现在依然处于起步阶段，美国上世纪七十年代起步，我们晚了别人40年。”魏杰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏杰介绍，广西可供潜水的自然洞穴很多，比如柳州、桂林等市，平均洞穴深度约80米，而名气在外的都安，深度平均在300米左右。多位洞潜爱好者告诉南方周末记者，在国内，都安的洞穴资源可排在首位，放在国际上比，“都安的洞穴潜水属于难度偏大的”，水下能见度一般，最主要的是洞穴太深。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在技术潜水领域，洞穴潜水和大深度潜水风险较高。2018年开始技术潜水的许天华告诉南方周末记者，他的国外潜水教练曾在十几年前被邀请到都安进行洞穴评估，看是否适合开发成为旅游资源。评估结论是不适合大面积推广，“深度太深了，风险很高”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了风险高外，时间和金钱的高投入也让这项运动较难推广。多位受访者介绍，几年来，自己花在潜水上的费用高达百万元，除了购买培训课程、装备，以及到世界各地潜水所产生的各项费用外，还有一些易耗品，比如氦气。潜水员下潜所用的气瓶中是混合压缩气体，大多包含氧气、氮气和氦气，其中氦气市场价约7角/升。当潜水员下潜至100米时，他每一口气约需花费7元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏杰坦言，在洞潜圈，不以当教练为生的洞潜爱好者多是高净值人群，他们往往来自一线城市，“有富家小姐，有赚美元的，还有一些挖煤挖矿的个体老板。他们年龄多在35岁以上，当然还有一些年轻的富二代”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高门槛让洞潜成了名副其实的小众极限运动，多位洞潜圈内人士介绍，国内有全洞穴潜水执照的活跃潜水员仅有100人左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不是每次洞潜都是拼命&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;来自北京的22岁姜钰宸没想到自己会走上洞潜这条路。6年前，他和母亲互为潜伴开始潜水，那时，他患有抑郁症，而潜水被他当作长期有效的治疗方法。他形容潜进洞穴后，就像回到了母亲的子宫，感觉非常平静。但水面之上并不平静，在洞穴潜水员出事的新闻下，姜钰宸经常能看到他不认可且充满怒气的言论：“说我们是吃饱了撑的，作死，说我们不负责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏杰悲观地认为，洞潜除了“实现自我”的价值外，再无意义。在他看来，水下考古、打捞、施工是有价值的，但他们平常潜水并不涉及这些，“都是玩。你的行为对这个社会起不到任何帮助，只是满足了自己。我们很多时候就是为了潜而潜”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但进入洞穴后，魏杰似乎将“意义论”抛到脑后，他向南方周末记者形容那是如入无人之境的愉悦：“也许你是第一个到达这里的人类，你的每一束光就是世界照向这个洞穴的第一束光，甚至是唯一一束光。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与魏杰“无意义”的看法不同，同为爱好者的黎文认为，洞潜不仅振奋人心，而且非常严谨，“严谨意味着这不是一项竞技性运动，不是比谁更强，谁更厉害，而是一项管理性运动，是自己让自己达到一个更好状态的运动”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月18日，在都安县一处洞穴内，黎文一行正在准备下潜。南方周末记者陈佳慧摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/11fd3a26bb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/11fd3a26bb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，在都安县一处洞穴内，黎文一行正在准备下潜。南方周末记者陈佳慧摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于洞潜，每位身处其中的爱好者都有自己的缘由，也有自己的追求。有人为了看鱼，有人是在疗愈，也有人为了突破自己。“出发点不同，也会导致最终的结果不同。”一位洞潜爱好者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎所有受访者一致认为，大部分的洞潜虽然危险，但是风险可控，甚至是安全的。许天华称，他每次下水前，都会将所面临的风险考虑在内，并且有应对风险的各种方法。“并不是你们所想象的，每次潜水好像要拼命一样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一旦发生了什么问题，我们会按照紧急预案撤出，不会在那里做任何逗留。洞就在那里，你是今天潜还是明天潜，它都在那里，不在乎一朝一夕。”魏杰认同韩颋此前提出的观点，“洞潜是一个放弃的艺术，你可以在任何时间放弃任何一次潜水，但是永远不要放弃你自己。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;风险并非一成不变，对于亚洲洞潜纪录保持者韩颋来说，挑战世界纪录意味着挑战人类极限，而伴随极限到来的则是难以估量的未知风险。“风险和挑战是并存的，它就像天平一样，自我实现和自我毁灭，往哪一边倾斜得更多。”魏杰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;挑战极限并不能被所有洞潜爱好者接受。“好胜心和欲望对我们来说，叫不良动机，是要避免的。如果说你潜水的目的是为了成绩，那你可能不太适合我们的理念。”黎文39岁，有10年洞潜经验，但他拒绝透露自己最深洞潜纪录——“我认为这不是值得被宣扬的事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;四个门派，两种分歧&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这种理念上的差异，源于洞潜体系不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，国内较为活跃的洞潜体系有四种，分别为PASI、TDI、IANTD与WUD，除了WUD为国内自创体系外，其余三种均源自国外。黎文说，不同的体系有不同的洞潜理念，培训过程也稍有区别，但“几乎95%是一样的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下水人数为例，WUD等体系更强调团队的重要性，规定必须要有两个及以上潜水员同行。但韩颋所在的PASI体系和TDI体系，潜水员独自下潜的机会更多。“像老猫出事的这一潜，但凡有两个人，可能就不一定会出事。”魏杰分析，他是WUD体系成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，许天华觉得，像老猫这种深度的潜水，“很难找到一样水平的潜水员组成团队下水”。曾上过韩颋潜水课程、归属TDI体系的萧亮认为，在“狭小空间、大深度”进行洞潜时，潜水员的能力匹配度也很重要，“若能力不匹配，两个一起，反而还要照顾另一个人。有时候solo（指独自行动）更安全”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个约百人组成的小圈子里，除了是否允许独潜外，另一个分歧主要在于是否要追求深度。多位受访者向南方周末记者坦言，圈内确实有攀比深度的风气。“国外也有一个追求深度的年代，现在好像没有了。”黎文介绍。魏杰则直言不讳：“就是一个不服一个。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因体系不同，这个小圈子形成了不同“门派”。“我打一个比喻，就像电影&#39;古惑仔&#39;一样，每个帮派都有一个名人，名人下面有很多小弟，也就是追随者。”萧亮说。不过，并非所有人都热衷追随“门派”，也有一部分爱好者自己玩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月18日下午，黎文一行五人在都安县一处水下洞穴潜水，同行的四人就来自三个不同的体系。“这项运动本身就很小众，可以一起玩的人不多，不同组织的人都是同好者，本身就是缘分，也是很难得的。”黎文说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22岁的姜钰宸有2年的洞潜经验，他最深下潜纪录为101米，20岁就成为TDI（中国区）最年轻的X-CCR（一种密闭式循环呼吸器）潜水员。姜钰宸坦言，自己确实会追求深度，但是不像其他人那么在意深度。“因为我还很年轻，未来至少还有30年可以进行高难度潜水。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;姜钰宸觉得50岁是一个坎，他解释，50岁之后各项身体机能会衰老，新陈代谢的速度变慢，意味着身体排放氮这类惰性气体的效率也会降低，很难再做长时间、高难度的潜水，“比如破纪录这种”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩颋发生意外那天，离他47岁生日还有3天。2020年，44岁的韩颋在九顿天窗下潜至234米，创下亚洲洞潜深度纪录。这一亚洲纪录于2023年3月30日被WUD成员陈潜在九顿天窗刷新，创下258米的最深纪录。但仅仅过去28天，这一深度再次被刷新，2023年4月27日，韩颋在九顿天窗创下277米的亚洲纪录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为陈潜亚洲纪录的团队支援，魏杰否认他们是在追求深度，“这个数字对他（陈潜）来说，是非常有意义的事情，因为5月8日是他妻子的生日，他是为了纪念亡妻才潜的这个深度。”对于不到一个月的时间就被韩颋刷新纪录，魏杰表示：“我们没有服不服气的，干嘛要不服气，我们纪念的目的达到了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏杰分析，韩颋之所以这么快就去追纪录，或是因为商业推动。在陈潜未打破纪录时，韩颋曾以亚洲洞潜深度纪录保持者的身份出现在某产品的发布会上，“如果那个产品上市的时候他不是亚洲第一，可能比较麻烦，因为当时亚洲第一在我们这里”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者获取一份标注“蓝旗潜水”的招商计划书。蓝旗潜水是一家由韩颋等人于2014年创办的潜水俱乐部。计划书显示，作为蓝旗潜水的总教练，韩颋将于2023年10月在九顿天窗挑战世界纪录，届时将邀请吉尼斯世界纪录认证官亲临现场，多平台全程直播挑战过程，“我们将把它打造成一次广泛传播的极限运动流量入口”。计划书承诺，与品牌方达成合作后，“韩教练将为每一位伙伴录宣传视频”。截至发稿，蓝旗潜水俱乐部工作人员并未就计划书真实性回应南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;韩颋。图片来自中国探险协会官网&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d93591b399.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d93591b399.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;韩颋。图片来自中国探险协会官网&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;放标与布线&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;国内洞潜圈子里，对纪录的渴望并非只发生在金字塔尖，也并非只发生在深度上。姜钰宸告诉南方周末记者，国外一些成熟的洞穴里，几乎没有任何个人的东西，但在九顿天窗，有很多带着潜水员名字的标。这些绕在牵引绳上的标通常出现在100米以下的深度，因为在浅水处没意思。“比如你在100米放了一个，别人到120米放一个，那他肯定比你厉害。”姜钰宸坦言，这种行为很容易引起圈内的攀比、竞赛的风气，“这在任何一个体系都是不值得提倡的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩颋也在九顿天窗放过标。在韩颋微博发布的一条视频里，在到达目标深度277米时，他按计划停止下潜，并打结、锁线、放箭头标，那枚橙色的三角箭头标上写着“DJ”。“那是为了纪念他的朋友董杰，所以打的是董杰的标。”姜钰宸说。2022年9月26日，董杰与一位潜伴在此遇难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了标多，九顿天窗的线也乱。多位受访者介绍，进入洞穴潜水时，一定要拉引导线，这是确保返程的安全措施之一。如果一个洞穴里已经有主线，那么潜水员可以沿着已经布好的主线进行潜水，不再拉线。“通常，我们会尊重最先布下的主线，除非线拉得很不合理，我们才会在他基础上进行修正。”魏杰介绍，2015年，一个法国人在九顿天窗布了主线，后来国内很多团队都进去布线，“线太乱了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而拥有布主线权力的，通常是第一个进入洞穴的潜水者。然而有的潜水者为了追求第一，会把布好的主线扯掉，重新布线，并对外声称自己是第一个探索该洞穴的人。姜钰宸称，这种做法比较过分。他的终极目标是发掘未知洞穴，在其中探索、测绘，布一条没有任何个人标识的标，然后发自内心地告诉大家，这里可以潜水了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，多位受访者指出，洞潜教练水平的参差不齐也是导致圈内状况频发的缘由之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有10年洞潜教学经验的魏杰举例，他所在的体系要求教练在教学洞穴里至少下潜100次，能够在没有灯光、没有引导绳的情况下安全出洞才能成为教练，但很多人没有达到这个标准就成为了教练，“他自己都不熟，再去教别人，那风险是很高的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在潜水领域，遇到一个能力强且负责的教练是非常重要的事，因为学员对潜水的认知较易受到教练影响，通常，这种认知又与安全直接挂钩。如果想评估一个教练的能力，萧亮建议可以问他三个问题：教过多少人？有多少年潜水和授课经验？在潜水上花了多少钱？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与驾校教练不同，潜水教练有权力判断学员是否达标，能否签发合格证。“教练说你行你就行，说你不行就不行。但教练的水平又是不同的，才会造成体系之间存在偏见。实际上根本不是体系的问题，是人出了问题，体系才会显得有问题。”萧亮解释，目前洞潜体系多源自国外，只针对管理教练，因此教练的权力很大，“他是引领你进入潜水世界的人，你的认知也是基于这个教练”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萧亮曾在3年前上过韩颋的课，他评价韩颋是一位好教练。“他的能力是国内顶尖，他上课认真，会照顾到每一个人，是大部分人都会喜欢和认可的类型。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;最终是机器人打捞&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;有着不同目的、不同理念、不同体系的爱好者组成的洞潜圈子，很难说是一个共同体。在他们面对同行的死亡时，展现出不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩颋出事当天，有圈内人表示并不意外，但更多受访者表示，对韩颋的遇难表示惋惜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;最终打捞韩颋遗体的是水下机器人。图为工作人员正在操作机器人水下作业。深之蓝供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ce383f53c7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ce383f53c7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;最终打捞韩颋遗体的是水下机器人。图为工作人员正在操作机器人水下作业。深之蓝供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摆在韩颋家人面前的是更为实际的问题。韩颋遇难的第13天，即10月20日，遗体仍未打捞上岸，韩颋的哥哥嫂子告诉南方周末记者，打捞遗体是一件非常复杂和危险的事，“考虑到安全问题，原则上不再接受国内的潜水员进行打捞的工作”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，在韩颋遇难的第8天，共有14名潜水员下水打捞遗体，但均告失败。韩颋嫂子开始理解韩颋说过的那句话——等哪一天我回不来了，你们也不要来捞我。“他当时可能想到，自己如果出事了，也会是在很深的地方，国内没有人能把他捞上来的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎文有打捞潜水员遗体的经验，他分析，在113米的深度进行打捞，“虽然在人类潜水员的能力范围内，但确实是在边缘了”。他此前也做了准备，“如果那边能帮上忙，随时能过去”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎文解释，抛开洞穴和大深度的风险，单纯的打捞任务就已有很大风险。“我们下去是用CCR呼吸器，CCR天然会有浮力变化。我如果把他带上来，相当于一个人在开八个方向盘的车，哪一个方向盘没注意到都很危险。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于家属所称不再接受国内潜水员帮助的说法，在南方周末记者采访中，也有受访者觉得不仅是专业意见。一位不愿具名的受访者告诉南方周末记者：“老猫在水下出了问题，他们组织的人不捞，别的组织人去捞上来了，对他们来说，这个门面也会有点问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩颋遗体所在的113米深度，魏杰认为国内有能力可能将他打捞上来的人有六七个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让人意外的是，最终定下的方案不是潜水员打捞，也不是人机配合打捞，而是只有机器人下水打捞。2023年10月25日，在韩颋遇难的第18天，两台水下机器人将韩颋的遗体带上了岸。负责此次打捞任务的深之蓝机器人操作员孙延向南方周末记者介绍，水下北洞地形狭窄，南洞较为宽阔满足打捞需求，于是决定使用两台水下机器人协同作业，将遇难人员从北洞转移到南洞后再进行打捞，避免遇难者在打捞过程中出现磕碰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月25日，打捞队成功作业，韩颋在遇难18天后，遗体被带出水面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，黎文、魏杰、许天华、萧亮为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多省辟谣“推行工龄退休”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259561]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来源：山东人社&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，一篇名为《山东省将实行“工龄退休”制度》的文章和相关截图在少数微信群、微信朋友圈、自媒体等网上传播。经核实，该文章和相关截图内容为虚假信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东省严格执行国家统一规定的退休政策，不存在网传文章和相关截图中所说将按“工龄退休”的情况，请大家不信谣、不传谣。我们保留追究相关造谣者责任的权利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东省人力资源和社会保障厅出台公共政策都会通过我厅门户网站和“山东人社”微信公众号对外发布，感谢大家一直以来对山东人社工作的关注和支持！&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;山东省人力资源和社会保障厅&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;2023年10月29日&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来源：河北人社&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近日，一篇名为《人社部：2024年1月1日起河北省将推行按“工龄退休”的政策》的文章和相似内容文章、截图在少数微信群、微信朋友圈、自媒体等网上传播。经核实，相关文章和截图内容为虚假信息。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;河北省严格执行国家统一规定的退休政策，不存在网传文章和相关截图中所说将按“工龄退休”的情况，请大家不信谣、不传谣。我们将保留追究相关造谣者责任的权利。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;河北省人力资源和社会保障厅出台公共政策都会通过河北人社网和“河北人社”微信公众号对外发布，感谢大家一直以来对河北人社工作的关注和支持！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来源：四川人社&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近日，一篇名为《人社厅：四川省将推行按“工龄退休”，将在2024年1月1日全面实施》的文章和相关截图在少数微信群、微信朋友圈、自媒体等网上传播。经核实，该文章和相关截图内容为虚假信息。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省严格执行国家统一规定的退休政策，不存在网传文章和相关截图中所说将按“工龄退休”的情况，请大家不信谣、不传谣。我们保留追究相关造谣者责任的权利。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省人力资源和社会保障厅出台公共政策都会通过我厅门户网站和“四川人社”微信公众号对外发布，感谢大家一直以来对四川人社工作的关注和支持！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;四川省人力资源和社会保障厅&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年10月27日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[朱哲琴：见山还是山]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259472]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi8FeyCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;703&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi 8FeyCC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhu Zheqin was a teenager, he dreamed of becoming a traveler. A few years later, she won the second prize in popular singing in the professional group of the Youth Singing Competition. If she embarks on the path of an acting singer, she can choose from many record companies, performance opportunities, and gain both fame and fortune; she can also leave everything behind and pursue what she really wants to do, but she doesn&#39;t know what she wants to do at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1991, the year after participating in the Youth Singing Competition, 23-year-old Zhu Zheqin left Guangzhou for Chengdu, still determined to be a tour guide. Her collaborator at the time and for many years to come, the composer He Xuntian, was a little angry and said it was a pity that she didn&#39;t sing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although she failed to become a traveler, she later went to India, Bhutan, Nepal, Tibet, Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, Guizhou, and Xinjiang to collect music. Her singing has also gone far. Her first album &quot;Yellow Child&quot; (1992) showed artistic qualities in addition to popular singing. &quot;A Sister&#39;s Drum&quot; (1995) was published in 56 countries, becoming the first A Chinese album released globally, with &quot;Yangjinma&quot; (1997), the scope expanded to 65 countries. In the wave of New Age Music that emerged at the end of the 20th century, Zhu Zheqin is a representative figure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes she attributes herself to the laws of history - her popularity in the 1990s coincided with people&#39;s pursuit of spirituality after their material life was abundant. Sometimes she just said that people are really strange. What is a living thing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took her a long time to figure out what she wanted to do. During this period, he released 6 albums, including a live recording album, held a world tour, served as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program, and initiated goodwill actions and original design platforms based on the protection and inheritance of Chinese traditional music and handicrafts. Then, by chance, I started sound art and have been creating it happily ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, social activities and artistic creation caused her to become relatively quiet in the field of music performance. After not giving a concert for nearly ten years, on September 30, 2023, she performed new music and sound art works, including a small concert, at the Aranya Jinshanling Community in Chengde, Hebei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I haven&#39;t sung for you for a long time.&quot; I saw her on the second day of the performance. We walked into a meditation room at the foot of the mountain. She took off her shoes and coat, and her black body disappeared on the gradually dimming tatami. Most of the lighting in this room comes from a floor-to-ceiling window. Outside the window is the dry landscape, only a sliver of sky is exposed, and dusk is approaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;A long-lost slightly impromptu concert&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from July, at the invitation of Aranya, Zhu Zheqin stayed in Jinshanling for three months to create music and sound art. It is located at the junction of Beijing and Hebei. The ridge is dotted with ruins of the Great Wall of the Ming Dynasty, which are ruined and mixed with rubble. To the southwest is the capital city, where the forests are gradually dyed in autumn. The Jinshanling area is inhabited by aboriginal mountain people, and real estate development has attracted many &quot;new mountain people&quot; to buy homes or travel with their families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intentionally or unintentionally, Ma Yin, the founder of Aranya brand, wants to create a paradise here. First of all, transportation here is inconvenient, and secondly, it is extremely close to nature. At a dinner party and a conversation, Ma Yindu said: In the next ten years or more, we will spend more time in pain than happiness in our lives, so warming people&#39;s hearts may be a mainstream thing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin’s exhibition will be completed in two landmark buildings in Aranya Jinshanling. One is the upper courtyard designed by architect Liu Yichun. It is built according to the mountain and is composed of a courtyard, a terrace and a hall. It is the spiritual highland of the community. One is the Valley Concert Hall designed by architects Li Hu and Huang Wenjing. It looks like a boulder and an alien object from the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three months of residency, Zhu Zheqin visited the concert hall and upper courtyard at different times, early morning, dusk, midnight, windy, rainy or foggy. &quot;It&#39;s like you get to know a very strange person.&quot; Friend, you have to know his character, know when he is the softest and most moving, and also know when he is the strongest. This is my working method.&quot; Especially the Valley Concert Hall, contrary to conventional concert halls, it does not There is no condition to completely purify the sounds of human voices and musical instruments, because its roof reaches the sky and the four walls are cut out, connecting the inside and outside. Sitting on the concrete seats of the concert hall is like sitting in a hollow boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is completely opposite to the concept of a standard concert hall. It does not block ambient sounds, but hopes that you can hear ambient sounds in an open state, feel the changes in light, and know that everything wakes up in the morning. .&quot; For musicians, these are unique and rare performance venues that burst the imagination, but they also have great limitations. They make people rethink, what kind of performance is a good performance? What kind of listening experience does this performance bring to the audience? Why do these two buildings appear here? Why do people come here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On several occasions, Zhu Zheqin went mountain climbing with Bai Chunxiang, the local Great Wall protector. Once she saw the back of Bai Chunxiang sitting on the Great Wall. She looked at it for a long time and thought, how should we as contemporary people deal with themselves in these cultures? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;She seemed to be embarking on a new journey, with old experiences falling off like frozen leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Zhu Zheqin spent 15 days in the mountains to collect various sounds, downloaded sounds from other planets from NASA’s official website, and used ambient electronic music editing throughout. She decided to compose in a minimalist way in three sections. The melody has only five notes, do re mi so la, and the lyrics only have three sentences - &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, Seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still mountains, and seeing water is still water.&quot; She invited Jinshanling aborigines and &quot;new mountain people&quot; to form a choir, and also successively contacted other musicians, including arranger Meng Ke Zhuolan, guzheng Chang Jing, and wind blower Wang Hua and percussionist Chen Shijie, all of whom participated in her tour ten years ago, are now reunited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete performance design is as follows: in the afternoon, the audience follows the guide silently throughout the entire process through the four performance locations along the upper courtyard building complex, using their &quot;hearing&quot; to experience nature and the musicians&#39; understanding of natural sounds. The performance of the performance was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;; in the evening, I entered the Valley Concert Hall to listen to the concert, which was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall structure of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; is strictly arranged, and each paragraph is mainly improvised. The day&#39;s weather, audience interaction, and the sounds of flora and fauna in the valley will all become part of the improvisation. Therefore, except for the chorus, which is composed, the other parts are improvised, and each rehearsal and performance will be different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final rehearsal and recording was going on in the concert hall the night before the official performance. At 8 o&#39;clock, the mountain breeze passed through the hall, and the recording tube was full of whistling wind. Meng Ke Zhuolan&#39;s curly hair was blown all over her head. She stood at the mixer at the top of the back row and shouted to Zhu Zheqin at the bottom: &quot;Aren&#39;t you scared?&quot; Zhu Zheqin looked at her happily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Later we thought it was actually good to have wind, because if your music is open enough, it can accommodate this.&quot; Meng Kezhuolan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the night, the rehearsal was over. The next morning, Zhu Zheqin got up and turned on the recording to listen again. Suddenly, he kept crying. &quot;I feel extremely happy. I have never shed tears because of a good meal, but I may have read a poem, stood in front of the sea, watched a movie, and listened to Dupree&#39;s Elgar Cello Concerto in E minor, It makes me feel like my life has been turned into gold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;166 cushions were squeezed into the originally 140-seat Valley Music Hall, and people were still coming in. Many people had to stand at the entrance to listen. At 6pm, the show starts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert hall was very dark at first, with only a beam of white light shining in from the roof, scanning the entire venue back and forth. In the center of the sunken stage, Zhu Zheqin’s long hair was tied up in a bunch, with his eyes closed, like an immortal sitting in a cave. middle. The sound of 432 Hz always surrounds this fairy cave. This is a soothing and healing sound frequency that Zhu Zheqin specially used this time. It is superimposed with the sounds of streams, frogs, chimes and alien planets to create a space far wider than a concert hall. Zhu Zheqin&#39;s voice has a long breath and a wide range, from far to near, from humming to singing. She was so happy with the performance that she clapped her hands and danced, swaying her three-meter-long costume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Derek Bailey discusses the concept of free improvisation in Improvisation: Its Essence and Musical Practice, he considers it to be a celebration of the moment. Li Jianhong, a musician who is keen on improvisation and the translator of &quot;Improvisation&quot;, regards improvisation as a channel. He believes that for a conscious musician, improvisation is always a way to explore the true self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhu Zheqin, all these are true, and can be interpreted in another way. Improvisation is also a coexistence between everyone and nature, and is a humble and great part of it, like flowing water, frogs, wind, and trees. Like crows, they live for a short period of time, but they also create enduring arts such as music, poetry, and painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the three-part singing was over, the musicians were supposed to be introduced, but that night she felt that anything she said in the middle of the performance was superfluous. So she performed all the way to the impromptu &quot;Finale&quot; that was originally prepared for everyone to leave at will. Halfway through the &quot;Finale&quot;, people still stayed where they were. Then she introduced the choir and performing members, thanked many people, and then said: &quot; It&#39;s been a long time since I sang for you.&quot; She paused and continued, &quot;We are already at the age when we are about to go down the mountain, but we climbed up a mountain together. This is rare in life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the time Near 8 o&#39;clock, Zhu Zheqin was worried that a strong wind was coming, and finally told the audience who were unwilling to leave, everyone should go back. People stood up one after another, but she was reluctant to leave. Amid the rustling footsteps leaving the concert hall, her singing voice suddenly sounded again, with a broad and clear voice: &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still water. Mountains, water is still water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255462&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;World Hear·Ethnic Music Discovery Tour&quot; Guizhou Station, Zhu Zheqin led a team to record Miao girls singing &quot;Soul of Rice Flowers&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Spiritual hometown&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A week later, I met Guo Rong in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin has been working together for 11 years. Guo Rong found that every time there was a new art project, Zhu Zheqin would always leave a place for the &quot;old people&quot; who had worked together. Zhu Zheqin is surrounded by collaborators who have worked together for more than ten years, and she has become close partners in life with many of them. Guo Rong said that Zhu Zheqin maintained his enthusiasm for people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large part of the reason why Zhu Zheqin was so moved at the end of the concert and later at the dinner was that many friends came, including Xi Chuan, Li Xianting, Xu Bing, Zhang Xiaogang, Wu Ershan... &quot;It&#39;s too luxurious.&quot; She choked up when talking about these names, &quot;Their works have been with me for many years, and the spirit, energy, touch, and encouragement released by their creations have been useful to me for life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After (New Crown) I miss these friends very much during the epidemic. I feel that life is meaningless. They come and go naturally, but they are the scenery of my life. If they need my voice, I think I should sing to them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dinner As usual, let the guest of honor say a few words during the ceremony. Zhu Zheqin took the microphone and said he had nothing to say. Everyone said, &quot;Let&#39;s sing.&quot; She said, &quot;Come on.&quot; &quot;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot;.&quot; It&#39;s too long ago. &quot;Return.&quot; Just right, this is the theme song she wrote and sang for the movie &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Christmas Eve 2019, Zhu Zheqin received a call from Wu Ershan and asked her if she wanted to go to Qingdao for Christmas. When I arrived in Qingdao, I discovered that it was a huge studio with thousands of people busy every day. Wuershan has been preparing for 10 years and spent 3 billion to make a trilogy of mythological epics. He hoped that Zhu Zheqin would write a song for &quot;Fengshen&quot;. They met as early as the 1990s. Zhu Zheqin watched Wu Ershan move from contemporary art to advertising shooting and then to film director. She felt that she did not have the courage to target a wider audience like Wu Ershan, and subconsciously refused: &quot;This is For a commercial blockbuster, I am not a traffic star and cannot bring you traffic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Our first choice is Teacher Zhu, and he is also the only choice. We want to write an art song with a melody Full, and at the same time the voice span is very large, because if you want to express very full emotions, it will involve a very large span between notes. No one (except her) can sing.&quot; said Meng Kezhuolan, who is Wu Ershan&#39;s wife , is also the music director of &quot;Fengshen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The guests fell silent, there was no accompaniment, and the sound was dry and dull, not suitable for singers to sing. But the three-part song was sung melodiously and stretched by Zhu Zheqin. It tells the story of the young Ji Fa who was sent to Chaoge as a hostage, and then escaped from the control of the tyrannical Shang King Yin Shou and returned to his hometown. The song was still being recorded during the COVID-19 epidemic. She had to return from abroad. According to epidemic prevention regulations, she was quarantined when she was in transit in Hong Kong, and then quarantined again after arriving in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin said that this is Ji Fa&#39;s homesickness, and it also embodies some of her nostalgia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 11 o&#39;clock during the dinner, the brightly lit restaurant suddenly lost power and became completely dark. The staff found real and fake candles for lighting, and the guests were happy and cheered softly. Then someone said, let’s go see the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The moonlight is bright and clear, the mountains are silent, and the cold night makes people shrink their necks and stamp their feet. A small group of people filed out through the narrow glass door and gathered on the platform to sing again, &quot;The moon passes through the white lotus-like clouds&quot; and &quot;You ask me how deeply I love you/How much I love you.&quot; / My love is true / My love is true / The moon represents my heart”... Sometimes it is a solo, sometimes it is a chorus of three or three, and someone brings a piano, and the echoes are like ripples. spread among the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They will definitely lose power when they are together. The spiritual energy field is too strong.&quot; Zhu Zheqin also remembered during the interview, &quot;It was like that in the 1980s and 1990s. There were no exhibitions at that time. There were no paintings to sell, no records, no concerts, all of this was nothing. Zhang Xiaogang was still painting stage sets for the Sichuan Opera Troupe as a living profession. But what he loved most was painting. He painted hard, and he had no money. No reason. In recent years, it seems that people paint just to go to auction, and how high the price is, and how good it is. In fact, it is not true. In my opinion, those are just projected phenomena. There is a powerful spiritual power behind it. I What I cherish is that kind of thing. I think that kind of thing will change the world and heal myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it this way, the narrow door that everyone passes through from the restaurant to the terrace seems to have become a door to time and space. , outside the door is their spiritual hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;I think people of every era are the masters of this era. The history of this era is created and left by us, so what do we want to create? If we are dissatisfied with reality, Then why don&#39;t we do some ourselves? I&#39;m not one to complain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She was singing &quot;A True Story&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Red-Crowned Crane&quot;&lt;/span>;) and became famous after winning the Youth Singing Competition, a fan appeared at the door of the hotel in the middle of the night and said to her, I think you are the Red-Crowned Crane. She was scared away because &quot;it impressed them so strongly that they stayed there forever.&quot; She didn’t know what she wanted at that time, but she knew what she didn’t want—not to become a singer, not to be packaged, not to enter a paradigm. &quot;Someone in my heart said, no, no, no. But, what are you going to do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Double CD &quot;Moonrise&quot; by Zhu Zheqin and ethnic singers&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, the market economy developed rapidly and social trends moved away from single collectivism. Zhu Zheqin recalled That feeling of liberating the mind, &quot;Actually, people are quite confused, and they don&#39;t know where they are in this coordinate.&quot; She did not sign with any record company, nor did she join an art troupe, and disappeared from the public eye. She went to Chengdu from Guangzhou, and a year later, &quot;Yellow Child&quot; composed by He Xuntian and sung by Zhu Zheqin was released. Later, historian Luo Xin wrote about a detail when he was reflecting on and criticizing racial thinking. On a winter night when he was working on his doctoral thesis, he heard &quot;Yellow Children&quot; being played on the radio, &quot;that empty and desolate feeling of loneliness and hopelessness.&quot; &quot;It tells the loss of the East in front of the West.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, &quot;A Sister Drum&quot; was released. This was the second collaboration between Zhu Zheqin and He Xuntian. They took a trip to Tibet, which they regarded as a spiritual holy land, and returned many times. But no matter how impressive the natural scenery, humanities and art in Tibetan areas are, what makes Zhu Zheqin most unforgettable is still the &quot;people&quot;. It is &quot;the scenes of their lives in poverty that made me have to re-evaluate the weight of my life.&quot; She got a new name, Dadawa. Dadawa is reminiscent of Dadaism, which was later basically annexed by Surrealism. Dadawa is the Tibetan word for the moon. Dadawa is neither the East nor the West. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot; and &quot;Yangjinma&quot; two years later form a complete expression of their Tibet, which is mysterious and strong on the one hand, and everyday and light on the other, bringing Zhu Zheqin to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, she also made a physical journey across Asia. From Kashmir to the Himalayas, I sweated and sneezed while clicking the shutter in the spice markets of India, and took a tricycle to look for gypsies. Gypsy Bopa played the music on a very simple folk violin. Zhu Zheqin was fascinated by it. It took him a while to come back to his senses and said that it was like hearing real music for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also during that trip, she saw Hindus waiting for death by the Ganges River, and the cremated corpses rolled down to her feet. &quot;Journey to the Ganges is another starting point in my life, where I realize the meaninglessness of life. Our life is redefined by our values ​​and culture, which celebrates the greatness of life. A person&#39;s birth must be celebrated, and a person&#39;s death must be commemorated. . But if you imagine that a fish is born and dies, it is a natural thing, nothing more. The truth of the universe is that you are like a leaf, yellow today and withered tomorrow.&quot; She thought, if life is like this, what will happen to people? Life? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ask the Mountain·Theme Concert&quot;, Zhu Zheqin and musicians performed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Asking is the beginning of Tao&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the first year of the new coronavirus pandemic, Zhu Zheqin entered a &quot;dormant state&quot;. She spent most of her time at home, cooking, taking care of the yard, and thinking about nothing. &quot;I rarely have such a stage where I shut down my phone. Suddenly I felt how fragile the world is and how vulnerable human civilization is to an invisible virus.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second year, she began to I thought, if there are no recordings, no exhibitions, no concerts in the future, what else will I do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin was admitted to the Guangzhou &quot;Little Skylark&quot; Chorus at the age of 7 and performed at the Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hall. At the age of 13, she recorded children&#39;s singing teaching materials. She can sing any type of opera. During school, she worked as a singer in a karaoke hall, and then she became famous. , hold concerts, explore your own expression and style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the trip to India shattered the meaning of life, Zhu Zheqin felt that he had reached a point in time where all expressions seemed pale and feeble, and he had to look inward to find something more essential. &quot;When you find yourself weightless or confused, only by daring to throw yourself out can you have a chance to regain your life.&quot; In 2009, she accepted the appointment as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program and launched the &quot;World Sees-China &quot;Ethnic Culture Protection and Development Goodwill Action&quot;, conducting field research on folk music and handicrafts in ethnic minority areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, she realized that she and the entire generation had a very weak understanding of their own culture. Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;In modern China, a &#39;modernity&#39; suddenly appeared, but this &#39;modernity&#39; may have nothing to do with its own culture and is a collage. From the time we started to imitate to the time we realized that imitation was not It is not ourselves, and then we have to find and construct it. The first stage is to create something from scratch, and then we have to take root, grow up, be local, and reflect the face of the people of this land and water.&quot; She deliberately made young people Many musicians participated in the project to organize and adapt folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, she released her last album to date, &quot;Moonrise&quot;, a double CD. One is a collection of original ethnic minority music, and the other is a musician&#39;s work that has been arranged and sung. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the creative team of &quot;Moonrise&quot; held a world tour with ethnic singers and young musicians. Meng Kezhuolan served as composer and arranger. She was less than 30 years old at the time and mainly wrote chamber music. Before a performance, Zhu Zheqin asked Meng Kezhuolan to come and listen. That was the first time she heard a singer and musician singing Miao Fei Song sitting in front of her. As soon as the other person opened his mouth, she got goosebumps all over her body. &quot;I was suddenly photographed there. His earthy, tanned look no longer existed in front of me. I thought to myself that if he were in a Miao village, all the girls would fall in love with him.&quot; Until a few days ago, wind player Wang Hua still remembered that tour during the rehearsal of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and said that it was the best performance he had participated in in so many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &#39;World Seeing&#39; thing seems to help others, but it actually saved me.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said frankly, &quot;After the meaning of life was shattered, it gave me a stage to learn and do something. Specific things. At that time, I had a very big feeling. I thought I was a drop of water, but I was also an ocean. Only when I became a water drop could I be an ocean.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But after that, Zhu Zheqin never released an album and had only a handful of public performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As a singer, I use singing to express my thoughts and feelings, but apart from that, I have always been more interested in inner energy.” Along this path, she entered sound art, “I want to Know what else is inside me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it didn&#39;t go well at first. In 2014, Gao Peng, then director of Today Art Museum, approached Zhu Zheqin and asked her to create a sound art work. After two visits, her reply was pending. Guo Rong hoped to persuade Zhu Zheqin to start a new attempt. She said: &quot;Teacher Zhu, I came to your team because I like your music and your voice.&quot; Something seemed to be touched in Zhu Zheqin&#39;s heart. A few days later, she flew abroad. Before leaving, she left a note for Guo Rong, which listed 20 issues, including time points, production schedules, and problems faced... Guo Rong was relieved when she saw it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, I think the process of her asking these questions is also a process of self-answering. If I didn&#39;t answer her at that time, someone else would answer her. If no one else answered her, she would answer these questions herself. Question.&quot; Guo Rong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, the Sound·Jue Zhu Zheqin sound art exhibition opened. Today Art Museum was painted into a dark box, with a pool on the ground. Zhu Zheqin recruited dozens of people to walk back and forth beside the pool, making sounds and playing chimes. She did not sing, but stood in the crowd, and all the sounds turned into ripples, reflected on the wall, turning the invisible into something tangible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The mystery of all things lies in the combination of things. The world is a temporary combination of consciousness, and music is sound. The essence of sound is waves and vibrations. So I think vibration is a very direct way to approach consciousness. . I am very lucky to be on this road.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;It was only when I became aware of my voice that I fully understood myself. I want to create a field and let everyone enter, so that people can realize that everyone is actually affected by something. Driven by an inner energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you are at the scene, as both Meng Ke Zhuolan and Guo Rong have described, it seems that everyone has come to another time and space, temporarily breaking away from external forces and moving inwards. Zhu Zheqin tried to create this feeling in his seven subsequent sound art works, including &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three lyrics in &quot;Ask the Mountain&quot; are also a portrayal of her journey back to her inner self. In the beginning, people looked at things through the universal laws of phenomena. The saying goes: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; When superficial phenomena are denied, solid and perfect things become vulnerable, and perfection is just a fantasy. This is: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, &quot;After the first year of the COVID-19 epidemic, I thought, when I was 6 years old, no one said that I would have concerts, wouldn&#39;t I still sing every day? I just love this thing, it is Bringing me joy in life, helping me grow and perceive the world, isn’t it more real than anything else? When you reach this point, you will see your true nature. Just like birds singing in the sky and fish swimming in the sea, if I have wings, I will Fly.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;In such an era, I think it is more important to maintain an imagination, maintain poetry, and maintain free thoughts about reality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this a mountain or a mountain? . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the concert &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;, everyone will get a small guide card at the entrance of the Valley Concert Hall, which reads: Creation stems from the perception of the mountains, and does not seek to understand the mountains and the world. Any definition of &quot;mountain dwelling&quot; nor explore any answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the performance, I walked up the mountain along the path connecting the Valley Concert Hall and the Upper Court. There was a small dark green sign hanging on a tree on the roadside, with a black arrow pointing to the depths of the mountain. There is a line of small words attached to the arrow: There will be answers in the mountains. Continuing in the direction pointed by the arrow, the same arrow guide appeared one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sign ends in front of an old cave. This is a small house built against a shallow cave, with three real people enshrined inside. There was a kang built against the wall. There were traces of fire underneath, but now the window paper was broken and air leaked from all sides. There was no sound for a while. Am I the only one in this world? &quot;Will there be answers in the mountains&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While listening to me talk about this experience, Zhu Zheqin looked at a certain place on the roof. The meditation room fell into silence, and became darker as the sky darkened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, she said, when you start asking, that is the beginning of the Tao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（感谢黄尧的帮助）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她研究在美中国本科留学生，发现高远志向下的挣扎和迷茫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259545]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QRIdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1226&quot; height=&quot;817&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QR IdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 17, 2022 local time, New York University graduates celebrated their graduation ceremony. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The annual application season for international students is here again. According to the &quot;2023 Study Abroad in China White Paper&quot; released by New Oriental, more than 50% of people intend to study abroad with a bachelor&#39;s degree or below. The situation of studying abroad is picking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, two other reports are also worthy of attention. On September 25, 2023, the National Student Credentials Certification Center in the United States released a report &quot;Completing College&quot; that showed that the undergraduate dropout rate for Chinese students in the United States was as high as 25%. In the same month, WholeRen, a Pennsylvania-based education consulting company, released the &quot;2023 White Paper on the Current Situation of Chinese Students in the United States.&quot; According to statistics, 70% of Chinese students who have been dismissed from the United States are undergraduates, and more than half of the students are studying in the top 50 schools in the United States. The top two reasons for being dismissed were academic dishonesty and poor academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The data only presents the tip of the iceberg. In the seemingly distant American education system, many Chinese students are indeed experiencing struggles under the glamorous impression&lt;/span>;. Ma Yingyi, a professor of sociology at Syracuse University in the United States, wrote the book &quot;Ambitious and Anxious: The Success and Struggle of Chinese College Students in American Higher Education&quot; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Ambitious and Anxious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;How Chinese College Students Succeed and Struggle in American Higher Education&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;) &lt;/span>;, describes the status of Chinese students in the United States as &quot;ambition and anxiety coexist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that whether they came from wealthy families or ordinary families, these international students began to experience this contradiction before arriving in the United States, and it intensified after entering college. They have big dreams, but in pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles and feel confused about their futures. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All this takes place against the background of the rapid development of Chinese society. All these anxieties forced them to think about the ultimate question: Is it really worth studying in the United States? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The samples surveyed by Ma Yingyi included 507 Chinese international students from 50 American undergraduate colleges and universities, all born in the 1990s. The survey period was from 2011 to 2019. The book won the 2021 American Association for Comparative and International Education Higher Education Best Book Award and the American Sociological Association’s Bourdieu Book Honor Award. Recently, Ma Yingyi accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The increase in undergraduate international students is not due to the financial crisis&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you pay attention to the group of Chinese international students in American undergraduate education? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My research began in 2011. At that time, major universities in the United States began to have a large number of Chinese undergraduates. Prior to this, most Chinese students studying abroad in the 1980s and 1990s studied in China for graduate school and then went to the United States to study for Ph.D., or they completed their undergraduate studies in China and then went to the United States for graduate school, as was the case for me. Twenty years ago, I first came to the United States after earning my bachelor&#39;s degree in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But around 2007, a large number of students came to the United States to study for undergraduates after completing high school in China, and some even went directly to the United States to study in high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is that most of the previous generation of international students either relied on scholarships from the United States to study for master&#39;s or doctoral degrees, or were sponsored by the Chinese government to study in the United States. As for the generation of undergraduates I follow, 90% are completely self-funded. For in-state students, tuition at public universities in the United States is very cheap, but international students have to pay extra, which is higher than out-of-state students, and private universities charge even more. Therefore, whether applying to public or private universities, the cost for Chinese international students is very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, this is a brand new phenomenon, reflecting the rise of the middle class and the accumulation of wealth in Chinese society. Then during the research process, I gradually discovered the duality of ambition and anxiety among this generation of international students. Whether it is academic or social life, or planning for the future, this contradiction is reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在市场上的留学中介会建议家长为孩子去美国留学准备一年一百万的巨额费用，相比英国、加拿大、澳大利亚、新加坡等地区花费更高。为什么还有那么多中国家庭愿意支付？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;美国本科留学的费用成本相比其他地区可能是最高的，所以很多人误认为，赴美留学的中国学生都是企业家的子女，但其实那样的人只是少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社会学里，收入和财富是两个不一样的概念。收入是你的工资，仅从收入来看，中国的中产阶层或许无力承担赴美的学费。但财富不一样，财富可以包括房产、股票等，在中国主要是房产。从2000年代开始，中国城市化发展迅猛，房市腾飞，许多并不算富裕的家庭也积累了一定的财富。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我收集到的样本中，有些父母是中学老师，有些甚至是基层工薪阶层。因为有房子，他们选择变现这个财富来支持孩子出国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;美国大学的老师们怎么看这种变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我曾遇到一位普渡大学的行政官员，他说学校在2008年金融危机以后出现了财政危机，恰好这个时候中国本科生来了，也有了支付高昂学费的能力。他形容这是一个“完美的婚姻”。我当时发现这是一个非常系统的现象，这背后不仅有双方的需求，于是开始着手研究。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;赴美本科留学生的增加是因为美国的金融危机吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多人说中国留学生的增加是在2008年金融危机之后，那时美国大学缺钱。但我的调查数据显示，中国赴美留学生人数年增长率最高的年份是2007年，是在金融危机之前。所以并不是美国大学的需求导致中国留学生迅速增加，更多是因为中国中产及以上阶层对于子女教育的需求。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时中国经历了经济发展迅速、中产阶级崛起，居民收入也迅速增加。我在书中提到的另一个因素是2006 到2014 年人民币升值，到2014 年，人民币升值了大约37%，中国家庭的支付能力更强了。另一方面是中国的好大学仍然非常难进，而美国目前为止仍然是世界上好大学最聚集的地方，所以很多人来到美国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;三个阶段都有“志向和焦虑并存”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的研究是如何展开的？又是怎样观察到“志向和焦虑并存”的情况？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的调查从2011年开始，最开始是用抽样法在线调查，再挑选出愿意参加深度访谈的学生。我们收到了来自50所院校的507 份调查问卷，最终对65名2013年到2016年在美国读本科的中国留学生做了深度访谈。我让学生选择英语或中文，几乎每个人都说中文。之后三年，我在中国六个城市的九所高中进行了实地调查，还采访了一些学校辅导员、校长和老师。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我把他们的经历分为三个阶段。第一个阶段是学生来美国之前，需要准备申请、考试、择校，整个过程充满焦虑，这很大程度来源于他们的抱负，因为他们就想进排名前30、前50的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个阶段是选专业。要选一个满足自己兴趣又好找工作的，这里开始出现与父母的矛盾。在社交阶段也焦虑，中国学生很不熟悉美国学生的社交方式和娱乐方式，导致难以融入。很多学生出国的目的就是想接触多元文化，接触不同的圈子，所以这也带来很大的压力和落差感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后一个阶段是对未来的规划。我做调研的时候，就业市场还不像现在这样，但也有各种问题。比如想留在美国就有签证的问题，回中国又有难以融入国内圈子、如何使用国内社会资本以及择业的问题。他们也迫切希望自己的学历和经历能够获得满意的回报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这三个阶段中都可以明显观察到这种“志向和焦虑并存”的二元性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相较于其他国家留学生而言，中国学生身上这种二元性会更突出吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;任何一个留学生都会面临这种状态。具体到中国留学生，不少人家里卖房或借贷供养孩子留学，这一代又大多是独生子女，很多人需要回到父母身边。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然从哲学的眼光来看待，志向本身就能产生焦虑。但中国留学生在这一点上更加突出，我在写作的过程中意识到，理解这一代留学生，其实非常重要的是理解他们背后的中国社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去二十年，中国社会其实也是一种志向和焦虑并存的状态。没有哪个国家像中国变化这么大，各个阶层的人都感受到很多变化，很多人实现了富裕，很多人有很大的抱负和野心。人们视野开阔，收入增加，同时也总在担心自己错失了什么机会，他们迫切希望获得国际视野，但这需要很多资源，人们也开始担心，自己的投资是否能获得足够的回报，这一切都带来焦虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自这个环境的中国留学生自然也如此。而且留学生在任何社会里都不是一个随机的人群，他们都是有志向、有一定特权的一群人。在社会学上，流动人口相对不流动人口是更具野心和目标性的。留学生要读书拿学位，要见识更大的世界，他们甚至背负着整个家族的期待和目光，承载着社会变迁带来的压力和机会，机遇和挑战并存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，中国的社会虽然发生了巨大的变化，但教育变化相对没有那么大，主要还在于高考仍是指挥棒。中国孩子和美国孩子接受的中小学教育差异非常大，中国留学生是带着中国教育的烙印到美国的高等教育去的，这个变化本身也给他们带来很大的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总而言之，中国留学生可能在全世界留学生群体里面，或者说流动人口里，是最具备“志向和焦虑二元性”的群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1007&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左：《雄心勃勃与忧心忡忡：中国大学生在美国高等教育中的成功与挣扎》。右：美国雪城大学社会学教授马颖毅。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;遭遇“落差感”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在书中还提到，一些中国留学生到美国后，会因学校在“村里”而震惊？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最有名的案例是伊利诺伊大学香槟分校，大家说它是一片玉米地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这和中美高等教育发展的历史有很大的关系。中国大学集中在大城市，而美国其实大城市没几个，但有很多大学城镇，就是在大农村建的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个州都有自己的旗舰学校，QS排名靠前的学校不一定在大城市里。当然大学排名是一个片面的、容易误导大家的信息。美国的大学非常多样，公立学校里有非常好的学术类院校，也有社区大学，不同的学校有不同的使命，它们没有严格意义上的优劣之分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么留学生那么看重大学排名？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;一个原因在于，美国的招生制度很不一样，它不是只看分数，你都不知道分数会占有多大比例，没有办法定量地判断是10%，还是5%，还是90%，每个学校都不一样，每个专业也不一样，每个学校不同年份也不一样，没有人会告诉你。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国学生也许因为这个学校的某项运动取得过很好的成绩、学校离家近，甚至风景好等各种五花八门的原因而选择。但中国学生不了解这些，大学排名就成为他们背负的压力和焦虑的其中一个来源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你的访谈对象中，这种“落差感”还出现在哪些方面？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;生活上的落差感，包括人际交往。他们此前可能认为美国人热情开放，后来才发现交朋友没有想象的那么容易。比如，有些学生刚开始雄心勃勃，希望能交到很多美国朋友，但很快受挫。美国大学生非常重要的社交娱乐方式是周末聚会，聚会上很多人都要喝酒，同时玩一些喝酒游戏，比如在一个啤酒瓶上放个乒乓球，大家一起吹，球击中了谁，谁就喝酒。很多中国孩子没办法加入其中，很多人觉得喝酒游戏难以忍受。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人就觉得很挫败，回到中国学生的圈子。这个圈子的娱乐可能是大家一起吃饭，去KTV唱歌，女孩逛街，男孩打游戏。很多中国学生会觉得，我出国不应该还是跟中国人在一起玩，甚至他们的父母会督促他们交美国朋友，说“不交美国朋友的话，你英语都还不如出国以前”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一位中国留学生，英语说得非常好，性格外向，有很多美国朋友，大家都以为他是在美国长大的。但他融入美国大学生圈子后，挺失望，没有像此前想象的那样享受多元文化，所以又回到了中国人的圈子，在中国留学生群体里承担领导职务，主持春晚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得这是一个很有趣的回归，出去转了一圈，想象破碎，再回来。在哲学意义上，这种回归是一个寻找自己的过程，尽管他表面上最后又回到中国学生当中，但他出来看过了、交往过了、感受过了不一样的世界，那和他当初没有走出去的状态，是完全不一样的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他们都是如何去适应这种“落差感”的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这种落差感会影响他们对留学的满意度，会影响他们整个状态，包括学习、社交、日常生活等，其实是很难适应的。但时间本身能带来习惯，一直不习惯的学生有可能会选择离开，比如说有些学生本科学校在美国的大农村，那他们毕业以后，就会申请去纽约、波士顿之类的大城市读研究生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总而言之还是要加深对自己和新环境的理解，留学之前，先了解自己到底想要什么，学校能够提供什么，尽量减少一些误解，才能减少之后因为误解带来的不满意和焦虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做一些准备工作对于适应环境很有好处，比如一位学生，家里条件比较好，父母在Twitter上给他找了一个美国朋友，专门陪他练口语、交流生活，还有一些学生会提前到美国学校附近适应环境。我还做了一些统计分析发现，多参加社团活动、参加学校组织等都可以提升学生的留学满意度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了生活，留学生不在课堂上发言，难以很好地融入课堂和学术活动其实也一直是个问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他们可能非常想表达、想参与，但很难参与。这种求而不得的状况，其实带来很多心理负担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于课堂讨论我有切身体验。我经常上课让同学们讨论，讨论不完全是对英语交流的挑战，语言是最基本的门槛，很多英语很好的同学同样难以参与讨论。我的调研显示，60%的学生都认为自己的英语很好，但所有学生里只有20%-30%的同学认为自己经常上课发言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是什么因素阻碍了他们？我认为，一个非常重要的原因是基本思维模式的差异，学生不能勇敢充分地表达自己。大多数中国课堂一直在寻求标准答案，学生总担心自己说出的话对不对。而美国大学课堂是开放式的讨论，没有正确答案，这是一个相当大的差异。中国学生需要改变思维模式，才能够有效地参与讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;扬长避短，而不是补差补缺&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这本书2020年出版，之后这3年间，我们都经历了更多变化，你有没有观察到一些新的情况？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;全世界的留学生在新冠疫情期间都很困难，旅行不便，远离家人，中国留学生应该说是处境更困难。我的基本结论没有改变，但这三年显然让“忧心忡忡”变严重了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;怎么理解“忧心忡忡”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;具体的挑战是不确定性，这体现在留学生活的方方面面。航班什么时候能增加？回国能不能容易一些？学生签证、工作签证怎么这么难办？美国的政策、舆论趋势等，都会增加中国学生的心理压力。这都是10年前的中国学生所没有的压力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，写这本书时，选择美国好像是非常一致的倾向，但现在有很多学生选择了欧洲、日本包括中国香港等，这是一个比较大的改变。近期发布的数据显示，在美的印度留学生已经超过了中国留学生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你如何看待留学低龄化的趋势？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;越来越多家庭选择送年龄小的孩子去留学，这可能是出于结构性的原因。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在标准化考试的淘汰体系里，大多数人都不是优胜者。有一些学生虽然成为了优胜者，但在这种竞争的环境下，他没办法获得比较平衡的身心发展，或者他不开心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以很多家庭选择低龄留学，显然大家都知道是有风险的，相比于大学生而言风险更高，但他们分析了风险和回报之后觉得利大于弊，才会做出这种选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对于中国留学生和家长有什么建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最重要的就是通过各种方式多去了解自己。比如通过父母、朋友，或者通过参与各种活动去更全面地认识自己。留学其实只是打开了一个窗口，来了以后要做出很多选择，包括选什么课、参加什么样的社团、选择怎样的未来道路等等。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国高等教育一个很大的优势，就是提供了很多选择。一个人要做出适合自己的选择，非常重要的前提就是自我认知。所以要了解自己，了解自己优势是什么，弱点是什么，对哪些东西有热情，哪些能力是培养不出来的。一个人不可能擅长所有的东西，现代社会最重要的是，要做自己擅长和感兴趣的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果不够了解自己的话也没有关系，我觉得这是一辈子的功课。但是学生现在要有这种意识，从现在就开始关注自己的兴趣特长，扬长避短，而不是去补差补缺。我觉得学生和家长都需要做出思维上的调整。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以舆论战开打，以色列缘何撤销公共外交部？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259553]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, 2023 local time, the Israeli cabinet decided to revoke the country’s main responsibility for public diplomacy through a telephone vote. , the Ministry of Information for External Propaganda Affairs (generally referred to as the &quot;Public Ministry of Foreign Affairs&quot; in news reports), and said that the ministry&#39;s budget will be transferred to the recovery and reconstruction of communities around the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a gesture by the Israeli government directed at both its domestic public and the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Abolish the so-called inaction departments internally, find scapegoats, and try to homogenize domestic public opinion. It has demonstrated its determination to burn its boats to the outside world, and any attempt by the outside world to interfere with Israel&#39;s will will be rejected. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does the dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs mean? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The term &quot;public diplomacy&quot; was first proposed by Professor Edmund Glean of Tufts University in the United States in 1965. He believed that public diplomacy is to ensure that one&#39;s own country maintains effective relations with foreign countries. Thought connection”. More generally speaking, public diplomacy is a strategic plan to carry out national marketing and create a positive and good international image. It is a &quot;popular project&quot; to win the hearts and minds of the international people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Israel directly announced the immediate dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs. It is obvious that it has deeply felt the changes in international public opinion. Israel’s external propaganda department cannot escape the blame for this, although Israel is doing a positive job The battlefield has an overwhelming advantage, but the corresponding situation is not shown on the battlefield of public opinion. The reasons behind this are worthy of scrutiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, global public opinion has embarrassed Israel, which not only seriously interferes with Israel&#39;s upcoming retaliatory actions, but also has the potential to further weaken Israel&#39;s internal unity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this atmosphere, Minister of Public Foreign Affairs Atbaryan&#39;s voluntary resignation not only gave herself a step down, but also showed her support for the Netanyahu government. She said, &quot;Put aside Self-deprecation aside, running a ministry in such a horrific time of war is an expensive problem and the Israeli people need every shekel.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, the latest opinion poll conducted by the &quot;Jerusalem Post&quot; showed that nearly four-fifths of the people believe that the Netanyahu government needs to deal with this large-scale Hamas infiltration and Responsible for the massacre of Jews, the Israeli government must not only unite internally and externally at this moment, but also consider a potential post-war political reckoning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Israel’s internal struggles remain complex and changeable, which has profoundly affected Israel’s security environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israeli media pointed out that the Ministry of Public Affairs not only failed to fulfill its obligations, but even interfered in Israel&#39;s internal affairs for a long period of time. This minister from the Likud Party has used his power to vigorously promote the government&#39;s judicial reform and made a series of inflammatory remarks. For example, in April 2023, Atbaryan directly pointed out that the military, police and media composed of The deep state network is working hard to overthrow the government, which is reminiscent of how the Turkish government described the Gulen movement before the attempted coup in 2016, highlighting that the Israeli state and society are gradually being torn apart. In addition, she has launched scar-revealing attacks on her political critics, underscoring her right-wing conservative ultra-hardline political stance, which runs counter to Israel&#39;s desire to be diplomatic in its international propaganda matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on October 12, before the department was disintegrated, she issued a resignation statement, saying that the power of her department had been weakened, and there was an overlap of powers between the Ministry of Expatriate Affairs and the Ministry of Public Affairs. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs only received its budget six months after the new government was formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first cabinet member to resign after a new round of conflict between Palestine and Israel broke out. This is just a microcosm of Israel’s domestic struggle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Palestinian-Israeli conflict, analyzed only from a technical level and from an absolutely neutral political stance, has greatly shocked Israel. It is comparable in form to the Fourth Middle East War and in terms of psychological trauma. Compared with the &quot;9·11&quot; incident in the United States. This is not unrelated to the division of domestic public opinion caused by Israel&#39;s promotion of judicial reform in the past year. The root cause is the long-standing dispute between left and right, religious and secular disputes in Israel&#39;s internal affairs, as well as the frequent changes of governments in recent years. hidden fundamental crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, fortresses are breached from within. Israel’s recent political chaos has seriously affected its military and intelligence systems, giving Hamas room to take advantage of the situation. In addition, the peace process between Israel and Saudi Arabia About to enter its final chapter, Hamas urgently needs to give the international community a heavy blow and prove to the world that Middle East reconciliation that bypasses the Palestinian-Israeli issue is putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs heralds the imminence of a larger-scale bloody operation. Israel is consolidating all resources and preparing for war. Israel&#39;s domestic thinking in fighting Palestine urgently needs to form a united front. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel’s move is also preparing for the worst for the safety of the hostages, that is, it ignores the hostage weight in the hands of Hamas, ignores domestic and foreign voices in favor of reconciliation negotiations, and treats Hamas the possibility of a complete liquidation. But this is undoubtedly a difficult decision. Hundreds of thousands of soldiers on the Israeli border are hesitant. During Biden&#39;s visit, he issued &quot;Advice to Israel&quot; and so on. These all prove that the large-scale ground war against Gaza will not only affect Israel&#39;s The international image is more likely to cause further division within Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The situation on the battlefield of public opinion is tense&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a medium for public diplomacy and a window for understanding the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the importance of public opinion is self-evident. With the many conflicts that have broken out in recent years Similarly, the public opinion field is the second battlefield opened by all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, various advanced technological means, such as 5G, streaming media, artificial intelligence and mobile-based social media networks, have made the battlefield of public opinion mixed, making it difficult to distinguish between true and false, and the situation is changing rapidly, which has brought about The &quot;information tide&quot; has a strong ability to induce and differentiate positions and values ​​and create opposing emotions for the public who lack certain professional knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the public opinion war in this Palestinian-Israeli conflict, it has the following three major characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the mature development of streaming media and online live broadcast technology has given global audiences a stronger audio-visual impact on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. The timeliness and impact of information dissemination have greatly increased, and it has also provided opportunities for the proliferation of false information. It has provided a breeding ground for various conspiracy theories, historical-realistic information confusion and propaganda, and fake accounts and robot trolls have emerged one after another on social media. While expanding attention, it has also set off a confrontation between the two factions around the world. These include positional opposition (supporting Israel or supporting Pakistan), religious opposition (Judaism and Islam), ethnic opposition (Arabs and Jews), and intra-sect opposition (moderate factions exist within both Arabs and Jews). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Hamas launched its attack, it used heavy bulldozers to break through the Gaza separation wall and carry out bloody killings inside the Israeli border posts. The video was broadcast live on the Internet. This video set off a new wave of sectarianism in the Arab world. , nationalistic sentiments, but also directly angered groups sympathetic to Jews. It is precisely because of the popularity of the Internet and mobile devices that war has achieved a certain form of visibility and transparency, and has become a hotbed and soil for breeding public opinion wars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, when the Western media reported on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the wording was the Israel-Hamas War, not the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. This highlights the asymmetric nature of the conflict and is a precautionary endorsement of a potential high-intensity Israeli military strike. Hidden behind this is the challenge to the loopholes in international law and the laws of war. Because the laws of war are applicable to sovereign states, the Israeli Defense Forces&#39; attack on Hamas is most likely to be a &quot;police-like war.&quot; Such a narrative will also separate the public from the perspective of ethnic and religious conflicts. The legitimacy of the war on terrorism is obviously greater than the battle for territory. It can be seen that the inclusion of stance in narrative strategies is an eternal pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the public opinion war in this conflict has typical sinking and spillover effects. This conflict has transcended the conflicts between Palestine and Israel and Kazakhstan and Israel, and has shown a trend of spillover and camp formation. Currently, both sides are working hard to seek legitimacy for the war, and have moved from the level of international authoritative media to the level of mass entertainment media. The two sides are competing for the right to speak across the air in other countries. This is not common in previous war conflicts, but it is inevitable for the vigorous development of modern information technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, after Israel announced the dissolution of its Public Ministry of Foreign Affairs, it has in a sense reaped the consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, Hamas publicly released two old Israeli women. A video of them shaking hands with masked Hamas members and saying goodbye went viral on social platforms, and they later faced dozens of reporters. , the released elderly people said that Hamas treated them very friendly and responded to their requests. The accounts of those who have witnessed it are extremely impactful, which has compressed the public opinion space in Israel now and even for a long time in the future, and also caused doubts in the Israeli media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The game between Palestine and Israel has never stopped when narrating the war. The mutual siege is not only a portrayal of the real battlefield, but also a manifestation of online public opinion. This is a microcosm of the structural contradiction between Palestine and Israel in the field of international political communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;（作者杨府鑫为浙江外国语学院环地中海研究院助理研究员；马晓霖为浙江外国语学院教授、环地中海研究院院长）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[难以推开的石门，看完很扎心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 22:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;In recent years, female-themed works have exploded, but most of them Focusing on the plight of urban women, there are still very few films with small town women as protagonists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which was recently released on streaming media, is a precious image of the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;01&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;The directors of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; are rising independent film stars Huang Ji and Otsuka Ryuji, who are a husband-and-wife team. The two co-produced the &quot;Women&#39;s Trilogy&quot; &quot;Eggs and Stones&quot;, &quot;Stupid Bird&quot; and this &quot;Stone Gate&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;391&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in Hunan In the small town, Huang Ji&#39;s perspective mainly focuses on the survival plight of rural women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Eggs and Stones&quot; focuses on the left-behind girls who were sexually assaulted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stupid Bird&quot; &quot;Through the carrier of &quot;mobile phone&quot;, it shows the growing confusion of left-behind girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;759&quot; height= &quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot; It takes the experiences of female college student Lin Sen as a slice to reflect reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ages of the heroines in the trilogy are consistent, they are 14, 17 and 20 years old respectively, and the same actor Yao Honggui was chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is more mature than the previous two films. The film style is very similar to the early works of domestic sixth-generation directors that we are familiar with. It uses non-professional actors, talks about marginalized groups, and prefers extreme Life-like scenes and an objective and calm perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the kernel , with Huang Ji’s own characteristics and personal experience, his friend and work partner Otsuka Ryuji can also make some observations about the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;02&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The narrative of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; relies on the three identities of a 20-year-old girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, she is Lin Sen, a beautiful female college student, studying as a flight attendant at a vocational school. She has a stable relationship with her boyfriend Liu Long, who even paid for her to enroll in an English training class. With the unexpected pregnancy, Lin Sen&#39;s life also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen&#39;s My parents run a small clinic. The father is disabled, the mother is addicted to micro-business, and a medical accident that caused a female patient to miscarry made the family worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sensible Lin In order to help his family pay off debts, Sen started working crazily to earn money. She worked as an opening welcome model and also went to shopping malls to sell milk powder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; height= &quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpected pregnancy and Family debt caused Lin Sen&#39;s originally peaceful life to plummet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen has no intention of becoming a mother, her boyfriend cannot be held responsible, and her creditor wants a child. With the help of her parents, she agreed to an incredible plan to give birth to a child to pay off the debt to the poor woman &quot;Yinfang&quot; who unfortunately had a miscarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pregnancy is a unique life experience for women. The difficulties unmarried young women face when they have an unexpected pregnancy, whether to have an abortion or not, are common themes in feminist films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Romanian film &quot;April, Three Weeks and Two Days&quot; and the French film &quot;As It Happens&quot; are both set in the last century when abortion was not accepted by most countries. Due to the complex social status quo, women Uterine autonomy is often not possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American movie &quot; &quot;Juno&quot; and the Norwegian film &quot;Ninja Babies&quot; focus on the physical changes and mental stress that pregnancy and childbirth bring to women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In domestic movies , Li Yu&#39;s &quot;Beautiful Beauty&quot; also reproduces the various pressures faced by women after unexpected pregnancy, mainly due to the relatively conservative social public opinion environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference in &quot;Stone Gate&quot; lies in the alternative way of handling the heroine Lin Sen&#39;s pregnancy - not having an abortion but abandoning her for adoption. ‍‍‍‍‍‍Children are also used as a commodity to solve her immediate life problems. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, this is Lin Sen’s active choice, but the film also pays attention to the soft coercion she suffered. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like at the beginning of the film, her boyfriend took her to an English speaking training venue. Others were communicating freely, and the topic revolved around the country they wanted to go to. After Lin Sen found that she couldn’t fit in, she went to the Start playing with your phone on the sofa. She has no strong desire to improve her English. She came here because her boyfriend took the initiative to make the choice for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;842&quot; height= &quot;375&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍This one , we can clearly feel the girl Lin Sen&#39;s numbness towards life and new life, the lack of vitality and confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high frequency of static shots in the film further exaggerates this sense of silent despair. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen She rarely showed her emotions. Even when her boyfriend asked for an abortion, she didn&#39;t make a fuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the pain in her breasts during pregnancy and the tearing during childbirth, as well as Lin Sen’s unbearable expression and voice, tell us that her pain is indeed real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In pain and In confusion, she gradually lost control of her destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;03&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The plot of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is not complicated, but the film is 147 minutes long because the director placed many shots on the social landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many scenes, Lin Sen does not participate in the main narrative, appearing as a background board and becoming a silent observer. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, she would watch her boyfriend shoot a Douyin wedding promotional video, and watch underground industry managers openly interview young girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen’s mother Obsessed with selling three-no products and telling his story at the organization&#39;s annual meeting. ‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outbreak Later, crowds of people gathered at medical equipment institutions to buy medical masks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is &quot; The biggest feature of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is also the film&#39;s problem. On the one hand, the unrestrained display of shots greatly affects the rhythm of the narrative, and too many idle strokes make the movie long and boring. On the other hand, it also leads to the heroine becoming a tool, making the entire story biased towards curiosity and lacking the power to move people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although film and television works showing women in small towns have been relatively scarce in recent years, they were not uncommon in previous years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excellent works can maintain an excellent balance in grasping female narratives and social and cultural landscapes. Let’s not mention the classic representative works of the fourth and fifth generation directors, such as &quot;Qiu Ju&#39;s Lawsuit&quot;, &quot;The Love of Humans and Ghosts&quot;, &quot;The Beginning of Spring&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here is an example of an unpopular masterpiece - &quot;The Crying Woman&quot;. The director and screenwriter of this film, Liu Bingjian, used the story of Wang Guixiang, a Guizhou woman who made money through mourning, to show the public that China has a long history of funeral culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;639&quot; height= &quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wang Guixiang Her strong vitality, her shrewd and kind feminine charm, and the warmth and warmth of people in rural society can all leave a deep impression on people. &quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which failed to do this, also formed a contradiction, with its novel subject matter but bland plot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is worth mentioning that &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is almost the same as a documentary in terms of realism. It is a story that grows out of the shooting environment and the actors&#39; performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors who play Lin Sen’s parents are director Huang Ji’s biological parents. They run this clinic in reality, and their home is also the real residence of the director and his wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This movie Filmed over a ten-month period following the pregnancy cycle, and with a limited budget, it didn&#39;t have a set designed in advance like many films, and the actors were thrown directly into real space. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha is the main filming location. The lens captures its glamorous and prosperous side, as well as its chaotic and dark corners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍‍In addition to the director The camera strives to be close to reality, and also tries its best to show the living conditions of girls in non-developed areas. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original setting of the heroine Lin Sen was an imaginary image of a proactive female college student. But this was completely different from the state of actor Yao Honggui at the time, and it was also different from the current situation of many young college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director and his wife rewrote the character design, and the protagonist’s story is a mixed experience of female college students obtained from interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the unexpected pregnancy experience of a small town girl, the film reflects the structural dilemma of this group. It originates from many constraints such as patriarchy, commodity society, and power class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255879&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine was The oppression does not occur openly, but it does not mean that multiple exploitation does not exist. This complex structural dilemma creates a low margin for error in women’s choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, it seems that Lin Sen can make different choices, take the initiative to have an abortion, not pay off the debt for his mother, or give birth to a child and raise him, but no life path will become easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are too many stone doors in her life that are difficult to push open, and she can only avoid falling by climbing hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ending of the film It is open-ended, and we have no way of knowing the final fate of the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the audience can see is that the male employer hopes to postpone the adoption date due to the epidemic. The heroine Lin Sen, who is waiting for the handover, was triggered by the child&#39;s cry and got chest pain and got out of the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it hurts and there is no escape. Escape, the pain is still there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of hope in her life made her breathless. However, instead of floating helplessly in the ocean of life, it is better to fight hard and push open the stone door to try to welcome new life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>