<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“旧式太太”与“新女性”：香港作家笔下的五四婚姻与女性命运]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258421]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/SDR2BRTIWWWHLJOKQPovkipsqx1v2adqelohmrupn.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 842 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;1206&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/medias/ima/ima GE/23/10/11/SDR2BRTIWHLJOKQPOVKIPSQX1v2adqelohmrupn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253795&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lin Huiyin is China&#39;s first female architect. When she was critically ill, she asked to see Xu Zhimo&#39;s ex-wife Zhang Youyi, and the two finally met. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A century ago, an ordinary village in southeast England witnessed an extraordinary event. The village is called Shaxton, and the protagonists of the incident are two young Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boys have been studying in the United States and the United Kingdom for more than two years, and the girls just left a conservative small town in China a few weeks ago; the boys are auditors at Cambridge University, and the girls have only learned basic daily English for a few weeks. ; The boy wants to be a pioneer in the new era and become a blockbuster, while the girl just hopes to adapt to life in a foreign country and have the opportunity to learn some new knowledge; the boy falls in love with a girl who comes from a reformist family and is studying in the UK at the time. Not long after the girl arrives in London, she vaguely notices her husband. There is another person that I like, but I still hope that my husband, who has always regarded me as a &quot;country bumpkin&quot;, can communicate more with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This couple is Xu Zhimo and Zhang Youyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 1921, less than nine months after Zhang Youyi was sent to England by her parents-in-law, Xu Zhimo suddenly filed for divorce and left without saying goodbye a week later, leaving her who was more than three months pregnant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2001, Hong Kong scholar and writer Kong Huiyi passed through Shaxton. The size of the town expanded and the old houses were demolished, but the practical and boring temperament did not change. She thought at the time: The struggle of a young Chinese woman in the early 20th century was buried in this inconspicuous place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, she thought again: How could the story of Chinese women be buried in just one or two places? The idea eventually evolved into a book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese women&#39;s movement began in the 1880s, with two major slogans: &quot;anti-foot-binding&quot; and &quot;promoting women&#39;s education.&quot; At that time, both the reformers and the revolutionary men believed that self-improvement was the basis for national salvation, so they included women&#39;s issues on the social reform agenda. At this time, the expectations for women were still limited to being good wives and mothers. Although they had greatly developed physically and mentally compared with their predecessors, they still only fulfilled their traditional family roles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The New Culture Movement broke the traditional family operating model of elders and younger ones, striving for personal and individual liberation. This new trend created another ideal image of free and independent women. To be called a &quot;May Fourth&quot; new woman with an independent personality, she must meet several conditions: receive education in a new-style school; have a career after graduation; be independent in marriage; and participate in public life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, education is the foundation. For adult women, they are unable to strive for new educational opportunities, so in the era of drastic changes, they are labeled as backward and feudal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Huiyi hopes to break this simple label division and &quot;explore whether the women of the May Fourth era can be revalued in a fair manner and whether the world they face can be seen from their perspective.&quot; In &quot;May 4th Marriage&quot;, she went against the tradition of male-centered biographies and turned her pen to seven women: Zhu An, Xu Guangping, Jiang Dongxiu, Cao Peisheng, Zhang Youyi, Lu Xiaoman, and Lin Huiyin, trying to explore through their life circumstances the problems faced by women at that time. practical problems, depicting the various faces of Chinese women in the period of change. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The trend of &quot;escape from marriage&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Whether it is the new cultural movement or the new concept of women, they all have the same core issues: marital autonomy and divorce. Since most young people had entered into arranged marriages at that time, there was a trend of &quot;escape from marriage&quot; - young men leaving home alone to start a new life in order to get rid of their old wives. According to a 1922 women&#39;s publication, 70% of the old-style wives abandoned by the new youth in Henan Province ended up committing suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reality of marriage and divorce in the new cultural period is a mirror that reflects how the drastic changes in social norms affect women from different backgrounds, and how they deal with the tide of change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Huiyi wrote about Zhu An, hoping to &quot;find their voices for a generation of women who have suffered a lot and are speechless.&quot; When Lu Xun started his second marriage, he did not abandon his first wife Zhu An financially and nominally. However, the blow to Zhu An was emotional and spiritual. When she was still alive, Lu Xun and the people around him regarded her as a gift that could not be refused. She might be worthy of pity, but not respect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous biographies surrounding Lu Xun, descriptions of Zhu An often tended to indicate that he was &quot;inadequate&quot;. Kong Huiyi pointed out that this historical perspective of discrimination against old women is based on prejudice and does not really reflect the mentality and personality of the person involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu An was interviewed by reporters in her later years. When talking about her relationship with Lu Xun and Xu Guangping, she once said: &quot;Mr. Zhou was not bad to me. There were no quarrels between us. We each have our own lives. I He should be forgiven... Mr. Xu treats me very well, she understands my thoughts, and she is willing to support me... She is indeed a good person.&quot; It can be seen from her words that she puts Lu Xun and Xu Guangping on an equal footing with herself On the other hand, she had no jealousy towards Xu Guangping, but instead established a mutually respectful relationship with her. This is no easy task, and this shows that her heart and character cannot be summed up simply by the label &quot;old woman&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu An was sacrificed between the old and the new. In contrast, Xu Guangping had the opportunity to receive modern education and enter the world of new women. However, the marriage relationship established through free love and personal choice caused Xu Guangping to lose his original independent status. She had her own career before she and Lu Xun lived together. After arriving in Shanghai, she actively looked for a job. However, she later became Lu Xun&#39;s secretary and assistant, embarking on a completely different path than she originally expected - becoming a virtuous person in the new cultural norms. A good wife and mother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guangping has always kept three hundred yuan in savings as &quot;emergency money&quot; and publicly told Lu Xun and his friends that if their relationship breaks down, the money can temporarily maintain her livelihood until she resumes her life. Get a job. A meager three hundred yuan became Xu Guangping&#39;s only way to maintain his independent personality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The traditional concept of &quot;men taking charge outside and women taking charge inside&quot; has not been diminished by the New Culture Movement. When Lin Huiyin faced Liang Sicheng, who was pragmatic and capable and treated her well, she could not help but complain that she was burdened with housework and was unable to develop her talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1950s and 1950s, although many women had successful careers, they were unable to get rid of the dilemma of marriage and love throughout their lives. Cao Peisheng is an extreme example. She married the husband arranged by her parents at the age of sixteen. With the support of her brother studying in the United States, she continued to study at the Women&#39;s Normal School when she was eighteen. When her husband&#39;s family decided to have a concubine, Cao Peisheng resolutely left the marriage. Soon after, she fell in love with Hu Shi. At that time, Hu Shi had been married to Jiang Dongxiu for six years and had three children. Hu Shi failed to divorce, and the two fell in love for three years, but the hopeless relationship was finally shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the first female professor of agriculture in China, Cao Peisheng has made extraordinary achievements in cotton and potato research and genetics. However, her bitter love with Hu Shi lingered throughout her life. She filled in a lot of words, constantly remembering the passionate love that year. After his death, he was buried on the only road from his hometown to Hu Shi&#39;s hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Huiyi believes that Cao Peisheng’s situation reflects the conflict between old and new culture. New women and their love partners often cannot control the compass of life. Although their eyes are on the new world, they are faced with the reality created by the old tradition. Stumble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/hr2KLTa7VdEADCwhMyt0UrsUlRnkbZScs5KLBFGv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/hr2KLTa7VdEADCwhMyt0UrsUlRnkbZScs5KLBFGv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253794&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1930, Xu Guangping took a photo with her husband Lu Xun and son Zhou Haiying. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Between the Old and the New&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Cao Peisheng was born in 1902 In that year, the Qing government issued an edict to &quot;anti-foot-binding&quot; and &quot;promote women&#39;s education.&quot; There is a gulf between what government says is one thing and how society works is another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actual effect of the ban was very small. The custom of foot binding continued to flourish until the early years of the Republic of China, and Cao Peisheng was not spared. She left her hometown in 1915 and followed her married brother Cao Chengke&#39;s family to Wuchang. Cao Chengke asked a tutor to teach his sister instead of sending her to a new school. This also shows that although the slogan of &quot;promoting girls&#39; education&quot; has been shouted for more than ten years, the results are still limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the new cultural transformation stage, the boundaries between the old and the new are far less clear-cut than imagined. Xu Guangping was born in Guangzhou. His mother is from Macau and his maternal grandfather is an overseas Chinese. However, his mother&#39;s family attaches great importance to the &quot;three-inch golden lotus&quot;, so they forced Xu Guangping to bind his feet. However, his father did not agree. However, the reason was that Xu Guangping had been married since he was a child. , she will marry into a country family in the future, and her small feet will be an obstacle to her married life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elders on the father&#39;s side did not allow girls in the family to study, thinking that it would dampen the ambition of boys. Xu Guangping&#39;s mother, who had studied with her brothers, raised objections and won the opportunity for her daughter to enter a private school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guangping’s parents had conflicting views on their daughter’s foot-binding and schooling issues, which reflected the social background at that time: even though they lived in Guangzhou and Macau, which had a lot of contact with the outside world, the people’s understanding of “new” and “old” The measurement is still uneven, there is no fixed standard, and opinions are mostly influenced by personal experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, the term &quot;new woman&quot; also has multi-layered connotations. Jiang Dongxiu, newly added to the simplified version of &quot;May Fourth Marriage&quot;, has never attended a new school and has no career of her own. However, she learned to write letters in vernacular after marriage and tried to write an autobiography. Twenty years of living in Beijing transformed her. He has his own opinions and social circle, and also fights for the rights of Liang Zongdai&#39;s first wife, appearing in court as a witness in their divorce lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She is not limited to any frame. She is neither a traditional woman who &#39;obeys her husband&#39; or &#39;submit her son&#39;, nor is she a new-style Yun Niang who follows her husband and his wife, nor is she a Western-style lady who likes to dress up fashionably.&quot; In Kong Huiyi&#39;s view, Jiang Dongxiu, who has an independent personality and individuality, is also an atypical &quot;new woman&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared to Jiang Dongxiu who &quot;steps out of the box&quot;, Lu Xiaoman, who seems to be trendy, is actually the one who &quot;falls into the cracks&quot;. She reflected another common new image of women in society at that time - leisurely at home, dressed fashionably, and her daily life consisted of shopping, attending theaters, playing cards, and dancing. In her early years, she was in and out of social circles and was the envy of everyone. Xu Zhimo made her leave her original life track. The new social circle forced her to face the scrutiny of another new female standard. In Xu Zhimo&#39;s circle of friends, no one would think that a modern woman who is accustomed to the life of an official wife is the new woman in their eyes. Lu Xiaoman is like a lost person, falling into the cracks of culture. Among them, the influence of family cannot be ignored. The female model she can refer to - the circle in which her mother hangs out, are such upper-class wives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the first wives of new culture celebrities, Zhang Youyi has left the farthest. Today, people associate her name with successful career women, but they tend to ignore the various conditions required for old women to grow into new women. Reflection on this point is the book&#39;s deep attention to female identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Trapped alone in England became a turning point in Zhang Youyi&#39;s fate. After joining her brother in Europe, she regained her ideal of studying at a normal school before marriage and studied in Germany for more than three years, which had a decisive impact on her path after returning to China. Later, it was a story that people talked about: he took charge of the Shanghai Women&#39;s Bank, served as the manager of Yunshang Clothing Company, and became famous in Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after having a successful career, Zhang Youyi still felt inferior and could not let go of the fact that she had received less new education. In her later years, she recounted the past to her grandniece Zhang Bangmei and said: &quot;In China, women are nothing: they obey their father at home, their husbands when they get married, and their sons after their husbands die.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this book, the last person to appear is It was Lin Huiyin, who was also born the latest among the seven women. As the leader of the May Fourth New Women in many people&#39;s minds, Lin Huiyin has achieved a rare balance between career and marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Douban netizen wrote a comment for &quot;May Fourth Marriage&quot;: &quot;Leaving Lin Huiyin for the last time really has a special meaning. This sense of strength is both the intentional cultivation of the family (father) and personal sensitivity and wisdom. , and cannot be separated from Liang Sicheng&#39;s inner stable &quot;freedom&quot; - which is also the only equality and autonomy in several relationships. Even so, it is difficult to escape the troubles of upbringing and family chores, not to mention the repeated hammering of the great waves of the times. The author has already stated that it is difficult to turn around: one must be young, have a good family background, and have fathers and brothers who are sensible and supportive of women—Zhang Youyi’s luck is a personal achievement and indeed a gift from fate.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;“To this day, women still face a lot of traditional pressure”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The order of the characters in this book seems to have a special meaning. Have you had any special considerations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Before I started writing, I felt that the descriptions of the so-called old women and new women failed to show the reality of the period of cultural drastic changes. To change the traditional conclusion about women, in addition to the author&#39;s basic position, we must also have substantial and reliable materials. As far as first-hand information is concerned, I always think it is inherently insufficient. How to remedy it? Choosing characters whose life lines have intersected can provide readers with overlapping visual effects, allowing everyone to better understand that things are not black and white. I feel that this book is a bit like a jigsaw puzzle with some missing pieces, relying only on the integration and comparison of the existing pieces to give readers a rough idea of ​​the overall picture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Seven women have various contrasts. Among them, Cao Peisheng There seems to be a sharp contrast with Zhang Youyi, one who has a successful career but is trapped in love all his life, and one who donates autumn fans but shines in the workplace. When you first read and sorted out the life experiences of these women, did you intuitively experience a sense of reflection? Or experienced a deepening of cognition? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Their experiences have some similarities. For example, after their marriages failed, they both received valuable opportunities for further study, and also gained valuable opportunities in their respective lives. The industry writes a new page for women. I think the differences between them in life are mainly due to their personalities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When collecting materials, I did not deliberately make comparisons, but the process of writing a book is like making friends with the characters in the book. The understanding will deepen, just like making friends in reality, and you will embrace them. Looking at their lives with an understanding attitude, they often have the feeling that &quot;people are different and each has their own face.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You emphasize the merging of boundaries between the new and the old in the new cultural transformation stage It’s not as clear as imagined. Is this one of the important starting points for you in writing this book? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is indeed a very important point. I have always been skeptical of black and white discussions, because our own experiences constantly remind us that life is not black and white. To this day, women still face many traditional pressures. For example, if you study for two more degrees, you will be warned that you will not be able to get married; if you don&#39;t get married, you will become the target of preaching every time relatives get together; if you get married and don&#39;t have children, you will be accused of being &quot;selfish.&quot; All these are just trivial matters, but they are annoying enough. Not to mention being belittled and taken advantage of in the workplace. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This kind of narrative in the book can also be seen as old and new Ambiguity of concept and identity: Unlike Zhu An and Lu Xiaoman, Jiang Dongxiu has truly gained respect in her husband&#39;s circle of friends. What factors do you think lead to this difference? At that time, were the standards for evaluating women in cultural circles complex and diverse? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Tang Degang said that Jiang Dongxiu was lucky. I agree very much because her husband has a gentle personality and a Western gentlemanly demeanor towards women, which makes her She can play to her strengths. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the cultural circle is not single. Each circle has its own internal operating standards. For example, when Zhu An was in the big Xintaimen family of the Zhou family, he would not be considered unqualified; Lu Xiaoman was the envy of everyone when he was in and out of social circles in his early years. It is only after entering a new circle that they are measured by another standard. Even if it is not a period of cultural upheaval, there are examples of such situations. For example, when an ordinary family marries a wealthy family, both parties will face new standards of measurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“When it comes to women’s experience, economic issues always rear their heads”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The article mentions that Lin Huiyin is regarded by many as China&#39;s leading new woman in the 20th century, and the same appreciation is revealed between the lines in your words. Lin Huiyin&#39;s consistent choices in career and relationships, in addition to her rationality and determination, does she have any deeper qualities? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What I appreciate most is Lin Huiyin’s calm attitude. As she said herself, she is a person with equally strong reason and emotion, so I believe that her decision is not purely driven by reason, but &quot;love&quot; also plays a large role. Speaking of being calm, I think this may be the reason why she wanted to see Zhang Youyi when she was critically ill - because Zhang Youyi&#39;s abandonment had something to do with her, she couldn&#39;t be calm. It is impossible to know what she wanted to say at that time. If I put on my hat as a novelist and made up a sentence for her, it would be &quot;I admire you.&quot; However, maybe she really doesn&#39;t need to speak: Zhang Youyi is willing to see her, she has the demeanor of a successful lady, and she has children and grandchildren around her, so she can feel at ease. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why was the character Jiang Dongxiu not included in the first edition? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a very important question. When I wrote the first version, I felt that Jiang Dongxiu was elusive. Looking back, it was a bit paradoxical, because I later realized that the biggest obstacle might be mahjong. This is related to the situation of big family gatherings when I was a child. During every festive occasion, the elders would always play mahjong when they got together, which we children found very noisy. But it was mahjong that finally broke the psychological barrier for me: One of my great-aunts was critically ill and was hospitalized. When relatives came to visit, she said in confusion, &quot;Ask the servant to open the table for you.&quot; This finally made me understand the role of mahjong in that generation. social function. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xu Guangping &quot;founded through free love and personal choice The marriage relationship actually caused her to lose her original independent status.&quot; In your observation, what are the significant similarities and differences between the situation of contemporary Chinese women in the workplace, marriage and love, compared with those during the New Culture Movement? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t know much about the lives of the younger generation in mainland China, so it is difficult to make in-depth comparisons. All we can say is this: Human nature is basically the same, and this is largely the source of women’s distress. For example, everyone thinks that women are attentive and good at taking care of others, so the young and old in the family are all supported by women. Even in the West, the women&#39;s movement has been booming for decades. When a couple gives birth to a child, the financial burden of child care is too heavy. If one of them is required to stay at home to take care of the child, the woman will always resign or work part-time, and the man will be responsible. Raising children is a hit or miss, and the result is that when retirement comes, women&#39;s pensions are far lower than men&#39;s. When it comes to the female experience, financial issues always rear their heads. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the differences between now and the May Fourth Movement, the main reason is that the social structure is different. The population has moved to big cities, and urban culture provides more opportunities for women. Population policy has also left many families with only one daughter. Now girls are treated much better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After nearly ten years of revising this book, what new understandings have you gained? and thinking? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first realization is to see your own blind spots, which are Jiang Dongxiu and Mahjong mentioned above. In addition, you can appreciate the role that details can play. For example, in the chapter about Xu Guangping, the new edition provides a lot of figures, including her salary in Guangzhou and prices in the 1940s, so the narrative is broader. Of course, the pursuit of details cannot be endless, and in the end you have to face the shortcomings calmly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Passing through Shaxton was an opportunity to write a book. While writing this book, did you visit any other places associated with your subjects? Can you share one or two of your travels that touched you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Kong Huiyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What impressed me most was seeing the Zhou family’s Xintai Gate in Shaoxing, the interlocking dowry beds in the museum, and the sitting The boat goes from Jianhu Lake to Yuewang Temple. Regarding Zhu An&#39;s written materials, except for her letters in her later years, they basically have to be filtered out from other people&#39;s accounts like gold mining. To understand the environment of her early life, one must rely on that one-week trip to Shaoxing. In addition, I was very moved when I read the original letters of correspondence between Zhu An, Xu Guangping and Hai Ying at the Lu Xun Museum in Beijing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other thing is that it was several years before I conceived this book. A Shanghai scholar accompanied me to the former residence of Lu Xun. When he stood outside the door, he said: This is also the former residence of Xu Guangping. I felt very &quot;comforted&quot; because there were also male scholars who noticed this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安机关公开通缉2名缅北电诈犯罪集团重要头目，最高奖励50万元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258471]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Currently, the situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar is severe, the harm to society is serious, and the people have reacted strongly. Investigations by the Public Security Bureau of Hangzhou City in Zhejiang Province and the Public Security Bureau of Kunming City in Yunnan Province revealed that Chen Yanban (also known as Bao Yanban) and Xiao Yankui (also known as He Chuntian) are important leaders of a criminal group involved in telecommunications network fraud in northern Myanmar. He has organized and opened fraud dens for a long time to carry out telecom and network fraud criminal activities targeting Chinese citizens. The amount of fraud is huge and the nature is extremely bad. It has been found that the criminal facts of Chen Yanban and Xiao Yankui are clear and the evidence is conclusive. The Public Security Bureau of Hangzhou City in Zhejiang Province and the Public Security Bureau of Kunming City in Yunnan Province have decided to publicly offer rewards for their arrests. The public security organs urged the criminal suspects Chen Yanban and Xiao Yankuai to recognize the situation clearly, step back from the brink, voluntarily surrender themselves, and strive for leniency. At the same time, we hope that all walks of life and the general public will actively report the crime and assist in the arrest of criminal suspects. For those who provide effective clues and assist in arrests, the public security organs will reward RMB 100,000 to RMB 500,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/b66902f5091a00a278af19b7c2b64497.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;283&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/b66902f5091a00a278af19b7c2b64497.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253877&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Suspect Chen Yanban (Bao Yanban)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ad5acecebd6294fb46481dca103a3d0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;358&quot; height=&quot;441&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ad5acecebd6294fb46481dca103a3d0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Suspect Xiao Yankui (He Chuntian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[输得起的郭宝昌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258484]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 18:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/9e016650df2ccce6b9fb2a03776f8df6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1624&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/9e016650df2ccce6b9fb2a03776f8df6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;During the 1927 Hebei disaster, carpenter Guo Shaochen fled to Beijing with his wife and daughter. After Guo&#39;s death, his 10-year-old daughter was sold into the wealthy Le family, and at the age of 23, she was married to the 70-year-old Le Si master. The daughter had no children, so she bought Li Baochang, the son of a beggar, in 1942. (Baochang lost his father when he was young and was first sold to a family named Wu by his biological mother, and then sold to the Guo family by his third aunt for two hundred yuan). From then on, Li Baochang was raised in his &quot;natal family&quot;. The fourth master Guan Yue called him aunt, and his adoptive mother Guo Rong called aunt. It was not until 1953 that she changed her name to mom and changed her name to Guo Baochang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang’s life before he was 12 years old is frozen in this short description of about 100 words. After that, after stepping into the mansion, he suddenly changed from a beggar to a &quot;superior&quot;, but he still had to experience the warmth and warmth of human relationships: in the third room, the adoptive mother Guo Rong was originally the girl who held the pet dog for the third old lady. After taking the position, she was careful in the cracks. , taught his son how to roll around in a crowd, and also helped him establish the ambition to &quot;do big things&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Gate of the Great House&quot;, which was written in four drafts, is like a miniature version of the Legend of Red Mansions in the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China. In the play, Guo Rong becomes Xiang Xiu, his adoptive father Le Jingyu (the Fourth Master Le of Tongrentang) becomes Bai Jingqi, and Guo Baochang himself becomes Li Tianyi. Viewers are talking about the correspondence between the plot in the play and the traditional Chinese medicine family. He said frankly: The script is 30% false and 70% real, and there are still a lot of stories that have not yet been written. &quot;Such a national bourgeois family closely follows the changes of the times and the political situation, and the relationships between the family characters are also constantly changing. If I have the ability to write it down and make some film and television works, it can better reflect the impact of history on human nature. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Compared with the prominent relatives in the house, Guo Baochang cares more about the little people who are rarely looked at carefully: Master Wang, the bodyguard who taught him real kung fu, the down-and-out San&#39;er, the lively and straightforward second sister Zhang Fei and the eccentric Gen Luobo, the gardener Qian Erye who makes cigarette paste and boils eagles, and the &quot;eldest brother&quot; whom he admires deeply but later goes to extremes...&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;They were like the leaves in the thick hardcover books he collected. &quot;I like to collect leaves. The leaves are calmer, indifferent, and unobtrusive than flowers, and the taste is a little lonely and bitter. The veins, textures, and patterns of the leaves are articles, history, and all living beings in the large forest family. They are easily ignored. The real past.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/f37d28b50e2eca913e27b9de59bd0441.png&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1234&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/f37d28b50e2eca913e27b9de59bd0441.png&quot; data -key=&quot;253922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;These little characters have become the protagonists in his collection of essays &quot;All Big Characters&quot;. The other protagonist is the author himself, who has gone through many ups and downs: he was admitted to the film school and excelled, but was labeled a &quot;reactionary student&quot;. He was reformed through labor and implicated his mentor Tian Feng, a life-long regret; after arriving at the Guangxi Film Studio, He worked hard to support the fifth generation of directors, paving the way for their collective guest appearance in &quot;The House Gate&quot; in the future. He wanted to write about the experience of the house gate, but the result was frequent changes. The manuscript was destroyed and rewritten several times, and it took 40 years of his life to finally come out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The people in the house call him &quot;Master Bao&quot;, which is the old family identity. In the film and television industry, people use the honorific title &quot;Master Bao&quot; to respect his sincerity, seriousness, and heroic spirit. Mr. Bao, who is over eighty years old, has deeper bags under his eyes and white eyebrows, but his figure has not been compromised. He launched the Peking Opera &quot;Mansion Gate&quot; tour and continued to write books, but he showed no signs of enjoying a happy life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a treasured master should always be satisfied? But he shook his head. &quot;I have never opened my arms in my whole life&quot; is not only talking about the second master, but also seems to be writing about myself, who is ambitious. For Guo Baochang, all his hard work and unwillingness in this life are not only to realize his ambition, but also to shed tears of repentance for his revered adoptive mother and mentor: &quot;Look, I know I was wrong. I hope you will be proud of me in the end.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The following is spoken by Guo Baochang:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;I don’t think they &quot;Noble&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Actually, before I was 12 years old, the house door was quite mysterious to me. Occasionally, I would go in and let me eat fruit, or suddenly it would be said that it was the Spring Festival and fireworks would be set off, and someone would bring me in and send them out again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After my grandma passed away, my mother took me in, and I officially entered the house. The impression was very deep and I will never forget it in my life. Because I suddenly escaped from my poor family, I clearly realized that a new life had begun, and my identity was different: you could ask the kitchen to eat whatever you wanted, and people could cook it for you. I will give you a fixed pocket money every month. In the 1950s, I was given 40 yuan a month. At that time, a worker&#39;s salary was only 36 yuan a month. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c2a5b9683c9a244f13dbc862682615f4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c2a5b9683c9a244f13dbc862682615f4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253921 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang’s cadre school years&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Children from other families still When I was kneading mud in the courtyard, Master Wang, who taught me boxing, often took us shopping, buying big knives and painted faces, going to the overpass, drinking noodle tea, shaving our heads, and taking a bath. I also learned to smoke, drink, watch theater, boxing, watch ballet, and changed my bicycle one after another. My mother said: &quot;Without this skill, you won&#39;t be able to deal with those bastards at the banquet.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But in the end, I have no status in the family. Because people think you are a &quot;bastard&quot; and suddenly come in to share the cake. Although they call you &quot;Young Master&quot;, their family has family rules and cannot have children with other surnames. So I have a deep...not so much inferiority, but a deep resentment. In fact, no matter in terms of life, interpersonal relationships, or attitude towards servants, I look down on those young masters and ladies. I don&#39;t think those people are noble. This is probably directly related to my later acceptance of the party’s education. But I had to endure a lot of things that I was unwilling to endure, and grew up slowly in the eyes of contempt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;My mother also knows it very well, so she must make me strive for success - the way to make me strive for success is not to let me study hard, do my homework, and take the college entrance examination. Teach you to be an independent, dignified person, to become a master, and to get rid of all kinds of servility. My resistance was very strong at that time, I just thought that I must be successful and I must be better than you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;(Is the adoptive mother neither humble nor arrogant to other people?) &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She gave it to me The overall impression is to be vigilant at all times. I can say without exaggeration that in the entire family, except for the old man, almost everyone is her enemy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because she has the lowest status among the wives, why can a girl with a dog suddenly give orders? They were unconvinced and tried every means to carry out all kinds of destruction. She had to be alert to everyone around her at all times. Over the past few decades, she has always been in such a high-pressure state, which is not easy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I also hope that I can stand behind her, as the strength behind her, so that people will not dare to bully her. This is a big wish of mine when I was a child. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1953, this big family finally couldn&#39;t support it anymore. Each house owner bought his own house and established his own portal. The old man and my adoptive mother and I moved to Donghuamen, while my grandmother and her family moved to Luogu Lane. I wanted a pipa in the warehouse, but Miss Wen flatly refused and said in a very unpleasant way: &quot;It&#39;s not your turn to choose! You&#39;ve come to take advantage of me!&quot; As soon as the funeral was over, Wen immediately took the lead in negotiating with several housemates. The boss jointly listed the so-called &quot;ten crimes&quot; against my mother. To put it bluntly, they wanted money. My mother focused on the overall situation, kept things quiet, and listed the family property and distributed it equally among the houses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is natural to divide money, but it is really spectacular to divide things. Let&#39;s start with calligraphy and painting, which are overwhelmingly displayed - no one wants Qi Baishi&#39;s or Chen Banding&#39;s paintings. Each room is allocated through negotiation based on the number of rooms. Then divide into fans, then jade, inkstones, snuff bottles, copybooks, furs, and materials. For three whole days and nights, there was a lot of traffic in front of the door, and no one looked tired. This is what is called when a tree falls and the hozens scatter. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/747c065c81d4ad01d34eefbc449f2b96.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1234&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/747c065c81d4ad01d34eefbc449f2b96.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253924 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Confess to my mother every day&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Of course my mother has her limitations. She looked down on Yang Jiuhong and called her &quot;Sister Yao&quot;. She also tried her best to hide my life experience. Later, she firmly opposed my making family affairs public. &quot;Isn&#39;t this exposing my family&#39;s scandal?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;You ask me how I feel about her now? Very complicated, more of a guilt.家里挂着我妈妈很多照片，我每天走过来走过去，每天都在向她忏悔。因为我背叛过我妈妈，曾经跟她断绝关系了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那时候我在南口农场劳动改造，回家过年，为了摆脱资产阶级出身，就逼问我妈，问我的亲生父母是谁。等她告诉我以后，我立刻去农场告诉组织自己的真实身份。没想到管理人员说：“你就是吃剥削饭长大的，你浑身都长了反骨，所以出身对你没有关系。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我还逼我妈交出全部财产，做了很久工作她才答应放弃一半股息。但我觉得还不够，再次劝说。她感受到了巨大的侮辱，跟我说：“你觉得有这么一个资本家的妈不光彩是吗？你可以不认我，自食其力成你的家，过你的日子去。我是不会交的。”我拿起破书包就走了，伤透了她的心。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我当时有很多的私心，就想利用她的“交出财产”来立功，减轻我的出身带来的处分。这种念头很强烈，以为只要我们不在宅门吃饭，可以减轻我的处分，也是立功表现。现在回想起来这想法挺肮脏的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;（她去世前你有表达悔意吗？）&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;忏悔了，就是没来得及表达。你说一个人认错怎么那么难？一个人说说道歉的话怎么那么难？我后来才知道，人们都喜欢文过饰非，明明有错就是不承认。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我所以写出来、说出来，就是要让大家知道，我曾经很丑。每个人都会有这样那样的错误、缺点，但只有面对它，你才可能新生。输了就要认输，别咬着牙死不认输。知道自己曾经做错过什么，对我们真诚地对待这个世界有很大的好处。当然我也觉得这是不是过于廉价，你承认了，就赎回了你的错了吗？没有。我做了很多不应该做的事情，造成的这种伤害是致命的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/48f8a869ca997dae8ffa69867018d2d4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;877&quot; height=&quot;1230&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/48f8a869ca997dae8ffa69867018d2d4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;郭宝昌的养父乐敬宇（亦作“乐镜宇”），宅门人都称他为“老爷子”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;对乐老爷子，我更多的是敬畏，为什么书里没给他写一章？因为全都写到电视剧里了，“七爷”是我一生的楷模：说戒烟，男子汉大丈夫说不抽就不抽，楞挺过来了。他每次去看我奶奶，没有什么大资本家的架子，非常平和。直到1953年以后，得了失忆症，垮了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;但是到我上小学，受了新式教育，觉得老爷子这种剥削者就是暴君，就是个流氓。等我写小说的时候思考这个问题，就开始用阶级分析方法来看他了，对他也不崇敬了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我妈对他的百依百顺，我也不理解。比如他忽然说我要上街，那会儿已经失明了——白内障，我妈妈就扶着他到街上走一圈再回来，其实他什么也看不见。我就觉得是多余，特别同情我妈妈。所以《大宅门》的第一稿，我把妈妈写成一个“被侮辱与被损害”的形象。那会儿雨果、陀思妥耶夫斯基对我影响都很大。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;有一次我妈不在，我就拉着老爷子的手在屋里转一圈，我说行了，看看街上就这样，看见了吗？好，坐下。我妈当时就拍了桌子了，你敢这样对待老爷子，你算老几？他一辈子那么英雄，你可以这样对待他吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我小时候特别不能理解，我妈那么年轻为什么要嫁给你？怎么可能有爱？我不相信。我都认为是忍辱负重，没有办法作为丫鬟卖在那儿，最后又嫁给这样一个老头子，是为了生活，有口饭吃。从这件事情以后，我才知道我妈真正地爱他。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;“在旧中国，再有权的女性，依然是男权赋予”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;你说芹小姐和雯小姐的故事特别让人唏嘘？是啊，编都编不出来这么戏剧。实在太色彩斑斓了，光怪陆离，出乎我们一般人的想象。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;芹和雯本是我们这个房头儿两位如花似玉的娇小姐。雯极有艺术天赋，古琴弹得好，歌喉也甜美。芹在上学时便看上了她二哥的一位大学同学。此人与二哥志趣相投、思想先进，使芹知道了外面还有另一个世界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6983b099477946550d887ccd57d8b896.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1056&quot; height=&quot;1385&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6983b099477946550d887ccd57d8b896.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;小时候的芹小姐（左）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;二哥为了逃避家庭的包办婚姻毅然出走，跟随这位同学一起参加了革命，而且入了党，直到北平解放才随解放大军入城。那位同学和芹私定终身，只是他没能在京停留，很快便随大军南下，两人相约书信往来。结果芹一直没收到他的信，过了大半年才发觉两人的通信都被母亲扣下。最后的信，那男生说估计芹变了心，已另寻伴侣，结婚了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;芹立马举刀向母亲砍去。老爷子拦腰抱住芹夺下了刀。从此芹疯了。雯则变得乖戾孤僻、任性自私。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;再后来，芹先后嫁给七十岁的老人和大兴一个农民，因为她根本无法自食其力。到了雯家落实政策后，芹找回娘家要求母亲和妹妹周济于她，遭到拒绝。拿了雯施舍的五块钱走出娘家，她夜里果然再次挥刀，要砍母亲和姐姐雯。几天后，芹死在了拘留所。人家说：“三十年前芹那一鬼头刀没有砍成，这回又算补上了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这故事里，姐妹、母女、亲情、金钱……全都在里头呵。但还没完。我断断想不到，后来还有故事。 1998年一位不速之客来访，说是芹的儿子。原来他父亲并非解放军，实乃国民党的一个官员，随军逃到南京，又转去台湾，且并不知芹已怀孕。芹在外地生了他，抱着他去了台湾，演绎了一出千里寻夫的悲剧。结果因其夫已再婚，芹无奈，扔下孩子返回了大陆。芹的儿子自此把雯当作亲人奉敬，在京时陪雯看病，多方照应，返美后依然寄钱，助雯医疗。他把对母亲的思念与爱全寄托在了自己的小姨身上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;雯活到71岁，终身未嫁。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1be4b404dfa104f69cb919f6692dd3da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;769&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1be4b404dfa104f69cb919f6692dd3da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253929&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;郭宝昌和老年雯小姐&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;说起来这种恩恩怨怨的事情，在大宅门里头是常态，每个房头都有他们自己的故事，但是芹和雯是给我印象最深的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我从小就在女人堆里混出来，因为我妈那会儿掌权。她在家里主要应对的目标就是各房头的女眷，通过这样的渠道更容易来掌握整个家族的命运，所以像奶奶、姑奶奶、少奶奶、小姐们，我都接触比较多。我对她们的情感挺复杂的，跟我母亲一样，要用不同的态度来对待家族的每一个成员、每一个女人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在女性意识上，从小也就受到了各种教育，特别是京戏里面，像王宝钏这样的戏，她和公主都是薛平贵的老婆，最后好像俩人都是胜利了做主，其实都是薛平贵给的呀。我觉得女权的问题中国没有解决，在我们家族里更解决不了，杨九红的故事就非常典型。她和香秀看似有权，一直掌握一个家族，依然是男权赋予的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不过我真没想到，在成千上万对《大宅门》的评论中，给杨九红的恐怕是最多的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;二奶奶这个人我真的没见过，可是杨九红的原型确实和我一起生活了20年。像二奶奶临死的时候不让她戴孝，宅里边无数人跟我讲过这个事儿。那不是一般的伤害了，因为猫狗都要戴孝，你不配，你连猫狗都不如，没有丝毫的做人的尊严。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;二奶奶也说，从了良，赎了身，你还是妓女！前阵我拍戏，还问剧组的这些小青年，我说假如你们结了婚，有了孩子，你的孩子有一天从外地带个妓女回来要结婚，你们会同意吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我们不要讲那么深刻的大道理，伦理道德，别说这些，就拿你自己来说好了，有谁能做得到？那你说这些是封建意识吗？太复杂的问题了，我们任何人看任何一个作品、评价任何一个人物，都不要用公式化的东西去解释。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;话说杨九红&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（原型）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;的晚年，我们院前院有一位大爷，非常儒雅，是个绅士型的男人，爱穿长袍，经常到我们家来玩。一来二去，我们这位杨九红，就爱上他了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;你想一个老太太经过了那么多的风风雨雨，她的暮年能有一个人真的坐在旁边愿意听她说话，不管说什么我都听着，不表态，她已经是很满足了，这个情感我太能理解了。可后来又出了些事情，闹得沸沸扬扬，她一下子成了整个家族的笑话。只有我非常同情她，大宅门里头能够和她坐在一起聊天、愿意仔细听她说话的，就我一个。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;在小人物的河流中蹚来蹚去&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1963年夏天，我跟随渔民出海，驾着渔船“赶溜子”。 “溜子”就是海中的河。河的边界是海，那流动是隐秘的，水的颜色却是不一样的。只有经年累月与大海生死与共的渔民汉子，才能辨识出来。赶上溜子，渔民们撒了几十里的大绳钩钓鱼，个个脱得精赤条条躺在船板上享受阳光，待鱼上钩。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;面对大海，人真小，不由得感叹，人哪，你算老几？ !我唱起京剧《空城计》里“我本是卧龙岗散淡的人”，船老大蹲在船头，边拉屎边为我叫好，充满诗意。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/42f5d33ae873ea35a3f771cfe0edfe3e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/42f5d33ae873ea35a3f771cfe0edfe3e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253930&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;重访大宅门。郭宝昌身后那三个窗户是门房，郑老屁就住在其中&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那会儿我喜欢在宅门门房待着，喜欢在厨房待着，听他们讲各种各样家族里的事，就跟听故事会一样。在这本书里，我也只想把我印象很深的、《大宅门》剧本里没法表现的这些人物推到前面来，给他们每人来个特写。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;比方教我武术的镖师王师父，个头不高，剃一大光头，永远是乡下人的短打扮；在胡同里永远贴着墙根儿走，低着头目不旁视，只看着眼巴前的路；一脸平和谦恭之气，眯着眼似笑非笑，总像是对不起谁似的表情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;遇见凶狠的亡命之徒，王师父宁可损失点儿银子，绝不伤人性命，所谓“能不动手就不动手”。我记得，有一回夜里，从东北方小跨院的房顶上窜过来一个哈着腰快步行走的黑影，一跃上了北屋上房的屋脊，走到西北角，黑影子稍稍一停，向院子里的人微微鞠了一躬，突然老爷子大喊一声：“赏！”一个仆人把一个装着大洋的小兜包递给了王师父，王师父将小兜包挂在鬼头刀的刀尖儿上，向上用力一甩，那兜包甩向黑影，正巧落在黑影举起的手上，黑影顺势在屋脊上磕了一个头，一缩身便不见了。原来那是个过路的贼，是借道儿向王师父这位武林高手打招呼致敬。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;还有油盐店小伙计，画得一手好画，山水、花鸟十分出色，还看过《钢铁是怎样炼成的》《卓娅和舒拉的故事》，和我有太多的共同语言。更重要的是他讲仁义。他不大看得上宅门里的人，说人和人都是一样的，没什么高低贵贱之分。他给过我一本《列宁的故事》，说你看列宁，他不带证件，站岗的照样不叫他进门。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;还有爱吃、爱放屁的郑老屁，会干粗活，多少年了，残疾的钱二爷上茅房手不利落，郑老屁都帮他系裤腰带。老屁一辈子不抽烟、不喝酒、不赌钱，没看过戏和电影，就好听书。他就是那种单纯、善良、勤俭、忠厚，却平平常常、普普通通的乡下人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我这辈子见过的人确实是形形色色。当然最奇葩的，要数我那位“大哥”了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他不是我亲大哥，是高中同班同学。家里极为贫困，弟弟偷吃一颗大蒜都要被大哥揍。他有才华，想法独特。我们俩交情甚笃，但他从来都拒绝我的援助。说所以对我这么好，是因为看我是一个不可多得的人才，因此绝不叫我落入资产阶级之手，一定要把我拉入无产阶级的队伍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;再后来我们俩都经历种种的沟沟坎坎，打过苦工，进过监狱。和他相比，我信仰过，崇拜过，忏悔过，洗刷过。而他一直还是那么“透”，那么纯。真不知道我们俩到底谁是悲剧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;可到晚年，大哥居然来了180度的大转弯，受别人的蛊惑，开始了无休止的借贷，从家里到朋友，几乎借遍。我也借给过他，也没指望他能还上。最糟糕的是，这些钱都不是他自己挥霍的，他没有享受过，都是转手给那些骗子。我告诉他那都是骗局，不要再闹了。有一次他特别过分，我大概一个小时没停嘴地骂他……他女儿说：郭叔你别骂我爸行吗？他也是没办法。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/319713849bc3670c65412fa24e05f9b6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/319713849bc3670c65412fa24e05f9b6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253931&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;后来的“大哥”（戴眼镜者）几乎完全变了一个人&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;大哥前些日子走了。一直到去世，他也没“醒”。所以人的思维方式不能走极端，他从青年时代就走到极端了，再走到另一个极端，一下子就摔倒了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;付出生命代价的“财富”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;有人说我幸运。是，我这一生起伏很大，这是一笔很大的财富。但这个财富需要生命的代价，这种幸运谁也不愿意重复，这种挣扎不是一般人能够承受得了的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1959年我考上了电影学院导演系，又入了团，我在家里的地位突然发生了巨变。家中的少爷小姐们大多吃祖宗饭赋闲在家，像我这样在学业、政治上双进取的人就算很有出息的了，用那帮爷的话来说：“行啊，宝爷，大学生还在党了！”雯的态度尤其变化大。今天的人恐怕很难理解，因为这样的环境已经没有了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;几年后，在北京电影学院导演系五年级学习时，我被划为“反动学生”。经历了劳改四年又监管劳动四年生生死死的岁月。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;劳改回来，我在东华门站着。出来以后我就站在街上，我不知道我上哪去，我妈和其他家人在哪，我完全不知道，前院后院里头都已经是造反派住着了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此后我又被发配广西控制使用，直到后来逐渐听到了落实政策的消息，发还了抄家物资和存款。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;回想起来，电影学院那段生活是我一生中最愉快的。那时真觉得我前面是光明大道，鲜花铺路，结果一下就跌到地狱，你连人都不是了，连起码的人的尊严都没有了。忽然间有一个作品&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（《大宅门》）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;出来，忽然间大家伙又开始追捧你，就是这样子大起大落的人生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我写过这辈子痛哭过四回，最难受的就是田风去世。那是嚎啕大哭，哭出声来嗷嗷叫的那种。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（停顿，脸朝一边，哽咽良久）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那会儿田风是我们学校导演系主任，他对学校打保票：“我是工农阶级出身，我来改造他（&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;郭宝昌）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”。当时我正在写《大宅门》的小说，写到三分之二被没收，罪名是为资本家著书立传。一边等待学校的处理，一边干刷厕所、扫剧场、称煤球的活儿。有天下午我从煤球厂出来，和田风老师撞见，两个人都低着头。他已经瘦得脱了相，没想到那是我们最后一次见面。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;可以说情感上，我多年来不只是内疚、自责、愧悔，而且是一直处于绝望、无助、无所适从、无可皈依的惶惑之中。对于“平反”我真的高兴不起来，因为失去的永远失去了。再多的言语和行为也补偿不了心中对老师的愧疚。他当时给我特殊的培养，给我开小灶，包括他因为我做了错事，而承担了他不应该承担的责任，这些真是让我后来痛不欲生。后来我再做所有的事情，就是要为我们的老师争气，不能辜负他对我的期望。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cffb27ac924d4ffdf78c586e6b32165a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cffb27ac924d4ffdf78c586e6b32165a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;郭宝昌在电视剧《东四牌楼东》拍摄现场执导&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我也很敬重恩师的夫人于华老师。有一阵我陷入哀怨和灰败，老想不通。加上改革开放后各种思潮涌进国门，我也发过些奇谈怪论。她有一次很严厉地对我说，“你受过迫害，心里有委屈，这很可以理解，大家都是这么过来的。可你人还在，还有大半生的路要走，你整天活在抱怨的心态里，还能做什么大事？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我就想说，人家一辈子怎么过来的？她受了那么多的委屈，依然那么坚强地活着，有那么坚定的信仰，我做不到。我也会时常想起一位忘年交杜伯伯跟我说过，“再险恶的路也是可以冲杀出来的。你要与众不同，学会自己掌握自己的命运。”就在别人都混日子、不知道应该怎么走的时候，一定要坚持，依然要把事情做到最好。我想这就是不认输，而且在不认输中间有赢的欲望。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;（您写过宅门里的二爷“一生襟抱未曾开”。那您自己呢？）&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;（摇摇头）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;我的抱负太大了，没实现的事情多了。小时候算命，先生就跟我说过，说你一辈子也达不到你自己的愿望。我40岁才起步，很多事情已经来不及做了。就靠一口气在那撑着，老有点不服输。怎么打我，也打不倒我，怎么歪歪扭扭的，我也得站起来是吧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（参考资料：《都是大角色》、《了不起的游戏》。感谢陈曦、卫纯对本文的帮助）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海老年相亲圣地，常客们不谈爱情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/qrJ2C4yqUr1iCcG3uGXG27rxSzDTODrZgFIVC1pB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/qrJ2C4yqUr1iCcG3uGXG27rxSzDTODrZgFIVC1pB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253723&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月12日下午，上海，宜家餐厅里的老年人。 （南方周末记者郑丹/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一席饭散，9个人，13样菜，人均结算现钞72元。 Wiping his mouth and getting up, another day passed by. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;68岁的洪建明站在霓虹灯通明的饭店大堂前，看着老友们三两结伴，互相搀扶着穿过斑马线，直至消失在马路对面的黑暗里，他才迈出步子。 “他们都不知道我住在这附近，不想让他们知道。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们，是洪建明在上海徐家汇的宜家餐厅认识的单身老人，冲着“多吃几个花样的菜”，每个礼拜二聚在一起吃饭。 Neither of them knew each other&#39;s names, and they seldom asked because there was no need. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;到宜家餐厅的单身老人，大多是想找个伴。 While they boldly express their love for the person they like, they can&#39;t help but be suspicious and wary out of self-protection, lest they suffer a loss. As time goes by, everyone has become acquaintances who maintain a sense of boundaries, and they get together just for fun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;孤独，终归是这里的底色。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;自留地&lt;/h4>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“缺乏一个老年人交流平台”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;初秋的上海阴雨连绵，但位于漕溪路126号的宜家家居徐汇商场人声鼎沸。 On the afternoons of Tuesdays and Thursdays, the young people dining in the restaurant on the second floor slowly dispersed, and crowds of elderly people poured in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月12日下午3时，南方周末记者初到宜家餐厅，一眼望过去，布置近700个座位的用餐区，被零散坐开的老年人完全占据，过道里始终有人走动，相互搭讪聊天。偶尔有人走到记者跟前，打量着年轻的新面孔问道：“是来找伴的不？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这是一处上海老年人自发设定的相亲角。 Xuhui Mall, opened in 1998, is IKEA&#39;s first store in mainland China. It&#39;s hard to explain how its restaurant came to be occupied by a group of singles. As long as you buy a cup of coffee for 7.9 yuan and get free refills, you can hang out in the restaurant with the mug in hand all day long. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;71岁的陈翠霞记得，18年前，徐汇商场还是一栋很小的两层楼，单身的她和姐妹6人来玩，底下商场兜一圈，发现二楼还有饭吃。 “这边蛮好的，完了以后我们就讲好，下次再来好不好？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来，人越聚越多，最多的时候，三百多号单身老人聚过来，都是来找伴的，整个大厅得靠喊话沟通，“声音吵&lt;span>;得&lt;/span>;能把房顶掀翻”。 Someone suggested that everyone pick a day to get together. Tuesday is the big day and Thursday is the small day. Chen Cuixia feels that the elderly actually have no other place to chat&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;“除了这里，就是人民公园，缺乏一个供老年人交流的平台。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上海是全国老龄化程度最高的超大型城市。 According to the 2022 Shanghai Municipal Elderly Population and Aging Care Monitoring and Statistics Information, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022, accounting for nearly 40% of the total population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone 300,600. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;宜家餐厅无疑成了他们排遣寂寞的一块自留地。每周二，一位90岁的老太太会乘坐456路公交，从三林出发，花40多分钟时间来到餐厅后，只是默默坐在角落看人头攒动；旁边另一位上了年纪的女人与老太太以姐妹相称，她用塑料袋&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“消失”的婴儿牵出代孕贩婴暗网：涉多名儿童与东南亚代孕妈妈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258433]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e9bfb77e42.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e9bfb77e42.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252367&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月13日，浙江湖州，邱佳红再次来到陈美凤住处。（南方周末记者郑丹/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;胎龄8个多月，早产，头发黑黑的，是个男婴。关于未谋面的孩子，这是37岁的邱佳红知道的全部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年9月16日23时35分，刚经历剖腹引产的邱佳红从全身麻醉中醒来，孩子的父亲郑小兵告诉她，取出来的婴儿是死的，被医生抱走了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在邱佳红的讲述中，自己原本健康的胎儿临产时被医院告知“孩子缺氧，脑神经不正常，要打掉的”。半年后，她突然意识到不对劲。在剖腹引产手术的头天下午，她接到过一个显示为浙江湖州号码的电话，连续打来两次，电话那头的老太太问她，孩子送人吗？“莫名其妙，我说怎么可能送人，就挂了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随着诸多疑点一点点浮现，邱佳红怀疑自己是中了人贩子的圈套。成为“猎物”并不是没有缘故，那是一个让她难以启齿的原因——自己未婚生育的孩子，是郑小兵的私生子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱佳红相信孩子还活着。她决定顺着那串陌生号码寻子，没曾想，阴差阳错掀开一起地下代孕、贩卖儿童大案。截至2023年9月13日，侦办该案的警方查明涉及多名被买卖儿童。&lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;雇私家侦探寻子&lt;/h4>;&lt;p>;雨下了一早上，灰蒙蒙的粮油批发市场里人少，安静，成排的卷帘门大多被拉下来，偶尔几个外卖员来去穿梭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身材瘦小的邱佳红领着南方周末记者，在市场里三拐两拐，熟练地钻进靠边的一幢居民楼，顺着贴满牛皮癣小广告的楼道到203室门前。这家住户就是当初给她打电话的老太太，如今已经置身于看守所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老太太名叫陈美凤，58岁，福建莆田人。那张脸邱佳红记得清楚，文两道弯眉，耷拉着深眼袋，圆脸盘，高颧骨，挨肩炸开的一头灰发用发箍卡紧。她体型偏胖，冬日里时常裹一件黑色貂皮大衣，蹬一双黑筒靴，脚底有劲儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;半年前，2023年2月，邱佳红雇佣两名私家侦探，三人驱车从上海前往浙江湖州找到陈美凤的住处，试图在这里找到当初从医院消失的儿子。她回忆，挨着冻在楼下蹲点一周，也没有见到陈美凤抱着五六月大的男婴出没过一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与陈美凤的正面对峙，发生在他们蹲点的第8天。2月23日，邱佳红一早在203室门口堵住了散步回来的陈美凤：“陈阿姨，你认得我吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不认得”，陈美凤的普通话里夹杂着浓重的莆田口音，她客气地将来者请进屋里坐，老头子在给小孙女烧饭，屋里有些杂乱。邱佳红目光扫了一圈屋子，没有男婴。她又问一句，“那我的号码你从哪里来的？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈美凤才明白邱佳红的来意，“没打过”，她说，一会儿又咕哝，“不记得了”。在邱佳红的执意要求下，陈美凤被陪同前往附近一处移动营业厅调取半年内的通讯记录，邱佳红的电话号码果然出现在其中，通话时间为2022年9月15日16时29分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ed9bdd81dc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ed9bdd81dc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252368&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年2月一天清晨， 陈美凤抱孙女回屋。（受访者供图/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时的邱佳红并没有注意，在陈美凤给她打电话前后，还和同一人打过3通电话，后来发现是浙江美福宝妇儿医院（以下简称美福宝医院）院长陈勇进的号码。2022年9月16日，邱佳红就在杭州的美福宝医院生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来邱佳红从警方得知，这二人是莆田老乡。陈勇进就此事的回应是，“有可能是我告诉陈美凤（邱佳红联系方式）的，我不确定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱佳红想起，剖腹产手术后第三天，开刀医生于艳芬走进她的病房拉家常，“我当时痛得有点迷迷糊糊，她跟我聊了有两小时，问我家里兄弟姐妹都是做什么的，先生是做什么的，怎么认识的，聊得跟自己人一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“一系列回想以后觉得不对，她到我病房肯定是来打探消息的。”邱佳红认定，孩子活着，但被陈美凤跟美福宝医院卖了；男友郑小兵也有把孩子“送出去”的嫌疑，两人因此闹僵，分道扬镳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;面对邱佳红和私家侦探逼问孩子下落，陈美凤带着哭腔，“我真的不记&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武打演员孟海患食道癌去世：当关注高危因素“烟、酒、烫、腌”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258469]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，武术指导、武打演员，洪家班重要成员孟海去世。他不幸确诊食道癌后，仅仅一年就去世了。他的去世，当引起大家对食道癌的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国居民食道癌、胃癌发生的危险因素主要是：热烫饮食、喜油炸食、腌制饮食、重盐食、三餐不定时和饮酒抽烟，特别是边抽烟边饮酒；而吃大蒜、新鲜蔬菜以及饮温茶是保护因素。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食道癌是常见的消化道肿瘤，其典型的症状为进行性咽下困难，先是吞咽食物时有哽咽感、异物感，然后难以咽下干的食物，最后，连半流物甚至水也不能咽下。食道癌还会引发胸骨后疼痛，如果发生转移或侵犯邻近器官，被累及器官会不适和疼痛。通常可能侵犯喉部，引起声嘶，所以，嗓子不舒服，未必是说话说多了，也可能是身体的紧急信号。如果侵犯下段食道癌可累及胃食管结合部，可能引起呕血或便血；如果侵犯气管可引起呼吸困难或咯血。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全世界每年约有30万人死于食道癌，中国是世界上食道癌高发地区之一，发病率与病死率都相对较高。发病率在全部恶性肿瘤中排第6位，死亡率约为第4位，平均每年病死约15万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食道癌的发病因素很多，年龄、性别、职业、种族、地域、生活环境、饮食生活习惯、基因、炎症与创伤、微量元素，都有一定关系。从性别看，男多于女，发病年龄多在40岁以上，但值得警惕的是，近年来40岁以下发病者有增长趋势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从地域看，农村食道癌发病率高于城市。但这里的地域实质是经济发展水平。一般来说，在相对发达的地区，肺癌、结直肠癌、乳腺癌、甲状腺癌和前列腺癌高发，而在经济相对落后地区，则是消化道肿瘤如胃癌、食道癌和肝癌等恶性肿瘤高发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从单纯的地理分布看，中国食道癌高发区主要集中在太行山脉附近：河南、河北、山西、山东、安徽、江苏苏北区域。这种发病的地域性在癌症中很常见，比如鼻咽癌的高发地区就是广东、广西、福建、湖南等南方地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一种地理分布，其实是基因分布。食道癌的其他高发区域与中原移民有关，包括四川南充、四川盐亭、广东汕头、福建福州等地区。这是因为特定人群带有易感基因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食道癌的高危因素，日常生活中最常见，可以总结为四个字：烟、酒、烫、腌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流行病学调查发现一些食道癌高发区居民吸烟相当普遍，一些地区居民不吸烟，食道癌则很少见。在嗜好吸黑檀叶烟和咀嚼萎叶的印度穆斯林、基督教徒和印度教徒中，食道癌发病率高，而无此嗜好的拜火教徒中食道癌则很少见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流行病学调查，还发现许多食道癌患者有大量饮酒史。英国和中国香港科学家调查了香港食道癌患者的吸烟及饮酒情况，经过详尽对比分析，发现饮酒可能比吸烟更容易导致食道癌发生。中国食道癌主要为鳞状细胞癌，吸烟与重度饮酒是引起食道鳞癌的重要因素，对于食道鳞癌，吸烟者的发生率增加3-8倍，而饮酒者增加7-50倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我国食道癌高发区中，许多居民和食道癌患者都有好吃热食习惯。研究者测量了高发区居民的食物温度，发现可高达70℃-80℃，最高为80℃-88℃。这是一个非常烫的温度了。 75℃热水就可以导致小鼠上皮细胞变性，黏膜炎症和细胞核酸代谢受影响，所以长期过烫饮食造成的局部炎症和热刺激，可能是食道癌发病的促发或诱发因素。在日本，喜吃烫粥烫茶人群均有较高的发病率。除了吃烫的食物，暴饮暴食、快速饮食、干硬食，也会刺激食道，引发癌症。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚硝酸盐也是导致食道癌、胃癌的重要因素，长期食用腌制食物，亚硝酸盐摄取过量，也会导致食道癌。在食道癌高发区，粮食和饮水中的亚硝胺含量明显高于其他地区。六十多年前，胃癌是日本主要的癌症，在1970年代普及冰箱后，人们吃腌制的食物少了，日本胃癌发病率大幅下降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，食道癌虽然可怕，也是可以预防的，避免高危因素，如吸烟、重度饮酒，少吃腌制食品，少吃烫的东西，如果当地饮水质量不好，可以加装净水器。住在高发地区、年龄在45岁以上、有直系家属食道癌或消化道癌症病史，或其他癌症病史、有食道癌的癌前疾病的人，要进行食道癌筛查，可以早发现早治疗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[外交部：已确认有3名中国公民在巴以冲突中不幸遇难 2人失联]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258473]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 15:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022427116074&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;19.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/959fffc55576678022427116074/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/959fffc55576678022427116074/rxPYRAIDGO8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/959fffc55576678022427116074/rxPYRAIDGO8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月12日，外交部发言人汪文斌主持例行记者会。有记者提问，据报道，新一轮巴以冲突已造成超万人死伤，包括很多外国在以公民。目前已有22名美国公民死亡，10多名英国公民死亡或失踪。发言人是否掌握目前中国公民伤亡情况?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪文斌表示，据了解，目前已确认有3名中国公民在冲突中不幸遇难，2人失联、数人受伤，我们对遇难者表示沉痛哀悼，向遇难者家属和伤者表示诚挚慰问。中国有关驻外外交机构正全力协调救治伤员，做好遇难者善后工作，敦促外方全力搜救失联人员，采取一切有效措施，保障中方人员和机构安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汇金出手增持四大行 系时隔8年再出手]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258427]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 11, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank collectively announced that the controlling shareholders Central Huijin Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Central Huijin&quot;) increased its A-share holdings. It has been eight years since Central Huijin last increased its holdings in the four major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the closing price on October 11, Central Huijin’s increase in its holdings in the four major banks was approximately 477 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to announcements from the four major banks, this increase in holdings is just the beginning. Central Huijin will continue to increase holdings in the secondary market in its own name in the next 6 months (counting from the date of this increase in holdings). The four major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin is a wholly state-owned company established in 2003. It has strong capital strength and holds shares in nearly 20 leading companies in four major categories, including banking, insurance, securities, and comprehensive institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This increase in holdings of the four major banks is of great significance to insiders in the securities industry. It sends a positive signal of stabilizing the capital market. It is also expected to drive bank stocks back to the main line of China Special Assessment, and then achieve the rhythm of the sector. Large with small, the floor pushes the ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Operation again after 8 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 11, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank collectively announced that the controlling shareholders Central Huijin increased its A-share holdings by 37.2722 million shares, 27.61 million shares, 24.8879 million shares and 18.38 million shares, and planned to increase its A-share holdings in the next 6 months (from the date of this increase). It continued to increase its holdings of the Bank’s shares in the secondary market in its own name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much is the amount of this increase? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the closing price on October 11, the four major banks increased their holdings by a total of 477 million yuan. Among them, the highest is 136 million yuan from Agricultural Bank of China, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China with 130 million yuan, China Construction Bank with approximately 117 million yuan, and Bank of China with 94 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Central Huijin increased capital for the four major banks was in 2015, at a total cost of nearly 20 billion yuan. In 2015, Central Huijin increased its holdings in Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank by 1.255 billion shares, 1.014 billion shares, 1.810 billion shares, and 497 million shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has also led some market participants to predict that Central Huijin’s increase in its holdings in the four major banks is only the beginning, and the proportion of subsequent holdings may be further increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin has strong financial strength. According to the 2023 semi-annual report, its total assets and net assets are as high as 6.71 trillion yuan and 6.21 trillion yuan respectively. Its operating performance is also remarkable, with operating income of 323.615 billion yuan and operating profit of 316.607 billion yuan in the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Affect geometry? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin has increased its holdings in the four major banks, and its market impact cannot be underestimated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yifeng, chief financial analyst at Everbright Securities, said that Huijin’s increase in holdings sends a positive signal to stabilize the capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the four major banks have stable profits and high dividend rates, but they are at very low valuation levels. Huijin&#39;s increase in holdings demonstrates the controlling shareholder&#39;s confidence in state-owned financial institutions with low valuations and high dividends; secondly, the four major banks have a larger weight in the Shanghai Composite Index, and continued increase in holdings is expected to have net-breaking valuations but stable operations and dividends Companies with high profitability will form support, which will help boost market confidence; finally, the four major banks play the role of &quot;lead goose&quot; in credit extension, and this increase in holdings will also help convey confidence in the stability of my country&#39;s financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Ma Kunpeng, chief analyst of CITIC Securities Bank, this will drive bank stocks back to the main line of China Special Assessment, and then achieve large and small stocks, and the floor will push the ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, he believes that the four major banks are the cornerstone of the banking sector and have key guiding significance for the overall prosperity of the sector. They are also the core of the banking industry’s valuation system with Chinese characteristics. They are important for today’s increase in holdings and The proactive announcement of the willingness to increase holdings in the future and the entry of real money into the market are not only an overall support for the banking sector, but also a high degree of affirmation of the special valuation of banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It suggested that we should attach great importance to the systematic revaluation of the banking sector starting from the special valuation of major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kunpeng regards the special valuation of major state-owned banks as a systematic revaluation supported by real logic and believes that it has three major logical pillars: First, the risks of major state-owned banks in key areas such as real estate and urban investment Not high, significantly better than the industry average; secondly, historical bad debt has been completely cleared, and the full-caliber bad debt rate has fully reflected and digested the bad debt implied by the current valuation, and has peaked; furthermore, the ROE of major banks has been at the bottom, promoting The profit growth rate at the critical point of ROE recovery is very close to the current profit growth rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kunpeng believes that on the one hand, the current macro economy is at a critical turning point for stabilization and improvement, and the macro turning point is more beneficial to major banks that are more biased towards sector beta. On the other hand, the main line logic of the special evaluation of major banks this year is also conducive to major banks taking the lead in performing. Therefore, unlike the previous rhythm of first anchoring the sector&#39;s ceiling valuation and then driving low valuations, this year&#39;s rhythm should be the opposite, first raising the sector&#39;s floor valuation and then pushing the ceiling higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的一则班内社会学调查：为何现在的年轻人不喜欢回家了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258419]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A recent post is very popular. The original text says this, &quot;When you are helpless, you often have thoughts in your mind. I said &#39;I want to go home&#39;, but it seems that it is not the real &#39;home&#39; in reality, but a safe, comfortable place in my imagination, without pain and trouble.&quot; I estimate that the posters are most likely young people, and the people who post and comment on them are also mostly young. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Home, also known as home in English, is different from house, which is only a building with residential functions. Home is a word with obvious cultural and geographical color, often associated with family, family, affection, warmth, shelter, arms, harbor, etc. Going home, the so-called going home, is also full of positive energy, a sense of justice and legitimacy, such as &quot;go home often&quot;, &quot;rich or not, go home for the New Year&quot;, &quot;fallen leaves return to their roots&quot; and other popular This can be seen in the song titles or sentences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For me, I must go home during holidays, especially long holidays. The simple truth is that it was very difficult for my parents to raise and train me as an adult. Now that they are older, I have no reason not to take the time to go home to visit and accompany them. In other words, if I don’t go home during the holidays and only play by myself or play with my wife and children, I will feel guilty and feel that I am a selfish and heartless person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Times have changed, and today’s young people, especially those born in the 1990s and 2000s, have completely different understandings and perceptions of home and returning home. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My sociological investigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;My nephew is a freshman. During this past holiday, he only stayed at home for three days and asked his friends out on the fourth day. Have fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I randomly asked the 18 people I teach, including sophomores and juniors, 7 of them &quot;did not go home during this holiday&quot; and 7 of them &quot;stayed home for 7 days or more&quot;. 1 person, 3 people &quot;stayed home for 5-6 days&quot;, 4 people &quot;stayed home for 3-4 days&quot;, and 3 people &quot;stayed home for 1-2 days&quot;. Among the 7 people who did not go home, 5 people directly expressed that they &quot;didn&#39;t like going home&quot; and 2 people said that &quot;I had other arrangements during the holiday, so I didn&#39;t go home.&quot; Among the 11 students who went home, 92% held the view that they “like to go home, but don’t like to stay at home for too long.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One conclusion is that the young people I observed do not like to go home very much, or do not like to stay at home for too long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering returning home as a population movement phenomenon, even if it is a temporary population movement, we might as well borrow the push-pull theory of demography to explain: Going home proves that there is something attractive to me at home, which makes me Things that feel comfortable, this is the &quot;pull&quot;, pull me home; if I don&#39;t want to go home, don&#39;t go home, or want to leave home after a few days, there must be something I don&#39;t like at home that makes me feel The uncomfortable place, this is the &quot;thrust&quot;, pushing me away from home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For young people, what are the main components of the “pull” to go home? &quot;It&#39;s holiday, I want to go home and eat something delicious&quot;, &quot;Studying at school is too stressful, I want to go home and rest for a few days&quot;, &quot;I miss my parents and want to go home to spend a few days with them&quot;, &quot;They It’s not easy to support my studies, so I have to go home and spend time with them during the holidays.” The students generally gave their answers in terms of emotional expression and feedback, as well as self-repair and relaxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are obviously many &quot;push&quot; components of not going home, not wanting to go home, and wanting to leave home soon after returning home. Here are some of the answers I got, and I divided them into categories according to the content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have other more important arrangements: &quot;I traveled with my boyfriend during the holidays. We went to Xi&#39;an to watch a concert, so I didn&#39;t go home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save money ’s: “If I don’t go home, I can save a lot of money. For example, if I stay at school for eight days, it costs 500 yuan, but the high-speed rail ticket alone costs more than 500 yuan for me to go home. Not going home is a big deal for me. A kind of financial savings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who feel that there are communication barriers with their parents, cannot talk together, or feel that they are not free and uncomfortable: &quot;Communicating with parents is obviously not as pleasant as communicating with roommates or peers. , my real sense of gain is also much different.&quot; &quot;I want to relax when I go home, such as watching a movie with my friends. I like to put on makeup before going out. My mother likes to keep asking, who are I with and what are I doing? , What time will you go home? I am very annoyed by it. I feel like I don’t have any freedom at home. I don’t like this feeling.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common ones are those who have thoughts about their parents’ thoughts, or want to get rid of their parents’ judgment on their own lives: “It was fine for the first two days when I went home. I ate the food cooked by my mother. I was very happy and relaxed, but Later, my parents, especially my dad, always asked me about my life plans and future plans, which made me feel even more stressed.&quot; &quot;As soon as I came back, my dad kept nagging me in my ears to take the postgraduate entrance examination and public entrance examination. , saying that a certain job has security and will be relatively stable in the future, and that that job is not good and has no future, etc., &quot;My mother gave me some instructions on how to find a boyfriend, telling me not to find a boyfriend in such and such a place, but to find a fellow villager. I&#39;m about to collapse.&quot; &quot;In the eyes of my parents, I am always a child. Once my ideas are inconsistent with theirs, they will think that I am disobedient, rebellious, and unfilial, and they will criticize me and scold me. &quot;I don&#39;t like this.&quot; &quot;My dad is a local teacher in our area. He wants me to return to my hometown to be a teacher after graduation, which will be stable and relaxing. The problem is that I don&#39;t want to go home, and I don&#39;t want to be a teacher.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that among the various elements of &quot;push&quot; in the eyes of the students, the differences in ideological concepts and lifestyles between the two generations, parental authority, and (excessive) control of children&#39;s rights to free development and self-determination Intervention is the most obvious manifestation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the acquisition and growth of students from professional fields has also made the parent-child relationship relatively tense, and conflicts or contradictions have become apparent. Some students said, &quot;I am studying sociology. I have a certain theoretical understanding of power asymmetry and discipline. When I went home and heard what my parents said to me, I clearly felt that their words were full of PUA, and their words and deeds reflected obvious power discipline. The traces of what I learned in school are vividly reproduced in my home, and this feeling makes me extremely distressed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, some students also pay attention to strategies when communicating or confronting their parents. One student mentioned, “When my parents talk about topics I don’t want to talk about, such as finding a partner, my The strategy is usually to use other topics to divert the topic. I will say that I am very busy, I have to study, I have to study, I have no time to fall in love, etc. to prevaricate them. I generally do not have head-on or direct conflicts with them, and I will selectively avoid them. Something I don’t want to talk about”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;push&quot; is greater than or significantly greater than the &quot;pull&quot;, the realistic choice for young people is naturally that they don&#39;t really want to go home, or they want to leave home after they can&#39;t stay home for a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“It’s OK to go home; it’s not OK to stay for a long time”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, most young people will not resist going home, but they are limited by the differences in thoughts and concepts between generations. , there are obvious differences in the understanding and cognition of some things and problems, which often leads to some problems when young people and their parents stay under the same roof for a long time. Young people have the mentality of doing more than doing less, so they choose not to Go home, or go home less often, or reduce the number of days you stay at home. In a nutshell, &quot;It&#39;s okay to go home; it&#39;s not okay to stay for a long time.&quot; This is the choice of most young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the students I surveyed, regarding the frequency or probability of going home during the holidays, I observed that: it seems that young people who were born and grew up in a good family or a wealthy family have a relatively low frequency, and those who think they are in a high position have a relatively low frequency. Parents who are powerful or well-connected will have more future expectations and life plans and designs for their children. They are more likely to overstep their authority and suppress and restrain their children more frequently. The latter will of course be more uncomfortable and less free. A classmate said, &quot;My dad always talks in a bossy and arrogant way. I hate it. &#39;You must take the postgraduate entrance examination&#39;, &#39;You must take the public examination&#39;, &#39;You don&#39;t need to spend time putting on makeup&#39;, &#39;You don&#39;t &quot;I always go out to drink&quot;, &quot;I have eaten more salt than you have traveled&quot;, &quot;If you don&#39;t listen to the old man&#39;s words, you will suffer a lot&quot;, I feel annoyed when I hear these words.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, for those families with average economic conditions, after the children come home, the main thing for the parents is to cook for the children and have fun with them. The atmosphere is relatively harmonious, and the communication topics are not involved or rarely involved. Children&#39;s future, children&#39;s real feeling is that they are comfortable and comfortable, and they feel no or little pressure. The holidays are real companionship for them, and they fulfill the original meaning of the holidays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real life, there are still a small number of young people who don’t like to go home. They have fierce arguments with their parents as soon as they come home. They show contempt for their parents. Even when they go home, they are locked up. They go out to watch movies and play games without any verbal or other communication with their parents. For families with average or poor economic conditions, some young people turn a blind eye to the objective fact that their parents save money on food and clothing to support their education and college. They think this is what parents should do and it is a matter of course. &quot;I am Your children, it is only natural that I spend your money.&quot; In their view, parents are synonymous with old traditions, old ideas, decadence and backwardness. Their strategy is usually to &quot;not work together if they have different paths&quot;, that is, to &quot;cut off the relationship&quot; in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, such children are not grateful to their parents for their upbringing. Faced with such a child, the other parent naturally feels disheartened and laments that his fate is bad and his family is unfortunate enough to have raised such a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Problems with parenting styles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not to mention the remark about &quot;raising children to prepare for old age&quot;. Parents work hard to cultivate and support their children. As children, we must have a basic sense of gratitude. Bar? Why is it missing? What is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the root lies in parents and their training methods. Many parents think that the standard of a good parent is to provide their children with basic or relatively superior material living conditions. I will try my best to satisfy my children&#39;s needs. This is even what good parents are all about, but this is not the case. In the process of raising and educating their children, parents cannot stop at purely financial support, but also involve all aspects, such as the source of value and the arduous process of creating value. Parents are too doting on their children. They have always known to give and give away since they were young. Children, let them feel that the material conditions they have are taken for granted, and do not instill in them values ​​such as a sense of responsibility, equality of rights and obligations, and the other side of freedom is self-responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As children, they never know or understand how difficult it is for their parents to make money. Their parents do not give their children the opportunity to experience and appreciate the hardship of their parents making money. Another example is paying attention to the inner world of children and the psychological changes during their growth. Many parents think that it is enough to feed and clothe their children, but they seldom pay attention, care and concern to their children&#39;s spiritual world and spiritual life. They seldom pay attention to, respect and listen to children&#39;s way of thinking and ideas. This is a common problem in so-called &quot;East Asian families&quot;. The common point is that both parties only focus on or care about material supply and acceptance, and do not care about each other&#39;s psychology. State, especially no or very little attention to the other person&#39;s mental state and personality traits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the solution to similar problems, from an economic perspective, when young people grow up and become adults, they theoretically have their own economic and behavioral capabilities. Shouldn&#39;t they completely &quot;cut off the relationship&quot;? Okay, is it okay for you to support yourself now? Then repay me all the fees I paid you after you turned 18, and then talk about &quot;breaking up the relationship&quot;. This may sound harsh, but it is the truth. Parents are adults, and their children are also adults, so they should get along with each other according to the contract in the adult world. If you borrow something, of course you have to repay it. This is only natural. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the question of whether young people are willing to go home, how often they go home, and how many days they stay home essentially refers to the relationship between young people and their parents. Young people and their parents have different values, different cultural levels, different starting points, and different life experiences, which will inevitably lead to different views and opinions. This is a normal phenomenon. In the process of communication or getting along, both parties should adhere to the basic principle of empathy, consider issues from the other party&#39;s perspective, respect the other party more, care more about the other party, especially respect and care about the other party&#39;s inner feelings and experiences, and advocate effective communication between the two parties. and communication to gradually resolve or eliminate the inner barriers and gaps between each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those &quot;rebellious children&quot; or &quot;parasites&quot; who only know how to take without knowing anything in return or feedback, I think parents can consider reducing or even stopping the material support for their children. In the past, they only focused on the material aspects of their children. Conduct in-depth examination and reflection on the parenting methods that focus on life but neglect the spiritual world of children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, I would like to return to a concept from the perspective of anthropology - making a home. The corresponding English word is home making, which means that home is not natural or naturally generated. Home is more than just a physical level. It refers more to the social level. Home is the result of social construction. Home requires the joint efforts of parents and children to build, build and operate. Only parents and children adopt common behaviors, actions, consultations and Only through collaboration can a true home be formed, and only then can the home in young people&#39;s imagination truly exist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大熊猫野化放归，都要上啥“培训课”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258425]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/482c666bae28b65adc021eac7d29f4cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/482c666bae28b65adc021eac7d29f4cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The Giant Panda National Park has beautiful scenery. The picture shows the Liziping area. Photo courtesy of the State Forestry and Grassland Administration&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driving from the urban area of ​​Dujiangyan, Sichuan, along the winding winding mountain road to the west, after driving for more than an hour, we arrived at the China Giant Panda Conservation Research Institute Center (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Panda Center&quot;) Wolong Hetaoping Base. The climate here is cool, rainy and humid, and it is located in the natural living environment of giant pandas. It is very suitable for wild training and captive breeding of giant pandas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reintroduction of captive giant pandas into the wild is a key technology pioneered by the Panda Center, which is mainly divided into the stages of reintroduction training, release and monitoring. Over the years, generations of scientific researchers have devoted a lot of effort to establish a complete technical system for giant panda wild training and reintroduction monitoring, which has achieved good results in practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why should giant pandas be reintroduced into the wild? What significance does this have for the protection of the giant panda population? From captivity to release, what &quot;training courses&quot; do giant pandas need to take? Recently, reporters conducted on-site visits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3acb8beb101d736d5a5f6e17e6c8354f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3acb8beb101d736d5a5f6e17e6c8354f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253798&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Researchers conduct a health check-up on a giant panda cub. Photo by He Shengshan&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Reintroduction into the wild is an important means to rehabilitate and rebuild the wild giant panda population&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The mountains and forests are green and the streams are trickling. In the rewilding training area of ​​​​Hetaoping Base, except for a path that the staff walked up and down the mountain, there are almost no traces of human activities, and the original ecology is preserved. In order not to disturb the silence, the reporter turned his cell phone to silent and walked in quietly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the dense jungle, giant panda &quot;Bosi&quot; and his cub are sleeping soundly. Not far away, keepers in &quot;panda suits&quot; were using this time to clean the pens and replenish fresh bamboo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In order to mask the human smell, the &#39;panda suit&#39; is sprayed with extracts of panda feces and urine.&quot; He Shengshan, director of the Field Research Animal Management Department of the Hetaoping Base, told reporters that unlike captive giant pandas, the The breeders are close to and dependent on them, and the breeders trained in the wild must remain &quot;invisible&quot; at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reintroduction into the wild is an important means to rehabilitate and rebuild the wild population of giant pandas, and is of great significance to the protection of giant pandas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, my country has vigorously implemented natural forest protection, wildlife protection projects and the construction of giant panda national parks to protect giant pandas and their habitats, with remarkable results. The results of the fourth national giant panda survey show that the number of wild giant pandas has increased from 1,114 in the 1970s and 1980s to 1,864, distributed in Qinling, Minshan, Qionglai Mountain, Daxiangling, Xiaoxiangling, Liangshan, etc. Six major mountain systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, natural geographical barriers isolate these wild giant pandas in six major mountain systems, and human activities have divided these six major habitat populations into small local populations that cannot interact with each other. &quot;Habitat fragmentation has resulted in the inability of genetic exchange between isolated populations, reducing the genetic diversity of small local populations and accelerating the disappearance of endangered small populations,&quot; said Wu Daifu, director of the Hetaoping base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To save a species, the integrity and stability of the community in which it is located and the genetic diversity within the species must be protected. &quot;Currently, the main measures taken to protect giant pandas in our country are in-situ protection and ex-situ protection.&quot; Wu Daifu said that the connection point between the two methods is to release giant pandas bred in captivity after rewilding training. Return to small endangered populations in the wild, thereby improving their genetic diversity, reducing the risk of extinction, and reviving the wild giant panda population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As global breeding problems such as difficulty in mating and conceiving and raising young to survive have been overcome, artificial breeding of giant pandas has achieved fruitful results, and the captive giant panda population has achieved self-sustainment. In 2003, the Panda Center launched the training and reintroduction of captive-bred giant pandas into the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2006, the male sub-adult giant panda &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; was released into the wild after independent rewilding training. However, less than a year later, workers found its body in the snow. After analysis and judgment, &quot;Xiangxiang&quot; fell from a height and was seriously injured and died during a fight with a wild giant panda for territory and food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Panda Center summarized the failed rewilding case of &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; and believed that maybe it was the lack of suitable learning objects that led to the lack of survival ability of &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; in the wild; maybe it was because the population in the reintroduction area was saturated, and &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; was not able to survive in the wild. &quot;Lack of enough living space; the competition for territory and mates among adult male giant pandas in the wild is extremely fierce. &quot;Xiangxiang&quot; may not have enough fighting experience and cannot resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sum up experience and make persistent efforts. In 2010, with the stable growth of the captive giant panda population, the Panda Center launched the second phase of the captive giant panda rewilding training project, and proposed for the first time a new rewilding training method of &quot;mother animals raising cubs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c89176807e0a5e9d5b83652545c85998.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c89176807e0a5e9d5b83652545c85998.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253797&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The giant panda &quot;Qin Xin&quot; was released into the wild. Photo by He Haiyang&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Helping giant panda cubs learn wild survival skills as soon as they are born&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“At 1:16 in the morning, the cub screamed, &quot;The mother lay on her side to protect her cub&quot; &quot;At 4:53 am, the mother adjusted her sleeping position to protect her cub&quot; &quot;At 8 am, the mother ate 9 bamboos in the morning and drank water twice. The cub screamed loudly and defecated once, but there were no abnormalities.&quot; ...In the monitoring room of the Hetaoping base, the work log of the keepers records in detail the daily activities of the giant panda &quot;Hui Hui&quot; and her newborn cubs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are 4 giant panda cubs in the first stage of rewilding training at the Hetaoping Base: &quot;Zhichun Zai&quot; and &quot;Bosi Zai&quot; who are over 1 years old, and two newborn cubs . &quot;All organs of newly born giant panda cubs are not fully developed. We must always pay attention to them and conduct video surveillance around the clock, and take timely measures if any abnormality occurs,&quot; said breeder Zhang Dalei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the growth and behavioral development characteristics of giant pandas, rewilding training is divided into two stages. From birth to about 1 year old, in a small training circle of about 2,000 square meters, the cubs eat breast milk. ; From about 1 year old to before release, in a large training circle of 200,000-300,000 square meters, the cubs gradually learn to eat bamboo independently. The large-scale training enclosure is located in the wild habitat environment of giant pandas, where there are tall trees, dense bamboo forests and complex terrain, in a completely natural state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on long-term practice and research, the Panda Center creatively implements &quot;mother animals raising cubs&quot; training. &quot;From birth, the cubs live with their mothers and gradually learn survival skills such as foraging for food, finding water sources, and avoiding natural enemies in nature. In the past, breeders could not teach pandas to climb trees in a few days. Now panda mothers use their mouths to climb trees. Just push the baby up the tree, and the panda baby will learn to climb the tree twice.&quot; He Shengshan said that giant pandas can be released into the wild only after completing a series of training and undergoing expert evaluation. &quot;At this time, two or three-year-old pandas will learn to climb trees. Giant pandas are in the post-weaning and pre-adult stage, and as sub-adults, it is easier to integrate into the wild giant panda population.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The selection of female animals is very particular. &quot;It is best for the mother animal to be a multi-parous giant panda with experience in wild life, or an individual with strong ability to raise young.&quot; He Shengshan said that at the same time, the body of the mother animal must be kept in good health, and factors such as age and genetic background must also be considered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid &quot;imprinting behavior&quot; in giant panda cubs, the impact of human activities must be minimized. &quot;Every time the female panda is fed food, the keeper will put on a &#39;panda suit&#39; to prevent the cubs from becoming dependent on humans.&quot; Zhang Dalei said that pandas should be made to avoid humans as soon as they sense humans instead of actively approaching them. Only then can they return to the jungle smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to feeding food, cleaning the enclosures, etc., keepers are also responsible for observing and recording the growth, development and behavioral performance of giant pandas, such as the time of first walking, first climbing, first eating bamboo, etc. Since 2012, Zhang Dalei has raised 7 giant pandas for rewilding training. &quot;Although the work is hard and tiring, as long as they return to the wild and live a healthy life, I will feel a sense of accomplishment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Accompanying giant pandas all year round is an enviable job, but it also contains risks and challenges that few people know about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In summer, mudslides often occur in the mountains, and the wild training circle is often put to the test. &quot;The mudslide that occurred on August 20, 2019, was less than 100 meters away from the cabin where we were resting. The situation at that time was very thrilling.&quot; He Shengshan still has lingering fears. Encountering wild animals in the wild is also common. &quot;Wild boars, snakes, etc. are often encountered in the mountains. Only by accumulating rich experience and being fully prepared can we avoid danger again and again,&quot; He Shengshan said. Now, he and his colleagues always make preventive plans in advance, bring enough supplies before going up the mountain, and carry satellite phones with them to ensure smooth communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researcher Wei Hua almost lost his life while training giant pandas in the wild. In December 2016, the cub &quot;Baxi&quot; who was trained in Tiantai Mountain was close to the age of release, but no sign of &quot;Baxi&quot; was found for two consecutive days. Wei Hua and his colleagues were very worried and entered the training circle to search, but found no trace of him. Thinking of being attacked and seriously injured by the giant panda mother &quot;Ximei&quot; who was eager to protect her cubs. Even so, Wei Hua still believes: &quot;&#39;Ximei&#39; biting me shows that it is wild and maternal. This is exactly the goal we pursue when releasing giant pandas into the wild.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6b7edb5080465fd325ad27a55d763969.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6b7edb5080465fd325ad27a55d763969.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Giant panda mother teaches her cub to climb a tree. Photo by Xue Yubin&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Carry out the reintroduction of giant pandas in an orderly manner to improve the genetic diversity of small populations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After giant panda rewilding training, how to determine Release back into the habitat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hao, senior engineer of the Investigation and Monitoring Department of the Panda Center, said that scientific researchers will comprehensively consider various factors such as suitable habitat quality, area, staple food bamboo biomass, and genetic background of released giant pandas to determine the release site. . In 2018, giant pandas &quot;Qin Xin&quot; and &quot;Little Walnut&quot; were released into the Longxi Hongkou National Nature Reserve in Dujiangyan City, located in the Minshan Mountains, after undergoing wild training and scientific evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to monitor the survival status of giant pandas after they are released? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hao said that when giant pandas are released, they will be put on an electronic collar that can be tracked and monitored, and their movement trajectory, health status and other information will be tracked through satellite signals. &quot;However, the collar It will fall off in about a year and a half, and long-term tracking and monitoring cannot be carried out. We must rely on infrared cameras, feces sampling and other methods to collect more data.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wherever the giant panda is, we will follow it.&quot; Xie Hao He said that the monitoring team members searched for giant panda feces in the deep mountains and old forests, recorded relevant detailed information, and analyzed the giant pandas&#39; gender, age, population, and genetic relationships by extracting DNA. &quot;In the mountains and valleys, we often walk for more than half a month, resting wherever we catch up at night. Sometimes we can&#39;t keep up with food supplies, and we have to go hungry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 2021, Dujiangyan During field monitoring, staff of the city&#39;s state-owned forest farm captured images of wild giant pandas through infrared cameras, which were suspected to be giant pandas released in 2018. A team of experts went to the site to inspect and collect fecal samples for further testing. Through the DNA extracted from it, it was determined that this female giant panda over 5 years old was the giant panda &quot;Little Walnut&quot; released in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/8900c1ccd18fd5129b1f27d7af40f4df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/8900c1ccd18fd5129b1f27d7af40f4df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253801&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Researchers use radio equipment to track and monitor the movements of giant pandas. Photo courtesy of China Giant Panda Conservation and Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingchun, deputy director of the Wild Ecology Research Office of the Panda Center, was excited when he saw the image of &quot;Little Walnut&quot;, &quot;This giant panda has a round body and a good mental state.&quot; Normal and living in good condition in the wild. When the DNA identification results confirmed that it was indeed &#39;Little Walnut&#39;, the rewilding training team was very excited. This showed that the rewilding training of &#39;Little Walnut&#39; for more than two years was successful. I hope it can be It thrives in the wild, and we look forward to finding a suitable husband, breeding offspring, and bringing us more surprises!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, the Panda Center has released 11 captive-bred giant pandas, and 9 are still alive. , 7 of which were successfully integrated into the wild population of the Xiaoxiangling Mountain System that are at risk of extinction, and 2 were successfully integrated into the wild population of the Minshan Mountain System. Among the released giant pandas, 1 male and 4 females, a total of 5, are over 6 years old and are in the prime stage of breeding. &quot;Only by releasing giant pandas into the wild population and breeding offspring can we achieve the goal of expanding the wild population. But finding clear evidence that the released giant pandas have offspring requires patience and time,&quot; Wu Daifu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, our country is building an integrated sky, air and ground monitoring system for national parks. &quot;We take this as an opportunity to add cameras, infrared cameras and other monitoring equipment in the areas where giant pandas are released into the wild to improve large-space monitoring capabilities.&quot; said Yang Jian, director of the Investigation and Monitoring Department of the Panda Center. At the same time, we will strengthen the research and development of collars. Efforts are made to improve battery life, improve positioning accuracy, and realize real-time transmission of recordings to understand the wild movements of giant pandas and other wild survival information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We will evaluate genetic contributions through dynamic monitoring of the population.&quot; Yang Jian said that through technologies such as &quot;cat face recognition&quot; and DNA individual identification, we will use technologies such as &quot;cat face recognition&quot; and DNA individual recognition to analyze giant pandas&#39; kinship, age structure and genetic level. We will carry out dynamic monitoring, establish a database of regional population size, structure and geographical distribution, and verify whether the released individuals are breeding offspring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Daifu said that within the scope of the Giant Panda National Park, we will analyze the factors limiting the recovery of small local endangered populations from aspects such as genetic diversity, population dynamics, community characteristics, and human interference, and scientifically formulate plans. , carry out the reintroduction of giant pandas in an orderly manner and improve the genetic diversity of small populations.同时，通过在生态廊道开展放归，增强种群间的基因连通性，为实现大熊猫种群的野外复壮提供关键支撑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，大熊猫野化培训梯队已经建立，未来每年将有培训合格的大熊猫个体放归野外，并努力复壮大熊猫小种群。 “我们将加快大熊猫野化培训、放归、监测等关键技术的创新和推广应用，力争每年放归大熊猫3至6只，并通过引种加大野生大熊猫濒危小种群资源保护，逐步建立野生大熊猫遗传种质资源库，实现圈养种群与野生种群基因双向交流。”吴代福说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列情报机构睡着了吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258423]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/xcPaSqDxQmYrHkrCAFG7JH82W519uIJUPDbL0XMu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1436&quot; height=&quot;958&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xcPaSqDxQmYrHkrCAFG7JH82W51 9uIJUPDbL0XMu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253630&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Gaza City, Palestinian militants fired rockets at Israel &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 7, 2023, the Palestinian resistance organization Hamas launched an attack on Israel in the border area between Palestine and Israel. Multiple cities launched compound sneak attacks, not only launching a large number of rockets but also conducting violent ground attacks. According to current statistics, at least 700 Israelis have been killed in Hamas attacks. This is the deadliest war between Israeli military and civilians since the Yom Kippur War in 1973. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu promised the people &quot;terrible revenge&quot; on Hamas and declared a state of war. This was Israel&#39;s first time in 50 years since the end of the Yom Kippur War in 1973. declared a state of war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this attack happened suddenly, there should be many clues to follow before such a large-scale attack. Why did Israel, which has Mossad, known as the most efficient intelligence agency in the world, not Can we give early warning? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before discussing this issue, we first need to understand that the intelligence work in the Palestinian-Israeli-controlled areas is positioned as domestic security business in Israel, so the main responsible agency is not the famous Mossad (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Intelligence and Secret Service&lt;/span>;), but the Shin Bet (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;National Security Agency&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shin Bet&#39;s past work in the Gaza Strip has always been considered low-key and effective. For example, in &quot;Operation Green Prince&quot;, they successfully instigated the rebellion of the son of Hamas senior Hassan Yusuf. Mosab Hassan Yusuf, for more than ten years since 1996, has obtained a large amount of intelligence from the core decision-making levels of the Hamas organization through him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Israel assigns the main intelligence work in the Palestinian-Israeli region to the Shin Bet is actually because there are frequent personnel exchanges between the two places, so there are many operations and inspections that require the cooperation of the police department, and Mossad Mainly responsible for external intelligence and covert operations, its personnel have less cooperation with local police forces, which is not conducive to seamless connection. In addition to internal counter-intelligence and anti-terrorism work, the Shin Bet also has security and protection work for dignitaries and important departments. It is closely connected with the police department, which is obviously more conducive to its work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So if we really want to hold the responsibility for the poor response to this Hamas raid, the Shin Bet cannot escape the blame, but in the final analysis, this incident also exposed the structural failure of the Israeli military and police intelligence and security system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information provided to me by some insiders, there are several main reasons for Israel’s ineffective response this time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is Israel’s constitutional crisis starting in 2022, which has led to military The police intelligence and security system is in panic. The judicial reforms carried out by the right-wing government led by Netanyahu may have shaken the foundation of Israel&#39;s national unity, causing experienced intelligence personnel and military police to retire early and emigrate overseas. The morale of those in office has also inevitably been low, weakening the country. overall combat capability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the internal security situation in Israel has been severe in the past year or so. The vendettas and gun battles between Arab gangs on the streets have seriously affected Israel’s social security. Organized crime investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also technical reasons. In recent years, the Shin Bet and the police have tended to rely more on signal intelligence and technical investigation. Due to their extensive electronic monitoring and aerial reconnaissance operations, as well as big data artificial intelligence intelligence analysis, they can obtain There is far more massive intelligence information than in the past, and automated processing is very fast. Classic manual intelligence acquisition methods like &quot;Operation Green Prince&quot; have become &quot;obsolete&quot; techniques and are no longer the focus of the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although signals intelligence has given Israel an advantage in recent years and is in line with the development direction of intelligence work, Hamas has now found a way to deal with it. Since the Gaza Strip is not large, a large amount of information can be transmitted through primitive person-to-person transmission to avoid signal detection. Since there is no electronic communication, no matter how powerful the monitoring technology is, it is useless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Israel, the current results can be said to be caused by a combination of low morale, personnel loss, resource tilt, and opponent evolution. In fact, the complexity of intelligence work far exceeds the imagination of the outside world. Some people use the term &quot;finding a needle in a haystack&quot; to describe it, which is actually not accurate. This type of counter-terrorism intelligence work is more like finding the poisonous needle in a sea full of needles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opponent&#39;s counterintelligence work is not limited to keeping secrets. At the same time, it will also release a large amount of true and false threat information to confuse the public, just like the shepherd boy who keeps shouting &quot;wolf is coming&quot;, leaving people at a loss as to what to do. Israel suffered heavy losses this time, and of course the intelligence and security agencies must be held accountable. However, from a professional perspective, the confrontation between intelligence and counterintelligence has never stopped. Signal intelligence obtained through network penetration, artificial intelligence, and big data analysis is not the only method for future military and counter-terrorism. Only through multi-method reconnaissance and multi-dimensional examination can the negative impact of the fog of war be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>