<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[在上海老年相亲圣地，常客们不谈爱情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258371]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/10/8025efd915.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 10/8025efd915.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253621&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of September 12, 2023, in Shanghai, in the IKEA restaurant Elderly people. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A meal for 9 people, 13 dishes, and the average cash per person was 72 yuan. Wiping his mouth and getting up, another day passed by. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;68-year-old Hong Jianming stood in front of the neon-lit hotel lobby, watching old friends walking in twos and twos, supporting each other across the zebra crossing until they disappeared. He took steps in the darkness across the road. “They don’t know that I live nearby, and I don’t want them to know.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They are single old men whom Hong Jianming met at the IKEA restaurant in Xujiahui, Shanghai. In order to &quot;eat more diverse dishes&quot;, we get together to eat together every Tuesday. Neither of them knew each other&#39;s names, and they seldom asked because there was no need. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of the single elderly people who go to IKEA restaurants want to find a companion. While they boldly express their love for the person they like, they can&#39;t help but be suspicious and wary out of self-protection, lest they suffer a loss. As time goes by, everyone has become acquaintances who maintain a sense of boundaries, and they get together just for fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Loneliness is the background here after all. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Private land&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Lack of a communication platform for the elderly&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;It is rainy in Shanghai in early autumn, but the IKEA Xuhui Shopping Mall at No. 126 Caoxi Road is bustling with people. On the afternoons of Tuesdays and Thursdays, the young people dining in the restaurant on the second floor slowly dispersed, and crowds of elderly people poured in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 3 pm on September 12, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters first arrived at the IKEA restaurant. At first glance, the dining area with nearly 700 seats was scattered. It was completely occupied by elderly people sitting apart, and there were always people walking around in the aisles, chatting with each other. Occasionally, someone walks up to the reporter, looks at the new young face and asks: &quot;Are you here to see some company?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a place where the elderly in Shanghai spontaneously Set dating angle. Xuhui Mall, opened in 1998, is IKEA&#39;s first store in mainland China. It&#39;s hard to explain how its restaurant came to be occupied by a group of singles. As long as you buy a cup of coffee for 7.9 yuan and get free refills, you can hang out in the restaurant with the mug in hand all day long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;71-year-old Chen Cuixia remembers that 18 years ago, the Xuhui shopping mall was still a small two-story building. She and her six sisters came to play as a single person. I walked around the mall and found that there was food on the second floor. &quot;It&#39;s pretty good here. Let&#39;s talk about it after it&#39;s over. How about we come back next time?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, more and more people gathered together. At the most, More than 300 single elderly people gathered here, all looking for companionship. The entire hall had to rely on shouting to communicate, &quot;the sound was so loud that it could knock off the roof.&quot; Someone suggested that everyone pick a day to get together. Tuesday is the big day and Thursday is the small day. Chen Cuixia feels that the elderly actually have no other place to chat&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;“Except here, it is the People’s Park, and there is a lack of a platform for the elderly to communicate.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest degree of aging in the country . According to the 2022 Shanghai Municipal Elderly Population and Aging Care Monitoring and Statistics Information, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022, accounting for nearly 40% of the total population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone 300,600. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;IKEA restaurant has undoubtedly become a private place for them to relieve their loneliness. Every Tuesday, a 90-year-old old lady takes bus No. 456 from Sanlin. After spending more than 40 minutes arriving at the restaurant, she just sits silently in the corner and watches the crowds of people; The wife treated her like a sister, so she packed some pumpkin seeds in a plastic bag for the old lady to eat. The two have known each other for four or five years since they met in the restaurant. When asked if they were looking for company, they shook their heads and said, &quot;Just chat, as long as Allah (in Shanghai dialect, we) are happy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Guicheng Coming from a farther place, he sets out from Fengxian District every Tuesday and takes two and a half hours by bus and subway. He comes here to chat and eat, and then goes back. He loses 70 to 80 yuan a day, just because he is lonely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 71-year-old is a matchmaker in Shanghai People&#39;s Park. He has worked for decades, but now he is also facing the dilemma of not being able to find a partner. &quot;Dating for the elderly is the same as dating for young people. They are all about business. Are your conditions good? How much money do you have?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Guicheng said, it is the same as all dating angles. , the most important condition here is also money. Everyone&#39;s opening remarks are nothing more than a few questions: Are you from Shanghai? How old are you? Have children? Is there labor insurance (retirement pension)? Have a house? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A 65-year-old old lady told Zhang Guicheng that she wanted a gift of 500,000 yuan. Zhang Guicheng also asked her this set of questions: Is there labor insurance? No; do you have a house? nor. Zhang Guicheng couldn&#39;t hold back a word, &quot;You have nothing, why would anyone give you 500,000? You just don&#39;t want the gift, and no one wants it from you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;Contempt chain&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Old ladies and old men will lose money in getting certificates&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;On the surface, the people who come to the IKEA restaurant are all wealthy elderly people, and bright gold jewelry is the most indispensable decoration here. Most of the men wear short-sleeved shirts and a bunch of keys on their waist belts, which makes them look well-behaved; those who are more individual like to wear a peaked cap upside down and stand up the collar of their short-sleeved shirts; a man often wears a brightly colored suit. The clothes, with big logos and patterns on them, reveal his wealth. He said he has had seven or eight girlfriends here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Women have also mastered the secrets of fashion. Sunglasses, silk scarves and cheongsam are all necessary items to enhance their temperament. There are also people who attract everyone&#39;s attention with their slender figures and use black masks to cover their wrinkled faces, giving them a sense of mystery. Another woman in her sixties from Gansu wears a purple top hat with huge flowers sewn on it. She speaks softly and smiles. However, because she is a foreigner, she has not found a partner yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/50a46731bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;743&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/50a46731bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253622&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 21, 2023, two women over sixty took a group photo at the IKEA restaurant in Shanghai. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As long as you spend an afternoon in an IKEA restaurant, you will clearly feel the chain of contempt among the elderly dating circle. Shanghai men with houses and high pensions are the most popular here. If you are more particular, you can also classify people from various districts in Shanghai into different grades. As for women, young and beautiful Shanghainese are the hot commodity, and some pensions are the best. Outsiders, regardless of gender, are at the bottom of the contempt chain and will be suspected of having ulterior motives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Past lessons tell the old people here that there are all kinds of &quot;traps&quot;. According to the old people&#39;s stories, there are men who dress in gold and silver and lie about how rich their family is just to sleep with the woman they &quot;took&quot;; there are women who claim they are in good health, only to expose their full body after they get together. Because of her illness, her male partner had to take her to the hospital every day; young women from other places often came to this place to &quot;talk about friends&quot; with single Shanghai men in their eighties or nineties with no children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Song Xiaofei is the &quot;confused person&quot; that everyone calls &quot;the trick&quot;. He is an 80-year-old old Chinese medicine doctor who is thin and has a slimy food residue at the corner of his mouth. Wang Xiumin, who is in her 40s, sits opposite him and peels longans for him. The two got together just a few months ago. Due to the huge age gap, they treat each other as father and daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Song Xiaofei receives a monthly pension of 8,000 yuan, which is quite high in a restaurant. All the pensions were given to Wang Xiumin for safekeeping. Song Xiaofei would receive 50 yuan of pocket money every day, which he would put into the interlayer of the veteran&#39;s preferential treatment certificate and used to buy cigarettes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Xiumin said that she felt sorry for Song Xiaofei&#39;s experience. Song Xiaofei has experienced three failed marriages, and his first wife made him suffer for 18 years. After the two divorced, the woman&#39;s natal house was allocated to Song Xiaofei. This house was divided into half during the second marriage. After the third marriage ended, the house was completely divided. Now Song Xiaofei can only rent a house in Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The third wife is Song Xiaofei whom she met at an IKEA restaurant&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; &quot;She said she owned three houses. We got a marriage certificate, but later we found out that she didn&#39;t own any of them.&quot; Song Xiaofei divorced decisively and became alone again. &quot;The third one has a very bad conscience. Now I want to find someone with a good conscience.&quot; Song Xiaofei looked at Wang Xiumin next to him, &quot;She has a pretty good conscience.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Xiumin described Song Xiaofei&#39;s experience as a cow turning into a sheep, the sheep turning into an egg, and finally the egg shell was gone. Song Xiaofei smiled after hearing this, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, I see clearly. As long as I have been around, it will all be in vain if I leave.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to avoid falling into the &quot;trap&quot;, the most common way for the elderly is not to get a marriage certificate or transfer the name on the real estate certificate . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past, Wang Liren talked about a beautiful female companion in a restaurant. &quot;We got along pretty well at first, but then she asked me to put it on the real estate certificate. Her name. I said if I don’t have a son, all three houses will be given to you after my death, but I have a son.”&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;Finally, considering that the two had already slept together, Wang Liren gave his female companion 2,000 yuan as compensation, and the female companion clutched the money and left angrily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No one wants their property to be divided in their old age. &quot;If the old woman and the old man don&#39;t have a good negotiation, they will lose money in getting the certificate! For example, if you have 500,000 yuan and want a divorce, you have to give her 250,000 yuan.&quot; A man raised his eyebrows and said that he was old &lt;span>;to&lt;/span >; said in a tone that he had already seen through the group of women in front of him. The woman on the side was not happy to hear this. She even supported the popular saying: Love without the purpose of marriage is a hooliganism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some people take the example of a successful couple in a restaurant: the man&#39;s financial conditions are not as good as the woman&#39;s, but his pension is high, so he gives all his pension to the woman and lives in the restaurant. Entered the woman&#39;s home. A few years later, the two of them did not get a marriage certificate, and their relationship was still good. &quot;It&#39;s enough to have company with each other, even if we don&#39;t get a certificate, we can live the same life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Loneliness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot; I sold myself for my son”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lao Zhang, a frequent customer in the restaurant, is also a famous &quot;confused person&quot; in IKEA restaurants. Some elderly people describe him as Being a &quot;bad guy&quot; (a dialect word for fooling around) also ruined the atmosphere of the restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is 78 years old and has lost all his teeth. He relies on the friction of his gums with black roots to eat. He can only eat mashed potatoes and liquid food, and chew a small bite of fried food. The chicken steak needs to be chewed slowly for seventy or eighty times before it can be completely swallowed. The soft chin moves the loose skin of the neck up and down, and the heavy gold chain flashes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Everyone used to call him the &quot;little tailor&quot;, which was a label for his poor days. When he was working in a garment factory, he had no money, so he would spend the night in a bathhouse near the factory. But 8 years ago, due to the demolition of his old house in Shanghai, Lao Zhang received 5 million demolition funds, became rich overnight, and more and more women began to surround him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lao Zhangtu was cheap and spent 1.5 million to buy two 92-square-meter houses in Qidong, Jiangsu. Almost every half month, he takes away a female companion from the IKEA restaurant and takes a bus back to Qidong to look at houses. He calls such women &quot;temporary workers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I spend money to buy someone to accompany me, take care of me, cook for me, wash clothes, 200 to 1,000 yuan a day.&quot; Lao Zhang said, he Prices will be based on age and appearance. The younger and more beautiful the price, the more expensive it will be. &quot;The younger ones are in their forties (years old) and want to sleep together and cuddle&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;48-year-old Shen Sufen is the &quot;temporary worker&quot; called by Lao Zhang. She served Lao Zhang for a period of time, earning 300 yuan a day. One time, I went to Lao Zhang Qidong&#39;s house. The smell was overwhelming. The things in the refrigerator had been there for a month or two. They were all packed and brought back by Lao Zhang after eating out. The ceiling was almost covered with mosquitoes and moths, and Shen Sufen spent three days cleaning it up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;My daughter doesn&#39;t care about me, she&#39;s busy.&quot; Every two or three months, my daughter will come to see Mr. Zhang and give him a wad of 3,000 yuan in cash. Zhang squandered all the money on his three major hobbies in life: coffee, mahjong and women. &quot;It&#39;s lonely every day, but having someone by your side will at least make you richer.&quot; In fact, what Lao Zhang is most worried about is that if one day he falls ill, there won&#39;t even be anyone around him to call 120. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ca8bf0b00a. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ca8bf0b00a.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;253623&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 20, Lao Zhang was going to take a bus from Shanghai back to Qidong. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The blind date story that happened in the IKEA restaurant is not all about love and love. Some of the old people are living for the next generation. And abandoned by the next generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time in the past, there was a beautiful woman in the restaurant who was looking for a companion. She was born in 1975. There was no restriction on the age and appearance of the man she was looking for. The only condition is to give her two million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason for making such a request is because my son is getting married soon and there is not enough money to collect. As long as you have 2 million yuan, you can buy a house and a car in your daughter-in-law&#39;s hometown, and you can also pay for the lottery gifts. The woman said, &quot;I sold myself just for my son.&quot; Later, she became what the old people called a &quot;psychopath&quot; and never came back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Jianming told another story about a single woman in Shanghai wearing a green dress who often hung out in restaurants. Ten years ago, her daughter asked her to help take care of the children at home. Now that the children have grown up, her daughter and son-in-law want her to live out. After several years of looking for a companion, no one wanted her, and she is still living at her daughter&#39;s house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She told me personally that they had two bedrooms and one living room, and the house was large. When her daughter and her family all went to bed, she went in quietly, washed up, and went to bed. Don’t meet them.” As he spoke, Hong Jianming waved the woman over to chat, and the woman waved her hand. &quot;Her brain has been damaged. She has no other idea but to find an old man to take her home to live with.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Old Face&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;If we can&#39;t become partners, at least we have a common topic&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After 5 o&#39;clock in the evening, the old people After getting up and going home one after another, 68-year-old Pan Yinhua chose a corner and sat alone. She laid out the cold steamed buns she brought from home, picked up a glass of hot water, and started to eat her dinner. “I don’t want to go back to that home and see He just makes a noise&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is Pan Yinhua’s ex-husband. It has been 10 years since their divorce, but neither one wants to move out of the house and they are still roommates. Pan Yinhua hopes to marry a Shanghai man who owns a house and then move out of that house. &quot;When I first got divorced, I just wanted to find a good and convenient one, so I divorced. I didn&#39;t expect it to be so difficult to find, and I was already discouraged.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Once, Pan Yinhua and an 80-year-old man fell in love with each other. The man took her home and looked around, and Pan Yinhua was quite satisfied. &quot;But that house is not his, he only has the right to use it.&quot; Pan Yinhua could see that the man wanted to form a companion, &quot;But I think he is pitiful and has no children, and I just want to remain friends with him. He is old and has difficulties. Call me and I can help him&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the 80-year-old man was attracted by a Shenyang woman in her forties who came to the restaurant, and he rented out the house in Shanghai. I followed the woman back to the Northeast. &quot;If this woman has a good conscience, she can take care of him and live for two more years. If it costs a lot of money for the old man to fall down, she will definitely not spend it.&quot; In the end, Pan Yinhua was still worried, &quot;He can talk to me very well, you can He&#39;s a reporter, can you go to Shenyang to find this old man?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Everyone who frequents IKEA restaurants knows that finding a partner here is extremely difficult. The blind date of the elderly is quick and decisive. On the basis of &quot;well-matched&quot;, the role of companionship is far greater than love. According to the usual process, as long as there is a compatibility in the first meeting, it means that the first level has been passed. Generally, the man will take the initiative to invite the woman to visit his home. If the conversation is good, they will live together. If the conversation is not good, don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/0081db2f79.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/0081db2f79.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253624&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At 21:00 on September 21, 2023, the remaining three elderly people were chatting at the IKEA restaurant in Shanghai. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past two years, Hong Jianming has taken seven or eight people he photographed home to visit, but none of them came to fruition. . &quot;Weird, why are you so weird?&quot; Some of the women brought back by Hong Jianming from the IKEA restaurant and People&#39;s Park frowned and spoke in a tone that made him uncomfortable, and some had lost their sexual needs in their later years. Hong Jianming knew it was inappropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Often after the two parties chat for half an hour, Hong Jianming will politely send the other party to the subway entrance downstairs and tell her to go home slowly. But what Hong Jianming wants most is another scene of seeing off guests: &quot;I told her, go down by yourself. Do you know the way?&quot; This means that Hong Jianming is &lt;span>;favorite&lt;/span>; of the other person. &quot;I will tell her that she will come again in the future, so I don&#39;t necessarily have to pick you up at the subway station every time, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to be in my own When the person he likes appears, he shows his intentions. Hong Jianming has practiced his &quot;lines&quot; many times &lt;span>; carefully and carefully. &lt;/span>;“I have thought about how to speak and how to answer the conversation, but no one can let me say it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I have been living alone for a long time. , Hong Jianming often feels that he has been forgotten. In this city with a population of more than 24.18 million, the hustle and bustle belong to young people. Time pushed him into his twilight years, accompanied by intense loneliness, and there was no way around it. Facing the same old faces day after day, it is impossible to become a partner, so just chat with each other as friends. Get together on a fixed day, at least there will be a common topic to pass the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is also because people are old and have nothing to do. From time to time, salespeople selling real estate and cemeteries come to the IKEA restaurant and organize sightseeing tours for the elderly. Pick-up and drop-off are included, and a free lunch is included. Some elderly people enthusiastically signed up. There is also an old man who has been developing business in a restaurant all year round. He organizes group trips with familiar people to travel to other places, and the business is constant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Every now and then, an old face will disappear here. After asking each other, they heard bad news: some old people who no longer come to IKEA restaurants have passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti ; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, all names in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 09:25:16 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深圳龙华街道工作人员抢记者摄像机，已被免职]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258355]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Situation Report (2)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;About &quot;A reporter from Guangdong TV station was improperly blocked by street staff while conducting interviews and reports near Longhua Bus Station on the morning of October 10th.&quot; Longhua Street issued a relevant briefing on the afternoon of October 10th (see the picture below for details) and immediately organized relevant activities. Situation investigation. After deliberation at the Longhua Subdistrict Party Working Committee meeting, it was decided to remove Zhou, the person involved, from his position as director of the key area governance office of the subdistrict. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/187e8c7d64171ae94152275cc831efb2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1147&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/187e8c7d64171ae94152275cc831efb2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253613&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Longhua Subdistrict Office, Longhua District, Shenzhen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;October 10, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为不上体育课，学生下跪求雨：体育何以与愉悦身心、强健体魄的初衷越来越远？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258260]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;One day, on the way home after picking up my son from school, I asked him as usual if he had anything interesting to share with me. , he said something happened before the fourth period of physical education class in the morning. Before the physical education class, a group of boys and girls in my son&#39;s class knelt down and prayed for rain, saying, &quot;God bless you, let it rain quickly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Kneel down and pray for rain&quot;, the first reaction in my mind is the plot in the TV series &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. A group of children knelt down to pray for rain in a serious manner. Of course I understood that there was an element of comedy in this, but I also realized an indisputable fact: some children do not like to attend physical education classes. On the one hand, the weather in Guangzhou is very hot. Running, skipping rope, and playing with hula hoops on the scorching playground for forty minutes is very painful or even torturous for most students; more importantly, some children There is a clear resistance to taking physical education classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can’t help but think of the time when I was in school more than thirty years ago. Physical education was, without a doubt, the most popular class, without “one”. During recess or physical education classes in elementary school, we would roll hoops, fold cards, play marbles, hopscotch, shuttlecock, and tug-of-war, and have a great time. Whether you come into the classroom with a red face after playing in the summer or warmed up after playing in the winter, it is always a very happy moment. In junior middle school and high school, before the class ends in the morning or afternoon, or before the physical education class, many of our classmates carry table tennis rackets. As soon as the bell rings, the students sitting in the back row of the classroom sprint at the speed of 100 meters. Running to the table tennis table and sitting or lying down on the table tennis table means &quot;we have occupied this table&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PE classes at that time were synonymous with relaxation, happiness, and fun, which perfectly matched the playful nature of children. Times have changed, and today’s physical education classes are far less popular than before. Some students don’t like or even hate physical education classes. What is the root cause? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we all know, the original intention of physical education classes is to strengthen children&#39;s bodies. The &quot;physical fitness&quot; here is not only about physical health and fitness, but also about cultivating the children&#39;s perseverance and fearless qualities. It has both physical and psychological implications, both of which are indispensable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to overeating, anorexia, other improper, unscientific, and unreasonable diets, or lack of exercise, or no exercise habits, many children are seriously out of shape, obese or suspected of being obese or weak. There are not a few children who are suspected of being weak. Out of shape will affect children&#39;s learning, social interaction and other aspects to a certain extent. As natural attributes, the body, body shape and body shape will construct and affect children&#39;s social attributes, usually with negative effects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to effectively solve or alleviate the above-mentioned difficulties and strengthen children&#39;s physical exercise, education authorities and schools have begun to pay attention to physical education. The importance of physical education in various subjects is increasing day by day. Not only weekly physical education The number of classes has increased significantly. In some provinces and regions, physical education classes have been officially included in the scope of entrance examinations, and physical education scores have been included in the high school entrance examination subjects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to achieve a higher overall score and not lose points along with the sports score, the original sports items as random or optional fun functions have been transformed into compulsory compulsory content for students. In other words, taking physical education classes is not to play, not to sweat, not to develop a lifelong habit of exercise, but to take the entrance exam and get a temporary score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original intention of including physical education as an examination item is to allow students to develop their moral, intellectual and physical development in an all-round way. The problem is that under such incentives, most students hope to get close to full marks or high scores in physical education. Many students In addition to physical education classroom training, students also spend a lot of time, energy and money on training for physical education examinations. Various expensive training courses, improvement courses and crash courses have sprung up like mushrooms after a rain. There is no difference between these extracurricular training programs for major subjects such as Chinese, Mathematics, and English. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the school perspective, some areas have implemented a policy that links student physical examinations to the performance of principals, and therefore to the performance of teachers. Therefore, physical education classes and physical tests are not just a matter for the physical education teacher, but also a matter for all teachers in the school, involving the welfare and treatment of all teachers in the school. Under such circumstances, strengthening physical education classes, allowing students to strengthen physical exercise even when they return home, and doing everything possible to improve students&#39; physical test scores has naturally become a common choice for many schools. &quot;Using the whole school&#39;s efforts to develop and revitalize sports&quot; has become a goal of many schools. slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let students strengthen physical exercise. The specific exercise content is very specific and clear, including the physical test items required above. Students have to insist on punching in every day, and ignore other items at all, such as kicking shuttlecock, Projects that are interesting to students or more popular among students, such as hoop rolling and hopscotch, are basically excluded. In other words, the sports that students play in class may not necessarily be what they like. They have no right to choose. They can only passively accept several types of sports designated by the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, some schools in some areas have also popularized activities designed to allow students to exercise for one hour a day - &quot;big break&quot;, which specifically includes free exercise, relaxation exercise, running exercise and other sections. The problem is that the evaluation criteria for this kind of &quot;big break&quot; are mainly beautiful formations, which require uniformity in an absolute sense. The row spacing, shoulder distance, arm raising range, left alignment, right alignment, and uniformity throughout the formation are not important. There are strict rules about not allowed to laugh and not allowed to make any sound. Students are forced to spend most of their &quot;recess&quot; time on superficial tasks such as formation rehearsals and pattern displays. Actual sports and exercise time are very limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to win the &quot;big break&quot; competition, to come out on top in the gymnastics competitions of other schools, to gain greater honors, and to get richer bonuses, some physical education teachers in some schools go to great lengths. Use your brains and find ways to &quot;create&quot;. How to &quot;create&quot; is nothing more than working on the formation and making the movements more difficult. For example, inventing a &quot;flexibility exercise&quot; requires students to be proficient in difficult movements such as splits and lower backs. How? Only repeated training once and for all, this kind of high-intensity training brings huge harm to the students&#39; bodies, and some of the damage is irreversible. From a psychological point of view, most students will feel that practicing these innovative exercises is more boring, boring, and uninteresting, and it is extremely painful for them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned various innovative exercises wearing a fitness &quot;hat&quot; are more difficult and less interesting, and there are fewer practical exercises for students. As a result, if the school radio station broadcasts &quot;Due to ****** reasons, today&#39;s recess is temporarily canceled&quot;, bursts of cheers will be heard from every classroom on the entire campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is obviously contrary to common sense, because not every student has the physical condition and talent to practice gymnastics, and not every student is suitable for doing difficult movements. This kind of training is only for professional gymnasts. It is really unreasonable to transplant standard machinery to ordinary students. The motivation behind this move - to win awards for the school and to increase the income of the school and some teachers, feels despicable and dirty, which is not an exaggeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standardizing and homogenizing sports, converting physical measurements into results and scores, and linking sports to the performance of school leaders and the pocketbooks of teachers have greatly reduced or obliterated the diversity of sports. The essential stipulations such as sex, diversity, and interest are used to alienate the children into tools for some people to pursue their political achievements. Such behavior is naturally not welcomed by the students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, we cannot oversimplify our understanding of students’ “kneeling down to pray for rain”. We cannot simply attribute it to the fact that today’s children are generally afraid of sweating, suffering, weak willpower, and weak ability to withstand stress. If you don’t like or even hate physical education classes, relevant parties should think about it in all aspects: Is the current function of physical education classes to strengthen your body, please your body and mind, or is it something else? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[研究女性劳动力市场的女性，问鼎2023诺贝尔经济学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258365]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/X0B4ScncQcKaw0hR2fkONFJQebCS37mC6nfK2fZl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/X0B4ScncQcKaw0hR2fkONFJQebCS3 7mC6nfK2fZl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253618&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Claudia Goldin. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, 2023, Beijing time, Claudia Gore, professor of economics at Harvard University Claudia Goldin will win the 2023 Nobel Prize in Economic Sciences for &quot;advancing our understanding of women&#39;s labor market outcomes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I studied Golding’s economic thought during my Ph.D., and in 2011 published “Review of Claudia Golding’s Economic Thought—Potential Female Nobel Economics” in Economic Trends &quot;A Review of the Academic Contributions of Academic Award Winners&quot;. Now I am very happy to see that she has actually won the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are traces of Goldin winning the Nobel Prize in Economics. She has served as president of the American Economic Association and the American Economic History Association, and has also been elected as a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and the National Academy of Sciences. These important indicators of a scholar&#39;s academic status have long meant that Goldin has the potential to aspire to the top. The strength of the Bell Prize in Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Uniqueness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 2023 Nobel Prize in Economics not only continues the common rules of previous years, but also has its own unique features. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the winner Golding is still from an American university. More than half of the scholars who won the Nobel Prize in Economics from 1969 to 2023 were from the United States, far ahead of the number of winners from other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Goldin was born in New York City in 1946. He received his bachelor&#39;s and doctoral degrees in economics from Cornell University and the University of Chicago. He has taught at the University of Wisconsin, Princeton University and the University of Pennsylvania. Now a professor of economics at Harvard University, she is the first female tenured professor in the history of Harvard University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, Goldin is the third female economist to win the Nobel Prize in Economics. When the Nobel Prize was first established, it did not include economics awards. Since the Nobel Prize in Economics was first awarded in 1969, male economists have always won this honor. Until 2009, Eleanor Ostrow Elinor Ostrom won the Nobel Prize in Economics for &quot;innovative research in economic governance, especially in the governance of public resources.&quot; This is the first time a woman has won the prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, in 2019, Esther Duflo became the second female scholar to win the Nobel Prize in Economics. The reason for the award was for her outstanding contributions in the field of global poverty research. contribute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third place is this year&#39;s Goldin. She revealed the main driving factors of gender differences in the labor market, which has far-reaching significance for understanding the female labor market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, both Ostrom and Duflo shared the Nobel Prize in Economics with other scholars. For example, Duflo won the Nobel Prize in Economics at the same time with her husband, Abhijit Banerjee of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and Professor Michael Kremer of Harvard University. Goldin’s husband, Lawrence F. Katz, is also an economics professor at Harvard University. The two have collaborated on many classic articles on labor economics and are a couple in the academic world. But it is a pity that Goldin and Katz were not able to share the Nobel Prize at the same time this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, the research fields of the Nobel Prize in Economics are becoming more and more &quot;down-to-earth&quot;. In the past, the Nobel Prize in Economics focused more on theoretical contributions. In recent years, the Nobel Prize in Economics has gradually begun to focus on the applied value of research. For example, Duflo, the second female economist to win the prize in 2019, studied poverty. Golding&#39;s systematic research on female employment and gender discrimination, the history of educational development and changes in wage structures also has important practical significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Goldin’s research characteristics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Goldin’s research not only focuses on the construction of a theoretical analysis framework, but also focuses on combining a large amount of economic history data to analyze Conduct research on real-life problems. Its research characteristics are to use a large amount of historical data combined with econometrics and other methods to conduct empirical research, and to analyze current problems through the perspective of the past in order to draw more practical conclusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, we quote two cases from Goldin, one is a study on women’s working time legislation in the United States. In the 1940s, 40 states in the United States passed legislation on women&#39;s working hours, setting mandatory maximum working hours for each day of the week. Many scholars believe that these laws not only fail to effectively protect these groups, but even harm their own interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Golding used manufacturing data to conduct research and found that the maximum working hour legislation not only reduced the working hours of women, but also reduced the working hours of men, and the proportion of women in the manufacturing sector was also reduced. It has not been reduced due to restrictions in working hours laws. She also pointed out that the proportion of women in other industries such as sales has increased as working hours legislation has become more restrictive. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example shows the skill of Golding&#39;s approach to researching problems. Most studies generally use some traditional &quot;discrimination coefficient&quot; and other methods to measure female employment discrimination. However, Goldin cleverly directly measured female employment discrimination by comparing the recruitment methods of American symphony orchestras before and after the reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the reform of recruitment methods, symphony orchestras mainly selected musicians through direct interviews among the many outstanding candidates selected by the music director. This method favored male applicants and favored female applicants. discrimination against persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the 1970s to the 1980s, the recruitment method was reformed in the form of &quot;blind performance&quot;, that is, listening to the performance level through a curtain screen. In this way, the judges will not know the gender of the musician applicant and can only recruit based on the applicant&#39;s technical level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the implementation of this reform, Golding found that the &quot;blind performance&quot; format can increase the likelihood of women advancing from the preliminary round by 50%, and the likelihood of entering the final stage has also increased several times. , the possibility of becoming an orchestra musician also greatly increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Employment discrimination problems may occasionally be encountered in real life, so some of Goldin&#39;s research may help solve these problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Main Economic Thoughts&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Goldin has made important contributions to the study of gender discrimination, the history of educational development and the evolution of wage structure gaps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Female employment and gender discrimination are important research topics in the field of labor economics, which have attracted the attention of many economists. Goldin&#39;s research mainly focuses on occupational segmentation caused by gender differences, factors affecting female employment, and the measurement of gender discrimination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Systematic research on the theory of discrimination in the labor market began with G. Becker (1957). Later economists gave various explanations on the causes of discrimination and the influencing factors of discrimination. Such as the crowding hypothesis (Bergmann, 1971) and statistical discrimination (Phelps, 1972). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from these theoretical explanations, Golding focuses on analyzing the influencing factors of gender discrimination in female employment from an empirical perspective. She believes that the gender discrimination faced by women in the job search process is the result of a combination of factors, and analyzes it from the perspectives of World War II, the availability of contraceptive pills, and legislation on maximum working hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scholars such as Golding believe that birth control pills reduce the likelihood of pregnancy and thus increase the age at which women get married for the first time. The widespread use of contraceptive pills among unmarried women has also reduced the cost of women&#39;s long-term career investment and increased the proportion of educated women. More female college graduates have entered the labor market, promoting women&#39;s employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Workers can improve their labor productivity and thus their income by receiving education, but what is the relationship between years of education and income? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the article &quot;The Quiet Revolution that Transformed Women&#39;s Employment, Education and the Family&quot; (2006), Golding divided women&#39;s employment from the late 19th century to that time into four stages based on changes in women&#39;s educational attainment: In the first stage, from the late 19th century to the 1920s, women in the labor market were usually young, unmarried women. At this time, the income elasticity of labor supply was very high, while the substitution elasticity was very small. Most female workers were not well educated. . The second stage lasted from the 1930s to around 1950. In this stage, restrictions on married women&#39;s work were relaxed. The income elasticity of labor supply dropped significantly in absolute terms. Secondary school enrollment and graduation rates increased, and part-time work increased. The rise of the economy and the popularization of office facilities have greatly increased women&#39;s labor market participation rate. The third stage, from the 1950s to the 1970s, was the origin stage of the &quot;Quiet Revolution&quot;. In the two age groups of 45-54 and 35-44, the labor force participation rate of women increased significantly, from 25% in 1950 rose to 46% in 1970. The fourth stage is from the late 1970s to the time when the paper was published, that is, the &quot;quiet revolutionary stage.&quot; The Quiet Revolution is mainly manifested through three indicators: horizon, identity, and decision making. Horizon mainly refers to a woman’s ability to predict her future career more accurately; identity refers to a woman’s name after marriage. retaining their surname; decision-making allows her to be better prepared to enter the labor market. The conclusion is that changing trends in women&#39;s education have promoted women&#39;s employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Economic inequality is closely related to the level of educational development. Goldin also gave a detailed explanation of the relationship between the two in his book &quot;The Race between Education and Technology&quot; (with L.F. Katz, 2008). She pointed out that the United States began to implement mass education at the beginning of the 20th century, making the 20th century known as the &quot;human capital century&quot; and the &quot;American century.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About education, technology and economic inequality, it can be summarized as follows: 1. A more educated labor force can produce higher labor productivity, which in turn produces rapid economic growth. However, it is important to note that economic growth does not depend solely on investment in education, but also on the type of government, the degree of protection of property rights, and many other prerequisites. 2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of education can also drive technological progress. In turn, the continuous progress of technology also requires more and better-educated labor force. Relative to the labor force with less education, the wages of labor force with more education are higher, and the insufficient supply of labor force with more education will inevitably lead to the labor force with more education and more education. The wage gap between the less educated workforce continues to grow. If the relative proportions of different levels of education remain unchanged, technological progress will inevitably bring about economic inequality; in other words, if the quantity and quality of education increase, technological progress will promote the decline of economic inequality. 3. Throughout the 20th century, the economic growth of the United States showed a continuous rise, but economic inequality showed discontinuity. In the first 70 years of the 20th century, economic growth brought about a decline in inequality, but in the last 20 years of the 20th century, economic inequality gradually increased. 4. Judging from the above statements, the main reason why inequality in the United States first declined and then increased in the 20th century was due to the out-of-synchrony between the speed of educational development and the demand for talents in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there is a close connection between female employment and gender discrimination, educational development history and economic inequality. The development of education is an important factor influencing the increase in female employment and changes in economic inequality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Goldin has a wide range of research interests. In addition to the above-mentioned fields, it also involves many issues such as slavery and immigrant migration. She is a female economist with extensive research fields and rich academic achievements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor and doctoral supervisor at the Department of Economics, School of Economics, Liaoning University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“国家需要就是我的专业”丨钱伟长110周年诞辰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258367]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/9CXRlLqfFveyoWxWucuEqpM9sLsWKAY9XzF2d1VJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;731&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/9CXRlLqfFveyoWxWucuEqpM9sLs WKAY9XzF2d1VJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253614&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qian Weichang (1913-2010), born in Wuxi, Jiangsu, majored in physics and mechanics , applied mathematician, academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and president of Shanghai University during his lifetime. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 9, 2023, is the 110th anniversary of Chinese scientist and educator Qian Weichang Birthday anniversary. At Shanghai University, which is called the &quot;Eternal President&quot;, activities such as &quot;Qian Weichang and Heritage Protection&quot; and &quot;Commemorating the 110th Anniversary of Qian Weichang&#39;s Birthday and the Development Forum of &#39;Long-lasting Great Deeds&#39;&quot; were held one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although he has been dead for more than ten years, the legendary stories about Qian Weichang still attract public attention from time to time. For example, his thesis that &quot;this article does not need to refer to any literature&quot;; he entered Tsinghua University with &quot;only a 5-point score in physics&quot;, but due to his strength he became a famous physicist as famous as Qian Xuesen and Qian Sanqiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned paper, called the &quot;hardest core&quot; by netizens, was published in the fifth issue of 2002 of the magazine &quot;Applied Mathematics and Mechanics&quot; (&quot;Nonlinear Calculation Problems of Large Deflection of Ningbo Yongjiang Bridge&quot;). In fact, he has a profound and unique understanding and use of research and documentation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1993, he said in his speech &quot;How to Be a Graduate Student&quot; that &quot;documentation is one aspect of investigation, and literature is an important aspect in learning, and it is also used to doing this internationally. .&quot; He also gave detailed guidance on how to write academic papers at the graduate work meeting, &quot;Before writing a paper, you must first go to the front line to find out where the person&#39;s &#39;shoulder&#39; is.&quot; &quot;What is touching the shoulder? It means looking up information and going Investigation and research.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2004, CCTV&#39;s &quot;Everyone&quot; column interviewed 92-year-old Qian Weichang. He recalled that he scored 225 points in his entrance exam, with full marks in Chinese and history subjects. &quot;I scored a total of 25 points in mathematics, physics, chemistry and English... I only scored 5 points in physics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, according to research, the facts may be doubtful. A document titled &quot;Admission Standards for Undergraduate Students Recruited by National Tsinghua University Over the Years&quot; shows that in 1931, Tsinghua University required an overall average score of 54 or above in the entrance examination, and the average score requirement for the three subjects of Chinese, English, and mathematics was at least 54 points. 49 points or more. According to the requirement of taking five compulsory exams and two elective exams at that time, according to this calculation, the total score of the seven subjects should reach 378 points. If only the five compulsory subjects are counted, it will be at least 270 points, both of which are higher than 225 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after enrolling, Qian Weichang successfully passed the &quot;High School Algebra Analytical Geometry&quot; screening test organized by Tsinghua University. In 1932, in April of his second year of enrollment, Qian Weichang was able to independently translate mathematician Fox&#39;s English paper on algebraic equations. &quot;According to our historical data research, he received very strict (academic) training at Suzhou Middle School, and their textbooks were almost all English textbooks.&quot; Wang Yuandi, secretary of the Party Committee of Shanghai University Library (Archives Museum), told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang spent his later years at the Yanchang Campus of Shanghai University. People often see Qian Weichang walking on the quiet campus. He enjoys greeting students and watching them walking hurriedly through the campus. He was particularly fond of a wide red jacket and always wore it when talking to students or communicating with leaders. Li Yin used to be the chairman of the Shanghai University Graduate Student Union and is now an academic teacher at Shanghai University. She and Qian Weichang met three times. She remembered that Qian Weichang, who was over 90 years old, was always full of energy and smiled with the innocence of a baby. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang maintained the curiosity of a scientist throughout his life. He once wrote an article sorting out &quot;The Origin of &quot;China&quot;&quot; and also discussed &quot;the structural characteristics and non-uniqueness of the Chinese Rubik&#39;s Cube&quot;; he was concerned about the problem of sandstorms in the north and once wrote to Premier Zhu Rongji in 2001: The problem of sandstorms in the north may be It is related to the number of goats raised in Inner Mongolia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He did not use political business cards during his lifetime. When introducing himself, he often used three titles: president of Shanghai University, editor-in-chief of &quot;Applied Mathematics and Mechanics&quot;, and director of the Shanghai Institute of Applied Mathematics and Mechanics. These are the three identities he cherishes and are also important achievements in the later life of Qian Weichang as an educator. Dai Shiqiang, a tenured professor of Shanghai University who has worked with him for many years at the Shanghai Institute of Applied Mathematics and Mechanics, recalled that the magazine &quot;Applied Mathematics and Mechanics&quot; edited by Qian Weichang had only two academicians including him at the beginning, but later the editorial board had a total of There have been 15 academicians, 16 presidents and vice-presidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dai Shiqiang said that Qian Weichang had three major interests in his life: football, Go and speaking. When he entered Tsinghua University, due to his poor family, Qian Weichang was only 1.49 meters tall, which was 1 centimeter shorter than the starting point of the height measurement benchmark. Like the ambitious young people of that era, he armed his body with patriotism. Less than two years after entering school, he participated in the Tsinghua cross-country team and won the championship at the sports meeting. He was later selected to the Tsinghua football team and represented the Chinese football team in the Far East Games held in the Philippines in 1937. When he graduated, Qian Weichang&#39;s height reached 1.65 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang likes to talk. Dai Shiqiang noticed that during speeches, Qian Weichang liked to tear off a corner of the newspaper on the table and chew it in his mouth. As president of Shanghai University (1994-2010), he gave speeches to students at the opening and graduation ceremonies every year, which was his unshakable practice in his later years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang&#39;s last public appearance in the media was in 2007, in Phoenix TV&#39;s feature film &quot;The Light of Life&quot;. At that time, he occasionally couldn&#39;t recognize people. Qian Wei always loved playing Go. Later, when he had no one to play with, he started playing backgammon, holding black in one hand and white in the other. Dai Shiqiang remembered that the last time he went to see him, Qian Weichang had sunspots in both hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time he spoke in front of students was at the graduation ceremony of Shanghai University in 2005. Qian Weichang gave a motto: &quot;Be worried about the world&#39;s worries first, and be happy after the world&#39;s happiness.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;He said to the students in the audience: Children, can you keep it in mind? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/HczUuZyE2ottYvWPOH3AOiVT6hMg5eEJsltukdNj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/HczUuZyE2ottYvWPOH3AOiVT6hMg5eEJsltukdNj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253616&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qian Weichang was in the study before his death. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Science is needed to save the country&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;In 1913, Qian Weichang was born in a rural intellectual family in Wuxi. His fourth uncle was Qian Mu, a master of Chinese studies. There is an anecdote that is still talked about today: During the Tsinghua University Entrance Examination, Chen Yinke asked a question in the history test paper, requiring him to write down the name, volume, author and annotator of the Twenty-Four Histories. This question was difficult to answer. Many people were interviewed, but Qian Weichang answered them all and finally got full marks for this subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a solid foundation in literature and history, it was a natural progression to enroll in the Chinese Department of Tsinghua University. But in 1931, on the third day after Qian Weichang entered school, the &quot;September 18th&quot; incident broke out. Qian Weichang&#39;s famous saying is widely known, &quot;I have no major, the country&#39;s needs are my majors.&quot; He felt that &quot;science is needed to save the country.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to enroll in the Department of Physics, Qian Weichang spent a week with Wu Youxun, the dean of the Department of Physics. Classes were held at eight o&#39;clock every day, and Qian Weichang went to the office to wait at a quarter past six. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Youxun couldn&#39;t test him, so he agreed to let him try it out. At that time, the Physics Department of Tsinghua University had requirements for probationary students. The three courses of general chemistry, general physics and advanced mathematics needed to reach the intermediate level (70 points) or above. If they did not meet the standards, they would be returned to the original department. During the first seven weeks of the trial, Qian Wei studied physics according to the memorization method of studying Chinese studies, and his test results were &quot;a complete mess&quot;. It was only after Professor Wu Youxun&#39;s guidance that things changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He goes to the Science Museum at five o&#39;clock every morning to recite. Usually when he gets there, Hua Luogeng has already finished reciting. After finding the key to learning, Qian Weichang successfully stayed in the Department of Physics. After graduating from his undergraduate degree, he was admitted as a graduate student in the Department of Physics of Tsinghua University with first place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like many progressive students at that time, Qian Weichang actively participated in the national salvation movement. In 1935, Qian Weichang participated in the &quot;December 9th&quot; student demonstrations. At the end of that year, he and several male classmates formed a bicycle team to go south and rode all the way to Nanjing to promote anti-Japanese and national salvation to the masses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After arriving at the Southwest Associated University in Kunming in 1939, he, Lin Jiaqiao and Guo Yonghuai were admitted to study abroad at the Chinese and British Boxer Indemnity Fund. The majors that the three people took the examination were all &quot;mechanics&quot;, and their scores were the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a boat trip from Shanghai to study in Canada, they were surprised to find a Japanese visa in their passports. The person in charge explained the reason: The cruise will be suspended in Yokohama, Japan, and the Japanese endorsement can facilitate their shore excursions. &quot;While the Japanese aggressor army occupied most of the motherland, they could not accept visas from the enemy&#39;s government,&quot; Qian Weichang wrote. They disembarked with their luggage. Seven months later, we set off again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After studying abroad at the University of Toronto for about fifty days, Qian Weichang co-authored &quot;The Intrinsic Theory of Elastic Plate Shells&quot; with his tutor Xin Ji. His research on the theory of elastic plate and shell bending unity began as early as Kunming. When I arrived in Canada, I found that I could combine the macro and micro ideas of my mentor. During World War II, due to the lack of guidance from a unified plate and shell strength theory, aircraft crashes and high-speed aircraft test failures were common. &quot;Intrinsic Theory of Elastic Plate Shells&quot; is also one of the first papers in this field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is included in the 60th birthday collection of American scientist von Karman. The authors of the collection also include physicists such as Einstein. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To study plates and shells, Qian Weichang creatively used Riemannian geometry and tensor analysis to study the unified theory of plates and shells. Einstein studied general relativity and also used Riemannian geometry as a tool. So Qian Weichang After the director reported the relevant results, it is not surprising that Einstein wanted to discuss and ask for advice from him.&quot; Dai Shiqiang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving his Ph.D., Qian Weichang went to the von Kármán Jet Propulsion Institute at California Institute of Technology as a postdoc. He collaborated with von Karman on &quot;Torsion of Variable Torque Rate&quot;, which von Karman called the most classic elastic mechanics paper in his life. Both Synge and von Karman belonged to the &quot;Göttingen School&quot;, a mathematical school that emphasized application. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Xin Ji&#39;s most significant influence on Qian Weichang is not to drown in the sea of ​​applied mathematics, but to climb up after solving the problem. After you get a knife, you have to sharpen it again. It&#39;s fast and good, and it can chop melons and vegetables, but you can&#39;t always appreciate how good and sharp my knife is,&quot; Dai Shiqiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang attaches great importance to practicality. When encountering practical problems that interest him, he does not limit himself to the subject areas in which he specializes. Some people call Qian Weichang a &quot;universal scientist&quot;. In 1970, domestic tank development faced difficulties: the four lead-acid batteries used in the tanks could only be started 15 times, and sometimes they could no longer walk after traveling dozens of kilometers. Qian Weichang is not a battery expert, but according to his creed, &quot;the needs of the country are my expertise&quot;, he organized a research team to study tank batteries while translating foreign documents and monographs. The next year, a high-energy battery was actually made that was the same size and weight as an ordinary battery but had eight times more energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even in his later years, Qian Weichang will study new majors for the &quot;national needs&quot;. In 1980, Qian Weichang led a delegation to Hong Kong to participate in the International Chinese Computer Academic Conference. At the meeting, the Chinese computer technology of overseas companies such as IBM was relatively mature. Some people said disdainfully: It is too difficult for you to do this. China only needs to buy the products. Qian Weichang, who was over 60 years old at the time, began to learn computers and designed a macro glyph code for Chinese characters, referred to as &quot;Qian Code&quot;. At the first national Chinese character input program evaluation meeting, the single-person input speed of &quot;Qian Code&quot; ranked first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1946, Qian Weichang returned to China on the pretext of visiting relatives. In order not to attract attention, he only brought simple luggage and books. After returning to China, he worked as a professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering of Tsinghua University. From 1946 to 1949, domestic prices soared, and professors lived in poverty. Qian Weichang&#39;s salary of 140,000 French currency was not enough to buy two thermos bottles. In order to supplement his family income, he went to Yenching University School of Engineering and Peking University School of Engineering to teach part-time, &quot;contracting&quot; applied mechanics and materials mechanics courses at the three schools, as well as some senior courses, teaching more than 15 hours a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following year, the Jet Propulsion Institute of California Institute of Technology invited him to return to the United States to work, promising generous remuneration that could solve his financial difficulties at the time. Qian Weichang filled out the application form at the U.S. Consulate. The question on the last line was: If China and the United States go to war, will you be loyal to the United States? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang resolutely filled in &quot;No&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/njgTdhnyAXpHUGqupVzYzcckzxEFgcaGXRRkBxf5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/njgTdhnyAXpHUGqupVzYzcckzxEFgcaGXRRkBxf5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253615&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1986, Qian Weichang lectured at the Shanghai Institute of Applied Mathematics and Mechanics. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“I am trying to recapture the good years that have been lost for a long time”&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang has the typical stubbornness of a scientist. &quot;He can&#39;t rub his eyes with sand and likes to make judgments and decisions,&quot; Dai Shiqiang observed. This caused him to suffer a lot in a special era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1952, Qian Weichang was appointed provost of Tsinghua University and was responsible for Tsinghua’s teaching reform. His educational philosophy was contrary to the Soviet model promoted at the time. The Soviet education model promoted the cultivation of specialists, but Qian Weichang believed that university education should cultivate students&#39; self-learning ability, and majors should not be divided too finely. Only in this way will students have the ability to discover and solve problems after entering society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; published the article &quot;Issue on the Training Objectives of Higher Industrial Schools&quot;. This article is a relatively complete presentation of Qian Weichang’s educational thoughts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the article, he wrote: &quot;Before the teaching reform, the teaching work in higher industrial schools was aimless generalist teaching. After learning from the Soviet Union&#39;s experience in teaching reform, we learned to carry out effective teaching around a clear goal. A complete set of systems and methods for planned teaching work. This is a great progress... The quality of teaching has been improved in some aspects, but students are overloaded with learning, have poor ability to work independently, and the majors are too detailed and too specialized. , resulting in difficulties in allocating employment. These are not in line with the requirements of our country and are worthy of our study and improvement.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, Qian Weichang was deprived of the right to speak on the podium after 1957. Only the title of &quot;Professor&quot; was retained, and the level was reduced from first-level professor to third-level professor. Later, when Deng Xiaoping was in charge of education work, he proposed, &quot;Qian Weichang should not stay in the laboratory, let him take classes.&quot; Later he said, &quot;There are many classes that cannot be taught, so let Qian Weichang take them; there are many problems, why don&#39;t you I understand, he understands, let him drive!&quot; So from 1961 to 1965, Qian Weichang went to nine departments of Tsinghua University and wrote nine lecture notes, and others used his lecture notes to teach. In his later years, he accepted an exclusive interview with CCTV&#39;s &quot;Everyone&quot; column and said: &quot;I still stick to everything I have.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His son Qian Yuankai was also unable to continue higher education due to identity issues. In front of CCTV cameras, he recalled his father&#39;s teachings: &quot;What you learn in school is only a small piece in a person&#39;s life... People can deprive you of the opportunity to go to school, but no one can deprive you of the opportunity to learn.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The main job of scientists is to discover and solve problems. When people and scientific and technological workers came to consult or send letters, he tried his best to help: he translated machine instructions for the factory free of charge; he provided corresponding enhancement plans for the stability of the &quot;work&quot; beams at the edge of the balcony of the Great Hall of the People; At that time, he relied on a hand-cranked calculator to calculate the &quot;sum of Fourier triangle series&quot; in a large table and made some practical contributions. The final manuscript was 30 centimeters thick. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There is a passage he said that I admire very much: I think about some problems every day, thinking about these problems that have not been solved by others in the past. Later, someone solved them and I was very happy. Later, no one solved this problem. I just wonder why. I am very happy when I can figure out a problem, and I am happier than being an official.&quot; Dai Shiqiang told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the end of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, Qian Weichang began to give lectures on the four modernizations across the country. &quot;Mr. Qian is so smart. He understands the spirit of the above very well. How to build our country (four modernizations) is clear and logical. Everyone likes to listen... He kept talking about Ili, Xinjiang, and the ethnic minorities in Ili came here on horses and camels. Listen to his lectures.&quot; Dai Shiqiang recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the preface of &quot;Selected Scientific Papers of Qian Weichang&quot;, Qian Weichang revealed his mood at that time: &quot;I regained the right to do scientific work. I was delighted to see the National Science Conference convened by the Party Central Committee in 1978, and the spring breeze was blowing. , a feeling of excitement arises spontaneously. Although I am nearly seventy years old, I can still serve the &quot;four modernizations&quot; and feel infinite happiness. I strive to recapture the good years that have passed away and work day and night.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>;Advanced education reform&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1983, Qian Weichang left Tsinghua University and went to Shanghai University of Technology (later merged to become the current Shanghai University) as president. The transfer order signed by Deng Xiaoping read: &quot;There is no age limit for this person&#39;s appointment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang&#39;s identity as president of Shanghai University continued until the last moment of his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a saying that Qian Weichang was appointed as the president of Shanghai University of Technology when he came to Shanghai. I was a little disappointed after reading &quot;Quality School&quot;. Dai Shiqiang told Southern Weekend reporters that this was not the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that in 1979, as Qian Wei grew older, he began to think about leaving Tsinghua University. Huazhong Institute of Technology (now Huazhong University of Science and Technology), Shanghai Jiao Tong University and Shanghai University of Technology are all interested in asking him to be their president. Zhu Jiusi, the dean of Huazhong Institute of Technology at that time, was a close friend of Qian Weichang. In 1980, when Qian Weichang founded the first domestic magazine &quot;Applied Mathematics and Mechanics&quot;, Zhu Jiusi contributed money and efforts to help publish the English version. When he learned that Qian Weichang was leaving Tsinghua University, he was willing to give in to others. However, Qian Weichang refused based on various considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Between Shanghai Jiao Tong University and Shanghai University of Technology, someone advised him: &quot;Jiaotong University is a famous school, and the famous school does not want your famous professors to increase its glory, but Shanghai University of Technology is not a famous school, and they are looking for talents. If you are thirsty, you can do it right away with real swords and guns.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first arrived at Shanghai University of Technology, Qian Weichang quickly started reforms. He offered to “tear down the four walls.” The first is to tear down the wall between school and society. In order to adapt to the changes and needs of society, some majors are streamlined and compressed, and majors such as applied mathematics and mechanics, fine chemical engineering, etc. are added. The second is to tear down the walls between various departments and majors in the school. Wall, the first two years of college are not divided into majors, regardless of arts and sciences, it is recommended to study computers; the third is to tear down the wall between education and scientific research. The last item is to tear down the walls of the old concept of &quot;teaching and learning&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang opposed teachers who read from the script. He once said: &quot;For any teacher who reads from the script, students can be absent from class or not attend his class, because the students themselves can read faster than he can.&quot; Zhong&#39;s requirements for teachers were initially influenced by his teacher Ye Qisun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On New Year&#39;s Day in 1939, when Qian Weichang arrived at Southwest Associated University after many twists and turns, his teacher Ye Qisun was transferred to the Chongqing Research Institute. Qian Weichang was responsible for teaching a one-semester thermodynamics course to Ye Qisundai. After getting Ye&#39;s lecture notes, Qian Weichang discovered that although the basic principles to be taught remained the same, the example questions had been replaced with the latest questions raised in international science and technology magazines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Although the same course is taught every year, the application scope of its basic theory should be changed every year, so that a basic course must keep up with the pace of scientific development. A large number of relevant international science and technology journals must be read every year. Only by digesting and absorbing the teaching materials can the professor fulfill his teaching responsibility.&quot; Qian Weichang was inspired by this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang also proposed three system reforms for the school: credit system, course selection system, and short-term system. The credit system and course selection system give students autonomy to the greatest extent. The course selection system allows students to &quot;jump&quot; classes and choose courses across grades. &quot;Students who study particularly well can learn more.&quot; This kind of educational reform was far ahead of other universities at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yuandi was a college student in the 1980s. He recalled that many schools followed the Soviet system at that time. &quot;The College of Engineering is the College of Engineering, and the College of Agriculture is the College of Agriculture. The distinction between majors is relatively strict. For example, if you study steel, you will immediately enter the blast furnace plant as a technician after leaving. For example, if you are a student of the Mining Department, you must be comprehensive. Knowing how to find ore, how to mine, and being able to use it right away is such a very specialized education.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang does not believe that there should be clear distinctions between disciplines, especially between liberal arts and science. . In 1998, he made it very clear in an article published in Guangming Daily: &quot;I believe that the traditional disciplinary boundaries between natural sciences, technical sciences, social sciences and humanities will soon be eliminated, and they will be combined into a complete scientific knowledge. System. Different disciplines are no longer separated by lines like mountains, but by learning from each other&#39;s strengths.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Qian Weichang&#39;s scientific research also benefited from his foundation in Chinese studies to a certain extent. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dai Shiqiang gave an example. Qian Weichang studied the intrinsic theory of plate and shell using the same ideas as studying Chinese studies. &quot;People who study Chinese studies are very good at analyzing and classifying.&quot; Qian Weichang divided the plates and shells into 12 plates and 35 types of shells based on their characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On today’s Shanghai University campus, traces of the lifelong president’s reforms can be found in many places. When designing the campus, Qian Weichang specifically proposed that the women&#39;s toilets should be larger than those for boys. Shanghai University has a corridor that is common in southern schools, making it easier for students taking courses to move around in different classrooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yin is now responsible for the academic work of international students. During the first lesson of the semester, she often takes the students to familiarize themselves with the campus environment. She told Southern Weekend reporters that when arriving at Weichang Building, she would always tell the students about the origin of the building: &quot;At that time, he felt that every university must have a very grand (place) where The student takes it from his parents, and when he graduates, he will be ceremoniously sent to society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Weichang attaches great importance to cultivating students&#39; problem awareness and innovative spirit. &quot;Society needs people who can come out of college with a head full of questions and be creative rather than imitative.&quot; He believes that college teachers should make it clear to students that they should not think that they have learned a lot after graduation. I understand everything, but actually I still understand very little. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From a person without problems to a person with problems, this is the success of university education.” Qian Weichang said that if students feel that they should solve these problems, they will continue to create and innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(Note: Main reference: Volumes 4, 5 and 6 of &quot;Selected Works of Qian Weichang&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/ a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 22:25:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[心理咨询中的性争议：“咨询师没有任何理由和来访者发生性关系”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258353]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/iyq1ToLamR5wWT8RlEbvi1gVIZVrifMYdJP2MdA1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/iyq1ToLamR5wWT8RlEbvi1gVIZVrifMYdJP2MdA1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253592&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中国心理学会的相关伦理守则明确规定，心理师不得与当前寻求专业服务者或其家庭成员发生任何形式的性或亲密关系。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月16日，网友“冬妮”发帖称，自己于2014到2018年间，接受咨询师李松蔚心理咨询服务，四年期间多次遭到性侵、精神虐待及心理控制等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月25日，心理咨询师李松蔚做出公开回应，称网帖指控纯属诽谤，否认自己实施过上述行为，并表示愿意接受心理咨询伦理的监管，接受相关调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，中国心理学会制定公布了《临床与咨询心理学工作伦理守则（第一版）》（下称《伦理守则》），被视为心理咨询行业的一份可靠规约；2018年，中国心理学会对第一版进行了修订。两版守则皆对咨访关系中的性或亲密关系做出了严格规定：心理师不得与当前寻求专业服务者或其家庭成员发生任何形式的性或亲密关系；心理师不得为有过性或亲密关系的来访者提供专业服务；咨访关系结束三年内，不得与寻求专业服务者或其家庭成员发生任何形式的性或亲密关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来访者与咨询师因不当亲密与性关系而陷入争议，在中国心理学界，并非首次出现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，心理咨询师王星波因与来访者发生不当性关系，被投诉至“中国心理学会临床与咨询心理学专业机构与专业人员注册系统伦理分委员会”，王星波当时是该注册系统的注册督导师。经过近半年的内外调查和当事人质证，该伦理分委会最终确认：王星波明确违背中国心理协会《伦理守则》，并被该注册系统除名。这是国内第一起被该注册系统公示的违反伦理案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，湖南心理咨询师罗登国，被长沙中级人民法院二审判定强制猥亵罪。该案终审判决文件显示，2017年5月起，被害人褚某因患抑郁症和双相情感障碍，在罗登国处寻求心理咨询服务5次。咨询过程中，罗登国主动和来访者谈起性相关的话题，并采用被褚某误认为心理治疗的方法，多次对被害人实施猥亵行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京大学临床心理学博士、大儒心理创始人徐凯文是中国心理学会心理工作咨询师委员会委员、伦理工作组组长，2014年时任该委员会秘书长和伦理委员，曾作为王星波事件伦理工作小组成员参与调查。他也曾作为组员参与了《伦理守则》第二版的修订。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据多次伦理事件的处理经验，徐凯文总结了心理工作中性与亲密争议可能的五种情形，并分别提出处理方向：一、咨询师确实实施性侵行为，属刑事问题，应走司法途径；二、咨询中存在不当性关系，属伦理问题，中国心理学会等专业协会需处理；三、咨询中产生了性移情，即来访者和咨询师之间产生情感反应，属临床议题，咨询师可与督导讨论；四、来访者有钟情妄想，可能有精神疾病，需要精神医疗帮助；五、诬告，属于法律问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于李松蔚事件，徐凯文对南方周末记者说，在事实尚未明确前，他不对该事件做出评价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月底，围绕咨询中可能存在的伦理不当和性侵害情形，徐凯文接受了南方周末的专访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“我们没有办法完全判定他是不是完全自愿”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2014年的王星波事件是国内第一起被“注册系统”公示的咨询师与来访者不当性关系伦理投诉案，你当时作为伦理工作小组的成员，具体做了哪些工作？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;来访者提出投诉，我们根据来访者提供的大量相关证据，经过先后历时近一年的调查取证，确认事实以后，我们伦理工作小组经过多轮讨论，按照《伦理守则》，提出处分意见。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在证明来访者遭遇性侵或性骚扰时，哪些可以成为证据？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得这个是很困难的，因为要证明两个人在单独相处的时候有过性关系，是不容易的。但是如果来访者能够提供比如暧昧的短信、微信，有咨询关系以外的联系，这样可以间接证明他们确实有过性关系的信息，在这种情况下，应该还是可以间接证明确实发生过不当的性关系。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2019到2021年，你担任过一位来访者的专家辅证人，当时的情况是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;就是咨询师和来访者发生了不当的性和亲密关系，来访者感到被伤害，所以来访者就状告了咨询师。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;专家辅证人在类似的性争议事件里起到什么作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;告诉法官为什么一个口腔科医生和他的病人谈恋爱不违反他的职业道德，但是一个心理咨询师和他的来访者发生性和亲密关系就是违反职业道德。因为心理咨询建立在信任的基础上，来访者向我们坦诚展示他内心的一切，首先根本上不是因为信任我们这个人，而是信任我们的职业。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打个比方，我做过一个阑尾炎的手术，全麻，全麻意味着我在大概在三四个小时中，完全失去对身体的控制，开个玩笑说是“任人宰割”。但是我为什么躺在手术台上“任人宰割”？我要解决我的阑尾炎。首先是因为我信任我的医生，不会因为我失去意识，做任何伤害我的事情，反而是帮助我。但是我跟这个医生可能根本就不认识，我为什么会信任一个不认识的人？是因为我信任的是职业，不是信任这个人。而且这里面也是有法律保障的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么心理咨询的过程跟做手术的过程相似的地方在于，只有来访者全然地信任我们，可以在我面前坦陈他经历过的一切痛苦、悲伤、羞耻、伤害，我们才有可能更好地帮助到他。那么我们要赢得这种信任，就不能辜负这种信任，而来访者来寻求帮助的时候，必定是脆弱的，他是容易受伤害的，他很痛苦，需要帮助，所以他是处在一个心理脆弱的状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来访者对我们的信任是心理咨询能够有效进行的前提和基础，所以绝对不能够破坏这种信任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更不能够利用这种信任去获取不当的利益。比如，如果我做一个咨询，我收他100块钱，但是来访者觉得很有帮助，要多给我100块钱，这也是不可以的。或者他要送我一个昂贵的礼物表示感谢，也是不可以的。这里面都涉及额外获益。因为我掌握了你内心的秘密，所以我理论上有可能会利用我对你内心秘密的掌握，去要挟你答应我的一些不恰当的要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像为什么高校里的老师不能跟学生发生性和亲密关系，因为他会决定你能不能拿到学分，能不能毕业，能不能拿到学位，这种权力上的不平等就有可能被滥用，产生不当利益的情形。为了避免这种情况，我们这个行业的职业伦理道德就要求任何这样不当的、额外的获益都不可以获得。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果有违反《伦理守则》的行为，哪怕来访者是自愿的，也会被认为是涉嫌违反心理咨询伦理。因为我们没有办法完全判定他是不是完全自愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你去年督导过一个公益心理咨询项目，当时有一个高校的咨询师遭遇性相关指控，能否展开讲讲？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;涉及来访者和咨询师的隐私，我不能说太多细节。简单地讲，是来访者认为咨询师对她有这种性意味的行为。学校进行了非常认真的调查。当然，谁指控谁举证。你认为对方是怎么性骚扰你的，要提供相关证据，比如老师给学生发过非常暧昧的、有性意味的短信、微信，都被认为违反师德规范，至少要有这样间接的材料。这位投诉的学生没有提出这样的证据，谈的都是她的主观感受，也没有发生实质性的行为，那当然这个指控就不成立。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/H9QNNJcZX730QWNkD7Mee1KvCKTYL5BiYzSzB16a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/H9QNNJcZX730QWNkD7Mee1KvCKTYL5BiYzSzB16a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253593&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2008年的美剧《扪心问诊》中，展示了一位女性来访者对心理咨询师产生移情的案例。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;注册系统除名是最重的处罚&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《中国心理学会临床与咨询心理学工作伦理守则(第二版)》涉及性关系的规则有两条，这两条的制定是出于怎样的考虑？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个规则的制定实际上是心理咨询行业的共识。类似这样的规定在国外早就有了，从这个意义上来说，是向国外心理学界学习的结果。这样一种不当性关系会对来访者造成比较严重的身心的损害，所以是一个明令禁止的行为。心理咨询伦理当中最重要的原则就是善行原则，以来访者利益最大化为利益第一，是我们工作的宗旨。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那这些年，《伦理守则》里和性有关的规定有发生变化吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;基本没有。如果说有什么变化的话，那么包括以电子方式发生性和亲密关系的行为，也是被禁止的，是违反伦理的。网络性爱这种没有发生实际身体接触的也被算在里边。在咨询关系里，所有跟来访者有任何形式的性和亲密关系，都被认为是对来访者的剥削、伤害和利用。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;网络性爱怎么界定？没有身体接触的情况下，网络上的表白、调情、暧昧等是否算在内？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这方面暂时还没有实践的案例。据我所知，我国对于网络性爱、虚拟性爱目前也还没有相关法律规定。但经过三年疫情后，网络电话等远程咨询越来越发展，因此发生这样问题的可能性越来越大。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从心理学的角度上来说，如果咨询师对于来访者实施了不当的性行为，会在心理上对来访者造成怎样的伤害？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我想对他可能造成的创伤最主要是在信任层面。因为来访者相信我们会以他的利益为重，相信我们会保守他的秘密，我们不会利用来访者对咨询师的信任去做伤害他的事情，但是这一切就发生了，那么他进而可能会对所有人难以建立信任。因为他可能受到过他人的伤害，这种伤害如果在咨询关系中再次发生的话，伤害可能会显得更严重。应该被信任的咨询师都不可信任，可能所有人都不可信，或者大多数人都不能信任。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相比一般情况下的性骚扰或性侵，当它在咨询师和来访者之间发生，会带来附加的伤害吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;无论什么职业，性侵或者性骚扰的行为首先都是违反法律的。如果来访者是非自愿的，那就是性侵和性骚扰，是法律问题。但如果来访者是自愿的，在其他行业可能不是问题，但是对我们这个行业来说，它就是伦理问题。因为你可能利用了来访者对心理咨询职业的信任。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当一个女性来访者，在心理咨询过程当中感受到了这方面的不适，现在心理咨询行业里，有没有可以投诉的渠道？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;可以向中国心理学会临床心理学注册工作委员会的伦理工作组投诉，但是投诉的渠道不一定能够非常适用，因为这是一个学术组织的伦理投诉机制，它并不是一个国家政府性质的机构，如果被投诉的咨询师不是中国心理学会临床心理学注册工作委员会的成员，就很难去做后面的投诉处理。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;也就是说，在国内，如果一个人想成为心理咨询师，并没有准入门槛？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。目前来说没有严格意义上的准入门槛。原来是有人社部的心理咨询师考试，但是这个考试2017年停止了。现在除了当时已经获得人社部心理咨询师资质的（心理咨询师），以及精神科医生和心理治疗师外，其他从业者并没有明确的证照。我们国家这方面的证照制度还没有建立起来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;是否可以理解为，在“注册系统”里注册的这些咨询师可以被视为正规从业者？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得可以，但不能说只有“注册系统”的人员才是正规的。也有大量受过很好训练的，包括获得硕士甚至博士学位的，包括留学回来的（人员），以及有丰富临床经验和良好职业操守的咨询师并没有参加注册，因为这不是一个强制性的国家标准。所以这不能是唯一的标准，但是它是一个靠谱的标准。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《伦理守则》看上去只是一种行业约束，遇到具体的性争议事件时，中国心理学会能起到什么作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;就像你刚刚提到的王某某（注：王星波）的情况，这应该就是最典型的华人世界第一起不当性关系伦理投诉案。但是我们做的事情也就是对他进行永久除名，也就是说他不再能够被接受成为“注册系统”的注册人员——注册心理师或注册督导师。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这是现在能做出的最严格的反应吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;哪怕被系统除名，被投诉的咨询师仍可以继续进行心理咨询工作？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，理论上来讲是这样的。实际上解决的方式就应该建立证照制度，就像医师有证照，如果被吊销执照，他就不能行医，否则就是非法行医，甚至要追究刑事责任。但是我们现在还没有建立证照制度，所以在这一点上比较困难。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;对道德自律性要求比较高的行业&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有文献认为，性伦理失范在来访者侧显示为“情欲性移情”（erotic&amp;nbsp;tranference）和“情欲化移情”（eroticized transference），这是否是你所说的“性移情”？在咨询关系里，为什么会有性移情的产生？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有各种各样的原因，可能很难用一句话概括。比如来访者有过被性侵的经历，然后她可能会产生一种心理，觉得自己所有的价值就是在于她的身体，那么她要用她的身体去获得有权力、有权威的人的认可，这是一种可能性，这是非常个体化的。所以很难讲哪一条是绝对的，要看具体的情况。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，心理咨询关系也是一种人际关系，一种专业的、职业的人际关系。在心理咨询和心理治疗过程中，咨询师会以来访者为中心，去深入地共情、理解、感受来访者并给与回应，这是一种全然的关心和无条件的支持，既是专业的也存在某种非现实性，因为这样的几乎单向的、全然以来访者为中心的人际关系，在现实生活中是一种理想化的存在。因为即便是最亲密的家人、朋友间的人际关系，也是双向的，既会给予和付出，也会得到同样类似的支持和回报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经和一位爱上自己的咨询师来投诉的来访者访谈过，她在咨询中会感受到咨询师是世界上最能理解和支持自己的人，也是最体贴和温暖的人，因此爱上了咨询师。但一旦进入了恋人甚至婚姻状态，来访者很快就感到越来越失望，因为她发现那个全然以她为中心的人一旦变成了恋人和夫妻，也会对自己有情感诉求以及并不能全然以自己为中心了。继而这种失望导致婚姻关系的破裂，甚至导致对对方当时和自己相恋的动机的怀疑，最后还对簿公堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种从天堂到地狱的感受转变就是跨越了专业咨询关系的界限，发生性和亲密关系必然的结果。但并不是说，咨询关系为来访者提供这样的安全、信任、温暖、支持的关系是不真实或不科学的，来访者在其现实生活中遭遇了困难和挫折，产生了心理的痛苦和困扰，因此来寻求帮助，咨询师为其提供心理疗愈的环境，就好像一个人生病后，需要住到非常洁净的医院病房里，有专业的医生、护士提供专业科学的医疗设备、环境、营养、药物来帮助其提高免疫力，恢复健康，甚至在其免疫力低下时还要住进无菌室，负压病房，病人在医生、护士的精心照料下，增强抵抗力，恢复免疫力，健康后就能出院正常生活了——在心理咨询中，来访者就能具备自己解决好自己的人际关系、亲密关系问题的能力，这个时候就能结束咨询了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来访者感到自己爱上咨询师并不是错，但可能是错觉。咨询师需要清晰地认识到这一点，并将其作为咨询中重要的临床议题进行专业的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来访者是否需要避免这种性移情？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得性移情的发生是有某种必然性的。它不是一个可怕的事情，它是个很正常的心理现象。所以如果发生这样情况，应该在咨询中加以讨论和解决，这本身是咨询重要的议题。这是一个专业问题。咨询师遇到这样问题，如果没有经验，可以去跟他的督导或者他的上级的咨询师讨论，怎么样更好地帮助来访者处理好这一切。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果咨询师对来访者产生了反移情，这种情况下怎么办？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;咨询师也有可能会出现这种情况，咨询师也是人，也有七情六欲，也有他自己没有解决好的个人议题。他确实可能会错把来访者的性移情当作是爱情，或者甚至于爱上来访者。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是咨询师的训练和职业道德要求，无论什么情况下，我们都不可以跟来访者有这样的性和亲密关系。这就好像是这个行业中，每个人都不折不扣去执行的法律。为何要执行这一条，是因为此前国外心理行业出现了很多这样的情况，对来访者造成了很大的伤害，对行业的声誉也造成很大伤害，所以是明令禁止的。如果他能够处理好这样的临床议题，当然最好；他处理不好，应该找督导；找了督导还是处理不好，他应该停止咨询，然后把咨询工作转介给更合适的咨询师，而不是继续做下去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这样的话，对于咨询师的道德自律性要求很高？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。我们这个行业是对道德自律性要求比较高的行业。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果咨询师发出了不当的性或亲密接触邀请，来访者可以怎么保护自己？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;首先，建议来访者要有清晰的认识，在咨询中发生的性和亲密关系是在特定咨询环境中发生的，并非完全自然真实的情感，无论是来访者感到爱上了咨询师，还是咨询师向来访者表达爱意。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，建议告知咨询师，根据《伦理守则》，如果咨询师发出了性和亲密关系的邀请，咨询师已经违反了相关规定，可以要求其停止相关行为并建议其接受督导。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再次，如果咨询师继续有相关言语、行为，建议向咨询师所在机构进行投诉。如果咨询师本人就是机构负责人，或者这是私人机构，例如咨询师的个人工作室，建议考虑终止咨询关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;心理咨询行业应该建立证照制度&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，心理咨询过程关于性与亲密的争议，还会涉及钟情妄想和诬告的情形，能否介绍一下这两种情况？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;钟情妄想是一个严重的精神疾病，比如经常有明星被疯狂的粉丝爱上，粉丝认为明星是爱他的，实际上明星见都没有见过他，明确否认对他有任何爱意。这是钟情妄想的例子。妄想就是跟现实不符，并且不能够被现实所纠正。妄想是基于生物遗传因素，不需要有任何现实基础和心理社会原因。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;诬告的情形通常是出于怎样的动机？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;诬告的情况，可能是对咨询师不满，为了毁掉咨询师的名誉，并没有依据事实或者捏造了一些事实，然后指控咨询师。所以我说，“事实是智慧”。先把事实搞清楚，究竟有没有过发生性和亲密关系？如果有，那么咨询师至少是违反了伦理，甚至违反法律。如果这个行为没有发生过，那么违法和违反伦理就无从谈起了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;诬告者需要付出怎样的代价？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;诬告主要是涉及名誉权的问题，侮辱、诽谤他人、损害他人名誉权的，有权要求停止侵害、恢复名誉，消除影响、赔礼道歉，并可以要求赔偿损失。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果核心证据缺失的情况下，伦理工作小组或整个心理学界、行业对性争议事件的处理方法是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这方面还是很困难的。确实要认定这个是很困难的，这个显然不是心理学家擅长的工作。所以谁主张，谁举证，需要有足够的直接或间接证据能证明该行为发生过。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;面对这类来访者和咨询师间的不当性关系，我们还能做什么来规避或减少类似情形的发生？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;让更多的来访者知道这一点，是会有帮助的。可能很多来访者不知道咨询师和来访者发生性关系这点违反咨询师的伦理道德，这个很值得去和公众宣传。当然来访者知道他能够拒绝，发生类似情况也知道怎么保护自己的话，这个显然是有效的方式。咨询师真的性侵来访者的情况不是没有，但是我想还是很少，犯罪行为毕竟是少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当人们需要心理咨询服务，如何找到靠谱的咨询师？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;来访者要审慎地选择咨询师和咨询机构，就好像看病的时候也要小心，应该去正规医院是同样的道理。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当寻求医疗诊治时，我知道什么是公立三甲医院，什么是私立医院。心理咨询行业有这样的分级吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐凯文：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在行业还没有成熟到这个程度，但是我想会有这么一天的，就好像二十多年前我刚开始当医生的时候，医疗行业也还没有成熟到现在这个程度，所以会有一个过程。我们也希望媒体能够帮助我们行业一起呼吁国家加强这方面的立法。现在有《中华人民共和国精神卫生法》相关的法律条文，但对于这个行业管理来说还是不够的，特别希望引起政府和法律界人士的重视，能够修订相关的法律。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《精神卫生法》是11年前颁布、10年前开始实施的，不够系统和全面，还不能够适应现代。现在的中国心理咨询行业不可同日而语，心理健康需求大大增加了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最简单直接的解决方式，就是建立执照制度。拿到执照才能够做心理咨询师，然后接受国家和行业协会的监管。如果有违反伦理、职业道德和法律的行为，他就会被吊销执照，如果在没有执照的情况下从事这样的工作，就是非法行医，可以追究刑事责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么要讲“科技伦理”？这是攸关文明与人类存续的大事丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月8日，科技部官网公布《科技伦理审查办法（试行）》，规定：从事生命科学、医学、人工智能等科技活动的单位，研究内容涉及科技伦理敏感领域的，应设立科技伦理（审查）委员会（第四条）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一引发关注的规定，既反映了这些领域科研活动高度活跃、正取得肉眼可见的进步，也折射出某些科研突破的不仅是认知边界，还有伦理边界，确有厘清伦理边界、凝聚社会共识的必要性与紧迫性，因为这不只是科学家个人或所谓“内部”的事，而是涉及每一个人权利的“众人之事”。期间一些关于科研伦理的认识误区，亦有必要加以辨析与澄清。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，“科研活动是善的或至少是中性的，因此科研无禁区”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科研跟科研不一样，不能一概而论。数学家拿纸笔进行演算，物理学家用天文望远镜眺望宇宙、用粒子加速器试图轰开原子核窥探微观奥秘，说这些科研是善的没有问题。既拓展了人类的认知边界，树立了求真标杆，又对支撑人类社会存续的价值观没有冲击、反有增益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而对药物的人体试验、人脑接口、人造子宫、对人类胚胎与DNA的操作，显然很不一样。此类科研，不仅直接拿人当研究对象或人本身就是参与者，而且研究过程与可能的成果对人类社会本身就形成现实与潜在的重大冲击，包括但不限于生活方式与价值观方面，必须慎之又慎，在有社会共识前提下谨慎推进，才是对社会与文明负责任的态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说严重些，如果让反人类分子进行此类研究，并将此类发现用于反人类目的，人类社会因此被毁灭也不是没有可能的。比如现在关于基因修饰、编辑的技术，成本与习得的门槛都越来越低，而这项技术对人类社会的存续来说不是中性的。过去发生过骇人听闻的事：拿人体当试验对象，研发细菌武器，这是对整个人类在犯罪。所以，1970年代国际社会形成了禁止生物武器公约，禁止发展、生产与储存此类武器。现在基因技术突飞猛进，如果不对此类技术加以管制，整个人类会面临空前的威胁。这种威胁比核毁灭的概率高多了。有风险不是最可怕的，最可怕的是无视风险而陷入自大与傲慢之中。科技伦理的重要性于此可见一斑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此，“科研无禁区”之说难以成立。科研包括研究目的/效果与研究手段。就目的/效果而言，有善/利、中性、不善/不利及善恶/利弊参杂等多种可能；就手段而言，也有合法、合乎伦理与非法、悖逆伦理等不同情形。某个具体的科研领域、某种具体的科研活动，该不该设立禁区，该设立什么样的禁区，禁区是从研发环节一开始就设立还是设立在传播环节，要系统衡量具体的科研目的/效果与手段，不能一概而论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、“科研是科学家的事儿，大众没有发言权”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于对第一点的分析，不难推知这一点也是不成立的。科研活动是科学家从事的高级认知活动，没有一定的天赋与专业训练做不来，这诚然是对的。“争辩火箭发射用水洗煤还是无烟煤”，专业人士认真回复都算输。不过，除此之外，大众或纳税人有权过问的事儿多了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，如果科研活动本来就是纳税人的钱资助的，纳税人当然有权过问这钱使用的合理性，包括但不限于：这一项目对知识边界的拓展、对社会利益、对价值观的各种可能影响是什么，成本预算是否合理，科研手段是否合乎伦理，出来的成果有没有达到预期的目标。如果是私人资助，私人赞助人也就有权过问类似的问题。谁出钱，谁就有权过问，这反映了人类社会的基本伦理“受人之托，忠人之事”，是从事任何活动包括科研活动的伦理前提。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，正如第一点所说，如果研究领域或研究活动使用人为研究对象，或者/而且对人类的生活方式、价值观、文明甚至智人作为一个物种存续本身有影响、冲击或威胁，那就是事关每一个人的切身权益，社会的每一分子都有权过问，研究不由纳税人资助或“个人自由”或“科研高贵神圣、是精英活动”等都不是逃避大众过问的理由。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综上，大众有权过问的两大理由，正是必须要有科技伦理的根源所在。在这个意义上，科技伦理也不神秘，只是人类社会每一个人都要遵循的普遍伦理与价值观在科研领域的体现：如果你从事的任何活动是有人资助之下进行的，那你就要接受资助人的问责；如果你从事的活动对第三方或社会有现实或潜在的“负外部性”，你就要有效控制之，不得为所欲为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科学家有光环，但有光环也不意味着可以无视踏伦理，或者对大众的过问权不屑一顾，觉得“靠科学家自律就行了”。科学家也是社会的一分子，在日常生活中遵守大家都遵守的伦理，在科研活动中遵循科技伦理的指引，这样科研才能向善，不至迷失航向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[棉校服里塞碎布条？校服何时成了家长的负担？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258343]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，吉林敦化一名学生家长发短视频称，女儿的校服“外表光鲜，内里不堪入目”，且“不穿校服不让进学校”，引发网络热议。 10月9日晚，敦化市委宣传部回应称，视频中的条状物为脱落的防水涂层，留样校服已送省级权威部门进行质量检测。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/8ll6wJV9z5ffF1B0vKyoQp7WafGhsXcwwN1MQSBd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1341&quot; height=&quot;1140&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/8ll6wJV9z5ffF1B0vKyoQp7WafGhsXcwwN1MQSBd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253590&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;视频中棉服内散落的条状物&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（央广网发网络截图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，对于“不穿校服不让进学校”的传言，当地回应称，不存在相关规定，但同时又表示，“基本都有学生上学时要穿校服的要求”。不难看出，穿不穿校服，家长和学生其实没有多少自由选择的余地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无独有偶，就在今年7月，广东东莞一中学发布的新生入学须知，要求学生需缴纳4000余元校服费，就引发争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/246663d7527f58bcab18c4db676eb3e5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/246663d7527f58bcab18c4db676eb3e5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253591&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;学校收费截图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（东莞市光正实验学校微信公众号/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了给家长减负，前些年发布的《进一步加强中小学生校服管理工作的意见》，提到“学生自愿购买校服”。但在实际操作中，校服往往是一件上学的必需品。这意味着，校服的生意，通常是一门刚需生意。据杭州中经智盛市场研究公司发布的报告称，我国校服行业市场规模在1120-1180亿元，可见校服是一个大市场。衍生出的校服摊派、校服垄断、校服腐败等乱象，也让校服质量问题频发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;校服真的是一个必需品吗？怎样看待学校要求买校服？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日本学者如何解读周作人：读东洋文库版五卷本《周作人读书杂记》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258311]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/CE6NWdcI8oUVCHLFD8In4KoAzRH479rd0fpNpenB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;871&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/CE6NWdcI8oUVCHLFD8In4KoAzRH479rd0fpNpenB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左图为周作人，右图为中岛长文翻译的《周作人读书杂记》。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（平凡社2018/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;日本的周作人翻译与研究&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;来日本留学后，虽然不是专攻文学，由于在国内时就喜欢阅读知堂的作品，一直很留心东瀛学界对他的研究。有意思的是，日本的知堂研究同样也受到政治问题的困扰。虽然战前就有松枝茂夫那样服膺知堂的学者开始翻译与研究，但二战后由于政治原因，以知堂为研究对象的学者很少，翻译也罕见，我看到过的只有一本，就是松枝茂夫翻译的《周作人随笔》(富山房百科文库，1996)，此书是旧书新编。松枝二战后还与人合译过《鲁迅的故家》，但他的新译仅此一册而已。胡适则待遇更差，直到最近才有一本传记出版，还是翻译美国汉学家格里德的《胡适与中国的文艺复兴》，国内早就出过了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪九十年代中期开始读研后不久，一位老师送给我东京大学比较文学专业博士刘岸伟写的《东洋人的悲哀：周作人与日本》。十多年前，刘岸伟更上层楼，写了一部《周作人传：一位知日派文人的精神史》，获得了著名的和辻哲郎文化奖。刘岸伟为了研究知堂，甚至还学习了古希腊语，在书中讨论了知堂译的古希腊经典，看得我好奇心发作，想哪一天全面校读一遍。最近刘岸伟还与人合作，出版了《知堂回想录》日译本，为日本读者提供了很好的传记资料。除了刘岸伟，这些年也有些日本学者在做知堂研究，比如参与编辑《周作人致松枝茂夫手札》的小川利康教授，近年出版了《叛徒与隐士：1920年代的周作人》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些年陆续有一些知堂的作品出了日文版，比如中国文学专家木山英雄编译的《日本谈义集》(东洋文库，2002)，收入包括四篇“日本管窥”在内的随笔计四十六篇。如书名所示，都是谈日本文化的。而最重要的则应推中国文学专家、《围城》译者之一的中岛长文编译的五卷本《周作人读书杂记》(东洋文库，2018)。五年前看到《朝日新闻》上刊登的《东洋文库》广告时，笔者大吃一惊，因为印象中《东洋文库》从来没有一举推出同一个人的五本著作。真佩服这家出版社的魄力，到底是出过日本最好的大百科全书和《林达夫著作集》等好书的老牌出版社。因缘凑泊，最近借来这套书，仔细读了几篇译文和解说，发觉果然是一套下了大功夫的好译著，很值得为国内读者介绍一下，看看东瀛的学者是如何阅读知堂的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/WmMqi6PYTz5zGEB8gOK40WZxUx6wNB8MsL1VybUE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/WmMqi6PYTz5zGEB8gOK40WZxUx6wNB8MsL1VybUE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;周作人与友人在苦雨斋。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;最好的日文版知堂著作&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们知道，知堂一辈子读书无数，写的很多文章都跟书有关系。用他的学生张中行的话来说，论读书量之大，读书之驳杂，在老一辈里知堂是名列前茅的。所以中岛教授从读书的角度来编选知堂的文章，把这套书命名为《周作人读书杂记》是很有见地的决定，可以说抓住了知堂一生求知的主线。而用来做翻译底本的，正是我当年读过的《知堂书话》。不过他用了更新的版本，是2004年中国人民大学出版社出的两卷本。当年跟《知堂书话》差不多同时推出的《知堂序跋》，则基本没有采录，因为在中岛教授看来，序跋是知堂写他亲见的书籍的，作为译者要一一验证并不容易，只好割爱。为了能够全面反映知堂作品的全貌，中岛教授说他还参考了《周作人自编文集》《周作人文类编》《周作人散文全编》和《周作人译文全集》，也就说事实上是从所有作品中编选出来的五卷本。在翻译底本的取舍方面，译者的认真劲儿着实令人佩服。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在确定了大方向后，具体各卷怎么安排，也是很费思量的事情，毕竟知堂写的文章涉及的学问门类繁多，文章的数量也惊人。用他自己的话来说，他的学问是“横通”，是“杂学”。所以中岛索性把那篇自传性的《我的杂学》放在第一卷开头，这样一来就是最佳导读了，可以让不熟悉知堂的日本读者对这位异国文人思想家有个大致了解。毕竟跟他兄长比，在日本的知名度有天壤之别，鲁迅的文章甚至日本中学语文教材都收入过。第一卷在《我的杂学》之后，译者还分了读书论、禁书、书志等子目，收入相关文章。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/BFTwoxiZlzn2Qnf35InJvKi9MDrcUHerQuqXJzTg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;897&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/BFTwoxiZlzn2Qnf35InJvKi9MDrcUHerQuqXJzTg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;对周作人影响较大的两位学者，左为霭里思，右为柳田国男。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二卷以跟民俗有关的文章为主。知堂对民俗的关心持续一生，在中国现代文化史上是很突出的一位。用中岛的话来说，在神话学和民俗学方面，知堂堪称现代中国相关学问的开山始祖，不仅对英国古典学大师简·哈里森女士的学问很熟悉，而且也很推崇日本现代民俗学开山始祖柳田国男。第三卷编入跟女性和性有关的文章。中岛说知堂之所以很关心女性和性的问题，其动机究竟是什么，就算现在还是不清楚，但至少在思想上是受英国学者霭里思的影响。把相关文章收入第三卷，也是很有眼光的选择，毕竟这是知堂一生学思的极其重要的组成部分，知堂说过，对他影响最大的是霭里思。据张中行说，知堂读过包括七卷本《性心理研究》在内的三百多万字的霭里思著作，可见影响之大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实这套知堂读书杂记日译本的分类也没有统一标准，中岛说从第三卷中途开始就从按标题分类转为按种类来分类，说其实也是受到《我的杂学》的影响，基本上跟这篇知堂述学的分类差不多。而到了第四卷，则以知堂谈论中国新旧文学的文章为一卷。第五卷收了很多谈笔记的文章，也有谈旧小说的。知堂一生喜欢读笔记，我们看他的集子就可以知道，他读了大量历代笔记，文笔不用说也受到影响，他自己的很多文章就是很好的笔记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;细看了中岛教授的编选分类后，笔者觉得他所选的文章，已把知堂一生的学思都囊括在内了。笔者也读了一些译文，质量都很棒，应该说这五卷译文，为日本读者提供了值得信赖的文本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/yviJvXqfXrRQF1Q5rv3EoAwXtz8iZwH82btzm5K3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;838&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/yviJvXqfXrRQF1Q5rv3EoAwXtz8iZwH82btzm5K3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;日本东京工业大学文科教育研究所刘岸伟教授和他的代表作《周作人传》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（东京工业大学网站/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不可错过的解说&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我原来觉得自己读了很多年知堂的作品了，附在每本书后的解说不读也罢，哪知稍读几页，就发现大错特错。等我耐心读完五卷本的解说，先是被译者下的功夫感动了，因为每篇解说都很长，有的近三十页，最短也有近十页。为方便日本读者阅读，除介绍了很多背景材料外，最有趣味的是中岛教授谈他对知堂看法的部分，不仅仅有称赞，也有很锐利的批评，更有站在日本人立场的入木三分的洞察，有的还发前人所未发。下面就择要介绍一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，在谈到知堂对神话学和民俗学的关注时，中岛指出知堂的相关工作都是在书斋里进行的，只在1913年在绍兴收集过两百首童谣。中岛说这点就和知堂推崇的柳田国男相差太大。柳田国男为收集民俗材料走遍了全日本，为日本民俗学建立了一套做学问的规则。中岛还指出，同为书斋型学者，知堂跟《金枝》的作者弗雷泽也不一样，因为他并不从事分门别类的工作，也不分析资料，也就是说没有体系化的工作。这点的确是说到点子上了，也许这跟知堂做学问的方式也有关系吧，毕竟他从来不觉得有写作论文的必要和压力，一直是用随笔的方式写作。中岛的批评也让笔者产生了一些联想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前听到过一种说法，说周作人号称是中国最好的知日派，但是他并不是真正研究日本的学者。乍听觉得很错愕，因为本能地会反驳，难道还有比知堂对日本文化更了解的中国学者吗？可冷静一想，知堂的确没有以写论文的方式做日本文化研究，他主要是以随笔的形式写出他对日本文化的观察与分析。他的民俗学和神话学方面的工作，也是如此。中岛指出，同样的特征也体现在知堂对女性与性心理的关注和研究上。他说知堂的方法是以自觉的个人为主体，没有结合大众运动，所以在实践上效果就是零。也就是说知堂想通过文章来启蒙，其结果就宛如坐等黄河变清。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/V8zfMLkNUczfDZ2Tuxrg5j0WLCv7gX9cU7keGaF0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;466&quot; height=&quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/V8zfMLkNUczfDZ2Tuxrg5j0WLCv7gX9cU7keGaF0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;晚年周作人。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一句话说最好的读书方法就是翻译。中岛作为译者，可以说通读了知堂的主要作品，反复推敲的结果，使他对知堂的文本有一般读者所没有的理解。比如，中岛指出的一个问题，我以前就没怎么注意过，就是对柳田国男的理解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;知堂有一篇谈柳田国男的名作《远野物语》的文章，篇名就叫《远野物语》。中岛说知堂读柳田的书时，跟他读郝懿行和俞正燮时是一样的，就是以思想通达和文章可读性为标准来读的，但对柳田的文章想传达的最重要的东西，就是民俗学，却并没有太强烈的关注，也就是说，没怎么从学问的角度来看。换言之，知堂承认柳田的书同时具有文章之美与民俗学的价值，却似乎看不到他从柳田的民俗学里到底挖掘出什么，进而阐述了些什么。这样的批评让我想起了知堂自己的话。他说他只是喜欢读杂书，多了解一点事情。自己并非文人，也非学者，只是打杂而已。两厢对照，也许就好理解了。中岛也说了，把柳田的文章当作好文字来欣赏当然无妨，但是如果没有读出民俗学的意味，就很可能产生误解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当年中日关系日益恶化时，知堂说过对自己的日本研究的困惑，比如在1937年6月写的《日本管窥之四》里，说他所欣赏的那个美好的日本与现实中侵略中国的日本无法联系在一起。知堂坦白说看不懂那样的日本，说他平时觉得日本民族跟中国有一点很相异，就是宗教信仰。借用柳田国男的说法，就是在日本人的崇拜仪式中往往显出“神人和融”的状态。知堂说日本上层思想界吸收了中国的儒家和印度的佛教，近代以来又加上了西洋的哲学与科学，但是民族的根本信仰似乎还是从南洋来的神道教，一直支配着国民的思想感情。中岛也谈到了这部分内容，他说知堂虽然说自己不懂，其实在这里已经基本上点出了事情的真相，因为知堂说他如果能够懂抬神舆的壮丁的心理，也就能够了解日本的对华行动了。中岛说在这里知堂总算不再是从文学角度，而是从民俗学角度真正利用了柳田的民俗学成果，分析日本侵华不是光从上层政治家、军人和知识分子的角度，而是把眼光投向民间。柳田研究民俗学的目的正是为了挖掘那些无法简单地作理性化处理的思考与心理机制，它们积淀在群体的无意识里，制约着民众的行为。中岛说知堂读了那么多年柳田，此刻才算真正明白柳田到底在说什么了。中岛的这一分析的确很锐利，因为这是我们中国读者很难察觉的一个问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/7foPziv5ixeyj6RBwyROIxk3eYlqFwezpIuIEz8w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;486&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/7foPziv5ixeyj6RBwyROIxk3eYlqFwezpIuIEz8w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;日本学者吉川幸次郎。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写到这里，我想起了另一位大学者吉川幸次郎回忆跟知堂见面的文字。在《外国研究的意义与方法》这篇文章的开头，吉川说在中日战争爆发后不久，他在北京见到了知堂。他说知堂对他说自己的日本研究过于重视日本文化里受中国影响的部分，对日本的宗教关注不够，这些都是致命缺陷。吉川说他很直率地回答的确如此。其实他对知堂的日本研究评价很高，因为在他看来，当时的中国人大都不承认日本文化有独特性，而知堂深爱日本，主张日本有自己的文化，对此吉川认为日本人和日本政府应该表示感谢。不过，在他看来周作人的日本研究事实上过于偏于平安时代，偏于江户末期和明治时代某一派的文人（应该是指白桦派），而这些虽然可以说代表了日本的文的时代，但却不能代表日本的武的时代。即便不能说这些是日本文化中很中国化的部分，但的确是中国知识分子很容易理解的时代。吉川接着说，日本还有代表武的时代，比如镰仓幕府，还有镰仓时代出现的日莲和亲鸾的宗教在日本的历史中占有重要地位，这些日本人是非常清楚的。可是在知堂的日本研究中几乎完全是被忽视的。之所以如此，吉川认为这是中国人重视文的缘故，日本重视武的这种国民性跟中国的传统不一致。吉川说还有一个原因，那就是中国文化里缺乏宗教。那种在死后、在脱离人间的、超感觉的地方寻找理想世界的想法，吉川认为儒家是强烈反对的。虽然这种倾向因佛教的进入而有所减弱，但很快就有反弹，到宋儒的时候就彻底定型了。而日本与中国相反，正是在这里有日本最特殊的地方。在吉川看来，因为日本在宗教方面与中国相反，即便是博学的知堂也没有对此产生兴趣，所以他的日本研究失之偏颇，也导致他无法理解日本的军事行动。吉川甚至说日本的中国研究应该以知堂为教训，反省是否犯了同样的错误。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/QLGfbMLg0t57Taac0rf6AigiLRR5K4hQIArMoTnh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;517&quot; height=&quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/QLGfbMLg0t57Taac0rf6AigiLRR5K4hQIArMoTnh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蒋百里。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉川对知堂的日本研究的分析与批评，跟中岛的放在一起看就更加完整了。对日本文化中武的一面的认识，笔者认为跟知堂同时代的蒋百里看得最为精准，毕竟蒋百里学军事出身，读过日本的军事院校，在日本军界也有一些友人，他对日本这个特点的把握，在中国的日本通里是最精准的，有些看法甚至预言了战争的结局。我们读一读他写的《日本人—一个外国人的研究》就明白了。知堂虽然精通日本文化，在日本也有很多文艺界友人，但他的日本研究确实也存在书斋派风格的问题，他对局势的误判，与此也有关系吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在谈到知堂的独特文学观时，当然会提到他对明末小品文的高度评价。中岛说明末小品文不仅在中国掀起热潮，而且跨海影响到日本的中国文学研究者。笔者孤陋寡闻，这点倒是第一次听说。中岛说据他所知至少有两位著名学者受到影响，一位是入矢义高，另一位就是在日本最早介绍钱锺书《宋诗选注》的小川环树。入矢义高有关于明代文学的研究，也以对禅宗的研究知名。据中岛介绍，小川环树并没有直接研究明末小品文，但是一直爱读知堂的文章，知堂文章里提到的书籍他顺藤摸瓜大体都收集了，如今都收在小川文库里。中岛说在翻译时因为有小川文库而获益匪浅。笔者读到这里时也觉得太巧了，因为手头有一套筑摩书房出版的《小川环树著作集》，跟知堂的著作放得很近。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/tlWHtV0tNa5wFO8rUzmU751NJYEPwcQ0G0F2ZXMx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;766&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/tlWHtV0tNa5wFO8rUzmU751NJYEPwcQ0G0F2ZXMx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;竹内好。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;启蒙与落水&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在总结知堂一生工作的特点时，中岛说可以用“物理人情”这四个字来概括。对知堂而言，这个“物理人情”不仅是判断文学作品的价值标准，而且也是所有事物的判断标准。这个观点跟张中行在《再谈苦雨斋》一文里的观点完全一致。中岛还说，用更通俗的话来概括就是“合理的思考和符合人性的感情”，这正是知堂从本国文明和外国思想那里吸收的启蒙精神的精髓。同时这也是知堂想用来解决中国根本问题的最重要药方。中岛说正因为有这一条，不应该因政治上的失足而抹杀他的贡献。有意思的是，此时中岛笔锋一转，谈到了这个启蒙精神在21世纪碰到的困境。他说原以为这个融合了东西思想精髓的“物理人情”再过一百年也还是会有效的，可是进入21世纪后，发现几乎所有的理想都破灭了，于是开始怀疑这个启蒙精神是否也有局限。之所以这样怀疑，是因为看到日本人已经过上丰衣足食的生活，教育普及，高中几乎都能入学，能进大学的也有近六成。不问质量的话这是个很惊人的数字。照理说这个数字跟近代以来有志之士抱有的理想很接近了，可是社会上谁也不负责任的无责任主义盛行（这话让人想起著名政治思想家丸山真男说的“无责任体系”），民主制度似乎变成了民粹主义，可以说有愚民政治的倾向。在这种情况下，如何提倡“物理人情”呢？如果真的那样，当年的启蒙先哲们的一切努力不就付诸东流了吗？这个问题太大，笔者也没有能力回答，不过中岛是很敏锐地察觉到了近代启蒙可能会带来的严重问题，这点写《启蒙辩证法》的阿多诺和霍克海默早就警告过了，中岛只不过是旧话重提。不过他能把“物理人情”这个知堂的启蒙理念跟近代以来的启蒙思潮放在一起讨论，显示了他宽广的视野，因为我们的启蒙毕竟跟西方是有密切关系的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写知堂就不可能不提他的落水。先前提到，中岛教授认为不能因为这件事就把他全部否定，这跟钟叔河先生说的人归人、文归文精神是一致的。不过站在日本人的立场上又是如何看这件事情呢？我记得好多年前读竹内好的《内部的中国》时，看到他提到知堂，他说我们日本人对不起他。中岛教授在解说里说了类似的话，但更为具体，让我这个中国读者读了很感动。他说把知堂当作风雨祭里的稻草人一样抬出来，让他坐上神舆，然后扔到村外路边的是我们的祖父、父亲那一代人。换而言之，就是现在社会上工作的那些人的曾祖父或是曾祖父的父辈，他们的名字都已经记不清了，但都是日本人。这点我们不应该忘记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，不管出于什么外部原因，毕竟是知堂自己的判断，无法把责任归咎于他人，但是竹内好和中岛长文这两位一生研究中国文化的日本学者的这番话，知堂若地下有知，肯定会很感慨吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;关于知堂译者的点滴&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;读完中岛教授的最后一篇解说后，尤其令人敬意油然而生。他说这个翻译工作最初是2005年平凡社的编辑提议的，一共花了13年，真是一场漫长的持久战。考虑到他的体力和年龄，能够坚持到最后真是很不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在谈到日本的知堂译者时，他重点提到了松枝茂夫和木山英雄，向他们致意。松枝茂夫晚年在整理知堂书信时曾说“半生潦倒红楼梦，一生倾心周作人”，前者指他的《红楼梦》翻译，后者当然就是指他跟知堂从学生时代结缘到知堂晚年的通信交流了。据说松枝茂夫曾打算翻译全部知堂的著作，后来没能实现这个夙愿。他的学生木山英雄1973年就把知堂谈日本文化的相关文章结集起来，编成《谈日本文化》一书，就是收入东洋文库的《日本谈义录》的前身。木山还通过采访知情者，写出了关于知堂落水的著作《周作人对日合作始末—〈北京苦住庵记〉补注及续篇》，是所有对那段历史有兴趣的读者都无法绕过的著作。他还协助耄耋之年的老师整理出版了先前提到的《周作人随笔》，收入知堂到三十年代为止的名篇三十九篇。除了翻译，很寡作的松枝先生写过《周作人先生》一文，虽然是1941年写的，但是笔者所看到的最好的写知堂的文章之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;读了这么多年知堂的文章，总算有机会写一写知堂。还是钟叔河先生的那句老话，人归人，文归文，知堂在政治上的失足，的确令人惋惜，让仰慕他的读者为他感到不值，因为胡适说过智者应该是识得轻与重的，但他却做出了令国人大跌眼镜的判断。但他的著作自有传世的价值，毕竟知堂给中国文化史和思想史留下了一笔宝贵的财富，有些思想至今不失光辉。据说胡适上世纪五十年代回台湾后，托人到处收集知堂的著作，说五四以来还值得一读的就是这位老友的著作。虽然不无夸张，但也说出了不可否认的真相。而本文介绍的东瀛学人的工作，也可以为我们提供一些理解知堂的新思路吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[解构“讲课费”，数读藏起来的医药腐败丨H5]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打击缅北电诈有重要突破！揪出幕后“金主”、组织头目23名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258333]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;span>;今年6月25日至9月30日，公安部党委针对夏季治安特点和安全稳定形势，统筹指挥全国公安机关全警动员、全力以赴，开展了一场严打各类违法犯罪、严整突出治安问题的夏季治安打击整治行动，简称为“夏季行动”。10月10日，公安部召开新闻发布会，介绍全国公安机关扎实开展夏季治安打击整治行动举措及总体成效等情况。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/12bb94e7ad11a35ebaacaedc57bc199b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/12bb94e7ad11a35ebaacaedc57bc199b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253568&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;公安部：抓获缅北涉我违法犯罪嫌疑人2317名&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部“夏季行动”办公室副主任、治安管理局副局长尹春吉在10日召开的新闻发布会上表示，公安部在“夏季行动”中坚持以打开路，形成严打高压态势。公安部部署开展打击缅北涉我违法犯罪专项行动，加强边境警务合作，抓获并移交我方涉诈犯罪嫌疑人2317名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据公安部消息，在云南省公安厅的指挥部署下，普洱公安机关进一步扩大战果，209名电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人于10月1日成功移交我方。同时，临沧公安机关边境警务执法合作取得重大进展，缅甸相关地方执法部门分别于9月25日和10月7日，先后两批向我方移交电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人497名。这是继西双版纳、普洱公安机关之后，云南公安机关开展边境警务合作取得的又一重要突破。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，相关犯罪嫌疑人已由内蒙古、黑龙江、浙江、安徽、福建、河南、重庆等涉案地公安机关押回。公安机关将彻查其全部犯罪事实，在依法严厉打击诈骗犯罪的同时，深挖境内黑灰产等关联犯罪，确保全链条打击，依法严厉惩处。经过持续有效打击，&lt;strong>;已有2317名缅北涉我电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人被成功抓获并移交我方，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;其中幕后“金主”、组织头目和骨干23名，网上在逃人员94名，&lt;/strong>;有力挤压了境外诈骗分子生存空间，近期全国电信网络诈骗案件发案呈现明显下降趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“夏季行动”期间公安部共破获刑事案件56.6万起&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尹春吉在发布会上介绍，行动期间，公安部共破获刑事案件56.6万起，查处治安案件204.2万起，抓获违法犯罪嫌疑人员97.5万名；化解矛盾纠纷284.6万起，消除治安隐患86.5万处；全国110接报刑事、治安警情同比分别下降13.8%、5.2%，全国道路交通事故起数、死亡人数同比分别下降11.5%、16.7%，行动实现了预期目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;公安部：“夏季行动”以来38个涉黑组织被打！&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部“夏季行动”办公室副主任、刑事侦查局副局长郑翔在10日召开的新闻发布会上介绍，各地公安机关深入推动常态化扫黑除恶斗争进一步向纵深发展，“夏季行动”以来，共打掉涉黑组织38个、恶势力集团430个、恶势力团伙286个，抓获犯罪嫌疑人8146名，其中，抓获“漏网之鱼”的目标逃犯348名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑翔表示，各地准确把握夏季犯罪规律特点，坚持“快、准、狠”地打击各类寻衅滋事、聚众斗殴、故意伤害、抢劫抢夺等违法犯罪活动，深挖黑恶线索，打掉街面寻衅滋事等恶势力团伙238个，抓获犯罪嫌疑人1808名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“夏季行动”以来公安部找回失踪被拐妇女儿童683名&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑翔在10日召开的新闻发布会上表示，各地公安机关以“零容忍”的态度，深入推进打击拐卖妇女儿童犯罪、性侵犯罪、医保诈骗犯罪等专项行动。“夏季行动”以来，抓获涉嫌实施拐卖妇女儿童的犯罪嫌疑人212名，找回失踪被拐妇女儿童683名；抓获涉嫌实施性侵的犯罪嫌疑人1.6万名；抓获涉嫌实施医保诈骗的犯罪嫌疑人1657名，打掉犯罪团伙83个，有力震慑了犯罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;打击黄牛！公安部研判拦截“黄牛”账号5万余个&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尹春吉在10日召开的新闻发布会上介绍，公安机关涉黄涉赌、涉枪涉爆、黄牛倒票等违法犯罪始终保持“零容忍”的态度。“夏季行动”中，全国公安治安部门坚持打防并举、源头治理，主要采取了三个方面的措施：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是集中开展“铲黄赌·治源头”专项打击。“夏季行动”开始后，公安部挂牌督办重大黄赌案件173起，部署对30起系列黄赌专案发起4轮次集群战役。各地公安机关按照统一部署集中开展“铲黄赌·治源头”系列专案攻坚，抓获违法犯罪嫌疑人7000余名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是深化打击整治枪爆违法犯罪专项行动。会同有关警种部门围绕境内制贩、网上贩卖、境外走私三个重点，对4起重大涉枪案件开展集群战役，核查涉案线索3084条，带破案件53起。“夏季行动”期间，公安部组织全国170多个城市集中开展销毁非法枪爆物品活动，将近年来收缴的气枪、猎枪等14万余支枪支以及一大批炸药、雷管等爆炸物安全销毁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是深入开展打击整治“黄牛”倒票专项工作。针对新冠病毒感染实施乙类乙管后，营业性演出赛事活动、热门景区景点“黄牛”倒票突出等问题，公安部专门召开视频会议，组织各地公安机关持续开展专项打击工作。行动以来，各地共排查网络倒票线索1.9万条，抓获违法犯罪嫌疑人900余人，查获各类门票1.2万张，约谈整治一批票务平台，下架处置违规门票网店300余家，研判拦截“黄牛”账号5万余个，有力维护了票务市场秩序和行业健康发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>