<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国务院国资委原副部长级干部骆玉林被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260729]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 15:08:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission punished Luo Yulin, a former deputy ministerial cadre of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council, for serious violations of discipline. Illegal issues were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Luo Yulin lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his original intention and mission, was disloyal and dishonest to the party, was inconsistent with his appearance, and acted two-faced; he violated the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepted private enterprises in violation of regulations Banquets and travel activities arranged by the boss; violating organizational principles, concealing personal matters, seeking benefits for others and accepting property during the selection and appointment of cadres; selfish desires and profit-seeking, long-term illegal acceptance of gifts and money, illegally engaged in profit-making activities, and many A private business owner lends money to obtain large returns and engages in power, sex, and money transactions; his life is corrupt, his family tradition is not upright, his family governance is lax, and he neglects the discipline and education of his family; he has no bottom line in discipline and law, uses public tools for private purposes, and uses power for personal gain. , colluding with unscrupulous businessmen, engaging in power and money transactions, taking advantage of his position to benefit others in business operations, project contracting, etc., and illegally receiving huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Yulin seriously violated the Party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and being suspected of bribery. He did not restrain himself or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Party. His nature It is serious and has a bad impact and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Luo Yulin from the party; The treatment he enjoys shall be canceled in accordance with regulations; his illegal gains shall be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues shall be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved shall be transferred together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年中国电影总票房已突破500亿元，国产片票房占比创十年来新高]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260699]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 14, Nandu reporters learned from the real-time data of the Beacon Professional Edition that as of November 13, 2023 The country&#39;s annual total box office (including pre-sales) exceeded 50 billion, and the top ten box office in the current year are all domestic films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258491&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Data show that the top ten films at the box office are all domestic films, including &quot;A River in Red&quot;, &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;, &quot;Desperate&quot;, &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot;, &quot;Fengshen Part 1: Chaoge Fengyun&quot;, &quot;Eight Anise&quot; &quot;In the Cage&quot;, &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, &quot;Bear Infested·Stand with Me &quot;Bear Core&quot;&quot;, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; and &quot;Unfamiliar Life&quot;, these ten films all have a box office of more than 1 billion yuan. It is reported that domestic films account for 83.4% of the current annual box office, the highest in the past 10 years; imported films account for 16.6%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;944&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258492&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨郑永流：学法律的自豪来自两部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu, the first doctor of jurisprudence in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1957 in Macheng County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963－1974&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;went to primary school and middle school in Macheng County and Huangpi County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1982, studied at the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1983-1986, studied at the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law and received a Master of Laws degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1986-1989, studied at the Law Department of Peking University and received a doctorate in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1989-1993, served as lecturer and associate professor of the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1993-1996, he served as a visiting professor at the School of Law and Economics, Saarland University, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2004, he served as Acting Professor at the Law School of the University of Freiburg, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2023, he worked at the University of Friborg in Switzerland, the University of Oslo in Norway, He has served as a short-term visiting scholar at the University of Frankfurt in Germany for many times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1997 to 2022, he served as professor at the Law School of China University of Political Science and Law and China Europe Law School. Professor, doctoral supervisor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently a distinguished doctoral supervisor at China University of Political Science and Law, legal philosophy and interdisciplinary legal research at China Europe Law School Director. He is a member of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR) and the editor-in-chief of the journal &quot;Philosophy of Law and Sociology of Law&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu (first from the right) held a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu ( First from right) giving a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For our generation, reform and opening up has brought a great turning point in our lives.” October 2023 is the most beautiful time of the year in Beijing. In the autumn season, in a teahouse near Xueyuan Road, Zheng Yongliu recalled his youthful years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1978, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to Hubei University of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law) and became a freshman in the law department. At this time, 4 years had passed since he graduated from high school. During those four years, Zheng Yongliu worked as an educated youth in the countryside and as a fisherman in the lake area. When he took the college entrance examination, he was a surveyor in the water conservancy engineering team of the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County, Hubei Province (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Born in a county town, Zheng Yongliu’s hometown did not have a university. He had never seen a university before. “Everyone yearns for a university, but they have no concept of it. They only know that a university is an ‘ivory tower’. &#39;, it&#39;s a world that you can&#39;t concretely imagine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing undergraduate and master’s degrees at Hubei University of Finance and Economics and Central South University of Political Science and Law, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to the Law Department of Peking University in 1986, where he studied under Chen Shouyi, a legal educator and one of the founders of contemporary Chinese jurisprudence. professor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, Zheng Yongliu graduated and became the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of New China. His doctoral thesis &quot;The Status and Development Path of Law in Rural Reform&quot; began to explore rural legal issues more than 30 years ago, and proposed the &quot;three-dimensional adjustment method of rural development of human ethics-law-policy&quot; and &quot;legal localization&quot;. The idea is extremely groundbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from Peking University, Zheng Yongliu taught at Central South University of Political Science and Law, Saarland University in Germany, University of Freiburg in Germany, and China University of Political Science and Law. In Zheng Yongliu’s view, “the first PhD in jurisprudence after the founding of the People’s Republic of China” was the starting point of his academic career, but it is his subsequent academic research that determines his reputation and academic status. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;This college is worth it&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From graduating from high school in 1974 to taking the college entrance examination in 1978, what were you doing in the intervening years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I graduated from high school, I was 17 years old. My classmates and I all went to the countryside to become educated youth. There was great enthusiasm at that time, and the countryside was a &quot;vast land with a lot to offer.&quot; We have all stated that we want to take root, blossom and bear fruit in the countryside and do not think about anything else. There are many lakes in Hubei. I worked as a fisherman in the countryside for two years. When fishing every day in winter, we have to get up at 5 o&#39;clock in the morning and set the net before the fish wake up. Otherwise, when the sun comes out, the fish will scatter and go out to look for food. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was transferred to the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City) as a surveyor, carrying a ruler and doing measurements everywhere. For example, when building a reservoir, it is necessary to measure the rain-bearing area, which determines the height and thickness of the reservoir dam. If the dam is built too high, it will be wasteful. If it is built too low or too thin, it will be easily washed away, so the watershed must be measured. Because we have not gone through any special study, our job is to go over mountains and ridges to place measuring rulers, trace and post pictures and other auxiliary tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You took the college entrance examination just after it resumed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In August 1977, Deng Xiaoping chaired a symposium on science and education and decided to resume the college entrance examination, which had been suspended for 11 years. At the end of 1977, each province resumed the college entrance examination with its own questions. When the exam notice was sent out, I was at a water conservancy construction site. If you don’t have time to review, you will naturally fail in taking the exam. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I took the college entrance examination in the second year, I had time to review by chance. At that time, a river in the county needed to be renovated, and the engineering team sent me to a cement factory in another place to purchase cement. The production environment in the cement factory was very bad. Although everyone wore masks and took other protective measures, there was a lot of dust in the factory. In May 1978, I contracted acute pleurisy. At that time, the water accumulation in my right chest was very serious, and I could even hear a &quot;gurgling&quot; sound in my chest when I breathed. A female doctor surnamed Gong said that I should be hospitalized immediately. She would use a particularly thick needle to puncture my back to my chest every day and extract about 100 ml of accumulated water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After about a week of pumping, the fluid in the chest was gone, but the inflammation was still not gone, so I could no longer go to the cement factory to purchase cement. The doctor asked me to stay in the hospital, but I said no, I had to take the college entrance examination. At that time, there were many people living in one room in the hospital, and I couldn&#39;t review. The doctor also understood. She kept me in the hospital for another three days, and then asked me to go to the hospital for injections during the day and stay at home at night. So I went to the hospital twice a day, and rested at home during the rest of the time while reviewing. In the summer of 1978, I entered college. I am very grateful to Dr. Gong. After I was admitted to college, I made a special trip to visit her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you went to college, was law your first choice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, law is my second choice. When I was filling out my application form, I preferred literature. At that time, everyone had a literary dream and wanted to be a writer. At that time, the most popular liberal arts subject was what we called &quot;xianxue&quot; - &quot;literature, history and philosophy&quot;. Students with high scores were admitted to the Chinese Department, followed by the History Department and Philosophy. At that time, I applied for the History Department of Wuhan University. In 1978, the key score for liberal arts in Hubei Province was 340 points. I scored 332.3 points, which was a few points short. Later, the key line was lowered to 330 points, and my score was enough, but at that time I had been admitted to the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics, so I missed the history major. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is college life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was particularly impressed. On the first day of college, the school arranged a movie reception and showed us movies. The movie is called &quot;The Black Triangle&quot; and it&#39;s about catching spies in the north. The plot of the movie is average, but there is a song in it that shocked us very much. It was &quot;The Spring Water in the Border is Clear and Pure&quot; sung by Li Guyi. She sang this song using a new so-called breath singing method, which was completely different from the heroic and aspirational singing method popular in that era. That was the first time I realized that the song could still be sung like this. At that time, I felt: I went to the right university. I have never been exposed to these before. If I had not gone to college and lived in a small county, I might not have heard this singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;University opened up a new world for me. The end of 1978 to 1979 was a period of surging ideological trends. At that time, there were many lectures in the school, such as those of Peking University and the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. Many famous scholars came to Wuhan to give lectures and spread some new ideas, which made me even more determined: this university is worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/16/79bc830a15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 79bc830a15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;What should we do when studying law&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After going to college, are you interested in law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the first half of college, I didn’t have much feelings about law. I really became interested in this major because of movies. At that time, every Saturday, the school would show movies in the playground, and we would all watch them for free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there was an Indian movie &quot;Wanderer&quot;, which tells the story of two young people. The woman&#39;s name is Lida. She is a lawyer who represents her friend in court. Raz defended, vehemently. Lida studied law, and we immediately felt that studying law was very impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, another movie was released, &quot;Tragedy on the Nile&quot;, which tells the story of a Belgian detective named Poirot who used reasoning to find the killer on the cruise ship. At that time, we felt that this was also related to the law, and we might have to do related work in the future. A classmate in the same class got the nickname &quot;Poirot&quot; because he often imitated the great detective, and his classmates still call him that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching the movie, we gained some pride in studying law and felt that we should eliminate violence and bring justice to everyone. At that time, some students from other departments watched these two movies and asked to transfer to our department to study law. Of course, the theory is obscure, but everyone still has a general understanding of &quot;what we should do when studying law&quot; through film and television works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After you have the pride of studying law, you are interested in jurisprudence Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our freshman year, we mainly took public courses and also offered jurisprudence. At that time, I felt that jurisprudence was too abstract and difficult to understand, but the teacher Wang Yajin, who studied in the Soviet Union, asked me to be the class representative of jurisprudence, so I did. At that time, there were no subdivisions in the legal profession, but you might be interested in a certain subject. Some people are interested in criminal law, others are interested in civil law. I am very interested in international law. My graduation thesis is also in the direction of international law, discussing the subject status of international organizations in international law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, the school asked me to stay and teach in jurisprudence. At that time, I thought that if I wanted to stay in school to teach, I would definitely need a higher degree, so I enrolled in a graduate program at this school. Zhang Ruolong, the dean of our Central South University of Political Science and Law, is a professor of jurisprudence, so I studied jurisprudence with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still didn’t feel much about jurisprudence when I was in school, but I felt that since I was a graduate student, I should study hard. It was also at this time that I started to become interested in jurisprudence because I had invested a lot of time in it. But to truly understand and study jurisprudence, it is still at the doctoral level and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you later go to Peking University to study for a PhD in Jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because I have entered the field of jurisprudence and want to continue my studies. At that time, only Peking University in the country was able to recruit doctors of jurisprudence. My supervisor is Chen Shouyi, who is also among the first batch of liberal arts and the first doctoral supervisors in jurisprudence in the country. According to research, in November 1981, the State Council approved four scholars from Peking University: Chen Shouyi, Rui Mu (International Economic Law), Wang Tieya (International Law) and Zhang Youyu (Constitutional Law) of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences as the first batch of law doctoral supervisors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Teacher Chen was getting older, in his eighties, and needed someone to assist him. At that time, Liu Shengping was the director of the Jurisprudence Teaching and Research Office of Peking University Law Department. He was not yet sixty years old and was in the prime of life, so the specific daily work was managed by Teacher Liu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Chen is not in good health. He asks us to come to his home from time to time to talk, mainly about what is happening in the courts and procuratorates and what new problems there are. Another thing is to listen to what we think in theory. What he said the most is that we need to start from China&#39;s reality and understand more about China&#39;s reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your doctoral thesis is &quot;The Status and Development of Law in Rural Changes&quot; &quot;Road&quot;, how did you pay attention to this topic? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I entered Peking University in 1986, the topic of reform was very hot and my thoughts were very diverse. There are many various academic seminars in Beijing. After I arrived in Beijing, I also participated in these academic seminars and met some people from the China Institute of Economic Structural Reform and the Rural Development Institute of the Rural Policy Research Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. At that time, they advocated legalizing reform measures, but they were all majoring in economics and did not know how to legislate or provide legal advice, so they needed some people who studied law, so I went there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two research institutes are think tanks for reform. The Institute of Structural Reform leads urban system reform, especially enterprise restructuring; the Institute of Agricultural Research studies rural issues, including township and village enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the Physical Reform Institute first and then to the Agricultural Research Institute. At the Agricultural Research Institute, I followed them to the Fuyang Township Enterprise Reform Experimental Zone in Anhui Province for investigation and did some empirical research. At that time, there was almost no legal issue in rural areas, and there were only some policies promoted by the annual No. 1 Central Document. After conducting research with people from the Agricultural Research Institute, I felt that I had found a direction and wanted to write about rural legal construction. In 1989, I co-wrote &quot;Promoting the System through the System - An Experimental Report on the Bankruptcy System of Township Enterprises in Fuyang, Anhui Province&quot; with Qiu Chengyi of the Agricultural Research Institute, which was published in &quot;Unfinalized&quot;, an internal journal of &quot;Chinese Social Sciences&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did your experience at the Agricultural Research Institute help you write your thesis? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The experience at the Agricultural Research Institute allowed me to understand and use empirical research methods instead of just deducing from theory. Scholars at the institute start from the facts, then make judgments and propose countermeasures and theories for reform. This inspired me a lot, because we used to introduce other people&#39;s theories, from theory to theory, PK was also PK between this theory and that theory. The impression given to me by the Agricultural Research Institute is that it is refreshing, and its examples are all real-life. We went there for about more than a month. We visited township enterprises and factories every day and held discussions with township cadres. This was completely different from my previous experience in college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I proposed in my paper at that time that human ethics, policies and laws should be mutually complementary and cooperative means of adjusting rural development. No one said this at that time. Everyone either only emphasized human ethics, or only emphasized policies or laws. I think these are biased, so I proposed the three-dimensional adjustment. &lt;p>; )&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;789&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu (back row, first from right) takes a photo with Chen Shouyi (front row, first from right), associate instructor Liu Shengping (front row, first from left) and classmates. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Propose a theory of practical legal philosophy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating with your Ph.D., will all your subsequent academic research be related to jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From the doctoral student stage in 1988 to before going abroad in 1993, I mainly focused on empirical research and also did some investigations, including my Several colleagues from the Central South University of Political Science and Law conducted research on farmers&#39; legal awareness in Hubei and published some articles, such as &quot;Realistic Changes in China&#39;s Farmers&#39; Legal Awareness&quot; published in &quot;Chinese Law&quot; in 1992. In terms of discipline, we call it legal sociology. It should be said that in China, I was one of the first scholars to do empirical research. Later I went abroad and did not do much research at that time. On the one hand, I did not have the conditions for empirical research. On the other hand, I had a teaching assignment at the University of Saarland in Germany. I also needed to understand German law and read their laws. Research is still in the accumulation stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China in 1997, I continued to teach sociology of law courses, but my research direction has shifted to legal methods, that is, how to apply legal methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 2000, in addition to paying attention to legal methods, I began to study legal philosophy. Jurisprudence and legal philosophy are the same concept, which is to answer the question &quot;What is law?&quot; It not only solves the problem of how to apply and interpret the law, but also forms a new law in the process. Later I summarized it as: law in a static sense is the 1.0 state of the law; after interpretation, the law you create yourself is the 2.0 state of the law. Later, this became my own set of legal philosophy theories. I called it practical legal philosophy because it was created in the process of legal practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The legal philosophy I mentioned today is different from traditional legal philosophy. Traditional legal philosophy is divorced from empirical research, but I proposed a new legal philosophy theory based on empirical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The theory of practical legal philosophy you proposed also partially compensated for the failure of Chinese scholars Are there any research gaps in this area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As we all know, modern legal science is the product of Western knowledge and came to China across the ocean. After more than a hundred years of &quot;apprenticeship&quot; career, Chinese legal scholars want to participate in the world&#39;s mainstream legal dialogue, and Practical Legal Philosophy is the result of such an attempt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a theoretical origin point of view, practical legal philosophy continues the tradition of practical philosophy, and also absorbs practical theory, as well as the famous German legal philosopher Kaufman’s idea of ​​​​&quot;actual reality&quot;. Theoretical resources such as the &quot;third way&quot; opened up between &quot;should be&quot; and &quot;should be&quot; strive to integrate the wisdom of several major schools of modern Western legal philosophy. This is a theory that can dialogue with the mainstream of the West rather than talk to itself. It wants to provide an answer to the age-old question &quot;What is law?&quot; and make a Chinese scholar&#39;s own contribution to the world of legal philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now let me explain, what do you think jurisprudence is? What kind of subject? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The core question of jurisprudence is to answer &quot;what is the law?&quot; This sounds simple to say, but is more complicated to actually study. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, doesn’t the National People’s Congress enact laws? What&#39;s so hard about this? But that&#39;s not the case. We call formulated and written laws statutory laws. In addition to statutory law, law also has other forms of expression. For example, we call the universal rules of society expressed in the form of concepts and thoughts natural law. Laws made by people do not necessarily contain these ideas, and statutory laws are not necessarily correct. For example, many laws in ancient China were autocratic and authoritarian laws; many laws enacted by Nazi Germany also contained many anti-human and unfair ideas. So natural law is needed to correct errors in statutory law, which is part of our answer to &quot;what is law?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also customary law, which is something that exists in real life and has been observed by us for generations. It also adjusts people&#39;s behavior, which also belongs to the scope of &quot;what is the law&quot;. So in terms of scope, statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all the content of our research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the most difficult part of studying jurisprudence is that statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all expressed in a static sense. When these concepts are related to facts, it will show Certain deficiencies and weaknesses. As Goethe said, &quot;Theory is gray, but the tree of life is evergreen.&quot; In other words, no matter what the rules are, they can never fully meet the needs of reality. In more professional terms, it is called &quot;there is an asymmetry between facts and norms.&quot; This requires us to constantly combine facts in the process of applying rules to propose our new theory about &quot;what the law is.&quot; This new theory will become binding law on specific cases, so the theory also needs to be constantly updated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We call the previous static law Law 1.0. After Law 1.0 is related to facts, it puts forward new understandings. We call it Law 2.0. Legislation and law amendment can also be regarded as this process, but the procedures for legislation and law amendment are slow and complicated. If a new type of case arises, we cannot wait for the law to be revised before deciding. Therefore, when the existing legal norms are not symmetrical to the facts, we need to judicially interpret the norms. On what basis do you base your explanation? You have to put forward your own theories and opinions in order to explain it reasonably. So at this time, jurisprudence plays a big role. In this sense, although jurisprudence sounds very theoretical, it is also highly practical, so jurisprudence is also a required course for law majors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zheng Yongliu during his study tour at the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/b12ad55cd6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;732&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b12ad55cd6 .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu while visiting the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The combination of &quot;accidental&quot; and &quot;inevitable&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Does the label &quot;the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; have a big impact on your future life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Judging from the time I got my degree, I am the first doctor of jurisprudence in the country. But when we entered school, there were actually two of us. The other one was my junior sister, and she delayed her graduation by one year. For many years after I graduated, I would not consciously mention it. It’s only in the last five or six years that some people started posting this on social media, and more people followed it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tag does not bring me much added value. Of course, my doctoral thesis is the starting point of my academic work. It can also be said that it established my academic confidence. Later, more people paid attention to me, not just because of this paper, but because I later published a series of research results in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, I publish the magazine of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR), which is also the top international publication in the field of legal philosophy, &quot;Transactions on Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy&quot; Three papers were published on Archives for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy, one of which was &quot;On the Practical Philosophy of Law&quot; published in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back at your study experience now, I feel that many important choices were An accidental result? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If it wasn’t because of illness, I wouldn’t have time to review, and maybe I wouldn’t be able to get into college; if I had successfully become a navy when I was a fisherman , I would not have been admitted to university; if I had studied history in university, I would not have become a doctor of jurisprudence. For example, when I graduated from college, I wanted to engage in practice. At that time, many of my classmates went to work in government agencies, but the school allowed me to stay in school. I originally liked international law, but was assigned to teach jurisprudence. Later, I went abroad, and my first choice was to go to the United States. The University of Wisconsin, a stronghold of legal sociology, accidentally ended up at Saarland University, which ranks among the top universities in legal philosophy in Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is true that there are too many accidents, and there are also inevitable consequences among too many accidents. It is impossible to say for sure. But going to college really opened a window for me to see a bigger world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you were asked to send a message to current college students, what would you do? explain? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes students come to ask me, and I say that I really can’t say anything good, so it’s better not to say it. I am also telling myself now not to educate students or ask them to do what they want. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I have to say something, this is not a message. I always emphasize that everyone, not just students, must have their own independent thoughts and not blindly follow fads and mainstream trends. Freedom of thought is the most worthy pursuit. I usually don&#39;t write these things for students, but sometimes when I say goodbye to students, they insist on asking me to write something. I once wrote this sentence: &quot;Tranquility leads to freedom, and freedom leads to scholarship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[悔婚拒退彩礼引发血案：当从悲剧中吸取教训丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Surveillance video circulated online shows that at 13:38 on November 11, two people were killed in a mahjong parlor in Liangshan, Sichuan. A woman playing mahjong was killed by two men with knives. According to media reports, insiders revealed that a knife-wielding man and a woman who was hacked were originally lovers and had paid a bride price of 300,000 yuan, but the woman regretted the marriage and was only willing to return 150,000 yuan. The two men are father and son, and the other woman is related to the woman who regretted her marriage. The next day, local police stated that the two assailants were controlled by the police on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tragedy sparked a lot of discussion. A mother said: &quot;Ever since my daughter entered the society, I have taught her that it is OK to fall in love, but you cannot use other people&#39;s money. You are not allowed to accept money or transfers from others!&quot; Some netizens said: &quot;You can go to the court to sue and demand She would not go to this step to return the gift.&quot; However, someone immediately appeared to give their own testimony or quoted the news to prove how difficult it is to return the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nature of betrothal gifts is different from the betrothal gifts in traditional society. There is a wedding ceremony of a scholar in &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Scholars were the lowest class nobles; there were six rites for marrying a wife, which were nacai, asking for name, naji, nazheng, asking for date and personally welcoming. Nazheng was the betrothal gift. This set of common people was imitated and integrated into traditional marriage customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gift is a &quot;new custom&quot; that has emerged in recent years. What is worrying is that betrothal gifts are becoming more and more popular. Not only are the prices getting higher and higher, but there is also a trend of generalization. Betrothal gifts were not available in some places, but now they are beginning to be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current legal definition of bride price is &quot;a gift for the purpose of marriage.&quot; The biggest problem caused by this characterization is that it has given rise to the stereotype that &quot;getting married is starting a business and getting divorced is getting rich&quot;. Some women disappear immediately after taking the bride price, or after receiving the marriage certificate, they refuse to live with the man, and then ask for a divorce in order to keep the high-priced bride price as their own. When more such incidents occur, social problems arise, and the judicial system has no choice but to add some patches to this characterization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People’s Court’s Interpretation on the Application of the Marriage and Family Section of the Civil Code of the People’s Republic of China (1) Article 5 stipulates: If a party requests the return of a betrothal gift paid in accordance with customs, if it is found that it falls under the following circumstances, the People’s Court It should be supported: (1) Both parties have not completed the marriage registration procedures; (2) Both parties have completed the marriage registration procedures but have not lived together; (3) Pre-marriage payments have caused difficulties in the payer&#39;s life.适用前款第二项、第三项的规定，应当以双方离婚为条件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在司法实践中，某些法院会根据结婚时间的长短来酌情确定彩礼退不退、退多少。道高一尺，魔高一丈。某些女方想出来一些套路：保持婚姻关系一年后提出离婚，这样法院判退还彩礼的概率就很小；在家里安装好摄像头，拒绝过夫妻生活，用各种方式激怒男方，引男方动手，拍下来就是家暴的证据，这样法院就会名正言顺支持女方各种诉求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久前，河南驻马店一男子发布视频，称妻子对其家暴及在室内纵火，事件发生在2023年6月16日凌晨两点多。视频显示：男子手机遭抢夺、被女子打巴掌都不还手；女子在屋内多处放火，沙发、餐桌与厨房垃圾桶都已见到火苗，男子跟在后面逐一将其浇灭。男子称，他为了结婚，已经花光了父母积蓄，一共花了包括10万彩礼在内的近20万元，如今结婚仅仅四个月，女方就要离婚，“让我滚蛋，一分钱彩礼都不退”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另据《法治日报》报道，近日，河南省高院审结一起离婚纠纷案。 2022年3月，男子小亚经介绍与女子小霜相识。同年5月，二人登记结婚；同年7月，小霜称怀孕，当月因胎儿异常进行流产手术。随后，小霜起诉离婚，小亚同意离婚，但反诉要求返还18.6万元彩礼。法院一审和二审，均判决双方离婚，但未支持返还彩礼的诉请。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小亚不服，申请再审。法院再审后发现：原审中，小亚就主张小霜是借婚姻之名索取财物，并称诉讼后发现小霜在结婚前已经与6名男子结婚，且均是婚后短期内怀孕打胎继而离婚，且均收取了昂贵彩礼。法院认为，彩礼是以结婚组建家庭并长期共同生活为目的而给付的，否则即违背给付彩礼方的真实意思，理应返还，但只判退了10万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果一次、两次结婚后短期怀孕打胎后离婚，那可能是真的；接连七次这样的套路，为真的可能性很小。该女子恐怕就是为了骗取彩礼，目的是建立共同生活的证据。但即便如此，第七次婚姻所收的18.6万彩礼还能保留8.6万，“利润率”实在太高了；加上前六次收的彩礼，恐怕轻松获利百万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这样的背景下，可以更深刻地解析凉山惨案何以发生。凉山是四川非常穷的一个地方，收了人家30万彩礼只退15万，对那家父子来说，就相当于拿走他们两人的一辈子。而且，真要去法院起诉，法院未必判全退；就算判全退，女方未必会履行：目前因彩礼纠纷而成为失信被执行人的已经超过万人。而悲剧发生后，两名行凶者也将为自己的行为付出惨重代价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彩礼是一个有内在矛盾的东西：出得起彩礼的人，结婚往往不需要出彩礼；反而是出不起彩礼或出得很艰难的人家，结婚才需要出彩礼，而且是高价彩礼，为了出得起彩礼，这样的家庭往往要省吃俭用、东挪西借甚至借高利贷。如果后者碰上了为了骗取彩礼的“离婚致富”套路，很难接受，可能会诉诸极端手段，造成无法挽回的后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在面对彩礼纠纷时，应采取合理合法的途径解决，依法维护自己的权益。但在深思前述悲剧的同时，也有必要反思对彩礼的法律定性，司法不能助长“离婚致富”套路。当只有钱归钱、财产归财产，婚姻才能归婚姻，婚姻若是成为财富再分配的工具，就会激发与助长人性之恶，既会伤害婚姻，也会伤害财产，还会引发各种本不会发生的悲剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山西永聚煤业发生火灾，已致11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:25:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山西省吕梁市离石区永聚煤业联建楼今天（16日）早晨6时50分左右发生火灾，截至记者发稿时，已确认11人遇难，具体伤亡人员仍在统计中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经现场了解情况，着火建筑共4层，目前累计疏散63人，其中51人送往吕梁市第一人民医院救治，救援仍在进行，起火原因正在调查中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑猩猩没有“祖母假说”模式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;谈论人类的近亲黑猩猩，就不能不提英国生物学家、动物行为学家和著名动物保育人士珍·古道尔，她是研究黑猩猩的祖母级人物，但是本文的“祖母假说”并非是以古道尔为主角。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;BBC拍摄的纪录电影《珍·古道尔的传奇一生》和古道尔的著作《希望之书：珍·古道尔谈人类的生存、未来与行动》，让人更深入地了解黑猩猩，并知道了黑猩猩是如何像人一样生活的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古道尔在长达38年的与黑猩猩的共同生活中发现，黑猩猩会使用工具（将植物茎秆伸进蚁穴探测、用树棍伸入水中捞取食物），也会制造工具（从植物茎秆上除去树叶），打破了长期以来只有人类才会制造工具的认知。同时，黑猩猩也会组成团队猎食其他小型哺乳动物，不同群体的黑猩猩之间还会发生战争，并在战斗中会使用武器。还有一些黑猩猩有袭击和残杀同类的行为，其动机有时仅仅是为了取乐。黑猩猩社会也有等级森严的制度，每只黑猩猩都有自己在社会中的地位，它们为争取社会地位而进行的明争暗斗丝毫不亚于人类。这些发现也打破了之前以为战争和同类相残只是人类独有的行为的认知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，除了古道尔外，也有其他研究人员研究黑猩猩，并且发现黑猩猩也有类似人类的“祖母假说”模式，但是黑猩猩的这一模式要弱得多。 “祖母假说”是指，健康存活的祖母祖父（外祖母外祖父）可以帮助照顾孙辈，提高孙子孙女的存活率，从而帮助自己的子女拥有更多的孩子。反过来，这种健康效应也会确保祖母长寿基因的传承。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国加州大学圣塔芭芭拉分校的研究人员通过对黑猩猩、狩猎采集者和园艺生产者3个群体的比较发现，人在老年时的生产贡献同样存在，而且远远高于黑猩猩。黑猩猩在30岁时的采集和生产能力可以有20%的食物或物质盈余，在40岁时有7%，而在50岁时只有2%。但是狩猎采集者在30岁时的生产盈余有66%，40岁时有45%，50岁仍有24%。园艺生产者在30岁时的生产盈余为64%，40岁时为40%，50岁时为21%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这个比较可以知道，黑猩猩在步入老年后，生产能力明显下降，其帮助家庭和孙子辈的能力也断崖式下跌，所以即便黑猩猩有“祖母假说”模式，作用也不大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，一项新的研究则完全否定了黑猩猩的“祖母假说”模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国亚利桑那州立大学、加州大学洛杉矶分校和德国马克斯-普朗克进化人类学研究所等研究机构组成的团队对乌干达西部基巴莱国家公园（Kibale National Park）的恩戈戈（Ngogo）野生黑猩猩群落进行了长达20年的研究，发现该群落中的雌性黑猩猩会经历更年期和生育后生存，但是它们进入老年后不会帮助它们的女儿带孙子，也不会住在附近。因此，黑猩猩是没有祖父母支持的社会体系，也即不存在“祖母假说”模式。但是恩戈戈的雌性黑猩猩仍然能活过生育年龄，以及之后的更长时间，甚至可以独自养老。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在人类圈养的黑猩猩中并不存在老年后的生存问题，因为人类会对它们提供良好的食物、营养和医疗照顾，但是，野外黑猩猩就不会有这么幸运，它们的生存模式比较艰难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了研究野外的黑猩猩的生活方式和老年后的生存模式，该联合研究团队的研究人员从&amp;nbsp;1995 年至2016 年收集的群体统计数据中研究了185只雌性黑猩猩的死亡率和生育率，计算了这些被观察的雌性黑猩猩成年后处于绝育状态的时间比例，并测量了66只雌性黑猩猩尿样中的激素水平。这些雌性黑猩猩的生育和绝育状态、生存和年龄各不相同，从14岁到67岁不等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个研究过程非常艰辛，时间持续了几十年，并且在恩戈戈进行了数千小时的实地考察，才收集到黑猩猩的尿液样本，用来研究更年期的激素水平。对黑猩猩的尿液中的相关激素研究与对人的研究是相似的，主要监测卵泡刺激素（FSH）和黄体生成素（LH），以及卵巢类固醇激素（包括雌激素和孕激素）水平的变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这些激素变化才能确认黑猩猩是否进入更年期。人类绝经期女性的雌性激素水平在100pmol/L以下，孕激素在2.2nmol/L以下，对比雌性黑猩猩就可以知道其是否绝经和进入更年期（绝育状态）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员发现，与其他黑猩猩群体和人类一样，他们所研究的黑猩猩在30岁以后生育能力下降，50岁后就不能生育了。同时，收集的黑猩猩的一些激素水平数据显示，恩戈戈雌性黑猩猩的更年期与人类相似，大约从50 岁开始。而雌性黑猩猩是从14岁成年，在成年生活中约有五分之一的时间处于绝育期，约为人类绝育期的一半，即黑猩猩进入更年期后的老年期只有人类的一半。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黑猩猩进入更年期就意味着老年的开始，但是，恩戈戈雌性黑猩猩即便不照顾孙子，而且不与子女住在一起，也能活过50岁。黑猩猩很容易死于源自人类的疾病，对这些疾病几乎没有天然免疫力，因此能活过50岁，就是长寿了；至于活到67岁，则算高寿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为何恩戈戈的黑猩猩没有“祖母假说”模式也能在老年后生存呢？研究给出的答案是，它们在绝育后的寿命可能是对极其有利的生态条件的暂时反应，因为这个群体享有稳定和丰富的食物供应，而且它们与人类引发的压力隔离开来，所以它们的存活时间更长一些。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，也有研究人员如美国杜克大学的灵长类动物学家苏珊·阿尔伯茨（Susan Alberts）怀疑这个结果，因为并非所有黑猩猩都会经历更年期。阿尔伯茨认为，在恩戈戈群体以外的大多数黑猩猩种群中，成年雌性黑猩猩能活到30岁左右，原因在于它们受到捕食者、疾病或其他因素的压力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过阿尔伯茨也承认，这项研究的结果是如此坚实，以至于她无法反驳。但她认为，下一步应对更多的野生黑猩猩种群进行类似的长期研究，以确定恩戈戈黑猩猩在繁殖年龄之后是否具有独特性，即更长的生存期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[螺蛳粉疯狂布局线下门店，能否成为下一个兰州拉面？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;今年以来，螺蛳粉餐饮门店增长速度迅猛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;家住广州的网友小吕表示，她家附近的商圈最近开了好几家螺蛳粉门店，不少是某个螺蛳粉品牌的连锁店——这引起不少网友的好奇：螺蛳粉也开始主攻线下门店了？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;凭借“闻着臭、吃着香、很上头”等特点，螺蛳粉在短短几年时间里成为火爆的网红食品，网络渠道的销量居高不下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;只不过，相较于线上的火爆，螺蛳粉在线下的发展就有明显的短板。螺蛳粉线上线下发展呈现出怎样的分野？螺蛳粉如何实现线下的突围？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;线上销量的火爆&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;螺蛳粉起源于上个世纪70年代的柳州夜市。 1980年代逐渐流行，但主要局限于当地，之后慢慢扩散到广西全域以及隔壁的广东省。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2012年，《舌尖上的中国》让螺蛳粉更多进入大众的视野，只不过对于两广地区以外的人而言，仍是只闻其名，因为螺蛳粉的线下门店并未向其他省份过多拓展，也没什么线上销售渠道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2014年，柳州第一家预包装螺蛳粉企业注册，工业化生产的袋装螺蛳粉出现。 2015年初，柳州市政府提出了将柳州螺蛳粉“产业化、标准化、品牌化、规模化”发展理念，确定了柳州螺蛳粉产业做袋装走工业化生产的道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016年是直播元年，螺蛳粉敏锐地抓住了时代趋势，搭上“互联网+”短视频、直播的快车，其“又香又臭”的特点颇具传播性，经由线上渠道迅速出圈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2019年，柳州袋装螺蛳粉的行业产值突破60亿元。疫情的冲击，“宅经济”的兴起，直播带货的如火如荼，助推了螺蛳粉线上热度的爆棚，2020年袋装螺蛳粉全年产值突破百亿。 2022年柳州螺蛳粉全产业链销售收入为600.7亿元，袋装螺蛳粉181.8亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自然地，线上出圈的螺蛳粉，线上销量占据半壁江山。艾媒咨询调研数据显示，中国螺蛳粉消费者购买产品的渠道分布中，网上商城以78.70%的比例居于首位。另有数据显示，2022年，通过快递渠道寄出的螺蛳粉包裹达1.13亿件，成为广西首个年寄递量破亿的单品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;螺蛳粉线上的火爆，除了它与“互联网+”的紧密结合以外，还在于它契合了这一代年轻人“速食生活”的特点，对食物的要求既要便捷、高效，还要料足、美味。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其他速食面食没什么配料，螺蛳粉的配料丰富，有腐竹、酸笋、酸豆角、木耳、花生米、萝卜干等常见辅料，一包螺蛳粉啥都有，更能抓住年轻人的胃。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;线下门店有短板&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，跟线上的火爆相比，螺蛳粉线下门店就有明显短板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一方面，如今螺蛳粉的线下门店约有4万多家，这跟兰州拉面大概有50万家的线下门店相比，就是小巫见大巫了。更不必说，兰州拉面年销售额粗略估计超过4000亿元，是螺蛳粉的好几倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一方面，相关数据显示，螺蛳粉线下餐饮连锁率平均水平仅为15%，相较之下，茶饮为45%，咖啡为55%，说明螺蛳粉还没有足够强劲的品牌跑出线下，“有品类无品牌”的风险加剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不仅如此，就现存的螺蛳粉线下门店而言，也存在一些令人忧虑的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其一，螺蛳粉的线下门店主要集中在广西、广东，全国渗透率还比较低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;比如艾媒咨询数据显示，从2020年到2023年2月，螺蛳粉新增企业多分布在两广，广西螺蛳粉企业占比高达21.63%，21.21%的螺蛳粉企业位于广东省。这跟兰州拉面、沙县小吃的全国辐射力度相比薄弱得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其二，由于连锁率低，很多螺蛳粉线下门店是“夫妻店”式的小作坊，口味、品质参差不齐，个别店面卫生状况堪忧，拉低了消费者对于螺蛳粉线下门店的信任度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;前段时间，“重庆一家螺蛳粉店后厨多只老鼠上蹿下跳”的谣言就广为传播。尽管重庆九龙坡区市监局做了通报，表示执法人员现场检查，并未发现该螺蛳粉店铺有老鼠痕迹；该视频拍摄于今年3月，因隔壁商铺装修损坏该店铺烟道出口导致老鼠进入后厨，当时该店负责人发现情况后，立即对店内进行了消杀及修复整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这样的谣言对螺蛳粉线下门店的伤害很大，也从侧面反映出公众对食安问题的忧虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其三，螺蛳粉线下门店的美食种类单一，仅依赖螺蛳粉将限制线下门店发展。比如兰州拉面店里不只有拉面，还有盖浇饭、肉夹馍、凉皮等西北风味的面食产品；沙县小吃，更是有拌面、蒸饺、扁食、鸭腿饭等多种选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;螺蛳粉的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;突出重围&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;固然相较于兰州拉面、沙县小吃线下门店的遍地开花，螺蛳粉线下门店还有广阔的拓展空间，但这并不意味着螺蛳粉就应该“妄自菲薄”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;事实上，跟兰州拉面相比，螺蛳粉的“产业化、标准化、品牌化、规模化”发展路线走得更早更成熟，兰州拉面面馆很多，却也面临着“有品类无品牌”的尴尬，这是兰州拉面如今正大力补齐的短板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;螺蛳粉线下门店要成功突围，一则，要充分发挥“产业化、标准化、品牌化、规模化”的优势，将目前几个螺蛳粉品牌继续做大做强，加快连锁布局，既要打出品类，也要打响品牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;二则，应该在供应链的产业化上发力，打造专业的、平台化的供应链服务商，填补螺蛳粉供应链业务的空白，让那些哪怕是小作坊式的螺蛳粉门店，也能够获得质量稳定的螺蛳粉原材料，让消费者可以品尝到口味稳定的螺蛳粉，稳住螺蛳粉线下门店的口碑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;三则，作为一种地域美食，螺蛳粉如果要征服全国人民的胃，除了做出道地的螺蛳粉以外，还需要丰富线下门店的美食品类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有一种路径是，主打螺蛳粉的同时，也售卖柳州乃至于广西的其他地方美食，丰富消费者的选择空间，比如柳州的一些地方美食，酿豆腐泡、牛鲜子、云片糕、苗族酸肉等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;还有一种路径是与当地的美食相结合，走向融合，推出跨品类的饭食、小炒、汤类等。这样的融合对于连锁品牌的管理提出了非常大的挑战，既要确保标准化，还要成功地“入乡随俗”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;虽然螺蛳粉已经充分地打开了线上空间，但螺蛳粉要不断突破产业的上限，就必须线上线下两条腿走路。螺蛳粉线下门店正在加速布局，能否像线上一样创造奇迹，值得观望。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么年轻人不愿意生孩子？社会学家山田昌弘谈日本低生育困境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260643]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6Ignwi5oPp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1559&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6Ignwi5oPp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;日本社会学家山田昌弘，中央大学教授，专攻家庭社会学和情感社会学等，著有《少子社会》《“婚活”时代》《低生育陷阱》等。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本中央大学教授山田昌弘长年深耕家庭社会学领域。高中之前，他一度想做数学家，但“因为我自己没有家庭，所以我决定探索什么是亲情”，自此步入“研究凌乱家庭的世界”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在学校教书时，他利用大量关于家庭的素材，讲述现代日本家庭的起源、现状和去向。他和学生一起召开的研讨会，话题前沿，探讨的问题包括：人孤独到何种地步需要“出租朋友”？ “同居伴侣婚姻”（注：只同居不结婚）是否探究了现行婚姻制度之外的另一种可能性？日本单身的年轻人越来越多，他们的亲密情感需求在何处得到满足？他最终在歌舞俱乐部（注：提供歌唱和跳舞表演的场所）、真人或虚拟偶像、宠物身上找到一些答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《低生育陷阱》一书里，山田昌弘试图解答一个问题：近些年，日本年轻人为何不愿意生孩子了？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一直以来，低生育率是盘桓于日本社会之上的一朵阴云。自1989年起，日本的生育率持续低迷，总和生育率低于1.6的情形维持了三十余年，2022年更是达到了1.26的历史低值。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;自1989年起，日本的生育率持续低迷，总和生育率低于1.6的情形维持了三十余年，2022年更是达到了1.26的历史低值。图为日剧《产科医鸿鸟》剧照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去三十多年，日本社会力图解决这一“顽疾”，但收效甚微。山田昌弘曾任少子化对策委员。有一次，一位委员提议要举办一场“育儿很精彩”的宣传活动，提升大众的生育积极性。 “日本社会的很多有识之士和政策负责人在很长时间内都忽视了与日本少子化原因直接相关的两个重要因素，即&#39;不婚化&#39;和&#39;年轻人经济水平差距的扩大&#39;。”山田认为，“对于&#39;想生但因条件尚不具备，所以不生孩子&#39;的多数人来说，开展这类宣传活动毫无意义。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在山田昌弘看来，年轻人的生育意愿和社会整体的经济状况挂钩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1955年，日本经济进入高速成长期，繁荣的经济环境催生出年轻人对未来的积极预期，他们倾向于相信，通过个人努力能够跻身“中流阶层”，过上比父辈更好、更富裕的生活。 “自第二次世界大战至1980年左右，人们没想过结婚后的经济生活会出现很大的风险，那时候的男性可以指望成为正式员工后，收入根据&#39;年功序列制度&#39;（注：工资随年龄和工龄的增长而增加）得到提高。”在山田昌弘看来，那一代人笃信孩子会在优于自己的成长环境下长大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而到了1980年代，情势发生了翻转。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“进入平成时代（注：1989年1月8日），日本经济结构调整，出现了大量的非正式雇佣人员（指有固定期限员工、兼职员工、派遣员工等），在就业方面产生了社会性差距，进而导致家庭贫富、子女教育环境产生差距，社会的两极分化进一步发展。”山田昌弘接受日本媒体采访时说，“对于大多数非正式雇佣人员而言，无论自身怎么努力，都无法获得能让自己将来过上富裕生活的收入，也没法结婚组建家庭。也就是说，自己的将来变得没有指望了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山田观察到，日本人更注重从经济角度看待婚姻的意义，作出结婚决定前，会作出慎重的风险评估。评估常从两个角度出发：一是相比婚前，婚后的生活水平会不会更好，或者至少不会更差；二是婚后能否为子女创造比自己更好的成长环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这种婚育观背后体现的是现代日本社会特有的价值观：希望回避未来生活所面临的风险。日本人将维持中产生活水平作为最高目标，认为在人生设计上，&#39;男女交往&#39;&#39;结婚&#39;&#39;生子&#39;&#39;育儿&#39;和&#39;子女教育&#39;这一连串问题不是单一、割裂的，而是环环相扣的。”山田昌弘在《少子化问题的东亚特征》这篇论文中写道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种风险意识也延伸至恋爱阶段。山田发现，在日本，不少年轻人甚至连恋爱的欲望都在减退。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NHK放送文化研究所曾经对日本的初高中生做过调查，发现“有喜欢对象的”初、高中生的比例，在1982年分别是41%和54%，而到了2012年，这个数据锐减到了25%和31%。 2014年，日本内阁府曾对年轻人做过调查，发现超过三分之一的调查对象更愿意把时间花在工作和学习上，46.2%的人觉得“恋爱很麻烦”。在山田昌弘看来，“麻烦”的意思或许是“性价比不高”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1990年代，少子化现象刚刚在日本社会出现时，人口学家们持有一种主流观点：年轻人只是为了享受单身生活而推迟结婚，总有一天他们会步入婚姻。山田昌弘认为，这样的逻辑基础未必成立。几十年来，随着日本社会逐步朝“高消费型社会”发展，育儿的焦虑和压力也向年轻人袭来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年12月，在日本东京街头，一对新人在挂满圣诞彩灯的街道上拍摄婚纱照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年，日本国立社会保障及人口问题研究所曾做过一次调查，关于30-34岁年龄段的已婚女性为何没能拥有预期数量的孩子，81.1%的调查对象认为原因在于“孩子的养育及教育太花钱了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在山田看来，现代社会对婚育功能的预期已和前现代社会不同。在以农业生产为中心的社会，生育意味着劳动力的添补，父辈在子女身上寄托着继承家业、晚来照拂父母的期待，孩子是一种“生产性财产”。但是到了1950年代后，日本参考欧美的家庭制度，开始“核心家庭化”，一对夫妻和他们的未婚子女成为基本的家庭单元。在现代社会，养育孩子需要投入大量的育儿金，孩子因此成了“消费性财产”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“孩子作为劳动力的意义不复存在，而且当核心家庭成为一种原则时，很难期待孩子在自己晚年时给予赡养和照顾。另外，可让孩子继承家业的父母也变少了。”山田昌弘在《低生育陷阱》中写道，不同于欧美父母享受育儿本身的愉悦和乐趣，很多时候，东亚父母在意的是是否拥有一个“高价值感”的孩子——在学历、工作等外在因素搭建起来的社会评价体系里，孩子能否占据鳌头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山田认为，东亚父母对孩子常有“呵护之情”，不想让孩子“过得辛苦”，孩子在接受高等教育乃至成年后，得到父母的帮助，也是父母价值的一部分。因而，东亚父母对孩子的责任年龄无限延长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月，日本社会学家山田昌弘接受了南方周末记者的书面专访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;东亚父母认为给孩子花钱理所当然&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;中国的总和生育率在2022年跌至1.09，这个数值低于日本的1.26，高于韩国的0.78，2022年东亚三国的总和生育率下降至历史最低值。你在日本做了很多关于生育意愿的调研，为什么年轻人不愿意生孩子了？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在东亚（中日韩），结婚和育儿首先会从经济角度进行考虑。人们在养育孩子时，会想把超出自己父母培养自己的钱花在自己的孩子身上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前（日本是50年前，中韩是30年前），大多数年轻人的父母的生活，以及年轻人自己的成长生活都处于相对贫穷的水平。又由于社会整体处于经济增长期，年轻人未来收入的增加是可以预期的。所以，在那个时候，把超出自己父母培养自己的钱花在自己的孩子身上会更容易，实际上也确实很容易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，日本从30年前开始，中韩从10年前开始，上一世代被父母花了更多金钱养育的孩子，如今成了需要花钱养育自己孩子的人。这些年轻人，往往拥有比自己更富裕的父母。中国则由于独生子女多，这一代独生子女的花费估计会是日韩的两倍以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在经济增长趋缓的情况下，想要在未来出生的孩子身上花费更多的钱，是非常困难的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;东亚社会家庭现代化的过程，是模仿学习欧美核心家庭的过程，同样的社会模型，为何东亚国家现阶段面对的生育困境比欧美社会更加剧烈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;东亚国家模仿的只是核心家庭的模式，但因为不同的社会环境和传统，这些模式得到的反馈自然也不同。例如，东亚的父母更多地认为给孩子花钱是理所当然的，也能带来很多情绪价值；比起夫妻之爱，更相信亲子之爱。这也导致如果不打算生孩子的话，结婚的必要性就大幅下降了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧美认为养育孩子到成年为止，而东亚各国则认为负担孩子的高等教育费用是理所当然的。相比之下，东亚国家的父母要承担更多的育儿责任，甚至在孩子成年后，也经常需要帮助解决孩子遇到的各种问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;过去几年，中国政府出台了一些鼓励生育的政策，比如三孩政策、多地提出建立育儿补贴制度等。你在《低生育陷阱》里说，日本政府没能赶上干预低生育的最好时机，日本的少子化政策因此失败了。日本经验能给其他国家带来哪些教训和启示？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;必须考虑减轻孩子的教育费负担。有四分之一的年轻人对未来感到不安，是日本少子化的主要原因。要采取让年轻人不会对未来过不上富裕生活而感到不安的措施。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要将我们的社会改造成一个无论哪个年轻人都有希望将来能够不让自己的孩子受苦的社会。即，建立一个工作可以重新再来、对双职工家庭同样友好，以及万一出了问题也可以通过社会保障重新自立的社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;能否结合你自己和你的上一代、下一代的经历，谈谈日本年轻人婚育处境和观念的变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;观念本身并没有太大的变化。如果有过上相对好的生活的预期，那就自然会结婚生子。区别可能在于，上一代的人会认为，仅靠丈夫的收入就能过上富裕的生活（大概30年前）。即便在今天，那些能够达到预期的将近四分之三的年轻人也都已经结婚生子，而剩下四分之一的年轻人之所以不选择结婚生子，大多也是因为自身收入不稳定，以及无法预期在结婚生子后能过上相对好的生活。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;婚育事关体面？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提出了一个观点：等待适合自己的对象出现然后结婚，这种从前被普遍接受的想法，如今很难把人领入婚姻。今天的年轻人如果想结婚，需要参加“婚活”（注：寻求结婚对象的各种活动，由山田昌弘首次提出），为何会有这样的变化？难道不参加婚活，就无法结婚了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为让年轻人可以自然相互邂逅的场所变少了。不说男性，就连女性所谓的“即便自己不主动，男性也会主动搭讪”的状况都变少了。不得不由社区或者企业提供一些机会，让年轻男女可以有更多的接触。如果想要找到结婚对象，还是应该积极采取行动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“婚活”在中国叫做相亲。对于中国1970、1980年代出生的人来说，自由恋爱结婚在他们年轻时是普遍的婚恋观，但在如今的年轻人中，门当户对的观念正在被重提。日本社会是否有类似的婚姻观念变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在日本，“先恋爱后结婚”的意识并没有改变。年轻人对恋爱结婚的憧憬和讨厌父母干涉自由恋爱的意识还是比较强烈的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然没有那么在意对象的家庭背景，但婚后的经济生活，即婚后夫妻两人的整体家庭收入是很重要的参考因素。现在的年轻人“中流”意识十分强烈，他们大多觉得在父母身边时处于一种中流的生活状态，因而非常不希望婚后生活会从中流跌落，这也是习惯“规避风险”和“重视体面”的日本社会特征的反映。不过日本没有像中国那样，结婚时男方家庭需要出很多钱的习俗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你似乎非常强调在经济层面上分析婚姻、生育的动机。你提到，在欧美社会，人们将构建家庭（结婚、生子）与经济状况联系在一起的想法并不强烈，但在东亚社会不是，为何东亚社会如此强调这两者之间的关联性？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;东亚人更看重体面，也就是中文里的“面子”。人们不想让别人看到自己过着不幸福的婚姻生活，或有着较差的育儿水平。过着贫穷的生活会有很强的耻辱意识。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧美，夫妻之间的爱情才是幸福的表现，生活贫穷也可以幸福的意识很普及；而在东亚社会里，即使没有夫妻间的爱情，过着富裕的生活也可能是很幸福的，这种意识十分强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有一种观点认为，现代家庭“男主外，女主内”的分工意味着女性要为育儿付出更多的时间和精力，你怎样看待这个现实问题？日本社会对此有何对策？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;女性拥有一定的收入并持续工作，正在逐渐成为富裕家庭生活的前提。既然能够做到“男主外，女主内”的高收入男性人数有限，那么为了在富裕的生活条件下养育孩子，女性外出工作和男性参与家务就变得十分必要了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，通过普及产假和完善幼儿园的建设，这一理想正逐渐变得现实起来。不过日本政府对女性工作与育儿的“两立支援”也显然还远远不够，后续仍需要继续完善工作环境，消除性别歧视，并让更多的女性从事有意义的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;培养“高价值”的孩子，一种扭曲的期待&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，日本年轻人抱有一种“不能让孩子受苦”的想法，这种想法在中国年轻人当中也存在，为什么年轻人会对哺育下一代产生如此强烈的责任意识？ “受苦”的意涵是否随着时代的发展也在发生变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在东亚社会里，让子女接受比自己更好的教育，找到比自己更好的工作，是父母的生活意义所在。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，孩子之间的歧视意识也很强，现如今的年轻人会担心自己的贫穷会让孩子受到欺负。孩子们在一起玩耍的时候，有时也会需求类似Switch游戏机这样的外部硬件。如果不买这些东西，会不会让孩子感到痛苦？年轻父母的这种想法正越来越强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前只要父母能够陪在孩子身边就足够了，但现在越来越多的父母觉得，不能在孩子身上花费足够的金钱会很难受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在中国，未婚适龄男女可能会遭到父母和长辈的催婚，被称为光棍、剩女，带有一定贬义。日本有类似情况吗？你如何理解这种现象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;单身=不受欢迎，这一等式会让人间接联想到，没进入婚姻是不是因为男性收入低，或者是不是因为女性的容貌有问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，因为未婚率高得非常明显，想结婚却做不到的人，和能做到但不想结婚的人都混杂在一起，因而单纯对于未婚者的贬低并不常见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样由于未婚率非常高，来自父母的压力已经要比以前小很多了。很多父母会认为，与其让孩子和收入低的人结婚，然后过上不太理想的贫困生活，还不如独身在家。在日本，越来越多的父母认为，与其被奇怪的结婚对象缠住，还不如让孩子保持单身。继承家业的意识在日本正逐渐淡薄（现在70岁以上的人仍然有很强烈的这种意识）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，在前现代社会，子女是一种“生产性财产”，进入现代社会则变为“消费性财产”，需要投入较高的育儿金，拥有一个“高价值感”的孩子成为育儿行为追求的价值，而高价值感由孩子的学历、工作的光鲜程度等因素决定。为什么父母对育儿会有这样的期待？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;孩子的地位=父母的地位，东亚文化圈的这种关乎面子或虚荣心的意识很强烈。从感情上看，这源于父母希望子女在经济上能过着无忧无虑的生活。虽然初心是好的，但随着体面意识带来的比较心理，培养高价值的孩子也就成了一种扭曲的期待。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧美的传统则有很大的不同，孩子成年后不再在经济上依赖父母，有着较强的自我责任意识。对于父母来说，孩子在养育过程中很可爱，长大后则只期待情绪交流的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看上去，育儿正在逐渐演化成一种竞争。日本有没有“学区房”“鸡娃”现象？高度竞争的社会是否会对生育率产生影响？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;日本的就业市场对学历的要求则相对比较宽松，高中毕业和大学毕业的工资差距在世界上也算小的。也就是说，即使是高中毕业或专科毕业，也有可能过上相对好的生活。父母也没必要那么热心，尤其是那些自己本身也只是高中毕业的父母。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;年轻人规避风险的倾向在不断加强&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;年轻人结婚意愿消退的一个可能的原因是，越来越多人意识到婚姻是一种契约关系，而契约有破裂风险。为何越来越多年轻人倾向于对结婚这件事做风险评估？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对年轻人来说，将来能否过上中流生活是他们非常关心的事情。在日本，1990年以前，大多数年轻人都可以期待依靠“年功序列制度”过上工资每年都增长的生活，但随着全球化的发展，经济风险越来越大，如今的年轻人已经不能再乐观地认为“将来总会有办法的”。出于这个原因，年轻人规避风险的倾向在不断加强。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果从一开始就过着相对贫穷的生活，那么一般都不会觉得有什么风险存在，但现在的很多年轻人在未成年时期过着相当充实且富裕的生活。不想放弃这种生活的意识会很强烈。特别是作为独生子女的这一代中国年轻人，这种意识应该会更加强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到一个现象：如今的年轻人甚至连恋爱的欲望都在消退。韩国有“三弃”（放弃爱情、婚姻、生育），日本有“草食男”（恋爱被动、不积极），中国也有一些年轻人觉得恋爱是件麻烦事，为何年轻人会丧失恋爱的欲望？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为现代的年轻人觉得，恋爱感情总是会“降温”的。在欧美，“与相爱的人在一起”就是人生的意义。但是，在东亚各国，这种想法并不普及。在不少人看来，谈恋爱其实就是寻找结婚对象的一种过程，因此他们也认为，和明知道不能结婚的人交往，是在浪费时间和金钱。越来越多的人认为，恋爱本身就是一种需要顾虑别人的不快乐的事。因为色情行业的扩大，尤其在日本，谈恋爱的性价值也降低了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;许多人通过虚拟关系满足恋爱需求，比如时下流行的AI男女友，或是“嗑CP”，在围观他人恋爱的过程中获得情感满足。你怎么理解这些现象？也有人质疑，通过数据计算、金钱付出而获得情感满足，削弱了爱情的复杂性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;虽然我认为这是逃避的一种形式，但对现在的年轻人来说，有越来越多的人认为这是比现实恋爱还要愉快的交流时间。如果现实恋爱的满足度下降了，那虚拟恋爱的价值就会上升。也许现在已经不能说现实中的满足就更优越了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1997年你就命名了日本社会的“单身寄生族”现象，近年，中国社会也出现了“全职儿女”，即儿女们放弃工作，回家承担家务、给父母养老，生活开支由父母负担，部分全职儿女还会得到父母开的工资。你似乎有意强调“单身寄生族”和婚育意愿的关联，能否再展开谈谈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在遇到自己理想的结婚对象之前，在父母身边过着富裕的生活，这种“等待”很可能是没有尽头的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧美，因为成年后必须脱离父母自立，所以两个年轻人凑一起过日子会比较有利。但是在东亚国家，脱离父母独立，一般意味着孩子能在外面过上比待在父母家里更好的生活。在遇到能一起过上更好生活的结婚对象之前，先在父母家里“等待”也没什么关系，甚至父母也如此期待着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，一直等不到理想的人出现，而就这样慢慢老去的“前”年轻人层出不穷，在日本，人到中年也依然与父母同居的未婚者正在不断增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;人们通常认为，年轻人拥有无限可能，正是积极试错的年龄段。但你却提出“社会为什么对年轻人冷酷无情”的疑问，为什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果能像欧美那样，大多数孩子在成年后就离开父母自立，那么即使在社会中冒险失败，重新来过也确实不是什么难事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，在东亚各国，年轻人会拿自己和父母做比较，越来越多的年轻人认为达不到父母的水平就是失败。在父母的关照下过着富裕生活的人更是如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，在日本，很多年轻人认为就业和结婚是不能重新来过的，这也是很重要的影响因素之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困生攒钱看演唱会惹争议，该不该限制助学对象高消费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[习近平同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260688]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:43:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765296853&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;独家视频丨习近平同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间11月15日，国家主席习近平在美国旧金山斐洛里庄园同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，我和总统先生上次会面是在巴厘岛，已经过去1年了。 1年来发生了不少事情。世界走出了新冠疫情大流行，但疫情带来的巨大影响还在。世界经济开始复苏，但动力不足，产业链供应链受到干扰，保护主义抬头，这些问题十分突出。作为世界上最重要的双边关系，中美关系要放在世界百年变局加速演进这个大背景下来思考和谋划，为两国人民带来福祉，为人类进步展现担当。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，50多年来，中美关系从来不是一帆风顺的，总会有这样那样的问题，总是在曲折中向前发展。这么两个大国，不打交道是不行的，想改变对方是不切实际的，冲突对抗的后果是谁都不能承受的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我还是那个看法，大国竞争不是这个时代的底色，解决不了中美两国和世界面临的问题。这个地球容得下中美两国，我们各自的成功是彼此的机遇。中美两国历史文化、社会制度、发展道路不同，这是客观现实。但是，只要双方坚持相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢，完全可以超越分歧，找到两个大国正确相处之道。我坚信，中美关系的前途是光明的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和总统先生是中美关系的掌舵者，对人民、对世界、对历史都担负着沉甸甸的责任。我期待今天同总统先生就事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，事关世界和平和发展的重大问题深入交换意见，达成新的共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被摘牌的55个中华老字号：停产、换新店、准备重申]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年商务部复核1128个老字号。图为10月29日市民在苏州老字号金秋消费嘉年华活动上。图文无关。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年商务部复核1128个老字号。图为10月29日市民在苏州老字号金秋消费嘉年华活动上。图文无关。视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被摘掉中华老字号的“帽子”后，传承人吴志勇向十来位老顾客解释：因为错过提交资料的时间，被依规移出，但吴家熏肉（品牌名宝兴善）的工厂正常生产，门店也正常营业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月9日，商务部在例行发布会上披露中华老字号复核结果，将长期经营不善，甚至已经破产、注销、倒闭或者丧失老字号注册商标所有权、使用权的55个品牌，移出中华老字号名录；对经营不佳、业绩下滑的73个品牌，要求6个月内予以整改；继续保留1000个经营规范、发展良好的品牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴家熏肉就是55个品牌之一。中华老字号最早由原国内贸易部评选，1991年评定1600余家。 2006年商务部进行了重新认定，第一批中华老字号有429家；2010年，商务部认定第二批699家。截至2023年初，全国共有1128家中华老字号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月，为促进老字号创新发展，商务部等5部门印发《中华老字号示范创建管理办法》（以下简称《办法》），在此《办法》中，建立了“红绿灯”机制，即“有进有出”的动态管理机制，对不符合要求的老字号品牌做出整改或移出措施。 2023年2月，商务部曾公开表示，中华老字号的“荣誉”不是一劳永逸的，更不能躺在功劳簿上“摆资历”“吃老本”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《办法》下发3个月后，商务部联合文旅部等部委决定对已有中华老字号进行复核，开展新一批中华老字号认定，让老字号“有进有出”。这是中华老字号商家被认定以来首次接受复核，但不是最后一次，《办法》规定，原则上每3年认定并公布新一批次中华老字号名录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;55个摘牌老字号&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;截至本次被摘牌，吴家熏肉享有中华老字号近30年。 1990年代初，山西省临汾市吴家熏肉被原国内贸易部评定为中华老字号。彼时，刚成年的吴志勇作为第五代传人，正从基础开始学习祖传佐料配方和加工工艺，如今他已到了知天命的年纪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴志勇告诉南方周末记者，因为当时忙于上新生产线，对复核这件事没有足够重视，同时查找补全历史数据花费时间太多，导致错过上报材料时间。吴志勇猜测，被移出或是因为《办法》第二十条：企业破产清算、解散、注销、被吊销营业执照或三年以上不开展经营活动，移出中华老字号名录并收回中华老字号标识使用权及牌匾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴家熏肉所属企业为临汾市尧都区吴家宝兴熏肉制品有限公司，该公司已于2017年进行清算。吴志勇解释，该公司是父亲吴宝善和二伯合营，他们因年龄大了身体不好，再加上2014年原熏肉加工厂因城市扩建被拆，俩人便“退休”，吴家熏肉的经营也中断6年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被移出中华老字号名录的55家品牌中，与吴家熏肉情况类似的不在少数。南方周末记者梳理发现，多数被移出名录的品牌公司显示注销、破产、除名等，甚至严重违法，一些公司法定代表人也被列为失信被执行人，限制高消费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者尝试联系移出名单上的55家品牌，除部分联系不上外，多数拒绝受访。少数受访品牌中，摘牌原因各异。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山西延虎品牌负责人告诉南方周末记者：“等把手上最后一个订单做完，就再也不做了。”内蒙古大盛魁品牌负责人称，企业还开，但是不生产了，只是维系这个品牌。安徽寿春堂表示，正在换新店，等找好了新地方再说。山西明泉宝负责人称，企业还在开，但是不生产了，“因为国家出台的标准不让用现在的锅炉，等换了新锅炉就能生产了”。山东石蛤蟆品牌负责人表示，自己完全不知道被“踢出”中华老字号这个事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者以商家身份咨询商务部流通发展司相关人士，对方回复称：“被移出的理由是各种各样的，不是只有破产、不经营了才会被移除。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实场景中，某些中华老字号的败落更为直观。 2010年经商务部核准成为中华老字号的北京华女内衣创始于1938年，是北京首家妇女用品专营店，曾提出立志让华夏女性穿“华女”内衣。曾在王府井大街开设店面的华女内衣，如今已找寻不到任何踪影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾坐落于广州市上下九商业街区的琳琅婚纱摄影店，创办于1947年，当时是其所在荔湾区最大的摄影店，如今店面已被运动品牌占据。年近80岁的陈阿婆向南方周末记者回忆，以前的摄影馆是两层骑楼，属于高端消费品牌，自己曾在1970年代到琳琅摄影馆拍过工作照，但未拍过婚纱照，“里面一间用来拍照，外面做大堂，比较高档，人还挺多”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年的重阳节前夕，市民游客排队购买上海老字号品牌的重阳糕。据商务部数据，2022年老字号企业营业收入超1.2万亿元。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年的重阳节前夕，市民游客排队购买上海老字号品牌的重阳糕。据商务部数据，2022年老字号企业营业收入超1.2万亿元。视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;计划重回老字号榜单&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;被移出老字号名录，吴志勇虽遗憾但并不气馁：“我们痛定思痛，不能让品牌停留在家族企业模式上，我们有信心下次申报（中华老字号）一定成功。”根据《办法》，被移出中华老字号名录的，自决定作出之日起两个申报周期内不得再次申报。也就是说，直到2032年，吴志勇才能再次申报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，吴家熏肉的生意似乎并未受到影响，商务部门曾授予的中华老字号牌匾暂未通知收回，印有“中华老字号”标识的包装袋已不能使用，所幸存货不多，损失不大。 2020年底，吴志勇和弟弟吴志君筹资另址新建了工厂。如今，这座占地6亩的工厂每天可生产约800公斤熏肉，供4个本地店面一天销售。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与第四代传承时的生产力相比，新工厂的面积缩小但产能提高了。据吴志勇介绍，自家秘方在光绪三年（1877年）由其身为郎中的祖辈配制，其间由爷爷改良过一次，后延用至今未变。该秘方约有22味中草药，不同季节使用不同的配料，猪肉、牛肉、鸡肉、兔肉等配料也不同，甚至不同部位用料都有区别。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴志勇告诉南方周末记者，多年来，吴家熏肉的秘方始终坚持口授。他回忆，自己和弟弟被父亲带到配料室，配料室没有窗户，只有一个门，父亲教他们夏天煮猪头肉所用的配方，他们只能死记硬背，若是用纸笔记下，出门前必须烧掉。不仅如此，该配方传男不传女，可以传儿媳。吴志勇称，他父亲那辈兄弟7人，都完成了传承；他这辈堂兄弟10人，目前有5人正在经营；现在，接力棒正慢慢交到第六代手里，这一辈中，有10名男性，其中9人暂未成年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，第六代传承人吴亚宙开始学习如何配料，以及洗、泡、腌、煮、熏、晾等工艺。吴志勇透露，目前25岁的吴亚宙并未完全掌握秘方成分，等他到了35岁心智成熟时，才可将秘方悉数传授。另一名传承人是吴志勇的儿子吴亚轩，还在读高二的他仍未拿定是否要继承祖传家业的决心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴志勇觉得，失去中华老字号称号的吴家熏肉不单是一种食品，更是老一辈人的心血和辛酸，他想把其发扬光大。如今，新工厂正在调试一条高温灭菌软包装生产线，调试完成后即可将产品推向外地市场，不仅如此，他打算引入直播带货。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月9日，商务部披露中华老字号复核结果当天，商务部新闻发言人何亚东说，2022年，中华老字号企业实现营业收入超1.2万亿元，近七成企业实现盈利。 2023年前三季度，营业收入已超过2022年全年水平。商务部将会同相关部门，进一步建立健全老字号保护传承和创新发展的长效机制，推动老字号深挖文化底蕴，对标先进理念，守正创新发展，更好发挥示范作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>