<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[多地健康码重出江湖？相关部门有必要澄清以释众疑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Recently, there are media reports that health codes in some places have &quot;reappeared&quot; &quot;Jianghu&quot; has aroused strong public attention. Nowadays, &quot;Category B and B management&quot; have been implemented to deal with the new coronavirus, and many places have also announced that the health code system will be offline and relevant data will be destroyed. Why is the health code back on the scene? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Recently, respiratory infectious diseases have broken out again. At this time, the health code has returned to the world, which makes many people wonder. However, some netizens said that this is just because the health code system in some places has not been offline and has always been there. It is not that it has just &quot;reappeared&quot; recently, so there is no need to worry. In response to relevant questions, the official citizen hotline in some places stated that as long as it does not affect life and travel, it is &quot;nothing&quot;, meaning that there is no need to worry about it &lt;span style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;, &quot;(epidemic) ) has passed.&quot;&lt;/span>;However, the health code is of great importance, and it is still necessary for relevant departments to provide further explanations to eliminate public doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After the COVID-19 &quot;Category B and B&quot;, the future of the health code has aroused widespread discussion. Many places have announced that they will offline the health code system and delete the data. For example, on February 14, 2023, the relevant departments of a certain province issued an announcement announcing that from 11:00 on February 16, 2023, service entrances such as antigen self-testing, health declaration, digital space, and epidemic prevention workbench will be completely closed. Delete and destroy all data related to the service to ensure the security of personal information. Although the announcement at the time did not mention that the health code applet would be completely offline and all data deleted, the public generally believed that the health code had completed its historical mission and should completely withdraw from the historical stage and destroy all data behind the entire system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;There is no doubt that the health code system stores a large amount of personal information. Information such as name, ID number, mobile phone number, and even face authentication are all extremely sensitive personal information. The health code system may also store travel information such as when and where each person has been, and medical and health information such as whether they have been vaccinated. This information is also personal privacy. During the epidemic, for the needs of prevention and control, the public can understand, accept and support. After the epidemic is over, the relevant systems have no reason to continue to save these users’ private data and should be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At that time, Wang Chunhui, a member of the Information and Communication Economics Expert Committee of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology and director of the Network and Data Law Research Department of the Chinese Behavioral Law Society, also said in an interview with the media that itinerary cards, health codes The mission has ended, the purpose of processing personal information is no longer necessary, and all personal information should be deleted in accordance with the law. Many places have also announced that personal data in the health code system will be destroyed, and some cities have also held public destruction ceremonies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, judging from the current situation, there are still many places where the health code system seems to have not been offline, and some places still retain at least part of the data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Storing this data for a long time, even if the health code system is not completely offline, the risk of data leakage will increase dramatically. Because after the epidemic, the technical maintenance of the health code system has basically come to a standstill. If the data is not destroyed and the system is not offline and is exposed to the Internet, it is likely to be attacked by hackers. If the data is leaked, the consequences will be disastrous. Even when the health code system was still running, the information of 48.5 million users of a certain health code system was suspected to have appeared on the dark web for sale. Investigators checked 47 sets of data published by the sellers and found that the names, ID numbers, and mobile phone numbers of these users were all true, and they had indeed registered for the city&#39;s health code application. These leaked data will exist permanently on the dark web and will continue to be sold back and forth. The mobile phone number can be changed, but the name and ID number are used for a lifetime. You don’t know when this information may be used to commit telecom fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The health code system is independently developed by each locality, and each locality is responsible for the handling after deactivation. Some places have announced that they will stop services and destroy data, but judging from the current situation, some places have not actually done this. Of course, there are also health code applications in many places that have indeed stopped serving, and mini programs are no longer available. But users have no way of knowing whether the data behind it has been destroyed. It is necessary for an authoritative third party to supervise and verify the deactivation and data destruction of health code systems in various places to ensure that these data, which store a large amount of user sensitive information, are completely destroyed and will not be leaked or used without the user&#39;s knowledge. case for other purposes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Whether the health code is &quot;reappearing&quot; or &quot;never offline&quot;, it shows that at least some data is still retained in some places. It is necessary for these places to issue official clarifications on this, and to take down the health code program under supervision as soon as possible and destroy the data to eliminate public doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“中印两国可以同时崛起”:访印度前驻华大使阿肖克·康特]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“没有中印参与，全球重大议题很难解决”：访印度前驻华大使]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261954]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of December 3, Conte accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo /Southern Weekend reporter Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/06/66ae1d4851.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/06/66ae1d4851.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of December 3, Conte accepted a face-to-face interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. (Picture/Southern Weekend reporter Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China and India are rising at the same time. How to handle Sino-Indian relations is not only related to the interests of the two countries, but also crucial to the entire world.&quot; December 3, 2023 On Japan, Ashok K. Kantha, former Indian Ambassador to China, said in an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend on the sidelines of the 2023 &quot;Understanding China&quot; international conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kant is a senior Indian diplomat and China expert. He served as the Consul General of India in Hong Kong, China, and as the Ambassador of India to China from 2014 to 2016. Currently, Conte works at the China Institute, an authoritative academic institution, which is located in New Delhi, the capital of India. It is the oldest institution on China issues in India. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have worked in China and been engaged in China research for 15 years. I can only say that I have a certain understanding of China. China is very big and complex. No one dares to say that they fully understand China.&quot; Conte said with a smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the Indian ambassador to China, Kant has witnessed the good development of Sino-Indian relations. During his tenure, the heads of state of China and India visited each other&#39;s hometowns. But he admitted frankly that &quot;the current Sino-Indian relations need to resolve some outstanding issues and pass them smoothly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are many similarities between China and India.&quot; Conte said that historically, the two countries used to be the world&#39;s largest economies, but subsequently lagged behind world development. Now China and India are re-emerging. , &quot;Both sides should support each other.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Seeing China from Two Perspectives&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First time participating in &quot;Understanding China&quot; How do you feel about international conferences? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For me, this is a good opportunity to try to understand China’s views on various issues. Especially how China tells its story to the outside world. This morning, I attended a closed-door seminar on Sino-US relations. Participants from China, the United States, South Korea and India had a long discussion, and I was also one of the speakers. This discussion was very fruitful and can help us understand a very critical issue - how the future development trajectory of Sino-US relations will affect the entire world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What suggestions do you have for promoting mutual understanding between China and India? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China has a long civilization and is also the world&#39;s second largest economy and the most important trading partner of nearly 40 countries around the world. There is no doubt that issues involving China will arouse the attention of other countries, including India, and some of China&#39;s measures will also cause concerns in other countries, so it is very important to understand China&#39;s ambitions and how China develops. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, China is India&#39;s largest neighbor, and India also hopes to maintain friendly relations with China. However, currently, relations between the two countries are in a difficult period due to border issues. If the boundary issue cannot be normalized, it will be difficult for the overall relations between China and India to return to normal. Against this backdrop, we hope to be able to communicate our concerns and expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You have served as India’s ambassador to China before. What new feelings do you have when you return to China this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have worked in China for a long time. The first time I came to China was in 1981, when I was a young diplomat. Later, I served as the Consul General of India in Hong Kong, China and the Ambassador of India to China. But at that time, I was working in China as a diplomat. Today, as an ordinary Indian citizen studying China issues, I went to China to participate in a conference and tried to understand China. These are two different perspectives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-India relations are very important. It is a complex relationship with challenges, but we hope to have constructive engagement with China. In the early years, I was working in China on behalf of India. My perspective on the problem and my specific working methods were all different. As an ordinary citizen, I can promote mutual understanding between China and India in my own way. In particular, I have many old friends in China. We can talk openly and honestly. I will tell them what concerns India has and what changes it expects China to make. The dialogue between us is very friendly and candid. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The most populous&quot; has mixed blessings&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2023, India will surpass China and become the The most populous country in the world, what does this mean for India? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think it made a big difference. India and China are the two most populous countries in the world, with about 1.4 billion people each. For India, we need to take greater responsibility to look after such a huge population to ensure that the country continues to develop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, India and China were once the largest economies in the world. Research by Angus Maddison, a well-known British economist, pointed out that in the 17th and 18th centuries, the economies of China and India were leading the world, but later India encountered colonial rule and lost development opportunities, and its economic growth continued to slow down. Slowly, GDP dropped from about 25% of the world at that time to 4% in 1950. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, we are working hard to rebuild our country and our economy. India has been doing very well over the past three decades, with economic growth rate second only to China. But we also face huge challenges in many areas, especially in providing a better life for our people and in technological development and transformation. China and India are very similar and we can learn from each other&#39;s experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What opportunities and challenges will becoming the world&#39;s most populous country bring to India? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;One of India’s great advantages is that it has a very young population. The median age of the population in India is about 28 years old, and that&#39;s the demographic dividend we have. A larger youth population means more people to serve in the Indian economy. We must make full use of this dividend and think about how to enable this young working population to contribute to India&#39;s achievement of becoming a developed economy. India&#39;s goal is to become a developed country by 2047, the 100th anniversary of India&#39;s independence. Although this task is difficult, India is working towards this goal. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, India provides jobs for nearly 12 million new workers every year, which is a huge number. Similar to China, India is also facing the problem of youth unemployment or underemployment, so we must create new job opportunities on a large scale. But this goal can only be achieved by ensuring that the economy continues to grow at a rate of 7% or 8%. It&#39;s a big challenge, but one we can meet. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Without the participation of China and India, it is difficult to solve major global issues&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As China&#39;s largest neighbor and a member of the BRICS, how does India view its relationship with China? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;India and China have a complex relationship with many unresolved issues, including border disputes. Both China and India are trying to establish a constructive and friendly partnership. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the situation on the Sino-Indian border is not stable. If the border issue is not resolved, it will be difficult for the overall relations between the two countries to return to normal. Therefore, the direct challenge we face is how to restore peace and tranquility on the border. Now, China and India have made some progress, but there is still a lot of work to be done. We need to have closer and more strategic dialogue so that bilateral issues can be effectively resolved, so as to contribute to the two countries&#39; efforts in regional and global issues. to create conditions for joint cooperation. China and India are the two most populous countries in the world and rank among the world&#39;s five largest economies. Without the participation of China and India, major global issues such as climate change, terrorism and artificial intelligence will be difficult to fully resolve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As the two largest developing countries in the world, how can the two sides enhance mutual trust and cooperation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China and India have maintained good cooperation in many fields in the past, and China is India&#39;s second largest trading partner. In 2022, bilateral trade between China and India will be close to US$135 billion. But India is also worried. India&#39;s trade deficit with China exceeds 100 billion US dollars. India looks forward to pursuing a more balanced economic engagement with China, but we also need to respect each other&#39;s concerns, interests and ambitions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now China and India are rising at the same time and becoming two major countries in the world. In this process, how to handle Sino-Indian relations is not only related to the interests of the two countries, but also to the entire world. Crucial. China and India can rise at the same time, and both sides should support each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;India will not join any military alliance&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For a long time, India has Diplomatically, India pursues a policy of non-alignment, but in recent years, India seems to be turning to the United States and strengthening military cooperation with Japan. What do you think of this trend? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;India seeks to have good relations with all major countries in the world, whether it is the United States, China, Russia, Japan and European countries. However, we will maintain an independent foreign policy and make decisions based on specific issues without joining any military alliance. This basic national policy has not changed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that the relationship between India and the United States has changed, especially in the past 20 years. The United States has become India&#39;s largest trading partner. We cooperate with the United States, Western countries and Japan because we believe this is very important for India&#39;s economic and technological transformation. In fact, China is also working closely with these countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India seeks to establish closer ties with the United States and is also strengthening security cooperation under the &quot;Quadrilateral Mechanism&quot;. But what needs to be made clear is that the &quot;Quadrilateral Security Dialogue&quot; between the United States, Japan, India, and Australia is not a military mechanism, and India is not willing to join any alliance. We just want to maintain our strategic independence. India&#39;s stance on the Russia-Ukraine conflict illustrates all this. We have adopted a stance that is completely different from that of the United States and Western countries. India will maintain an independent foreign policy on all issues. On some issues, we will cooperate with the United States and Japan, but on some issues, we may also have differences with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What factors will India pay attention to? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Conte:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;India does not want to see any confrontation and armed conflict between China and the United States, because this will have a negative impact on global development . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2023, the heads of state of China and the United States will meet in San Francisco, which will help restore Sino-US relations to a certain extent. India welcomes such changes and looks forward to seeing the world’s most Two powerful countries re-establish a more stable relationship. However, the strategic competition between China and the United States still faces potential structural challenges, and it is still unclear how the relationship between the two parties will evolve. We hope that China and the United States will avoid conflict, because this is not in the interest of both parties, nor is it in the interest of other countries, including India. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[面对民主制度的退潮，查尔斯·泰勒开出了这样的药方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 12:02:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/05/ibDnm46IXLOJQYg6c9u3Z3FsQhTaeL8ipzgyGOqz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;726&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/ibDnm46IXLOJQYg6c9u3Z3FsQhTaeL8 ipzgyGOqz. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Canadian philosopher Charles Taylor and his new book &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot; (with Craig Calhoun, Dilip Parameshwar Gaonkar). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the end of the last century, the trends of neoliberalism, globalization and democratization have swept the world, as if the entire There is only one way, one path in the world. But twenty or thirty years later, since Brexit, Trump’s rise to power, and right-wing parties winning elections around the world, political scientists are talking about the decline of democracy, both trying to explain why (as Fukuyama puts it in his book Identity Politics) Identity analyzes how disadvantaged communities thrive), while also continuing to defend democracy (e.g. Przewski&#39;s Why Bother with Elections?). Canadian philosopher Charles Taylor also co-authored a new book with two scholars, &quot;Degenerations of Democracy&quot; (Harvard University Press, 2022), which adds to the literature that has emerged in recent years on the decline of democracy. , adding another important book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before talking about the new book, let me first explain the background. Taylor wrote a masterpiece, &quot;A Secular Age&quot;, analyzing how the Western world evolved from the medieval era when &quot;no god was necessary&quot; to a secular era where God was &quot;all-powerful&quot;. The world experienced a helpless time. The historical process of looking back. Recognizing that history moves forward (rather than repeating ebbs and flows) is equally important to understanding the decline of democracy today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as in the new book, the authors led by Taylor describe today&#39;s democracy as a &quot;degenerate&quot; rather than a &quot;retreat&quot;. To clarify the difference between the two words, the point I want to explain is that With the qualitative change of the democratic system, it will no longer be able to return to &quot;normal&quot; as before. It will not be regarded as the &quot;golden rule&quot; as before (that is, democratic countries have a transcendent status but non-democratic countries are eager to imitate it). The kind of system that was once The &quot;good days of democracy&quot; that briefly appeared are long gone from a global perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another focus of the author in &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot; is to define democracy as a telic concept. In other words: democracy is an ideal situation, but the world can never be so ideally democratic (It is defined by standards that can never be met). To move towards democracy, elections are certainly one of the keys, but the presence of elections certainly does not mean democracy (just like the lack of rotation of political parties in Japan does not mean the lack of local democracy), democratic elections must have the two qualities of &quot;free&quot; and &quot;fair&quot; Big conditions. In reality, there is never true and ultimate freedom and fairness, but there is often the possibility of being a little freer and a little fairer. Similarly, the author regards democracy as a goal in the book, either getting closer to democracy or moving further and further away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like other scholars of democratic theory, Taylor and other authors in &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot; also hope to explain why the current world is contrary to democracy, and their answer is that the public has lost a kind of will that will change tomorrow. People feel they are deprived of the ability to make good lives for themselves and their families, so the public no longer has clear ideological preferences as before, but it is easier to resort to emotions and vent their dissatisfaction in life. Complaining collectively in small groups has become the greatest comfort in life. This is called populism. It is against this background that the democratic system has gradually changed from the past where everyone competed to pursue their own interests (agonistic), into an antagonistic arena. This is what the author calls the decline of democracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to ask how a democratic system can be brought back to life, the key must be to analyze the cause of death. The fundamental reason for the decline of the democratic system is the loss of the people&#39;s trust. If no one trusts any system, politics and political-related figures will only be hated by gods and ghosts. The author believes that ideal democracy is practiced through representative politics, that is, the people vote for political parties and authorize the formation of the government. The government is elected by one person and one vote. Everyone has a &quot;share&quot;, and the government therefore needs to be accountable to the people. However, scholars such as Charles Taylor revealed the miserable situation of democracy in the real world in &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In political research, the decline of the democratic system and the people&#39;s indifference or even disgust with politics are not something that has only happened in recent years. It is only the situation that has taken a turn for the worse in recent years that has attracted more attention. The situation is exactly like global warming. It has been talked about for decades, but in recent years it has really started to feel like it has burned its heels. So now more people are coming out to speak out for the earth, but we know that the distance problem will be alleviated (let alone solved). The volume is still far from enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for democratic systems. The voting rates in old Western democracies have been low for decades, and political party support has also been deteriorating. Behind these things is that the democratic system and the people are getting further and further apart. The death of democracy will have as much impact on the world as global warming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot;, the three authors describe the failed democratic system in reality: social inequality is infinitely magnified through the democratic system, and power and wealth are concentrated in a very small number of people. Regularly held elections and the political parties participating in them are to blame. The political parties themselves enjoy it, but (most) people don&#39;t actually feel it. Social development has become more diverse, but representative political parties have been unable to keep up. The opposition between left and right has left the people feeling indifferent. Political parties no longer represent the people, and a sense of powerlessness has enveloped the public. This is the key point that the author emphasizes repeatedly in the book: the people have lost their sense of accomplishment (efficacy). Who wants to get involved in politics when the “sacred vote” is effectively optional? The people&#39;s inefficacy is both the cause and the result of the decline of the democratic system. All problems are intertwined to form a vicious cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the system is incompetent and useless, populism, which allows people to share the same hatred and hatred, becomes extremely attractive. However, the author emphasizes very much in the book: populism is not the cause of the decline of democratic systems. Populism does indeed grow stronger when the democratic system is at its most fragile, but don’t forget that populism originally relied on the democratic system and mass mobilization. Forcibly treating populism as the biggest enemy actually ignores the root of the problem. If the democratic system is to be revived and active again, the most important thing to do is to re-inject a sense of achievement into the people and make them believe that the vote in their hands is not a piece of waste paper, but that they can really make a difference because of their vote. And elect a government that is responsible for itself and the country, but how to do it and is it possible? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In their book &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot;, Taylor and others wrote that the democratic system was beyond recovery, but the great philosophers did not just end it irresponsibly. Before they concluded, they wrote that it might be The most important chapter of the book, &quot;What to do?&quot; attempts to propose four life-saving methods for the declining democratic system. I will briefly summarize them here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The primary method is to restart democracy (Renew the Democratic Project). To put it simply and concisely, it is to re-respect the people of every country, because as mentioned before, one of the main reasons for the decline of democracy is that the people feel powerless and angry. For democracy to become an effective system, it must first make the people believe that they are part of the country again. That is to say, everyone&#39;s social background, blood culture, ideology and beliefs can be different, but the premise is that everyone should have the most basic and important thing in common - national identity, and use this identity to identify and transcend. and accommodate their differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it is extremely difficult to achieve mutual respect between people. If you look at the long-standing card of &quot;immigration&quot; in Western countries, you will know how divided and exclusionary the reality is. But the author said that the connection between people can be achieved in many ways, and uniting the masses with emotions like populism is one of the ways; similarly, returning to the community and starting to cultivate people&#39;s sense of belonging in the community can also be used to unite the people with emotions. People unite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second way to save democracy is to Overcome Neoliberal Bias against the Public Good. Under marketism, public expenditures have been continuously reduced in recent decades. When the world is at peace, the world is at peace. But when a crisis occurs, public institutions can respond immediately to whatever extent they can withstand it, at the cost of countless lives. Adequate and effective public expenditure is also an important source of people&#39;s sense of belonging to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last two methods: Think Big and It Takes a Movement. Before establishing something, we must first break it. Since the democratic system is now outdated and ineffective, more powerful reforms are needed. After reading this, the biggest revelation for readers may not be that democracy can be saved, but that the problem of democratic decline is so serious that it is almost impossible to save, because all the methods mentioned by the author are far from reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to work needs, I recently stayed in Belgium and visited the European Parliament a few days ago. I talked about how the EU&#39;s democratic system is innovative, how to value the opinions of people of all countries, and how to embody the practice of democracy. But the reality is that Belgium is like other European and American cities: there are many homeless people on the streets, and there are people (and more than one) begging on every subway ride. I tried two rides back and forth on the same day, and I met the same person. A beggar is really destined, and I lament that my fate in Belgium actually fell on a beggar...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What should I do? If you ignore various social problems, you will naturally not be able to gain the trust of the people. So is this book &quot;The Decline of Democracy&quot; worthless and just to release emotions? Not really. Do you remember the key point mentioned at the beginning of the book? Democracy is a &quot;telic concept&quot;. The ultimate democracy is just a goal. The people can always look at the benchmark and run straight. Even if we can never reach the benchmark, we can still get closer to the benchmark. distance between. Human beings grow old, sick and die, and governments and regimes come and go. If we can walk in the direction of democracy and freedom and try our best to bring the goal closer instead of farther away, even if it is only a small amount, it is considered progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 12:25:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“脱钩是一种‘双输’战略”：专访奥地利前总理沃尔夫冈·许塞尔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261950]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 10:35:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;I need a cup of coffee.&quot; At noon on December 3, 2023, before the official interview began, Xussel Again, stress this to your assistant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From December 1st to 3rd, 78-year-old former Austrian Chancellor Wolfgang Schüssel spent three busy days in Guangzhou. Opening speeches, media meetings, parallel forum speeches... his schedule is filled with &quot;brain activities&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is his first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; international conference. &quot;This is an open discussion, very interesting and exciting.&quot; Xussel told Southern Weekend reporters, and &quot;people read and wrote &quot;Good speech&quot; is different. This is a conversation with controversy, &quot;both positive and negative, and people express their own opinions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are representatives from different countries here. Whether they are Europeans, Americans, or Chinese, everyone can participate. This makes it possible for people to reflect on their existing positions, understand new ideas, and gain enlightenment.&quot; Xu Sai I said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 40 years, Xussel has visited China more than ten times and witnessed China&#39;s &quot;incredible development.&quot; Xussel is friendly to China and values ​​relations with China. During his term as prime minister from 2002 to 2007, the trade volume between China and Austria doubled several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, against the background of tense Sino-US relations, voices such as &quot;decoupling theory&quot; and &quot;deglobalization&quot; have become increasingly popular, casting a shadow on China-EU cooperation. Schüssel said he was &quot;totally opposed to decoupling&quot; because it was globalization and international trade that brought affluence and prosperity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Globalization is good for China, good for Europe, good for the United States, and good for those less developed countries. And decoupling is a &#39;lose-lose&#39; strategy.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;At noon on December 3, Wolfgang Schüssel accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/06/e991a2c2ec.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/06/e991a2c2ec.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260855&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;At noon on December 3, Wolf Gun Xussel accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“China is a special model”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span>;What do you think is the difference between China&#39;s development model and that of the West? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China is certainly a special model. In the past, China did not have free movement, free enterprise, private ownership and private property, but today the situation is completely different and China is developing in a positive direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This combination is very interesting. Usually we believe that market economy, free enterprise, private companies, etc., are complementary to freedom, openness, and pluralistic democracy. China, on the other hand, shows a different model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the Communist Party has a certain dynamic, an elitist management approach. They take the best and most talented people and then put those people to the test. If these people are successful, then they will be assigned to different positions again and then enter the next stage. This is a very interesting model. It&#39;s not our model, but it&#39;s a very effective model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;How does Europe view the rise of China? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Generally speaking, the European people respect China’s peaceful rise very much. I am an economist. I remember when Deng Xiaoping came to power, China&#39;s GDP was less than 200 billion US dollars. Today, that number is $7 trillion. This is incredible growth. China has lifted hundreds of millions of people out of poverty, and their living conditions have now greatly improved. The “One Belt, One Road” initiative proposed by China is also playing an important role. So I think China plays an important role on the international stage and has huge influence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have great respect and admiration for the Chinese model. Of course, we have different views on our respective political systems, that&#39;s for sure. But no matter what, every country has the right to choose its own future, and China does not belong to Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In recent times, Europe’s voice on China has not been positive. What is the reason behind this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the Russia-Ukraine conflict, one million people have been killed or disabled in the past two years. Mostly young people. Every day, missiles and drones rain down on Ukraine, destroying infrastructure, homes, and apartments. Today, the area where the battle was fought looks like the moon, a no-man&#39;s land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, I think both Europe and China should use their influence to stop this war and respect the sovereignty of independent countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Decoupling&quot; is a &quot;lose-lose&quot; strategy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What do you think? &quot;Decoupling theory&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am completely opposed to decoupling. it&#39;s out of the question. It is globalization and international trade that bring affluence and prosperity. According to customs figures, global trade has exploded over time. Globalization is good for China, good for Europe, good for the United States, and good for those less developed countries. So (decoupling) is absolutely impossible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some research suggests that when decoupling actually occurs, it will cause a loss of more than 7% of global GDP. For countries that are more deeply integrated into global supply chains, decoupling will do more harm. Like China or Austria, Europe and the United States. Therefore, decoupling is really a “lose-lose” strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Are de-risking and decoupling the same? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;De-risking is different. I know some people suggest that these two statements are consistent, but in fact they are not the same. De-risking refers to the reluctance of people to rely heavily on a single partner. Take the COVID-19 pandemic, for example. Suddenly, we saw a shortage of medical equipment. Moreover, due to the trade blockade, all channels have been closed. We have no medicines from India and no masks from China. De-risking means you have to leave some protection areas in place to protect your people, just in case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As another example, in terms of energy, we cannot completely rely on Russia. We have to diversify our sources. If someone blew up the pipeline in Austria, or Ukraine or Russia stopped the Nord Stream 1 pipeline, everything would be ruined. No energy, no electricity, you can imagine what that means for the economy. So, you have to diversify. China is also de-risking. China needs to maintain sovereignty in data, supply chains, etc. This is completely understandable, and we will do the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is national defense. The Europeans have outsourced national defense to the Americans. Trump said that we will eventually leave NATO and Europe will be responsible for itself. This is what de-risking means. We have to invest more in our own defense because in a crisis you have to protect your own people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What should you do if you suddenly encounter cyber hackers, surprise attacks, or blockades? What about your government, your site, your hospital, your energy company? Just like a company, we analyze potential risks in all directions of the company from a professional perspective - including paying attention to usage context, technical risks, external risks, market risks, etc. Every company will protect itself from risks, and the government must do the same . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In recent years, China has emphasized high-level opening up. What opportunities do you think this will bring? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think China’s opening up to the outside world is very important. Two factors struck me during the discussions at this conference. The first one is that a Chinese friend suggested that China is now focusing on developing a unified domestic market, such as managing the financial market, allocation, lending standards, etc. in all provinces with the same rules. This is exactly what the EU has always wanted to do but has not quite done yet. And once we complete that, it will be a huge catalyst for new growth. So, China is also following the same path. If China provides a large-scale market for its consumers and industrial partners, this is a major benefit for all of us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second point is that China is now committed to developing regional trade with ASEAN countries, which will also help Europe. Because I know that many companies in Europe are also interested in establishing ties with ASEAN countries. In many cases, people cannot accurately tell where a product comes from. For example, if you look at my smartphone, it contains 700-800 different components. They may be from Vietnam, Thailand, China, the United States, etc. As another example, my Audi car is made up of 900 different parts. It&#39;s assembled in Mexico, its engine comes from Slovakia, the gasoline comes from Hungary, parts come from China, and some elements come from Germany. So, this isn&#39;t just a &quot;German car&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I think this kind of inter-regional cooperation is beneficial. Moreover, cooperation enhances neighborly relations. For example, the EU intends to integrate the Western Balkan countries into the EU. Thirty years ago, a bloody war broke out in the Balkans. If Serbia develops cooperative trade with Croatia, Slovenia, etc., it will &quot;force&quot; peace. Therefore, I believe that inter-regional cooperation is conducive to prosperity, conducive to peace, and conducive to a harmonious future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“In short, we need to cooperate”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2020, Austria’s first trip from The China-Europe train from Vienna to Xi&#39;an sets off. How do you evaluate the impact of China-Europe freight trains on Austria? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China-Europe freight trains are very important. Shipping containers by rail is much faster and more environmentally friendly than shipping by sea. Although shipping is cheap, it does have more negative impacts in terms of environmental pollution and carbon dioxide emissions. So in my opinion, rail transportation is one of the elements of the future, which can both reduce costs and make cooperation more effective. Such applications have been very successful in Germany. If you look at the actual data, you will find that trade is growing positively, and it is not the so-called &quot;deglobalization&quot; or &quot;decoupling&quot; trend. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the changes in Sino-US relations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel:&lt;/strong>;First of all, 80% of the world’s population is neither Chinese nor American. Therefore, I think Sino-US cooperation is not the only cooperation that both sides need. I think we should really work on promoting cooperation between Europe and China. Currently, we are looking for and working hard to develop together. By the way, same interests as China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, a multipolar world requires well-functioning institutions, such as the United Nations and the World Trade Organization. This is important, if something goes wrong, arbitration is always better than bilateral tensions and that is in our interest. First, it is important to resume military engagement because no one wants to cause an accident, but it can happen. Likewise, what we need is a multipolar world, not a bipolar world. This could be beneficial to all of us if there were some effectively functioning international institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few weeks ago, the heads of state of China and the United States met in San Francisco, and I felt very optimistic about it. This is a positive step towards cooperation. We should look forward to a positive and bright future, because the world needs such a future, and we are also facing common problems, such as climate change, financial problems, inflation, regional conflicts, etc. All in all, we need to work together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Do you think Austria or Europe will choose sides? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wolfgang Schüssel: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The boat will naturally go straight when it reaches the bridge. I trust the leaders on both sides, they are rational politicians. I believe that good political initiatives always have the welfare of the people at heart. And the happiness of the people means prosperity, it means peace, it means employment, it means a good position when competing with other countries - of course in a peaceful and economic way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this conference, we honor Henry Kissinger. He is one of the architects of such a good policy. He was born in Germany and was deported. (He) came to the United States as a refugee from Nazi Germany but became a historian and an advocate for peaceful cooperation. Not confrontation, but working together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We also recently commemorated the late Premier of China, Li Keqiang. He founded the Forum Connecting Europe and China about 10 years ago to develop innovative worldviews and explore overall solutions to related problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think they are our role models in how to deal with tough times. This is the challenge we see today, but we should not be pessimistic, we should make a positive future possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[聚焦丨2023年“读懂中国”国际会议（广州）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261802]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 10:06:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;From December 1st to 3rd, the 2023 &quot;Understanding China&quot; International Conference (Guangzhou) was held at Yuexiu International Convention Center , hundreds of domestic and foreign guests from more than 30 countries and regions exchanged and discussed. Expand the convergence of interests and build a community with a shared future. Amid a century of changes, how will China act in new ways?</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陈尚君|站在传统与现代之间的学术巨匠：略谈翁同文先生的出版史与科技生活史研究]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261934]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73960&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70751&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/bdeda79f60.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;wengtongwen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1495&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/bdeda79f60.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260815&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Weng Tongwen (1915-1999) was born in Taishun, Zhejiang. In 1935, he was admitted to the History Department of Tsinghua University and was taught by professors such as Yu Pingbo, Chen Yinke, Qian Mu, and Jin Yuelin. In 1948, he went to study in the UK. In 1955, he was invited by the French sinologist Bai Lege to assist in the &quot;Song History Research Project&quot; and write &quot;The Births, Deaths and Chronology of Figures in the Song Dynasty&quot;. Since then, he has served as professor in the Chinese Department of Ruhr University Bonn in Germany, the Department of Oriental Languages ​​at the University of Wisconsin in the United States, the Nanyang University in Singapore, and the History Department at Soochow University in Taiwan. Published include &quot;Chinese Science and Technology History Series&quot;, &quot;Yilin Congkao&quot;, &quot;Siku Synopsis Supplement&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Mr. Weng Tongwen is an internationally renowned scholar of Chinese literature and history. His academic fields include not only the traditional four-part study, but also social history, literary history, and cultural history. He is well known to the world for his outstanding achievements and widespread influence in many fields, such as history of art, history of science and technology. I entered school late, and due to the cross-strait barrier, I didn’t get to know him, which I regret very much. Recently, Taishun held a meeting to commemorate Mr. Weng to discuss Mr. Weng&#39;s achievements. After a brief review of Professor Wu Songdi&#39;s two huge volumes of works, I was impressed by his admiration. What is particularly admirable is that Mr. Weng cared about his hometown in his later years and donated a lot of money. Later scholars in the country did not forget his kindness. They published anthologies and commemorated discussions, which are enough to make good stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Mr. Weng and I have not had the opportunity to ask for advice in person, and there are few points of intersection in our academic fields. I feel that Mr. Weng Tongwen’s nostalgia for boxing and his academic merits , I am also grateful for Professor Wu Songdi’s enthusiastic invitation. The organizer of Taishun is motivated by the desire to advance cultivation and promote academics. However, I am sometimes troubled by trivial matters and am unable to advance. I would like to write down my rough experience after reading &quot;The Collected Works of Weng Tongwen&quot;. . A little bit of petal incense is used to pay homage to the former philosopher. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1. &quot;Supplement to the Siku Synopsis&quot;: traditional reading notes with high spirits&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Let me first talk about the philological research that I am more familiar with. , take the fifth volume of the anthology, &quot;Supplements to Siku Synopsis&quot; as an example. The eighty-eight articles in this part are written according to the traditional bibliographic and postscript method. Most of them are relatively simple and record the correction of errors found in &quot;Siku Synopsis&quot;. Some of them show the depth of effort. The first article examines the three volumes of Guo Zhongshu&#39;s &quot;Peijin&quot; in the early Song Dynasty. It discusses the summary and quotes Zhongshu&#39;s biography from &quot;History of the Song Dynasty&quot;. It is believed that the summary quoted is very different from the popular Baiji version and the palace version &quot;History of the Song Dynasty&quot;. It is speculated that the two There was originally a rift in the shogunate of Liu Yun, Duke of Xiangyin, and the target was misunderstood. Then based on the surviving documents of the Five Dynasties and the early Song Dynasty, Guo Zhongshu&#39;s life was restored, Daduan was restored, and he criticized Zhongshu for being a &quot;drinker and irresponsible person who had many disobediences with others&quot;. He also revealed what Wang Guowei had studied and later engraved the &quot;Nine Classics Characters&quot;. It was written by Zhongshu, and his contribution is indescribable. Today, people have a lot to say about the eight volumes of the four-storey version of &quot;The Biography of Talented Scholars of the Tang Dynasty&quot; written by Xin Wenfang of the Yuan Dynasty. Weng Kao has a particularly valuable historical material, that is, it is revealed that the second volume of &quot;Shitian Collection&quot; written by Ma Zuchang of the Yuan Dynasty contains &quot;Ti Xinliang Shi &quot;Pisha Collection&quot;&quot;: &quot;If you can&#39;t sort through the sand, there will be too much gold. The meaning of modern and ancient times is short and short. Long song. Autumn plugs sing frost armor, spring houses cut paintings, chanting turns the remaining hair, desolate is Yin He.&quot; Mr. Weng therefore knew Xin You&#39;s &quot;Collection of Poems on Peeling Sand&quot;, and commented: &quot;Yin He, Yin Keng, He Xun is also . Compared with this, it is profound, and there is no doubt that he is as famous as Wang Zhiqian and others, and Yang Zai and others advocated peace with them.&quot; &quot;>;(&quot;Collected Works&quot; mislabeled this passage as Ma Zu Changyu)&lt;/span>; This is very important for understanding the poetry level and achievements of Xin Wenfang himself, who worked most diligently on the poets of the Tang Dynasty in the Yuan Dynasty. A study of Zhang Tangying&#39;s &quot;Shu 梼杌&quot; in the Song Dynasty shows that the original book must have been in ten volumes. The whole article is only over 200 words long and contains extremely rich information, so you can rely on it for basic judgments. There are five volumes of &quot;Luoyang Jialan Ji&quot;, and the biographical annotations are all mixed into the main text. Since the Qing Dynasty, many scholars have hoped to separate out the annotations as Quanzu Wangxiao&#39;s &quot;Shui Jing Zhu&quot; did. Tang Yan&#39;s &quot;Gou Shen&quot;, recent scholars Fan Xiangyong&#39;s &quot;College Notes&quot;, Zhou Zumo&#39;s &quot;College Notes&quot; and Xu Gaoruan&#39;s &quot;Republication&quot; believe that Xu Shu &quot;learned from various schools and came from behind&quot;, but did not add annotations to historical events. In this regard, it is known that Fan and Zhoujia have &quot;profound skills&quot; and the attached pictures are &quot;sufficient for reference.&quot; This has gone far beyond the revision and supplement of &quot;Siku Synopsis&quot;. In five or six hundred words, one can read the gains and losses of modern people&#39;s governance of &quot;Jialan Ji&quot;. Since the publication of the abstract, Yu Jiaxi&#39;s &quot;Diagnosis of Syndrome&quot; has been particularly famous, and his scholarship has paid special attention to the collected works of the Song and Yuan Dynasties, which can supplement the author&#39;s actions and the beginning and end of the original book. Mr. Weng Tongwen also paid attention to the historical events of the Song and Yuan Dynasties. He discussed various articles with Yu, such as the life story of Ye Zhi, the author of &quot;Ai Rizhai Congchao&quot;, and the article in &quot;Xijing Miscellaneous Notes&quot; quoted Lao Gan and Hong Ye, The remaining books are unknown. Wang Chen was the author of &quot;Tang Yulin&quot;. There are many inventions in the remaining books. Mr. Weng Tongwen even read Su Shi&#39;s &quot;Wang Danian&#39;s Lament&quot; written for Chen&#39;s father. He also knew that Chen came from a maternal relative&#39;s house and was a cousin to Shen. , Chen is older than Shen. There are so many wonderful things like this that it is impossible to list them all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73967&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70758&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/05/101090ef9a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;WeChat picture_20231204163902.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;759&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/101090ef9a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260816&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;In 1936, Weng Tongwen (first from left) was with his family in Xi&#39;an. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;2. Research on Publishing History: China’s Contribution from a Western Academic Perspective&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Research on the History of Science, Technology and Culture&quot;, Part Three of &quot;Collected Works of Weng Tongwen&quot; &quot;, there are twenty-one surviving articles, one of which talks about silkworm breeding, eleven on the history of publishing, two on the custom of sitting on chairs, one on the history of gunpowder, one on the incorruptibility of Han corpses, and one on It talks about the observations of genetic phenomena by people in the Tang Dynasty, and the other four articles talk about social and cultural exchanges between China and foreign countries, covering a wide range of topics. The most direct impression is that Mr. Weng is a traditional scholar who has read many Chinese books in depth. However, because he has studied and taught in the West for a long time, his research interests and narrative stance are fundamentally different from those of traditional scholars. Whether he reads common books or Xi Jian&#39;s books all have unique insights and revelations, numerous discoveries, solid evidence, and new and reliable conclusions. These are the common characteristics of this group of papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Let’s talk about the history of publishing first. From writing to publishing, the Tang Dynasty was a critical period. Exactly when the earliest engravings began has been debated among bibliophiles. Due to the discovery of Dunhuang posthumous documents and new documents, the earliest publication was probably in Shuzhong during the Yizong period. As for the scriptures found in South Korea with Empress Wu&#39;s new characters, the exact date of publication is still controversial. The articles written by Mr. Weng Tongwen were written at different times, but they involve more detailed interpretations and discovery of documents. Here is a summary, which is very enlightening to read. &quot;Correct Interpretation of the Word &quot;Mule&quot; in Yuan Zhen&#39;s Writings Intertwined with the History of Printing&quot; is a large article that analyzes it from a small perspective. In December of the fourth year of Changqing reign of Yuanzhen, he wrote the &quot;Preface to the Collection of Baishi Changqing&quot;. There is a self-note: &quot;Yang and Yuejian wrote many calligraphy models of Le Tian and Yu&#39;s miscellaneous poems, which were sold in shops.&quot; Hu Zhenheng of the Ming Dynasty also wrote It is believed that &quot;Mule&quot; refers to engraving and printing. In modern times, Hu Shi advocated Youli, and then there were as many as 20 or 30 writers. Only three people such as Xiang Da expressed their opposition, thinking that &quot;Mule&quot; refers to double-line hooks to draw white. Reproduction technology of ink marks on poetry manuscripts. Mr. Weng agreed with Xiang and analyzed the interpretation and changes of the two words in the past dynasties from the etymology and word formation, hoping that future researchers will no longer be troubled by this word. His argumentation process was extremely rigorous, and he had two unexpected gains. First, he compared the word &quot;mo&quot; with the words &quot;mo&quot;, &quot;motuo&quot;, &quot;motuo&quot;, &quot;mole&quot;, and &quot;moji&quot; that have appeared successively since the Eastern Han Dynasty. They must all be the same. &quot;The technique of making copies on paper according to the original pattern of writing strokes or ink marks.&quot; The second is to prove that &quot;mule&quot; is a new term that appeared in the mid-Tang Dynasty. This argument may seem trivial, but it actually resolves the ambiguity in the interpretation of a large number of documents related to engraving issues in the Middle Ages, and the conclusion is fully credible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The earliest self-engraved poetry collection was Chen Yong, a native of Shu in the late Tang Dynasty&quot;. It is not long, but it is very interesting. &quot;Si Ku Yuan Jiu&quot; identifies the person who first engraved a collection of poems as Qian Shu Guanxiu, whose disciple Tanyu&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Collection of Chanyue&quot; says: &quot;Then I searched for and inspected the collection of poems and secretly memorized about a thousand poems, which were carved into a volume. The title is &quot;Collection of Chanyue.&quot; This preface was written in the fifth year of Qiande in the former Shu Dynasty &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(923)&lt;/span>;, and it is clear that there is no Disagreement. Ye Dehui&#39;s &quot;Shu Lin Qing Hua&quot; according to the &quot;Old History of the Five Dynasties - He Ning Biography&quot; states that &quot;there are hundreds of volumes collected, self-sealed on the board, hundreds of seals printed, and benefits distributed to others&quot;, which lists his events before Guanxiu. Mr. Weng believes that He Ning is later than Guan Xiu, and there is no absolute date for the engraving of his books, so he disagrees. He uncovered a neglected record from &quot;Beimeng Suoyan&quot;, that is, Chen Yong, a Jinshi during the reign of Emperor Zhaozong, had a pair of lines at the beginning of his poem: &quot;Buffaloes on the other side cross with their noses floating on their noses, and sandbirds nod their way along the stream.&quot; Taoist priest Du Guangting Questioned, these two sentences are not good, &quot;Why should this be the beginning of the volume?&quot; Chen Yong replied: &quot;It was once rewarded by the nobles, so it is engraved on the beginning of the volume.&quot; Mr. Weng revealed this article, which is of course very valuable and should be able to supplement the previous ones. A case study of Shu engraved poetry collection. Whether the absolute date is earlier than Guanxiu can be discussed again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The earliest publisher in world history appeared in Chang&#39;an in the middle and late Tang Dynasty&quot;, first based on Dunhuang documents, it was confirmed that there was a person selling almanacs in the second year of Emperor Xizong&#39;s reign in the late Tang Dynasty. The Fan Shang family in Chengdu and the Bian family in Longchifang, Chengdu County, which sold Buddhist mantras, are all mentioned in the discussions of Zhang Xiumin, Li Shuhua, and Qian Cunxun. Chen Zuolong, a bookseller in Chang&#39;an, has passed the examination of two calligraphers surnamed Li. Mr. Weng even cited the example of Bo 2633&#39;s &quot;Mrs. Cui&#39;s Training of Women&quot;, although it was a banknote version, but there was no &quot;printed version of the Li family in Shangdu&quot; at the end, so it was written based on the printed version. I have read this volume again and again. The so-called &quot;Praise to Bai Shilang&quot; is definitely named after Bai Juyi, and the work may not have been published during Bai Juyi&#39;s lifetime. The second is Bo&#39;s 2675 reverse note of &quot;New Collection of Emergency Moxibustion Sutra&quot;, which has the characters &quot;Seal of the Li family in Beijing in Dongshi&quot; at the end. Although it can be inferred to be after the second year of Xiantong, it is also very precious. The third one is a printed copy of the Si 8010 residual calendar, with the cross &quot;Shangdu Shi Dongshi Dadaojia seal&quot; at the end, which is considered to belong to a bookstore or publisher with &quot;Da Dao&quot; as its inscription. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the two articles about movable type printing, in addition to researching Bi Sheng&#39;s invention of clay movable type printing stated in Shen Kuo&#39;s &quot;Mengxi Bi Tan&quot;, Mr. Weng vigorously pursued Bi Sheng His real life and what inspired his clay movable type skills. Particularly exciting among them are &quot;the doubts caused by clay type and its efficiency issues&quot; and &quot;the reason why movable type could not replace engraving before the late Qing Dynasty&quot;. The former, based on bits and pieces of records, shows that Bi Sheng had several projects in succession in the two hundred years after Bi Sheng. Several attempts were made, but there was no big development. Mr. Weng’s explanation for this is that although Bi Sheng was the first to invent movable type, there was no inheritance of linearity in the future. Instead, everyone kept starting from scratch and never overcame the shortcomings of the crude and rough movable type. Although China invented movable type printing, it did not replace woodblock printing. Fundamental changes did not occur until Western technology was introduced. &quot;Supplementary Discussion on the Invention of European Movable Type Plate Also Induced by Engraving Printing&quot; examines the way Europeans experimented with printing techniques before Gutenberg in Germany promoted the principle of movable type in the 15th century. In particular, he saw that the high frequency of letter engraving made it easier for Westerners to get ideas. Chinese woodblock printing methods inspired Europeans even more prominently. Although there are many speculations in this article, the basic insights are still within a reasonable range, and what I see is quite reasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition, the study of the life and book engraving career of Chen Qi, a descendant of Wu Zhao from the Later Shu Dynasty, the Xiangtai Yue family of the Southern Song Dynasty, and the book printer, are also included. They are all important and key figures in the history of Chinese printing. It is interesting to read clearly. &quot;Printing reduces the cost of books by nine-tenths&quot; is also an interesting topic. What I am more interested in is the interesting story at the end of the article about the fairy Wu Cailuan&#39;s book &quot;Tang Yun&quot;. Mr. Weng continued the opinion of Taiwanese scholar Wang Meng&#39;ou and believed that Wu Cailuan&#39;s &quot;Tang Yun&quot; was hidden in the National Palace Museum in Taipei. He always regretted not being able to see it in person. According to Zhou Zumo&#39;s &quot;Collection of Yun Shu of the Tang and Five Dynasties&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Zhonghua Book Company)&lt;/span>;, this volume is stored in the Palace Museum in Beijing and was photocopied by Zhou After reading the complete version, it was concluded that it was the Tang Dynasty Pei Wuqi&#39;s orthographic version of &quot;Public Mistakes, Filling the Gap and Qie Yun&quot;, not Sun Wei&#39;s &quot;Tang Yun&quot;. As for the book written by the female fairy Wu Cailuan, it is only a beautiful legend caused by the inscription and postscript of Xiang Yuanbian of the Ming Dynasty, and cannot be taken as true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73968&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70759&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/05/61524c0624.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;WeChat picture_20231204164056.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/61524c0624.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260817&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;In the 1950s, Weng Tongwen (first from right) was in France with his friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3. Science and Technology Life History Research: Daily and Important Perspectives&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Regarding life history, Mr. Weng Tongwen talks about the origin of chairs in China These two magnificent articles are examined in the context of global human history. They not only draw on the insights of Chinese and foreign scholars, but also extensively quote rich material objects obtained from literature and archaeology, and strive to restore the Chinese people from sitting low or kneeling to gradually sitting high. The process, including the &quot;Chronological Record of Rope Bed Materials&quot;, covers a period of more than 700 years. It mentions six chairs that appeared east of Congling from the Jin Dynasty to the end of the Six Dynasties. Five of them originated from India, which further proves that the chairs were introduced from India via the Silk Road. He also came to the same conclusion when he investigated the special-shaped rope beds of chairs, and proved that most of them were related to monks and monasteries. He pointed out that the rope bed was a tool for monks to meditate and meditate, and some monks developed the habit of not lying down day and night throughout their lives, and most of them He sat on the rope bed. After the Middle Tang Dynasty, he examined the traces of chairs entering the palace and scholar&#39;s homes, and explained that chairs also led to an increase in the height of other furniture, such as tables, tall cabinets, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Mr. Weng talked about the era when the book &quot;The Synopsis of Zhenyuan Miaodao&quot; was written. Based on the mention of Yanluozi in the book, it is suspected that it was written in the middle and late Five Dynasties. . I quoted the general rules of Taoist discussion from Taoist books, and felt that it was more likely to be written in the Song Dynasty. Based on the experience of the Waidan family, the article believes that incendiary gunpowder weapons began in the Song Dynasty, and the emergence of firecrackers should be after Song Renzong. The general conclusion can be believed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Three Interlocking Inventions Traced to Silk Production Techniques&quot; is the first and most important article in this part, so I I’ll introduce it at the end. China is a large agricultural country, and there has been a tradition of men farming and women weaving since ancient times. This article will explain that China&#39;s three great inventions (referring to printing, gunpowder, magnets) or four great inventions (the first three plus papermaking) have certain logic in themselves. His opinion is: 1. The discovery of the use of silk The invention of techniques for breeding silkworms to produce silk and bleaching wadding; 2. Papermaking originated from the imitation of &quot;natural paper&quot; appearing in bleached wadding; 3. Block printing originated from the combination of &quot;printable paper&quot; and &quot;plate lettering&quot;; 4. Movable type printing technology was conceived due to the &quot;phenomenon of discarding undamaged carved boards&quot;. Although this does not include all the four great inventions, it well explains the intrinsic reason why only China can pioneer the invention of papermaking and printing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73966&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70757&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/05/9bc7149361.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;WeChat picture_20231204162745.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1504&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/9bc7149361.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260818&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;&quot;Collected Works of Weng Tongwen&quot;, Zhejiang People&#39;s Publishing House, 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;4. Standing between tradition and modernity, showing the path for future generations to learn&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Finally, I would like to express my gratitude to Mr. Weng Tongwen as the representative Make a brief summary of the academic achievements and characteristics of the older generation of scholars. Mr. Weng Tongwen is a generation of scholars born in the early Republic of China, and his research path continued until the end of the twentieth century. When he was born, the Qing Dynasty was already dead, but he was proficient in the four classics, based on the Classics, and enriched with poetry. He took notes because of his gains in reading, and concentrated on writing papers based on his experiences. This is a traditional academic method. There are still lingering thoughts. However, the trend since the early Republic of China has strongly advocated using Western learning to explore the path of national salvation and development, and has also led humanities scholars to strive to accept Western academic approaches and explore various new academic topics related to life and society that the sages often ignored. Mr. Weng Tongwen was initially educated at Southwest Associated University, Yunnan University and St. John&#39;s University. He studied and worked in Britain, France, Germany, the United States, New Zealand and other countries, and finally served in universities in Taiwan. His scholarship is rooted in tradition, and his vision and methods are deeply influenced by Western learning. He highly integrates documents and cultural relics, fully integrates society and life, and pays special attention to the lower society, special skills, and basic classics. As mentioned above in this article, there are less than a hundred articles in the &quot;Sikubiaoyao Supplement&quot;. The long ones are more than a thousand words, and the short ones are only a hundred words. However, what they say must contain new insights and maintain a high spirit. It is a reference to the sayings of many famous writers in modern times. , all with outspoken comments. Articles on the history of life, science and technology, and publishing history can also exhaust the literature, refer to the sages of the times, analyze the subtle ideas, invent new insights, cite abundantly, be cautious in speaking, have clear opinions, and write well. Being peaceful can fully reflect everyone&#39;s style and can show the path for future generations to follow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[感冒发烧了，到底感染了啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261944]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-06 08:01:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/12/06/d8d9dbf252.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2860&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/ 06/d8d9dbf252.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[五月天被质疑假唱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261928]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 23:10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Recently, Mayday was questioned for lip-synching at the concert. A blogger released a video saying that 12 songs from Mayday&#39;s Shanghai concert were identified, and 5 of them were lip-syncing. At present, the Cultural Market Inspection Department has launched an investigation, which will scientifically evaluate and analyze the original video and audio of the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert, and publish the investigation results. In recent years, lip-syncing has frequently appeared in concerts and commercial performances, causing public anger and dissatisfaction.</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[校长9年性侵22名女童，乡村小学里的罪恶为何难以发现]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261936]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73945&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70736&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/7a0ad81139.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3263.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;November 2023, Pingliang City, Gansu Province Jingning County, the village where the primary school where the incident occurred. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/05/7a0ad81139.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260819&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023, Gansu Jingning County, Pingliang City, the province, is the village where the primary school where the incident occurred. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The car stopped at the location where the name of the village was marked on the electronic map, with mountains on one side and cliffs on the other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The driver carefully turned around, turned in through the overlooked gap, and drove through three turns on the newly found path and around two mountains. The ravine between them reaches the other side of the mountain. This is the destination - a remote village within the jurisdiction of Jingning County, Pingliang City, Gansu Province, where the electronic map failed to include the correct location. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking from a distance, this village almost looks like it grows on an earthy hillside, with buildings with red roofs and white walls stacked on top of each other around the mountainside. On November 16, 2023, the village was sparsely populated. The snow has melted, and an elderly couple is working in the fields, planning to hoe the soil to grow potatoes. The apples that the locals are proud of have been picked and sold, and the village is about to enter a slack period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nine days ago, a person close to the village was executed. His name is Zhang Longji, born in Jingning County in 1979, with a university education. According to the announcement of the Pingliang Intermediate Court, from 2010 to June 2019, when he served as the teaching director, principal and teacher of a primary school in Jingning County, he used corporal punishment and other means to form a mental coercion on primary school students who lacked sexual defense ability. He used explanation exercises, When students handed in homework and other opportunities, they repeatedly raped 5 young girls aged 8 to 12 years old in their dormitories, and repeatedly raped 17 girls aged 8 to 14 years old in public in the classroom or in their dormitories. Child molestation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Perhaps to protect the privacy of the victim, the court did not disclose the name of the elementary school where Zhang Longji taught. Southern Weekend reporters learned that the primary school where the incident occurred was the village primary school in the aforementioned village and had been withdrawn and merged in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the news that &quot;a primary school principal raped and molested 22 girls in 9 years&quot; caused an uproar on the Internet, this village in the eye of the storm seemed particularly silent. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A small village in the mountains&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Especially in our village, don&#39;t ask about these things.&quot; Upon hearing Zhang Longji&#39;s name, villager Zhang Bi Peng&#39;s tone became stern. On November 16, 2023, he stood at the gate of the hospital and waved his hands to the Southern Weekend reporter as if to drive him away. &quot;It&#39;s all my sad past.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Bipeng’s yard is only a few hundred meters away from the original site of the primary school where the incident occurred. Only the couple lives at home, and his father, Zhang Pinghe, takes care of his grandson in Jingning County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Pinghe is the old principal of the primary school where the incident occurred. He has taught in the village for more than 40 years and has now retired. On social platforms, he is called &quot;Perseverance in the Mountains.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, the empty and abandoned school building remains at the north end of the village. The gate is locked from the outside and cannot be entered. The outside of the courtyard is filled with corn stalks as high as the wall. Compared with the picture that appeared in the news ten years ago, the red roof of the elementary school bungalow still looks the same, and the exterior wall has turned white, as if it had been painted and repaired in the last few years, and the windows and doors are sealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The yard next to the school is still open. There are only two old houses. One is piled with props for celebrating the New Year and the lion dance. The other has several An old, dusty wooden table with medals hanging on the wall. Among the dead branches and weeds, there are two green basketball hoops. A villager said that this area is the school playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The villager introduced that the primary school was merged in 2019, and then the children in the village went to the central primary school in the town. It was the first boarding school in the town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the merger, this rural primary school was once a model in Jingning County. Among more than a dozen schools in the township, it ranked among the top three in performance every year. There are not many people in the school. When Sun Chuning, a staff member of the Jingning County Education Bureau, visited in 2015, there were only 29 students and 5 teachers in the school. Many students go to towns or counties with their migrant parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2015, Zhang Pinghe was still the principal, one or two years away from retirement. Sun Chuning had a good impression of the old principal, &quot;Teacher Zhang has been taking care of the school for decades, both during winter and summer vacations.&quot; He said he did not know Zhang Longji and did not pay attention to his situation when he visited the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The old principal has been commended repeatedly. According to public reports, he once took teachers to quarry clay to paint classrooms, went to a forest farm to collect waste materials to make simple tables and stools, and stayed at the school building to dig canals to divert water during heavy rains. Some netizens said in the comment area that in their memory, even the wife of the old principal pulled a trolley and worked in the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A Pingliang photographer once shot a short film for the old principal when he was about to retire. He said that the photo was taken for &quot;awards and competitions&quot;. At the end of the film, the words &quot;Produced by Jingning County Education Bureau&quot; appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, Zhou Lan, a school-age student who lived in a nearby village, came to this primary school to study. The school&#39;s reputation is one of the reasons why parents choose the school, but more importantly, it is almost his &quot;only solution&quot; for transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The surrounding area is inconvenient and there is no public transportation. Students measure distance by round-trip walking time, and anything that can be reached by walking in 30 minutes is considered &quot;very close.&quot; The map shows that Zhou Lan has to walk about 7 kilometers to the central primary school in the town, which takes an hour and a half on foot. At that time, &quot;there was an age requirement for living in school there, and you had to be in fifth grade or fourth grade.&quot; So Zhou Lan could only attend this village primary school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The grandchildren of the old principal did not study in this village primary school, but were sent to the county town and are now studying in high school. Zhang Bipeng explained that it was because “the conditions in the county are good.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The number of teachers and students in rural primary schools is constantly decreasing. At its peak, the school had more than 200 students. A few years before Zhou Lan enrolled, there were more than 100 people in the school. “There were quite a lot of people at that time, but they all left in the end.” In a school evaluation and acceptance self-inspection report filled out by Zhang Pinghe in 2016, the school had only 21 students and 4 faculty members, divided into 4 teaching classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The report states that the primary school was founded in 1957. It was expanded into a standardized primary school on the original site in 2002 and changed to a six-year complete primary school in 2003. The old principal wrote this paragraph in the report: The school carefully organizes teachers and students to study education laws and regulations, teachers&#39; law, and the Law on the Protection of the Rights and Interests of Minors. All teachers and students in the school know, understand and abide by the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Longji is one of the above-mentioned teachers. A relevant roster of Jingning County in 2014 shows that Zhang Longji was a professional technical level 12 and a primary school teacher level 2 at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2017, Zhang Longji took over as the principal of this village primary school. The transfer of teachers in rural schools is the responsibility of the local education bureau. The principal of a rural primary school in Gansu said that the position of principal must go through layers of selection before being qualified, including examinations and background training. “Each unit has to go through it again. For example, if there is a problem with your credit card, you will not be allowed to pass. , particularly strict.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the court notice, Zhang Longji had been committing crimes for several years at this time. Why didn’t Zhang Longji’s actions attract attention during this period? As of press time, Zhang Pinghe had not responded to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jingning County Education Bureau stated that the relevant details involve the protection of minors, so it is inconvenient to disclose them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I didn’t understand it at that time, so I saw it as a joke”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Zhou Lan was studying in this village primary school, he saw Zhang Longji with his own eyes He molested students in the classroom, but felt he had no choice but to do anything about it because &quot;he is the principal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the school was annexed and the school building was locked, Zhou Lan and several male classmates secretly climbed over the wall and entered. He said that Zhang Longji had two dormitories at the school, one of which belonged to his wife. The couple has two girls and one boy, and their three children sometimes come to live in the dormitory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Lan said that he and his classmates tore off the seal on the dormitory door and held a &quot;special ceremony&quot; inside. According to the video sent by Zhou Lan, they placed a photo on a low table, placed three small trays in front of the photo, placed chocolate pie on it, and burned paper on the side. Before Zhang Longji&#39;s execution, this &quot;ceremony&quot; with the meaning of memorial was a kind of revenge. They have been held three times in total, the last time in October 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Lan hated this teacher in her heart. He said that Zhang Longji often corporally punished and beat students, and he was very cruel. &quot;He took a stick and hit me on the head, (beating) to death, which cast a shadow on me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They are the last batch of students Zhang Longji taught and are now in junior high school. Zhou Lan recalled that before the incident in 2019, there were only three girls left in the school, and some had transferred away before. Zhang Longji would molest girls in front of him. When correcting homework in class, he would also call girls to the podium and molest them in public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also heard from girls in the school that Zhang Longji would call them to the dormitory. When school was over in the evening, Zhang Longji would use excuses such as &quot;the homework was not finished&quot; to prevent female students from going home and keep them until after nine o&#39;clock in the evening. He said that he was still young at the time and had little idea of ​​what Zhang Longji did. He only thought it was strange and did not tell his parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What Zhou Lan saw was just the tip of the iceberg. During an interview with Southern Weekend reporters, we learned that the incident of being molested by Zhang Longji was probably earlier than the time mentioned in the court notice and had occurred since his early years of teaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From 2004 to 2005, Lulu was in the first grade of a primary school in the town, and Zhang Longji, who was about 25 years old at the time, was her math teacher. She recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that at that time the school was a bungalow and it was very cold in winter, so they used stoves to burn charcoal for heating. During math class, Zhang Longji would call a female student to the podium, hold her in his arms, and &quot;do some very intimate gestures&quot; in front of thirty or forty students in the class, in the name of checking her homework. She said that she had personally seen several girls in the class being hugged, and &quot;he would pick some of the prettier little girls.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lulu herself is also a victim. Zhang Longji held her in his arms and breathed into her, &quot;I felt very strange, so I hid.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;By 2009, Professor Zhang Longji’s subject changed from mathematics to English. That year, Zhang Lei, a male student, was in the third grade. During class, Zhang Longji held the girl in his arms and taught her vocabulary, touched her face, and behaved affectionately. He saw a female classmate sitting on Zhang Longji&#39;s lap with a look of disgust on her face. Forced by the teacher&#39;s authority, she did not dare to make any big moves to resist. She could only twist her body to avoid his physical contact, but it did not have much effect. “I didn’t understand it at that time, so I just took it as a joke.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the same year, during a break in class, fifth-grade Lin Ling said that she was lying on her back in class. When she was sleeping on the table, there were many students in the classroom, and Zhang Longji suddenly hugged her from behind. Lin Ling was frightened and quickly said, &quot;Hurry up and let me go.&quot; He let go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the accounts of former students, Zhang Longji’s obscene behavior lasted for a long time, and students of different grades were victimized. &quot;He should have been molesting girls since he first joined the workforce... My last class, my current class, my next class, including my sister&#39;s class all know about it.&quot; November 2023 , Lin Ling told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Ling said that female students did not dare to get along with Zhang Longji and were afraid of being hugged by him. They felt &quot;especially annoying&quot; and privately complained to each other &quot;Why is he That’s it again”. &quot;But we didn&#39;t even realize at the time that he was breaking the law.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ignored help&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first female students Zhang Longji molested Have tried to save myself. Lulu, who was 7 years old at the time, told her mother about this &quot;strange thing&quot;. Her mother didn&#39;t take it seriously and just thought it was an elder&#39;s love for children. &quot;She said that your math teacher thinks you are very good and feels sorry for you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the parent-teacher conference, Zhang Longji would face Lulu’s mother Praise her and say that the little girl is &quot;very smart and well-behaved&quot;. Lulu analyzed that this strengthened her mother&#39;s judgment and made her feel that the young mathematics teacher was very responsible and appreciated her daughter, without any warning. Looking back, Lulu feels that rural parents “are very lacking in awareness in this regard.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Ling agreed with this analysis. She euphemistically said that the adults in the village are relatively simple, traditional and conservative. Lin Ling, who was 12 years old at the time, told her mother that there was a teacher in school who always hugged female classmates during class and also hugged herself, but the answer she received was unexpected. &quot;My mother said that my thoughts were not sincere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Talking about the memory of asking her parents for help in fifth grade to no avail, the adult Lin Ling hesitated for a few seconds. ,Sighed. &quot;Maybe he has a better personality, but the adults don&#39;t believe it.&quot; She told her mother two or three times, but when she saw her mother&#39;s reaction, she stopped mentioning it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In front of children and adults, Zhang Longji has two different faces. When facing students, he sometimes kissed and hugged them, and sometimes violently punished them. But when facing adults, in Lulu&#39;s words, he behaved politely and responsibly, &quot;it&#39;s quite invisible.&quot; His WeChat avatar is an ID photo with a red background, a Chinese character face, single eyelids, a wide nose, a smile, wearing a black suit and a red polka dot tie, and his hair is meticulously combed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where Zhang Longji grew up, the villagers also had a good impression of him. Compared with the remote teaching villages, Xiaohe Village in Gangou Town, where Zhang Longji&#39;s home is located, is closer to Jingning County and has convenient transportation. In the eyes of the villagers, Zhang Longji is one of the few &quot;top students&quot; who has gone to university, with high academic qualifications and decent work. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A villager said that Zhang Longji and his two sisters were both college students. After graduation, they earned money and renovated old houses in the village. A building was bought in the county seat. Zhang Longji&#39;s wife is a teacher. &quot;His wife is teaching. She is slim (dialect means thin) and her family is in good condition.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now the Zhang family&#39;s house is vacant, the iron door is rusty and locked, unused bricks are piled in the inner courtyard, and the red paper on the porch has faded. The courtyard is scattered with yellow leaves floating off the branches. The above-mentioned villagers said with some sadness that Zhang Longji&#39;s family was poor when he was a child. The shoes his mother wore were made of rags without uppers. His father sold rapeseed and raised three college students with hard work. They never thought that he would go down the wrong path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73929&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70720&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/05/b9dc7b55d7.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3262.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The old house of Zhang Longji&#39;s family in Xiaohe Village, Jingning County, Pingliang City, Gansu Province. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/b9dc7b55d7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260820&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house of Zhang Longji’s family in Xiaohe Village, Jingning County, Pingliang City, Gansu Province. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The last time the villagers saw Zhang Longji was in 2019. Some villagers remember that in April of that year, an old man died in the village, and Zhang Longji returned to the village to &quot;carry and bury the person.&quot; He was in &quot;good condition&quot; at the time, but he did not expect that the crime of rape and molestation was about to be exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than a month later, Zhang Longji was taken away by the police during the Dragon Boat Festival after a victim&#39;s family called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Longji still has relatives who run a supermarket in Xiaohe Village. He said that Zhang Longji rarely returned to the village after settling in the county, and there was not much contact between the two parties. &quot;After the old man (Zhang Longji&#39;s parents) disappeared, he would not come back for a year or two. When he came back, he would have a quick meeting and we would not chat.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;He refused to recall when he learned that Zhang Longji molested students. &quot;These things have happened, and now everyone here knows that there is such a person. There are some things that we can&#39;t talk about in depth, can&#39;t say, and don&#39;t want to say.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A 64-year-old villager still has a good impression of Zhang Longji, thinking that he is a decent person and behaves &quot;stablely.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He may have never seen Zhang Longji&#39;s ruthless side. According to the students&#39; accounts, both boys and girls were beaten by Zhang Longji, and iron rods, steel bars, and mops were all &quot;weapons.&quot; A boy recalled that when he was 9 years old and in third grade, he was beaten so hard that he &quot;couldn&#39;t sit still for a month, and his buttocks were all black.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Violence makes seeking help more difficult. Lin Ling remembers that when he was in first grade, Zhang Longji kicked a boy from the front of the podium to the back of the classroom. &quot;No one dared to resist, really. Because he beat people so fiercely, we didn&#39;t dare to say anything.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;I never mentioned the past injuries again&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The most difficult time for Lin Ling to let go was watching her friend being hurt by Zhang Longji. One day when she was in the fourth or fifth grade, during extracurricular activities, she and her friends went to Zhang Longji&#39;s dormitory to hand in homework. Zhang just came back from playing ball and was naked in the dormitory, wearing only shorts. &quot;When we handed in our homework, he hugged my classmate and kissed him hard there. It scared me. I ran away quickly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;There were no other teachers around at that time. Lin Ling ran out and told another classmate what happened. The two comforted each other and said, &quot;It should be fine.&quot; About 10 minutes later, the classmate who was hugged came out of Zhang Longji&#39;s dormitory. Lin Ling asked about her situation, and the reply she received was &quot;nothing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I was very worried about that classmate of mine, but when we were young, we didn&#39;t dare to say anything.&quot; Lin Ling recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That memory became the shadow of her childhood. She always remembered that the female classmate who was being hugged was trying to resist and try to break free, but she was only a primary school student, thin and not very strong. Zhang Longji kept holding her and kissed her on the mouth. It was only after Lin Ling grew up that she realized, &quot;Every time we hand in homework or do anything else, we have to go to his separate dormitory.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Things are buried deep in the hearts of the two girls. &quot;I know (that incident did) a lot of harm to my classmate, but until now I haven&#39;t dared to ask her. She is now married, and the matter has never been mentioned again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For twenty years, most of the victims licked their wounds silently. After the news that &quot;a primary school principal raped and molested 22 girls in 9 years&quot; attracted attention, some people worried on social platforms: What will happen to the children who have been harmed? They still have a long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Xuemei, the initiator of &quot;Girls Protection&quot; and deputy editor-in-chief of ifeng.com, told Southern Weekend reporters that after being sexually assaulted, children&#39;s psychology will change, even in the long term. Troubled, I hope that with the help of the local Women&#39;s Federation and other departments, the children can receive timely psychological intervention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She specifically reminded parents not to beat, scold or blame their children. &quot;This is not the child&#39;s fault. We need to make the child feel that the family is safe and that parents can accept talking and relying on them. If after such an incident, parents beat, scold and blame them, they will push the child into a more helpless situation. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Girls Protection&quot; project team has been to many rural schools across the country to conduct sexual assault prevention courses. Sun Xuemei found that the common problem currently is the lack of sex education, and many people talk about sexual perversion. However, it can be seen from the gradually increasing reporting rate that people&#39;s awareness is improving. &quot;Only when everyone&#39;s awareness increases and they pay attention to this problem, and (the problem) is exposed more and more, will it be solved faster.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The end of Zhang Longji’s criminal behavior was due to the call to the police by the victim’s family in June 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Lan recalled that at noon on the day of the incident, Zhang Longji drove away from school. Also disappearing was a female classmate from the school. &quot;After class, (I) saw that the girl was not there, so I told other teachers. I didn&#39;t know that until the next day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He heard from the girl’s sister that the girl tried her best to resist and was beaten with a heavy object by Zhang Longji and was seriously injured. The girl was sent to Jingning County Hospital, but her injuries were serious and she was sent to Lanzhou for medical treatment. Zhang Longji was later taken away by the police in Lanzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In November 2019, 30-year-old Yu Tong met Zhang Longji in the detention center, and the two stayed in the same cell for three months. After completing his sentence in 2023, he provided his release certificate to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the prison cell, Zhang Longji wore a red vest, handcuffs and shackles. Yu Tong said that &quot;inmates&quot; all knew that he was suspected of rape and child molestation. During that period, Zhang Longji was often bullied by his fellow prisoners and had to be moved from one cell to another. Another &quot;inmate&quot; Zhao Wuping also confirmed that &quot;people like him are often bullied in there.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Wuping entered the detention center for drunk driving in July 2019. He was &quot;headache&quot; about his situation and did not want to chat with other people. But he remembered that Zhang Longji&#39;s condition at the time was &quot;not bad&quot; and he said, &quot;He will be released after being sentenced to more than ten years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The seriousness of the matter obviously exceeded Zhang Longji&#39;s expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pingliang Intermediate Court sentenced Zhang Longji to death for rape and deprivation of political rights for life; for child molestation, he was sentenced to ten years in prison; several crimes were punished concurrently. ,Decided to implement the death penalty, deprivation of political rights for life. Zhang Longji once appealed, but the appeal was rejected by the Gansu Provincial High Court and the original death sentence was upheld, which was approved by the Supreme People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 7, 2023, the Pingliang Intermediate People’s Court followed the execution order issued by the President of the Supreme People’s Court, verified Zhang Longji’s identity, and escorted him to the execution ground. Execution by lethal injection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Zhang Longji and Sun Xuemei, pseudonyms are used in the article)&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家长罢课拒纳“问题学生”：为何开除与送专门学校不是选项？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261927]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some parents posted online that on November 23, 2023, Changtu County, Tieling City, Liaoning Province The Experimental Primary School transferred a student from Class 11, Grade 4, to Class 8 without communicating with the parent committee. The article stated that the student threatened the entire class when handing out mid-term exam papers, hugged the teacher&#39;s lap and cried and made a fuss. He also knelt down and prayed to the teacher not to tell his parents about the test results. After being rejected, he threatened and insulted the teacher, causing the head teacher to be hospitalized due to sudden illness. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents protested collectively and picked up their children early to start a class strike. On November 29, the local education bureau issued a notice stating that the primary school was transferring a student to a parallel class. Parents of the students who were transferred to the class showed resistance, and many students did not attend school. They reported the matter online. Changtu County Education Bureau and Experimental Primary School... decided after research to cancel the class adjustment plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this incident? First, it is necessary to explore the nature of the student&#39;s problem. If what the above parents said is true, then from the fact that the student threatens the whole class, begs the teacher, and threatens and insults the teacher, it seems that the student may have behavioral problems, but the specific problem is still difficult to determine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is not difficult to understand the position of the parents of Class 8: originally the class order and discipline were good, but suddenly a &quot;troublemaker&quot; and &quot;trouble maker&quot; came, making other children uneasy and affecting their learning. No one will welcome it, cause tensions, or even upset children&#39;s moods. If you can&#39;t turn them away before you come, it will be difficult to ask them to leave after they come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because a student in a class has behavioral problems or character problems, disrupts classroom order or bullies other students; or parents are overprotective of their children and have serious conflicts with other children and their parents. , As a result, other parents can&#39;t bear it anymore, and they &quot;go on strike&quot; in anger, go to the Education Bureau to petition, and complain online. This often happens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, parents of fifth graders at Hangzhou Wenlan Experimental School published an open letter online saying that a student named W was an overprotected child by his parents. If he had any disputes with teachers or classmates at school, his parents would directly They stormed schools and classrooms, and repeatedly threatened and abused the children, parents, and even teachers in extreme ways. For this reason, parents went on strike in anger. A situation report issued by the school stated that &quot;an incident occurred in Class 505 of our school where many students asked for leave but did not come to school to study.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the way the school and the local education bureau handle such incidents is nothing more than trying their best to mediate and persuade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changtu County Experimental Primary School gave up its plan to adjust classes, saying it &quot;will further optimize educational resources, rationally allocate teachers, and teach students in accordance with their aptitude.&quot; The implication is that the students with the problem will continue to remain in Class 11, but it seems that they will be replaced by teachers who are more resistant and more capable to tackle the problem. &quot;Currently, students have fully returned to school,&quot; and the problem has been temporarily resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the case of the strike at Hangzhou Wenlan Experimental School, a joint special class composed of the District Education Bureau and the District Public Security Bureau was established, and then a parent interview meeting was held to &quot;carefully listen to the parents&#39; feedback and demands.&quot; “Both parties actively communicated to eliminate differences, and after discussions, a preliminary consensus was reached.” Students who asked for leave “returned to school one after another” that afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are similar solutions so common? This is because the current Compulsory Education Law stipulates that students who violate the school management system shall be criticized and educated by the school and shall not be expelled (Article 27). Under such constraints, if there are &quot;problem children&quot; in a class who are considered unbearable by many parents, they can only tolerate it at the beginning. If they can&#39;t bear it anymore, they will use strikes, petitions, and open letters online to try to overcome the pressure of public opinion. Let the &quot;problem children&quot; transfer to another school; if they really can&#39;t be driven away, well-connected parents will consider transferring their children to another school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are many people on the Internet who say, and their voices are quite loud: Isn’t it enough to transfer “problem children” to vocational schools for correction? This simplifies the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, Article 6 of the Law on the Prevention of Juvenile Delinquency stipulates: The state shall strengthen the construction of specialized schools and provide specialized education to minors with serious bad behaviors. So, what constitutes serious bad behavior? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bad behavior defined in this law refers to &quot;behavior carried out by minors that is not conducive to their healthy growth&quot;, such as truancy and truancy for many times; associating with people with bad habits in society, organizing or Joining a gang that commits bad behavior, etc. Obviously, it is fine if bad behavior only harms oneself. The key is that many bad behaviors have negative externalities and will harm other children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 31 of the Law stipulates: Schools shall strengthen management and education for underage students who have bad behaviors and shall not discriminate; for those who refuse to correct or the circumstances are serious, the school may punish them according to the circumstances or take the following measures: Management education measures: provide discipline; require compliance with specific codes of conduct; require participation in specific special education; require participation in on-campus service activities; require psychological counseling and behavioral intervention from social workers or other professionals, etc. But obviously not including expulsion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called serious bad behavior refers to &quot;behavior committed by minors that is stipulated in the criminal law and not subject to criminal punishment because they are under the legal age of criminal responsibility, as well as behavior that seriously endangers society&quot;, such as fighting in groups, chasing , intercepting others, forcibly taking or arbitrarily damaging or occupying public or private property and other provocative and troublemaking behaviors; beating, insulting, threatening, or intentionally injuring others&#39; bodies, etc. So can someone with this kind of behavior be immediately sent to a vocational school? Neither. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 41 of the Law stipulates: For minors who have serious bad behavior, the public security organs may take the following corrective and educational measures according to the specific circumstances: admonish them; order them to apologize and compensate for losses; order them to declare repentance. ; Ordered to regularly report on activities; ordered to abide by specific behavioral norms and not to perform specific behaviors, contact specific people, or enter specific places; ordered to receive psychological counseling and behavioral modification; ordered to participate in social service activities, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a minor commits an act that seriously endangers society, the circumstances are egregious or causes serious consequences, or if a minor commits an act that seriously endangers society multiple times, or refuses to accept or cooperate with the corrective education measures stipulated in Article 41 above, Upon evaluation and approval by the Specialized Education Steering Committee, the education administrative department together with the public security organs may decide to send the student to a specialized school to receive specialized education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that students only disrupt classroom discipline and bully other students, which is not considered &quot;serious bad behavior&quot;. It is impossible to be expelled and it is impossible to go to a vocational school. However, this type of behavior is enough to cause great consequences. Externalities make other children and even teachers and parents miserable. Within the above framework, the problem is difficult to solve, and I am afraid it will still happen from time to time in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>