<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[小城千人围捕鳄鱼：已追回69条，仍有两条或在逃]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256981]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 17:31:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/598242ea15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/598242ea15. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Crocodile capture scene. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 15, 2023, the water in the crocodile farm was basically drained, and the bottom of the pond was silt A fishy smell gushed out. A pickup truck drove up from the night and stopped in the middle of the nearby road. In the truck was a freshly caught crocodile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Gui, a 43-year-old crocodile catcher, pulled the crocodile by its tail and dragged it out of the pickup truck with his team members. They were about to transfer the crocodile to the van, where three crocodiles were already tied up. The crocodile was dragged to the back of the truck, its limbs were tied to its sides, and its long mouth was tied with tape so that it could not open or close. Qiu Gui and three other team members wearing headlamps stood on both sides of the crocodile, holding its limbs and pushing upward together: &quot;One, two!&quot; The people standing in the carriage pulled the hemp rope around the crocodile&#39;s head and also Together they exerted upward force, and the crocodile successfully entered the &quot;cage&quot;. When untying the hemp rope, a crocodile in the carriage seemed to be very angry and threw its big head with its mouth tied tightly at the people on the side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by Typhoon Haikui, Maoming City, Guangdong Province suffered from heavy rains for days. On September 11, floods destroyed the fence of a crocodile farm in Luocun, the northern boundary, causing some crocodiles to escape. According to Nanfang+ news, there are a total of 71 crocodiles in the farm. As of September 16, a total of 69 crocodiles have been captured, and there have been no incidents of crocodile injuries. Currently, multiple search teams are still hunting the last two escaped crocodiles day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3846f4d486.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3846f4d486.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The farm where the crocodile escaped. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;51 sentinel points, 33 patrol teams&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A large number of crocodiles escaped Most are adult male crocodiles, and the species is Siamese crocodile. This is a crocodile species commonly found in breeding farms in Hainan, Guangdong and other places. According to relevant literature, there are no wild Siamese crocodiles in China, only breeding populations, which can be traded and operated with a license. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company owned by the crocodile farm where the incident occurred is the Guangdong Yufeng Crocodile Breeding Professional Cooperative, which was established in March 2019. Its legal representative is Xu Jinwang. With tens of thousands of crocodiles being farmed and more than 20 years of breeding experience, Mao celebrity Xu Jinwang is known as the &quot;Crocodile King&quot;. Xu Jinwang&#39;s wife, Ke Yiming, told Southern Weekend reporters that after the crocodile escaped, they were under great pressure and suffered a huge loss, amounting to two to three million yuan. &quot;The crocodile is very valuable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wu Liming, an 81-year-old villager in Luo Village, Beijie, the fish pond used by Xu Jinwang to breed crocodiles was rented to him four or five years ago, totaling more than 30 acres, with an annual rent of 2,000 yuan. /acre, rented for 18 years. Wu Liming told Southern Weekend reporters that after the crocodile escaped and the flood level had not receded, he called Xu Jinwang every day out of fear: &quot;Let him take care of it, (the crocodile) is very dangerous.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Ke Yiming explained that the flooding of the breeding farm was a natural disaster. &quot;We (the breeding farm) have done everything very safely. The floods there are so severe that we will not dare to raise them there in the future.&quot; On September 15, a Southern Weekend reporter saw at the scene , each crocodile pool is separated by a plastic baffle about 1.3 meters high. As to whether the use of plastic baffles can effectively prevent the crocodiles from escaping, Qiu Gui, a professional crocodile catcher with more than 20 years of experience, explained to Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;This The baffle is OK. As long as the crocodile can&#39;t see outside, it will stay in the crocodile pond.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The news of the crocodile&#39;s escape frightened 75-year-old villager Wu Yanxin: &quot;I&#39;m scared. Why aren&#39;t you afraid?&quot; Wu Yanxin lives in Dapo Village, Zhensheng Town, about 400 meters away from the crocodile farm. Although he was scared, Wu Yanxin had a way to comfort himself: as long as he didn&#39;t go into the water or go to the shore, &quot;crocodiles don&#39;t walk that fast on the ground.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the crocodile escaped, Wu Yanxin often cycled and ran along the road around Pengcun Lake, taking 70 minutes to run an 8-kilometer lap. This is the largest body of water around the crocodile pond. Standing on the road around the lake, Wu Yanxin can see the crocodiles living in the pond. After the crocodile escaped, Wu Yanxin could no longer ride around the lake. The road was surrounded by a 1.5-meter-high wire fence to prevent the crocodile from hurting anyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/333bc75667.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/333bc75667.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huanhu Road is surrounded by barbed wire. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workers who installed the protective net were Zhou Hui and his colleagues who were born in the 1990s. On September 17, Zhou Hui told Southern Weekend reporters that after the crocodile escaped, they began to install protective nets along Huanhu Road. It took about three or four days to complete the installation, and then spent several days reinforcing it. One morning around 1 a.m., he and his colleagues were installing a protective net on the road to the crocodile pond. About 20 meters away, a crocodile surfaced and opened its mouth, then sank into the water; another weighed three to four hundred pounds. The crocodiles were lying on the shore 50 meters away. Zhou Hui took a light and found two yellow eyes staring at them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yahong, the person in charge of supervision of the Crocodile Farm Residents Group, told Southern Weekend reporters that after the crocodile escaped, the village committee actively participated in catching the crocodile and arranged on-duty duty to ask the villagers not to go out and pay attention to safety. Wu Yahong said that when there were heavy rains in the past, he would remind the staff in the crocodile farm to pay attention to safety: &quot;The water has almost reached your crocodile pond, and the crocodiles have escaped. But this time the water is too big, and the crocodile pond has been soaked.&quot; ), the crocodile ran out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the adjacent Dapo Village Committee told Southern Weekend reporters that after the crocodile escaped, in order to ensure that there were no casualties, &quot;we launched There are more than 30 party members and volunteers, guarding various checkpoints 24 hours a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to capture the crocodile as soon as possible and ensure the safety of nearby residents, the 5-kilometer radius around the incident site is a key investigation area. A total of 51 outposts, 33 patrol teams, and nearly 1,000 staff were set up in the area to carry out arrests. On September 15, a militiaman on duty told Southern Weekend reporters that the day the crocodiles first escaped, the water level was still very high, and the farm was full of people. Everyone was busy pumping water and holding sandbags to block the water. &quot;If you are not afraid of the crocodiles appearing, then There are so many people, what are you afraid of, the special police are all armed with guns.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/fb508a3153.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;626&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/fb508a3153.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to find crocodiles, the farm conducts water surveys. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;56 crocodiles were caught The team&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the Maonan District Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, 40 of the 71 crocodiles in the crocodile farm were captured in the farm, and the remaining 31 may have escaped to the waters 5 kilometers surrounding the farm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three or four days after the crocodile escaped, Wu Yanxin could hear gunshots every day, with more than a dozen &quot;bang bang bang&quot; sounds. The nearest gunshot to him was on the night of September 14, when a crocodile weighing two to three hundred pounds was found in a small drainage ditch near his family&#39;s paddy field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shooting a crocodile in the water is not easy. &quot;When you shoot it, it goes into the water. It&#39;s not like those on the ground, where it stays in place.&quot; A special police officer holding a sniper rifle said. A colleague on the side gave him an idea, &quot;Someone has to fill in the gun.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/187650e8d2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/187650e8d2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;SWAT searches for an escaped alligator. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with shooting crocodiles in the water, Qiu Gui believes that finding crocodiles is the most important and most time-consuming link. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to find the escaped crocodiles, the local area used sonar detection, drone inspections, and even tied ducks to the shore to lure the crocodiles to prey. A staff member of the sonar team told a reporter from Southern Weekend that the difficulty in detecting crocodiles with sonar is that it is difficult to detect crocodiles when they are swimming. The sound produced by drones usually scares timid crocodiles. The duck trapping effect is even weaker. The water area within which the crocodile escapes is large and there are many fish and shrimps. The crocodile has no shortage of food at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Gui has his own methods after dealing with crocodiles for more than 20 years. In this arrest operation, including at the breeding farm, their team of six arrested a total of 56 animals, with the most on September 14, when 14 were captured. The remaining 13 were killed by special police and captured by crocodile catching teams from Zhanjiang, Yangjiang, Guangzhou and Foshan. Most of the crocodiles caught weighed more than 200 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Gui and his party usually go out at night, because crocodiles are more alert during the day and will quickly hide in the water after noticing any movement around them. At night, crocodiles often stay in one place and are relatively slow. You can catch them by moving slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike humans, crocodile eyes do not close from birth to death. Therefore, as long as you shine a flashlight at night, the yellow-glow eyes will reveal the location of the crocodile. At 2 a.m. on September 18, while searching for the last two crocodiles, Qiu Gui boarded the kayak again and searched for traces of crocodiles in Pengcun Lake. The night before, they found and captured three crocodiles here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Gui pointed the flashlight at the water and grass on the shore. He explained that the crocodile likes to come ashore at nine or ten o&#39;clock in the morning when the sun is getting warmer. Basking in the sun will make it easier for it to digest food in its stomach. A 200-pound crocodile can eat 10 pounds a day. After it is full, it will come ashore. If it is not frightened, it will stay until it has finished digesting and then go into the water to hunt. &quot;There is not much knowledge to find crocodiles, and there is no shortcut, just use a lamp to shine.&quot; Qiu Gui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crocodiles at night are easier to find and catch. After Qiu Gui and his party discovered the crocodile, they would carefully move the boat closer and stun the crocodile within one meter of the crocodile. &quot;After the stun, the crocodile&#39;s body seemed to be stiff.&quot; Taking advantage of the 10-15 minutes when the crocodile was unconscious, the capture team The crocodile man drags the crocodile onto the boat and binds its mouth and limbs as soon as possible. &quot;As long as you tie its mouth and don&#39;t let it open, the crocodile will be 100% controlled.&quot; Qiu Gui said that the most important thing is teamwork, and nothing can be done without tacit understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A tied up crocodile is equally dangerous. After the crocodile wakes up, its head and tail can still attack. If it hits the leg, &quot;it will break the leg directly, no joke.&quot; Qiu Gui said that the crocodile has an attack range. &quot;We usually stand in the middle of it, which is equivalent to its blind spot. But we should also stay 1.5 meters away from it, which will be safer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/eabb6219cc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/eabb6219cc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;A crocodile was captured near a fence. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Expand the water area to look for the last two&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Catching the crocodiles is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of September 15, a total of 58 crocodiles had been captured, and the remaining 13 had escaped. One of the focuses of the search that day was several fish ponds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fish pond is located in Helijing Village, only two to three hundred meters away from the crocodile farm. On September 15, the owner of a fish pond told Southern Weekend reporters that two crocodiles had been pulled into his fish pond. One was electrocuted and the other was shot. There may be crocodiles in the fish pond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the fish pond is three to four meters deep and there are many fish, methods such as electric shock, duck trapping and even shooting are ineffective. A staff member of the Maoming Emergency Management Bureau told a Southern Weekend reporter: &quot;The water is too deep to find the crocodiles. It would be best if they could be put into water about one meter deep.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, the village Negotiations between the committee and fish pond owners on the compensation plan after the water was released did not go smoothly. Cai Fang, the wife of the above-mentioned pond owner, told Southern Weekend reporters that tens of thousands of fry were put into her fish pond, as well as some fish feed. &quot;The total cost is tens of thousands of yuan. Now we propose to pump half of the water and compensate for 2,000 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Fang does not agree with the compensation plan. She believes that if half of the water is drained, the remaining fish will He died of lack of oxygen and was worried that the crocodile would not be found hiding in the mud at the bottom of the pond. &quot;What if someone is bitten later, will I, the pond owner, be responsible?&quot; Cai Fang hoped that a thorough search could be carried out and the pond water could be drained. , make sure there are no crocodiles in the pond, and also handle the fish in the pond casually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After several rounds of negotiations, on the evening of September 15, the two parties reached a compensation agreement at a price of 1,000 yuan per mu of water surface. Early the next morning, an excavator dug up the edge of the pond. After searching, no trace of the crocodile was found in the fish pond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of September 16, a total of 69 crocodiles have been captured, but there are still two cases with no clues. After another two days of searching, this data has not changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/9f921aceea.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/9f921aceea.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The capture team searched the lake at night. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of September 18, Qiu Gui and his party returned to the crocodile farm. They suspected that the two crocodiles May have died during breeding. &quot;Crocodiles are the most ferocious during the mating season. They will fight for the right to mate. If they fight too hard, some crocodiles will die.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of September 19, the scope of the crocodile search The crocodile hunter&#39;s team began to search along the lower reaches of Pengcun Lake, one kilometer away from the crocodile farm. The search was still fruitless all night long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the last two are not found, we will not stop the work.&quot; said the above-mentioned Maoming Emergency Management Bureau staff member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Zhou Hui and Cai Fang are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被指定居所监视居住者离世：公安称其余同案人员“不应当追究刑责”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256978]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/sA6bxukyIFAQtylG7MLw3gnjOtDGltCBo6F8Vjfv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/sA6bxukyIFAQtylG7MLw3gnjOtDGltCBo6F 8Vjfv. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251184&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Qinrui was once placed under residential surveillance at a designated location in Xinle Hotel. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of September 19, 2023, Bao Qinrui has been dead for 426 days, but his wife Bao Linlin and her family have not yet received the conclusion of the death investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Qinrui was from Shijiazhuang City, Hebei Province. He was once placed under residential surveillance at a designated location for picking quarrels and provoking trouble. He died 13 days later at the age of 33. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residential surveillance is a coercive measure stipulated in the Criminal Procedure Law. Residential surveillance at a designated residence is a special situation: when the criminal suspect or defendant has no fixed residence, or the case is suspected of crimes endangering national security or terrorist activities, it can be implemented in a designated residence. Commonly used locations in practice include hotels, guest houses, hospitals, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Bao Qinrui has a house in Yuhua District, Shijiazhuang, he was still placed under residential surveillance in Xinle City (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Shijiazhuang). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Medical records show that the person who accompanied Bao Qinrui to the hospital was a staff member of the Xinle City Public Security Bureau, and the &quot;work unit or home address&quot; column was filled in with Xinle Hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the reply from the Xinle City Public Security Bureau to Bao Qinrui’s father, on July 19, 2022, the day of the incident, the Shijiazhuang City Procuratorate intervened in the matter and investigated Bao Qinrui’s death. In the meantime, his body has been stored in the Xinle City Funeral Home and has not been cremated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The investigation into the cause of death has stalled&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bao Linlin remembers that in the early morning of July 7, 2022, Bao Qinrui was taken away by the police at his home in Yuhua District Walk. Later, she received a notice mailed by the Xinle City Public Security Bureau, which stated that Bao Qinrui was placed under residential surveillance at a designated residence because he was &quot;suspected of picking quarrels and provoking trouble.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Linlin saw her husband again at the Xinle City Funeral Home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rescue records of Xinle City Hospital record that at 21:38 on July 19, 2022, the hospital received an emergency call, and Bao Qinrui was subsequently sent to the hospital. After more than three hours of continuous resuscitation, Bao Qinrui was still unconscious, without spontaneous breathing and heartbeat, and the hospital declared him dead. Xinle City 110 police officers signed at 1:38 a.m. the next day and contacted the Xinle City Funeral Home. The hospital recommended an autopsy to further clarify the cause of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight months after Bao Qinrui’s death, on the morning of March 30, 2023, the Shijiazhuang City Procuratorate arranged for an autopsy on Bao Qinrui’s body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Qinrui’s father Bao Jiye recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that on June 19, 2023, the Shijiazhuang Municipal Procuratorate presented him with an autopsy report, which concluded that “mechanical injury was excluded as a cause of death.” &quot;, it excludes death caused by poisoning, and does not rule out sinus node disease causing cardiac electrical activity disorder and cardiac arrest leading to death.&quot; Bao Jiye did not sign the report and applied for a second autopsy to be performed by an agency commissioned by the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation into the cause of Bao Qinrui’s death has stalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Jiye asked Cao Zhi, the prosecutor of the Shijiazhuang City Procuratorate who participated in the investigation. Cao Zhi replied that a second autopsy needs to be applied to the Xinle City Public Security Bureau. Xinle City Public Security Bureau staff replied to Bao Jiye that this application should be communicated to the Shijiazhuang City Procuratorate, &quot;The Public Security Bureau is also a party, and you don&#39;t believe it even if we do an autopsy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 18, 2023, Cao Zhi said in an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend that there is currently no investigation conclusion on Bao Qinrui’s death. As for whether a second autopsy can be performed, &quot;this is an internal investigation process and cannot be announced to the outside world.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Regulations on Handling the Death of Persons in Detention Centers&quot; jointly issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the Ministry of Public Security, and the Ministry of Civil Affairs stipulate that when institutions commissioned by the public security organs and procuratorates conduct autopsies, the opinions of the deceased&#39;s close relatives should be solicited. Close relatives who request to entrust another institution to conduct an autopsy should be allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if a person dies during residential surveillance at a designated location, there are no clear regulations yet on whether family consent is required when an autopsy is commissioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Co-defendant&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Bailed&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bao Linlin still doesn’t know about Bao Qinrui What specific behavior is suspected of provoking quarrels and provoking trouble? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day as Bao Qinrui, there were eight other people who were placed under residential surveillance at a designated location - Bao Qinrui&#39;s father Bao Jiye, brother Bao Shaorui, uncles Bao Jizhong and Bao Jitao, and his cousin. Diba Zhuorui and three other villagers from the same village were all suspected of provoking quarrels and causing trouble, and the execution location was also Xinle Hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a month after Bao Qinrui passed away, on September 1, 2022, Bao Jiye and Bao Shaorui were released on bail pending trial. On September 28, the other six people, including Bao Jizhong and Bao Jitao, were released on bail pending trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All eight people said they were beaten and given electric shocks while under residential surveillance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days after Bao Qinrui’s death, on the afternoon of July 22, 2022, Bao Jitao, who was still under residential surveillance, was sent to Xinle City Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital for treatment due to fever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Bao Jitao&#39;s hospitalization record, when he was admitted to the hospital, he had &quot;pain in both calves for 3-4 days, pain in the left chest and ribs for 1 day, skin damage and scabs on the left knee, and flakes on the right lower limb.&quot; Bruises and red rashes can be seen on both calves.” After experiencing chest pain, he was diagnosed with left rib fracture after examination. After being hospitalized for 7 days, Bao Jitao was discharged from the hospital on July 29. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 19, 2023, the Xinle City Public Security Bureau lifted the bail pending trial for eight people on the grounds that &quot;it was found that criminal liability should not be pursued.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The whistleblower expressed a &quot;reversal&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the notice of release on bail pending trial that Bao Jiye received, it was written that the case he was involved in was &quot;5• 25 project&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Jiye and Bao Shaorui recalled that during the residential surveillance period, the police asked them whether they had beaten Sun Huiqiang and others who came to ask for wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Qinrui and other nine people involved in the case are all from Nantaying Village, Gaoyi County, Shijiazhuang City. Before the incident, Bao Qinrui worked in the Gaoyi County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau. Bao Jiye runs a ceramic tile factory in Gaoyi, and Bao Shaorui, Bao Jitao, and Bao Zhuorui all work in the factory. Bao Jizhong is the party branch secretary of Nantaying Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Huiqiang is a contractor who participated in the construction of Bao Jiye’s ceramic tile factory in 2013 and 2014. He told Southern Weekend reporters that on May 22, 2022, at a worker’s home, police from the Yuhua District Public Security Bureau took notes on him and five other workers involved in the construction. At that time, he and the workers said that in the spring of 2014, they went to the ceramic tile factory to ask for wages and were beaten by Bao Jiye, Bao Jizhong and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on September 12, 2023, Sun Huiqiang said in an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter that he gave false testimony at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sun Huiqiang&#39;s account, he and Bao Jiye did have a financial dispute at the beginning of 2022. There was a discrepancy of 200,000 yuan between the two parties regarding the amount of project funds, and they were in the negotiation stage at that time. Bao Moumou (pseudonym), a villager from the same village as Bao Jiye, contacted him and said that he had conflicts with Bao Jizhong, who served as the party branch secretary in the village. Bao promised that as long as Sun Hui did what he said, not only would the project money be returned, but the amount would even be higher than what he asked for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After learning about Bao Qinrui’s incident, Sun Huiqiang and the workers made new records to the public security organs in September 2022 and June 2023, re-explaining the situation and showing that they had not been raped by Bao Jiye or Bao Jiye. Bao Ji Zhong and others beat him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2023, Bao Jiye noticed that reports against him for &quot;criminal involvement&quot; appeared on the short video platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of them is 66-year-old Zhang Shuke, who also had some disputes with Bao Jiye over the amount of project funds. On April 21, 2023, a user with the online name &quot;Dou E Yuan&quot; posted a video on the short video platform entitled &quot;Real people and true stories will never lie&quot;: Zhang Shuke held his ID card and told, &quot;Real-name reporting is very high. A triad gang in Yi County, headed by Bao Jiye and Bao Jizhong, maliciously owed me 600,000 yuan for a project through fraud. When I went to demand the account, I was beaten and insulted many times, and threatened to be beaten to death if I went back to the factory to demand the account. Buried alive”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bao Jiye sued Zhang Shuke for infringement of reputation rights. On June 7, 2023, the Gaoyi County Court conducted mediation on the case. The two parties reached an agreement: Zhang Shuke deleted the above video and recorded a video to apologize to Bao Jiye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this video can still be searched on the short video platform. Zhang Shuke explained to Southern Weekend reporters that what was said in the video was not true and that he was not beaten by Bao Jiye. The video was recorded at Bao&#39;s suggestion. At that time, Bao Moumou told him, &quot;If you talk about the seriousness of the matter, someone will take care of you. If you tell the truth, no one will take care of you.&quot; After the court mediation, he contacted Bao Moumou to delete the video, but Bao Moumou could not delete it either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 18, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter contacted Bao. The statement he provided was different from that of Sun Huiqiang and Zhang Shuke. He said that after Bao Jiye, Bao Jizhong and others were released on bail pending trial, they used &quot;coercion and inducement&quot; to bribe the informants and get them to retract their confessions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is “residence”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After his son passed away, Bao Jiye was confused as to why he was placed under residential surveillance at a designated residence by the Xinle City Public Security Bureau as he was from Gaoyi County, Shijiazhuang City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residential surveillance is one of the five coercive measures stipulated in the Criminal Procedure Law. Chen Yongsheng, a professor at Peking University Law School, explained that the coercive intensity of the five types of coercive measures is a ladder structure. From weak to strong, they are summons, bail pending trial, residential surveillance, detention and arrest. As a transitional measure, residential surveillance means that criminal suspects or defendants do not need to be completely detained like detention or arrest, but they are required not to leave their residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For criminal suspects or defendants who meet the conditions for arrest, residential surveillance measures can be taken under three circumstances. One is due to their own factors, serious illness, pregnancy, etc.; the other is the special nature of the case or the handling of the case. necessary; third, the detention period has expired and the case has not been settled. In order to avoid extended detention, residential surveillance is implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residential surveillance at a designated location is a special case of residential surveillance. The Criminal Procedure Law stipulates two types of circumstances under which residential surveillance can be carried out at a designated residence: the criminal suspect or defendant has no fixed residence, or the case is suspected of crimes endangering national security or terrorist activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Interpretation of the Criminal Procedure Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; compiled by the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress explains &quot;residence&quot; as meaning that the criminal suspect or defendant lives in the city or county where the case-handling agency is located. Legal residence for work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nine people involved in the case all have residences in Gaoyi County, and Bao Qinrui and Bao Shaorui also have properties in Yuhua District. Chen Yongsheng believes that as long as the parties concerned own real estate in Shijiazhuang City, according to legal provisions, they do not meet the requirements for designated residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 15, 2023, a deputy director of the Xinle City Public Security Bureau told Bao Jiye that the case was handled by the Yuhua Branch of the Shijiazhuang City Public Security Bureau, the Xinle City Public Security Bureau and the Gaoyi County Public Security Bureau. The three parties formed a task force to jointly handle the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But why did the Xinle City Public Security Bureau ultimately place Bao Qinrui and other nine people under residential surveillance in a designated location? On September 18, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter contacted Guo Jie, director of the Xinle City Public Security Bureau, via text message. As of press time, no reply had been received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D重现利比亚极端洪水，上万人身亡，大量高楼被夷为平地]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256966]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从奥本海默到“核武之王”，这70年经历了什么？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256964]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/r6FiloQ2QNq1q67PqYHr7zhROxZiFIGrf2SP6ELu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/r6FiloQ2QNq1q67PqYHr7zhROxZiFI Grf2SP6ELu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251162&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 15, 1957, local time, in Princeton, the United States, the creator of the atomic bomb, Robert Oppenheimer. A new film about Oppenheimer&#39;s life and his leadership in creating the world&#39;s first atomic bomb during World War II will be released in theaters on July 21, 2023, local time. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the summer movies, &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; is one of the most eye-catching ones. The protagonist in the film is Julius Robert Oppenheimer, a genius Jewish scientist known as the &quot;Father of the Atomic Bomb&quot;. His &quot;work&quot; directly changed the face of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, as the conflict between Russia and Ukraine continues to escalate, at a critical moment when the Ukrainian army launches a large-scale counterattack, Russia demonstrated a powerful weapon-the &quot;Sarmat&quot; land-based intercontinental ballistic missile. This giant intercontinental missile has been put on combat readiness to prepare for possible crises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From Oppenheimer to &quot;Sarmat&quot;, what has happened in the past 70 years? Let&#39;s review the history of nuclear weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Oppenheimer&#39;s &quot;Legacy&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Oppenheimer, a name closely associated with the atomic bomb and the &quot;Manhattan Project.&quot; This Jewish genius scientist has shown extraordinary talents since he was a child. In his childhood, he was influenced by his mother and dabbled in various fields such as art, literature, philosophy, history, science and language. The youngest member of the Mineral Club, he graduated with first place from Fieldston School of Arts and Sciences in New York at the age of 18 (many political, business and cultural celebrities in the United States came from this school) and was admitted to the Department of Chemistry at Harvard University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from college, Oppenheimer first entered the famous Cavendish Laboratory of the University of Cambridge in England. After that, Oppenheimer was taught by the founder of quantum mechanics and the winner of the 1954 Nobel Prize in Physics. Born’s recommendation led him to the famous University of Göttingen. In 1927, Oppenheimer received his PhD for his research in quantum mechanics and decided to return to the United States not long after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of his life was presiding over the United States&#39; nuclear weapons project, the &quot;Manhattan Project.&quot; As the commander-in-chief of the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot;, which cost US$2.5 billion and involved more than 500,000 people at its peak, Oppenheimer fully demonstrated his scientific literacy and management skills. In the movie, Oppenheimer called the project a &quot;gamble&quot; - he won the bet, and the United States also won the bet: at 5:30 in the morning on July 16, 1945, the first atomic bomb in human history was dropped on Los Angeles A successful explosion in the Alamos Desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the rest of his life, Oppenheimer suffered from humiliation and trouble because of this project that brought him great fame. The movie &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; vividly reproduces how he was persecuted by politicians represented by McCarthyism and General Strauss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 18, 1967, Oppenheimer died of throat cancer at the age of 63. What legacy did he leave to the world in the half century that followed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of early 2020, data from the Stockholm Peace Research Institute shows that the United States, Russia, the United Kingdom, France and other countries possess approximately 13,400 nuclear weapons, of which 3,720 have been deployed with combat troops, and approximately 1,800 of them are on high alert. . These nuclear weapons are specifically carried by a variety of delivery systems, including land- and sea-based long-range ballistic missiles, heavy bombers, fighter-bombers, air- and sea-launched cruise missiles, air defense and missile defense interceptor missiles, torpedoes, and depth charges . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hans Christensen, director of the &quot;Nuclear Information Project&quot; of the Federation of American Scientists, believes that both the United States and Russia possess very large nuclear arsenals, backed by short-range tactical nuclear forces, including intercontinental ballistic missiles, Sea-launched ballistic missiles and aircraft capable of carrying nuclear weapons constitute the &quot;trinity&quot; of long-range strategic nuclear forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some other countries have &quot;two-in-one&quot; medium-range nuclear forces and/or long-range nuclear forces (that is, they have any two of the three elements of the &quot;trinity&quot;). Some are transitioning to the &quot;Trinity&quot;, and there are rumors that Israel may already have the &quot;Trinity&quot; nuclear power. In addition, Pakistan and India possess short-range nuclear weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that after 70 years of development, nuclear weapons have not only changed the form of military struggle, but also had a profound impact on the development of human society and the international strategic pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The birth of the &quot;King of Nuclear Weapons&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Sarmat&quot; intercontinental ballistic missile was born in a time of crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the disintegration of the Soviet Union, Russia, which inherited its legacy, is not comparable to the Soviet Union in terms of armed force building. Unlike the Soviet Union, Russia is a resource-based country and therefore far inferior to its rival NATO in terms of conventional weapons. Nuclear power has therefore increasingly become the core of Russia&#39;s military power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Land-based nuclear forces are the foundation and pillar of Russia’s “trinity” nuclear forces. Russia&#39;s nuclear power was inherited from the Soviet Union. The three old intercontinental ballistic missile systems of SS-18 &quot;Satan&quot;, SS-19 &quot;Dagger&quot; and SS-25 &quot;Topol&quot; installed by the Strategic Rocket Force account for half of Russia&#39;s land-based nuclear weapons delivery vehicles. As mentioned above, these three old missile systems will reach the end of their service life. Once decommissioned, it will have a huge impact on the stability of Russia&#39;s strategic nuclear forces. Therefore, Russia decided to develop a new intercontinental ballistic missile to replace the SS-18 that is about to be retired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, the &quot;Sarmat&quot; intercontinental ballistic missile was developed by the Makeev Design Bureau. It conducted ejection tests in December 2017 and March 2018 and achieved success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of performance, this &quot;national weapon&quot; that Russia has high hopes for is really amazing. &quot;Sarmat&quot; is about 35 meters long, about 3 meters in diameter, has a take-off weight of about 200 tons, a payload of up to 10 tons, and a range of up to 17,000 kilometers. The hit accuracy is about 200 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; adopts a cold launch scheme. During launch, a gunpowder accumulator is used to eject the missile to a height of 20-30 meters above the launch silo, and then the missile ignites itself and takes off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; can carry up to 10 heavy or 15 light independently targeted separately guided nuclear warheads, or 24 &quot;Vanguard&quot; hypersonic boost glide bombs, which can target different targets Deliver devastating strikes and identify attacks from multiple targets. When carrying 10 submissive warheads, the yield of each warhead reaches 750,000 tons of TNT. The missile warhead adopts a variety of advanced penetration technologies, such as stealth technology and materials, separately guided multiple warheads and decoy bombs, hypersonic boost-glide warheads, and maneuverable and flexible orbit-changing capabilities. Its strike power is equivalent to 1,600 times that of the atomic bomb exploded in Hiroshima. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; has three unique skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, hit far. This type of missile has a range of 17,000 kilometers. The ultra-long range allows this missile to be launched from any area in Russia and can effectively hit predetermined targets around the world. It is speculated that the &quot;Sarmat&quot; can fly over the Antarctic, completely bypassing all current U.S. missile defense systems, and strike against the United States. Others speculate that it has partial orbital bombing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to play skillfully. This cleverness is reflected in the super defense penetration ability.在现代战争中，地对地导弹的突防能力日益成为衡量导弹综合技术水平的重要指标。该型导弹外形设计和涂料上采用了隐身技术及材料，导弹助推段较短，增大了敌方雷达和卫星发现、跟踪并实施拦截的难度。强大的动力使其具备超远的射程，能够飞越两极实施攻击，甚至可能具备部分轨道轰炸能力，可最大限度避开反导系统。导弹可携带十余枚分导式弹头，同时配合使用多个诱饵弹头，大幅提高反导系统的辨识难度和自身的突防概率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，“萨尔马特”还可携载“先锋”高超声速滑翔弹头，这种弹头具备极快的速度和超强的变轨能力，敌方防空和反导系统几乎无法拦截。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是打得准。 “萨尔马特”采用惯性制导、星光制导和格罗纳斯卫星制导的复合制导方式。三种方式相互结合、优势互补，将导弹命中精度缩小至约150米，而采用惯性制导方式的SS-18导弹命中精度为350米。打击精度的提高就是打击威力的提高，在这方面，“萨尔马特”做得非常出色，处于世界先进水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“萨尔马特”是一款液体燃料导弹。对于弹道导弹而言，使用固体燃料和液体燃料的差别在于比推力、毒性、安全性、易控制性方面。液体燃料比固体燃料比推力大，因此，使用液体燃料的弹道导弹段数比固体燃料少一级。而燃料的加注需要较长时间，因此不太适合作为核反击的手段使用——更适合进行“先发制人”的核打击，这无形中又增加了对北约的威慑力度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;核武器的未来&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作为地球上最具毁灭性的力量，核武器的发展在未来将呈现出几个趋势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，投掷核弹头的手段将向高超声速导弹发展。随着现代导弹防御系统的不断成熟演进，如何提高核导弹的突防能力已经成为一个重要问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在当前的装备中，高超声速导弹这种新概念武器开始脱颖而出。高超声速技术是指飞行速度超过5倍声速的飞行器技术，是21世纪航空航天技术的制高点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高超声速导弹的突出优势主要体现在3个方面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是它基本在大气高层飞行，飞行高度仅有30-80公里，末段高度可能只有20多公里，极大地影响了传统弹道导弹防御系统的早期预警雷达的探测能力。以美“铺路爪”为代表的早期预警雷达对远程和洲际导弹的探测距离高达数千公里，但对数十公里高度飞行的高超声速武器的探测距离只有数百公里。因此，弹道导弹防御系统对这类飞行器的防御效果大打折扣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是由于它在大气层内受控飞行，相比传统弹道导弹呆板的弹道，其具备不错的机动能力。加上高超声速的速度，导致对其拦截的难度大幅度上升，进一步削弱了传统弹道导弹防御系统的拦截能力。或者说，高超声速滑翔飞行器显著提高了突防能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高超声速滑翔飞行器还可结合传统弹道导弹使用，这样的结合虽然提高了飞行中段被拦截的危险，但大幅度提高了导弹的实际射程。这种技术趋势在“萨尔马特”导弹身上已经表现得非常明显。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未来，深海将有可能会成为核武器投射的重要空间。深海由于其特殊的物理特性，雷达波无法穿透，因此开展军事行动非常隐蔽。俄罗斯开发的“波塞冬”核鱼雷就是基于这种逻辑进行研发的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据称，“波塞冬”最大时速将超过200千米（约110节），最大下潜深度超过1000米。在水下具备如此高的航速，无法对其实施有效拦截，目前服役的最快的核潜艇的最大时速为35节，西方国家装备最先进的鱼雷最大速度为55节，这样使得现有的鱼雷武器无法拦截“波塞冬”。该鱼雷能搭载200万吨TNT当量的核弹头或常规弹头。在敌方海岸附近爆炸时，可引发巨大的海啸，对港口、城市等造成毁灭性打击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经推算，其能够形成跨幅达550千米，最大浪高500米的巨大海啸冲击，任何停泊在港口中的船舶都无法幸存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界上第一颗原子弹在试验场成功爆炸后，奥本海默曾引用印度教经文《薄伽梵歌》中的一句话：现在我变成了死亡，世界的毁灭者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着70年的发展，导弹技术的进步将倒逼反导技术进一步提升。高能激光、电磁炮等新概念武器将有可能运用到导弹防御体系中去。人类战争将因此拉开又一轮攻防博弈的序幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而片中奥本海默与爱因斯坦的对话，显示出对个人命运和未来的迷茫，依然没有答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为上海政法学院东北亚研究中心副主任）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年轻人买金，老年人卖金？广州市民卖1公斤套现44万多元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256960]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 14:30:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“上个月收了一单，1公斤，给了他44万多元。”一位从事黄金回收十几年的业内人士说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，国内黄金零售市场价格连续上涨，一度冲破每克600元，关于金价等话题连上热搜，至今消费者的热情依然不减，在买金热之下，黄金回收市场同样迎来卖金热。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月18日工作日，南都记者走访了广州荔湾区长寿西路黄金批发商圈以及广州天河区商超，看到仍有不少人前去咨询或购买黄金，当天金价比上周降了，且线上线下、不同品牌的黄金回收价格均不同，有较大差异。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，近期买金的年轻人居多，尤为青睐每颗售价500元上下、重量为1克的金豆豆并作为储蓄方式，曾引起热议。值得留意的是，经走访还发现，如今有不少中老年人卖金。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“都是四五十岁的人来卖”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月18日中午1点左右，广州荔湾区的长寿西路，挂满了“回收金银首饰”“黄金高价回收”等灯牌招牌，街道十字路口，不乏匆忙走进金店的年轻人，以及捂着小包进店四处观望的中老年人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深圳水贝被称为黄金珠宝市场的“晴雨表”，位于长寿西路这条黄金批发商圈的恒泰珠宝是深圳水贝的广州分店，记者发现，半小时内，店内消费者人数一直保持在20人以上，多围坐在展示柜询问及购买金饰，一排卖金豆豆等克数较小的金饰，另一排是克数较大的金镯等，“我们准备结婚了，趁午休来买，今天（9月18日）价格比之前降了一点。”一对年轻人正在购买金镯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/82a468ff6fffb6646188ca3ce6d49589.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1383&quot; height=&quot;1086&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/82a468ff6fffb6646188ca3ce6d49589.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251166&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广州荔湾区的长寿西路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;店内一角的黄金回收处，有一面电子屏显示持续波动的盘价：黄金回购468.98元，当日最高价471.72元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“去年年底回收的价格就已达400多元。”据该店的工作人员介绍，当天全店金价统一是471元，回收金条或黄金板料价是468元，而回收黄金饰品要少5元，按照463元来算，比周末跌了2元。目前市面上绝大部分黄金板料是以一公斤为主，而诸如金豆豆、手镯等属于黄金饰品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;半小时左右，已有两位50岁以上的市民前来询问黄金回收行情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“最近卖金的人要排队排到外面，整个街上都是来卖金的人。”一位从事黄金回收十几年的业内人士，同样在黄金批发商圈开了一家专门做黄金回收的珠宝店，当天，他同样按照463元回收黄金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“回收克数多，回收价还能谈。”这位业内人士表示，这半个月涨到了460元以上，上周回收价最高去到每克479元，维持了半天时间，“上个月收了一单，单价440多元，1公斤，给了他44万多元。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;半个月左右的时间，回收价从每克440多元涨至460多元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，国内黄金零售市场价格连续上涨，带动回收业务增长，据该业内人士表示，当天他回收了1单，最近十天已经做20多单，“都是四五十岁的人，没有年轻人来卖。”上述业内人士说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;品牌金饰售卖回收价差百元以上&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;而与批发市场不同的是，广州天河区商超的回收市场较冷淡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下午3点左右，位于天河区的天河城基本每家黄金品牌店内均有人在选购，不同品牌店的黄金挂牌价不同，均在每克600元以上，部分达到每克610元，不过基本会有20-40元不等的价格优惠，据现场多位工作人员表示，金价比上周最高峰降了几元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而对于回收服务，仅少数品牌提供且回收价格偏低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据天河城中国黄金店的工作人员介绍，优惠后的金价是每克568元，回收价是每克405元，来卖的人比较少，“今天（9月18日）没有人回收。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而金至尊黄金售价是每克609元，仅回收投资金条，当日按430元回收。老凤祥、周大福则没有现场回收服务，其中，周大福黄金售价是每克608元，回收价是451元，据周大福的一位工作人员介绍，本店不能回收，要去北京路的门店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/cf496b79e899c0812c38fc1f670143aa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/cf496b79e899c0812c38fc1f670143aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广州天河城周大福店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了线下平台，不少电商平台也提供黄金回收服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者随机在淘宝、天猫等平台搜索“广州黄金回收”，选取4家销量在1000+付款的店铺，并客服发起询问，均表示回收价是每克465元，同城可以上门回收，当场打款；而店铺在其他城市的，需要在线上评估鉴定，消费者拍下店铺的链接并邮寄给商家，商家签收核对克数后，打款给消费者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见，线上线下、不同品牌的黄金饰品回收价格均不同，且有较大差异，对于批发市场，普遍比售卖的金价少8-10元；对于商超的品牌店，则相差百元以上；而线上的回收价则比线下批发市场的还能多2元。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;部分商超换购&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;需补近千元&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我刚刚接待一位顾客来换购。”记者在走访商超品牌还发现，多家品牌店虽然不回收黄金，只可以以旧换新来换购，且方式复杂，但有不少前去咨询或者换购成自己喜欢款式的消费者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;换购，就是将消费者手中的黄金产品按现有金价折价后，按现有售价，购买店内商品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/086b9e703a353149adb07af4c5f76fde.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/086b9e703a353149adb07af4c5f76fde.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广州荔湾区的长寿西路恒泰珠宝店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据老凤祥的工作人员介绍，若是非该品牌的黄金要换购，按照该品牌当天黄金挂牌价每克608元计算，要换购的每克折价30元，克数也要打9折，购买的克数增加30%。换句话说，若是你有10克黄金来换购，即原来是6080元，需要按照9克578元来计算价格，即5202元，并且要另外加3克的价格，即1824元，换购的总价就是7026元。也就是说，需要最低补946元才能换购，且手工费另算。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样，中国黄金、周大福等门店对于换购均有不同的折价。其中，中国黄金工作人员表示，若是非该品牌的黄金要换购，每克补40块钱差价，不用收手工费，换购种类和数量任选；另据周大福工作人员介绍，则有两种方案，若是有10克黄金来换购，一是换购比10克更重的产品，且按每克折价85元计算；二是以当天售卖价，换购克数是两倍的产品，即20克。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在长寿西路这条黄金批发商圈内，记者同样也发现不少消费者换购黄金产品。9月18日午间，两位50岁左右的广州市民带着10.06克金链子前去换款式走进金店，金店外挂着招牌“黄金以旧换新，一克换一克”。据介绍，该金链子是按照回收价463元加15%手工费进行收费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽十元“盒饭姐”爆火后流泪，围观的边界感在哪？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[苹果“芯”，闭环未完成丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256950]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 11:57:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/EF18nz4G745NrZGbfXK5vE46XmfTmtmdvfpRt0BX.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1423&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/EF18nz4G745NrZGbfXK5vE46XmfTmtmdvfpRt0BX.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251156&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;通讯&amp;amp;芯片&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.qualcomm.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1351/qualcomm-announces-agreement-with-apple-for-chip-supply&quot;>;&lt;strong>;高通与苹果达成芯片供应三年协议&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月11日，高通宣布和苹果已达成新协议，高通将为苹果在2024年、2025年和2026年推出的iPhone供应骁龙系列5G调制解调器及射频系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日苹果发布iPhone 15系列，带来全系灵动岛、USB-C接口、4800万主摄，其中iPhone 15 Pro及iPhone 15 Pro Max升级搭载全球首款3nm工艺制程芯片、6核图像处理器。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：iPhone的基带芯片长期与高通捆绑，2010年苹果在iPhone4上首次引入高通3G/4G基带产品，2011年起，高通成为iPhone基带独家供应商，并从销售价格中抽取5%作为专利授权费。2018年前后，双方在5G基带芯片续约谈判中爆发争端，并相互向对方发起专利诉讼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;同时，苹果公司也试图打造自研芯片闭环，2019年7月以10亿美元收购英特尔大部分的手机基带芯片业务，2021年3月在慕尼黑投建全新的欧洲半导体实验室，首期投资10亿欧元。根据2019年苹果与高通达成的为期6年的许可协议，苹果将在2024年后停止向高通采购5G基带芯片。不过从此次供应协议看，尽管目前苹果3nm制程芯片领先商用，自研基带芯片仍然在路上，还不能解绑高通。（唐家乐）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1973239/000119312523216983/d393891df1.htm&quot;>;ARM在纳斯达克上市&lt;/a>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月14日，软银集团旗下芯片设计公司ARM正式在纳斯达克挂牌上市，股票代码为“ARM”，本次共计发行9550万股美国存托股票。IPO后，日本软银集团仍保留该公司约90%的股份。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021-2023财年，ARM的研发投入金额为8.14亿美元、9.55亿美元、11.33亿美元；收入分别为20.27亿美元、27.03亿美元、26.79亿美元。ARM的收入主要包括两部分：授权许可（license）和版税/特许权使用费（royalty）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：ARM成立于1990年，最初是由Acorn Computers、Apple Computer和VLSI Technology 联合投资成立，此后几经资本市场沉浮，直到2016年被软银收购。目前大多数智能手机、电脑、智能穿戴设备等电子消费产品，芯片都是基于ARM架构设计。按照ARM自己的数据，自发布以来，共有2500亿颗基于ARM架构的芯片出货，2023财年内有超过300亿颗基于ARM架构的芯片出货，ARM生态圈共有1500万名开发者。ARM上市首日收盘价比发行价上涨25%，市值高达650亿美元。随着人工智能的崛起，算力为王的新时代来临，同样也是ARM的新机遇。（唐家乐）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/open-networks-ecosystem-competition-successful-projects&quot;>;&lt;strong>;英国8800万英镑用于&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;O&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;pen&amp;nbsp;RAN&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;计划&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月14日，英国政府宣布为19个项目提供8800万英镑(1.09亿美元)的资金，以在主要城市中心、标志性体育场馆和海滨度假胜地，展示开放无线接入网络(Open Radio Access Network ，简称Open&amp;nbsp;RAN)的潜力，实现更好的移动服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些项目来自Open Networks Ecosystem（ONE）竞赛中的获胜者，该竞赛是英国政府斥资2.5亿英镑（3.12亿美元）的5G电信供应链多元化战略（&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/5g-supply-chain-diversification-strategy&quot;>;UK 5G Supply Chain Diversification Strategy&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;）的一部分。竞赛旨在展示Open&amp;nbsp;RAN这种构建移动网络的新方法，在需要无线连接的繁忙场所提供快速、可靠的连接，它让不同公司的技术能够协同工作，而不是只使用一家公司的设备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：Open RAN指的是开放式无线接入网络，目前英国电信运营商Vodafone（沃达丰）已在欧洲正式商用5G Open RAN。英国以真金白银推进Open&amp;nbsp;RAN研发计划，旨在打破不同公司和设备之间的隔阂，对用户来说，至少信号覆盖要有所改善吧。（唐家乐）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/K4GEB1hyOslOY5qNLxVAKA&quot;>;&lt;strong>;华为率先完成5.5G全部功能测试&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;2023年9月11日，华为完成5G-A（又称5.5G，全称5G-Advanced，是3GPP正式确定5G演进的名称）全部功能测试用例，涵盖上下行超宽带和宽带实时交互5G-A关键技术。作为5G的演进和增强，5G-A的连接速率和时延等网络能力实现了10倍提升，同时引入了通感一体、无源物联、内生智能等全新的革命性技术，是构建未来智能社会的基础设施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：移动通信技术从5G到6G的迭代还需要时间，在过渡期内，5G-A被寄予厚望。在2023MWC上海世界移动通信大会上，华为副董事长、轮值董事长、CFO孟晚舟表示，2024年，华为将会推出面向商用的5.5G全套网络设备，为5.5G的商用部署做好准备。每一次通信技术的升级换代，都将带来产业生态的新发展。（赵俊）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;汽车&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/press-room/20230911IPR04912/state-of-the-eu-ukraine-green-deal-economy-china-artificial-intelligence&quot;>;&lt;strong>;欧盟将对中国电动汽车发起反补贴调查&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月13日，欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩（Ursula&amp;nbsp;von&amp;nbsp;der&amp;nbsp;Leyen）在欧洲议会发表“盟情咨文”时表示，将启动对中国电动汽车的反补贴调查。冯德莱恩强调了公平过渡对农民、家庭和工业的重要性，并表示欧洲将“不惜一切代价”保持其竞争优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：2021年、2022年及2023年上半年，中国汽车出口销量分别为201万辆、311万辆与214万辆，同比分别增长102%、54%和76%，其中新能源汽车占大头。2023年上半年更取代日本一大汽车出口国。形势一片大好，但总量仍然很少，也不应过分乐观，对国际竞争的复杂和激烈程度，要有足够的准备和应对。（赵俊）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://global.honda/en/newsroom/news/2023/c230912eng.html?from=latest_area&quot;>;&lt;strong>;福特、宝马和本田&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;联手搭建充电网络&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月12日，福特汽车公司、宝马集团和本田汽车美国公司宣布联合成立一家新公司ChargeScape，以搭建一个连接电力公司、汽车制造商、电动汽车车主的平台，车主可通过充电管理、能源共享服务等，将能源回馈电网，从而节省资金，甚至获得收益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ChargeScape还将为电力公司和系统运营商提供安全的能源数据，从而实现电动汽车电池的智能使用。三家汽车制造商将均分新公司的股份，并且欢迎其他汽车制造商加入。不过，新公司仍需监管部门的批准，预计将从2024年开始运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：电动汽车不仅是能源使用者，也是储能载体。车网合一，汽车制造商们终于联手行动起来了。（罗仙仙）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;技术要闻&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scitranslmed.abo6889&quot;>;&lt;strong>;稳定微管治疗慢性创伤性脑病的新思路&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月13日，中国科学院上海有机化学研究所和美国宾夕法尼亚大学研究机构合作，在《科学-转化医学》（Science&amp;nbsp;translational&amp;nbsp;medicine）上发表题为&lt;em>;A&amp;nbsp;microtubule&amp;nbsp;stabilizer&amp;nbsp;ameliorates&amp;nbsp;protein&amp;nbsp;pathogenesis&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;neurodegeneration&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;mouse&amp;nbsp;models&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;repetitive&amp;nbsp;traumatic&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;injury&lt;/em>;的研究论文，报道了重复性创伤性脑损伤（repetitive&amp;nbsp;traumatic&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;injuries,&amp;nbsp;rTBI）可以诱导生理tau蛋白发生阿尔茨海默病（AD）相关的病理变化，并进一步促进tau病理性传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，上述研究团队研究人员使用了一种先前研发的微管稳定剂CNDR-51657，治疗重复性脑损伤小鼠。这种微管稳定剂能够穿透到大脑中发挥作用，小鼠经过一段时间的用药后，视神经束中神经元投射恢复，点状tau蛋白沉积减少，并且视觉皮层神经元活性恢复，小鼠视觉功能恢复，行为实验表明小鼠的认知功能也有所改善。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：上述研究证明微管稳定剂可能在调控tau蛋白异常聚集和传播过程中具有重要作用，或将为慢性创伤性脑病、阿尔茨海默病（AD）、额颞叶痴呆（FTLD）等脑组织中出现tau蛋白病理沉积的神经退行性疾病，提供新的治疗靶点和思路。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06473-y&quot;>;&lt;strong>;通过单细胞大脑类器官筛查自闭症发育缺陷&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月13日，《自然》（Nature）发表奥地利科学院分子生物技术研究所（IMBA）、苏黎世联邦理工学院研究团队论文&lt;em>;Single-cell&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;organoid&amp;nbsp;screening&amp;nbsp;identifies&amp;nbsp;developmental&amp;nbsp;defects&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;autism&lt;/em>;&amp;nbsp;。该研究开发了一种CRISPR-人类类器官-单细胞RNA测序系统，简称CHOOSE系统，研究人员可在单细胞水平上追踪每个突变的影响，并绘制每个细胞的发育轨迹。该系统使用经过验证的gRNA、基于诱导CRISPR-Cas9的基因敲除和单细胞转录组学，对嵌合型大脑类器官进行了功能缺失筛查，揭示了36个与转录调控有关的自闭症风险基因突变对大脑类器官不同细胞命运的影响，其中背侧中间祖细胞、腹侧祖细胞和上层兴奋性神经元是最脆弱的细胞类型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：自闭症被称作人类大脑的最复杂的疾病之一，上述创新方法为自闭症研究提供了新见解，通过了解致病基因共同的分子机制，也为自闭症临床研究带来新希望。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06473-y&quot;>;&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qiluguquan.com/guquan-article-read-11391.html&quot;>;&lt;strong>;齐鲁股权交易中心“专精特新”专板开板&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月13日，由齐鲁股权交易中心负责建设的山东区域性股权市场“专精特新”专板正式开板，首批226家企业登录专板。根据企业不同发展阶段，齐鲁股权交易中心在“专精特新”专板设置了孵化层、规范层和培育层，并发布了入板规则；聚焦专板企业服务，搭建了以“六大服务载体、七大专属服务工具、八大重点服务产品”为主体内容的“六七八”综合服务体系，强化上市培育体系建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：区域性股权市场，也被称为“四板市场”，过去一直不太受关注。齐鲁股权交易中心此次高调推出“专精特新”专板，是服务中小企业融资的重要举措。2023年9月1日，中国证监会发布《关于高质量建设北京证券交易所的意见》，提出要加强多层次资本市场互联互通，开展新三板与区域性股权市场制度型对接。这一“专精特新”专板，若能打通企业进入多层次资本市场的渠道，倒是真有可能开启“四板”的创新试验田。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杨妞花不放过余华英：这样的不宽容彰显正气与血性丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256958]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年9月18日，贵阳市中院以拐卖儿童罪判处余华英死刑。法院认定：余华英1993-1996年期间伙同龚某良（已故）为牟取非法利益，在贵州省、重庆市等地流窜，物色合适的孩童进行拐卖，得手后二人将被拐儿童带至河北省邯郸市，其间共拐卖11名儿童。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余华英当庭表示上诉，这是她的权利，也说明她对这个判决既不服，也不想死。不过，想想被她诱骗、绑架与拐卖的11个孩子，哪个父母不对她恨之入骨？&amp;nbsp;当孩子不见了，父母急火攻心、以泪洗面、茶饭不思，在本地找、去全国各地找，正常的生活、工作被打乱，失去欢乐、家庭破碎。在这个过程中，有的父母陷入自责不能自拔，人生失去意义，或自暴自弃，或抑郁而终，有的父母在某个节点放弃了希望，但心里永不愈合的伤口还会时常隐隐作痛甚至急性发作，也有父母不依不饶、不止不休，但以中国之大，找回自己孩子又何其难也。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在庭审现场，就有受害者家属甚至当年被拐卖、现在已成年但永远是父母眼中的“孩子”在场，杨妞花就是其中的一个。在将余华英绳之以法、予以应有惩罚的过程中，杨妞花起到了不可替代的作用，正是她的坚持与不依不饶，余华英才最终落网，我们才能看到9月18日的那一幕。一句话，杨妞花是当之无愧、令人感佩的英雄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1990年，杨妞花出生于贵州织金县，是家中最小的女儿，有一个幸福的家庭，有很多难忘的童年回忆，正是这些不可磨灭的回忆成了她心中不灭的光，助她找到了回家的路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余华英及其团伙租住在杨妞花家附近，她对“自己和姐姐很好，会带姐妹俩逛街，会给买东西”。有一天余华英趁家中没有大人时，骗走并拐卖了时年5岁的杨妞花，价格是2500元。杨妞花忘不了：被骗上火车之后，余华英随即变换出一张凶狠的脸，不仅对她拳打脚踢，还将暖壶里的开水直接浇到她的头上，这是为了“降低管理成本”的服从性训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，杨妞花开始了漫漫寻亲之旅。2021年4月，她在短视频平台上发布寻亲信息，回忆起和家人相处的点点滴滴：自己掉进水坑差点淹死，爬上来后姐姐在一旁哭；从猪圈摔下头破血流，姐姐背着自己哭着去找妈妈。同年5月3日，杨妞花的视频引起了贵州织金县一位杨姓女孩的关切，她从小听长辈说，有个堂姐在1995年时丢了。经过DNA比对确认，被拐26年的杨妞花终于踏上了回家之路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不幸的是，在她被拐后，她的父亲因伤心过度饮酒过量于1997年去世，母亲因承受不住精神打击也于翌年离世，姐姐遂成为孤儿。后来，姐姐告诉她，那时一到晚上，父母就会带着姐姐到火车站里找人，夜里就在车站打地铺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接受媒体采访时，杨妞花表示：“之前我在没有找到家的时候，我从来没想过去找人贩子。是找到家之后发现家里面变故那么大，才下决心要找人贩子的。”2022年6月，杨妞花向贵州警方提供线索。24天后，余华英被贵阳市公安局南明分局抓获。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，贵阳市南明区检察院以“拐卖儿童罪”对余华英提起公诉。据杨妞花的代理律师王文广透露，检方最初建议判处有期徒刑14年。杨妞花对这一量刑建议并不满意，她委托律师申请，将此案由贵阳市南明区法院移交到贵阳市中院审理，后面的部分我们都看到了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余华英此次被指控的11起拐卖儿童案件，并不包括之前已审理结案的，也不包括她卖掉的自己的亲儿子，正是这一次的收益，让她尝到了甜头与血腥味，从此一发不可收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末报道，庭审时，余华英曾两次对被拐家庭道歉，希望获得他们谅解，也希望法院能从轻处罚。但杨妞花难以接受余华英的道歉。这样的不宽容，彰显的是正义和血性！《论语》有一段经典对话，或曰：以德报怨，何如？子曰：何以报德？以直报怨，以德报德。一个人遭受很大的伤害，被剥夺权利、被凌辱，失去本有的生活，当然有权向施害者索求自己应得的正义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受害者有权索求正义，与TA最终能否得到正义，当然是两件事，前者也不能自动导向后者，而是需要受害者本人“做功”。杨妞花不放过人贩子，于她而言的直接动机，是为自己、为自己的父母讨回一点公道，而她同时也为所有被拐卖的孩子及其家庭讨回了公道，也给我们这个社会树立了正气与血性。主观为自己，客观利他人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步，惩恶扬善，不惩恶何足以扬善？坏人得以善终是对善与正义的最大嘲讽。只有当这个社会的正气与血性越来越多，心怀不轨者才会有所顾忌，欲行不轨前而三思，我们才能安享更大的自由与安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赛百味700亿卖身：降不住中国胃的轻食还会越吃越肥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256932]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/c01164b14aab8acb3eb16ac74acd8b48.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/c01164b14aab8acb3eb16ac74acd8b48. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the world-famous Fast food chain Subway has successfully &quot;sold itself out&quot;. According to its official website, it agreed to the acquisition proposal from private equity firm Roark Capital, with an acquisition price of approximately RMB 70 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the news came out, it immediately became a trending topic. Many foodies left messages lamenting that the fast food chain Big Mac, which had more stores than McDonald&#39;s and KFC at its peak, is no longer popular. Data shows that Subway has been in operating difficulties since 2014. As of November 2022, the number of Subway stores worldwide has decreased by nearly 8,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, Subway&#39;s stores are mainly concentrated in first- and second-tier cities. A sandwich sells for 30 yuan. It focuses on being &quot;healthier&quot; than ordinary fast food. It has been famous for providing freshly customized sandwiches, wraps, salads, etc. It is widely popular in weight loss and fitness circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as competition in the catering industry intensifies, under the name of health, waves of ketogenic diets, meal replacements, and sugar replacements come one after another, and various &quot;fat-reducing diets&quot; &quot;Meals&quot; are emerging one after another. Gradually, Subway&#39;s sandwiches have lost their originality and are no longer fashionable in the eyes of Chinese foodies who pursue healthy consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An endless stream of weight loss meals&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to successfully lose weight, people take great pains in their diet, and this can always be captured by keen merchants, so over the years, diets in the name of weight loss have Wave after wave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meal replacement is quite popular nowadays. Meal replacement, as the name suggests, can replace part or all of the main meals. It is a type of food that quickly, conveniently and quantitatively provides the human body with appropriate amounts of protein, fat, carbohydrates, fiber and other necessary nutrients. There are meal replacement powders and meal replacement milks. Shakes, meal replacement porridge, meal replacement snacks, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meal replacement was initially targeted at patients with specific diseases, astronauts, mountaineers and other people. Later, it quickly became popular among weight loss people, and the market scale expanded rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Tmall statistics, sales of meal replacement light food products in 2021 increased by 290% year-on-year. The number of meal replacement consumers increased by 78% in three years, and the per capita annual consumption amount has exceeded 3,000 yuan. . Statistics from global market research company Euromonitor International show that in 2017, China&#39;s meal replacement market size was approximately 57.17 billion yuan, and is expected to reach 120 billion yuan in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Substitute sugar is similar to meal replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sugar substitutes have a sweetness similar to sucrose, but do not produce calories or have very low calories. This is most common in beverages and snacks, which are all labeled with &quot;zero sugar&quot; and &quot;zero calories&quot; to tell consumers that they can satisfy their cravings without gaining weight. For example, drinks represented by Yuanqi Forest under the banner of &quot;zero sugar&quot; adjust the taste by adding sugar substitutes &quot;erythritol&quot; and &quot;sucralose&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the stereotype of some dieters, sugar and carbohydrates are the main culprits of obesity, so in addition to avoiding sugar, some people also do everything possible to reduce or even eliminate carbohydrates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ketogenic diet, which rejects all carbohydrates, has become popular. The traditional Chinese eating habits are too high in carbohydrates, and the ketogenic diet goes to the other extreme: only eating lean meats and vegetables, and not eating staple foods containing carbohydrates, thereby producing a large amount of ketone bodies and forcing the body to burn fat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next step is the fat-reducing meal. Simply put, it is a meal that can reduce fat. It is generally less oil, less salt, and low in calories. Unlike the ketogenic diet, its nutrition is relatively balanced. Most diets for weight loss are not delicious. Fat-reduction meals now stand out on social platforms because they can be &quot;delicious&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, some people found hope in the burgers and fried chicken of the carbohydrate giant. On the one hand, burgers and chicken legs can not only provide excellent protein and necessary fat for the human body, but on the other hand, their calories are not as high as imagined. For example, some burgers only have 450 calories. The daily caloric intake of adult women in my country is about 1,800 kilocalories, and that of adult men is 2,250 kilocalories, so eating a hamburger for one meal is not a big problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with other weight-loss meals, fat-reducing meals are becoming a major source of traffic on social platforms. Other weight-loss meals can basically only be bought from merchants, which are unpalatable and expensive. However, fat-loss meals are suitable for DIY. There are a wide variety of menus to share on social platforms, and all kinds of food are available. They are delicious and can help you lose weight, so why not for? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/af1c4b7c289a7bcdee642927260594ac.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/af1c4b7c289a7bcdee642927260594ac.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It may not work&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;But, can Internet celebrity weight loss meals really help you lose weight? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many Internet celebrity weight loss meals are specious and just seek psychological comfort. For example, the various meal replacement snacks that have become popular in the past two years, such as oatmeal brittle, compressed biscuits, cereal yogurt, and instant corn flakes, are not low in sugar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although some sugar substitute biscuits replace sucrose with sugar substitute and wheat flour with coarse grain flour rich in dietary fiber, the main ingredient is still starch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is the popular salad set on the takeout platform, which is piled with vegetables, fruits and some meat, and looks very healthy. In fact, although fruits supplement vitamins, their sugar content is not low; avocados are not low in fat; a few grains of purple/brown rice just look like whole grains and are probably refined carbohydrates; more importantly, there are various sauces that enhance the taste. Ingredients, the calories are very likely to explode...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Salad sets on takeout platforms often do not provide accurate energy tables, but merchants with little nutrition knowledge prepare them at will, and consumers spend more money. Just buy a psychological comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if it may not work, Internet celebrity weight loss meals may also bring health risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, although meal replacement is a way to supplement nutrients and reduce energy intake, the nutrients in meal replacement cannot replace a balanced diet, and studies have shown that long-term consumption of meal replacement shakes , will affect intestinal peristalsis, reduce metabolism, and in severe cases may cause endocrine disorders in the body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for sugar substitute products. After eating sugar, the human body will automatically undergo a glucose metabolism reaction. If you eat sugar substitutes but do not take in the required calories, the normal glucose metabolism reaction will be weakened, resulting in a subsequent decrease in glucose tolerance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ketogenic diet carries greater risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the standards of the &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents&quot;, 55%-65% of adults&#39; daily energy intake should come from carbohydrates. A ketogenic diet that refuses carbohydrates will cause insufficient energy for the body, leading to side effects such as fatigue, gastrointestinal dysfunction, and irregular heartbeat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A study in &quot;The Lancet&quot; showed that there is a U-shaped relationship between carbohydrate intake and life expectancy. A low-carbohydrate diet will reduce life expectancy by up to 4 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest bug with various fat-reducing meals is that we can eat them for a month to achieve the goal of reducing fat, but can we eat them for a lifetime? Once it fails, the next problem will be: rebound. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior nutritionist pointed out: &quot;A single food weight loss method actually deviates from a healthy dietary pattern. The result is that the more you reduce your basal metabolism, the lower your basal metabolism will be, and the rebound will be more severe.&quot; Long-term deficit habit The body will fully absorb them when exposed to carbohydrates and fats to help the body return to normal operating levels, and the weight will rebound quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn&#39;t this just &quot;losing your wife and losing your troops&quot;? The operation was as fierce as a tiger, but in the end it returned to the same way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/3710cf01919af6f3692376196c081165.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/3710cf01919af6f3692376196c081165.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Shut up and open your legs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is the truly effective way to lose weight? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is the clichéd six words, &quot;Shut up and open your legs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Keeping your mouth shut does not mean not to eat, but it means to control your diet appropriately and ensure a balanced diet. The &quot;Reference Intake of Dietary Nutrients for Chinese Residents&quot; clearly states: The recommended dietary energy supply ratio for adults is 50%-65% carbohydrates, 20%-30% fat, and 10%-15% protein. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humans are not machines. Only by consuming sufficient and balanced nutrients can normal metabolism be maintained. Of course, overeating is not advisable, but if you diet blindly, once the intake cannot cover the basal metabolism, it will have a negative effect on the body, causing muscle and bone loss. Therefore, any kind of weight loss meal must be based on health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person’s fatness or thinness is not only related to the total daily caloric intake, but also related to the total daily caloric consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there is a calorie surplus, the body will gain weight. If calorie consumption is greater than calorie intake, then the body will lose weight. To successfully lose weight, your total energy intake should be less than your total energy expenditure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many internet celebrity weight loss meals focus on reducing intake, but their low energy intake has fallen below the bottom line of health. The healthy fat loss formula is: caloric consumption >; caloric intake >; calories required for basal metabolism. The body&#39;s caloric deficit is between 10% and 15% of total consumption. The best way to burn calories is to spread your legs and move. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it’s better to just “keep your mouth shut and open your legs” if you follow all kinds of celebrity weight-loss meals on the Internet and the prices are quite low. Maintaining a normal and balanced diet while ensuring a certain amount of exercise may not make you lose weight immediately, but it will give you a well-proportioned figure and a healthy body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如何评价历史人物？从“被泼脏水”的隋炀帝说起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256914]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Over the years, there are probably very few &quot;tyrants&quot; in history who have not been demonstrated by researchers or history buffs He is &quot;actually a talented and strategic monarch&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, the images of many &quot;tyrants&quot; left in history books, especially their images in traditional literature, are often far from their historical prototypes. After a change of dynasty, if the new dynasty wants to prove its legitimacy, the history books will throw dirty water on it. The identity of the &quot;tyrant&quot; has been recognized, and folk literature and art like to use him to tell erotic and violent stories - after all, deep in human nature, there is such a hobby, but it is not appropriate to place this hobby on a good person, so the &quot;tyrant&quot; &quot;It&#39;s always good to make it very pornographic and violent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fate of popular emperors in literary and artistic works such as Shang Zhou and Sui Yang Emperor is probably always like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the question is, peel off the outer layer of skin, what is the inner layer exposed? Let’s take Emperor Yang of Sui Dynasty as an example. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty first came to the throne, he inherited a powerful empire that had not been seen for hundreds of years after the fall of the Han Dynasty, and it was also a huge powder keg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, long-term divisions have been unified in a very short period of time, and some people are dissatisfied with the current regime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, his father, Emperor Wen of the Sui Dynasty, had some important institutional reforms and policy practices, which were very beneficial from the national level, but felt uncomfortable at the social level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the household registration management in the Sui Dynasty was particularly good. According to official population statistics, the population has increased from 29 million to 46 million in less than 30 years. These 17 million people are definitely not just the result of everyone trying their best to have children when the world is at peace, but the population that was originally hidden has all been plundered. From the perspective of the imperial court, the country had extremely abundant manpower and material resources at its disposal. However, if you look at the perspective of ordinary people at that time, these people did not have to pay taxes or serve in the military. Now all these burdens have been placed on them, and they are not necessarily happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these people are all in disarray, there is nothing they can do even if they are dissatisfied. But Emperor Wen of the Sui Dynasty also made another major reform, which was to change the three-level local administration of state-prefecture-county to the second-level state-county administration, and abolish the county level. As a result, tens of thousands of people, from county chiefs to ordinary officials, were about to be laid off. From a national level, this is reducing staff and increasing efficiency. But with so many officials losing their vested interests, they will definitely be furious. If the Sui Dynasty returned all the savings to the people, then the people should be very happy to see these people lose their official positions. But the problem is that the Sui Dynasty concentrated all the profits in the court, and the people of the Sui Dynasty did not get any benefits from this reform that could have benefited them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above two reforms, together with other new policies, resulted in a great increase in the income of the Sui Dynasty and a decrease in expenditure. Therefore, many scholars have noticed that when it comes to ancient dynasties, it is said that In terms of &quot;national wealth&quot;, it is unmatched by the Sui Dynasty. But at the same time, this also means that as long as someone wants to rebel, there will immediately be tens of thousands of unemployed officials with administrative organizational skills, and tens of millions of dissatisfied people who can take advantage of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty was completely unaware of the existence of this problem. He was from a good background, had a smooth life since childhood, and was really smart. He had no ability to empathize with the pain of ordinary people. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He only saw that there were so many resources in the court now, so he wanted to do big things, so he dug the Grand Canal and conquered Liaodong three times, which were all extreme tests of social endurance. It was not that Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty did not feel that his throne was threatened, but it was not from this huge powder keg, but from the Guanlong Group that the Sui Dynasty relied on for its success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before becoming emperor, Emperor Sui Yang was particularly successful in commanding the war in the south. His ability to win over the southern nobles far exceeded that of the older generation of famous generals and ministers of the Guanlong Group. This gave him the illusion that I have new forces available, and you are nothing special. This intensified the division of the ruling group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the excluded Guanlong dignitaries at the top, the laid-off officials at the middle level, and the ordinary people at the grassroots level who are overwhelmed by heavy labor and taxes will have full anger from top to bottom. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emperor Sui Yang was indeed not the nymphomaniac or sadist in literary works, but when faced with the challenge, he seemed completely unqualified as a politician. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are too willful when things are going well. I don’t want you to think so. I want you to think that you can’t do things and never give up even if you hit a wall. But when it comes to adversity, they lack resilience and willpower, and their willpower collapses immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world was in chaos. When Emperor Sui Yang arrived in Jiangdu, he actually no longer expected to recapture the north. But his troops were all from the north, and they were afraid of not going back, so they were discussing rebellion. A palace maid heard the news and told Queen Xiao. Empress Xiao is still very smart, so you can speak for yourself. As soon as the result was mentioned, Emperor Sui Yang became furious. Are you qualified to say this? Just kill this palace maid. Later, there were more and more news that the army was going to rebel. Queen Xiao told the people in the palace that there was no need to talk to His Majesty. Why add to his worries? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in terms of the combat effectiveness of Emperor Sui Yang&#39;s army at that time, it was still very powerful, but at the last moment of his life, Emperor Sui Yang had given up treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The summary is that as a political figure, Emperor Sui Yang:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, he was unable to reconcile complex political and social contradictions;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, Failed to build a core team that was loyal to itself and capable;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, there was no awareness of changing course when the situation started to go unfavorable;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, there was no persistence when the situation was very unfavorable. will. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the things he did, such as building the Grand Canal, you might as well look at it this way: When discussing long-term history, even if a person is an emperor, his influence may not be that important. The study of factors such as finance and taxation, technology diffusion, productivity, economic and social structure is enough to explain the problem, and it might as well not involve character evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To evaluate a character, you need to look at the history of a short period of time. A short period of time in the historical sense is a lifetime for ordinary people. The great social collapse of the late Sui Dynasty triggered by Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty caused the death and displacement of tens of millions of people. This is real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, traditional history books and literary works often apply too much paint to characters. This problem does exist. But if you think the truth is revealed by turning traditional records over, you might as well save it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人贩余华英获死刑，受害家庭：“几十年的辛酸，终于清楚了”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256948]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 10:16:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/19/f6b4e7615e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 19/f6b4e7615e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251151&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, Yu Huaying was charged with child trafficking. Sentenced to death. (Guiyang Intermediate People&#39;s Court/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, the Guiyang Intermediate People&#39;s Court publicly pronounced the verdict on the crime of child abduction and trafficking against the defendant Yu Huaying. Yu Huaying was sentenced to death for child abduction, deprived of political rights for life, and confiscated all personal property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the video shot by the media, Yang Niuhua read the verdict to the parents looking for relatives at the door of the court, hoping that they could all see hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Niuhua was abducted and trafficked by Yu Huaying when she was 5 years old. She successfully found her relatives 25 years later. In 2022, Yang Niuhua reported the case to the police and provided clues, and the child abduction and trafficking case of Yu Huaying was officially filed. (For details, please see the relevant report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/253854?source=134&quot;>;Human trafficker Yu Huaying was sentenced to death: abducted 11 children and also sold her own son&lt;/a a>;》)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The trial by Guiyang Intermediate People’s Court found that the defendant Yu Huaying collaborated with Gong Mouliang (deceased) from 1993 to 1996 for profit Illegal interests circulated in Guizhou Province, Chongqing City and other places, looking for suitable children to abduct and traffic. After they succeeded, the two took the abducted children to Handan City, Hebei Province, and through the introduction of Wang Moufu and Yang Moulan, they found a buyer for the sale. , profiting from this, during which a total of 11 children were abducted. The Guiyang Intermediate Court held that the defendant Yu Huaying had repeatedly abducted and trafficked children in order to obtain illegal profits. His behavior constituted the crime of child abduction. The crime was particularly serious and extremely harmful to society and should be severely punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Huaying appealed in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I hope she will die, but I don’t want her to die”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although it was only a first-instance verdict, Cai Huiying, a family member of the victim who attended the sentencing, Feeling devastated, she told her relatives on the phone: &quot;We have finally figured it out after decades of hardship and fatigue. We finally understand.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;After Cai Huiying walked out of the court, she started calling her family. The first one is the abducted party - his younger brother Cai Zhansheng. Cai Shengsheng was 6 years old when he was abducted in Zunyi and disappeared with his brother. A few months later, the elder brother came back alone without seeing his younger brother. It was not until the end of 2022, after the Yu Huaying case was filed, that Cai Shengsheng went home through DNA comparison. Thirty years later, Cai Zhansheng can no longer remember many details, but he still remembers Yu Huaying with high cheekbones and a long face. Cai Huiying said that her brother was also very happy to learn that Yu Huaying was sentenced to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cai Huiying called her parents for the second time. After his younger brother was lost, his father insisted on going out to look for his relatives for more than 20 years, traveling to Yunnan, Sichuan, Guangxi, Guangdong, Fujian, Henan, Jiangxi and other places. Wherever there was news, my father immediately went out to verify it. He went out with hope again and again, but his hope was shattered again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Logically speaking, my father should hate Yu Huaying very much. But two months ago, when my father learned that the prosecutor recommended the death penalty for Yu Huaying in the first trial, &quot;the first sentence he said was that I hope she (Yu Huaying) dies, but I don&#39;t want her to die.&quot; Cai&#39;s father hopes that Yu Huaying will be sentenced to death because she has brought endless harm and pain to his family; he does not want her to die, but he wants to give her some time to tell the story of the children who have been abducted and trafficked over the years, so that more parents can Find the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cai Huiying replied to her father: &quot;This is our common idea, but can she do it?&quot; Cai Huiying once attended the first trial. At that time, Yu Hua Ying expressed that he was &quot;unclear&quot; and &quot;cannot remember&quot; many of the circumstances of the crime. Only when talking about his son and daughter, Yu Huaying burst into tears and choked with sobs. This made Cai Huiying quite angry, and she clenched her fists from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Huaying abducted 11 children, involving 8 families. This time the court pronounced its verdict, and relatives from five families came to listen. One mother had two sons abducted, another mother had a son and a daughter abducted, and yet another mother had a son abducted. When Cai Huiying saw the mother who came from Zunyi, after Yu Huaying was sentenced to death, she stood up with excitement and seemed to want to beat her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During lunch, Cai Huiying chatted with several mothers about their respective situations: the children of five families were recovered one after another after Yang Niuhua reported the crime. However, the relationship between the biological family and the foster family is quite complex. Some abducted children find it difficult to cope with the situation, fail to accept family recognition, and rarely come back for reunions. &quot;But we are all grateful to Niuhua, because she reported the crime and we were able to find our relatives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The regret of broken family ties has appeared in many victim families. In Dazu, Chongqing, Bai Ticai, whose son was abducted by Yu Huaying, was completely unaware of the court verdict. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the child had never seen him since the spring of 2020 when he recognized his relatives, and the two had lost contact. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7486ba21cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7486ba21cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, parents looking for relatives gathered outside the gate of Guiyang Intermediate Hospital. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Encourage parents looking for relatives to &quot;don&#39;t give up&quot;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;On September 18, outside the gate of Guiyang Intermediate Court, there were still three floors inside and three floors outside surrounded by parents who came to look for relatives, just as they did during the court hearing in July. Everyone held a family-searching information board in front of their chests, on which the information about the abducted children was printed in the most conspicuous yellow letters on a red background. The children were still young when they were abducted, and the printed photos show them when they were one or two years old, and most of them are blurry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the court hearing in July, Southern Weekend reporters saw An Shiming, who came to search for his son. He came to the court door early holding a family search information board to broadcast live. This time when the verdict was announced, he once again came early with some parents looking for relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Cai Huiying arrived before 8 o&#39;clock, more parents saw this search than at the first trial. She stood far away and did not dare to walk into the crowd. &quot;I felt that as soon as I stood there and heard what they said, I naturally couldn&#39;t control the emotion.&quot; For parents who are still looking for relatives, Cai Huiying feels that what she can say is feeble: &quot;Have more courage and continue.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Niuhua Dare to speak to parents looking for relatives. In a live media broadcast after the trial, she once again encouraged parents looking for their children not to give up. She mentioned her own example: the first time she took blood to find her relatives was in 2012, but there has been no news in the past ten years. But in 2021, in just over a month, she miraculously found her home through the short video platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After finding a home, Yang Niuhua lived in Hebei, Yu Huaying was in Chongqing, and the trafficking case occurred in Guizhou. The three places were far apart. It seemed that it was very difficult to find human traffickers. Disaster. But now, Yu Huaying has been punished by law. &quot;Really never give up,&quot; Yang Niuhua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before and after every court session, Yang Niuhua’s schedule is tight and busy. On the one hand, families looking for relatives hope to take this opportunity to spread the information about finding relatives, and find her to live broadcast and record videos together; on the other hand, media interviews continue, and Yang Niuhua repeatedly recounts her experience of being abducted and the hardships of growing up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sister Sang Ying felt a little distressed when she saw Yang Niuhua always rushing ahead. Both sisters were actually victims. After Yang Niuhua was abducted in 1995, her parents were extremely sad and died in 1997 and 1998 respectively. Sangying lost her home and was forced to go out to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>