<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[最高法再审百亿金海矿山案，山西前首富张新明败诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260044]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the integration of coal resources in Shanxi began in 2009, the Jinhai Coal Mine was retained separately, and the market price soared. to 10 billion yuan. Visual China/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/795278dcc0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/795278dcc0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the integration of coal resources in Shanxi began in 2009, Jinhai Coal Mine was retained separately, and the market price soared to tens of billions of yuan. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanxi “Ten Billion Mine Contest Case” that once shocked the legal community has taken a major turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;17 years ago, Zhang Xinming, the former richest man in Shanxi and chairman of Jinye Group, and his related parties transferred their shares in Jinhai Coal Mine to the state-owned Shanxi Coal Transportation and Marketing Group Jincheng Yangcheng Co., Ltd. in order to alleviate their financial difficulties. (hereinafter referred to as Yangcheng Coal Transportation) and Qinhe Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Qinhe Investment) headed by Lu Zhonglou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as the Shanxi coal industry began to merge and reorganize in 2009, the value of Jinhai coal mine soared sharply. Zhang Xinming began to launch a series of lawsuits against Yangcheng Coal Transportation, Qinhe Investment and its chairman Lu Zhonglou. When the plaintiff transferred the equity to the defendant, the price was too low. Zhang Xinming won all these lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinhai Coal Mine is located in Yangcheng County, Jincheng City, Shanxi Province. The coalfield area is about 53.7 square kilometers and the total resource reserves are 409 million tons. It is extremely rare in Shanxi, where coal mines are everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verdicts of this series of cases have caused huge controversy, and the fates of two coal tycoons, Zhang Xinming and Lu Zhonglou, have also taken different paths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xinming is known as the &quot;Minister of Shanxi Underground Organization&quot;. In August 2014, Zhang Xinming was taken away by the public security organs in Taiyuan, and there has been no news since. Shanxi&#39;s officialdom also experienced constant earthquakes, and officials were dismissed one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, three of the above-mentioned series of lawsuits were heard by the Supreme People&#39;s Court of the People&#39;s Republic of China (hereinafter referred to as the Supreme Court) and the Shanxi Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court (hereinafter referred to as the Shanxi Provincial High Court), and the original judgments were revoked. Another case upheld the original verdict. Zhang Xinming, who had &quot;disappeared&quot; for more than nine years, also returned to the stage due to the reopening of these cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, Yangcheng Coal Transportation and Zhang Xinming’s son Zhang Wenyang were retried over the equity dispute in Jinhai Coal Mine. Zhang Xinming appeared at the court hearing as his son’s litigation agent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Informed sources revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that Zhang Xinming will be released from prison on medical parole in mid-2020, and the relevant judgment will be kept confidential. In a photo in May 2020, 57-year-old Zhang Xinming was sitting in a wheelchair, dressed casually and looking relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the old and new judgments, a multi-party battle to grab the ore can be recreated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ten-billion mining case and the sacking of the Vice President of the Supreme People’s Court&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Zhang Xinming obtained the mining rights of Jinhai Coal Mine and established Shanxi Jinhai Energy Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jinhai) Energy), with a registered capital of 30 million yuan. Except for obtaining the mining license of Jinhai Coal Mine on March 15 of that year, the company has not conducted other investments and operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, coal resources in Shanxi were still allocated administratively, and were either used free of charge by enterprises, or some symbolic resource fees were paid. This means that in a short period of time, those who obtain new mines can make huge profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mineral resource fee of Jinhai Coal Mine totals 224 million yuan (0.55 yuan/ton), which is paid in six years. In May 2004, Jinhai Energy paid the first installment of 37.3849 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Jinhai Energy was short of funds and began to introduce external investors. At that time, Zhang Xinming and his related natural persons held 60% of the shares in Jinhai Energy, and Beijing Xinye Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Beijing Xinye) held 40% of the shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of the above 60% shares&lt;span>;, Zhang Xinming holds 17%, his son Zhang Wenyang holds 40%, Feng Xiaolin holds 2%, and Wang Xiangdong holds 1%. &lt;/span>;Zhang Wenyang and Feng Xiaolin once stated during the trial that they were both acting on behalf of Zhang Xinming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Finance&quot; magazine once reported that Wang Xiangdong is the son of a former main leader of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. People familiar with the case also confirmed this to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original executive director and legal representative of Beijing Xinye is the mysterious Shanxi businessman Yan Qi. According to Caijing magazine, Yan Qi was originally a student of the Shanxi Provincial Department of Materials and Materials, and later founded Shanxi Yunchang Real Estate Company. He has never been involved in coal mining during his career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Qi later founded Sanya Luhuitou Tourist Area Development Co., Ltd. and developed the famous villa market &quot;Banshan Peninsula&quot;. Its subsidiaries also include Sanya Aidi Real Estate Company and Hong Kong Tianfu Company. &lt;span>;In 2015, Yan Qi ranked as the richest man in Hainan on the Hurun Rich List with assets of 9 billion yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2005, Jinhai Energy and Yangcheng Coal Transportation signed an equity transfer agreement. Zhang Wenyang and Beijing Xinye transferred 13% and 15% of their equity respectively, and Yangcheng Coal Transportation paid for these equity A transfer price of 8.4 million yuan was obtained, which is equivalent to 300,000 yuan per share, which is the same as the registered capital price per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Yangcheng Coal Transportation provided entrusted loans of 280 million yuan each to the Yuefeng Coal Washing Plant under Beijing Xinye and Jinye Group (Zhang Xinming is the chairman), with a term of 6 years, and the interest is based on bank deposit interest rates for the same period. calculate. After obtaining 28% of the equity of Jinhai Coal Mine, Yangcheng Coal Transportation paid another 74.76 million yuan in resource price, and Jinhai Energy’s mining rights were extended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, Jinhai Energy also acquired Qinhe Investment from Lu Zhonglou as a shareholder. In September of that year, six shareholders of Jinhai Energy signed an equity transfer agreement with Qinhe Investment. Zhang Xinming, Zhang Wenyang, Feng Xiaolin, and Beijing Xinye transferred 17%, 27%, 2%, and 15% of their equity respectively to Qinhe Investment. The latter paid an equity transfer fee of 18.3 million yuan, which is also 300,000 yuan per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Qinhe Investment also provided a 5-year interest-free loan of 375 million yuan to Beijing Xinye, and signed a loan agreement with Zhang Xinming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Beijing Xinye transferred its equity to Qinhe Investment, the two parties signed a supplementary agreement to change the transfer price of 15% of Beijing Xinye’s equity from 4.5 million yuan to 200 million yuan. It was previously agreed that The 375 million yuan loan lapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, 1% of Wang Xiangdong’s equity was transferred to Qinhe Investment for 300,000 yuan. At this point, the shareholders of Jinhai Energy have become Qinhe Investment, Yangcheng Coal Transportation and Beijing Xinye, with each of the three parties holding 62%, 28% and 10% of the shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, Shanxi coal resources began to merge and reorganize, but Jinhai Coal Mine was retained alone, and the market price soared to tens of billions of yuan. According to the above report, in the first half of 2009, Zhang Xinming repeatedly persuaded Lu Zhonglou to sell 62% of the Jinhai Coal Mine equity for 900 million yuan, but Lu disagreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, Zhang Xinming began to sue Qinhe Investment and requested to terminate the equity transfer agreement on the grounds that the value of each equity share of Jinhai Coal Mine was much greater than 300,000 yuan. The lawsuit went all the way to the Supreme Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Supreme Court quoted the supplementary agreement between Beijing Xinye and Qinhe Investment, a non-party in the case, and considered that the transfer price of 15% of Jinhai Energy held by Beijing Xinye was changed to 200 million yuan, and held that Qinhe Investment changed from Zhang The market value of the 46%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; equity transferred by Xinming Division should exceed&lt;/span>; 600 million yuan. The amount paid by Qinhe Investment was &quot;significantly lower than the market value of the equity involved in the case&quot;, and accordingly the original trial was upheld. The court supported Zhang Xinming’s request to terminate the contract, transfer Qin and return the equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case was judged in September 2012, and the case number was &quot;(2011) Minerzhongzi No. 76&quot;, also known as &quot;Judgment No. 76&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This verdict caused huge controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2013, two seminars on the &quot;Judgment No. 76&quot; were held in Beijing. More than 30 civil and commercial law scholars, including jurist Jiang Ping, professor of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences Liang Huixing, and professor of China University of Political Science and Law Li Shuguang, attended discuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Huixing said at the above-mentioned seminar that if coal prices did not rise, there would be no case. He believes that &quot;the Supreme Court made a judgment based on the principle of fairness, which is wrong.&quot; Since both parties are businessmen, the agreement between the two parties is fair. As long as it does not violate the law or harm the interests of the country and society, the court has no power to intervene. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then Vice President of the Supreme People&#39;s Court&lt;span>;Xi Xiaoming also compiled the case into the book &quot;Supreme People&#39;s Court Commercial Trial Guidance Cases (2012) Company and Finance&quot;&lt;/span>;. In July 2015, Xi Xiaoming was investigated for suspected serious violations of discipline and law, and was eventually accused of accepting a huge financial bribe of 114 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Caixin&quot; reports, Zhang Xinming paid 30 million yuan in bribes to Xi Xiaoming through a broker, of which 18 million yuan was given to Xi Xiaoming&#39;s son Xi Jiacheng, and the remaining 12 million yuan belonged to Xi Xiaoming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Judgment No. 76&quot; is the final judgment of the Supreme People&#39;s Court. If you are not satisfied with the judgment, Qinhe Investment can also apply for a protest to the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. Lu Zhonglou told Southern Weekend reporters that Qinhe Investment is preparing to apply for a protest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;Judgment No. 76&quot;, from 2010 to 2012, related parties such as Yangcheng Coal Transportation, Qinhe Investment and Lu Zhonglou were also sued by Zhang Xinming and his associates, Beijing Xinye The lawsuit was filed, all demanding that the Jinhai Coal Mine Equity Transfer Agreement be terminated and that all parties return their equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, there are 4 cases that were retried this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Restart&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another person close to the Jinhai Coal Mine Equity Dispute case told Southern Weekend reporters that there has been no movement in this series of lawsuits for 10 years. He suddenly got the lawsuit at the end of 2022. It is known that the case will be restarted. After the spring of 2023, the pace of the trial will gradually slow down and return to a normal pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, Yangcheng Coal Transportation received two final judgments one after another, from the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Shanxi Provincial High Court, and the signing dates were September 7 and September 18, 2023 respectively. The original judgments were all revoked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011 and 2012, Zhang Wenyang and Beijing Xinye sued Yangcheng Coal Transportation to court. They argued that the 28% equity transferred by Jinhai Energy to Yangcheng Coal Transportation included a loan principal of 560 million yuan. , please rule that the equity transfer agreement between the two parties is invalid and return the equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Shanxi Provincial High Court and Shanxi Jincheng Intermediate Court, the original courts of the two cases, both cited &quot;Judgment No. 76&quot; and held that Jinhai Energy&#39;s &quot;transfer price of 300,000 yuan per share was not between the parties to the agreement.&quot; True meaning &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;, &lt;/span>; thereby supporting Zhang Wenyang and Beijing Xinye. Yangcheng Coal Transport was dissatisfied and appealed to the Supreme Court and Shanxi Provincial High Court respectively. Since then, there has been no progress in the two cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Supreme People’s Court and the Shanxi Provincial High Court, which were responsible for the final review this time, believed that the entire transfer consideration of the 28% stake in Jinhai Energy involved included both the 8.4 million yuan clearly agreed in the transfer agreement and Zhang Xinming’s Fang used the business interests of 560 million yuan for 6 years through entrusted loans at low interest rates. Therefore, the original judgment was revoked and the validity of the equity transfer agreement was recognized. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The core requirement of the market economy legal system is the protection of property rights. These two judgments demonstrate the Supreme Court’s respect for the order of market transactions and the expression of the will of market entities.” Yangcheng Coal Transportation Lawyer Hu Xiaoyong told Southern Weekend reporters. He has taken over the equity dispute between Yangcheng Coal Transportation and Zhang Xinmingfang since 2012. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Commercial interests can be understood as opportunity value.” Hu Xiaoyong explained that Zhang Xinming obtained the opportunity value of using hundreds of millions of yuan of funds at low interest rates for 6 years, and then used it to invest in other real estate projects, thereby obtaining huge commercial interests. . These commercial interests together constitute the equity transfer price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On September 18, 2023&lt;/span>;, the Supreme People’s Court also made a final judgment on Beijing Xinye’s lawsuit against Qinhe Investment, revoking the original judgment and supporting some of Qinhe Investment’s requests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2011&lt;/span>;, Beijing Xinye sued Qinhe Investment, saying that the two parties agreed that Qinhe Investment would transfer 15% of the equity transfer money to Beijing Xinye in the form of a loan, totaling 375 million yuan, 25 million yuan per share. &lt;span>;Beijing Xinye changed the equity information to the name of Qinhe Investment as promised&lt;/span>; Qinhe Investment only paid 200 million yuan, leaving 175 million yuan unpaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing Xinye believed that Qinhe Investment constituted a fundamental breach of contract, and requested the first instance judgment to terminate the equity transfer agreement and the loan agreement between the two parties, and to allow the latter to return the equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial of the case, Yan Qi, the legal representative of Beijing Xinye, denied that he had signed a supplementary agreement with Qinhe Investment, that is, the equity transfer amount was changed from 4.5 million yuan to 200 million yuan, and also reported to the police that he had signed a supplementary agreement with Qinhe Investment. The agreement was &quot;forged.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the Shanxi Provincial High Court also quoted &quot;Judgment No. 76&quot; and stated that &quot;Judgment No. 76&quot; and the 15% shares involved in the above-mentioned case &quot;were based on the same background, at the same shareholder meeting, at the same time.&quot; , changed at the same time with the same price per share&quot;, it is believed that &quot;the equity transfer price of 300,000 yuan per share is obviously low.&quot; In the end, it was ruled that the agreement was invalid and Qinhe Investment returned its equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinhe Investment was dissatisfied with the above-mentioned first-instance judgment and appealed to the Supreme Court. On May 29, 2013, the Supreme People&#39;s Court formed a collegial panel to hear the case, but nothing happened. In January 2023, the Supreme People’s Court heard the case again after the change of the collegial bench. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, the Supreme People’s Court accepted the supplementary agreement and determined that Qinhe Investment should pay Beijing Xinye the equity transfer price of 200 million yuan. It was finally recognized that Qinhe Investment had paid 147.265 million yuan for the equity transfer, corresponding to all 11.044875% of the equity, and the court ordered Qinhe Investment to return the remaining 3.955125% equity to Beijing Xinye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Basically fair.” Ji Jingwu, attorney for Qinhe Investment, told Southern Weekend reporters, but the judgment is still unsatisfactory. In his view, Beijing Xinye had admitted in the first instance that Qinhe Investment had paid 200 million yuan for the equity transfer, so Qinhe Investment no longer needed to prove this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, Ji Jingwu believed that &lt;span>; Beijing Xinye’s lawsuit on the grounds that Qinhe Investment failed to perform the loan agreement cannot be established, and the court should dismiss Beijing Xinye’s lawsuit in accordance with the law. The current judgment results in changing its litigation claims. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Empty the cage and change the bird&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There is still one retrial to uphold the original verdict, which is also the earliest verdict among the four retrial cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 12, 2009, Wang Xiangdong, a shareholder of Jinhai Energy, signed a letter of authorization entrusting Yan Qi to handle the transfer of Jinhai Energy&#39;s equity interests. Yan Qi has served as the legal representative of Beijing Xinye and Jinhai Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 9 of that year, Yan Qi signed an equity transfer agreement with Qinhe Investment on behalf of Wang Xiangdong, stipulating that Wang Xiangdong would transfer 1% of the equity he held to Qinhe Investment for a price of 300,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2011, Wang Xiangdong took Qinhe Investment to court. The reason was that the equity transfer price was too low. Please terminate the transfer agreement and return the equity. The case went through two trials, and the Shanxi Provincial High Court of the second instance upheld the original verdict on September 27, 2012, supporting Wang Xiangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xiangdong acknowledged the authenticity of the power of attorney during the trial, but said he had no knowledge of the equity transfer and did not agree to transfer equity worth more than 20 million yuan with a registered capital value of 300,000 yuan. transfer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both courts of both instances held that the equity transfer price of 300,000 yuan was significantly lower than the transfer price that Yan Qi and Qinhe Investment knew of, and both parties transferred Wang Xiangdong’s equity at an obviously too low price without Wang Xiangdong’s consent. equity, harming its interests, and the behavior of Yan Qi and Qinhe Investment constituted malicious collusion. Qinhe Investment was dissatisfied and applied to the Supreme Court for retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main basis for the court of first instance to judge that Yan Qi knew that the equity transfer price was too low was the supplementary agreement signed between Beijing Xinye and Qinhe Investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 28, 2023, the Supreme People’s Court made a final judgment on the case, still based on the supplementary agreement, and determined that 1% of Jinhai Energy’s equity would exceed 13 million yuan. Yan Qi and Qinhe Investment jointly Wang Xiangdong&#39;s rights and interests were damaged and the original verdict was upheld. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ji Jingwu’s view, the case between Wang Xiangdong and Qinhe Investment is the simplest in the series of lawsuits over Jinhai Coal Mine equity disputes. “Does such a simple case need to be tried for 10 years?”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; He believes that Wang Xiangdong entrusted Yan Qi with full authority to handle the equity transfer, so the equity transfer agreement signed by Yan Qi on behalf of Wang Xiangdong and Qinhe Investment did not exceed the agency authority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, before the judgment of this case, the authenticity of the supplementary agreement had not been recognized by any court. Secondly, even if the agreement is genuine, the court determined that the equity transfer price in this case was low and unreasonable based on an agreement between a party outside the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wonder if the disputes between shareholders can stop here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, after reexamination, the equity structure of Jinhai Energy has become: Zhang Xinmingfang 46%, Yangcheng Coal Transportation 28%, Beijing Xinye 13.955125%, Qinhe Investment 11.044875%, and Wang Xiangdong 1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jinhai Coal Mine, which was supposed to shine, has been in a state of stagnation over the years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2021 coal mine classification list released by the Office of the Work Safety Committee of the Shanxi Provincial People&#39;s Government shows that Jinhai Coal Mine is a Class D coal mine, that is, a coal mine that has been suspended for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Jinhai Coal Mine may have new progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2021, Jinhai Coal Mine appeared in the list of the first batch of projects released by Shanxi Provincial state-owned enterprises in 2021. The provincial state-owned enterprise is Jinneng Holding Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jinneng Group). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Empty the cage and replace the bird&quot; is a key measure in the reform of Shanxi state-owned enterprises, which specifically includes disposing of inefficient and ineffective assets to effectively revitalize accumulated funds; selling part of the equity to recover cash while introducing various types of capital to achieve equity diversification; obtain funds by selling part of the shares of listed companies, optimize the equity structure of listed companies, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Jinhai Coal Mine is under the responsibility of Jinneng Group may be because Jinneng Group controls Yangcheng Coal Transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 20, 2022, the Yangcheng County People&#39;s Government Office issued the &quot;Notice on the Establishment of the Yangcheng Daning Jinhai Coal Mine Project Construction Leading Group&quot;. The notice stated that the Jinhai Coal Mine plans to officially start construction in the fourth quarter of 2022 , the construction period is two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters repeatedly interviewed Zhang Wenyang (who holds Zhang Xinming’s behalf) and Beijing Xinye’s attorney through phone calls and text messages, but both declined to be interviewed. &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[烂尾楼生活翻篇了，昆明“别样幸福城”业主圆了住房梦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260052]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“全国”到“中央”， 这些会议在升格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260058]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 31, 2023, the Central Financial Work Conference closed. Photo provided by People&#39;s Vision&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/1d131217ee.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/1d131217ee.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257184&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;On October 31, 2023, the Central Financial Work Conference concluded. Photo courtesy of People’s Vision&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 31, 2023, the Central Financial Work Conference concluded, and the concept of &quot;financial power&quot; was proposed for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;If the finance is not strong, the blood is not connected.&quot; Zhang Zhanbin, director of the Chinese Modernization Research Center of the Central Party School (National Academy of Administration), told Southern Weekend reporters that the &quot;financial power&quot; is This concept was first proposed at the Central Financial Work Conference, reflecting the urgency of financial work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The name of the meeting is &quot;Central Financial Work Conference&quot;, which reflects the central government&#39;s great importance to financial work. The last time a high-profile meeting in the financial field was held was in 2017. The meeting was called the &quot;National Financial Work Conference&quot; and was attended by five members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau. This time, all seven members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau attended, and relevant statements such as &quot;the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee on financial work must be upheld&quot; appeared four times in the meeting draft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only the financial work conference, Southern Weekend reporters found that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the National Political and Legal Work Conference, the National United Front Work Conference, the National Urban Work Conference, The National Talent Work Conference and others have been upgraded to work conferences held in the name of the central government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ruan Siyu, director of the Department of Political Science and Administration at South China Normal University, has long studied conference politics. In his opinion, the original national work conferences were generally within the system. The meeting was upgraded to a working meeting held in the name of the central government, which reflected the importance of the Party Central Committee in this field and facilitated the strengthening of centralized and unified leadership. &quot;Many problems cannot be solved within the department.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Weak financial supervision and governance capabilities&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In In economic development, finance plays the role of “bloodline”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Zhanbin believes that major cases in the financial field are occurring frequently, financial supervision still has problems, the financial system still needs to be improved, and financial security and stability need to be maintained to prevent them from happening. The bottom line of systemic risks, &quot;Compared with the blueprint for financial power, the gap is reflected in &quot;many problems cannot be solved within the department&quot;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Central Financial Work Conference clearly pointed out that “various contradictions and problems in the financial field are intertwined and influence each other, and some are very prominent, and hidden economic and financial risks are still relatively high. The quality and efficiency of financial services to the real economy are not high, financial chaos and corruption problems persist, and financial supervision and governance capabilities are weak.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as March 2023 In September, the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; issued by the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council proposed the establishment of the Central Financial Commission and the Central Financial Working Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Central Financial Work Conference pointed out that it is necessary to improve the system and mechanism of the party&#39;s leadership in financial work, give full play to the role of the Central Financial Commission and the Central Financial Working Committee, and implement territorial responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Zhang Zhanbin&#39;s view, this reflects the central government&#39;s determination to lead financial work and helps eliminate the blind pursuit of local interests in economic development, while Some practices that ignore the overall interests of the country and the overall benefits of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Short meeting time, long preparation time&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the whole country The Financial Work Conference was upgraded to the Central Financial Work Conference. Ruan Siyu’s understanding is that the former is usually organized by a ministry or commission of the State Council, while the latter is under the guidance of the central organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the National Political and Legal Work Conference was first upgraded to the Central Political and Legal Work Conference in 2014. Since then, the National United Front Work Conference, the National Urban Work Conference, The National Talent Work Conference and others have been upgraded one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Ruan Siyu&#39;s view, the upgrade of the meeting not only reflects the importance that the Party Central Committee attaches to a certain field, but also makes the coordination between the Party Central Committee and local party committees smoother at the practical level. Many issues &quot;require the party committee to come forward and advance them as a whole.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take talent work as an example. In 2021, the &quot;National Talent Work Conference&quot; will be upgraded to the &quot;Central Talent Work Conference&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The meeting called for improving the talent work pattern in which the party committee leads the unified leadership, the organizational department takes the lead in grasping the overall situation, functional departments perform their respective duties and cooperate closely, and social forces participate extensively. Government departments at all levels including education, science and technology, industry and information technology, security, human resources and social security, culture and tourism, state-owned assets, finance, foreign affairs, etc., give full play to their functions and work together to implement various tasks of talent work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past, some departments did not have a starting point to carry out talent work. Organizational departments focused on talent work, but social security issues need to be solved by the human resources and social security departments. If teachers are introduced, they cannot do without it. Education sector policies. Ruan Siyu believes that after the Party Central Committee and local party committees attach great importance to it and require all departments to do a good job in talent issues, the enthusiasm and initiative of each department have been improved, and &quot;there is more space.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of meeting procedures, the working meeting convened in the name of the central government &quot;the meeting time is very short, but the preparation for the meeting is very long&quot;, and the research on relevant issues is relatively mature. There are clear instructions on future development directions and reform ideas. Most national work conferences only involve policy briefings, work summaries and task assignments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the work conference convened in the name of the central government, all-round publicity will be carried out at the national level. At the same time, the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commission will also carry out the implementation of the party’s line, principles and policies. Carry out patrol inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the upgrade of national work conferences, some meetings that had not been held before were also held in the name of the central government after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, the Party Central Committee convened the Central Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference Working Conference, and two years later, the Central People&#39;s Congress Working Conference was held. This was the first time in the history of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[福原爱或面临2年以上监禁：抚养权的归属应以有利于孩子成长为原则丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260062]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 15:05:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The love affair and marriage changes of Fukuhara Ai and Taiwanese Jiang Hongjie have always attracted widespread media attention. Currently, due to a criminal complaint filed by her ex-husband with the police, &quot;Ai Fukuhara may face more than 2 years in prison&quot;, which has triggered a lot of discussion on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mainland netizens have always had a good impression of Fukuhara Ai. She is cute, fluent in Chinese, and her Northeastern dialect, which tastes like corn pancakes, is very friendly. After Fukuhara Ai&#39;s affair and marriage change, many mainland netizens still regard themselves as &quot;family members&quot; and are willing to speak for her. This has led to a very interesting phenomenon: At present, Fukuhara Ai&#39;s public opinion image in Japan and Taiwan is relatively negative, but in mainland China it is still positive. This is probably the power of true love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fukuhara Ai was born in 1988. He started playing table tennis at the age of 3. He was once the main player of the Japanese national team and participated in many Olympic Games. He is perhaps the most popular Japanese athlete among the Chinese people. Jiang Hongjie is a table tennis player on the Taipei team. The two officially announced their marriage in September 2016. They gave birth to a daughter in 2017 and a boy in 2019. They announced their divorce in July 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the marriage change, some Japanese media reported that Fukuhara Ai looked happy on the surface, but in fact she had silently endured years of verbal violence from her husband and his family; her husband’s family also treated her as a cash cow. The information read from it is that Jiang Hongjie&#39;s family &quot;eat soft food&quot; and are not grateful. At that time, public opinion was overwhelmingly sympathetic to Fukuhara Ai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, things soon took a turn for the worse. During her marriage, Ai Fukuhara was photographed by the media having a very intimate behavior with a married man, and they went to a hotel to spend the night together. At that time, she did not admit that she had cheated on her, saying that the other person was her good friend and they lived in the same room. After the divorce, Fukuhara Ai and the man openly fell in love. Then, the man&#39;s ex-wife came out and complained that their divorce was due to the intervention of a third party by Ai Fukuhara. This caused the persona and image that Ai Fukuhara had worked so hard to cultivate to suddenly collapse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Frankly speaking, Jiang Hongjie and his family have verbally despised and insulted Ai Fukuhara, treating her as a tool to make money. Outsiders have no way of confirming the truth and can only have a different opinion. However, Ai Fukuhara was later caught cheating and lying, which became a real evidence, which lowered the credibility of these revelations. Many people will speculate that these so-called revelations are because they have a new love, and in order to reduce the moral pressure and public criticism of their marriage, they deliberately feed it to the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, when Fukuhara Ai was exposed to have cheated on her, her mother was still at Jiang Hongjie’s house and returned to Japan soon thereafter. Media reports stated that the mother decided to return to Japan because she felt she had no position and was embarrassed to stay any longer. Later, her mother even refused to live with Fukuhara Ai, indicating that she had objections to her cheating and divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 27 this year, Jiang Hongjie held a press conference in Japan and said: Due to the complete loss of contact with Fukuhara Ai, he has not seen his children for a year. Previously, Fukuhara Ai secretly brought her son back to Japan from Taiwan on the pretext of visiting. Jiang Hongjie announced: &quot;I have something to report. I received the judgment result from the Japanese court on July 20. The content is the court&#39;s order requiring Miss Fukuhara Ai to deliver the child to me. I am very grateful for the Japanese court&#39;s judgment and hope to hurry up.&quot; Meet the children.&quot; Fukuhara Ainori stated through her lawyer: The Japanese court&#39;s ruling is only a temporary sanction and not a final judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, more than two months have passed and the matter has not been resolved, so Jiang Hongjie took further legal action. According to the Japanese Criminal Code, there is the crime of &quot;abduction and abduction of minors&quot; (Article 224), and the perpetrators may be sentenced to not less than three months and not more than seven years of hard labor; there is the crime of &quot;abduction and abduction for the purpose of transfer abroad&quot; (Article 226), Seizing and abducting people abroad may result in a sentence of not less than 2 years of hard labor. This has nothing to do with whether the perpetrator is a relative or whether it is for profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Jiang Hongjie’s purpose is to get his son back, not to put Fukuhara Ai in jail. How this matter develops remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two direct interpretations of this matter. First, the concept of rule of law in Japanese society is quite strong. The court ruled that it respects the merits and legal principles of the matter, neither conciliates nor acknowledges the fait accompli, nor does it favor Fukuhara Ai because she is a Japanese national. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the family values ​​and moral concepts in Japanese society are quite strong. Public opinion has a low tolerance for marital infidelity and lies. It’s okay to complain that your marriage is unhappy and that you want to pursue freedom and true love, but please wait until you’re divorced before talking about it. If a public figure cheats on his wife and lies to the public, after the cheating is confirmed and the lie is exposed, the backlash and recoil will be considerable, and his persona, image and career will be greatly affected. Influence. In the eyes of the public, on the basis of these criminal records, secretly taking the child away from the father and refusing to comply with the court&#39;s order is morally and legally unreasonable, and it is difficult to empathize and sympathize with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A further thought is: Even if we promise each other before marriage, some marriages will always break down, and if there are children, they will often involve custody battles. If one party wants the other party not, this is easy to handle and can be solved through a divorce agreement. It is more difficult to handle whether both parties want it or neither wants it. There have been cases in China where couples wanted to divorce, but neither wanted custody of their children, and then the court refused to allow the divorce. The worst among them was the children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both parties want the custody of their children, but the agreement cannot resolve the matter, and it finally goes to court. How should the court decide? Of course, the child&#39;s wishes should be considered and which party he wants to be with. However, if the child cannot express his wishes when he is very young, or the wishes expressed by the child may not be in his or her best interests, how will the court consider this? It is still necessary to consider which parent&#39;s custody is most beneficial to the child&#39;s physical and mental health and growth, and the interests of adult men and women cannot be placed above the interests of the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One party has better economic conditions, educational background, and a legitimate and stable career, which should be an advantage. Because children living with such a father or mother will not only get better care in life, but the adults themselves are also good role models and can teach children better family education through precepts and deeds, especially values ​​education, which is more conducive to children&#39;s good health. Character development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If one party makes a major mistake during the divorce process, violates morality or the law, and shows problems with personal values ​​and character, then the child&#39;s values ​​may be distorted by living with such an adult. Few people face up to their mistakes, so when they make major mistakes, they either distort the facts and give their children a wrong version of the narrative, or they distort the standards for judging right and wrong, which are values, for example, beautifying one&#39;s own infidelity as the supremacy of true love. No matter what kind of situation, it is detrimental to the growth of the child, or it may make the child hate adults who are not at fault, or it may make the child&#39;s mind and values ​​​​very different from ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if the court must determine the ownership of child custody, the principle that is most conducive to the child&#39;s growth should be established, and the child should be allowed to stay with the adult who loves him/her the most, and should not condone the struggle for custody. In order to fight for a larger share of property, or to fight for custody rights as a means of revenge on the other half. Children should be the purpose, not the tool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新鲜白菜凑厨余？垃圾不仅要分，更要减]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260032]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/06/3adc4c0617.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 06/3adc4c0617.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257159&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 31, witnesses saw a piece of garbage on the streets of Zhongguancun At the bucket station, sanitation workers unpack fresh cabbage and chop it into pieces to collect food waste. Interviewee/Photo provided&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The round, crispy and fresh Chinese cabbage was not brought to the table, but spread on the floor. A sanitation worker at the garbage sorting bin station used a shovel to chop the vegetables into pieces. The green and white chopped vegetables were dumped into the green trash can for &quot;food waste&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 31, 2023, staff from the China Biodiversity Conservation and Green Development Foundation were investigating plastic waste. Unexpectedly, at the corner of Zhongguancun Street in Haidian District, Seeing such a scene, many surrounding residents also stopped to watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Everyone feels sorry for this cabbage. It&#39;s such a waste. The sanitation workers ignore us and just shovel vegetables.&quot; An eyewitness told Southern Weekend reporters that they I was surprised and angry when I saw the sanitation worker&#39;s skillful movements, so I took a video and uploaded it to the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This video quickly attracted attention. On the evening of November 1, the Zhongguancun Sub-district Office issued a statement on the official WeChat account &quot;Lohas Zhongguancun&quot;, admitting that the location of the garbage classification bin station posted online is located in the Baofu Temple bungalow area of ​​Kexu Community in the street. The person involved is Beijing Green. An employee of Xincheng City Environmental Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Beijing Luxin&quot;) &quot;because the kitchen waste sorting task for the month had not been completed at the end of the month, the cabbage from the company&#39;s internal canteen was used as food waste for disposal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4906186e28.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1267&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4906186e28.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月1日傍晚，中关村街道办事处在官方微信号“乐活中关村”发布情况说明。公众号截图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;清华大学环境学院教授刘建国对南方周末记者说，北京垃圾分类这些年进步显著，市民垃圾分类的意识大幅提升，行为也更加普遍，但不平衡不充分的问题依然存在。 “此次事件表面上看，是第三方企业为自身利益采取的荒唐行为，实际体现了垃圾分类管理难以将责任触达垃圾产生者。”刘建国表示，垃圾分类是涉及千家万户的基层社会治理工作，对象本质上还是人，而不是垃圾，实际工作中“不能只见垃圾不见人”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;何为厨余垃圾分拣任务&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月2日15时许，南方周末记者来到“白菜凑厨余”事发地，视频中那位身着亮橙色制服的环卫工不在现场，只有一位穿着蓝色马甲的工人正在站内清扫。被询问“大白菜充当厨余垃圾”事件时，这位工人说“不知道，我今天刚来”，自称“居委会第一天调我过来（工作），现雇的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;视频中标记着第004号的垃圾分类桶站已被打扫干净，地面也看不出大白菜的痕迹。多个垃圾桶摆放井然有序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/f372f11b49.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/f372f11b49.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257161&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月2日下午，事发地垃圾分类桶站新来的一名环卫工人正在清扫，地面已看不出大白菜的痕迹。南方周末实习生习丽杰/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;《北京市生活垃圾管理条例》（以下简称《条例》）于2020年5月1日开始执行，将生活垃圾分为厨余垃圾、可回收物、有害垃圾、其他垃圾四类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为何涉事公司每月还有厨余垃圾分拣任务？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“垃圾分类是一个复杂的系统工程，环环相扣，有相关考核指标正常，比如垃圾分类知晓率、各类垃圾分拣量（或分出率）等。”贵州高远环保咨询有限公司董事长兰亚军对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据《条例》，北京市将制定规则引导社会投资进入生活垃圾清扫、收集、运输、处理及循环利用等领域。上述“情况说明”也提到，北京绿鑫日常工作是保证桶站周围干净整洁、督促居民正确投放厨余垃圾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“现实生活中，一些居民在家里没有分类或者分得不对，到了垃圾站，只好由垃圾分类指导员帮着二次分拣。”兰亚军说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者走访事发地周围社区发现，附近市民普遍具有较强的垃圾分类意识，不同垃圾投放进入不同的垃圾桶，到点会有专员来提醒市民分类投放，厨余垃圾中不能出现纸张和塑料。但市民投放厨余垃圾无需破袋，专员负责后续的检查和再分拣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“企查查”显示，涉事公司北京绿鑫成立于2014年7月，注册资本300万元。北京绿鑫官网显示，有在职员工260余人,各类环保作业车辆数百部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我们现在也的确挺难，积极解决，自己的员工该处罚处罚，现在正在开会讨论这个问题。”11月2日上午，北京绿鑫相关负责人对南方周末记者表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;关于后续北京绿鑫将面临何种处罚，往后能否继续为中关村街道提供垃圾分类服务，街道办宣传负责人在电话中婉拒了南方周末记者采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;厨余垃圾分类考核&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;事发后有评论认为，作为第三方运维公司，白菜凑厨余是为了获取政府补贴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2017年发布的《海淀区推进生活垃圾分类工作方案》显示，“对物业单位或专业公司分出的厨余垃圾按量予以补贴（1700元/吨）”。相较1700元/吨的补贴，北京新发地大白菜的近期批发价在0.3元/斤左右，即600元/吨，白菜变厨余垃圾，身价居然翻了三倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;各地经济发展水平不同，对垃圾分类的重视程度不同，有的按桶数补贴，也有像北京对厨余垃圾按吨数补贴，1700元/吨在全国属较高的补贴水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过2020年推行的《条例》中，只提及北京市制定鼓励政策，未提及金额。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京绿鑫这样的运维公司，实际上属于政府采购的第三方服务。除二次分拣厨余垃圾，还有其他工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;例如，2023年9月25日，朝阳区望京街道发布2023-2024年度垃圾分类第三方服务中标公告，总中标成交金额为558万余元，乙方整理员需负责厨余垃圾的收集，保证厨余垃圾纯净度，对未按规范投放的混合垃圾进行二次分拣；乙方还需要负责垃圾桶保洁、建立再生资源回收体系；配合属地社区、物业等开展垃圾分类工作，接受政府检查考核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“垃圾分类补贴和厨余垃圾拣出率制度设计的初衷是好的，鼓励企业更好完成垃圾分类工作，但政策制定者可能也没有料想到企业&#39;走捷径&#39;。”兰亚军说，“如果企业无法完成考核指标，不但可能难以拿到补贴，还可能会被地方主管部门批评，影响后续的签约，主管部门或许也要承担监管不力的责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不仅公司有指标，政府也有考核压力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;海淀区城市管理委员会官方微信号“海淀城事”显示，区生活垃圾分类工作领导小组曾对各街镇垃圾分类工作进行考核，列红黄绿榜公示和排名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;以2023年2月为例，中关村街道以77.76分位列黄榜第三，在全榜排名第11，属于海淀区中上水平。南方周末记者注意到，在北京海淀区，除了街道之间要评比垃圾分类的效果，小区之间也要争上游，表现好的会被公开表扬。类似的评优，在各大城市比比皆是。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京市海淀区的考核中，厨余垃圾分出率在总分100中占据10分。值得注意的是，南方周末记者未从公开资料找到北京市厨余垃圾分出率的具体考核指标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/88286f46cd.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;886&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/88286f46cd.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257162&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年3月14日，海淀区城市管理委员会在官方微信号“海淀城事”上发布垃圾分类考核的相关信息。公众号截图。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;全国各地公布的生活垃圾考核办法中，几乎没有对厨余垃圾分拣率作出具体要求，绝大多数是综合表现的考评，但在实际工作中，部分地区有具体要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘建国对南方周末记者介绍，北京设置的考核指标在18%左右，上述朝阳区望京街道的招标公告也提及，厨余垃圾收集及清运，收集率达18%以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者搜寻资料发现，18%在全国来看并不高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;以垃圾分类较好的上海为例，根据上海市绿化市容局数据，湿垃圾分出量基本稳定在干湿垃圾总量35%左右；根据上海环境卫生工程设计院2023年6月的数据，厨余垃圾占生活垃圾总量的30%左右。据环卫行业自媒体“环卫之声”，厨余垃圾分拣率普遍在20%-30%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月3日，央广网报道称，海淀区个别地区的分出率要达到20%，有生活垃圾投放点负责人表示，在冬天难完成这个指标，因为瓜果皮核等较少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;兰亚军看来，涉事公司没有分出足够的厨余垃圾，拿大白菜凑数肯定错了，但厨余垃圾分出率不光是第三方企业的工作，也要看前期宣传动员的力度大不大，市民参与度高，指标容易完成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;源头减量更重要&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;垃圾管理中，分类只是前端工作，分出来的厨余垃圾还需后续处置，处置价格不菲，设备投资更是动辄上亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;3R原则已普及多年，reduce (减量化)、reuse(再使用)、recycle (资源化)的顺序中，减量化排在最前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021年，北京市海淀区城市管理指挥中心主任李伟撰文写道，全区厨余垃圾分出量快速增长，分出率稳定在18.5%以上，其他垃圾量同比下降了28.68%，进入垃圾焚烧和填埋设施的生活垃圾处理量增速控制在了4%以内，生活垃圾源头总量控制在97.22万吨的指标以内。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从事垃圾分类工作十余年，兰亚军也认同垃圾分类的目的不是精心分成四类，而是从源头减量，无需光盯着厨余垃圾分出量（或分出率）一个指标。他认为，更值得关注的指标还有末端进入垃圾填埋场/发电厂的垃圾总量（或人均量）、处理的成本（或人均成本）降低了多少。 “现在政府也过紧日子，垃圾分类的钱从哪里来，怎么花在刀刃上，提质增效是很实际的问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会11月4日闭幕，累计境外采购商比上届增长超50%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260028]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 13:00:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, in the venue of the third phase of the Canton Fair, A buyer passes by a large panda doll.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/d53c3c3321.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/d53c3c3321.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, at the venue of the third phase of the Canton Fair, buyers passed by a large panda doll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, the 134th Canton Fair concluded successfully in Guangzhou, and the online platform operated normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The total exhibition area of ​​this Canton Fair is 1.55 million square meters, with more than 28,000 exhibiting companies and a total of 74,000 booths. The exhibition scale has reached a new high. A total of 198,000 overseas purchasers attended the exhibition during the 15-day exhibition period, an increase of over 50% compared to the previous session. There were 126,343 buyers from countries co-constructing the “One Belt and One Road”, accounting for 63.9%, an increase of 68.6% over the previous session. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the cumulative number of overseas buyers attending the 134th Canton Fair increased by more than 50% compared with the previous session.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/2da5a01466.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/06/2da5a01466.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257150&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, the cumulative number of overseas buyers attending the 134th Canton Fair increased by more than 50% compared with the previous session. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, several overseas buyers were trying out massage seats.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/12519afa74.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /06/12519afa74.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257151&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, several overseas Buyers are trying out massage chairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This year&#39;s Canton Fair has been attended by overseas buyers enthusiastically. The more open and dynamic Canton Fair has attracted buyers from all over the world. Offline export transactions reached US$22.3 billion, an increase of 2.8% over the 133rd session, showing a restorative growth trend. The export turnover of brand enterprises was US$6.35 billion, an increase of 7.8% over the 133rd session, accounting for 28.5% of the total export turnover. Transactions with countries co-building the Belt and Road Initiative amounted to US$12.27 billion, an increase of 2% over the 133rd session. Exhibitors said that the &quot;rapid return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the exhibition. In addition to signing orders on-site, buyers are constantly making follow-up appointments to visit factories, workshops, and production capacity, and are expected to reach more cooperation in the future. The quality of overseas purchasers attending this Canton Fair has improved and they are actively placing orders, which further enhances the confidence of enterprises in foreign trade exports next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, a bubble machine attracted the attention of overseas buyers.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/06/ac1d0fb344.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/06/ac1d0fb344.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a The bubble machine has attracted the attention of overseas buyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair were selecting colorful dolls and toys.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/06/b645302e77.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/b645302e77.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong , overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair are selecting colorful dolls and toys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, the optimization of the exhibition area structure of this Canton Fair has achieved remarkable results, and innovative exhibits have emerged in large numbers. Exhibitors have uploaded a total of more than 2.75 million exhibits to the online platform, including more than 700,000 new products, about 110,000 smart products, more than 430,000 green and low-carbon products, and about 230,000 independent intellectual property products. A total of 401 new product debut events were held. The 2023 Canton Fair Design Innovation Award (CF Award) award ceremony was held to award 141 innovative products from 118 units. New products, new technologies, new materials, new processes, and new services are emerging one after another. High-end intelligent, green and low-carbon products have become mainstream, and innovative and creative products are deeply favored. From small and beautiful new consumer products to cutting-edge cutting-edge technology, from simple OEM to going global with their own brands, from selling products to providing solutions, from traditional industries to emerging fields, Chinese companies continue to climb to the mid-to-high end of the industrial chain, demonstrating This reflects the strong development resilience and innovative vitality of China’s foreign trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair were selecting cute animal dolls.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7a1ea2d941.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/7a1ea2d941.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257154&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong , overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair are selecting cute animal dolls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers negotiated in the exhibition area of ​​a baby stroller brand.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/06/e9d743c1c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/06/e9d743c1c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas Buyers are negotiating in the exhibition area of ​​a baby stroller brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A total of 650 companies from 43 countries and regions participated in this year&#39;s Canton Fair Import Exhibition, focusing on displaying products such as intelligent manufacturing, quality home furnishings, and leisure life. The participating countries of the “Belt and Road Initiative” accounted for 60% of the exhibitors. Overseas exhibitors said that the Canton Fair Import Expo has built a fast channel for them to enter the Chinese market, allowing them to share the &quot;super traffic&quot; of the Canton Fair, while also meeting a large number of customers from all over the world, bringing new opportunities to expand the global market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Import Exhibition was attended by 650 companies from 43 countries and regions&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4e80921716.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/06/4e80921716.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257156&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Import Exhibition. A total of 650 companies from 43 countries and regions participated in the exhibition&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Exhibition General The total area is 1.55 million square meters, with more than 28,000 exhibitors and a total of 74,000 booths.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/36c7b8c2a9.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/36c7b8c2a9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 257157&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair has a total exhibition area of ​​1.55 million square meters, and exhibitors There are over 28,000 exhibitors, with a total of 74,000 booths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is understood that after the closing of this Canton Fair, the online platform will continue to be open. In addition to the functions of exhibitor connection and appointment negotiation, the other functions will be operated on a regular basis throughout the year. The 135th Canton Fair will be held from April 15 to May 5, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas buyer was browsing a brochure. The &quot;quick return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the Canton Fair. &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/cb7159e811.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/cb7159e811.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257158&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas buyer was browsing a brochure. The &quot;rapid return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the Canton Fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天津助学金事件通报：不存在国家助学金名额遭“挤占”情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260050]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 12:23:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, students have reported on the Internet about our school’s scholarship evaluation issues, which has attracted social attention. We are very grateful to the media and netizens for their concern for our students and their supervision of school work. The school set up a special work class to review relevant archives and materials, get an in-depth understanding of the situation from relevant teachers and students in the school, and organized a working group to conduct on-site visits and investigations in three students&#39; places of origin. The relevant situation has also been reported to relevant students. The relevant situation is now reported as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, since the student concerned raised objections to the identification of students with difficulties in the class on September 18, the person in charge of the financial aid work at both the school and college levels has maintained communication with the student and listened patiently to him. The opinions and appeals indicate that the school understands its actual difficulties and meets the conditions for receiving national scholarships in accordance with regulations. The specific grade is determined after comprehensive evaluation in accordance with relevant procedures. Since the student&#39;s enrollment, the local government and relevant relatives have guaranteed his tuition and living expenses. He has received second-class national scholarships for his freshman and sophomore years, and all have been paid out. The comprehensive evaluation for the junior year is expected to receive a second-class national scholarship. The college has announced the evaluation results from October 24th to October 27th. There is no &quot;crowding&quot; of the national scholarship quota. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, the family and personal circumstances of the other two students involved meet the conditions for financial aid for needy students. One student is expected to receive a second-class national scholarship this school year through comprehensive evaluation, and the other student is evaluated comprehensively for this school year. The candidate is expected to receive the National Inspirational Scholarship. No material fraud was found, the assessment complied with relevant regulations, and no &quot;malfeasance and abuse of power&quot; issues were found. The daily necessities alleged in the video were purchased with the above-mentioned students’ income from their work-study studies or were gifts from their relatives. Their high consumption behavior has been verified to be untrue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After repeated investigations by the school, there are no children of martyrs among the students at school, and there is no situation where the children of martyrs are not supported. All orphans among current students who have been identified by the civil affairs department have enjoyed state funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation also found that the relevant departments of the school were insufficient in their sincerity and care for students when carrying out funding work. The school will carefully summarize, further refine and optimize the student aid work, and provide more warmth and care to students from families with financial difficulties. We would like to thank all sectors of society for their concern, support and assistance to our school and related students, and welcome all sectors of society to continue to supervise and guide the work of our school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寒潮来袭羽绒服涨价，你有在准备过冬吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260042]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, strong winds, cooling, rain and snow have occurred in many places in the north. The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue orange blizzard warnings, cold wave blue warnings and strong wind blue warnings at 6:00 on November 6, and the heavy snowfall in Northeast China has entered its strongest period. Some media visited many wholesalers in Yiwu and learned that due to the increase in raw material prices this year, the purchase price of down jackets has generally increased. In addition to offline stores, e-commerce platforms are also celebrating Double Eleven, and gloves, thermos cups, and thermal underwear from many brand stores are also selling well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, summer is not over yet for some areas in the south, such as Guangzhou. Since summer officially started on April 11, the summer of 2023 in Guangzhou has exceeded 200 days, and this fall may be late. Moreover, an El Niño event is currently taking shape, and under its influence, temperatures in most central and eastern parts of my country will be higher than normal for the same period of the year. For many southern friends, down jackets are only used for a few days a year, and there are many who have never even bought a down jacket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Are you prepared for winter? Are you considering buying a down jacket for winter? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年各级政府支持就业创业资金超2000亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260030]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;1337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257144&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security Learned&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year various types of funds from governments at all levels&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Direct support for employment and entrepreneurship has exceeded 200 billion yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adjustment and optimization of employment stabilization policies&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Continue to implement the return policy until employment is stabilized&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue to expand from absorbing employment subsidies&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To promptly restart the one-time employment expansion subsidy&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Accelerate the release of policy dividends&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Injecting strong impetus into employment growth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to September&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10.22 million new jobs were created in urban areas across the country&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Complete the full-year target 85% of the target&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national urban surveyed unemployment rate at the end of September was 5%&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lower than the same period in 2019&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employment situation has generally improved and remained basically stable&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》，没写进报道的那些事丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260011]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Is there anyone else you particularly want to interview now? I was asked this question. I tried to count them on my fingers, but there seemed to be only a few. Qiu Litao may be one. I&#39;m looking forward to it after watching &quot;The Bomb Disposer 2&quot; at the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be able to create a huge allegory with big scenes of banging, banging and jingling bells, allowing the audience to take what they need and understand each other, is an amazing creative power. I wonder how this person recognizes his own expression. But Qiu Litao is obviously not someone who can talk about this. This may be a bit embarrassing for him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, when asked questions that are too serious and strict, he will usually say &quot;I didn&#39;t think so much&quot; and &quot;I can&#39;t make a movie if I think so.&quot; For example, when it comes to anarchism - which he corrects to anarchism - he says that the definition is too vague and he doesn&#39;t know what everyone is talking about when they say these words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao definitely does not &quot;think so little&quot;. This is my feeling when I watched the movie &quot;The Decameron of Sex Workers&quot; directed by him. Regarding the young lady&#39;s situation, the mockumentary had a lot of back and forth, flashes of swords and swords. They are not expressions of &quot;pretentiousness&quot;, but are full of market acumen, speculation and ridicule. It&#39;s quite clever, but also quite embarrassing, like someone has taken off your clothes. Qiu Litao doesn&#39;t like clear things. From a utilitarian point of view, he is of course more tolerant of gray and vagueness. You can call him rough, but there are so many things that help him enrich his semantics. Who can I ask to explain? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first watched &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, I liked the sense of relaxation - many things that others have to put effort into laying out - such as whether this character is convincing or not, whether he resembles that era or not, it is not Qiu Litao Something that can be confusing. His camera flicked by, and his lack of restraint even formed a style. But that’s it, sometimes it works sometimes... I want to explain to readers that I don’t think this is a very good movie, although it is not without its merits. For example, the audience can see people and people in the early 1990s in the cinema. society. One of my interviewees felt that Qiu Litao might need a good screenwriter to help him overcome the cultural barrier of making films outside of Hong Kong. This is a tolerant statement, and after completing the reporting and writing of the report, I am willing to give a tolerant understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; uses many details to restore the social scene of the early 1990s. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Qiu Litao has leg problems and walks with a long stride, but he works hard enough to make People ignore this. People should be able to understand this feeling. When we were young and could not travel far away, the TV was a magical door at home, which could take us to different countries and distant starry skies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the interview, I wrote an email to Director Qiu Litao and asked him to introduce the interviewees. He felt that it would be a bit embarrassing for him to come forward and tell his partners, &quot;The media did an exclusive interview with me, and I would like to interview you to talk about my story and working methods.&quot; But he listed the right names and ways I could contact them. This is not his responsibility. I am grateful for his understanding and sympathy for media work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interviewed the main creators behind &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, such as the producer, screenwriter, action director and assistant director. In addition to talking about Qiu Litao, I also talked about their own work. Some stories that couldn’t be written into the main manuscript, I wanted to record in my notes. I hope I live up to their expectations and time, and I hope this information is useful to readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When screenwriter Chen Daming received the invitation from Chinese Pictures, he heard that multiple versions of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; had been written. Chen Daming is familiar with that history. In the late 1980s, he stayed at the Beijing Film Academy to teach. During the period when &quot;trafficking&quot; was most popular, most of the people lining up in the hall of the film school and making phone calls were not talking about art, but reselling color TVs and jeeps. The most successful business was selling MiG fighter jets - this last detail was written into the film. The character played by Andy Lau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What he wanted to show in the script was animality. &quot;People don&#39;t care about anything when they are hungry.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The villain Miao Qingshan played by Huang Xuan is nicknamed Old D. He likes to listen to Shostakovich&#39;s music. There is not much metaphor in this setting. Originally, Chen Daming wanted to call him Lao Bei, referring to Beethoven, but it didn&#39;t seem to fit him, so he wanted to find a Russian composer. One day he met a neighbor in the courtyard, an Englishman who was a conductor in China, and recommended Shostakovich. Chen Daming feels that his works have &quot;black elements&quot; and &quot;seem to be fighting against black forces and evil forces.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257131&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scene after the Shostakovich concert in the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, action director Li Zhongzhi was filming with Jackie Chan , there is no script for the scenes he is responsible for, just one word, play. Now the action scenes have to be integrated with the plot of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Gui Youming made great efforts to introduce me to the team of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The art designer Zhao Hai has worked on &quot;Ming Dynasty 1566&quot; and &quot;Toward the Republic&quot;, and one of the computer special effects production teams has worked on &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;. With the help of a digital imaging technology referred to as DIT, Gui Youming can see the shooting scene from anywhere with his iPad. Because of this technology, producer Andy Lau was able to follow up on-site shooting every day in the quarantine hotel at the time. Gui Youming believes that this is a characteristic of the industrialization of the film industry. This technology is very helpful when shooting movies of a scale similar to &quot;The Wandering Earth 3&quot; and &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As the producer of the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, Andy Lau (left) relied on high-tech communications to improve work efficiency during the filming of the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao was particularly impressed by the scene at the international train track-changing station interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deputy director Wen Zhenwei contacted the National Railway Administration and got back a lot of information. Qiu Litao was not concerned about the ins and outs and technical details of the train&#39;s track change at the Sino-Russian border. He only wanted to know where the people on the scene should be and how they reacted when the different carriages were raised. For example, that is when the flight attendants are most busy and when passengers are most curious. Few people have seen the train changing tracks at the border. At this time, the robbers rush in. &quot;It is a good timing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vasily, played by Andy Lau, has many fake passports. The fake name on one of them is Wen Zhenwei, which is the name of the assistant director. In order to avoid misunderstandings about the real names, the names of the staff will be used as much as possible when making movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Daming once saw some photos in National Geographic magazine, taking pictures of abandoned rocket bases around the world. He especially hopes to film a crime-related gunfight scene in such a place in the future. There is such a scene in &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. Gui Youming said to Zhao Hai, have you ever seen a movie called &quot;Oriental Condor&quot; (there is a similar scene in the film), I want to make it bigger than that. . So they referred to a lot of information about abandoned Russian rocket bases. &quot;I remember that day Uncle Zhi (Li Zhongzhi) came to the scene and said, &#39;What are you doing? Why is it so big?&#39;&quot; Gui Youming warned that we must make full use of this scene: &quot;Blow up here and there, run around, inside and outside Use everything, don’t waste it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chen Daming, the earliest draft of the script ended with a courtroom scene. Vasily was sentenced to 5 years in prison, suspended for 2 years. Policeman Cui Zhenhai patted him on the shoulder and said, if you look back, Vasily saw his daughter. In the original script, the daughter was 15 years old and attending a technical school. The daughter looked at her father from a distance, nodded, and that was how it ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao made major changes to the ending. In addition to adding the scene of the rail-changing station, he also changed Vasily&#39;s ending to one in which he was blinded due to a gun accident. Chen Daming thinks that there is a bit of blank space in this ending, and many people are guessing whether the daughter Vasily met at the end is real or fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[流连菖蒲河的老人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpIRG4hA5NAwK4U.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;781&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpI RG4hA5NAwK4U. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256659&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The social stage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, the ancient trees along the Changpu River in Beijing are still lush, and pairs of wild ducks inhabit the dark green stream. Every Tuesday and Saturday, when the sun is at its strongest, the classical promenade in Changpu River Park is filled with elderly people looking for partners, and the golden light spots add romantic vitality to them. The red wall of Huangshichen blocks the busy traffic of Chang&#39;an Street, bringing the park a secluded space suitable for romance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t expect a successful match based on true love.&quot; This is the sincere warning to latecomers from an old man who often comes to parties in Changpu River Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman in her fifties, dressed in an emerald-colored Tang suit and with exquisitely braided hair, refused to communicate with any of them in depth after an afternoon of ballroom dancing with a few uncles, and stayed alone. The pillars of the gallery rest. Asked why she wasn&#39;t looking for a partner in Changpu River Park, she said she wasn&#39;t looking because &quot;the blind dates here come with various conditions, and people are sold like livestock.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bald man in his sixties who always wears gold-framed sunglasses from Beijing has been here for 15 years. He can freely blend into any dating gossip and naturally bring together any interested couple. men and women. But when the other party&#39;s ambiguous signal reaches him, he always laughs at himself: &quot;I won&#39;t look for it. I have no money. If I don&#39;t have money, I can&#39;t find the right one.&quot; With a 14-square-meter bungalow and a retirement salary of more than 4,000 yuan, he always Can extinguish the other person&#39;s enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changpu River Park has been criticized by the elderly, but it always has the magic to tie them up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During a conversation in the corridor, it was like a default etiquette to ask each other about houses, household registration, salary, and medical insurance information. No one wants to be dragged down, everyone is rushing to get better conditions. After a while of &quot;greetings&quot;, there is a more detailed matching of needs. As long as you stay here for a day, the old people will not help but tell you that there are only a handful of people who set marriage registration as their goal; there are not a majority of people who are sincerely looking for a long-term wife. Maybe what the other person wants is just an ambiguous opposite-sex friendship or an extramarital affair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a common and decent ending to look down on each other. We can also become nodding friends - old acquaintances who say &quot;here we come&quot; to each other. And getting along emotionally involves the risk of paying for lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a week of official dating, his girlfriend asked Uncle Zhou to use his savings to buy her a gold ring worth 20,000 yuan. Uncle Zhou emphasized that &quot;that is pension money and cannot be touched.&quot; Afterwards, they broke up, and Uncle Zhou kept blaming himself for being a fool. Sister Qin met a man in his sixties in the park. During a video call at 9 o&#39;clock one night, other women vaguely appeared in the other party&#39;s kitchen. &quot;He didn&#39;t tell me at first that he had a relationship with more than one woman. I didn&#39;t like that he kept talking about sexual matters between men and women all day long.&quot; Sister Qin blocked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A typical temporary union occurred between a Northeastern woman in her fifties and a Beijing man in his seventies. One needs wealth and shelter, the other desires youth and care. After a period of time, there will always be a reason to bring an unhappy end to the relationship due to the ownership of the house, differences in consumption concepts, and the opposition of the man&#39;s children. After they broke up, the woman thought she was cheated of sex, and the man thought he was cheated of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Changpu River Park, some people can adapt to this &quot;exchange&quot; rule, while others find it chilling. Uncle Chen, 63, has a monthly rent income of 30,000 yuan. After ending his romantic relationship with a woman in her forties, he always took the initiative to compensate her with something, whether it was a big meal or a red envelope: &quot;Why should I let you, an old man, take advantage of me?&quot; Uncle Zhou would say Lamenting under the street lights at night, &quot;This place is like a microcosm of society. There is true love, but too little. Everyone has lost faith and only has the word &#39;profit&#39; in their eyes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who complain, People who have been deceived, people who are ready to break up, and people who seem to be watching indifferently will eventually return to the Changpu River. They persuaded the elder sister who was eager to be a matchmaker and register information for the elderly: this place is too chaotic and not a serious place to find a partner. They themselves are willing to be trapped in chaos. They always come here on Tuesdays and Saturdays to chat, strike up conversations, dance, and play cards. An old man riding a bicycle claimed that he was not here to fall in love, but on the blind date day, he would shuttle back and forth between the east and west gates of the park to observe and inquire around. He pointed to the winding corridor and said: &quot;This is the big stage of society. (I am here) to see how these people perform here wearing masks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Late release&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>; Geng Tielin wears a peaked cap and a mask and often hangs out in gathering areas where Northeasterners gather. He is from Harbin. He is 1.76 meters tall, well-proportioned and lean, and his posture when climbing up the river is brisk and flexible. It seems hard to believe that he is already 65 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m not looking for a date, I&#39;m just here for a walk. Besides, as a tall guy like me, I don&#39;t have to worry about no one liking me.&quot; Geng Tielin is confident in his charm. When he comes to the park, he just needs to stand there and many women will come and add their WeChat messages. He will approve the application out of politeness, but the only people he is interested in are &quot;tall, good-looking, and under 60&quot;; the only people he agrees to get along with are people who don&#39;t covet his money and &quot;don&#39;t want this or that.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his chat history, there are three women in their fifties who he calls &quot;sisters&quot;. When chatting with other elderly people in the park, Geng Tielin referred to them more as &quot;friends&quot; - people who can meet up to eat, travel, and sleep in the same bed without binding each other to a fixed identity. The sisters came from a well-off family and never asked Geng Tielin to bear any expenses. He sent a wedding red envelope to the son of one of his sisters, but the other party politely returned it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since his divorce 35 years ago, Geng Tielin has never had a long-term girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When my wife left, my daughter was only 5 years old. In order to raise his daughter, Geng Tielin worked as a driver, a chef, and opened a breakfast shop to help her get admitted to a graduate school in a Beijing university. The daughter found a job in a bank in Beijing, and the old father moved to Beijing with her and cooked in a factory canteen in Daxing. Geng Tielin was very proud when talking about his daughter who bought a house with an area of ​​more than 80 square meters and a value of more than 6 million yuan in Chaoyang District with an annual salary of one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geng Tielin said that he had not touched a woman for more than 20 years after his divorce. The biggest reason is that he doesn&#39;t want the shadow of his &quot;stepmother&quot; to hinder his daughter&#39;s growth. But he has desires - physiological desires that cannot be channeled and are born at the wrong time. In those days, having sex outside of marriage was considered hooliganism. Geng Tielin did not dare to tell anyone, so he could only hold back or solve it on his own. &quot;It&#39;s such a shame, I was so miserable during those twenty years.&quot; After the millennium, he gradually tried to date different women. Sometimes it’s a hotel clerk you meet while driving, sometimes it’s an acquaintance whose husband is crying to him about his loss of sexual function due to cerebral palsy. However, no romance has turned into a stable relationship. Geng Tielin believes that it is impossible for him to ask others to adapt to his &quot;bad habits.&quot; Worrying about his daughter and raising a family, he often stayed awake all night, pacing back and forth and scrolling through his cell phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, he suddenly took off his peaked cap and showed me: his almost smooth head had only short, gray and sparse hair, dotted around the ears. At this time, he became a 65-year-old man. &quot;Our family has good genes, and no one has ever lost their hair. My grandfather was lying in a coffin at the age of 90 with black hair. It was because of his insomnia in those years that my hair became like this. I also want to have a wife to love, and have My wife loves me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frugal and chic single life is also what Geng Tielin enjoys. He refused to live under the same roof as his daughter and rented a house of more than 20 square meters in Yanjiao to live alone, paying only 400 yuan in rent per month. Sauce elbow is Geng Tielin’s specialty. The price of raw materials in Yanjiao is only half of that downstairs in my daughter&#39;s community. Geng Tielin feels that now is the best time in life. His daughter has a future and he does not have to worry about raising his granddaughter. He is in good health and lives a comfortable life. There is no new partner to divide one&#39;s salary, but there are tender greetings and the joy of traveling together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On National Day two years ago, while wandering around, Geng Tielin accidentally discovered Changpu River Park. Although the elderly people here &quot;have their own thoughts,&quot; the situation of single elderly people is very similar to his. Even if he can&#39;t find a satisfactory &quot;friend&quot;, Geng Tielin still likes to chat here. He said he was not lonely at all, and his life of walking in the park and recuperating at home was well arranged. He also said that after his daughter got married, she was too busy and made fewer phone calls than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I met Geng Tielin, a slender lady with wavy hair reaching her waist, wearing a silk scarf, took the initiative to sit next to him, and the two talked and laughed. When I met him for the second time two days later, he said he wanted to delete the other person. According to him, the two went on a date to visit Zhongshan Park, and the man paid for the trip. Naturally, the lady ordered an extra bun, and asked Geng Tielin to buy the &quot;Pulse&quot;. She also insisted on asking for a 50 yuan hat in the scenic spot. Three more days later, I saw him for the third time. While chatting, Geng Tielin suddenly held his chin in a daze and murmured to himself: If there is someone better than those sisters, he will fall in love with her, and he will live with her wholeheartedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Live life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compare calamus Among the other well-dressed ladies in He Park, Zhang Ming&#39;an&#39;s clothing is obviously pragmatic. Her short hair was dyed jet black but didn&#39;t appear to be trimmed carefully. The upper body is a warm but bloated dark blue fur coat, the lower body is black pants and black shoes, and a styleless cross-body bag hangs casually in front of the body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In just one hour by bus, Zhang Mingan can go to the park from his home near Tiantongyuan. It was 9:30 a.m. on Saturday before the elderly people who lived further away had time to arrive. The promenade of the park was a little quiet. Most of the people who came were local Beijingers like Zhang Mingan who lived in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, Zhang Mingan also wanted to find a local who lived in the city to be her wife, but it was obvious that she had not met anyone she was satisfied with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Beijing gentleman communicated with her back to back for a while, then turned and left.她撅着嘴望向对方的背影，在接受采访时对我说：“你有老婆了上这儿来干嘛？不是霍霍儿（注：北京话，糟蹋、破坏事物）吗？我成什么啦？”大爷有法律关系的妻子长期生活在国外，而他已经参加过三次北京老年相亲节目《选择》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张明安口中，这些都是“花里胡哨”的关系。 62岁的她，只有一个朴素的要求，那就是找一个能“过日子”的老伴，一起过完人生最后二十几年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张明安没有孩子。三十多岁时因子宫病变做了切除手术，之后，她和第一任丈夫离婚。 50岁，她找到了可以一起环游世界的伴侣，老方。张明安笑着告诉我，10年间，他们曾一起参加实惠的旅行团，去过美、泰、日、韩。在她60岁时，老方因胰腺癌去世。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;花了一年多时间走出抑郁，张明安想通了，要为自己而活。和单位的退休姐妹跳舞打球，追追抗日剧，家里收拾得利索整齐。 “动不了再去敬老院，确保有人替自己收尸就行，没有想找老伴的事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年12月，张明安意识到孤身一人的脆弱。感染新冠后，她一个人躺在家里的沙发上，茶几和水杯离她很近，但全身无力，够不到这口水，在沙发上渴了一天。她真希望，身边有一个人，能递个药，熬口粥。 “我不行了，你伺候伺候我。你不行了，我照顾照顾你。付出真心，互相搀扶。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我是过日子的一把好手。”张明安这样认为。炸油饼、烙馅饼、蒸花卷，都不在话下。邻居说她有洁癖，家里总是很干净，地上有一丝头发都要捡起来。邻居还说，老方真有福气，生病后动不了，每天洗脚、剪指甲都是张明安在伺候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张明安总是找不到能好好过日子的人。去中介所相亲时，对方开口闭口都在谈自己有十几套房子。张明安指出，她不信，也不图这个。联谊会上，有许多外地人，也不符合她的择偶期待。来菖蒲河公园后，来问她的，或者是有老伴的人，或者是跳跳舞、纯玩的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;线下相亲平台的匮乏，也是一个问题。张明安回忆，在昌平某婚庆中介所登记介绍，需要交1000元。在东城区，价格则在1万以上。昌平那家登记后，第一次和第二次为她匹配对象的时间，隔了一年。线下集会效率更高，但日常的集会地点，她只知道周二、周六的菖蒲河公园和周日的天坛公园。张明安更希望，在线下活动中，户口、婚姻、财产等状况都能得到实名认证，减少不必要的沟通成本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;执念&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在菖蒲河公园的相亲圈内，外地人，尤其是外地女人的口碑并不算太好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些人口中，她们五十多岁背井离乡，希望在北京立足，刚从火车站下车就拖着行李来到公园，有老头给钱给房子就愿意和他生活，条件是承担所有家务。有一位北京大爷告诉我，他曾遇见一位39岁的美丽的外省女人。女人知道他是北京人后，立马表示要嫁给他——这是为了给儿子争取北京户口，她说北京高考更容易考上清华北大。在另一位大爷口中，一位外省女性老是把彩礼的条件摆在嘴边，这让他感到观念上的巨大鸿沟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本地人心中，即便不是所有来这里的外地女性都这样，但这张地域名片背后也暗暗刻上了“无情重利”这4个字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自外地的王鸿桢似乎能坦荡地接受这个标签。她的内蒙朋友孟纾影，却希望在菖蒲河找到有爱情基础的长期伴侣。王鸿桢恨铁不成钢：“她这个想法，在这儿根本找不着。趁我身体还好，能抓钱就抓钱，在这儿找长期过日子的，那是不可能的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她口中的抓钱，是领着三千多元的工资在男方家中做保姆。 2023年8月之前，她住在88岁的北京老教授家中，直到对方的女儿把他接到美国去。除了做家务，王鸿桢陪他买菜、锻炼、去公园，听他讲历史，帮他洗澡搓背。他们在同一个屋檐下单独待了两年，王鸿桢分不清这算不算有情感，自己算不算当了对方的老伴。但她认为这个已经不重要了，“挣钱为主，对象其次。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15年前，王鸿桢和她的朋友一样，渴望通过这个菖蒲河公园的平台重获婚姻和幸福。这个梦想后来破碎了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2000年，41岁、离异的王鸿桢带着两个儿子来到北京打拼。她开过美容店，也在中介公司和旅行社打过工。 2007年，当王鸿桢还是菖蒲河公园一枝花的时候，在这里遇到了一位丧偶的自来水厂经理。对方和她年龄相当，高大俊朗，两人坠入爱河。但在对方儿女的强烈反对下，他们没能再走下去。每年王鸿桢从老家回北京，都会给曾经的恋人带上一份土特产以示感谢。在她最困难的时候，他曾资助她租房和看病。和第二个对象的情感不如第一个那么炽烈，但恋情同样终止于对方女儿的忌惮。之后的故事并不甜蜜，王鸿桢和一位男士登记结婚一年后，对方把她甩了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，菖蒲河公园的大爷们，在王鸿桢眼中都是骗人睡觉、玩够就踹掉女方的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的执念变成了在北京拥有独立住所。以自己的实力，王鸿桢没法在北京买到房子。和大儿子住在大厂（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;河北大厂回族自治县&lt;/span>;），她不得不包揽照顾全家五口人的家务。 “他们工作太忙，带俩小孩遛弯、做饭、洗衣服都是我在做。住3个月就得生病。”出来当保姆，反倒是一种休息。王鸿桢的另一种考量是，“现在我身体好，不想住在儿子家麻烦他们。如果时间长了有矛盾，老了以后怎么找人家帮你呢？多不仗义呀。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果非要结成有男女之实的伴侣，王鸿桢的要求是：第一要在北京有能住的地方。第二，要么登记结婚，满两年后让她把户口迁到北京；要么不登记，但每月给她一笔钱。她说，拥有北京户口，离婚了也可以申请经济适用房，可以在北京报销医药费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有大爷向王鸿桢发出温情脉脉的吃饭邀约，她总是预感对方要骗色，于是吓唬回去：“你现在跟我登记结婚，房本写下我的名字，我就和你吃饭，否则拉倒。”一旁的大爷责怪她太霸道：“你得先有情感基础再谈这些经济付出，要不怎么叫恋爱呢？”王鸿桢笑了笑，没回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周六晚上的人总比周二的多，老人们不用赶着接放学的孙辈回家。 6点以后，天空转成暗蓝色，长廊尽头的舞曲还在播放，宴会还没进入尾声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我遇见了一位在陈晓楠的节目《和陌生人说话》中出现过的受访者。正是这个节目挖掘了菖蒲河公园的老年相亲角，让它暴露在媒体的聚光灯下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位受访者并不像节目中那么昂扬。他坦言，节目播出后的6年，自己一直在这里寻寻觅觅，有过几段感情，但仍未找到理想伴侣。他说，“周二、周六菖蒲河，周四中山公园和陶然亭，周日天坛公园。每一个地方，去的都是这同一拨人。”这里已经变成老人们上班打卡的地方。即使找不到对象，抱团聚一聚总好过一个人闷在家里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大家都是老年人。也许哪一天，其中一个就不能再来了呢。”谈话期间，一位大爷上梯子时突然绊倒，受访者和周围几位相对年轻一点的老年人，急忙跑上去把他搀扶起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(为保护受访者隐私，文中人物均为化名。)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>