<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《完蛋！我被美女包围了！》热销：戳中男性痛点，顺利开辟生态位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 22:25:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, &quot;It&#39;s over!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! &quot;&quot; became the number one best-selling game on Steam in China after only one day of being online. Discussions about this game have also become hot searches on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon deserves concern and analysis. The plot line setting of the game is very simple. You transform into the male protagonist Gu Yi and use the first-person perspective to immersively meet, interact and socialize with six beauties with different ages, looks, personalities and family backgrounds. You can choose one of them. Develop the character deeply and make it your other half: the charming witch who loves to go to nightclubs, the intellectual sister who loves literature and art, the innocent school girl who is not materialistic, the unruly rich lady, the sexy mother who raises her children alone, and the girl who wants to be a little girl at heart. The cool CEO, the choice is yours, which one you will end up with, you can do whatever you want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, this is a male-oriented love clearance game. The target audience is men. There is no harem or side effects. It is just pure love and satisfying men&#39;s various fantasies about their significant other. There are relatively few games in this category on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public has the impression that young people, especially young men, love to play games, which is true. The hunting and war that our ancestors engaged in in the tribal era were the first priority for survival. This has become the pursuit of power and victory engraved in genes. The mainstream favorites of men are action, combat, war, civilized hegemony and strategy. The game involves a battle of wits and courage. In this type of game, most of the male players are male. Love is either absent or is just an add-on or embellishment. There is a high probability that the game producer has established such a mental position: every man’s dream is to conquer the world. , falling in love is also about capturing a woman’s heart by conquering the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The design idea of ​​this game is very different. It just allows a very ordinary man without any cheats to fall in love with a beautiful woman. Although the game has 12 hidden endings and hundreds of route choices , &quot;Every choice you make will trigger unexpected hidden stories.&quot; However, compared with the mainstream male-oriented games on the market, it is not really complicated, nor can it be said that the workmanship is exquisite, so it must be so popular. Particularly successful is that it hits the pain points of young men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A major feature of the game is &quot;real-person interactive images&quot;: six beauties with different styles are all played and photographed by real people. In the era of general artificial intelligence (AGI) led by GPT-4, it is not difficult to use AI to design stunning beauties that are more perfect than real people, and the cost is lower. This approach has already had a negative impact on the profit model of &quot;welfare girls&quot; who sell personal photos. The impact. The producers of this game went in the opposite direction, using real people to act on camera, and pre-filmed various plot lines like genuine film and television works, allowing players to choose the objects and plots they want to develop in depth, allowing players to become film and television male protagonists. , the power to control and promote the development of the plot on your own, and it can also approach the experience of interacting with real people in real life, which can be said to be thoughtful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sexual version of this game is the so-called otome game. Otome is a girl. Women choose to fall in love with men, whether they are domineering CEOs, rich second generation, celebrities, or race car drivers. In short, it is to satisfy women&#39;s perfect imagination of their significant other. In terms of proportion, there are several orders of magnitude more otome games than male-oriented romance games. In this sense, &quot;Done!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! &quot;The reason why it is so popular may be because there are too few such games. Game producers ignore and underestimate men&#39;s emotional needs. In addition, &quot;live-person interactive images&quot; fill the gap, so it suddenly opens up. an ecological niche. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The popularity of this game is enough to show that the male world is not all about killing and working to make money. Men also have emotional needs. Our traditional culture does not encourage men to open up and express themselves. &quot;A man cannot shed tears easily.&quot; Men must appear strong and carry everything without being weak or shrinking. However, everyone has moments of weakness and emotions. There are times when I cannot bear the need to express myself and my emotions break down. Men are human beings too, and their spiritual world should also be cared for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, men’s voices have been absent from public opinion. In the statements of some merchants, there is even a saying that &quot;men&#39;s consumption power is not as good as that of dogs.&quot; However, this situation is changing. The values ​​and consumption concepts of the new generation of young men are very different from their parents. They care more about themselves and invest more in their own image and spiritual world. For example, in recent years, the consumption and consumption of male cosmetics have increased annually. Significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to iiMedia Consulting data, among Chinese users who choose to shop through online live streaming channels, 58% are men and 42% are women. Among them, those born in the 1980s and 1990s are the main shopping force, accounting for The total exceeds 80%; live streaming e-commerce shopping users are mainly distributed in first- and second-tier cities, with second-tier cities leading the way with 42%. This is very different from the impression some people have. The consumption power of young men is rising and blowing out, which is a trend worthy of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When men convert their productivity into consumption power, they also win the hospitality of businesses. This is the rule of the game in the consumer society. &quot;It&#39;s over!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! 》The fire is another footnote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, since it is a romance game, it will inevitably lead some people to discuss the relationship between games and reality. Some people worry that the quality of opposite-sex partners in romance games is much higher than in real life, which will cause players to invisibly raise their inner expectations and standards for mate selection, and lose interest in the available partners in reality. There should be a real social investigation on whether this effect exists and how big it is, and it is meaningless to talk about it in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a person who has to earn money to support his family and career during working hours, but only occasionally spends some time playing games during get off work hours or weekends to satisfy his dreams and fantasies that cannot be realized in real life, should not be punished. Even if you are harsh, you won’t lose your sense of reality just by playing a few games, because the gravity of the real world is strong enough to pull you back to the ground. Occasionally falling into fantasy, even if it is a fantasy that cannot be realized, will make a person&#39;s heart shine, or make the soul gain a sense of relaxation and transcendence, which is necessary for a person&#39;s mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if you are completely immersed and lost in fantasy due to the lack of anchors in the real world, and never want to get out of the virtual world, or use the perfect objects in the virtual world to ask for optional objects in the real world, then of course It is a pathology and not desirable. A sane adult should never go to this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[​张又侠：中国军队绝不答应、绝不手软]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:25:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话上野千鹤子：学术是弱者的武器丨视频]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259590]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[500万人次求助，800亿元捐赠：慈善法修正可否终结个人求助争议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259592]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2022, when a girl fell from a building, her family asked for help on Shuidichou. At present, this type of personal help donations has exceeded 80 billion yuan. Chinese Business Daily Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256024&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2022, when a girl fell from a building, her family asked for help on Shuidichou. At present, such individual donations for help have exceeded 80 billion yuan. Chinese Business Daily Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 25, 2023, the draft amendment to the Charity Law after deliberation at the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress will be officially released for public comment. The revised draft adds new content to regulate personal help-seeking behavior and the management of personal help-seeking online service platforms, which is considered to fill the legislative gaps and has attracted much attention. On the National People&#39;s Congress website, this is called one of the four highlights of this draft amendment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recent incident of a 2-year-old girl being bitten by a Rottweiler dog in Chengdu, public opinion questioned the individual&#39;s request for help. After the girl was bitten, her family started to raise 2 million yuan on the Easy Raising Platform. Within 5 hours and 18 minutes, more than 87,000 people donated, and the donation goal was achieved. But the girl&#39;s family quickly fell into disputes over the amount of the aid and the use of the funds. On October 25, EasyCho released refund instructions and refunded all unused donations in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to reports, Xu Anbiao, deputy director of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, said that the original intention of this revision of the law is to improve the charity, fundraising, funding, service and other systems during emergencies, and to address some new issues that have emerged in the charity field. New situations and new problems, summarizing practical experience, such as &quot;fingertip public welfare&quot; and &quot;public welfare for everyone&quot; and other new situations and new problems that have emerged in the Internet era, it is necessary to reasonably regulate these phenomena and improve relevant systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are endless problems with personal help-seeking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Charity Law was reviewed and passed by the National People&#39;s Congress in March 2016 and has been in effect for 7 years. However, personal help-seeking has not been included in the regulation before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xijin, a professor at the School of Public Administration at Tsinghua University and deputy director of the Philanthropy Research Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that the legislative purpose of the Charity Law is to promote charity and regulate charity behaviors and charitable organizations. Charitable organizations can raise funds publicly for public welfare purposes and enjoy tax-free treatment, which is equivalent to the use of public resources, so its beneficiaries must be a non-specific public rather than a specific individual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Personal help-seeking does not meet the purpose of public welfare, so the Charity Law did not regulate personal help-seeking at the beginning of the legislation. However, in recent years, with the help of online fundraising platforms such as LoveChou, EasyChou and ShuidiChou, personal help-seeking has become more active and prominent than charity activities, and problems in the field of personal help-seeking have also emerged one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Luo Yixiao, a 6-year-old girl from Shenzhen, Guangdong, unfortunately suffered from leukemia. Her father Luo Er wrote an article online to raise about 2.7 million yuan for treatment expenses. Later, it was revealed that Luo Er had three houses and three companies in his home. He also said in an interview that &quot;the house in Shenzhen is reserved for his son,&quot; which caused him to be questioned. Amid the whirlpool of public opinion, Luo Yixiao died of illness, and Luo Er also returned all donations to the donors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Wang Fengya, a 3-year-old girl from Taikang County, Henan Province, suffered from retinoblastoma. Her mother requested help on multiple online platforms. In April 2018, it was revealed that his mother had donated 150,000 yuan through fraudulent donations to treat her son&#39;s cleft lip. Although the police investigation found that the donation fraud claim was untrue, Wang Fengya died of illness in May of that year, and her family was also subjected to online abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amid repeated controversies, calls for strengthening supervision of online fundraising platforms are getting louder and louder. In 2018, under the guidance of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, the three major online fundraising platforms, LoveChou, EasyChou and ShuidiChou, issued a self-discipline convention. This was upgraded again in 2020, proposing that platforms should abide by seven &quot;bottom-line rules&quot; to strengthen platform self-discipline management and improve Risk prevention level and improve social supervision mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2019, the country’s first online dispute over personal critical illness help was pronounced. In this case, Mr. Mo launched a personal fundraising campaign on Shuidichou for his seriously ill son. However, because he concealed his property and other social assistance, the fundraising platform took him to court and demanded the return of the donation. After trial, the Beijing Chaoyang District Court found that Mr. Mo misappropriated the funds raised for other purposes in violation of the agreed purpose, constituting a breach of contract. The first instance order ordered the full return of more than 150,000 yuan raised and the payment of corresponding interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference after the verdict was announced in the case, Wang Min, the president of the Wangjing Tribunal of the Chaoyang District Court, pointed out that there are problems in the field of personal help for serious illnesses on the Internet, such as unclear legal definitions and overly principled provisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judgment of the case also mentioned: &quot;At present, only departmental regulations stipulate that personal seeking help does not belong to charitable fundraising and charitable public fundraising information. Regarding the rights between the network platform and the donor in personal seeking help for serious illness on the Internet, The obligations have not yet been clearly defined.” In addition, many unclear boundaries emerged during the trial, such as whether Mr. Mo provided comprehensive information, whether the fundraising platform should provide separate items to fill in the family property item by item, whether there were insufficient verifications, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, the Chaoyang District Court sent judicial suggestions to the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the Shuidichou platform respectively, recommending that the Ministry of Civil Affairs coordinate and promote the legislation on personal help-seeking behavior for serious illnesses, establish and improve departmental regulations, and promote orderly personal help-seeking for serious illnesses on the Internet. carry out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Guoke, a lawyer at Beijing Zhicheng Law Firm, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that as an individual right, individual seeking help is not subject to legal restrictions or prohibitions. For example, going to the streets to beg, as long as it does not violate city management regulations; seeking help from classmates or relatives after falling ill is a small-scale personal request for help. Whether the information for help is true or not only involves both the donor and the recipient. issues of rights and obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the factors of the Internet, the scope of communication and influence of personal help-raising on the Internet have changed dramatically. At this time, the authenticity of the help-seeking information has a certain degree of publicity. Netizens who make donations on an online fundraising platform are both donors and users of the platform. From the perspective of providing services to users, the platform also needs to verify the authenticity of the information of the help seekers, &quot;for our vast number of donors.&quot; Very good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the volume of personal requests for help on the Internet is huge. The first domestic &quot;Research Report on the Personal Serious Illness Help-Seeking Internet Platform (2022)&quot; shows that according to incomplete statistics, from September 2014 to the end of 2021, a total of more than 5 million serious illness patients posted help information through the personal serious illness help-seeking Internet service platform, and more than 20 100 million people donated funds through critical illness help platforms including Shuidichou, with a fundraising scale of more than 80 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Individual seeking help is a relatively active and large-scale phenomenon in society at present, and it is necessary for the Charity Law to respond in principle to this.” Jia Xijin said, but the current amendment to the Charity Law includes the addition of individuals The content of asking for help does not mean that individual asking for help is regarded as a charitable activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Information inspection” rather than “information review”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a member of the Expert Advisory Committee of the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, He Guoke participated in the meeting discussion of the revised draft of the Charity Law. According to him, due to the essential difference between personal help-seeking and charitable public welfare activities, the personal help-seeking section did not include chapters on charitable donations and charitable fundraising. Instead, it was placed in the supplementary provisions, and in the form of authorized legislation, the Civil Affairs Department of the State Council, in conjunction with Relevant departments will formulate specific management measures separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This draft amendment to the Charity Law clarifies: If an individual causes financial difficulties for his family due to illness or other reasons, and releases information for help to the society, the person seeking help and the information publisher shall be responsible for the authenticity of the information, and the personal assistance network service The platform shall bear the obligation to inspect information, and specific management measures shall be formulated separately by the civil affairs department of the State Council in conjunction with relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Guoke believes that compared with the first revised draft, the latest revised draft has three main adjustments to the content of personal help-seeking: first, the definition of personal help-seeking puts more emphasis on the reasons of &quot;personal illness&quot;; In addition, the &quot;network service provider&quot; in the amendment is clearly defined as &quot;personal assistance network service platform&quot; in the amendment, which means that when the Ministry of Civil Affairs formulates specific management measures in the future, it is likely to re-qualify the platform party to do so. Stricter management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last adjustment is that the &quot;information review obligation&quot; that the platform should bear is changed to &quot;information inspection obligation.&quot; &quot;&#39;Review&#39; is more important than &#39;inspection&#39;.&quot; He Guoke said that the platform has not been granted the power and responsibility like government departments and judicial agencies, and cannot review the property in the name of the requester. &quot;For example, the requester said that he only has one house. &quot;The platform can only see that the real estate certificate of this house is basically true, but it cannot go to the Housing Authority to check how many properties he owns in total.&quot; This adjustment was made after considering the opinions of multiple platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xijin believes that in the draft amendment to the Charity Law, it is necessary to add the principle content that &quot;the person asking for help and the person publishing the information should be responsible for the authenticity of the information&quot; because the basis for personal seeking help is still civil. In the &quot;gift&quot; relationship, the primary responsible parties are both the donor and the recipient. &quot;Whoever publishes false information is responsible&quot;; as a third party that promotes cooperation, the platform needs to conduct necessary formal reviews, such as requiring family financial information. Certificates, medical certificates, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above-mentioned Shuidichiou case, the Chaoyang District Court held that the Shuidichiou platform has strict formal review obligations and strict supervision obligations. In this case, the court found that Shuidichiou had review flaws, but this did not affect Mr. Mo’s responsibility to return the donation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information provided by Shuidichou to Southern Weekend reporters, Shuidichou has currently strengthened measures to ensure the authenticity of fundraising cases, using technology and manual methods to pass preliminary review, reexamination, third-party review, etc. The platform will continuously review user information. Only after the platform reviews the information is correct and meets the qualifications, can online fundraising be initiated normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the materials provided by Shuidichou, the platform intercepted an average of 12 fundraising applications that did not meet the requirements every day. In the first half of the year, it intercepted and rejected a total of 2,096 fundraising applications that did not meet the launch conditions, including There are 544 illegal users who have been permanently blacklisted from the platform and are prohibited from launching fundraising again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in Jia Xijin&#39;s view, individual case assistance and personal help are like &quot;after-care medicine&quot; for the plight of seriously ill families. They can exist but do not need to become bigger and stronger. She believes that it is more important to establish multiple response mechanisms, such as inclusive medical insurance and medical assistance systems, commercial insurance, public welfare advocacy and beneficiary services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明星发声缘何遭遇舆论反弹：公共空间不应是少数人表演的舞台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the discussion surrounding the incident of vicious dogs injuring people in Chongzhou, Sichuan has gradually extended to the management and disposal of stray animals in the city. On many public affairs, it has become a vent for social emotions for a period of time, including relatively rational thinking and suggestions, as well as more radical remarks and propositions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon of &quot;using topics to vent emotions&quot; is common in itself, but one of the phenomena is very interesting. After several well-known actors made remarks on personal social media calling for kindness to stray animals, their comment areas were blocked. Netizens were &quot;outraged&quot; and a large number of fans left messages to &quot;unsubscribe&quot; and &quot;drop followers&quot;. Many actors have closed the comment area to passively fight against the storm of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of traditional communication studies, it is generally believed that film and television stars rely on their personal charm, the persona they have created in public affairs for a long time, as well as the fans and traffic they bring, and they have great influence in the field of public opinion. With huge appeal and influence, the joint &quot;voice&quot; of several celebrities can often change the direction of public opinion. However, in this incident, the celebrities without exception failed in the field of public opinion. This is thought-provoking The changes actually include a series of quite profound social changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“A stage for the few” and “a society for the majority”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the era of television media and the early era of online media, “unitary subjectivity” and “central focus” are reflected Incisively and vividly, young people in frontiers and villages gaze at the love affairs and joys and sorrows of middle-class people in the reinforced concrete forests of Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou from fashion magazines, movies, TV and computer screens, and have not yet realized the need for self-subject expression. Most cultural products are produced in megacities and only depict life there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the society of the majority revolves around the stage of the minority, and regards the lifestyle of the super urban middle-class citizens performed on the stage as an advanced, civilized, and universal And one-size-fits-all paradigms and templates. The imitation of this lifestyle is considered a fashionable, progressive, and civilized pursuit, while the opposite is considered an archaic, backward, and barbaric conservatism. This “progressivist life template” is not original to urban middle-class citizens, but an imitation of the lifestyles of European and American middle-class citizens who achieved modernization and urbanization earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cultural industry born in super cities produces cultural products through imitation and interpretation of this &quot;progressive life template&quot;, and then promotes it to the whole society through cultural products. As one of the producers of cultural products, actors must naturally accept this &quot;progressive life template&quot; and the ideas behind it. Otherwise, not only will they not be able to work smoothly, they will even find it difficult to gain a foothold and live in the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is not difficult to see that although the acting styles of the actors are different, a considerable number of actors have a highly consistent personality in life: they love nature, sports and travel, and have certain ideas. Depth and artistic taste, emphasis on material enjoyment and emotional value, and a &quot;personality&quot; that is passionate about environmental protection and public welfare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in a series of public discussions derived from the &quot;Vicious Dog Injury Incident&quot;, some celebrities&#39; actions to speak out for &quot;kindness to stray animals&quot; are not only a commercial act to create and maintain their personalities, but also their A true reflection of values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some celebrities have ignored two issues. Their standards of civilization are based on their living environment and lifestyle. The probability of them being bitten and injured by off-leash dogs and stray dogs in their lives is extremely small. . But this is not the case for ordinary people. Data from a public health study show that taking Zhengzhou City, Henan Province as an example, there are more than 90,000 rabies exposure risk cases in Zhengzhou City every year, and dog bites account for 77.68%. More than 80% of bite cases occur in urban areas. This The data also does not include bites that did not seek medical attention. Judging from Zhengzhou&#39;s population base of nearly 13 million people, the probability of being bitten by a dog in the city is not low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a natural and instinctive reaction for people to become anxious about their own safety due to the incident of vicious dogs in Chongzhou and their own living environment. While some celebrities make empty calls to &quot;be kind to animals&quot;, they lack in-depth rational thinking about the incident itself, let alone put forward any meaningful suggestions and feasible solutions. Instead, they deliberately pretend to be &quot;civilized&quot;. Inadvertently pushing those netizens who are worried about their own safety to the opposite side of &quot;barbarism&quot; will naturally encounter fierce backlash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the trend of flattening of social public opinion in the Internet era has become more and more obvious, and &quot;mono-subjectivity&quot; has been eliminated. The routine of eliminating freedom and pluralism under the banner of freedom and pluralism has increasingly aroused public concern. In the past, it was difficult for a few celebrities to appeal to their fans and reverse the trend of public opinion. On the contrary, this can easily make &quot;vocal&quot; stars become the target of public criticism and the vent of collective emotions, leading to a situation where the comment section has collapsed and fans have collectively lost their fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let the screen return to the screen, let the reality return to reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with developed countries, our country’s modernization process is too rapid. In the process of modernization, the film and television industry has developed particularly As a result, a considerable part of the public lacks an accurate understanding of the profession of actors, and a considerable number of actors also lack an accurate positioning of their profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confusing the image of an actor in reality with the image he plays in opera is a common psychology among people in pre-modern society. Our overly rapid modernization process has more or less extended this psychology to modern society. Actors play politicians, scientists, business tycoons and other social elites on the screen, as well as the profound lines of these elite images. , making it easy for the audience to ignore one of the most basic facts:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how professional and outstanding the doctors, scientists, and soldiers the actors play on stage and screen, their most professional and outstanding field is still acting. Only in the field of performance are they truly outstanding experts. They may shine in other areas outside their majors, but in the final analysis they are still ordinary people. Once their opinions exceed their professional fields, they can easily make the same mistakes as ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, because of the ultra-high income level and ultra-high social status that this profession achieved during the economic boom period, which far exceeds that of general industries in society, the above basic facts are easier to ignore. Not only do a considerable number of ordinary people generally follow celebrities as &quot;opinion leaders&quot; who are morally and intellectually superior to others, there are also a considerable number of actors who increasingly express opinions outside of their own profession on public affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the &quot;disenchantment&quot; effect brought about by the flattening of the Internet, more and more people&#39;s perception of celebrities is becoming increasingly mature, and they can objectively realize that acting is just one of many professions, and celebrities are among other professions. Apart from the halo of his acting career, he is just an ordinary person who specializes in art. When faced with some public opinions expressed by celebrities that are not constructive, lack in-depth thinking, and are purely emotional expressions, we dare to express different opinions instead of blindly following them. This is also an important reason why the comment sections of many celebrities have overturned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thoughts derived from this &quot;rollover&quot; incident are actually more than the above two points, but one thing is absolutely certain: in a social environment where the pre-modern state lasts too long, the post-modern state comes too early. , the standards of &quot;civilization&quot; are set by a few people and required to be accepted by the majority, which is definitely not a civilized plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香山论坛 外国代表怎么看？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:57:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023软科世界一流学科排名：中国内地收获17个世界第一学科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 27, Ruanke, a professional institution for higher education evaluation, officially released the 2023 &quot;Ranking of World-Class Subjects of Ruanke&quot; (ShanghaiRanking&#39;s Global Ranking of Academic Subjects). The 2023 ranking covers 55 disciplines, involving five major fields: science, engineering, life sciences, medicine and social sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This ranking targets more than 5,000 universities around the world. A total of more than 1,900 universities from 104 countries and regions finally appeared on the lists of various subjects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/40c9bfc857c252c4575a006558b08b7b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/40c9bfc857c252c4575a006558b08b7b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256014&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;U.S. universities have an advantage in the total number of universities on the list, and universities in mainland China have increased significantly&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;U.S. universities still have an absolute advantage in the rankings of various subjects, winning the championship in 30 subjects, with 303 universities on the list. The total number of times on the list reached 4318 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 333 universities in mainland China are on the list, with a total of 3,390 times on the list, ranking second in the world after the United States. Compared with last year, the number of universities in mainland China and the total number of universities on the list increased by 13.7% and 26.2% respectively, both of which were significant improvements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2023 Ranking of World-Class Subjects in China, Harvard University won the championship in 11 subjects, ranking first among universities in the world. Other universities with more than one champion subject are the Massachusetts Institute of Technology ( 5), University of Michigan-Ann Arbor (2), Hong Kong Polytechnic University (2), University of Chicago (2). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three universities with the largest number of disciplines in the world&#39;s top ten are Harvard University (26), Stanford University (22), and Massachusetts Institute of Technology (18). The others have more than 10 in the world. The universities with the top ten disciplines include Tsinghua University (16), Oxford University (11), Columbia University (11), Shanghai Jiao Tong University (11), and the University of Pennsylvania (11). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Mainland China has reached a new high, ranking first in the world in 17 disciplines&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the 2023 Ranking of World-Class Subjects in China, mainland China’s universities have added three new disciplines to rank first in the world. Hua University won the first place in the textile science and engineering discipline released for the first time, Northwest A&amp;F University ranked first in the world in the agricultural discipline for the first time, and Nanjing Agricultural University ranked first in the world in the veterinary science discipline for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, universities in mainland China have become global champions in 17 disciplines, namely Tsinghua University (Energy Science and Engineering), Xi&#39;an Jiaotong University (Mechanical Engineering), Harbin Institute of Technology (Instrument Science), Tongji University ( Civil Engineering), Hohai University (Water Resources Engineering), Jiangnan University (Food Science and Engineering), Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics (Aerospace Engineering), Shanghai Jiaotong University (Shipbuilding and Ocean Engineering), Beijing Jiaotong University (Transportation Engineering) , Wuhan University (Remote Sensing Technology), Central South University (Mining Engineering), University of Science and Technology Beijing (Metallurgical Engineering), Xi&#39;an University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (Communication Engineering), University of Science and Technology of China (Nano Science and Technology), Donghua University (Textile Science and Engineering), Northwest A&amp;F University (Agriculture), Nanjing Agricultural University (Veterinary Medicine). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/2e69a42f1f13ce0a02a202202d846223.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1286&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/2e69a42f1f13ce0a02a202202d846223.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256013&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the number of listed subjects among universities in mainland China, Zhejiang University ranks first in mainland China with 53 listed subjects, and has also become the school with the largest number of listed subjects in the world. Sun Yat-sen University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Peking University, Tsinghua University, Wuhan University, Fudan University, Sichuan University, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, and Central South University also all have more than 40 disciplines on the list. Tsinghua University has 16 subjects among the top ten in the world and 33 among the top 50 in the world. It has also become the university with the largest number of top ten and top 50 subjects among universities in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The newly selected universities in the second round of &quot;double first-class&quot; construction have performed well in the ranking of world-class disciplines in China. Southern University of Science and Technology has 31 disciplines on the list, 15 of which are among the top 100 in the world, and 6 of which are among the top 50. South China Agricultural University has 13 disciplines on the list, and 4 disciplines are among the top 100 in the world and ranked among the top 50 in the world. ShanghaiTech University and Nanjing Medical University each have three disciplines ranked among the top 100 in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among non-&quot;Double First-Class&quot; universities, Shenzhen University has 39 subjects on the list, leading non-&quot;Double First-Class&quot; universities in the number of subjects on the list. Qingdao University and Jiangsu University ranked second and third with 25 and 24 appearances respectively. Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou University and Zhejiang University of Technology tied for fourth place among non-&quot;double first-class&quot; universities with 20 appearances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Ruanke World-Class Subject Ranking&quot; uses a series of internationally comparable objective academic indicators to measure the performance of global universities in relevant disciplines. The ranking indicators include international authoritative academic awards, top academic achievements, and high-level scientific research. Output, scientific research quality, international cooperation, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马修·派瑞：说一声再见，就是死去一点点丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259601]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:00:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/zCyareI9Bnps0Wz6kcjlUKCcLzYtj8SDLrIqeHMZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/zCyareI9Bnps0Wz6kcjlUKCcLzYtj8 SDLrIqeHMZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256078&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matthew Perry (1969-2023), American, actor&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Friends&quot; has been so popular that many people think that there is always a parallel time and space where youth remains forever. It wasn&#39;t until the news of Matthew Perry&#39;s sudden death came from across the ocean that people discovered that there are no fairy tales in the real world. Time passes through everyone&#39;s body and soul equally, growing up, aging, and finally accepting impermanence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many media have sorted out Matthew Perry’s life: his parents divorced when he was less than 1 year old, and he lived with his mother in Canada; he once wanted to be a professional tennis player, but acting was the next best thing. However, he was lucky. At the age of 25, he encountered &quot;Friends&quot;, a hit drama that is rare in the world. He played Chandler Bing for ten years, a sensitive, gentle man who can always rely on cold jokes. Masters of dry humor to relieve embarrassment - they are so well-suited that they are indistinguishable. If it weren&#39;t for the clothes that were loose and tight, the audience wouldn&#39;t even realize that they are two people - Chandler lives in In Matthew&#39;s out-of-control body, Matthew hides the pain in Chandler&#39;s face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/oqfWuMLOKGt8hH5H11laGV4V4tgOo6IaWC1dEzYG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/oqfWuMLOKGt8hH5H11laGV4V4tgOo6IaWC1dEzYG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256079&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Friends&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alcoholism and drug dependence made Chandler lose his temper in the series Matthew&#39;s sudden fits of weight and weight caused him to go back and forth between nursing homes and rehabilitation. &quot;I can stay awake for a while, but not completely.&quot; In 2000, Matthew, who was in his thirties, underwent pancreatic surgery. His pancreas became inflamed and swollen due to alcoholism. However, the body&#39;s alarm failed to stop Matthew from seeking peace in alcohol and drugs. He made up his mind to say goodbye to the chaotic life again and again, and searched for inner order in the chaos again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Matthew&#39;s colon exploded inside his body. After seven hours of surgery and two full weeks of coma, he woke up from a 2% hope of survival. After that, he lived with a colostomy bag for 9 months, and it was not until 2020 that the situation improved. In April 2021, Matthew recorded a reunion show with the other five leading actors of &quot;Friends&quot;. Everyone recalled the scene of filming twenty years ago. Matthew used a black suit and black tie to hide his departure from Chandler. The storm that followed. He and they all said to let the story stop there and not to make another comeback series just to imagine &quot;what are they doing now&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last episode of Season 10 of &quot;Friends&quot;, the six people were about to start a new life. Chandler hugged his adopted child and said: &quot;Little guys, look around, here are you The first home, a happy place, full of love and laughter.&quot; Everyone left their keys, and Phoebe said, &quot;I think that&#39;s the end of it.&quot; Joey nodded, and Monica began Crying: &quot;It&#39;s harder than imagined.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sPYxVGOlW9oSgmfmOAbLLtbmNQkoqxbtnoGJb7OL.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sPYxVGOlW9oSgmfmOAbLLtbmNQkoqxbtnoGJb7OL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256080&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Friends&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;On October 28, 2023, Matthew Perry passed away at his home in Los Angeles. According to local police reports, the cause of death was drowning caused by cardiac arrest. There were no drugs and no signs of homicide. Of course, there was no goodbye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the play, the crying Monica fell into Chandler&#39;s arms, and he said: &quot;It&#39;s okay, it will be fine.&quot; Rachel suggested going for coffee again, and Chandler once again They used cold jokes to relieve their sadness: &quot;Where to go?&quot; They pushed the stroller outside. In the barrage, an audience member said that every time at this time, he would immediately go back and watch the first episode. The audience naturally did not explain the reason. Perhaps a long time ago, he understood what another Chandler - the famous American writer Raymond Chandler - said in the novel: &quot;To say goodbye is to die a little bit. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广西官宣“试管婴儿”纳入医保，你怎么看？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259594]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since the implementation of the three-child policy, many places have intensively released fertility support policies, among which medical insurance provides for assisted reproductive medical services. support is an important measure. For example, in July 2023, Beijing officially included 16 assisted reproductive technologies such as ovulation induction examinations and embryo transfers into medical insurance. Recently, Guangxi has officially announced: &lt;strong>;From November 1, medical services such as &quot;test tube baby&quot; will be included in medical insurance, and up to 70% can be reimbursed&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice mentioned that some therapeutic assisted reproductive medical services such as &quot;ovum retrieval&quot; will be included in the payment scope of basic medical insurance and work-related injury insurance funds; when insured persons enjoy basic medical insurance benefits, there will be no The minimum payment standard for the fund, the reimbursement ratios of basic medical insurance for employees and basic medical insurance for urban and rural residents are 70% and 50% respectively, which are included in the maximum annual fund payment limit for insured persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by the authoritative medical journal &quot;The Lancet&quot;: from 2007 to 2020, the incidence of infertility in China has increased from 12% to 18%. According to data from the National Bureau of Statistics, there will be 9.56 million births in the country in 2022, with one child accounting for less than 50%, and the natural population growth rate is -0.60‰—&lt;strong>;This is the first time that New China has experienced negative population growth since 1961&lt;/strong>; strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some experts said that the inclusion of &quot;test tube babies&quot; in medical insurance will be a good boost to reduce the burden on patients and increase the national fertility rate. At present, there are first-, second- and third-generation IVF technologies, with an average cost of 30,000 to 100,000 yuan. This price will also vary depending on the age and physical quality of the individual. Some experts are cautious. The &quot;reservoir&quot; of medical insurance is limited. If it is included in the scope, it may increase financial pressure. Young people should be encouraged to marry early and have more children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this? Welcome to share your opinions in the message area and I will send you hot comments! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[志向和焦虑并存，留学还是好选择吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259576]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;International students have lofty dreams, but in the process of pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles, and also have negative feelings about I feel confused about my future. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. All these anxieties force them to think about the ultimate question: Is studying abroad really worth it?</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[东北亚新安全态势初现，如何推动局势缓和？| 智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the post-epidemic era, leaders of various countries have reunited, but they have not yet achieved significant results on political, economic and climate issues. Results. It is difficult for countries to unite collectively and instead prefer small-scale alliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, even in Northeast Asia, a similar new security situation has emerged, and the roles of South Korea and China in dealing with the new situation have also attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New security issues emerge in Northeast Asia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On August 13, the summit held at Camp David, Maryland, brought together the leaders of South Korea, the United States, and Japan to jointly respond to pressing international security issues situation. During the summit, the leaders announced the opening of a &quot;new era of trilateral partnership&quot; and emphasized the three countries&#39; commitment to security cooperation. They held a joint press conference to outline plans and cooperation strategies involving tripartite cooperation, the Camp David Principles and the Camp David Spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the meeting, in order to ensure the stable development of trilateral cooperation between the United States, South Korea and Japan, a cross-level and cross-field systematic cooperation foundation was established. In addition to standardizing the U.S.-South Korea-Japan summit, officials from each country, including the ministers of foreign affairs, defense, and national security advisers, also agreed to hold annual meetings in their respective fields to closely coordinate cooperation plans among the three countries. In addition, the three leaders decided to establish communication channels to facilitate rapid consultation and rapid response when urgent regional issues that threaten the common interests of the three countries arise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to strengthen strategic cooperation among the three countries in the region, the three countries agreed to establish a ministerial-level dialogue called the &quot;U.S.-South Korea-Japan Indo-Pacific Dialogue&quot; and explore new areas of cooperation within the Indo-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the leaders discussed practical cooperation measures to enhance joint operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the United States, South Korea and Japan reiterated their commitment to maintaining an international order based on norms such as sovereignty, territorial integrity and peaceful resolution of conflicts. Similarly, the three countries also agreed to support strengthening maritime security capabilities in ASEAN and the Pacific Island countries when implementing the Indo-Pacific strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, on September 13, Kim Jong-un and Putin held a summit meeting at the Vostok Cosmodrome in Amur Oblast, Russia. This time they met again after about four years and five months since April 2019. The background of the emergency meeting is that North Korea faces strong sanctions mainly imposed by the United States and Western countries. North Korea is subject to United Nations Security Council (UNSC) sanctions and suffers severe food shortages and technological deficiencies. Russia is also facing economic sanctions from the European Union and other countries, and is working hard to solve the long-standing &quot;weapons shortage&quot; problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current international situation, Russia and North Korea are considered unique partners capable of meeting each other&#39;s needs, and the two countries also intend to cooperate in the activities of the United Nations Security Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If new security issues arise in Northeast Asia, South Korea, China, and related countries will experience a vicious cycle of instability in terms of security and broader economies. Resolving the North Korean nuclear issue will also become more complicated, and regional economic development will surely stagnate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;South Korea and China promote cooperation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this context, South Korea and China are one of the major countries with the potential to control this situation. The relationship between the United States and Russia is still hostile, and the bilateral dialogues between the United States and North Korea and between South Korea and North Korea have been stagnant for a long time. South Korea and China can play a key role in mitigating and responding to new security issues in Northeast Asia through cooperation. Therefore, in order to achieve this goal, South Korea and China can cooperate in various ways and contribute to easing tensions in Northeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the trilateral summit between South Korea, China and Japan is a direct opportunity for cooperation. The trilateral summit has been held eight times since 1999. However, the trilateral summit has not been held since December 2019, with South Korea currently chairing the summit. The tripartite summit, which has been suspended for three years, may clear away the dark clouds hanging over Northeast Asia. South Korea&#39;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to host a trilateral summit within this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, South Korea and China may hold a summit summit. The summit was proposed by South Korean Prime Minister Han Deok-soo. A recent survey conducted by the South Korean newspaper Mainichi Yonhap Newspaper in collaboration with the public opinion research company Opinion and Public showed that 82.3% of the respondents believed that the South Korea-China summit was &quot;necessary&quot; to be held, while only 11.3% of the respondents believed that &quot; No need&quot;, 6.3% of the respondents were unsure. Regardless of differences in region, age or political affiliation, a majority of respondents believe a summit between the two countries is necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, while rebuilding trust between South Korea and China, it is necessary to activate various security cooperation mechanisms. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations in 1992, South Korea and China have made significant progress in various fields. The relationship between the two countries developed from a good-neighborly and friendly cooperative relationship in 1992 to a China-ROK cooperative partnership for the 21st century in 1998, and further developed to a comprehensive cooperative partnership in 2003, and was upgraded to a strategic cooperative partnership in 2008. However, after the THAAD missile defense system was deployed in South Korea in 2016, relations between the two countries became tense, resulting in restrictions on exchanges and cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the strategic competition between the United States and China and the international order have affected the security exchanges between South Korea and China. The uniqueness of North Korea-China relations and the South Korea-US alliance will also limit exchanges between South Korea and China. Additionally, the political climate may affect communications between South Korea and China, resulting in a lack of substantive agenda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from the perspective of the common national interests of pursuing stability, peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, it is necessary for South Korea and China to resume exchanges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, it is necessary for the two countries to maintain communication channels to resolve sensitive security and military issues and prevent accidental conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea and China are close neighbors, partners and indivisible. Today, cooperation between South Korea and China can jointly dispel the shadows and jointly open up a path to achieve regional stability, peace and prosperity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;(Author: Lee Chang-hyung, Director of the Korea Continental Strategic Research Institute, Korea Institute for Defense Analysis; Translator: Zheng Weihao)&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>