<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会11月4日闭幕，累计境外采购商比上届增长超50%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260028]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 13:00:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, in the venue of the third phase of the Canton Fair, A buyer passes by a large panda doll.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/d53c3c3321.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/d53c3c3321.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, at the venue of the third phase of the Canton Fair, buyers passed by a large panda doll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, the 134th Canton Fair concluded successfully in Guangzhou, and the online platform operated normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The total exhibition area of ​​this Canton Fair is 1.55 million square meters, with more than 28,000 exhibiting companies and a total of 74,000 booths. The exhibition scale has reached a new high. A total of 198,000 overseas purchasers attended the exhibition during the 15-day exhibition period, an increase of over 50% compared to the previous session. There were 126,343 buyers from countries co-constructing the “One Belt and One Road”, accounting for 63.9%, an increase of 68.6% over the previous session. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the cumulative number of overseas buyers attending the 134th Canton Fair increased by more than 50% compared with the previous session.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/2da5a01466.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/06/2da5a01466.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257150&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, the cumulative number of overseas buyers attending the 134th Canton Fair increased by more than 50% compared with the previous session. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, several overseas buyers were trying out massage seats.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/12519afa74.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /06/12519afa74.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257151&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, several overseas Buyers are trying out massage chairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This year&#39;s Canton Fair has been attended by overseas buyers enthusiastically. The more open and dynamic Canton Fair has attracted buyers from all over the world. Offline export transactions reached US$22.3 billion, an increase of 2.8% over the 133rd session, showing a restorative growth trend. The export turnover of brand enterprises was US$6.35 billion, an increase of 7.8% over the 133rd session, accounting for 28.5% of the total export turnover. Transactions with countries co-building the Belt and Road Initiative amounted to US$12.27 billion, an increase of 2% over the 133rd session. Exhibitors said that the &quot;rapid return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the exhibition. In addition to signing orders on-site, buyers are constantly making follow-up appointments to visit factories, workshops, and production capacity, and are expected to reach more cooperation in the future. The quality of overseas purchasers attending this Canton Fair has improved and they are actively placing orders, which further enhances the confidence of enterprises in foreign trade exports next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, a bubble machine attracted the attention of overseas buyers.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/06/ac1d0fb344.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/06/ac1d0fb344.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a The bubble machine has attracted the attention of overseas buyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair were selecting colorful dolls and toys.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/06/b645302e77.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/b645302e77.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong , overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair are selecting colorful dolls and toys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, the optimization of the exhibition area structure of this Canton Fair has achieved remarkable results, and innovative exhibits have emerged in large numbers. Exhibitors have uploaded a total of more than 2.75 million exhibits to the online platform, including more than 700,000 new products, about 110,000 smart products, more than 430,000 green and low-carbon products, and about 230,000 independent intellectual property products. A total of 401 new product debut events were held. The 2023 Canton Fair Design Innovation Award (CF Award) award ceremony was held to award 141 innovative products from 118 units. New products, new technologies, new materials, new processes, and new services are emerging one after another. High-end intelligent, green and low-carbon products have become mainstream, and innovative and creative products are deeply favored. From small and beautiful new consumer products to cutting-edge cutting-edge technology, from simple OEM to going global with their own brands, from selling products to providing solutions, from traditional industries to emerging fields, Chinese companies continue to climb to the mid-to-high end of the industrial chain, demonstrating This reflects the strong development resilience and innovative vitality of China’s foreign trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair were selecting cute animal dolls.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7a1ea2d941.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/7a1ea2d941.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257154&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong , overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair are selecting cute animal dolls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers negotiated in the exhibition area of ​​a baby stroller brand.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/06/e9d743c1c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/06/e9d743c1c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas Buyers are negotiating in the exhibition area of ​​a baby stroller brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A total of 650 companies from 43 countries and regions participated in this year&#39;s Canton Fair Import Exhibition, focusing on displaying products such as intelligent manufacturing, quality home furnishings, and leisure life. The participating countries of the “Belt and Road Initiative” accounted for 60% of the exhibitors. Overseas exhibitors said that the Canton Fair Import Expo has built a fast channel for them to enter the Chinese market, allowing them to share the &quot;super traffic&quot; of the Canton Fair, while also meeting a large number of customers from all over the world, bringing new opportunities to expand the global market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Import Exhibition was attended by 650 companies from 43 countries and regions&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4e80921716.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/06/4e80921716.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257156&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Import Exhibition. A total of 650 companies from 43 countries and regions participated in the exhibition&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Exhibition General The total area is 1.55 million square meters, with more than 28,000 exhibitors and a total of 74,000 booths.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/36c7b8c2a9.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/36c7b8c2a9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 257157&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair has a total exhibition area of ​​1.55 million square meters, and exhibitors There are over 28,000 exhibitors, with a total of 74,000 booths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is understood that after the closing of this Canton Fair, the online platform will continue to be open. In addition to the functions of exhibitor connection and appointment negotiation, the other functions will be operated on a regular basis throughout the year. The 135th Canton Fair will be held from April 15 to May 5, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas buyer was browsing a brochure. The &quot;quick return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the Canton Fair. &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/cb7159e811.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/cb7159e811.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257158&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas buyer was browsing a brochure. The &quot;rapid return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the Canton Fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天津助学金事件通报：不存在国家助学金名额遭“挤占”情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260050]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 12:23:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, students have reported on the Internet about our school’s scholarship evaluation issues, which has attracted social attention. We are very grateful to the media and netizens for their concern for our students and their supervision of school work. The school set up a special work class to review relevant archives and materials, get an in-depth understanding of the situation from relevant teachers and students in the school, and organized a working group to conduct on-site visits and investigations in three students&#39; places of origin. The relevant situation has also been reported to relevant students. The relevant situation is now reported as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, since the student concerned raised objections to the identification of students with difficulties in the class on September 18, the person in charge of the financial aid work at both the school and college levels has maintained communication with the student and listened patiently to him. The opinions and appeals indicate that the school understands its actual difficulties and meets the conditions for receiving national scholarships in accordance with regulations. The specific grade is determined after comprehensive evaluation in accordance with relevant procedures. Since the student&#39;s enrollment, the local government and relevant relatives have guaranteed his tuition and living expenses. He has received second-class national scholarships for his freshman and sophomore years, and all have been paid out. The comprehensive evaluation for the junior year is expected to receive a second-class national scholarship. The college has announced the evaluation results from October 24th to October 27th. There is no &quot;crowding&quot; of the national scholarship quota. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, the family and personal circumstances of the other two students involved meet the conditions for financial aid for needy students. One student is expected to receive a second-class national scholarship this school year through comprehensive evaluation, and the other student is evaluated comprehensively for this school year. The candidate is expected to receive the National Inspirational Scholarship. No material fraud was found, the assessment complied with relevant regulations, and no &quot;malfeasance and abuse of power&quot; issues were found. The daily necessities alleged in the video were purchased with the above-mentioned students’ income from their work-study studies or were gifts from their relatives. Their high consumption behavior has been verified to be untrue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After repeated investigations by the school, there are no children of martyrs among the students at school, and there is no situation where the children of martyrs are not supported. All orphans among current students who have been identified by the civil affairs department have enjoyed state funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation also found that the relevant departments of the school were insufficient in their sincerity and care for students when carrying out funding work. The school will carefully summarize, further refine and optimize the student aid work, and provide more warmth and care to students from families with financial difficulties. We would like to thank all sectors of society for their concern, support and assistance to our school and related students, and welcome all sectors of society to continue to supervise and guide the work of our school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寒潮来袭羽绒服涨价，你有在准备过冬吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260042]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, strong winds, cooling, rain and snow have occurred in many places in the north. The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue orange blizzard warnings, cold wave blue warnings and strong wind blue warnings at 6:00 on November 6, and the heavy snowfall in Northeast China has entered its strongest period. Some media visited many wholesalers in Yiwu and learned that due to the increase in raw material prices this year, the purchase price of down jackets has generally increased. In addition to offline stores, e-commerce platforms are also celebrating Double Eleven, and gloves, thermos cups, and thermal underwear from many brand stores are also selling well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, summer is not over yet for some areas in the south, such as Guangzhou. Since summer officially started on April 11, the summer of 2023 in Guangzhou has exceeded 200 days, and this fall may be late. Moreover, an El Niño event is currently taking shape, and under its influence, temperatures in most central and eastern parts of my country will be higher than normal for the same period of the year. For many southern friends, down jackets are only used for a few days a year, and there are many who have never even bought a down jacket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Are you prepared for winter? Are you considering buying a down jacket for winter? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年各级政府支持就业创业资金超2000亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260030]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;1337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257144&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security Learned&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year various types of funds from governments at all levels&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Direct support for employment and entrepreneurship has exceeded 200 billion yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adjustment and optimization of employment stabilization policies&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Continue to implement the return policy until employment is stabilized&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue to expand from absorbing employment subsidies&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To promptly restart the one-time employment expansion subsidy&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Accelerate the release of policy dividends&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Injecting strong impetus into employment growth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to September&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10.22 million new jobs were created in urban areas across the country&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Complete the full-year target 85% of the target&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national urban surveyed unemployment rate at the end of September was 5%&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lower than the same period in 2019&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employment situation has generally improved and remained basically stable&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》，没写进报道的那些事丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260011]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Is there anyone else you particularly want to interview now? I was asked this question. I tried to count them on my fingers, but there seemed to be only a few. Qiu Litao may be one. I&#39;m looking forward to it after watching &quot;The Bomb Disposer 2&quot; at the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be able to create a huge allegory with big scenes of banging, banging and jingling bells, allowing the audience to take what they need and understand each other, is an amazing creative power. I wonder how this person recognizes his own expression. But Qiu Litao is obviously not someone who can talk about this. This may be a bit embarrassing for him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, when asked questions that are too serious and strict, he will usually say &quot;I didn&#39;t think so much&quot; and &quot;I can&#39;t make a movie if I think so.&quot; For example, when it comes to anarchism - which he corrects to anarchism - he says that the definition is too vague and he doesn&#39;t know what everyone is talking about when they say these words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao definitely does not &quot;think so little&quot;. This is my feeling when I watched the movie &quot;The Decameron of Sex Workers&quot; directed by him. Regarding the young lady&#39;s situation, the mockumentary had a lot of back and forth, flashes of swords and swords. They are not expressions of &quot;pretentiousness&quot;, but are full of market acumen, speculation and ridicule. It&#39;s quite clever, but also quite embarrassing, like someone has taken off your clothes. Qiu Litao doesn&#39;t like clear things. From a utilitarian point of view, he is of course more tolerant of gray and vagueness. You can call him rough, but there are so many things that help him enrich his semantics. Who can I ask to explain? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first watched &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, I liked the sense of relaxation - many things that others have to put effort into laying out - such as whether this character is convincing or not, whether he resembles that era or not, it is not Qiu Litao Something that can be confusing. His camera flicked by, and his lack of restraint even formed a style. But that’s it, sometimes it works sometimes... I want to explain to readers that I don’t think this is a very good movie, although it is not without its merits. For example, the audience can see people and people in the early 1990s in the cinema. society. One of my interviewees felt that Qiu Litao might need a good screenwriter to help him overcome the cultural barrier of making films outside of Hong Kong. This is a tolerant statement, and after completing the reporting and writing of the report, I am willing to give a tolerant understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; uses many details to restore the social scene of the early 1990s. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Qiu Litao has leg problems and walks with a long stride, but he works hard enough to make People ignore this. People should be able to understand this feeling. When we were young and could not travel far away, the TV was a magical door at home, which could take us to different countries and distant starry skies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the interview, I wrote an email to Director Qiu Litao and asked him to introduce the interviewees. He felt that it would be a bit embarrassing for him to come forward and tell his partners, &quot;The media did an exclusive interview with me, and I would like to interview you to talk about my story and working methods.&quot; But he listed the right names and ways I could contact them. This is not his responsibility. I am grateful for his understanding and sympathy for media work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interviewed the main creators behind &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, such as the producer, screenwriter, action director and assistant director. In addition to talking about Qiu Litao, I also talked about their own work. Some stories that couldn’t be written into the main manuscript, I wanted to record in my notes. I hope I live up to their expectations and time, and I hope this information is useful to readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When screenwriter Chen Daming received the invitation from Chinese Pictures, he heard that multiple versions of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; had been written. Chen Daming is familiar with that history. In the late 1980s, he stayed at the Beijing Film Academy to teach. During the period when &quot;trafficking&quot; was most popular, most of the people lining up in the hall of the film school and making phone calls were not talking about art, but reselling color TVs and jeeps. The most successful business was selling MiG fighter jets - this last detail was written into the film. The character played by Andy Lau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What he wanted to show in the script was animality. &quot;People don&#39;t care about anything when they are hungry.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The villain Miao Qingshan played by Huang Xuan is nicknamed Old D. He likes to listen to Shostakovich&#39;s music. There is not much metaphor in this setting. Originally, Chen Daming wanted to call him Lao Bei, referring to Beethoven, but it didn&#39;t seem to fit him, so he wanted to find a Russian composer. One day he met a neighbor in the courtyard, an Englishman who was a conductor in China, and recommended Shostakovich. Chen Daming feels that his works have &quot;black elements&quot; and &quot;seem to be fighting against black forces and evil forces.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257131&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scene after the Shostakovich concert in the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, action director Li Zhongzhi was filming with Jackie Chan , there is no script for the scenes he is responsible for, just one word, play. Now the action scenes have to be integrated with the plot of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Gui Youming made great efforts to introduce me to the team of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The art designer Zhao Hai has worked on &quot;Ming Dynasty 1566&quot; and &quot;Toward the Republic&quot;, and one of the computer special effects production teams has worked on &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;. With the help of a digital imaging technology referred to as DIT, Gui Youming can see the shooting scene from anywhere with his iPad. Because of this technology, producer Andy Lau was able to follow up on-site shooting every day in the quarantine hotel at the time. Gui Youming believes that this is a characteristic of the industrialization of the film industry. This technology is very helpful when shooting movies of a scale similar to &quot;The Wandering Earth 3&quot; and &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As the producer of the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, Andy Lau (left) relied on high-tech communications to improve work efficiency during the filming of the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao was particularly impressed by the scene at the international train track-changing station interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deputy director Wen Zhenwei contacted the National Railway Administration and got back a lot of information. Qiu Litao was not concerned about the ins and outs and technical details of the train&#39;s track change at the Sino-Russian border. He only wanted to know where the people on the scene should be and how they reacted when the different carriages were raised. For example, that is when the flight attendants are most busy and when passengers are most curious. Few people have seen the train changing tracks at the border. At this time, the robbers rush in. &quot;It is a good timing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vasily, played by Andy Lau, has many fake passports. The fake name on one of them is Wen Zhenwei, which is the name of the assistant director. In order to avoid misunderstandings about the real names, the names of the staff will be used as much as possible when making movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Daming once saw some photos in National Geographic magazine, taking pictures of abandoned rocket bases around the world. He especially hopes to film a crime-related gunfight scene in such a place in the future. There is such a scene in &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. Gui Youming said to Zhao Hai, have you ever seen a movie called &quot;Oriental Condor&quot; (there is a similar scene in the film), I want to make it bigger than that. . So they referred to a lot of information about abandoned Russian rocket bases. &quot;I remember that day Uncle Zhi (Li Zhongzhi) came to the scene and said, &#39;What are you doing? Why is it so big?&#39;&quot; Gui Youming warned that we must make full use of this scene: &quot;Blow up here and there, run around, inside and outside Use everything, don’t waste it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chen Daming, the earliest draft of the script ended with a courtroom scene. Vasily was sentenced to 5 years in prison, suspended for 2 years. Policeman Cui Zhenhai patted him on the shoulder and said, if you look back, Vasily saw his daughter. In the original script, the daughter was 15 years old and attending a technical school. The daughter looked at her father from a distance, nodded, and that was how it ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao made major changes to the ending. In addition to adding the scene of the rail-changing station, he also changed Vasily&#39;s ending to one in which he was blinded due to a gun accident. Chen Daming thinks that there is a bit of blank space in this ending, and many people are guessing whether the daughter Vasily met at the end is real or fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[流连菖蒲河的老人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpIRG4hA5NAwK4U.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;781&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpI RG4hA5NAwK4U. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256659&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The social stage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, the ancient trees along the Changpu River in Beijing are still lush, and pairs of wild ducks inhabit the dark green stream. Every Tuesday and Saturday, when the sun is at its strongest, the classical promenade in Changpu River Park is filled with elderly people looking for partners, and the golden light spots add romantic vitality to them. The red wall of Huangshichen blocks the busy traffic of Chang&#39;an Street, bringing the park a secluded space suitable for romance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t expect a successful match based on true love.&quot; This is the sincere warning to latecomers from an old man who often comes to parties in Changpu River Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman in her fifties, dressed in an emerald-colored Tang suit and with exquisitely braided hair, refused to communicate with any of them in depth after an afternoon of ballroom dancing with a few uncles, and stayed alone. The pillars of the gallery rest. Asked why she wasn&#39;t looking for a partner in Changpu River Park, she said she wasn&#39;t looking because &quot;the blind dates here come with various conditions, and people are sold like livestock.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bald man in his sixties who always wears gold-framed sunglasses from Beijing has been here for 15 years. He can freely blend into any dating gossip and naturally bring together any interested couple. men and women. But when the other party&#39;s ambiguous signal reaches him, he always laughs at himself: &quot;I won&#39;t look for it. I have no money. If I don&#39;t have money, I can&#39;t find the right one.&quot; With a 14-square-meter bungalow and a retirement salary of more than 4,000 yuan, he always Can extinguish the other person&#39;s enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changpu River Park has been criticized by the elderly, but it always has the magic to tie them up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During a conversation in the corridor, it was like a default etiquette to ask each other about houses, household registration, salary, and medical insurance information. No one wants to be dragged down, everyone is rushing to get better conditions. After a while of &quot;greetings&quot;, there is a more detailed matching of needs. As long as you stay here for a day, the old people will not help but tell you that there are only a handful of people who set marriage registration as their goal; there are not a majority of people who are sincerely looking for a long-term wife. Maybe what the other person wants is just an ambiguous opposite-sex friendship or an extramarital affair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a common and decent ending to look down on each other. We can also become nodding friends - old acquaintances who say &quot;here we come&quot; to each other. And getting along emotionally involves the risk of paying for lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a week of official dating, his girlfriend asked Uncle Zhou to use his savings to buy her a gold ring worth 20,000 yuan. Uncle Zhou emphasized that &quot;that is pension money and cannot be touched.&quot; Afterwards, they broke up, and Uncle Zhou kept blaming himself for being a fool. Sister Qin met a man in his sixties in the park. During a video call at 9 o&#39;clock one night, other women vaguely appeared in the other party&#39;s kitchen. &quot;He didn&#39;t tell me at first that he had a relationship with more than one woman. I didn&#39;t like that he kept talking about sexual matters between men and women all day long.&quot; Sister Qin blocked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A typical temporary union occurred between a Northeastern woman in her fifties and a Beijing man in his seventies. One needs wealth and shelter, the other desires youth and care. After a period of time, there will always be a reason to bring an unhappy end to the relationship due to the ownership of the house, differences in consumption concepts, and the opposition of the man&#39;s children. After they broke up, the woman thought she was cheated of sex, and the man thought he was cheated of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Changpu River Park, some people can adapt to this &quot;exchange&quot; rule, while others find it chilling. Uncle Chen, 63, has a monthly rent income of 30,000 yuan. After ending his romantic relationship with a woman in her forties, he always took the initiative to compensate her with something, whether it was a big meal or a red envelope: &quot;Why should I let you, an old man, take advantage of me?&quot; Uncle Zhou would say Lamenting under the street lights at night, &quot;This place is like a microcosm of society. There is true love, but too little. Everyone has lost faith and only has the word &#39;profit&#39; in their eyes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who complain, People who have been deceived, people who are ready to break up, and people who seem to be watching indifferently will eventually return to the Changpu River. They persuaded the elder sister who was eager to be a matchmaker and register information for the elderly: this place is too chaotic and not a serious place to find a partner. They themselves are willing to be trapped in chaos. They always come here on Tuesdays and Saturdays to chat, strike up conversations, dance, and play cards. An old man riding a bicycle claimed that he was not here to fall in love, but on the blind date day, he would shuttle back and forth between the east and west gates of the park to observe and inquire around. He pointed to the winding corridor and said: &quot;This is the big stage of society. (I am here) to see how these people perform here wearing masks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Late release&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>; Geng Tielin wears a peaked cap and a mask and often hangs out in gathering areas where Northeasterners gather. He is from Harbin. He is 1.76 meters tall, well-proportioned and lean, and his posture when climbing up the river is brisk and flexible. It seems hard to believe that he is already 65 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m not looking for a date, I&#39;m just here for a walk. Besides, as a tall guy like me, I don&#39;t have to worry about no one liking me.&quot; Geng Tielin is confident in his charm. When he comes to the park, he just needs to stand there and many women will come and add their WeChat messages. He will approve the application out of politeness, but the only people he is interested in are &quot;tall, good-looking, and under 60&quot;; the only people he agrees to get along with are people who don&#39;t covet his money and &quot;don&#39;t want this or that.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his chat history, there are three women in their fifties who he calls &quot;sisters&quot;. When chatting with other elderly people in the park, Geng Tielin referred to them more as &quot;friends&quot; - people who can meet up to eat, travel, and sleep in the same bed without binding each other to a fixed identity. The sisters came from a well-off family and never asked Geng Tielin to bear any expenses. He sent a wedding red envelope to the son of one of his sisters, but the other party politely returned it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since his divorce 35 years ago, Geng Tielin has never had a long-term girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When my wife left, my daughter was only 5 years old. In order to raise his daughter, Geng Tielin worked as a driver, a chef, and opened a breakfast shop to help her get admitted to a graduate school in a Beijing university. The daughter found a job in a bank in Beijing, and the old father moved to Beijing with her and cooked in a factory canteen in Daxing. Geng Tielin was very proud when talking about his daughter who bought a house with an area of ​​more than 80 square meters and a value of more than 6 million yuan in Chaoyang District with an annual salary of one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geng Tielin said that he had not touched a woman for more than 20 years after his divorce. The biggest reason is that he doesn&#39;t want the shadow of his &quot;stepmother&quot; to hinder his daughter&#39;s growth. But he has desires - physiological desires that cannot be channeled and are born at the wrong time. In those days, having sex outside of marriage was considered hooliganism. Geng Tielin did not dare to tell anyone, so he could only hold back or solve it on his own. &quot;It&#39;s such a shame, I was so miserable during those twenty years.&quot; After the millennium, he gradually tried to date different women. Sometimes it’s a hotel clerk you meet while driving, sometimes it’s an acquaintance whose husband is crying to him about his loss of sexual function due to cerebral palsy. However, no romance has turned into a stable relationship. Geng Tielin believes that it is impossible for him to ask others to adapt to his &quot;bad habits.&quot; Worrying about his daughter and raising a family, he often stayed awake all night, pacing back and forth and scrolling through his cell phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, he suddenly took off his peaked cap and showed me: his almost smooth head had only short, gray and sparse hair, dotted around the ears. At this time, he became a 65-year-old man. &quot;Our family has good genes, and no one has ever lost their hair. My grandfather was lying in a coffin at the age of 90 with black hair. It was because of his insomnia in those years that my hair became like this. I also want to have a wife to love, and have My wife loves me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frugal and chic single life is also what Geng Tielin enjoys. He refused to live under the same roof as his daughter and rented a house of more than 20 square meters in Yanjiao to live alone, paying only 400 yuan in rent per month. Sauce elbow is Geng Tielin’s specialty. The price of raw materials in Yanjiao is only half of that downstairs in my daughter&#39;s community. Geng Tielin feels that now is the best time in life. His daughter has a future and he does not have to worry about raising his granddaughter. He is in good health and lives a comfortable life. There is no new partner to divide one&#39;s salary, but there are tender greetings and the joy of traveling together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On National Day two years ago, while wandering around, Geng Tielin accidentally discovered Changpu River Park. Although the elderly people here &quot;have their own thoughts,&quot; the situation of single elderly people is very similar to his. Even if he can&#39;t find a satisfactory &quot;friend&quot;, Geng Tielin still likes to chat here. He said he was not lonely at all, and his life of walking in the park and recuperating at home was well arranged. He also said that after his daughter got married, she was too busy and made fewer phone calls than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I met Geng Tielin, a slender lady with wavy hair reaching her waist, wearing a silk scarf, took the initiative to sit next to him, and the two talked and laughed. When I met him for the second time two days later, he said he wanted to delete the other person. According to him, the two went on a date to visit Zhongshan Park, and the man paid for the trip. Naturally, the lady ordered an extra bun, and asked Geng Tielin to buy the &quot;Pulse&quot;. She also insisted on asking for a 50 yuan hat in the scenic spot. Three more days later, I saw him for the third time. While chatting, Geng Tielin suddenly held his chin in a daze and murmured to himself: If there is someone better than those sisters, he will fall in love with her, and he will live with her wholeheartedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Live life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compare calamus Among the other well-dressed ladies in He Park, Zhang Ming&#39;an&#39;s clothing is obviously pragmatic. Her short hair was dyed jet black but didn&#39;t appear to be trimmed carefully. The upper body is a warm but bloated dark blue fur coat, the lower body is black pants and black shoes, and a styleless cross-body bag hangs casually in front of the body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In just one hour by bus, Zhang Mingan can go to the park from his home near Tiantongyuan. It was 9:30 a.m. on Saturday before the elderly people who lived further away had time to arrive. The promenade of the park was a little quiet. Most of the people who came were local Beijingers like Zhang Mingan who lived in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, Zhang Mingan also wanted to find a local who lived in the city to be her wife, but it was obvious that she had not met anyone she was satisfied with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Beijing gentleman communicated with her back to back for a while, then turned and left.她撅着嘴望向对方的背影，在接受采访时对我说：“你有老婆了上这儿来干嘛？不是霍霍儿（注：北京话，糟蹋、破坏事物）吗？我成什么啦？”大爷有法律关系的妻子长期生活在国外，而他已经参加过三次北京老年相亲节目《选择》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张明安口中，这些都是“花里胡哨”的关系。 62岁的她，只有一个朴素的要求，那就是找一个能“过日子”的老伴，一起过完人生最后二十几年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张明安没有孩子。三十多岁时因子宫病变做了切除手术，之后，她和第一任丈夫离婚。 50岁，她找到了可以一起环游世界的伴侣，老方。张明安笑着告诉我，10年间，他们曾一起参加实惠的旅行团，去过美、泰、日、韩。在她60岁时，老方因胰腺癌去世。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;花了一年多时间走出抑郁，张明安想通了，要为自己而活。和单位的退休姐妹跳舞打球，追追抗日剧，家里收拾得利索整齐。 “动不了再去敬老院，确保有人替自己收尸就行，没有想找老伴的事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年12月，张明安意识到孤身一人的脆弱。感染新冠后，她一个人躺在家里的沙发上，茶几和水杯离她很近，但全身无力，够不到这口水，在沙发上渴了一天。她真希望，身边有一个人，能递个药，熬口粥。 “我不行了，你伺候伺候我。你不行了，我照顾照顾你。付出真心，互相搀扶。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我是过日子的一把好手。”张明安这样认为。炸油饼、烙馅饼、蒸花卷，都不在话下。邻居说她有洁癖，家里总是很干净，地上有一丝头发都要捡起来。邻居还说，老方真有福气，生病后动不了，每天洗脚、剪指甲都是张明安在伺候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张明安总是找不到能好好过日子的人。去中介所相亲时，对方开口闭口都在谈自己有十几套房子。张明安指出，她不信，也不图这个。联谊会上，有许多外地人，也不符合她的择偶期待。来菖蒲河公园后，来问她的，或者是有老伴的人，或者是跳跳舞、纯玩的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;线下相亲平台的匮乏，也是一个问题。张明安回忆，在昌平某婚庆中介所登记介绍，需要交1000元。在东城区，价格则在1万以上。昌平那家登记后，第一次和第二次为她匹配对象的时间，隔了一年。线下集会效率更高，但日常的集会地点，她只知道周二、周六的菖蒲河公园和周日的天坛公园。张明安更希望，在线下活动中，户口、婚姻、财产等状况都能得到实名认证，减少不必要的沟通成本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;执念&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在菖蒲河公园的相亲圈内，外地人，尤其是外地女人的口碑并不算太好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些人口中，她们五十多岁背井离乡，希望在北京立足，刚从火车站下车就拖着行李来到公园，有老头给钱给房子就愿意和他生活，条件是承担所有家务。有一位北京大爷告诉我，他曾遇见一位39岁的美丽的外省女人。女人知道他是北京人后，立马表示要嫁给他——这是为了给儿子争取北京户口，她说北京高考更容易考上清华北大。在另一位大爷口中，一位外省女性老是把彩礼的条件摆在嘴边，这让他感到观念上的巨大鸿沟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本地人心中，即便不是所有来这里的外地女性都这样，但这张地域名片背后也暗暗刻上了“无情重利”这4个字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自外地的王鸿桢似乎能坦荡地接受这个标签。她的内蒙朋友孟纾影，却希望在菖蒲河找到有爱情基础的长期伴侣。王鸿桢恨铁不成钢：“她这个想法，在这儿根本找不着。趁我身体还好，能抓钱就抓钱，在这儿找长期过日子的，那是不可能的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她口中的抓钱，是领着三千多元的工资在男方家中做保姆。 2023年8月之前，她住在88岁的北京老教授家中，直到对方的女儿把他接到美国去。除了做家务，王鸿桢陪他买菜、锻炼、去公园，听他讲历史，帮他洗澡搓背。他们在同一个屋檐下单独待了两年，王鸿桢分不清这算不算有情感，自己算不算当了对方的老伴。但她认为这个已经不重要了，“挣钱为主，对象其次。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15年前，王鸿桢和她的朋友一样，渴望通过这个菖蒲河公园的平台重获婚姻和幸福。这个梦想后来破碎了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2000年，41岁、离异的王鸿桢带着两个儿子来到北京打拼。她开过美容店，也在中介公司和旅行社打过工。 2007年，当王鸿桢还是菖蒲河公园一枝花的时候，在这里遇到了一位丧偶的自来水厂经理。对方和她年龄相当，高大俊朗，两人坠入爱河。但在对方儿女的强烈反对下，他们没能再走下去。每年王鸿桢从老家回北京，都会给曾经的恋人带上一份土特产以示感谢。在她最困难的时候，他曾资助她租房和看病。和第二个对象的情感不如第一个那么炽烈，但恋情同样终止于对方女儿的忌惮。之后的故事并不甜蜜，王鸿桢和一位男士登记结婚一年后，对方把她甩了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，菖蒲河公园的大爷们，在王鸿桢眼中都是骗人睡觉、玩够就踹掉女方的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的执念变成了在北京拥有独立住所。以自己的实力，王鸿桢没法在北京买到房子。和大儿子住在大厂（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;河北大厂回族自治县&lt;/span>;），她不得不包揽照顾全家五口人的家务。 “他们工作太忙，带俩小孩遛弯、做饭、洗衣服都是我在做。住3个月就得生病。”出来当保姆，反倒是一种休息。王鸿桢的另一种考量是，“现在我身体好，不想住在儿子家麻烦他们。如果时间长了有矛盾，老了以后怎么找人家帮你呢？多不仗义呀。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果非要结成有男女之实的伴侣，王鸿桢的要求是：第一要在北京有能住的地方。第二，要么登记结婚，满两年后让她把户口迁到北京；要么不登记，但每月给她一笔钱。她说，拥有北京户口，离婚了也可以申请经济适用房，可以在北京报销医药费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有大爷向王鸿桢发出温情脉脉的吃饭邀约，她总是预感对方要骗色，于是吓唬回去：“你现在跟我登记结婚，房本写下我的名字，我就和你吃饭，否则拉倒。”一旁的大爷责怪她太霸道：“你得先有情感基础再谈这些经济付出，要不怎么叫恋爱呢？”王鸿桢笑了笑，没回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周六晚上的人总比周二的多，老人们不用赶着接放学的孙辈回家。 6点以后，天空转成暗蓝色，长廊尽头的舞曲还在播放，宴会还没进入尾声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我遇见了一位在陈晓楠的节目《和陌生人说话》中出现过的受访者。正是这个节目挖掘了菖蒲河公园的老年相亲角，让它暴露在媒体的聚光灯下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位受访者并不像节目中那么昂扬。他坦言，节目播出后的6年，自己一直在这里寻寻觅觅，有过几段感情，但仍未找到理想伴侣。他说，“周二、周六菖蒲河，周四中山公园和陶然亭，周日天坛公园。每一个地方，去的都是这同一拨人。”这里已经变成老人们上班打卡的地方。即使找不到对象，抱团聚一聚总好过一个人闷在家里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大家都是老年人。也许哪一天，其中一个就不能再来了呢。”谈话期间，一位大爷上梯子时突然绊倒，受访者和周围几位相对年轻一点的老年人，急忙跑上去把他搀扶起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(为保护受访者隐私，文中人物均为化名。)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《老友记》钱德勒一生对抗毒瘾：美国“鸦片危机”有多严重？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260017]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月28日，美国知名情景喜剧《老友记》的钱德勒(Chandler)扮演者Matthew Perry（马修•派瑞）在洛杉矶家里热水浴缸中疑似溺水身亡，终年54岁。当地执法部门称“现场没有发现毒品，也没有被谋杀迹象”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;案件尚在调查中，且暂时在“现场”没发现毒品，但不代表此案没有药物滥用背景。事实上，从1990年代中期《老友记》第一季时，Matthew就沉迷于酒精和药物。在其回忆录《Friends, Lovers and the Big Terrible Thing》中自述：他一生的时间都在对抗毒瘾，其间两次濒临死亡，花费高达900万美元（相当于6585万人民币）。但最终仍败下阵来，最严重时，他每天吞服55粒Vicodin（维柯丁，阿片类镇痛药），猛灌1升伏特加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此次事件非常相似，2012年2月11日，美国歌坛天后、48岁的Whitney Houston，在洛杉矶比弗利山庄的希尔顿酒店，因服用药物过量导致心脏病发作，失去知觉后滑入浴缸溺亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更早些，2009年6月25日，美国摇滚巨星Michael Jackson，因私人医生Conrad Murray为其注射了致命剂量的异丙酚（短效静脉麻醉药）而诱发心脏病死亡。此前，Jackson也多年大量使用多种止痛药、麻醉药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这些大牌明星嗑药旗帜号召之下，美国人吸毒、致瘾类药物滥用异常严重。按“美国国家药物滥用统计中心”分类标准，主要有八大类型毒品：酒精、大麻、可卡因、海洛因、芬太尼、甲基苯丙胺（冰毒）、阿片类药物（受管制的精神药物）、处方兴奋剂。美国以不到全球5%人口，却使用了全球80%的阿片（鸦片）类药物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“美国疾控中心（CDC）”数据：12岁及以上年龄的约2.8亿美国人中，约有3190万吸毒者，平均每12人就有1人吸毒，占全球吸毒总人数的12%。平均每天约300人死于毒品，每年吸毒致死者达10万人，其中约7.1万死于芬太尼滥用，毒品致死人数是死于枪祸的美国人8倍，远超艾滋病、车祸、枪祸死亡人数的总和，其中70%为25-54岁之间的男性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国国会联合经济委员会”2022年报告指出：滥用阿片类药物给美国造成近1.5万亿美元损失，约占当年GDP的7%。2022年，与“新冠疫情”暴发前相比，美国损失了约630万劳动力，其中约20%是药物滥用所致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论从生命损失、经济损失、社会治安、道德败坏……各方面来看，美国陷入了规模宏大、遥遥无期的全民性“鸦片危机”。与1840-1842年晚清那场灾难不同，美国人的“鸦片危机”没有外部武力入侵，完全是他们自导自演：青少年群体，是美国吸毒人数增长和死亡人数增长最快的年龄组，18-25岁人群吸毒率达39%；26-29岁人群为34%；13岁之前尝试非法药物者达70%，吸食毒品低龄化趋势明显。这一趋势显示出：传统的美国价值观正在崩溃，正如李光耀在《中国与世界》中谈到的“美国精神”的消散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国“卫生与公众服务部”前副部长表示：当前美国毒品和药物滥用是最具破坏性的公共卫生灾难之一。这场危机是美政府多系统监管失败的反映，急需紧急、统一、全面的应对措施。美国“全国公共广播电台”（NPR）痛陈“美式自由主义”酿成了美国的悲剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导致毒品泛滥的“新自由主义”（New Liberalism），又称进步主义，乃是极左意识形态。其与古典自由主义是截然对立的，后者所主张的自由是在不妨碍他人权利前提下按自我意志行为的权利，没有法律就没有自由，私有财产不可侵犯，每个人为自己的行为负责。其主张的自由是：不受任何限制、不承担任何后果的行为，即“想做啥就做啥、想咋做就咋做”，最好还由政府或社会来埋单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美式自由主义，从1960年代开始通过性解放、性放纵、吸食毒品、颓废文艺等手段，在西方掀起诸多“进步主义”社会运动。持续几十年至今，导致了婚姻和家庭逐渐土崩瓦解、毒品泛滥、犯罪横行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国“鸦片危机”的祸根却难以根治，美警方曾谈到：如果按东方社会的严厉禁毒措施，那就得处决超过百万毒贩，把美国监狱全部腾空再扩容十倍，用于强制戒毒。但这在美国和西方社会，是根本不可想象的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国民主党政府搞“理念创新”：把吸毒合法化，不算犯罪，那么涉毒犯罪率不就下降了吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是把毒品区分为“硬毒品”和“软毒品”，对成瘾性、危害性稍微低些的，如大麻，在美国的31个州被允许合法使用（医用）、10个州允许合法使用娱乐大麻。然后，俄勒冈州通过了“110法案”，成为美国首个将持有海洛因、冰毒、可卡因等“硬毒品”非罪化的州：持有少于1克的海洛因、摇头丸，少于2克的可卡因、冰毒，少于12克的裸盖菇素，少于40剂的致幻剂、羟考酮等情况，将不再被视为犯罪，取而代之的是100美元罚款或健康评估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一理念创新“成果显著”，美国《国会山报》2022年8月28日报道：盖洛普民调显示，吸食大麻的美国人数创下历史新高，首次超过了吸烟人数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了“硬毒品”和“软毒品”分阶段走的策略之外，美国制药产业还推出了“阿片（鸦片）类处方药”策略。俄亥俄州“罗伯戒毒中心”负责人Hill认为：相比其他国家，美国人更倾向于选择通过药物来缓解疼痛，释放压力。促成这一社会文化形成的主要动力，是1990年代中期，美国大型医药企业投入重金展开的“制药史上最慷慨营销活动”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中最典型的是1995年，美国“普渡制药公司”推广其研发的Oxycontin（奥施康定），率先打响了“阿片类药物无害论”宣传攻势，其上市后6年内，普渡公司赞助了2万个宣教项目。阿片类药物制造商和经销商在10年内花费了8.8亿美元，用于营销广告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿片类药物将阿片衍生物含量大大降低，服药者就采取增加服药量的对策。譬如前文的Matthew就曾每天吞服55粒阿片类镇痛药，采取医嘱处方的合法方式，“曲线”服用毒品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毒品导致的深层次社会问题，包括：毒品对吸食者脑内神经造成破坏，引发心理变态和认知障碍、诱发精神疾病、加剧情绪激化，导致家庭危机、暴力犯罪、儿童心理创伤等问题；贩毒所导致的黑社会犯罪、凶杀等暴力灾难，影响社会稳定，产生洗钱等上下游犯罪。在社会层面，毒品泛滥削减了美国社会劳动力基数，影响美国人口平均寿命；在精神层面，毒品及其诱发的犯罪摧垮传统价值观、泯灭正义良知、毁灭道德、释放人性中的至恶，是具有击垮社会、动摇国本、摧毁后代精神与意识形态基础的毁灭性犯罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国的“鸦片危机”已积重难返，仍将长期继续，毒品泛滥成为美国社会中传统群体所深恶痛绝，但却难以真正铲除的痼疾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被诬偷拍的人，不可逆转的伤害]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260001]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 23:03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;11月3日，“成都地铁被诬陷偷拍案”开庭审理。近年来，“偷拍乌龙”事件频出，面对被当众指责偷拍、变态的窘况，被冤枉者只能忍气吞声吗？应该如何理性维权？&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走，去大自然丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 22:00:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;5月23日，2023年珠峰科考登顶队员在冲顶&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相关报道详见《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/259430&quot; title=&quot;冰川记忆：中国珠峰科考六十年&quot;>;冰川记忆：中国珠峰科考六十年&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两年，我时常怀念一个或许并不存在的昨日世界。就好像茨威格形容他的父辈，被理想主义蒙蔽的一代人抱着乐观主义的幻想，坚信宽容和友好是不可缺少的约束力，真诚地认为各个国家及各个教派之间的界限和信仰的分歧，将会在人们的友善中逐渐化解，整个人类将享有最宝贵的财富：和平与安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;种种原因，我的工作和生活都在面对各种各样的人群，了解各式各样的思想，在沟通、靠近、了解、解释。而就像我的同事M所形容的，时常会想“即时退出人类社会”。每当此时，我就会做一些和人类无关的选题，动物或植物，大河或高山。无论大象出走还是洪水泛滥，无论冰川消融还是山林火灾，这些都折射出人类的渺小和愚蠢，人类的退让与自救。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这便是我想报道珠峰科考、冰川消融的最初动机。简单地说，连珠峰都能测出DDT（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有机氯类杀虫剂&lt;/span>;）了，连东绒布冰川都在节节败退了，对于喜马拉雅这座横跨五国的年轻山脉，人类难道不该搁置偏见与分歧，互相信任合作么？也确实，在采访中，冰川研究者普遍把世界视为一体，面对自然，面对宇宙，争端与冲突都失去了意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管，全球变暖不仅关乎环境，也关乎公平。最脆弱人群和生态系统遭受的损失和损害尤为严重，也正在承受与自身责任不相称的气候变化的不利影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如同对上世纪八九十年代主张“重写文学史”和人文精神大讨论，意图在文学中剥离立场本就是一种立场，意图超越意识偏见去记录科学工作，或许本身就是一种意识的选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰州和西藏的采访，在我面前展开的是开阔的世界，是造物者之无尽藏也。这些在中国西部从事冰川研究的科学家热爱野外科考，部分原因就是热爱自由，追求潇洒的生活，他们能够忍受在珠峰脚下驻扎十年的艰苦，也是他们不吝啬时间，有能感知到地球脉动和珠峰壮阔的幸运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有回晚上采访，我们坐在兰州大学的操场上，受访者跟我说，有时候还挺同情你们大城市人，那么多压力，永远走不出钢筋水泥的城市森林。我突然想到印象派的诞生：经历了工业革命的都市人，开始厌弃弥漫着工业雾霾的伦敦，向往田园与大自然。而后脱胎于印象派，又诞生了更为自由的野兽主义、立体主义、表现主义。中国也已经完成了工业革命。今天的国人，是否也向往自然与田园？向往离开小环境或大环境里的冲突与争斗？这是否会催生新的文化形态？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说回对全球变暖、冰川消融的关注。我心里过不去的愧疚是，记录一些研究冰川、感知地球脉动的人以科学证实人类活动剧烈地伤害了环境，好像谈不上是关注环境变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但最近，我读到了一段金国威的创作阐述，感到有所安慰甚至自洽。他是以拍摄《徒手攀岩》、《泰国洞穴救援》享誉全球的纪录片导演，他说：“我喜欢拍摄人性积极的那一面，那些能激励我们变得更好的品质。我有很多朋友拍摄人性的另一面，战争、冲突、争议。很显然，我还没有拍过这种主题的作品。世界上已经发生了这么多灰心的事，让人悲伤，让人愤怒，我希望试着制作能与之抗衡的作品，我想这是我能为世界做出的贡献。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[自家院子聚餐要办证？行政执法别乱来丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260013]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，河南滑县执法人员称农村立火聚餐就需要办证的视频，引起极大关注。滑县市监局11月1日发布情况通报，称执法人员解读政策不规范，引起误解，对其停职处理。不过这一通报对事件的定性语焉不详，引起了网民更大的质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据网友反映，他们正准备在自家院子里聚餐，突然来了几个执法人员。视频中，一名穿制服的工作人员表示，“只要立火就属于经营了，集体聚餐得办食品安全许可证、食品经营许可证，如果不办是罚款。”面对网友的质疑，执法人员拿出一本食品安全法，表示要求办证有法律依据。这引起了网友的极大质疑，很多人在视频下跟帖：“自己家烧火做饭要不要办证？”“前几天请几个亲戚来家吃饭，没办证，是不是违法了？”“过几天打算请几个朋友自家聚餐，请问去哪里办证？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成为网络热点后，滑县市监局通报称，10月17日，该局接到举报称某村一院内有人聚餐。执法人员到达现场后，“发现并不是农村正常红白喜事聚餐活动。5名人员正在现场备菜、清洗餐具，加工环境简陋、露天作业，无&#39;三防&#39;设施，操作人员未持有效健康证明，存在严重的安全隐患，易引发食品安全事件，危害群众身体健康。执法人员对上述人员进行相关法律法规的讲解并劝导停止加工行为”；“在执法过程中，执法人员对政策解读不规范，引起了群众误解。责令该同志作出深刻检查，停职处理”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说实话，这个通报看得人一头雾水。前面一段，似乎是说执法没问题。只是执法人员解读政策不够规范。果真如此的话，只是一点小错误，犯不着停职吧？批评教育，然后学习规范的政策解读就可以了嘛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但仔细一读第一段，却是越读越糊涂。现场“不是正常红白喜事聚餐”，那是什么聚餐？红白喜事聚餐是正常的，其他的聚餐是不正常的？“正常”的红白喜事聚餐需要办证吗？还是只有“不正常”的聚餐才需要？这到底是个什么聚餐？聚餐的有多少人？现场在备菜的5人，也是聚餐人员还是他们请的厨师？这些问题的答案不同，可能事件的性质就完全不一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说，这只是亲朋好友之间的聚餐，备菜的也是聚餐人员的一部分，那所谓执法就完全没有理由。亲友聚餐，自己做菜自己吃，需要办食品安全证、食品经营证吗？当然不需要。没有任何一条法律有这样的规定。所谓“加工环境简陋、露天作业，无&#39;三防&#39;设施，操作人员未持有效健康证明”等等，都不违反任何法律。农村聚餐，无论红白喜事也罢，其他理由也罢，人多的话，在自家院子里露天炒菜，主人家忙不过来，亲戚朋友一起帮忙，也都是常有的事。难道还要亲友提供健康证？只要自家亲戚不嫌弃，监管部门没有什么理由去干预。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有可能备菜的是主人家专门请的厨师。聚餐人多的活动，请专业厨师上门服务，这在一些地方农村也已经非常普遍。这些厨师一般有固定的团队，在四邻八乡流动服务，收取服务费。这确实是一种经营性的餐饮服务，要求相关人员办理健康证明、食品经营许可证等似乎有法可依。但问题在于，原食药监总局制定的食品经营许可办法要求“一地一证”，也就是说，在一个场所进行食品经营，就要取得一个许可证。对于流动的餐饮服务，这个要求很难实现，不可能每到一个地方服务，都提前去监管部门办证，更不用说这些临时的场地，很难满足许可法规规定的条件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人说，或可以将其视为食品摊贩进行管理。食品安全法对食品生产加工小作坊和食品摊贩等作了较宽松的规定，并授权省级政府制定具体管理办法。但河南省人大2017年通过的《河南省食品小作坊、小经营店和小摊点管理条例》中，食品小作坊、小经营店都要求有固定的生产经营场所，小摊点虽无固定店铺，但也要在批准的地点和规定的时间内摆摊设点。所以，这一条例也不适用于流动上门提供餐饮服务的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在没有明确法规可依的情况下，要怎么办？是以食品安全法中“从事食品生产、食品销售、餐饮服务，应当依法取得许可”的抽象规定，强求提供流动餐饮服务的团队去办证，然后又以不符合办证条件为由拒绝，将他们取缔，还是遵循行政执法的谦抑原则，在无明确法条可依据的时候，尽可能少干预？正确的选择应该是不言而喻的。毕竟，农村不像城市一样到处都是饭店，有的地方可能离镇上的饭店有十几里路，交通工具也没有那么方便，办完事再跋山涉水去吃饭，也不现实。无视农村公众的实际需求，机械执法，只会让这一市场转入地下。监管部门，还是要多服务，少“执法”，尤其不要动不动就用罚款来威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深秋川西：最美季节，斑斓画卷]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259992]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>