<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[视频小作文与泛道德批判：真的有助于社会道德风尚的提升吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259108]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some time ago, &quot;netizens posted a video reporting that a woman had accompanied her leader to drink and lie drunk on the street many times&quot;, which triggered a large number of onlookers and Hot discussion, many people have seen it, many people immediately established such a &quot;mental position&quot;: This thing seems to be untrue, and emotions such as contempt or anger suddenly surged, and then they put the matter aside Go aside and rush to the next hot spot that is real or seems real, and you are filled with the same sense of justice or righteous indignation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on October 6, Tai’an High-tech Industrial Development Zone in Shandong Province issued an investigation report on this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is ironic is that in the so-called &quot;report video&quot;, the video shooter claimed that Zhang, a member of the Party Working Committee and Deputy Director of the Management Committee of Tai&#39;an New District, had an improper relationship with the woman. In fact, Zhang There is no such relationship with the woman (Xu), but the person who has a male-female relationship with Xu is precisely the person who shot and posted the video, Meng. The married man Meng had a relationship with the unmarried woman Xu during the relationship. Because of an emotional dispute, he created a related video through grafting and malicious editing and published it on a certain platform, in order to &quot;retaliate&quot; against the other party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng released a video containing false information and insulted and slandered others, which is obviously an illegal act that blatantly infringes on the reputation rights of others. If this is regarded as a report, then it is undoubtedly a malicious and false accusation. . The matter is far from that simple. The investigation showed that although Zhang and Xu, who both worked in the high-tech development zone, did not have an improper relationship between men and women as mentioned in the &quot;report video&quot;, they had the problem of accepting corporate banquets in violation of regulations. It is this situation that has caused differences of opinion among netizens who have been paying attention to the incident. Some netizens believe that although Zhang and Xu have other problems, &quot;one code to one code&quot; cannot change the illegal fact that Meng has violated the reputation rights of others. Other netizens believe that although the &quot;report&quot; of the video publisher Meng was untrue, it uncovered other problems. If Meng is held accountable, potential whistleblowers like this will be discouraged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This debate actually contains a rather profound social moral issue, that is, the encouragement of &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; and &quot;low-cost reporting&quot; will really help to form a clean and upright society. Environment? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pan-moral criticism&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pan-moral criticism&quot; is a very popular criticism method in the Internet era. Critics often moralize all personal grievances and social phenomena and use &quot;public opinion&quot; to moralize them. &quot;In the name of &quot;justice&quot;, they gain the moral high ground and condescendingly carry out absolute moral criticism of the target of attack. Critics often use &quot;group labels&quot; to project a certain stereotype of the public on the specific parties involved in the incident, deliberately disrupting the public&#39;s judgment of the basic facts of the incident, and then leading the public to attack the parties in order to achieve the moral integrity of the parties. &quot;social death&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Precisely because &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; can often occupy the moral high ground in the name of public opinion, after successfully arousing public sentiment, the critic himself obtains a certain kind of &quot;moral golden body&quot;, even if he himself Even if there are major moral flaws, they can often be exempted from questioning and accountability under the banner of &quot;justice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the aforementioned incident, the video publisher Meng apparently used identity labels such as &quot;leader&quot; and &quot;official&quot; to &quot;label&quot; the parties involved, Xu and Zhang, and then led the public to label &quot;corruption&quot; This impression was projected onto Xu and Zhang, disrupting the public&#39;s attention and judgment on the fact itself &quot;whether Zhang and Xu had an improper relationship between men and women,&quot; and ultimately achieved the goal of &quot;discrediting&quot; Zhang and Xu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that this farce of &quot;exposure&quot; and &quot;reporting&quot; directed and performed by Meng is a standard &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot;. Meng himself has moral problems, but he dares to make up unbridled stories. In fact, to conduct &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; of others is to believe that once one occupies the high ground of &quot;justice&quot;, one has the privilege of unilaterally criticizing others without any moral questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moral sense is a social ideology that embodies the public’s pursuit of social fairness and justice. The purpose of moral criticism is to praise the beautiful and belittle the ugly, punish the evil and promote the good at the moral level, and then promote the social morality. improvement. However, this is not the case with &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot;. There are many grotesques and farces in which moral depravity stands on the high ground of &quot;justice&quot; and criticizes the moral depravity of others. &quot;Pan-moral criticism&quot; not only fails to promote the improvement of social morality, but also allows speculators to run rampant on the Internet, which not only causes the focus of public opinion supervision, but also creates a society where &quot;ruling the virtuous with no virtue&quot; Moral regression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said unceremoniously that &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; is the alienation and distortion of &quot;moral criticism&quot;. Therefore, in a society, if the public is generally keen on &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; and cannot extricate themselves, it will not only fail to improve social morality, but will lead to the regression and collapse of social morality. Netizens who believe that Meng&#39;s unjust behavior has a &quot;just&quot; result and therefore should not be punished or should be given a lighter punishment have actually been subtly influenced by Meng&#39;s &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; trap. And unconsciously accepted such an alienated network morality. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Low-cost reporting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot;, there is another problem in the incident of &quot;netizens posting videos to report that the woman had accompanied the leader to drink and lie drunk on the street many times&quot;: we Whether the society accepts &quot;video exposure&quot; as a low-cost &quot;reporting&quot; method? If this &quot;reporting&quot; method is established, should it be the same as other reporting channels, requiring the reporter to bear the corresponding responsibilities and consequences arising from the untrue content of the report? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty in defining whether &quot;video exposure&quot; behavior meets the definition of &quot;reporting&quot; is that it is not a point-to-point one-way transmission relationship between the whistleblower and the accepting agency like the traditional reporting method. Instead, they often start with a &quot;pan-moral criticism&quot; and ferment into public opinion on the Internet platform, forcing relevant departments to investigate. What ultimately responds to problems is often not the traditional petition and disciplinary inspection and supervision mechanisms, but the public opinion handling mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This leads to a series of problems. First of all, because this method of &quot;reporting&quot; is not a traditional channel, it is difficult to be constrained and restricted by various regulations. Even if there are legal consequences, it is often punished for &quot;releasing false information to disrupt social and public order&quot;, and Their &quot;false accusations&quot; are difficult to pursue, which makes it possible for them to exploit loopholes in the system and corrupt the social atmosphere by evading the most important and minimizing the minor, writing essays and videos that are both true and false. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this kind of &quot;forced reporting&quot; that uses the public opinion handling mechanism conducts a moral trial on the parties in advance before the relevant departments investigate, forming invisible pressure from public opinion to interfere with the investigation. Once the investigation is carried out, The results are inconsistent with the results of the moral trial, which can easily lead to public doubts and criticism of the investigation department and damage the credibility of the relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, once those with ulterior motives find that this reporting method is more &quot;effective&quot; than traditional channels, then the mentality of &quot;let the matter go unnoticed and someone else will take care of it&quot; will inevitably spread. Trivial matters in daily life and personal grievances rise to the level of morality, and then publicity and hype form online public opinions, which in turn force relevant departments to come forward to &quot;solve&quot; the problem. There will inevitably be more and more phenomena, and a large amount of social resources are forced to invest in endless meaningless investigations. In itself, it is a huge internal friction for society. It was just an accident that Meng’s false accusation was finally revealed. Our tireless pursuit of social fairness and justice must not rely on the false accusations of online accusers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 22:25:17 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大账高企小账不绝  银保业务何以常年畸形？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259167]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As the channel business that contributes the largest premium to insurance companies, bancassurance is facing a new round of high pressure from regulations and new policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, Liu Sheng, the person in charge of the personal insurance supervision work of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, said that the regulatory authorities will consistently do a good job in the work of &quot;unifying reporting and banking&quot;; insist on catching up early and small , grasp the typical cases, continue to strictly supervise and strengthen accountability, rectify industry chaos, and effectively safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of insurance consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 22, the Personal Insurance Department of the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration issued the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products through Bank Agency Channels&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;) to all personal insurance companies, requiring all When filing products, insurance companies should clearly state the cost assumptions and fee structure in the product actuarial report, and list the commission ceiling; each insurance company should truthfully list the commission rates paid to the bank, and the actual fees such as commissions should be compared with the filing materials. Stay consistent, that is, &quot;unity of reward and action.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of the &quot;Notice&quot;, the Shanghai Insurance Association has issued an industry self-discipline convention. Following the Notice, insurance industry associations in Guangdong and other places also issued a self-discipline convention for bancassurance business. Self-regulatory conventions in various places target stubborn problems such as high fees and disorderly competition in bancassurance channels, and strictly prohibit vicious price competition, commercial bribery and other illegal activities that disrupt the order of the bancassurance market. We promise not to covertly increase bancassurance business fees through other channels and methods, and resolutely put an end to small accounts in bancassurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the pressure of supervision, it is imperative to reduce bank insurance fees. But why does the bancassurance business always suffer from the chronic industry problem of high large accounts and constant small accounts? It seems to be getting more and more popular as it becomes more banned. As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand any benefits other than those agreed in the agreement in any way from insurance companies and their personnel.&quot; Under this round of high pressure, will the chaos in the banking and insurance channels end? Will the bank insurance premium rate difference that plagues insurance companies turn into a fee difference from now on? How do bancassurance alliances develop internationally? What are some lessons worth learning from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center reviewed the development history of bancassurance at home and abroad, and used horizontal comparative research methods to find that the root cause of the &quot;big and small account problem&quot; lies in the profit distribution mechanism caused by the loose cooperation between insurance and banks. imbalance. Under this cooperation model, banks are driven by unilateral profits, and the overall business falls into a dilemma of incremental growth but no efficiency gain. Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center also visited different bank outlets as policyholders and conducted unannounced visits and found that the professionalism of bancassurance sales staff needs to be improved. Only when banks and bank employees transfer their focus on sales fees to professionalism will bank cooperation enter a new stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The stubborn problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank insurance refers to a business model in which banks mainly sell insurance on their behalf. Together with personal agents and group insurance, it constitutes the main sales channel of insurance companies. Bancassurance is the core business of life insurance companies and the leading business of many small and medium-sized companies. In order to compete for premiums,&amp;nbsp;many small and medium-sized insurance companies have always maintained high-priced large accounts and various forms of small accounts, and many large companies have been passively involved in price wars. This is what the industry calls &quot;big and small accounts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;big and small accounts&quot;? The &quot;big account&quot; refers to the handling fee agreed in the written contract between the insurance company and the bank, which is the bank&#39;s official income from the agency sales of insurance; the &quot;small account&quot; refers to the sales incentives privately given by the insurance company to bank staff, in various forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2019, when talking about strict management of violations of regulations and disciplines at an internal meeting, the president of a joint-stock bank said that the one thing he could not tolerate the most was employees receiving kickbacks from insurance companies. In fact, regulatory agencies have also cracked down on small accounting issues many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand from insurance companies and their personnel in any way other than what is agreed in the agreement.&quot; any benefit”. Over the past few years, rectification has continued, but no significant results have been achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Big accounts are high, small accounts are endless&quot; Why does it become a chronic disease? On the surface, the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is due to the strong position of banks and bancassurance cooperation due to their huge channels and strong customer resources. However, the root cause is that the interest distribution mechanism under the short-term and loose cooperation model between banks and insurance companies is insufficient. Reasonably caused. Banking and insurance are independent entities and there is no basis for equal cooperation between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reasons for the strong position of banks are complicated, but in the financial market structure dominated by banks, it does not necessarily lead to the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;. For example, in Europe, where the bancassurance business originated, in countries such as France and Italy, the bancassurance business not only accounts for a high proportion, but also makes a large contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is related to my country’s bancassurance cooperation model. Except for bank insurance companies and some giant insurance companies, the cooperation model between most banks and insurance companies is a &quot;many-to-many&quot; distribution agency model, that is, banks sign distribution agreements with insurance companies, and banks sell insurance through agency insurance companies. Products earn fees and commission income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this model, the determination of business philosophy, development of bancassurance products and insurance claims settlement are all undertaken by the insurance company, and both bancassurance and bancassurance parties only carry out superficial cooperation based on channel-level factors such as marketing channels and customer resources. cooperation. From the perspective of contract theory, it is essentially a simple principal-agent relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, outside the bank, the insurance company serves as the principal and the bank acts as the agent. The two define each other&#39;s rights, obligations and interest distribution methods by signing a cooperation agreement. The main incentive mechanism of the contract is that the bank earns handling fees from the bancassurance agency business, while the insurer transfers part of the benefits in exchange for rapid expansion of premium income, thus forming the first level of entrustment-agency between the bank and the insurance company. relation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within the bank, sales tasks are distributed layer by layer in the order of head office - branch branches - outlets, and the products are ultimately sold directly by bancassurance specialists at each outlet. According to the &quot;About Further Strengthening the Compliance of Commercial Banks&#39; Agency Insurance Business&quot; &quot;Notice on Sales and Risk Management&quot; stipulates that commercial banks shall not allow insurance company personnel to be stationed in bank branches. Therefore, relevant personnel of the insurance company can only supervise and assist bancassurance sales in the form of patrol points. A second principal-agent relationship is formed between the bank and its employees based on the sales of bancassurance products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the sales intensity of sinking channels determines the amount of premiums to a large extent. Moreover, because of the existence of a double principal-agent relationship, the two parties have conflicting goals. Specifically, banks tend to sell single payment or short-term regular payment insurance products with high commission rates, simple terms and simple benefit demonstrations. As for the compatibility between customers and products, agents are not particularly concerned. However, regular payment insurance with long payment period and comprehensive protection functions is the type of insurance that insurance companies hope to sell because of its high intrinsic value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, insurance companies compete fiercely for banking channels. The &quot;Measures for the Administration of Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; promulgated in 2019 (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;) stipulates that each branch of a commercial bank can only cooperate with no more than 3 insurance companies in the insurance agency business in the same fiscal year, that is, &quot;1+ 3&quot; mode. The quality and configuration of banks’ sinking channels have become the focus of competition among insurance companies. Therefore, the Measures have to a certain extent intensified competition among insurance companies for banks’ high-quality channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of serious product homogeneity, large accounts and small accounts have become an alternative competitive weapon. Liu Sheng commented that in recent years, the personal insurance industry has experienced severe homogeneous competition, and insurance companies generally have extensive expense management, resulting in actual expenses exceeding the level at the time of product filing, resulting in &quot;inconsistent reporting&quot;. High fees not only disrupt the market order, but are also the root cause of problems such as false fees, false insurance applications, and false surrenders. They are also the breeding ground for &quot;black agency products&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To what extent are bancassurance channel fees exaggerated? Liu Sheng revealed that as of October 20, the vast majority of banks carrying out bancassurance business have re-signed contracts with insurance companies in accordance with the requirements of &quot;unification of banks and banks&quot;. Preliminary estimates show that the commission rate for the bancassurance channel has dropped by about 30% compared with the previous average level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the results of the competition between &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the fragmentation of market share. According to statistics from Guolian Securities, judging from the scale of bancassurance channel premiums of personal insurance companies, the market share of the top ten companies in bancassurance channel premiums has dropped from 59.9% in 2017 to 52.1% in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Due to the intertwining of various reasons, the bancassurance channel has formed a status quo of &quot;high cost and low value&quot;. The bancassurance channel is also one of the channels where policyholders complain more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the intersection of history and reality, and is the product of the extensive development of the insurance industry in the past. In recent years, the insurance industry has received great attention in supporting economic and social development, and regulatory authorities have promoted deepening reforms in multiple key areas, including comprehensive system construction and core areas such as corporate governance, solvency, capital utilization, and consumer rights protection. The &quot;Notice&quot; releases a signal of reform, which will curb the industry&#39;s &quot;big and small accounts&quot; problem to a certain extent. However, whether the stubborn problem of &quot;big accounts, high prices, small accounts, and constant supply&quot; can be completely eradicated still depends on industry self-discipline, deepening cooperation between banks and insurance companies, and improving long-term incentive mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Change&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Window period&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why are the temporary management agencies stepping up their efforts to rectify the bancassurance business at this time? A researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that the insurance industry has undergone major changes under the new situation, and this is a window period for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the insurance industry is concerned, the agent team continues to shrink, and the growth rate of original premium income of the personal insurance industry is hovering at a low level. In 2022, the personal insurance industry will continue to be under pressure and enter a period of deep adjustment. That year, the original premium income of life insurance was 2.45 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 4%, accounting for 71.6% of personal insurance premiums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the public’s awareness of social security is gradually increasing The trend of aging and social aging still creates demand space for the development of the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of consumer behavior, insurance consumption has changed from &quot;should I buy it&quot; to &quot;is it good or not.&quot; The &quot;2022 China Internet Insurance Consumer Insight Report&quot; shows that consumers aged 31-40, mainly those born in the 1980s, spend more on insurance, and 75% of households spend more than 5,000 yuan on annual insurance. It can be seen that young consumers’ awareness of insurance and willingness to pay have increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an operational perspective, some small and medium-sized insurance companies have relatively aggressive product pricing strategies, and some products have risks of long-term insurance and short-term insurance. At the same time, in the context of declining long-term interest rates and declining corporate investment yields, incremental whole life insurance with the function of locking long-term interest rates will expose insurance companies to the risk of spread losses. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the life insurance version of “interest rate cuts” has been implemented. Supervision has clearly provided window guidance. Before the end of July 2023, the predetermined interest rates for new personal insurance products will be adjusted. After dealing with the interest rate loss in the short term, how to solve the fee difference loss has become increasingly urgent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of bancassurance channels is a key measure to alleviate fee differences. What conditions are met for channel purification at this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found through statistics and comparison that as of the end of 2022, the total number of agents of Ping An, China Life, China Pacific Insurance and New China Insurance was 1.59 million, down from 1.64 million in 2010 Thousands of people. The efficiency-improving reform of personal agency channels continues to show no significant results. At the same time, since 2020, major domestic listed insurance companies have been actively developing bancassurance channels, promoting the strategic transformation of &quot;new bancassurance&quot;, and have introduced a series of measures to strengthen the depth of cooperation with banks, hoping to achieve Growth in scale and value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Ping An Life as an example, financial report data shows that, From 2019 to 2022, the growth rate of new policy premiums in the bancassurance channel was as high as 19.1%, significantly ahead of the individual insurance channel and other channels. The premium growth rates of the two during the same period were -10.1% and -7.5% respectively. The proportion of the company&#39;s new premiums increased from 4.2% in 2019 to 9.2% in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This also shows that the agent channel that can best bring high intrinsic value policies to life insurance companies is still being adjusted. However, small and medium-sized insurance companies are basically unable to cultivate a large-scale agent team. In other words, the importance of the bancassurance channel has increased, highlighting the need for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks are also facing performance pressure. In a situation where interest spreads have shrunk, wealth management products have been depleted and trust products have become scarce, the agency insurance business has become a performance highlight. Take China Merchants Bank as an example. In 2022, China Merchants Bank&#39;s fund agency business revenue dropped by 46.4% year-on-year, and its proportion of non-interest income also dropped from the highest value of 13.0% in 2015 to 6.6%, while insurance agency sales revenue has remained at around 50% for two consecutive years. positive growth, and its proportion in non-interest income also increased significantly to 11.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;974&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the depth of both banks and insurance companies The window period for cooperation has arrived, and regulatory agencies and associations have the “right time, favorable location, and harmonious relationship” to crack down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that from the perspective of insurance companies’ profit models, among the “three differences”, death and fee differences account for relatively small proportions. The &quot;Notice&quot; aims to standardize sales expenses and prevent unfair competition. It is one of the important measures to standardize insurance sales behavior in a multi-dimensional and systematic manner. Following the &quot;Notice&quot;, the &quot;Insurance Sales Behavior Management Measures&quot; recently issued by the State Administration of Financial Supervision will be implemented from March 1, 2024. The &quot;Measures&quot; echo the &quot;Plan for the Construction of the Sales Ability Qualification Grading System for Insurance Sales Practitioners&quot; previously issued by the Insurance Industry Association, and aim to guide insurance companies to establish a product grading and channel grading system that matches customer needs. With the combined efforts of multiple measures, the results of this round of bancassurance channel rectification are worth looking forward to. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Overseas Bancassurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Close&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Type&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank Insurance It has existed abroad for more than 60 years. What can we learn from it? Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found out that there are two theories about the origin of bancassurance: one is Britain in the 1960s; the other is France in the 1970s. However, the development of bancassurance business in Britain and France is quite different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;New Bancassurance Era: The Beginning of Value&quot; released by Deloitte in 2023 shows that bancassurance channels in France, Italy and Spain account for 64%, 74% and 60% of all premiums respectively. %. Among Asian countries, South Korea accounts for 50%, Indonesia accounts for 48%, Singapore accounts for 30%, and India accounts for 25%. The UK bancassurance business has developed slowly and mainly relies on insurance broker channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the evolution of cooperation models in various countries, four bancassurance business cooperation models, namely agreement agency, strategic alliance, capital cooperation and financial group, have proven to be quite successful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1535&quot; height= &quot;3358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take France as an example. Banks enter the bancassurance field mainly by controlling insurance companies. Banks control insurance companies in two ways: establishing self-owned subsidiaries and acquiring other insurance companies, with the former being the main form. In terms of products, simplified and standardized life insurance or savings products are the main products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banking and insurance in Hong Kong, China also implement mixed operations, and large banks build their own insurance companies to achieve bancassurance synergy. The same is true for Taiwan, China. Bancassurance is mostly carried out in the form of a financial holding company. Its insurance product sales channels mainly include joint marketing through financial holding companies and strategic alliances, that is, business cooperation promotion through financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overseas experience shows that the development process of bancassurance is a process of banks and insurance companies jointly exploring consumer needs. It is a common choice for banks and insurance companies to choose the path of bancassurance cooperation and provide bancassurance products that meet the diverse needs of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development experience, the global bancassurance industry has experienced three stages: bancassurance, insurance banking and universal finance. They are essentially the cross-penetration, mutual integration, mutual complementation and common development of banks and insurance companies in many aspects such as product research and development, sales channels, organizational forms and business strategies, that is, the mixed operation of banks and insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the development models of bancassurance vary in different countries and regions. In other words, there is no universally applicable bancassurance development model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that my country’s bancassurance started relatively late but is developing rapidly. Data from the &quot;Insurance Yearbook&quot; show that in 2010, China&#39;s bancassurance channel premium income accounted for 50% of life insurance premium income, which was the highest in history. However, the cooperation between banks and insurance companies has always been based on the sales agreement model, and the cooperative relationship between banks and insurance companies is relatively loose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This model has obvious shortcomings. First, bancassurance cooperation is limited to the sales level, and there is a lack of motivation to jointly develop products; second, banks only act as agents for insurance products to obtain agency fees, and the cooperation between the two parties is short-term and unstable. Third, driven by short-term financial goals, both parties lacked enthusiasm in cultivating bancassurance professionals, resulting in low bancassurance service levels and frequent misleading sales problems. Therefore, my country’s banking and insurance cooperation model needs to be further deepened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Explore new ways of bancassurance cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to establish a healthy and win-win bancassurance ecosystem? The development experience of overseas banking and insurance shows that the financial legal environment and the form of organizational cooperation are crucial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the banking and insurance industries are under the unified supervision of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the regulatory coordination of the two industries will be smoother. At the same time, banks’ huge channels and strong customer resources are excellent channels for bancassurance to acquire customers. In addition, after years of market education, people generally have insurance awareness. Bank customers are naturally aware of financial management, and the question has changed from &quot;whether to buy&quot; to &quot;which product to buy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for insurance companies and banks, the customer acquisition cost advantage of the bancassurance channel will exist for a long time, and it will still be the main channel for insurance companies, especially small and medium-sized insurance companies, and it is not to be underestimated in banks’ collection business. field of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to build a new cooperation method for banks and insurance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that judging from overseas experience, the four models each have their own merits. At this stage, we can appropriately promote the development of in-depth bancassurance cooperation models. Those who have the conditions can try it at a higher level. my country&#39;s bancassurance development model has transformed from a sales agreement model to a strategic alliance model. In the future cooperation between bancassurance and insurance, the following points should be implemented: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. In terms of business philosophy, both bancassurance and bancassurance parties should completely transform the extensive operation that puts scale first, and truly shift from &quot;sales-centered&quot; to &quot;sales-centered&quot; Customer-centric&quot;. This will help both banks and insurance companies reach a consensus and shift to long-term business goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. In terms of cooperation methods, promote the transformation and upgrading of bancassurance cooperation. On the one hand, through strategic alliances between banks and insurance companies, &quot;capital integration&quot; and other methods, the constraint mechanism for the distribution of interests between banks and insurance companies will be reconstructed, and the &quot;discourse power&quot; of insurers in bank-insurance cooperation will be enhanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of laws and regulations, it is recommended to further optimize relevant laws and regulations. Objectively speaking, under the &quot;1+3&quot; model, the collaborative business relationship between banks and insurance is not stable, which increases the coordination costs between the two parties and exacerbates the inequality between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科技之手点燃梦想之火——访杭州亚残运会主火炬手徐佳玲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259159]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the lighting ceremony of the opening ceremony of the 4th Asian Para Games in Hangzhou on the evening of the 22nd, the last torch bearer , disabled swimmer Xu Jialing stepped onto the main torch stand and changed the torch &quot;laurel crown&quot; from her right hand to her left hand in front of everyone&#39;s attention - her smart bionic hand lit the main torch of this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, I only found out through the news that I was the last one.” Before the rehearsal of the opening ceremony, Xu Jialing had already worked with the intelligent bionics with the help of the research and development company Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. It took me a while to get my hands on it and I can control it pretty well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Some staff notified me before that I was the infield torchbearer for the opening ceremony, but I didn’t know which torchbearer I was.” Until I saw Sha Xiao, the chief director of the opening ceremony, in the news Lan revealed how to light the main torch, and Xu Jialing realized that she, who had been working with the intelligent bionic hand, would bear the final blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, I felt that I was very honored to be given such an important task.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1016&quot; height= &quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255023&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Beh In Chinese language, this is called &quot;control with thoughts.&quot; &quot;Actually, I am already used to life after amputation, but the smart bionic hand allows me to hold the torch with both hands and light the sacred flame. It is also very convenient in life. I can hold a water cup and twist the bottle cap.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smart bionic hand that looked very technological at the opening ceremony has actually undergone improvements in appearance design. &quot;At the beginning, we made a skin-colored version of the hand and socket for Xu Jialing. In order to make the overall visual presentation more technological, the team replaced her with a space gray hand and a carbon fiber socket. She also said she liked it very much. .&quot; revealed the intelligent bionic hand engineer team of Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My prosthesis is very cool!” Xu Jialing’s tone revealed happiness and pride. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;729&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255025&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Bei He&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, Xu Jialing’s cheerful and optimistic words often make people forget that the “cool” high-tech product we are discussing is being worn on her slightly defective left arm. superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2006, 4-year-old Xu Jialing was involved in a car accident and her left arm was no longer intact. Two years later, by chance, her mother discovered that Xu Jialing liked to play in the swimming pool, so she considered sending her to learn how to swim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教练认为徐佳玲可能是练游泳的料子，再加上当地残联的推荐，徐佳玲在家乡宁波训练了6年，顺利进入了浙江省残疾人游泳队，又随国家队出征2016年里约残奥会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1019&quot; height=&quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255027&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2016年9月15日，里约残奥会，徐佳玲（中）获女子100米蝶泳S9级冠军。新华社记者杨磊摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在里约，年仅14岁的徐佳玲作为当时中国代表团最年轻的参赛选手，斩获1金2铜，可谓“出道即巅峰”。此后，她又在2018年雅加达亚残运会揽下7金2银。尽管在之后的东京残奥会经历了低谷，但徐佳玲如今的心态已十分沉稳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在里约拿到金牌的时候，可能一路太顺风顺水，当时感觉站上领奖台也不是太难的事情，东京的时候一次都没能登上领奖台，还是会有失落，但是也是有所预料，因为那时候确实状态不太好。”徐佳玲说，“现在的心态更多的是好好训练，然后顺其自然。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅是开朗乐观，徐佳玲还常常在交谈中展现出超越年龄的成熟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在里约残奥会时，时年14岁的徐佳玲就在采访中说：“我觉得我的生活很精彩，一点不比身体健全的同龄人差。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1015&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;8月2日，在英国曼彻斯特举行的残疾人游泳世界锦标赛女子蝶泳100米S9级决赛中，中国选手徐佳玲以1分08秒34的成绩获得冠军。新华社发（乔恩·休珀摄）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7年过去，回望一路成长的历程，徐佳玲的青春确实可以用“精彩”来形容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了耀眼的比赛成绩，徐佳玲在有限的假期里也喜欢出去旅行，再加上随队在海外训练、比赛，让她在世界各地都留下了宝贵的回忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐佳玲目前还是北京体育大学“冠军班”的一名学生，她的专业是运动训练学。 “能重回学校还是蛮开心的。”过去近十年大部分时间都在进行游泳训练的徐佳玲说，“在大学读书既能学到知识，又可以更加了解自己从事的专业，我觉得这样的机会很好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10月22日，最后一棒火炬手徐佳玲在开幕式上点燃主火炬。新华社记者伍志尊摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，徐佳玲又成了亚残运会主火炬手，借助科技的力量，在万众瞩目中点燃主火炬，也照亮了自己的青春。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着科技的发展，越来越多像智能仿生手这样的设备、装备帮助残障人士弥补了身体的缺憾，点燃了逐梦的信念。但在徐佳玲看来，“平等”二字，对于残障群体来讲，或许与科技的辅助同样重要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我个人觉得，不希望大家用一种怜悯的、想落泪的心态去看待我们。我们能够站在亚残运会的赛场上，和任何运动员都一样，是努力训练的结果。可能我们训练是会比较辛苦，一开始会比较艰难，但我们还是希望大家能用平常心来对待我们。”徐佳玲说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网传“前台实名制”将落地：能有效改善网络空间的现实生态吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259112]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，网传“前台实名制”即将落地，引发关切与讨论。“来去之间”（新浪微博CEO王高飞）转引了一条媒体评论《“前台实名制”，大V早该卸马甲了》，显示传言非虚，又在一条回复中表示：前台实名针对的是100万粉丝的自媒体账号，未来最多降到50万粉丝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，中央网信办发布《关于加强“自媒体”管理的通知》，凡13条，其中有要求“规范账号运营行为”：网站平台应当严格执行“一人一号、一企两号”账号注册数量规定，严禁个人或企业操纵“自媒体”账号矩阵发布传播违法和不良信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前网络平台实行的是“后台实名制”，前台实名化名自行决定。真在网络上作奸犯科，也不可能逍遥法外，警察很快就能找到本人。因为注册用的电话号码本身就是实名的；上网者的IP地址后台都有记录。不过，哪怕后台实名，只要本人不主动暴露自己的信息，网络账号的匿名性还是挺强的，线上道德约束也远远不如线下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，对一些人来说，要维护大号已建立的安静美男子/娴静淑女之类的人设，或大号有暴露私人信息，另建小号就是了，去说一些大号不会说的话。这样，一个人的人格可以一分为三：线下是一种，在周围同事、家人眼里的正常人；大号是一种，一个拥有理想人设的形象；小号是另一种，各种阴暗、龌龊毕现。自我、超我与本我无缝切换。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;匿名性更大的问题在于：某些自媒体，为了制造话题与流量，完全没有底线，用各种对立进行动员，搞“团建”，刷评论、刷热搜，以小博大，有组织地制造巨大的声量，以制造舆论、影响立法与司法进程；党同伐异，有组织地对不同意其作为与价值观的个人与机构进行超饱和攻击与滋扰、实施威胁，这已经成了公害，不断消解社会赖以生存的共识与价值观，极大地恶化了公共空间的生态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么让有100万甚至50万粉丝的自媒体账号前台实名，能解决这些问题吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们不妨做一个模型分析，有一群人，每人都有一个投票权。那匿名投票与实名投票哪个更好，使每个人能表达自己的真实看法，并令结果更公正？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人认为匿名投票好：这样每个人可以没有压力地表达自己的真实看法。但匿名的缺点也是明显的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，某些人可能被收买、可能被私下请托，因为最终结果是匿名的，除了互相勾兑的人之外，别人无从知道他怎么投票、对他无从产生道德压力，这种情况下，他投出的票恐怕不能称之为“表达自己的真实想法”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，另一些人哪怕没有被收买、没有接受私下请托，他的投票倾向也未必就公正，如因为有私人恩怨就是不想让别人过。又或者纯粹因为“囚徒困境”：无论你投票支持还是反对我的心水对象，我一律投票反对，至少是不亏的，这样，一概反对就成了优势策略。有相当部分人这样想，就可以显著扭曲整体投票结果。这些投票人固然是“表达了自己的真实想法”，但与公正沾不上边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，也不排除有一些人天性纯良，在任何情况下都不会被收买或接受私下请托，并且在投票过程中放下私人恩怨，也不屑于进行精致利益算计，会根据候选对象本身的优劣客观地进行判断，这样的人有，但想必是少的。另外，也不排斥前述两类人在某些情况下也会公正投票，如候选对象实在太优异/糟糕，硬要投反对票/支持票实在对不住自己的良心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有人认为实名投票好，可以有效减少匿名投票上述两种不公正的情形，每个人的投票结果都会被其他人看到，从而让投人情票、投私人恩怨票与投精致算计票的行为暴露在众目睽睽之下，就会显著约束这类行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是实名投票也不是全无问题。一是某些心性比较弱的人怕得罪人，在实名投票时不敢通过投票真实表达自己的意愿，投出公正的一票；二是实名投票会让派系的分化从模糊走向清晰，而不同的派系或抱团形成之后，冲突会明显化，并且可能加剧。这两点也是实施匿名投票的主要理由：让大家无压力地投票，从而限制冲突的烈度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综上，是匿名投票还是实名投票，最终还是要看所涉机构更偏好哪些价值，需要迫切解决哪些问题。如何把这个模型分析应用到前台实名制该不该实行及实行范围上？如果要解决有组织的制造舆论及有组织地对个人与机构进行超限攻击与滋扰这两个问题，那无疑应该推行前台实名制，让这些自媒体有组织的阴暗行为暴露在众人面前，接受道德阳光的炙烤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，如果仅仅是100万粉丝乃至50万粉丝的自媒体账号才需要前台实名，恐怕也不足以遏制自媒体有组织的阴暗行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，有一个前台实名到什么程度的问题。实名实控人还是运营的小编？让没有决策权的人员去顶缸、去应付前台实名，怎么破？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，现在有组织的制造舆论以及有组织的超限攻击与滋扰，已经高度进化了。几十万或几百万粉丝的主账号先不动，让一些外围或粉丝通过小号发出恶意信息或动员信息，然后策动或耐心等待一些粉丝较少的账号进行转发，在层层转发之外，主账号再跟进转发，这样就把主账号的风险最小化。这种“戴多层套子”的方法，对部分粉丝多的自媒体账号前台实名制是很难破的，因为小号与粉丝较少的账号仍可自行其是。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访广东省卫健委：基层诊疗“不仅要有大楼，还要有人才”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259151]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/9c64b58a94.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/9c64b58a94.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广东省河源市紫金县蓝塘镇中心卫生院，医院门诊楼大厅内摆放着卫生首席专家的宣传易拉宝。（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;让优质医疗资源下沉,让群众在家门口看名医，备受各级政府关注。2023年政府工作报告提到“推动优质医疗资源扩容下沉和区域均衡布局”，2023年广东省政府工作报告中也提出“深入实施新一轮基层医疗卫生服务能力提升计划，有效增加农村和欠发达地区医疗资源”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;提升基层医疗卫生服务能力，最重要的是补齐人才短板。2023年3月，中共中央办公厅、国务院办公厅印发的《关于进一步完善医疗卫生服务体系的意见》中强调，加大基层、边远地区和紧缺专业人才培养扶持力度，缩小城乡、地区、专业之间人才配置差距。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为打通服务群众健康的“最后一公里”，提供更为便捷、优质、高效的卫生健康服务，广东推出“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”。该计划通过面向全国选聘100名具有高级职称且符合岗位条件的退休医生，在广东省内47家升级建设的中心卫生院担任首席专家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;就广东省基层诊疗体系建设、“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”新一轮实施情况，南方周末记者专访了广东省卫健委。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“扶上马，送一程”，加快形成服务能力&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;广东是全国经济总量第一大省，但发展不平衡是广东高质量发展的最大短板，这也体现在基层卫生健康体系上。近几年，广东投入大量资金全面开展基层医疗卫生服务能力建设，目前进展如何？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;从2017年开始，广东投入500亿元，从设施、设备、人才等方面全面开展基层医疗卫生服务能力建设，夯实基层基础。并把升级建设47家中心卫生院作为强基层的“头号工程”，计划“三年建成、五年形成服务能力”。到2020年底，47家中心卫生院圆满完成“三年建成”目标任务，基层医疗卫生机构面貌焕然一新，具有广东特色的基层卫生健康服务之路逐步形成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“三年建成”只是阶段性任务的完成，是新的起点。在接下来时间，继续完成“五年形成服务能力”，达到中等水平县级医院能力，为当地人民群众提供更优质的基本医疗和基本公卫服务才是最终目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;硬件设施是基础，基层诊疗要“形成服务能力”，人才非常关键，广东是如何破解基层诊疗人才队伍建设困局的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;硬件设施完善后，如果相关配套制度仍固守成规、不及时进行调整，很可能出现“只有大楼、没有人才”“开局良好、后劲不足”的局面，背离省委、省政府下大力气织密筑牢基层医疗保障网的初衷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为此，省卫生健康委出台相应扶持政策，对基层医疗卫生机构“扶上马，送一程”，推动其加快形成服务能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;基层卫生健康人才是基层卫生资源的主体，是基本医疗卫生服务的提供者，基层卫生健康人才队伍建设对于改善基层医疗服务能力和质量具有重要意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我们在加强基层卫生人才队伍建设三年行动计划（2018-2020年）基础上，又出台了《广东省基层卫生人才队伍增量提质实施方案》《广东省三级甲等公立医院与县级公立医院开展医疗卫生“组团式”紧密型帮扶行动方案》《广东省百名卫生首席专家下基层计划实施方案》等，多措并举全力加强基层医疗卫生人才队伍建设，推进医生培养与使用激励机制改革，有效提升了省域基层卫生人才的专业服务能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;门诊量逐年提升，居民认知度高&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”已启动实施，首席专家是如何选出来的？有哪些特点？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”是根据基层实际需要，通过面向全国选聘100名具有高级职称且符合岗位条件的退休医生，在省内47家升级建设的中心卫生院担任首席专家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;首席专家获聘后担任所在单位的学科带头人，主要负责指导提升医务人员在常见病、多发病的诊疗，预防保健、康复与慢性病管理、专科疾病危重情况应急处理等方面的能力水平，做到“三个一”——建设1个特色专科，开展1项以上新业务、新技术，“传、帮、带”打造1个专科团队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;省财政给予每人每年20万元补助，每3年为一周期。2018年12月正式启动第一轮项目，吸引了来自全国各地的五百多名医疗卫生领域专家踊跃报名，经过优中选优，最终确定了100名第一批首席专家名单。这100名首席专家中，平均年龄62岁，共计具有22类临床学科专业背景，广东省内外退休专家比例大致为3∶2。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;刚刚提到“三个一”，第一轮计划目前已经结束，取得了哪些成效？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;首席专家协助中心卫生院开展专科建设，帮助中心卫生院建立及完善相关专科，同时，通过培训、指导基层医务人员等方式，为所在中心卫生院带教一批医务人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;统计结果显示，有65.2%的中心卫生院在首席专家的帮助下建立了包括妇产科、中医科、儿科、普外科、消化内科等特色专科，其中建立了2个以上特色专科的中心卫生院占39.1%；超过半数的首席专家开展了1项及以上的新技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;就基层卫生健康人才队伍来说，首席专家为医院带来了什么改变？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;首席专家充分发挥传帮带的作用，对基层医疗人员进行系统化的技术培训，使他们能够掌握先进的医疗技术和方法，提高专业水平和服务能力。同时，指导所在医院制定标准化操作流程、优化服务流程，提高诊断和治疗的效率和质量，不断提升基层医疗机构服务能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;广东省47家中心卫生院在三年间年平均门诊量从11.4万人次增加到14.9万人次，年均增长率为9.3%。受新冠疫情影响，与2019年相比，2020年广东省基层医疗机构总诊疗人次减少20.2%，而参与该项目的47家中心卫生院平均门诊量仅下降1.5%，充分说明参与项目的中心卫生院提供的医疗服务获得了当地居民的充分认可。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;比如，河源市紫金县蓝塘中心卫生院是项目实施单位之一，在当地卫生健康行政部门的支持下，中心卫生院选聘了普外科、骨外科2名退休医生担任首席专家。在首席专家的带领下，该院普外科建立了腔镜微创中心，骨外科开展了股骨头置换、髋关节置换等三、四级手术，有效提升了医院服务能力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;首席专家还主动邀请熟识的教授学者来院开展学术讲座和交流活动，提供了掌握学科发展前景、前沿理论、先进技术及专业经验的机会，促进提升基层诊疗水平的同时，该中心卫生院的门诊量也获得显著增长。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;省卫健委是否做过相关调查，比如计划实施医院所在地区居民的满意度如何？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;我们对基层就诊患者的调查显示，居民就医获得感得分88.9，75.9%的受访者表示清楚知晓本地中心卫生院开设了首席专家诊疗服务，92.8%的患者表示更愿意接受首席专家的诊疗。调查结果表明参与项目的卫生院为患者提供了较好的医疗卫生服务，在群众中有较高的认知度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a66f76cb29.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a66f76cb29.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广东省梅州市丰顺县留隍镇中心卫生院内，正在急诊科就诊的患者。（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;建立考核体系，开展专科建设等为考核重点&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相比过去，新一轮“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”有何不同？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;第一，结合当地实际，精准设置岗位。新一轮“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”，积极吸收前一轮的工作经验，不断调整完善实施方案，针对岗位设置，由各中心卫生院综合考虑本单位急需紧缺专业、基础薄弱科室、带教团队设置等实际情况，提出本单位首席专家岗位专业需求，实施按需定岗、按需聘用，推动各地精准匹配、人岗相适。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;第二，开发完善项目管理系统，以信息化助力项目实施。着眼于信息化助力，开发项目管理系统，通过采取信息化管理模式，实现了岗位设置、人员报名、资格审核、面试公示、协议签订、人员退出、补助计算等全流程一体化操作。目前，管理系统使用效果基本达到预期，项目管理高效化、信息电子化、沟通网络化的成效初步展现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;第三，加强沟通协调，建立良好交流机制。为便于项目高效推进，组建了工作交流群，对工作中遇到的问题第一时间进行解答。在报名和资格审查阶段，充分发挥统筹协调和磋商作用，针对具体岗位，积极与专家、相关卫生院沟通协调，了解专家的具体情况，详细介绍岗位信息，为专家和卫生院双向选择提供更加精准的匹配。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;新一轮“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”专家聘请进展情况怎么样？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;据统计，46家中心卫生院（高州市第二人民医院已于2021年合并至高州市中医院，数量由47家变为46家）100个岗位共设置23个专业类别，共收到186人的报名信息。经审核，144人进入面试环节，最终100个岗位全部完成人员录取工作，录取率为100％。其中，本科以上学历占比73%，正高级职称占比48%，17人为第一轮上岗专家。7月1日，首席专家已到岗开展工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;聘请专家是双向选择的过程，将从哪些方面考核首席专家？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;为更好考核专家工作效果，在项目开展之初我们就做好了基线调查，全面掌握专家所在医院和科室的医疗服务质量情况，为下一步科学评价专家履职效果和项目总体成效提供决策依据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;同时，建立项目绩效评价参考指标体系和标准，将首席专家协助开展专科建设、带教医务人员以及拓展新业务作为考核重点，考核就诊患者和聘用单位对首席专家的满意度，推动科学、规范开展考核。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;新一轮“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”也将持续三年，卫健委将如何确保计划满足预期？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;广东省卫健委：&lt;/strong>;我们将加强督促指导，指导各地各单位按照实施方案等要求，落实各项任务和要求，做好专家日常管理和服务工作，选取部分中心卫生院开展“四不两直”（不发通知、不打招呼、不听汇报、不用陪同接待，直奔基层、直插现场）实地调研，了解首席专家工作情况。同时，指导各单位做好专家年度考核工作，并依此落实专家保障待遇，对优秀的首席专家，做好宣传工作，营造良好的工作氛围。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;通过实施“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”项目，既满足了群众对医疗资源的需求，又满足了基层医生对适宜医疗技术学习的需求，切实为基层群众提供了更为便捷、优质、高效的卫生健康服务，打通了服务群众健康的“最后一公里”，让基层群众在家门口就能享受到高质量的医疗服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层：三年会带来什么改变？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259149]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层：“最希望留下技术”，乡镇也能看大病]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259147]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/3408881631.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/3408881631.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广东省云浮市郁南县连滩镇中心卫生院，中医首席专家黎均铭在给患者做康复训练。（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘建祖刚填好卫生首席专家的志愿，广东省云浮市郁南县连滩镇中心卫生院（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;下称连滩卫生院&lt;/span>;）的电话就打了过来。一直在临床一线、刚退休，在连滩卫生院党委书记姚嘉新看来，刘建祖简直是不二人选，“年龄太大的我们要斟酌下，刚刚退休的最好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;61岁的刘建祖刚退休一年，之前在供职医院担任普外科主任，经同事介绍，得知了广东省百名卫生首席专家下基层项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;与姚嘉新一同“相中”刘建祖的，还有另一家中心卫生医院。不过，当该家医院院长打电话“挖人”的时候，刘建祖已经坐在连滩卫生院办公室里与姚嘉新喝茶了。“电话来迟了几分钟，我刚答应这边，反悔了不好做人。”刘建祖对南方周末记者回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;被“抢”的还有来自全国其它地区的退休名医。为打通服务群众健康的“最后一公里”，提供更为便捷、优质、高效的卫生健康服务，2018年，广东推出“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”，面向全国选聘100名退休医生担任中心卫生院的首席专家，此举在全国尚属首次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年2月，广东省卫生健康委印发《广东省百名卫生首席专家下基层计划实施方案（2023—2025年）》（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;下称《实施方案》&lt;/span>;），启动实施新一轮计划。2023年广东省政府工作报告也提出“深入实施新一轮基层医疗卫生服务能力提升计划，有效增加农村和欠发达地区医疗资源”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不同于三甲医院组团式帮扶，卫生首席专家将直接深入到广东省47家中心卫生院全职工作，开展“三个一”——建设1个特色专科，开展1项以上新业务、新技术，传帮带打造1个专科团队，缓解基层医疗卫生机构人才数量不足、服务能力不强等矛盾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;生活在粤北乡村广东河源凤安镇的一名14岁留守儿童已成为上述项目的受益者之一。他患有扁平足，因为脚疾、交通不便，很难前往80公里之外的惠州大医院就医，直到卫生首席专家来到离家7公里的河源市紫金县蓝塘镇中心卫生院（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;下称蓝塘卫生院&lt;/span>;）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“手术很成功，像他这种情况在外面地方反复治疗效果也未必好，现在既就近治疗，也解决问题。”主刀医生、中山大学附属第八医院退休骨科专家陈庠仑对南方周末记者说。陈庠仑是蓝塘卫生院选聘的骨科首席专家。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不仅看真本事，还得会讲普通话&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;被47家基层卫生院相中是第一步，但想拿到卫生首席专家的聘书，还要经过面试。《实施方案》规定，面试时，应邀请地级市三甲医院相关专家对申报人的专业技术水平进行评估，同时充分考虑本地区语言文化、饮食习惯、风土民俗等实际情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;常见的技术问题包括：一个手术如何操作，某种疾病有何治疗方案，带外科团队1-2年怎么带等等。面试之后，专家组再向医院提供相应建议。不同医院亦有选人侧重点，例如蓝塘卫生院、留隍卫生院等就格外关注外科专家腹腔镜、微创的手术能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除了医疗技术，语言、家庭等也是关注重点，“不要求会说当地语言，但普通话要过得去”。相比第一轮卫生首席专家下基层计划，新一轮计划吸引到的广东省外专家数量增长不少，而广东有粤语、潮汕话、客家话等。梅州市丰顺县留隍镇中心卫生院（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;下称留隍卫生院&lt;/span>;）面试的一位外科专家，技术好、人也好，唯独口音太重，讲的普通话连专家都很难听懂，只能作罢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;医生讲求实践，面试并不能让院长们完全放心。“招专家不是招大学生，到了这个年纪，会就会，不会就是不会。”惠州市博罗县杨村镇中心卫生院（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;下称杨村卫生院&lt;/span>;）院长吴开锋对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在签聘任协议前，不少卫生院都希望先见见专家的真本事。蓝塘卫生院院长陈伟高专门请外科首席专家胡玉辉做了两台手术，请专业人士跟他探讨输尿管结石等常见三、四级手术的要点，层层把关后，他才放心聘请。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;破解“医院有设备，但没人会用”困局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;基层卫生院聘请外科专家时执著于腔镜和微创技术，在于“医院有设备，但没人会用”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蓝塘卫生院扩建时引入的设备，会使用的人并不多。“在我们这里，不会用腹腔镜的医生就是普通医生，会用腹腔镜的就是高端医生。”院长陈伟高向南方周末记者直言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;希望聘请医院紧缺领域的专家，这是诸多中心卫生院的共同愿望。比如连滩卫生院骨科、神经外科之前有云浮、肇庆的帮扶专家，但一直缺少普外科专家，虽与三甲医院签约帮扶解了燃眉之急，但每周坐诊两三天依旧不能满足基层群众的需要，所以这次专门聘请普外科专家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;广东省卫健委告诉南方周末记者，硬件设施完善后，如果相关配套制度仍固守成规、不及时进行调整，很可能出现“只有大楼、没有人才”“开局良好、后劲不足”的局面。2023年7月，外科首席专家丁胜文刚来杨村卫生院就做了十几台腹腔镜手术，以后当地村民就不用到外地去做腹腔镜手术了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“没有完善的师资队伍，这是我们基层最大的困惑。”连滩卫生院党委书记姚嘉新对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在原单位南部战区空军医院，骨科首席专家卢书文做手术是团队作战，一台手术他只需要做其中最关键的部分。刚到杨村卫生院做首席专家时，一台手术从消毒、铺单开始，他都亲力亲为，将大医院的管理规范教给杨村卫生院的基层医生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;首席专家的到来，可以帮助基层医院不断提高规范化水平。杨村卫生院院长吴开锋感叹，首席专家展现了他所在的上一级医院的管理水平，在专家来到卫生院这一段时间里，整个科室的面貌都发生了很大变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另外，在首席专家的建议下，基层医院也根据诊疗需要补充相关药品，更好满足患者需要。老年病学主任医师闫新政来到留隍卫生院后发现缺少一些药物，随即在院长的支持下，医院补充了20余种药品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/f41522b8f2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/f41522b8f2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广东省梅州市丰顺县留隍镇中心卫生院是广东省内升级建设的47家中心卫生院之一，新落成的院区建筑面积25771平方米，按编制床位250张建设配套。（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“用心用情，让专家认同医院文化”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和退休名医过去供职医院相比，新的工作环境确实有较大差距，而且离开家人到不熟悉的地方，难免会有些不适应。如何留人这一问题就摆在了很多卫生院面前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;基层卫生院能为首席专家提供的薪酬并不高，但大家想方设法在用心用情上下功夫。如提供合口味的饮食、干净舒适的居住环境，也有卫生院做得更细致——夏天太阳晒，为专家保留单独的室内停车场，安排专人帮助专家熟悉信息管理系统等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;留人先留胃，留隍卫生院没有食堂，特地为专家请了厨师做饭，既有本地菜，也有专家的家乡菜。下班后，医院的同事也会邀请专家到家中吃饭，让他们感受到员工的尊重和家庭的氛围。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于很多首席专家来说，院长是不是“干事的人”，是选择来该院的重要原因之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨村卫生院院长吴开锋认为，留住专家要先知道对方所求，外科专家的心愿是继续自己的手艺，将技术传承下去。所以，医院就将外科团队交给外科首席专家丁胜文带，让他觉得工作有意义，带起一个学科有成就感。“要让专家对医院有文化认同，就要营造出学科发展好、职工发展好、为患者着想的文化氛围。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据南方周末记者了解，不少退休专家放弃了远高于20万的薪资，来到广东一些卫生院应聘首席专家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;留隍卫生院外科首席专家张凤云刚退休时去了北京一家新建的社区医院，待遇好但医院迟迟不开张，清闲反而让她担心“作为外科医生，再这么闲着就浪费了”，看到广东招聘消息，就填了报名表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;之前在四川工作的张凤云感叹“客家话比英语还难”，为了克服语言关，留隍卫生院配了一名本地医生作翻译，与张凤云一起看诊、查房，做好翻译的同时也学习知识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蓝塘卫生院选聘的一位会微创、会腔镜还懂管理的专家，因个人原因要推迟到医院工作时间，陈伟高生怕有变故，和副院长、医院办公室轮流给专家打电话，直到将执业变更到蓝塘卫生院，敲定入职时间，才稍微放心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”服务期限三年，医院可结合实际与专家1年1签或一次性签订3年协议。医院各有考量，例如，留隍卫生院选择1年1签，给双方留有余地，“不要捆死大家”；而蓝塘卫生院，为能留住专家，直接签署了三年期合同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;广东省卫健委告诉南方周末记者，新一轮“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”中，共有186人提交报名信息，经审核，144人进入面试环节，最终100个岗位全部完成人员录取工作，录取率为100％。2023年7月1日，首席专家已到岗开展工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/97d2c32be2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/97d2c32be2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广东省云浮市郁南县连滩镇中心卫生院内排队取药的患者。（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;从3分钟到20分钟，用服务留住患者&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;即便是专家，要马上取得患者的信任也并不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中医首席专家黎均铭来到连滩卫生院第一天，门诊只看了三四位患者，其中还包含慕名而来的医院职工。而他在原来供职的医院，半天就能看三十多位患者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在基层，患者一般年龄偏大、就诊意识相对薄弱，感到身体不舒服去就诊时往往已经错过最佳治疗时间。“患者肚子痛得厉害，一看晚期了，别人看到这病医院治不好，以后更不会来了。”丁胜文告诉南方周末记者，他经常遇到肠癌晚期、梗阻、穿孔的手术，早中期疾病反而少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这也间接影响了患者对基层医院的信任。张凤云曾遇到一位患者，不相信留隍卫生院的麻醉能力，要求转院到梅州市医院手术，最后采用的也是相同方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在姚嘉新看来，中心卫生院最大的优势就是服务。他希望自己医院的医生都能有很好的服务态度，尤其在乡镇这样的熟人社会中，30万人口耳相传，贴心服务产生的社会效益不容小觑。技术反而其次，只要患者留下来了，医生可以请教专家，也可以邀请专家过来做手术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;大医院患者多，就诊时间自然就少，闫新政发现在自己原单位一位患者的就诊时间只有3分钟左右，但在留隍卫生院，在一位患者身上能花费15-20分钟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尤其患者如果是基础疾病叠加的老年人，一次看诊就要解决不少历史遗留问题，而且很多农村老年人其实对自身疾病并不清楚，健康意识差，需要医生多问几句，张凤云有次问一位患者是否有高血压，对方说没有，但是一测，血压特别高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前，每家中心卫生院的辐射人口在30-50万，“如果周边人可以直接到中心卫生院看病，不跑去云浮、惠州，车费都能省下两三百。”陈伟高说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据陈伟高初步统计，引入专家之后，蓝塘卫生院门诊量、住院量、手术量增长30%以上。而留隍卫生院2023年7、8月平均门诊量6000例，比1-6月平均门诊量增加近1300例，相比2022年同期增加50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c130c1b752.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c130c1b752.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广东省梅州市丰顺县留隍镇中心卫生院聘请的首席专家闫新政、柳江带领医院年轻医生查房，询问患者康复情况。（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“希望专家把技术留给我们，这是吃饭的本钱”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“医院还没有开展过骨科，你来到这里能不能顺利工作？”蓝塘卫生院选聘的骨科首席专家陈庠仑刚来到医院时，院长还有些犹豫。“骨科病人占外科病人40%以上，正是因为没开展，所以市场很大、前途很广。”陈庠仑很有信心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最开始的骨科器具甚至是陈庠仑自己带来的，之后才陆续采购了其他器械。事实证明了陈庠仑的判断，骨科建立起来后，从没缺过病人，其他医生遇到骨科相关疾病的患者也转给陈庠仑，之前漏诊、转诊的患者就留在了医院，转诊率从过去的100%下降到30%-40%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这正是“百名卫生首席专家下基层计划”最希望看到的——建设1个特色专科，开展1项以上新业务、新技术，“传、帮、带”打造1个专科团队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;广州医科大学教授陈建平是首批下基层专家之一。退休后，他在连滩卫生院“二次创业”建了一个康复科。刚到岗时，医院缺少设备，只能拿出30万让陈建平选购耗材，他自己动手制作简易的康复耗材。如今，连滩卫生院康复科能够开展中医药康复适宜技术6类58项，年康复治疗人次从2017年约1万人发展至2022年4万人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我们最希望专家把他的技术留给我们，这是吃饭的本钱。”相比看门诊，留隍卫生院书记叶壁镇告诉南方周末记者，医院归根到底还是想得到专家的技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;广东省卫健委的统计结果显示，在首批计划之后，有65.2%的中心卫生院在首席专家的帮助下建立了包括妇产科、中医科、儿科、普外科、消化内科等特色专科。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蓝塘卫生院聘请的心血管内科专家曾中博之前在惠州市第一人民医院执业，距离蓝塘卫生院只有一个多小时车程，医院看中其患者基础好，镇上也有不少居民专程到惠州找他看病。希望他能指导高血压、糖尿病的管理，带来新的技术和治疗手段，将来增设一个心血管疾病特色专科。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张凤云向南方周末记者描绘了自己的构想：第一年前三个月让医生熟悉操作乳腺手术，之后三个月可以上手简单的缝合，再经过半年进修，争取逐渐将乳腺科从外科中分离出来，只有专业化，患者才会信任。“乳腺科耗资少，没有复杂的设备要求，很适合作为一个新设的专科。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;医生是一个永远学习的职业。闫新政发现，基层医生通常在看诊中积累经验，缺少系统的理论培训，他计划将农村的常见疾病，例如高血压、糖尿病等，做成几期30分钟左右的小课，培训年轻医生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丁胜文则希望慢慢将大医院的工作作风移植到杨村卫生院，他要求医生每周有一天提前半小时到医院，并带来了原单位的培训资料，给医生讲课，“年轻人手术视频剪辑、查资料都会，但是需要推一把，形成习惯”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259078]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;广东百位退休名医下基层，近半数正高级职称。妙手仁心，打通诊疗“最后一公里”。</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[揭秘杭州亚残运会开幕式背后的“大脑总动员”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259161]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“桂花开了，来吧，来杭州吧！”秋夜的钱塘江畔，杭州奥体中心体育场变成一方金桂花盛开的舞台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22日晚举行的杭州第4届亚洲残疾人运动会开幕式上，最后一棒火炬手用通过大脑操控的智能仿生手高擎火炬“桂冠”向全场观众致意，随后点燃主火炬。当科技与梦想相逢，所有不可能将变为可能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/77778ecca21227f5f10525d7e580640c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/77778ecca21227f5f10525d7e580640c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255028&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10月22日，最后一棒火炬手徐佳玲在开幕式上点燃主火炬。新华社记者伍志尊摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚残运会开幕式延续了亚运会开闭幕式的文化自信、科技温暖和动人情感，展现“阳光、和谐、自强、共享”的精神。“亚残运会开幕式点燃主火炬的方式是科技和温度相结合的。”杭州亚残运会开幕式总导演沙晓岚在“剧透”时说，科技弥补了身体的缺憾，更夯实了逐梦的信念，赋予了运动员炫奇的未来感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扑面而来的炫奇未来感背后，是一场基于脑机接口技术的“大脑总动员”。“大脑想做什么动作，仿生手就执行什么动作。”坐在位于杭州城西人工智能小镇的办公室里，浙江强脑科技有限公司创始人韩璧丞缓缓道出智能仿生手背后的奥秘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位长期沉浸于探索人类大脑奥秘的“85后”哈佛大学博士解释，此类融合非侵入式脑机接口技术与人工智能算法的康复辅具，通过采集、处理人体运动产生的肌电、神经电信号辨识使用者的运动意图，模拟人手仿生神经肌肉控制通路，从而实现动作控制，满足人们生活中常用手势需要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4ff22a3516fc62ed0c7a12617573cac8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;992&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4ff22a3516fc62ed0c7a12617573cac8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255030&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10月22日，最后一棒火炬手徐佳玲在开幕式上。新华社记者黄宗治摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研发智能仿生手需要解决的核心技术问题是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“数据采集。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩璧丞坦言，人类大脑被称为“三磅宇宙”，包含约1000亿个神经元，生物电信号非常微弱。这使得隔着皮肤了解人体内部情况存在信息衰减、噪声混叠问题，捕捉收集存在困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩璧丞说，这就像在杭州努力采集北京首都国际机场里一只蚊子扇动翅膀的声音并分析它的飞行情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2015年哈佛大学实验室中十几个人的挑灯攻关，到如今在杭州、深圳、波士顿设立办公室研究脑机接口技术的科技企业，韩璧丞一直带领他的团队走在科技创新和应用拓展的道路上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5c8f2d48399a74a6ecd29ef36d739842.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;1020&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5c8f2d48399a74a6ecd29ef36d739842.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255029&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10月22日，最后一棒火炬手徐佳玲在开幕式上。新华社记者江汉摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，杭州亚残运会开幕式并不是智能假肢第一次出现在公众视野。北京冬残奥会上，残疾人游泳运动员贾红光正是佩戴智能仿生手完成火炬传递。前不久的千岛湖畔，本届亚残运会火炬手、射箭运动员叶金燕依靠一条深空灰色涂装的智能仿生腿完成火炬传递。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着探索“三磅宇宙”的深入，我们距离主流科幻片中呈现的世界还有多远？韩璧丞回应称，主流科幻片中的效果70%至80%都能凭借脑机接口实现，相信在不远的未来，“意随心动”可以“触手可及”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩璧丞办公桌对面的墙上，挂着一幅爱因斯坦的画像，画中的“最强大脑”露出神秘的微笑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[豪宅152处，公司数十家，“奢侈品巨量” 谁在新加坡“洗”148亿元？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259123]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;平日爱炫富、出行高调的苏海金终于玩“出圈了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年8月15日早上，听到大儿子的呼唤声后，苏海金从二楼阳台跳下，栽在了别墅后院。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;八名新加坡执法人员在别墅后排水沟旁发现了他。在新加坡警方公布的照片中，苏海金当时只穿了短袖短裤、光着脚。腿还摔骨折了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;祖籍福建安溪的苏海金在2017年定居新加坡。“他个头不高，一口闽南腔，住在武吉知马的豪宅，出入劳斯莱斯接送。”见过苏海金的《新加坡眼》作者描述。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新加坡法庭记录显示，2019年，苏海金与伍琴结为夫妻。起初，他们一家住在乌节路附近的格美华庭复式公寓，很快又租下新加坡武吉知马友和园的别墅。后者月租高达8万新币（折合人民币超40万元）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这栋别墅绿树环绕，少有人能从外部看到家中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“他的别墅如同娱乐室，庭院里有迷你高尔夫球场，地下室建有卡拉OK。”一名知情者告诉新加坡《联合早报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏海金举手投足间颇有老板做派，近年间，他在中国厦门、柬埔寨都做过不少“生意”。苏海金还是新加坡圣淘沙高尔夫俱乐部的会员。高尔夫会员服务中介Active Golf Services透露，圣淘沙高尔夫俱乐部是新加坡最贵的高尔夫俱乐部，外国人会员费高达100万新币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏海金奢侈的生活在8月15日暂停。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这一天里，四百余名新加坡警察还逮捕了其他9名外国人，包括苏宝林（41岁）、苏剑锋（35岁）、张瑞金（44岁）、林宝英（43岁）、王水明（42岁）、陈清远（33岁）、苏文强（31岁）、王宝森（31岁）和王德海（34岁）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们被指控洗钱、诈骗、线上赌博和伪造文件等，彼此或有亲属、情侣、合伙关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡内政部长兼律政部长尚穆根在接受采访时称，“这是新加坡最大的反洗钱行动之一”。新加坡警方统计，10名嫌疑人涉案款项高达28亿新币（折合人民币148亿元）。&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至发稿时，新加坡法庭因担心嫌疑人潜逃，尚未接受任何一名嫌疑人的保释请求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;洗钱案嫌疑人落网地点&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/52eaa57e8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1156&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/52eaa57e8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254954&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洗钱案嫌疑人落网地点&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“洗钱案”拼图&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为了逮捕10名嫌疑人，新加坡警方筹备了近三年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“最早发现了一些伪造银行户头款项的文件、可疑的金融报告等，（新加坡政府）便逐个展开调查。”2023年10月3日，新加坡通讯及新闻部长兼内政部第二部长杨莉明在国会上说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;可疑的金融报告来自嫌疑人的公司交易、银行存款等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2017年长居新加坡后，苏海金挥金如土，买房、买游艇、开公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/dec5d214d5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/dec5d214d5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;新加坡乌节路上的独栋洋房。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（娄晓希/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者查询新加坡会计与企业管制局（ACRA）文件发现，苏海金陆续担任了爱情海投资、Daily Glory国际、Yihao网络科技、美宁（亚洲）国际电子商务和SG-Gree等新加坡公司的董事或股东。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据新加坡《商业时报》报道，苏海金在2021年以3640万新元买下了圣淘沙岛Cove Drive的两栋海景独栋别墅，将其合为一栋（以避开外国人在圣淘沙岛上拥有多套房的限制）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;也是在2021年，新加坡警方侦测出一些可疑的金融活动，比如向银行提供伪造文件等。2022年初，新加坡警方开展全面调查，锁定了一群有亲属关系的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年新加坡警方只派出了一小组查案人员调查，以免打草惊蛇。“如果嫌犯有所察觉，可能会卷款潜逃，调查行动也会前功尽弃。”杨莉明介绍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;直到2023年年初，新加坡总检察署评估警方已掌握充分资料后，有充足理由怀疑这群人涉嫌从事犯罪活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;于是8月15日，新加坡警方派出400名警员展开全岛逮捕行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;警方认为，41岁的苏宝林和苏海金是亲兄弟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏宝林和苏海金的祖籍，同为福建安溪，两人在金钱上有密切往来。新加坡警方调查发现，苏海金名下在美芝路的两套房产是苏宝林在2021年出资购买，总价约228.5万新币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏宝林还是新加坡房产网99.co认定的高净值人士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年，苏宝林、苏海金与另外两人合资购买了总价为545万新币的游艇。该游艇命名为“Family”，全长38米，可搭载10名乘客，悬挂着南太平洋国家库克群岛的国旗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月初新加坡法庭称，Family游艇已驶离新加坡，目前在泰国普吉岛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8ab322f176.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8ab322f176.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月，新加坡圣淘沙岛东部的圣淘沙湾游艇码头。苏海金、苏宝林出资购买的游艇，已经在洗钱案事发后驶离新加坡。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（娄晓希/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但两人的律师否认了警方的亲属关系指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，南方周末记者发现苏海金、苏宝林存在密切的商业联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏宝林也是苏海金相关公司美宁（亚洲）国际电子商务、SG-Gree的股东兼董事。他还是新宝投资控股、Xinjiamei投资公司和圣淘沙开发项目Sentosa Project的股东。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至发稿，洗钱案仍在调查中，新的证据还在浮出水面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一嫌疑人苏剑锋（35岁）被逮捕后，警察在调查三个保险机构时发现，他共存有1700万新元现金。可10月18日洗钱案过堂时，苏剑锋却改口称这1700万新元是帮他人保管。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;开公司是洗钱的头等方式&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“10名嫌疑人通过非法线上赌博和网络诈骗获取的资金收益便是&#39;黑钱&#39;，而隐藏、掩饰非法资金来源，使得黑钱变得表面合法化的行为就是洗钱。”复旦大学中国反洗钱中心主任严立新向南方周末记者解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/428c19b966.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2469&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/428c19b966.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;开公司是嫌疑人洗钱的头等方式，在新加坡，10名嫌疑人陆续开过投资公司、科技公司、建筑承包公司等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏海金、苏宝林共同担任高管的公司近20家。不过，大多数公司都是空壳公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者整理工商记录发现，其中有3家还在运营，这三家的注册地址均在新加坡淡马锡大道新达城一号#15-02。其他11家公司的注册地无迹可寻，另外6家位于限制出入的私人住宅等地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏剑锋在录口供时承认，他并不知道自己名下的An Xing Technology公司地址在哪里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在新加坡，外籍人员频繁开设公司，也培养出一批“挂名人士”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“外籍人士在新加坡单独开公司的门槛较高。”新加坡DMC咨询公司董事王俭向南方周末记者解释，没有创业准证（Enter Pass）的外籍人士开公司时，必须有一名新加坡本地人或新加坡永居者担任公司的董事或秘书。“目前新加坡暂未限制本地人担任名义董事、法定秘书的数量。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在会计与企业管制局记录中，有20名“挂名人士”跟嫌疑人的公司有关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这些“挂名人士”不间断地担任几百家公司的秘书，或兼任股东、董事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“他们让我投资、照顾他们的公司。但我从来没有拿过一分钱，也没有股份。”祖籍上海的41岁新加坡人王源告诉《海峡时报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一些洗钱团伙还会“诱惑”正规公司“做壳”代为洗钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;福建三明人岳思秋在新加坡做了10年生意，她曾接触过新加坡的洗钱者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“对方想在我的公司里挂一个他们团队的人，再以我的公司买房。买房的钱他们来付，给我提10%的报酬。”岳思秋告诉南方周末记者，对方盯上她的公司，只因为公司账目是干净的，银行不会怀疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;岳思秋拒绝了洗钱者，反而被骚扰了很久。“由于报酬丰厚，乌节路的部分华人商家会答应这些人的要求。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10名嫌疑人名下持有大量资产。截至10月3日，新加坡警方已对多达152处房地产发出禁止处置令。被禁止处置的房地产属于嫌疑人、他们的配偶或所属公司，包括7栋圣淘沙升涛湾的独栋洋房、79套公寓（其中19套仍在建造中）和19块商业用地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“可以说，挣钱的方式有多少种，洗钱的方式就有多少种。”严立新告诉南方周末记者，“比特币等加密货币、黄金珠宝贵金属、奢侈品、收藏品等因其体积小、价值高、利于携带或运输、方便变现等特点，常常成为洗钱工具。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;近年来，不少房地产人接触过出手阔绰的“土豪”。新加坡房产经纪人田鑫向南方周末记者证实，他曾给新加坡福建人销售过高档公寓、独栋住宅。“一些闽南口音的富豪，一下子能在我手里买两三套房子”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;只需要有一支会计师、律师组成的团队，做好账面工作，用房产洗钱的行为就可以瞒天过海。“如果遇到银行询问资金来源，只要假账做得完美，就可以骗过。”一名房地产经纪人告诉新加坡《联合早报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡警方在嫌疑人住宅内缴获的奢侈品中，不乏豪车、腕表、名画和潮玩积木熊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如一辆售价50万新币的奔驰AMG豪车；价值800万新币的百达翡翠白金天文陀飞轮腕表；多瓶30年茅台和100支麦卡伦威士忌酒……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;柬埔寨赚钱，新加坡生活？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;南方周末记者梳理10名嫌疑人资料发现，他们多来自福建省安溪县，早年在菲律宾、柬埔寨等国开设网络赌博园区、从事线上诈骗生意。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们的“黑钱”，大多在柬埔寨、菲律宾等国通过非法线上赌博和网络诈骗获取。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随后，他们伪造文件，通过新加坡境内银行，把非法所得转进新加坡，并购置、租用多处豪宅，购买豪车和奢侈品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;42岁的王水明是洗钱案中总资产较高的嫌疑人。他被指控伪造文件、持有非法放贷赃款等罪名，他持有土耳其、中国和瓦努阿图三国护照。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡法庭揭露，王水明在新加坡资产超过两亿新元，而他在其他国家的资产约3550万新元，其中柬埔寨资产高达2453万新元。王水明拥有11套新加坡公寓，其中十套位于背山向海的康宁河湾（Canninghill Piers），另一套是乌节路汤林生路的柏皓（Park Nova）公寓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/d9f6d933d6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/d9f6d933d6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌节路汤林生路的柏皓Park Nova公寓。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（娄晓希/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据柬埔寨政府记录，王水明与苏宝林、苏剑锋和苏文强四人在2019年拿到公民身份。其他五人均在2018年8月至2021年3月间成为柬埔寨公民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;拿到身份期间，他们大多数时间在新加坡生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“嫌疑人陆续成为柬埔寨公民，同一时间段还有其他中国人一起入籍，这些人多半是柬埔寨网赌公司的&#39;幕后首脑&#39;。”非营利组织网络诈骗监察网认为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者询问多位生活在柬埔寨的中国人，不少人能认出苏宝林、苏海金，还有人与王水明“打过交道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“王水明算是柬埔寨网络赌博圈子里比较出名的福建人，九成以上在柬埔寨的中国人都认识他。”居住在柬埔寨的吕泽源告诉南方周末记者，并称王水明算个“人物”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;十年前，王水明依靠菲律宾的赌博网站起家，算是第一批在菲律宾开设线上博彩的福建人之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;巅峰时期，王水明手下的雇员达到1万人。在菲律宾积攒资金后，王水明又前往柬埔寨拓展网络赌博业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;柬埔寨华文媒体人林啸告诉南方周末记者，王水明入局网赌圈早。他们团队研发的资金盘“大发系统”被柬埔寨、缅甸、迪拜等地的网络赌博公司使用。这个系统“相对公平，不会轻易&#39;杀猪&#39;”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一般情况下，网赌公司将参与线上赌客视为“猪”，当赌客大额充值时，公司后台就会锁住赌客的账号资金，与其切断联系，实现“杀猪”目的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者查询柬埔寨、新加坡的工商信息发现，王水明是柬埔寨大明信息技术服务（Daming IT Services）公司的董事长，同时还是新加坡卓驰科技公司（Zhuo Chi Technology）的董事兼股东。上述公司均对外宣称“主营软件开发”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王水明也是柬埔寨SCWD Construction公司的八名董事之一，该公司于2016年注册，公司字母所写与董事的姓氏相对应：苏、陈、王、邓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;本次洗钱案另一名嫌疑人王德海也是SCWD Construction的八名董事之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;8月15日，王德海在乌节路巴德申山（Paterson Hill）一带公寓被捕，被控洗钱。新加坡警方在他的公寓搜出了超过220万新元现金、35块名表、51件首饰和数款名牌包。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吕泽源在柬埔寨生活了近十年，他告诉南方周末记者，网络诈骗生意做大后，幕后大佬在菲律宾、马来西亚、泰国都会设立公司，一些“大佬”甚至会有私人专机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“这些人最后都偏向于去新加坡换一种生活。”吕泽源说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但生活在新加坡的网赌老板，不会停止在东南亚的网络诈骗生意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“这些网赌公司老板会远程管理公司事务，可能一年飞两三次柬埔寨，只处理大事，小事交给园区总经理。”林啸告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“他们几乎整村人都在新加坡”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡的福建帮也随着洗钱案曝光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“新加坡的福建帮少则几十人，多则上百，他们当中按姓氏划分帮派，苏、王、胡、陈是几大主要帮派。”一名匿名的房地产经纪人告诉新加坡《联合早报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;苏海金和另一名嫌疑人王德海被认为是苏姓和王姓两个帮派的老大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡福建帮一向出手阔绰。“他们平常生活高调，开兰博基尼、法拉利等，到高档夜店消费时，陪同的都是中国籍女郎。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;福建帮重地缘、宗族关系，偏好小圈子文化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;林啸的一个朋友与王水明同村，“他们算是小圈子文化，他帮王水明代理业务（做诈骗）。他们自己会做一个盘出来，村里人自己玩。”林啸告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而在2023年9月底，苏海金的辩护律师郑惠龙在法庭上表示，苏海金的四个孩子、他的父母、岳父岳母，甚至数名兄弟姐妹和亲属都在新加坡。“他们几乎整村人都在新加坡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“福建帮的人喜欢找优秀年轻男性当说客，约本地华人见面、洽谈合作。”新加坡华人刘亚南告诉南方周末记者，他被说客邀约过几次，“但我没有答应”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于这起洗钱案，新加坡政府采取“零容忍”态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月中旬，新加坡内政和法律部长尚穆根接受新加坡《联合早报》采访时表示，任何人在新加坡做任何违法的事，或是在海外做非法勾当，再试图在新加坡洗钱，他们都会采取行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月29日，王水明第三次过堂时，新加坡法官以“可能潜逃”“与其他嫌疑人串供”为由拒绝了他的保释申请。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王水明等多名洗钱案嫌疑人在中国还背有案底，是国内的在逃人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年5月，山东省淄博市博山区公安局破获一起“恒博包网赌博案”，抓获开设赌博网站、非法盈利的犯罪嫌疑人131名，追缴涉案资金一千余万元人民币。王水明是博山区公安局记录下的头号通缉人物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上述案件仍有9名涉案人员非法滞留国外，除了王水明外，其余八人均为福建安溪县人，多数为王姓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;福建帮王姓头目王德海在2018年因涉嫌网络赌博案，被湖南省桂阳县公安B级通缉。同一时间被通缉的还有本次洗钱案的苏剑锋、苏文强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡法庭调查发现，王德海在2012年从菲律宾参与赌博公司，从客服、推广，逐步将生意做大。目前，王德海以前就职过的赌博网站仍在运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5177e81064.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5177e81064.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌节路上的巴德申山The Marq on Paterson Hill公寓。洗钱案嫌疑人王德海的逮捕地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（娄晓希/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“十名嫌疑人属于一个更大的犯罪集团，他们彼此间有着千丝万缕的联系。”2023年9月，负责洗钱案的新加坡警方商业事务局（CAD）在法庭宣誓书中坦言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前，新加坡警方暂未发现王宝森与其他九名嫌疑人的商业联系。不过，王宝森的名字早已与东南亚诈骗团伙绑定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者查阅判决文书网发现，早在2013年，王宝森便加入了福建安溪人王斌刚成立的菲律宾“鸿利国际”网赌网站，负责财务工作。2014年网站团队迁入柬埔寨边境城市巴域（越南称木排），随后王宝森逐渐负责鸿利国际网站的全面管理工作，底薪为1万元人民币，另有奖金提成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;该网站涉赌资金高达9.8亿元人民币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除了被指控的10名嫌疑人，目前还有多人正协助新加坡警方调查，包括企业服务提供商、房地产经纪和金融机构等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年8月28日，新加坡律政部向宝石和贵金属经销商发出的一份34人审查名单中，王宝森的妻子何惠芳、“鸿利国际”网站创始人王斌刚赫然在列。该审查名单旨在提醒宝石经销商及时通报可疑交易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;案件不断发酵，9月初新加坡法庭宣誓书显示，王宝森一位表兄弟的1亿资金被冻结，此人已逃出新加坡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为了在他国生活，嫌疑人多持有多国护照。新加坡法庭10月18日揭露，唯一一名女性嫌疑人林宝英曾分别支付13万美元和16万美元，购买了多米尼克和柬埔寨的护照。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“小国家护照可以通过移民中介买到，并不难获得。”新加坡DMC咨询公司董事王俭告诉南方周末记者，洗钱案曝光后，新加坡就推出了一个政策，凡是拿着小国护照的中国人很难在银行开户、开设公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“除非这些人可以出具放弃原籍证明。”王俭说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至发稿日，10名嫌疑人仍在寻求法院保释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡法律规定，犯有洗钱罪的人可被判处最高10年监禁、最高50万新元的罚款，或两者并罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尚穆根坦言，10名洗钱案被告一旦治罪，将在新加坡服刑，服完刑期后遣送回他所持护照的国家，或被送回跟新加坡有引渡协议的国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而中国与新加坡没有引渡协议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中王源、刘亚南、林啸、吕泽源、田鑫、岳思秋为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[致3死17伤的弥勒坠梯事故被提级调查，当地称伤者状态趋稳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259119]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10月18日，云南省弥勒市佛城商都发生电梯坠落事故。截至目前，共造成3人死亡，4人重伤、13人轻伤。23日，云南省人民政府办公室工作人员告诉南都记者，该事故已被提级调查，由云南省市场监督管理局负责。该工作人员还称，当前伤者状态趋于稳定。云南省市监局工作人员表示已派人前往事发地进行调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/04f086e7662ba541a8337c36e6aca659.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/04f086e7662ba541a8337c36e6aca659.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;事故现场。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故现场视频显示，事故现场有救护车、消防车等，医生、消防员在一栋楼下搬运担架，多名市民在现场围观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18日，据弥勒市政府新闻办发布通告，当天12时许，弥勒市佛城商都发生电梯坠落。弥勒市立即组织力量全力救治伤员，截至目前，共造成3人死亡，4人重伤、13人轻伤。坠落原因调查等工作正在紧张开展中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23日，南都记者从云南省人民政府获知，该事故已被提级调查，由云南省市场监督管理局负责。云南省市监局表示已派工作人员前往事发地，调查工作正在开展。此外，云南省人民政府办公室工作人员告诉南都记者，当前伤者状态趋于稳定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南都此前报道，19日，佛城商都的两位商户告诉南都记者，事故电梯于2015年投入使用，为货梯，主要用于进货。其中一位商户表示，商都里有客梯和货梯，“货梯不载人”，之前没有出过事故。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;云南省特种设备安全技术协会工作人员向南都记者表示，“按规定来说，货梯客梯不能混用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据云南省市场监督管理局官网介绍，佛城商都市场是弥勒市最大的农贸市场，日均人流量可达到2至3万人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>