<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国际观察｜“美国的手上沾满智利人的鲜血”——起底美国阴谋颠覆阿连德政府始末]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256568]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;I will defend the precious principles of the motherland with my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 1973 On the 11th, in Santiago, the capital of Chile, at the presidential palace surrounded by coup soldiers, Chilean President Salvador Allende from the left-wing camp gave a radio speech expressing his determination to fight to the end. Later that day, the presidential palace was captured and Allende was killed in the line of duty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This coup opened one of the darkest chapters in Chilean history.” A report by Cuba’s Latin American News Agency commented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 11 this year marks the 50th anniversary of the overthrow of the Allende government by a coup. Over the past half century, many historical studies and declassified archives have shown that the United States went to great lengths and used all means to prevent Allende from coming to power and overthrow the Allende government. This year also marks the 200th anniversary of the &quot;Monroe Doctrine&quot; proposed by the United States. For a long time, the United States has held hegemony, manipulated the rhetoric of &quot;democracy and freedom&quot;, and used coup intervention, economic sanctions and other means to cause deep suffering to Latin American countries and people. Nowadays, more and more Latin American countries and people are awakening, and their voices against US hegemonic interference are rising day by day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/4e16d2ae2dfe95e2b91054641f81e9fb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/4e16d2ae2dfe95e2b91054641f81e9fb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250505&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On September 11, 2022, in Santiago, the capital of Chile, a man held a red carnation in front of the memorial The 49th anniversary of the death of President Allende. (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Xinhua News Agency, photo by Jorge Villegas)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The only chance of success is to launch a military coup&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is clear that any form of political or constitutional approach to preventing the Allende government from exercising power is unlikely to succeed. The only chance of success is before or after Allende takes power. Immediately launch a military coup... It is hoped that the intelligence station will establish direct contact with as many influential military figures as possible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 9, 1970, the CIA sent a secret cable to its intelligence station in Chile. Earlier, voting in the Chilean presidential election had just concluded. Allende, the candidate of the Popular Unity Front of the left-wing political party alliance, came first in the vote, which made the US government very angry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The US government’s suppression of Allende can be traced back to 1964. This year, Allende, who was defeated in the previous Chilean presidential election, ran again. At that time, the Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union was raging, and the U.S. government, which regarded Latin America as its &quot;backyard,&quot; did not want to see this left-wing leader elected as the president of Chile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the United States secretly supported Allende’s campaign opponents, provided millions of dollars in campaign funds to the parties of Allende’s opponents, and funded Chilean right-wing groups and media through the CIA to publish a large number of attacks and discredit Allende. Germany&#39;s message encourages people not to vote for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. intervention achieved what it wanted, and Allende lost the 1964 presidential election. These behind-the-scenes manipulations obviously go against the &quot;democracy&quot; rhetoric that the United States has always promoted, but the absurd reason given by American politicians is that the damage caused by US intervention to Chile is less than the harm that a left-wing government that came to power through democratic elections might cause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, 1970, Chile held a presidential election. Allende, who ran again, came first in the vote, but did not get more than half of the votes. According to the law, Congress must vote for the president among the top two candidates. Seeing that a &quot;second Cuba&quot; was about to emerge in Latin America, the panicked U.S. government decided to step up its intervention efforts to prevent Allende from winning the congressional vote. On September 15, then US President Richard Nixon issued instructions to CIA Director Richard Helms and others: &quot;Don&#39;t consider the risks, don&#39;t involve the embassy, ​​US$10 million in available funds, and more if necessary.&quot; Work day and night, select our best people... Let Chile&#39;s economy scream in pain, and come up with an action plan within 48 hours.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plan the CIA came up with was to stage a military coup in Chile. Documents later declassified by the CIA showed that the United States promised some Chilean military officers that if they launched a coup, the United States would provide any assistance other than direct troops. The then commander of the Chilean Army, Rene Schneider, firmly opposed the coup and therefore became a &quot;thorn in the side&quot; of the CIA. On October 22, 1970, he was attacked by a gang associated with the CIA and died a few days later. The U.S. move was self-defeating and shocked the entire country of Chile, raising voices against foreign interference. In the congressional vote held on October 24, Allende won by a clear advantage and was elected President of Chile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/5c180aa6ab63290afe289dd730c92787.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/5c180aa6ab63290afe289dd730c92787.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250504&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On September 11, 2022, people gathered in Santiago, the capital of Chile, to commemorate former President Allende 49th anniversary of the death. (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Xinhua News Agency, photo by Jorge Villegas)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Anyone who affects the interests of the United States will automatically become its enemy”&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a major Latin American country, Chile’s political changes are one of the important trends in regional politics. The United States was afraid that Allende&#39;s model of coming to power through democratic elections would spread, lead to the rise of a left-wing wave in Latin America, and challenge the hegemony of the United States in Latin America. Therefore, after the failure of its first attempt to instigate a coup in 1970, the United States decided to focus on politics, economy, and military. All parties worked together to weaken the Allende government and create conditions for promoting a coup in Chile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the political level, according to the New York Times, the US government allocated US$815,000 to create divisions among various parties within the Allende government. Between 1970 and 1973, the CIA spent a total of more than $8 million in Chile, most of which was used to fund strikes, demonstrations and other activities organized by right-wing opposition groups. At the same time, the CIA&#39;s &quot;black propaganda machine&quot;, which had been honed in the 1964 Chilean elections, was operating at high speed. Information collected by Chilean journalist Victor Herrero shows that between September 15 and November 3, 1973 alone, the CIA published 726 slanderous articles through various channels in Chile and abroad, accusing Allende of wanting to The media exerts control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the economic level, in order to combat the Chilean economy, the U.S. government on the one hand prevents international financial institutions such as the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund from providing loans to Chile; on the other hand, it suppresses copper prices in the international market and attacks the export of copper products. This is an important source of foreign exchange for Chile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the military level, the &quot;Chilean Secret Operations 1963-1973&quot; report released by the US government shows that the United States continues to provide assistance to the Chilean military, maintains high arms sales to Chile, and trains a large number of Chilean military officers. , to cultivate pro-American forces within the Chilean military. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the influence of a series of sabotage and suppression measures by the United States, by the eve of the 1973 coup, the Allende government was in trouble: there were serious divisions within the government, domestic prices were soaring, protests were frequent, and the military was becoming increasingly divided. Hair is unstable. Finally, on September 11 of that year, Augusto Pinochet, the then commander of the Chilean Army, launched a coup and overthrew the Allende government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Without the support and financial assistance from the United States, the Chilean opposition would not be so strong.&quot; Chilean historian Victor Boulanghier told Xinhua News Agency. Chilean academic circles generally believe that US intervention created conditions for the Chilean army to launch a coup, leading to the collapse of the Allende government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the 17-year military rule has caused great harm to Chile. Chilean official data shows that during this period, more than 40,000 people were arrested for political reasons in Chile, more than 3,000 people died at the hands of the secret police or disappeared, and at least 200,000 people were forced into exile overseas. The United States cannot absolve itself of the blame for this. As an article in the British &quot;Guardian&quot; said: &quot;The hands of the United States are stained with the blood of Chileans.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chilean Communist Party Representative Luis Cuello said that the United States&#39; intervention &quot;profoundly changed Chile.&quot; historical process, violates international law&#39;s protection of the rights of countries to choose their own political and social systems, and is a systematic violation of human rights.&quot; Former Chilean Senator Alejandro Navarro said: &quot;The United States has never cared about the democracy of the American people, but only cares about its own economic and political interests. The United States regards Chile and Latin American countries as its own &#39;property&#39;, Anyone who affects U.S. interests automatically becomes its enemy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/69c4f486f25ac1460659c3de23a5090d.jpeg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/69c4f486f25ac1460659c3de23a5090d .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On September 11, 2021, people were in the Plaza de la Constitución in Santiago, the capital of Chile. rallied in front of the statue of former President Allende to commemorate the 48th anniversary of Allende&#39;s death. (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Published by Xinhua News Agency, photo by Jorge Villegas)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The &quot;Monroe Doctrine&quot; is imperialist power politics&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The tragedy of Allende fully exposed the hypocrisy and hegemony of the United States. The history of Latin America has proven that when the governments of some countries are not in line with the wishes of the United States, politicians in Washington will not hesitate to plan and instigate coups, and even go so far as to personally carry out butcher knives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1915, turmoil broke out in Haiti. The United States sent troops to Haiti on the grounds of &quot;protecting expatriates&quot; and exercised full control over the country. It did not withdraw its troops until 1934. In the early 1950s, the Guatemalan government implemented land reform and distributed the idle land of the American-owned United Fruit Company to landless farmers. The U.S. government, with lobbying from the United Fruit Company, supported Castillo Armas in launching a coup to overthrow the government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various actions of the United States have aroused dissatisfaction in Latin America. In recent years, the will of Latin American countries to oppose U.S. hegemony has become stronger and stronger: In March 2022, the Panamanian government announced that December 20 will be designated as a &quot;National Day of Mourning&quot; to commemorate the victims of the U.S. military operation against Panama in 1989. ; During the Summit of the Community of Latin American and Caribbean States in January this year, participating leaders jointly urged the United States to end its long-term blockade on Cuba; in June, Nicaraguan President Ortega sent a letter to United Nations Secretary-General Guterres, demanding that the United States pay more than 120 US$100 million in compensation to fulfill the International Court of Justice&#39;s judgment on the United States&#39; funding of the Nicaraguan civil war in the 1980s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a recent interview with a reporter from Xinhua News Agency, Fernando Huanacuuni, the former Foreign Minister of Bolivia, pointed out that for the past 200 years, the United States has adhered to the &quot;Monroe Doctrine&quot; and regarded Latin America as its &quot;backyard&quot;, using hegemony and interference to These actions hinder the development of Latin American countries and seize resources in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The essence of the &#39;Monroe Doctrine&#39; is to interfere in Latin American countries and promote hegemony in Latin America,&quot; Vanakuni said. &quot;There have been countless examples of the United States blatantly interfering in the internal affairs of Latin American countries over the past 200 years. This is completely It is the power politics of imperialism, which is destined to fail because more and more countries want to independently determine their own democracy, economic model and national governance model.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打赏秀才的老年人，直播间里的情感供养]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256572]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/OvdWo957x5iBiGHa4n3ZmrxPa6RErMw0RrFaaeeJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;781&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/OvdWo957x5iBiGHa4n3ZmrxPa6RErM w0RrFaaeeJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Behind the short videos are the emotions that the elderly cannot place. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Ermei, a female assembly line worker, once pinned her hopes for a counterattack in life on making short videos. superior. She tried documenting her life and singing lip-syncs, but she persisted for a long time but no one took notice. In the end, the most popular works were those that were &quot;co-produced&quot; with famous Internet celebrities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When all romance returns to nature and tranquility reaches far away, will you grow old together with me?&quot; In a video pinned to the top by Lu Ermei, photos of her and Xiucai were combined. Together, they smiled and cuddled up to each other. Amidst the accompaniment of earthy love songs and the special effects of flying red hearts, this sincere &quot;vow&quot; was played on the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It must be said that in addition to the purpose of operating a video account, the video also contains the admiration of the host and fans for the show. This video received more than 200 hearts and 39 comments, such as &quot;a perfect match&quot;, &quot;perfectly matched with the handsome guy&quot;, and &quot;may the scholar brother not grow old and stay with his sister until he grows old&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price Lu Ermei paid for this was a reward of more than 100,000 yuan. &quot;There is a sister who gave a reward of more than 500,000 yuan, but she did not get it back.&quot; Before the scholar&#39;s accident, Lu Ermei regretted her lack of calmness and whims. &quot;Now that his account has been blocked, I will Very happy.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 2, 2023, the anchor Xiucai, who has tens of millions of fans and is known as the &quot;harvester of middle-aged and elderly women&quot;, had her short video account banned for violating the relevant regulations of the platform. Previously, the scholar&#39;s signature moves of pretending to be shy, lifting his hair, covering his mouth, and ogling, were imitated and parodied, and spread virally on major platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scholar’s ​​ban also exposed his “crazy fans” to the spotlight. Among Xiu Cai&#39;s fans, there are many &quot;true fans&quot; like Lu Ermei who reward hundreds of thousands or even hundreds of thousands of yuan. What kind of charm do these elderly emotional anchors have that can make fans donate generously? What are these middle-aged and elderly people who spend a lot of money really looking forward to? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Induced &quot;reflux&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Lu Ermei&#39;s hometown is Huaining County, Anhui Province, and she works in a garment factory in Changshu City, Jiangsu Province. Because she is the second eldest child in the family and is called the second sister of the Lu family, she simply named her short video account &quot;The Second Sister of the Lu Family&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has been a fan of Xiucai for three or four years. At the beginning, Xiucai only had 500,000 or 600,000 fans, but later it skyrocketed to tens of millions. &quot;He said he was going to teach me how to make videos and asked me to help him play PK.&quot; Lu Ermei recalled the initial exchanges between the two to Southern Weekend reporters. Because she gave gifts to the scholar, she got many opportunities to communicate with him and established initial trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, Xiucai is a 39-year-old native of Mengcheng, Anhui Province. His family background was average. In his early years, he and his wife worked in Suzhou, and their children stayed in their hometown to attend boarding school. A few years ago, at the suggestion of a classmate, I started shooting short videos. At first, they were mainly about migrant workers, and gradually turned into anchors wearing suits and singing lip-sync. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gradually, Lu Ermei came up with the idea of ​​making short videos. She posted the composite video with Xiucai on her account and accumulated some fans. However, the most direct way to get the opportunity to be exposed is to interact with the talents in the live broadcast room, and this requires buying gifts. From the most basic little hearts, gold chains, and hot air balloons to valuable Porsches and helicopters, Lu Ermei went all the way up, and she frequently received compliments from scholars: She is very beautiful, and she should listen to her brother, etc. wait. Xiucai also praised Ermei for doing a good job in her video and her fans were increasing quickly. Lu Ermei was very happy and replied, &quot;It&#39;s all because of you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Ermei got Xiucai’s promise to help her create an account, but there were more and more requests for rewards. &quot;Just let me help him with PK, and ask me to help him in the live broadcast room.&quot; The so-called PK is a common form of popularity competition on live broadcast platforms. The anchors show off their talents or skills and call on their fans to give rewards. The method is &quot;upvote&quot;. Whoever gets the most rewards will be the winner of the PK competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fierce competition, scholars frequently asked for rewards of &quot;carriage&quot; and &quot;Hua Zi&quot;. &quot;Hua Zi&quot; is the common name for the gift &quot;Carnival&quot;, which is equivalent to RMB 3,000. The most recent reward was more than 4,000 yuan from Lu Ermei during a live broadcast. Over the past few years, she claimed to have consumed more than 100,000 yuan in savings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is a relatively common form to create an account and lead an apprentice.” Liangzhou (screen name) is a knowledge-based blogger on social platforms. She used to be responsible for the virtual anchor business in an MCN company. As a short-term An in-depth user and long-term observer of the video platform, she attracted attention for her series of blog posts analyzing the phenomenon of &quot;scholars&quot;. She told Southern Weekend reporters that this method of promising to teach people how to create an account in order to ask for rewards is deceptive and misleading to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liangzhou analyzed that in addition to the form of &quot;teaching how to create an account&quot;, the more direct way of inducement is to &quot;fight backflow&quot;: &quot;It is to act as a support to increase the popularity of the live broadcast room.&quot; The so-called fighting Returning means that the anchor and the fans agree in advance that the fans will help buy gifts in the live broadcast room to increase their popularity, and the anchor will refund the amount they spent in private. However, because the platform will take half of the water, the cost of returning it is very high, and because it involves data fraud, the platform does not encourage or even prohibit this behavior. Therefore, reshoring is usually an operation used by MCN organizations to recruit new talents. Personal promises to fight back are often suspected of inducement and deception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, a 62-year-old woman from Beijing said that she rewarded scholars with more than 520,000 yuan in the form of gifts. She said that the reason for being so generous was that the scholar promised her that he would not treat her badly and would return the money, but the promise was never fulfilled. In the past three years, she has been asking Xiucai for the 520,000 yuan, but only 17,000 yuan was recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;He is such a ruthless thing&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, Lu Ermei&#39;s short video account has not been launched, and the number of fans has remained at more than 10,000 , she did not have the financial resources to continue to reward, so the scholar stopped talking to her in the live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He said he voluntarily swiped gifts, and it&#39;s impossible for others to use my mobile phone to swipe it, right?&quot; In 2021, Lu Ermei went to Mengcheng, Anhui to find a scholar to discuss the theory, but was scolded by the other party. Later, He was also blocked by the other party, saying, &quot;He is such a heartless and meaningless thing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there are mixed ideas of making a short video account, in the minds of fans, the most attractive reason is the emotional value provided by the anchor, but this value requires money to support. &quot;This type of anchor actually has poor ability to &#39;organize&#39;.&quot; Liang Zhou analyzed that in order to attract fans, many live broadcast rooms will set up studios with lighting, props and furnishings, and have rich talent displays, and some will even design scripts. , relatively speaking, there will be much less emotional live broadcast routines for the elderly. &quot;Old people don&#39;t like to be noisy, what they need is companionship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/UXZYTnTr7JHSV5qkyvCfGgwpNodqtpXVV7xWen9D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/UXZYTnTr7JHSV5qkyvCfGgwpNodqtpXVV7xWen9D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic shy expression of a scholar. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Internet screenshots/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liangzhou registered a new account and deliberately liked and collected videos of senior citizens to feed the account&#39;s popularity &quot;Habit&quot; opens up a new world. For the first time in the homepage recommendation, she came across a live broadcast room where the elderly were grouped together. The users who were connected were all men in their sixties. They also played PK. The audience could designate the anchor among them to &quot;open the arena&quot;. Then vote for them separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there was no talent show in this PK, only voice chatting with fans, mostly middle-aged and elderly women. Liangzhou judged from the chat content that the two were familiar with each other and it was not the first time they were on the mic. The anchor used instant messaging software to call fans to come over and help &quot;vote.&quot; The content of the chat is also very common: What kind of tea did you drink today? Is the road easy to walk or not? If it rains, don&#39;t go out because your shoes will get muddy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These words must not be heard by her at home.&quot; Liang Zhou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the video and comments, the anchor ran a business when he was young and was considered a prominent figure in their local village. However, although he is much older than Xiucai, his video style is similar, with fixed scenes and fixed music, and he is usually holding a purple clay pot and making tea. The uncle’s account only has 10,000 to 20,000 fans, but the interaction volume is very high. Each video has thousands of likes, and the number of comments is close to half or one-third of the likes. Through this PK, the anchor got more than 6,000 votes, which were converted into money and he could get 300 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiucai first came out of the industry because in May 2023, a 70-year-old woman took a train alone to Mengcheng, Anhui Province to seek an offline meeting. Sister Zhang was a classmate of the scholar and had been a short video partner for a period of time. She claimed that her relationship with the scholar later deteriorated because she discovered that the scholar promised to meet his fans in private as an inducement and asked fans to give him large gifts. Sister Zhang believes that this breaks the moral bottom line and is not a very honorable thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister Zhang considers herself to be the leader of short videos made by scholars, and she felt ashamed to see such a situation. In July 2023, she began to publicly solicit victims who were &quot;deceived&quot; by scholars on the short video platform. . A girl in her twenties asked for help. Her parents had divorced. After her mother fell in love with a scholar, she gave him a reward of more than 10,000 yuan and talked about going to find the scholar. She and her brother could not persuade her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s unclear whether the old lady in her seventies came here to give him a reward, but the fact that the old lady came to us is definitely related to them.” Sister Zhang told Nanfang a reporter said over the weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Fans of Xiu Cai&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liang Zhou also browsed the account of an active fan of the uncle anchor mentioned above. His character image is very clear: in his early career Yousheng is now widowed, her son is married and has settled in a big city, while she lives alone in her hometown. What is particularly impressive is that this woman has a strong desire to share. The most she posted was 33 videos in one day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She seems to have no one to talk to in real life.&quot; Liang Zhou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I support my grandma to watch short videos of scholars.” Xiao Xie is a post-90s generation who has been working for three years. She told a Southern Weekend reporter that her grandma is 68 years old and was in good health a few years ago. , I would also go to square dance. In 2022, I accidentally fell and fractured my bones. After recovery, I rarely went out and developed the habit of checking my mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Xie said that her grandfather had used a smartphone a few years ago and would hold it all day long. Grandpa and grandma seldom communicated with each other in daily life. After grandpa became addicted to using his mobile phone, the two of them talked less. Until grandma also used a smartphone, she gained a lot of emotional sustenance. The two elderly people often stay up until one or two o&#39;clock in the evening, &quot;you can say they are very obsessed with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xiao Xie found that her grandma’s ability to distinguish was very low. She used to like &quot;Fake Jin Dong&quot;, but she couldn&#39;t tell it was fake. Later, she liked Xiucai, and many video platforms gradually appeared. Even if you imitate or pretend to be a scholar’s ​​account, grandma won’t be able to tell whether it is genuine or fake. &quot;I can&#39;t tell whether it&#39;s a platform or an anchor, an organization or an individual, but she believes it anyway.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time she goes back, grandma will explain her views on mate selection and tell her granddaughter to look for a scholar. The ideal type of boy is not only good-looking, but also very capable, and at the same time considerate and caring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma also thought of giving rewards to scholars. Every time Xiao Xie goes back, she will clean up the phone memory for her grandparents and close some unreliable accounts. She discovered that her grandma’s mobile phone had received text messages indicating failure to reward and failure to bind bank cards. &quot;I&#39;m too old to do this.&quot; The two old people&#39;s mobile phones have never been bound to bank cards. The family realized that they would not waste any money, and as long as the elderly were happy, they could feel free to let them watch short videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the elderly, short videos are also the spiritual sustenance of Lu Ermei. &quot;Working in the factory is too tiring, and I have to move my hands and feet.&quot; Lu Ermei and his wife met in a garment factory in Changshu, Jiangsu. They have been married for more than ten years. However, over the years, her husband has worked in Changshu, Suzhou and other places. Get together less and stay apart more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Working in a garment factory is very boring and I only have 3 days off every month. Because of making accounts and giving rewards, her relationship with her husband had a serious crisis. Her husband went to Suzhou to work alone. The two had little contact and were basically in a cold war. &quot;He (husband) was suspicious and thought I was betraying him.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Growing old does not mean giving up all needs&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;The elderly&#39;s blind pursuit of stars is different from ours. We chase stars and buy a concert ticket. At least these things can be seen on the surface, they are internal (emotional needs).&quot; Sister Zhang said that in the spiritual world of many elderly people, emotions are relatively lacking, and their empty hearts cannot be comforted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister Zhang added that men usually die earlier than women, leaving the old lady alone; there are also cases where men go out to make money while women stay behind, and their emotional worlds are generally empty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Before, I saw a post saying that when women reach a certain age, their secretion of hormones decreases and they lose sexual desire. This is definitely wrong.&quot; Liangzhou said that when a person enters old age, it seems that The concept of losing vitality in a social sense also means that the related lust and emotional needs should not appear in the elderly - this is obviously a very incorrect perception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Companionship, humor, love, conversation and many other things are essential human needs. We want all these when we are young, but when we get older, age does not mean It means that we have given up all these needs. And society and the people around us should not directly ignore this series of needs. This is a manifestation of giving up basic responsibilities.&quot; Liang Zhou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the process of scholars becoming popular, whether it is older women or middle-aged and elderly people, I think it is understandable to like scholars.&quot; Peng Huamao, a professor at the Institute of Developmental Psychology of Beijing Normal University, has been doing psychological cognition and training for the elderly for many years. According to the research, after observing some short videos and fan messages of scholars, she believed that these messages were a relatively flamboyant emotional expression and reflected the emotional needs of the elderly. “Many of these comments are about women’s desire for emotion. , or, in other words, the awakening of one’s own emotional needs within.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Huamao analyzed that the emotional needs of this group rarely receive attention from the outside world, especially among middle-aged and elderly women. &quot;When you are young, you live for your family. When you get older, your value in the family is not reflected.&quot; She said that instead of exploring why scholars are popular, it is better to pay attention to the emotional needs of middle-aged and elderly people in real life. How to satisfy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Huamao said that there is a common misunderstanding in society that love will weaken with age, which makes everyone ignore the psychology of the elderly. Excessive ridicule and stigmatization will cover up the underlying problem. &quot;So, I think whether you give a reward to a scholar or pay attention to a scholar, it actually expresses that she needs a spiritual sustenance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[华为苹果新机接连亮相，你多久会换一台手机？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256564]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the early morning of September 13th, Beijing time, the 2023 Apple Autumn Conference arrived as scheduled. The highlight of the series, the iPhone 15 series, was previously expected to no longer contain toothpaste. However, after its actual debut, netizens on social media were slightly disappointed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 29, Huawei suddenly launched the Mate 60 Pro for sale without warning, which also made many mobile phone enthusiasts happy and queued up offline to try and purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the market data is not optimistic. Many young people have now recovered from the digital craze. From following Huawei and Apple, they changed their phones every year, to now they have not changed their phones for more than three years. In the second quarter of 2023, global smartphone sales fell 8% year-on-year. This is the eighth consecutive quarter in which the global smartphone market has been in decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaomi founder Lei Jun was once surprised that 23% of users have not changed their phones for more than three years. Honor CEO Zhao Ming also revealed that Honor has the longest replacement cycle among almost all brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Do you want to change your mobile phone? How often does it take to buy a new mobile phone? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[两部门规范大型演出活动管理：面向公众销售门票比例不得低于85%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 14:24:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to strengthen large-scale commercial performance activities with an audience of more than 5,000 people (hereinafter referred to as &quot;large-scale performance activities&quot;) To standardize management and promote the healthy and orderly development of the performance market, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Further Strengthening the Standardized Management of Large-scale Commercial Performance Activities to Promote the Healthy and Orderly Development of the Performance Market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; pointed out that at present, the performance market is rapidly recovering and development, and large-scale commercial performance activities such as concerts and music festivals have increased significantly. While meeting the spiritual and cultural needs of the people, ticket speculation in individual performance activities Problems such as ticket scalping, irrational star chasing, and uncivilized viewing are also prominent. It is required that in accordance with the principle of &quot;whoever organizes the performance is responsible&quot;, the performance organizer should strictly implement the responsibility of the safety subject, strictly establish and implement the safety management system, and clarify the person responsible for safety , establish and improve risk assessment and emergency response working mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; makes the following clear requirements for strengthening ticket management:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large-scale performance events implement a real-name ticket purchase and admission system. Each performance can only purchase one ticket per ID card. For each ticket, the identity information of the ticket purchaser and the visitor shall be consistent. Performance organizers and performance ticket sales platforms should strengthen the protection of consumers&#39; personal information to prevent unauthorized access and leakage, tampering, and loss of personal information;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Performance organizers should establish a refund mechanism for large-scale performance events and set up Establish reasonable tiered refund fees to protect ticket buyers’ legitimate rights to refunds;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further increase the proportion of ticket sales for large-scale performance events, and the number of tickets sold to the market by performance organizers shall not be less than the number of approved audiences 85%. For the remaining 15% of tickets, personal information should be bound 24 hours before the performance to achieve &quot;real-name binding and real-name admission&quot;;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance organizer should clearly indicate its authorized ticketing agency, Guide consumers to purchase tickets from legal channels. The notification obligation should be fulfilled and consumers should be informed of the rules for ticket purchase, admission and refund;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culture and tourism administrative departments should urge performance organizers and performance ticket sales platforms to provide ticketing information for large-scale performance events (including but not Limited to the name of the performance, performance time, number of performances, number of tickets, ticket sales plan, box office revenue and other information) are transmitted to the national cultural market technical supervision and service platform in real time to further strengthen the management of ticketing information for large-scale performance events;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Cultural and tourism administrative departments and public security organs should strengthen the management of local work tickets for large-scale performance event organizers and venues, strictly control the scope of issuance, and prevent work tickets from entering the market and being illegally traded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; requires: Cultural and tourism market management departments and comprehensive law enforcement agencies should strengthen on-site inspections of large-scale performance activities, verify actor information and performance content on-site, and it is strictly prohibited to change actors and performance content without authorization. Lip-singing, false playing and other illegal activities; intensify the crackdown on illegal activities; the cultural and tourism administrative departments must strengthen the management of performance ticket sales platforms, and deal with those who fail to perform the obligation to verify the qualifications of ticketing business units and performance approval documents in accordance with the law, and resell tickets for Providing services and other violations; the public security organs should intensify the crackdown on reselling performance tickets, comprehensively collect information on ticket reselling and speculation online and offline, promptly discover clues about price increases and disguised price increases, and crack down on online and offline ticket scalping and fraud. Illegal and criminal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; also clarifies: The cultural and tourism administrative departments shall, in accordance with the &quot;Cultural and Tourism Market Credit Management Regulations&quot;, handle large-scale performance activities where the number of tickets sold to the public is less than 85% of the approved number or is less than 85% of the approved number. Performance organizers and ticketing agencies that resell tickets, facilitate the purchase and sale of performance tickets, etc., are deemed to be untrustworthy entities in the cultural and tourism market in accordance with the law. To guide the audience to watch performances in a civilized manner, it is recommended that actor brokerage companies and related entertainment brokerage practitioners should strengthen education and reminders for actors, and actively guide actors to always respect the legal red line and strictly abide by the moral bottom line. Actors are encouraged to take the initiative to speak out, guide the audience to abide by the management regulations of the performance site, and jointly maintain the order of the performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[超标七千多倍？小心“毒耳环”里的有害元素]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256570]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/Q0cYLBRGe5Z0RfFYjKdB6PdQQ5EScvFfqnc512Pw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Q0cYLBRGe5Z0RfFYjKdB6PdQQ 5EScvFfqnc512Pw. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The production process of simulated jewelry includes design, molding, sand casting, welding, polishing, In many processes such as electroplating, harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead appear to be excessive, in order to make the jewelry more beautiful and cost-effective. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nong Jian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Are you here to touch porcelain?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the south of Beijing In a jewelry store near Luogu Lane, when a Southern Weekend reporter inquired about the origin of the earrings, the name of the manufacturer, and whether there was a quality inspection report, the clerk showed an incredulous expression: &quot;It&#39;s just a few dozen yuan, why do you ask? &quot;It seemed like this was the first time she was asked this question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A wall full of earrings, earrings, and ear clips are packed in small grids, densely packed. Under the spotlight, these imitation jewelry, jade and precious metals made of imitation jewelry reflect brilliant light. When the girl picks them up, she also picks up her imagination of beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But behind the beauty, there may be hidden health risks. Many earrings and other imitation jewelry are &quot;three-no products&quot; - no production date, no quality certificate, no manufacturer, and even harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead exceed the standard. Wearing them may cause &quot;allergy&quot; and threaten your health. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mandatory national standard &quot;Regulations on Limits of Hazardous Elements in Jewelry&quot; (GB 28480-2012) regulates harmful elements in non-precious metals (precious metals mainly refer to 8 metal elements such as gold, silver and platinum group metals) Relevant regulations have been set on the limit. Because piercings are in contact with the human body, earrings are more stringent than jewelry such as necklaces that are in contact with human skin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it has been ten years since the implementation of national standards. Due to high testing costs and lack of mandatory requirements, cases and recalls of alloy earrings and other imitation jewelry containing harmful elements exceeding the standard are still common. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The amount of cadmium released in &quot;hot-selling&quot; earrings exceeds the standard by more than 7,000 times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is the quality of &quot;hot-selling&quot; earrings with a total sales volume of more than 60,000 pieces and an average price of more than five yuan? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, on an e-commerce platform, the non-toxic pioneer team of the environmental organization Shenzhen Zero Waste Environmental Protection Public Welfare Development Center (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;non-toxic pioneer&quot;) placed an order for the top-selling product 10 styles of earrings were sent to a qualified third-party laboratory for testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of these 10 earrings have quality certificates, product names, manufacturer and other information labels. They are &quot;three noes&quot; products and violate the product quality law. The test report even showed that cadmium content in 3 models exceeded the standard by 6808 times, 6872 times, and 7208 times; nickel release in 4 models exceeded the standard by 0.25 times, 0.5 times, 0.5 times, and 1.8 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oYt6uFkA6kDbYxGTmA7M4spKESuOui1aCpS6Apd2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1332&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oYt6uFkA6kDbYxGTmA7M4spKESuOui1aCpS6Apd2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Test results of harmful elements in 10 earrings. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-Toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Non-Toxic Pioneer&quot; reported to the e-commerce platform, 6 products with excessive heavy metals have been downloaded shelf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a customer, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the certificates of other products sold by these merchants. Some said that they “have no quality certificates,” while others claimed that they “have them but it is not convenient to provide them.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for imitation jewelry to contain harmful elements that exceed standards. In 2014, authors from the Zhuhai Quality, Metrology, Supervision and Inspection Institute published a paper stating that after testing 40 pieces of imitation jewelry in Zhuhai’s retail market, 19 items contained excessive levels of harmful elements, indicating “the overall quality problem is very serious.” There is basically no ingredient description on the packaging or markings of jewelry. Even large imitation jewelry processing companies only use names such as &quot;alloy/silver-plated/gold-plated jewelry&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, an author from the Guangdong Product Quality Supervision and Inspection Institute published a paper: 50 batches of simulated jewelry purchased on an online platform and the Guangzhou Jewelry Wholesale Market were tested, and 11 batches of harmful elements exceeded the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing, director of the National Jewelry Quality Inspection and Testing Center, is one of the drafters of the national standard &quot;Regulations on Limits of Hazardous Elements in Jewelry&quot;. She told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2007 and 2010, for domestic imitation jewelry , the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) twice proposed large-scale recalls, which attracted the attention of domestic regulatory authorities and promoted the introduction of national standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country’s supervision of the export of imitation jewelry is also becoming increasingly strict. Starting from January 1, 2011, imitation jewelry has been included in my country&#39;s import and export legal inspection product catalog - the import and export commodities that must be inspected are formulated and adjusted by the national commodity inspection department. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even so, news of recalls of exported jewelry has remained frequent in recent years. On the official website of the &quot;Hebei Provincial Defective Product Recall Management Center&quot;, search with &quot;earrings&quot; as the keyword, from March 2018 to November 2022, there are 62 earring product recall information released by the EU, most of which are produced in China, and the defects are all Excessive levels of harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel or lead. According to statistics from the testing agency &quot;ETC Les Testing&quot;, in the second quarter of 2021, there were 66 recall notifications for imitation jewelry from European countries and Canada, including 41 cases of Chinese jewelry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There is still a lack of quantitative research on the health effects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Many people have this experience. Their skin becomes red or even allergic when wearing jewelry, especially earrings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Environmental Sciences, told Southern Weekend reporters that in addition to being related to personal constitution, another main reason for allergies may be that the amount of nickel released from jewelry exceeds the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jF5c9yTRnuv4kqrnnCTfDps3iCEoNsD9dw89Qzv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jF5c9yTRnuv4kqrnnCTfDps3iCEoNsD9dw89Qzv2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Four earrings that were found to have excessive nickel. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-Toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production process of simulated jewelry includes design, molding, sand casting, welding, polishing, electroplating, etc. Through multiple processes, harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead appear to be excessive, in order to make the jewelry more beautiful and cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hua, a designer at a jewelry factory in the south, said that nickel is mainly produced in the electroplating process. The worse the electroplating process, the lower the cost, and the easier it is to release nickel. Zhang Jinliang said that in the production of jewelry, adding cadmium will increase the gloss and have an anti-rust effect. Adding lead can improve the flexibility of the jewelry and facilitate shaping. Lead and cadmium are also the main components of many pigments. If cheap earrings and other jewelry are rich in color, the content of these two harmful elements is more likely to exceed the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/guumhbZZDicrgBhye5ii4ryU5TZwZspWZmmQXGHl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/guumhbZZDicrgBhye5ii4ryU5TZwZspWZmmQXGHl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Three earrings that were found to have excessive levels of cadmium were all around 7,000 times the standard. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quality of raw materials is also very important. Zhang Jinliang said that the raw materials of some jewelry are scrap metal or low-quality alloys, which are cheap and may cause excessive heavy metal content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The harmful elements in jewelry exceed the standard and will threaten human health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang said that nickel can easily cause skin contact allergies, and long-term exposure to nickel may cause contact dermatitis, neurasthenia, and cancer reactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cadmium has been certified as a carcinogen by the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC), and is listed as the sixth toxic substance harmful to human health by the United Nations Environment Program and the International Committee on Heavy Metals in Occupational Health. Chronic intake may cause high blood pressure, increase a person&#39;s risk of diabetes, and even cause severe bone damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the alloy earrings tested by Non-Toxic Pioneer, 8 models were found to contain lead. Although the content meets the standard, it is still not recommended to wear them. Because lead is a cumulative poison that can enter the human body through the respiratory tract, digestive tract, skin, etc., lead poisoning will occur when the accumulation reaches a certain value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simulation jewelry with substandard quality is more harmful to children’s health. Children like to bite jewelry, and some lead products have a sweet taste. Scientific research has proven that the absorption rate of lead in the respiratory tract and lungs of children is much higher than that of adults. my country and other countries have also specifically set limits on harmful elements for jewelry worn by children ≤14 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there have been cases of recalls of children&#39;s jewelry in recent years. For example, from March 12 to 22, 2021, Health Canada issued 4 recall notices for children&#39;s imitation jewelry, involving 4 products, a total of 3,904 pieces, all produced in China. The reason for the recall was the lead and cadmium content in the products. Exceeds local standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhang Jinliang also said that the toxicity of harmful elements is only a theoretical statement. Heavy metals mainly enter the human body through the respiratory tract and digestive tract, and the skin absorption is relatively small. At present, there is no quantitative research data on the impact of heavy metal exposure in earrings on human health; in addition, the piercing part of earrings has a small contact area with the human body. If the heavy metal exceeds the standard, it may cause some adverse reactions, but the probability of causing heavy metal poisoning is very high. Small, &quot;so there is no need to be too alarmist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang suggested that if you wear earrings and other jewelry for a long time, try to choose precious metals such as gold, silver, and platinum. Their supervision is more standardized and their quality is better. Alloy jewelry with many styles, good shapes and low prices has different usage scenarios from precious metals. You can clean it with alcohol before wearing it, which will help reduce the exposure of heavy metals on the surface of the jewelry. Try not to wear alloy jewelry when exercising, bathing, swimming, etc. , because sweat may increase heavy metal exposure after contact with the alloy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are hidden tricks in the testing industry&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;my country&#39;s imitation jewelry industry started in the 1980s. China is currently the world&#39;s largest exporter of imitation jewelry, forming three major distribution centers in Yiwu, Qingdao and Guangzhou. According to data from Yiwu City, there are more than 300,000 employees in Yiwu&#39;s jewelry industry, with annual sales of more than 20 billion yuan, accounting for more than 2/3 of the total output value of the national jewelry industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gRmBhVAobWJmAbyX2sObDLPh7cQTxyOheciRUyAC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gRmBhVAobWJmAbyX2sObDLPh7cQTxyOheciRUyAC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In November 2017, Qingdao Airport Inspection and Quarantine Bureau and Liuting Airport Customs sampled a batch of incoming imitation jewelry and sent it to the laboratory for testing. The results showed that the sample of imitation jewelry contained lead. More than 30 times more than the standard. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simulated jewelry exported for sale on international e-commerce platforms such as Amazon must provide testing certificates that comply with local standards. For example, the European Union and Amazon require merchants to provide statements or test reports that can prove that products comply with &quot;REACH&quot; (Registration, Evaluation, Authorization and Restriction of Chemicals of the European Parliament and of the Council) regulations, including values ​​for harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many third-party testing companies provide testing services, but a Southern Weekend reporter’s investigation found that there are hidden “tricks” in the testing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter consulted as a jewelry manufacturer and found that the charge for testing the release of cadmium, nickel, and lead is between 500 yuan and 800 yuan per sample, and the time required is about 7 working days. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many imitation jewelry, this testing fee is equivalent to the cost of hundreds of products, so there are &quot;hidden rules&quot; for testing services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s possible to play around with the edges.” The customer service of a testing agency on Taobao said that REACH requires each product to provide a test report, but the agency can only conduct one actual test for multiple jewelry with similar materials, and other &quot; For &quot;Hitchhiking&quot; products that have not been tested, if you replace the photos with them and the test values ​​remain unchanged, you will also have an &quot;exclusive&quot; test report. The above-mentioned customer service stated that the agency can support a maximum of 10 packages for testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customer service of some institutions also introduced the &quot;hidden rules&quot; for packaging and testing in larger quantities. &quot;More than 100 models (packaged for testing) are a bit exaggerated, because export customs clearance and selling on the platform are risky, and the customs and the platform may doubt the authenticity of the test report.&quot; Yang Le, customer service of this testing agency, said to the south A reporter from the weekend said that this kind of demand from customers is very common. &quot;Considering cost issues, it is impossible to test every product, so our customers will put many products together for testing in the name of &#39;series&#39;.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Le said that if jewelry companies are worried that the actual measured harmful elements in their products exceed the standard, they can also provide a &quot;certificate package&quot; service and issue a non-actually measured test report, and the test results can be filled in at will. &quot;This test report must also be uploaded and filed. Although we have not tested it, it is exactly the same as the test report of the actual test.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the premise of &quot;guaranteed certificate&quot; is that the customer needs to sign a contract with the testing agency Disclaimer, exempting the testing company from liability. The disclaimer template sent by Yang Le reads: &quot;In consideration of the time relationship of customer needs, after negotiation between the two parties, the testing agency evaluates and issues certificates and reports according to customer requirements. At the same time, the customer promises that the product is qualified and ensures that the products in the sales market meet the requirements. If there is any non-compliance, the testing agency will not assume any legal responsibility or compensation obligations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Le said that the fee for &quot;package certificate&quot; and packaged testing of multiple products are the same, both 700 yuan. Since the &quot;certificate package&quot; does not require actual testing, it only takes 5 working days to complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New standards are being revised&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Similar to most products, the supervision of imitation jewelry is based on laws and regulations such as the Product Quality Law and the Import and Export Commodity Inspection Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Product Quality Law stipulates that producers shall be responsible for the quality of the products they produce; if there are national standards and industry standards to protect human health and personal and property safety, product quality shall comply with such standards. Li Suqing said that the simulation jewelry produced and sold by merchants must meet the national standard requirements, but when it is launched in the country, it is not required to undergo compulsory product certification like food, home appliances and other consumer goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, home appliances must obtain &quot;3C Certification&quot; (China Compulsory Certification, China Compulsory Product Certification) before they can be put on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing believes that if imitation jewelry is included in the 3C compulsory catalog, there will be difficulties and controversy. For earrings that sell for a few yuan, it is unrealistic to ask merchants to spend hundreds of yuan to detect harmful elements. &quot;It will not only increase the costs for merchants and consumers, but also increase the cost of law enforcement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market supervision department mainly adopts random inspections to supervise imitation jewelry. For example, Yiwu City has carried out several special rectifications on alloy jewelry and carried out supervision and spot inspections on an annual basis. The 17 batches of products randomly inspected in 2022 were all qualified after being tested by third-party testing agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, whether simulated jewelry is sent for inspection mainly depends on customer demand. &quot;Many customers do not need test reports because it will increase costs.&quot; Li Hua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior person in the testing industry told Southern Weekend reporters that in China, e-commerce platforms such as Tmall and JD.com and some large supermarkets will require merchants to provide quality inspection reports for jewelry, but some e-commerce platforms Commercial platforms and many offline sales venues do not require this. Li Benben, communications director of the Shenzhen Zero Waste Environmental Protection Public Welfare Development Center, said that Toxic-Free Pioneer plans to collect more earring samples from multiple e-commerce platforms in 2024 to investigate product quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing suggested that to improve the qualification rate of imitation jewelry, the illegal costs of enterprises must be increased. According to public information, few jewelry manufacturers have been punished for substandard harmful elements in their products. The Product Quality Law stipulates that those who produce or sell products that do not meet the national standards for protecting human health and personal and property safety may be fined not less than three times the value of the illegally produced or sold products; if the circumstances are serious, the product may be revoked. Business license; if it constitutes a crime, criminal liability will be pursued in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shapes of earrings and other accessories are becoming more and more complex, and the ingredients are not only simulated metals, but also textiles and even batteries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing revealed that the national standard promulgated 11 years ago is being revised. The new version of the national standard in terms of chemical properties may further tighten the limit requirements on lead content; it may also add some requirements on mechanical and physical properties. For example, there are certain regulations on the position of jewelry needle tips and battery-containing jewelry. The specific changes will be subject to the final standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Li Hua and Yang Le are pseudonyms, Southern Weekend intern Liang Chengyuan also contributed)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公职人员做发型被拒，税务局翌日上门查税：这样的营商环境如何让人安心丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256530]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a woman in Tancheng County, Linyi City, Shandong Province threatened a barber shop by showing photos of her uniform, which became a trend on social media. Search. On September 8, the Tancheng County Joint Investigation Team reported that the woman was a staff member of the County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, and she was given a major demerit. This incident cannot be taken lightly, because it is not just a matter of &quot;the low quality of individual public officials&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to an interview with Mr. Xu, the owner of the barber shop, by Chinese Business Daily, Dafeng News and other media, on August 30, the woman came to the shop to do a &quot;protein correction&quot; hair care project. The hairstylist assessed her hair and said her hair was too dry to do the job. As a result, the woman showed the &quot;uniform photo&quot; on her mobile phone and threatened to &quot;call people from our brigade to come (investigate and deal with the case).&quot; Mr. Xu thought she was just saying harsh words to scare people, but he didn’t expect that tax bureau personnel would come to check the tax the next day. After confirming that there was no tax evasion problem in the barber shop, they would also ask for every account of Charlie’s hair shop since it opened. Mr. Xu was so angry that he posted the surveillance video online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens have speculated who this woman is. She can easily mobilize the tax bureau to investigate taxes if she is unhappy. However, both the Tancheng County Taxation Bureau and the Market Supervision Bureau denied that the woman was their staff. After the video attracted attention online, on September 6, two men who claimed to be the woman&#39;s colleagues went to the barber shop to apologize to the owner, but still did not reveal what company she worked for. It was not until this incident became more and more intense online that Tancheng County issued a notice in the name of the joint investigation team on September 8, confirming that the woman was Wang Moumou, a staff member of the county&#39;s Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What this Wang Moumou did reminds people of the &quot;borrowed personnel&quot; of a certain district transportation bureau in Harbin more than a year ago. Because the online ride-hailing driver refused to allow him to smoke in the car, he called the &quot;brothers&quot; from the Transportation Bureau to check on illegal cars and &quot;deal with&quot; the online ride-hailing driver. Why do public officials dare to call &quot;brothers&quot; to inspect cars when they are not performing official duties, or threaten barbershops by showing photos of themselves in uniform? I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s still a sense of superiority: If you don&#39;t follow my requirements, I can punish you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the one from Harbin is from the Transportation Bureau (although he is &quot;borrowed&quot;) and has the power to investigate and deal with illegally operated vehicles, so he can &quot;handle&quot; online ride-hailing drivers. And this Wang Moumou from Tancheng is from the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. How could Wang Moumou mobilize the tax bureau to investigate taxes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Tancheng County’s official announcement, she called the 12345 citizen hotline to report the incident. However, most netizens are skeptical about this. After the woman made the threat, the tax bureau came to inspect the tax the next day. Moreover, after the tax bureau confirmed that the barber shop had just opened for a few months and had not yet reached the tax filing period and that there was no tax evasion problem, it also demanded every account from Charlie&#39;s hair shop since its opening on the grounds that the whistleblower was not satisfied. If an ordinary citizen calls the hotline to report, will the tax bureau respond so quickly? Will every account within a few months be verified after confirming that there is no tax evasion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens’ doubts are not unreasonable. Why is the tax bureau so concerned about such a report? Relevant parties in Tancheng County should disclose Wang&#39;s phone recordings or online reporting records to clarify the facts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to showing off his power and threatening the store, netizens also suspected that Wang Moumou was absent from work at will. According to video surveillance, the incident occurred at about 9:40 a.m. on August 30. Tancheng County did not explain in its report why Wang Moumou could go to the barber shop to have his hair done on Wednesday morning. Does the Agricultural and Rural Affairs Bureau&#39;s &quot;lax management of staff&quot; mentioned in the bulletin include its lax management of attendance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this incident are public concerns about the local business environment. Just imagine, an ordinary public official can show off his power and threaten, and he can torment operators at will with just a phone call. Who would dare to come here to invest and start a business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, the investigation and processing results reported by the Tancheng County Joint Investigation Team may be difficult to eliminate public doubts about the local business environment. In an interview with CCTV, the barber shop owner said that he &quot;hopes that the normal operation of the barber shop will not be affected in the future.&quot; This also shows that he is still worried about whether he can operate normally in the future and whether he will be retaliated against again. Relevant parties in Tancheng need to disclose the incident more transparently, and at the same time introduce corresponding measures to prevent merchants operating normally from being unreasonably tortured just because of a &quot;reporting phone number.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[IPO收紧撤单潮起：36起超370亿募资喊停]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256518]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since the China Securities Regulatory Commission made it clear at the end of August that it would tighten IPOs in stages, the long-rumored market listing has become more difficult. It started slowly but gradually became solid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comprehensive interviews and research by reporters from the 21st Century Business Herald found that, in fact, as early as July 24, when the Political Bureau meeting of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China first proposed &quot;activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence,&quot; IPOs had already become obvious. Be strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind data statistics, from July 24 to September 10, a total of 36 companies planning to IPO on the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges withdrew or terminated their registration. Among them, there are up to 18 companies on the GEM, 4 on the Science and Technology Innovation Board, 11 on the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board, and 3 on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange Main Board, raising a total of 37.814 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5a2dfc0c3241535e10176d2e83b60319.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5a2dfc0c3241535e10176d2e83b60319.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250411&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;The net profit threshold for listing is raised&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A senior insurance agent of a leading brokerage firm who has been in the industry for nearly 20 years told reporters that whenever IPOs are tightened, net profit often becomes a &quot;hard indicator&quot; for listing, and various sectors have The requirements for net profit bottom line have increased. Today, this situation appears again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, the main board could achieve success with a net profit of 80 million yuan, but now it is basically hopeless if it is less than 100 million yuan. It was more likely that the GEM would be listed at 60 million yuan last year, but now it is almost impossible to achieve less than 80 million yuan. . The fifth set of standards for the Science and Technology Innovation Board has been suspended. Once there is a large loss, even hard-core technology companies will not be able to go public. For companies with technological attributes but not hard enough, as long as they suffer losses, the listing process is likely to be blocked. Moreover, each sector has a negative impact on the listing process. The net profit requirement is not only for the most recent fiscal year. If there has been substandard performance or performance decline in recent years, sustainable profitability will be questioned, and it is also likely to be stopped.&quot; The above-mentioned Baodai told reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Wind data, the statement of the senior insurance agent has been confirmed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From July 24th to September 10th, a total of three companies on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange main board withdrew, two of which had a net profit of less than 90 million yuan; although the other one had a net profit of 122 million yuan in 2022, it will not be listed in 2021. The annual net profit was only 94 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 20.39%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 11 companies withdrew from the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board, 4 had net profits of less than 90 million yuan last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 18 companies withdrawn from the GEM, 12 will have a net profit of less than 80 million yuan in 2022, accounting for as high as 66.67%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of the four companies withdrawn from the Science and Technology Innovation Board, three have suffered losses in the past two years. Among them, Shugen Internet Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Sroot Internet&quot;), a hard-core technology company focusing on software applications, has no choice but to withdraw. Its losses since 2021 have been more than 700 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For a hard technology company like Shugen Internet, which has suffered huge losses year after year, it is naturally impossible for it to be listed on the main board or GEM. However, it has stepped on the industry trend supported by policies and placed itself on the During the loose period of IPO, it was possible to rush forward according to the fifth set of standards of the Science and Technology Innovation Board, but now that the fifth set of standards is suspended, its listing process can only come to an end.&quot; Baodai said bluntly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the fifth set of standards of the Science and Technology Innovation Board is not universal, but a green channel specially opened for star companies in special industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the requirements, companies that meet the fifth set of standards need to &quot;break through key core technologies and possess original leading technologies.&quot; Such companies may be listed on the Science and Technology Innovation Board even if they are in the research and development stage without generating revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Baodai said, the fifth set of standards is now suspended, which means that regardless of the technological attributes of a company, if it wants to go public, it must not suffer a significant loss, and must even maintain a stable net profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For companies, it will be more difficult to go public and subsequent financing will become more difficult; for investment banks, the number of projects that can be sponsored will decrease and underwriting income will decline. Naturally, they will suffer losses and do not want to see it. &quot;Another industry insider told reporters, &quot;But for investors, it is a kind of protection. Excluding loss-making companies and companies with relatively low profitability from the stock market will, on the one hand, effectively improve the quality of newly listed companies. It helps investors select high-quality stocks; on the other hand, it forces more funds to flow into existing stocks, which helps stabilize stock prices.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/12/e594ea773537f379c1452f71c5c2b28e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e594ea773537f379c1452f71c5c2b28e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; Image source: Visual China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Capital-driven companies have little hope of going public&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to investment bank insurance agents, in addition to the increase in net profit requirements, the number of years on the market is also a factor in whether a company can succeed. IPO assessment factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The purpose of assessing the number of years on the market is to determine whether the company is capital-driven.” An investment bank insurance agent told reporters. At present, in addition to emerging fields, hard technology and other industries, regulators expect listed companies to be established for more than ten or even twenty years, rely on their own strength to become stronger and bigger, and become leaders in subdivided industries before listing. Instead of relying on multiple rounds of financing driven by capital, IPO can be achieved in just a few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this is that the insurance agent believes that there are two main points: on the one hand, from the perspective of the purpose of listing, compared with companies that have been operating for many years and then apply for listing, companies that have been established for a shorter period of time and rely on capital to promote, After listing, there is a greater probability that relevant shareholders will reduce their holdings and cash out. On the other hand, companies that have been established for a longer time are more likely to enter the maturity stage, have more stable operating performance, and have relatively less risk of performance changes after listing, which is more conducive to safeguarding the interests of investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind, as of September 10, among the 36 IPO projects that have been withdrawn since July 24, 7 projects are located in companies that have been established within 10 years, and 5 were established in 2016 or 2017. Newly established in the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Zhejiang Tongfute Meike Household Products Co., Ltd., which was established in 2017 and plans to be listed on the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange, has performed well in terms of operating income and net profit in recent years. A net profit of 126 million yuan was achieved in 2021, and the net profit in the first half of last year reached 97 million yuan; operating income is also relatively high, with operating income of 1.948 billion yuan for the whole year of 2021, and operating income from January to June 2022 totaling 916 million yuan. Since 2020, operating income and net profit have increased by more than 20% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the above-mentioned insurance agent also mentioned that the age of establishment is an important factor in whether a company can successfully IPO, but it is not an absolute factor. If the company has good quality, stable ability to continue operating, and broad prospects in the field, even if it is only established for In a few years, there is also the possibility of going public. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Food, clothing, housing, and pharmaceutical companies concentrated on withdrawing orders&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-August, there was news in the market that there was basically no hope of IPO listing of new shares of food, clothing, housing, and housing companies. At that time, the relevant cancellation data was not yet clear. Now, this statement is gradually supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind, from September 4th to 6th, three food companies stopped IPOing, one of which has a net profit of over 100 million since 2021 and continues to grow. If the statistical time is advanced to August 14, the number of food, clothing and housing companies that have been forced to terminate the IPO process will reach 7. All seven companies plan to list on the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July 24, a total of 11 companies have withdrawn orders from the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board. This means that among the companies with orders withdrawn from the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange, companies related to food, clothing and housing account for more than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Ocean Family (Zhejiang) Co., Ltd., which terminated its IPO on August 14, was established in 2009. Since 2020, its net profit has been the lowest at 198 million yuan and operating income at the lowest at 1.835 billion yuan. Its performance far exceeds Motherboard profit requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that, judging from the industries of the companies that have withdrawn orders, in addition to clothing, food and housing companies, pharmaceutical companies with good operating performance and longer establishment years also have relatively more cancellations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July 24, a total of four pharmaceutical manufacturing companies have terminated the IPO process. Among them, Fujian Mindong Lijiexun Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., which is preparing for the GEM, was established in 1997. From 2020 to 2022, its net profits were 87 million yuan, 73 million yuan and 98 million yuan respectively, far exceeding those on the GEM. Profit requirements, wipe existing profit standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianjin Tongrentang, a time-honored brand in the traditional Chinese medicine industry founded in 1981, also failed to go public as expected. Its operating income and net profit have increased year by year since 2020. From January to June this year, operating income and net profit have reached 577 million yuan and 144 million yuan respectively, which is several times higher than the profit requirements of the GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[抗癌且延寿——裸鼹鼠体内的神奇能力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256544]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Both ancient and modern people, most people hope to be healthy and live a long life. The ancients made elixirs to seek the elixir of immortality, while modern scientists explore the secrets of longevity from animals. For example, scientists have discovered something that people have long dreamed of in the naked mole rat, a rodent with sparse hair and wrinkled skin that likes to live on the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This amazing story began ten years ago. Ten years ago, researchers at the University of Rochester announced on the website of Nature that they had discovered an anti-cancer ingredient, high molecular weight hyaluronic acid (HMW-HA), from naked mole rats. Ten years have passed, and on August 23, 2023, the team once again published a more interesting study on the &quot;Nature&quot; magazine website. They found a gene responsible for making high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid and transferred it into mice. As a result, the mice&#39;s health improved, they had significant anti-tumor properties, and their lifespans were extended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/mTnNMgewFJdbzlzWoxQSrfgbcH7NnQM7lEHNpH5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1231&quot; height= &quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/mTnNMgewFJdbzlzWoxQSrfgbcH7NnQM7lEHNpH5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The long-lived and cancer-resistant naked mole rat. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Amazing abilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;University of Rochester Biology The reason why Professors Vera Gorbunova and Andrei Seluanov studied naked mole rats was not their initial interest in the longevity characteristics of naked mole rats, but their innate Anti-cancer mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mice and rats are the most common experimental animals, but their life span is generally only 3-4 years, and the incidence of tumors is relatively high, so they cannot be used to study anti-cancer mechanisms. Therefore, Professor Gerbunova The Rochester research team, co-led by Professor Seluan Ruf, focused their attention on naked mole rats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The naked mole rat is a magical rodent that is native to Africa. It lives underground most of the time and feeds mainly on ants and other insects. Compared with common rodents such as mice and rats, naked mole rats have sparse body hair, exposed flesh-colored skin, and are not good-looking. What interests biologists is that naked mole rats have a long lifespan. Their lifespan can reach 30-40 years, which is more than 10 times that of rodents of the same size. Not only do naked mole rats live long lives, they also have extraordinary cancer-fighting abilities. According to scientists’ years of observations of large naked mole rat groups, naturally occurring cancer has not been observed in naked mole rats, and it is difficult to induce cancer in them through experiments. This makes naked mole rats a prime candidate for scientists to study new anti-cancer methods. Ideal animal model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are naked mole rats not prone to cancer? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous studies, the Rochester research team found that naked mole rat cells have the ability to inhibit early contact. Contact inhibition is a powerful anticancer mechanism. Normally, when cells come into contact with each other, receptors on the cell surface sense other cells and send a &quot;brake&quot; signal to the interior of the cell to prevent the cell from continuing to grow. However, this mechanism fails in cancer cells. As a result, cancer cells cannot be suppressed even under high-density conditions, and continue to grow wildly until they accumulate into multi-layered lesions. Naked mole rat cells will show contact inhibition at lower densities, while mouse cells need to reach more than three times the concentration of naked mole rat cells to show similar contact inhibition. Therefore, the research team believes that naked mole rats have Early contact inhibition, while other mammalian cells such as mice only have conventional contact inhibition capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how does early contact inhibition develop in naked mole rats? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers found that the protein kinase inhibitor P16 mediated early contact inhibition in naked mole rat cells, while the protein kinase inhibitor P27 mediated regular contact inhibition in other mammalian cells. When P16 mutates and loses its normal function, the early contact inhibition mechanism of naked mole rat cells will be destroyed, and only conventional contact inhibition can be performed, making malignant transformation and even cancer more likely to occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This study did not attract much attention, but it opened the door for the Rochester research team to study the anti-cancer mechanism of naked mole rats. Even greater discoveries are yet to come. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cancer-fighting genes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Rochester research team continues to observe the growth of naked mole rat cells and compare them with mammals such as humans, guinea pigs and mice. Comparing the cells, they found that compared to other mammalian cells, the naked mole rat cells in the dish quickly became viscous, like syrup. After analysis, scientists found that naked mole rat cells secrete large amounts of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hyaluronic acid is an acidic mucopolysaccharide, also known as hyaluronic acid. Hyaluronic acid is commonly found in mammalian skin, cartilage, and other connective tissues and is widely used in pharmaceutical products and cosmetics. Hyaluronic acid mainly acts as a filler and support between animal cells. According to the molecular weight, hyaluronic acid can generally be divided into high molecular weight hyaluronic acid and low molecular weight hyaluronic acid. The hyaluronic acid secreted by naked mole rat cells is mainly high molecular weight and is secreted by other mammals such as humans, mice and guinea pigs. 2-5 times the molecular weight of hyaluronic acid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through further research and analysis, the Rochester research team found that high molecular weight hyaluronic acid is a key extracellular signal for the formation of early contact inhibition in naked mole rat cells, that is, these cells secrete large amounts of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid to cause It floods between cells and forms physical constraints. Naked mole rat cells sense the hyaluronic acid signal secreted by the other party and their growth slows down. Therefore, they can undergo contact inhibition earlier than other mammalian cells and are less likely to undergo cancer. of crazy growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can naked mole rat cells alone secrete large amounts of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that in vertebrate cells, there are three types of hyaluronic acid synthases responsible for producing high molecular weight hyaluronic acid, including HAS1, HAS2 and HAS3. Among them, HAS1 and HAS3 have nothing in various mammals. The difference is that only the HAS2 molecule has undergone important mutations in naked mole rats. The HAS2 molecule consists of 552 amino acids, and these amino acid sequences are highly conserved in other mammals, but the naked mole rat version has two key amino acid substitutions. This mutation causes naked mole rat cells to secrete large amounts of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid. At the same time, the hyaluronic acid-degrading enzyme activity of naked mole rat cells is also much lower than that of other mammals, resulting in slower degradation of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid. Once the HAS2 gene of naked mole rat cells is destroyed through genetic engineering technology, or the hyaluronic acid degrading enzyme is over-synthesized, the high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in the genetically modified naked mole rat will be greatly reduced, and its early contact inhibition function will be reduced. Along with the loss, these naked mole rats are also prone to induce tumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These studies prove that high molecular weight hyaluronic acid is a unique anti-cancer factor in naked mole rats and will bring new ways to prevent cancer. In July 2013, this research was published in the internationally renowned academic journal &quot;Nature&quot;. This was also the first time that the research team of Professor Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf published a paper in the &quot;Nature&quot; magazine. In this paper, they also transferred the HAS2 gene from naked mole rats into human cells and observed that the transgenic human cells could also synthesize high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid in large quantities, laying the foundation for another blockbuster study ten years later. A foreshadowing was made. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Double surprise&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since naked mole rats are less susceptible to cancer under the protection of rich high molecular weight hyaluronic acid, if other mammals can also Can synthetic high molecular weight hyaluronic acid reproduce the anti-cancer and life-extending effects seen in naked mole rats? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the ultimate goal of the research team of Professors Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf is to find anti-cancer and life-extending drugs for humans, it is obviously not suitable to directly use them in human trials when the research is not yet mature. Research on human cells cannot completely simulate the effects on the human body, so trying it on mice first is a very good choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research idea and process are simple, but the results are surprising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team of Professors Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf transferred the HAS2 gene, which is responsible for the production of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid, into mice to create transgenic mice. It was found that these transgenic mice The content of hyaluronic acid increased significantly, especially high molecular weight hyaluronic acid was detected in organs such as muscle, heart, kidney and small intestine. However, the hyaluronic acid content in the transgenic mice was not as high as that in the naked mole rats. The researchers speculated that it may be mainly because the hyaluronic acid-degrading enzyme in the mice is more active than in the naked mole rats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further observation found that the incidence of spontaneous tumors in these transgenic mice was significantly reduced, and they were significantly resistant to artificially induced tumors. Regardless of whether they are transgenic mice or non-transgenic control mice, they all age naturally, and most of them eventually die of tumors. Among them, the tumor incidence rate of control mice was 70%, while that of transgenic mice was only 57%. When the mice lived for more than 27 months, the anti-tumor properties of transgenic mice were more significant, and their spontaneous tumor incidence rate was only 49%, while In control mice, it was as high as 83%. When the researchers induced skin papillomas in mice, the incidence of papillomas in the transgenic mice was also much lower than that in the control mice, indicating that the transgenic mice were also significantly resistant to artificially induced tumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even more surprisingly, the transgenic mice also showed extended lifespan and improved health. Relative to control mice, the median lifespan of transgenic mice increased by 4.4%, while the maximum lifespan increased by 12.2%. At the same time, the researchers also conducted a physical examination on the mice participating in the experiment and found that the overall health of the transgenic mice was significantly better than that of the control mice. Especially during the aging process, the inflammation in most organs of transgenic mice was significantly less than that of control mice, and inflammation is an important indicator of organ aging, and the intestinal health of transgenic mice was also significantly improved. Further analysis found that the high molecular weight hyaluronic acid possessed by transgenic mice can reduce inflammatory responses through multiple pathways, including direct immunomodulatory effects on immune cells, protection from oxidative stress, and improvement of intestinal barrier function during aging. etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research lays the foundation for the application of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in human clinical trials, and also brings new hope for the development of anti-cancer and life-extending drugs or treatments. On August 23, 2023, the research team of Professors Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf published the results of this research on the website of &quot;Nature&quot; magazine. It took a full 10 years from the discovery of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in naked mole rats to proving that it can improve the health of mammals, which reflects the difficulty of basic research and also reflects the efforts of Professor Gerbunova and Serouanlu. This is the reward for the long-term efforts of Professor Hu’s research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the team also plans to conduct human clinical trials, hoping to achieve the goals of both anti-cancer and extending lifespan by increasing the synthesis of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid in the body or slowing down its degradation. The miraculous anti-cancer and life-extending benefits of the body are brought to humans, opening up a new way for human health and longevity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人寿保险（集团）公司原董事长王滨一审被判死缓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256536]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/93c908a94264080cab76402e2672ddba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;3909&quot; height=&quot;2827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/12/93c908a94264080cab76402e2672ddba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Jinan City, Shandong Province publicly pronounced the verdict of the former Party Committee of China Life Insurance (Group) Company In the case of Secretary and Chairman Wang Bin accepting bribes and concealing overseas deposits, the defendant Wang Bin was sentenced to death for accepting bribes, with a two-year suspended execution, deprived of political rights for life, and all personal property was confiscated, and his death penalty was suspended for two years. After the sentence is commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he will be sentenced to life imprisonment without the possibility of commutation or parole. He will be sentenced to one year in prison for concealing overseas deposits. It is decided to execute the death penalty with a two-year suspended sentence. He will be deprived of political rights for life and all personal property will be confiscated. After the two-year suspension of execution of the death penalty is commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he will be imprisoned for life without commutation or parole; the property and accrued property obtained by Wang Bin from bribery that have been seized, detained, and frozen will be recovered and turned over to the state treasury. The remaining portion will continue to be used. Recover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/174fe68c179a8af032bfcdd04fb3ffe6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4635&quot; height=&quot;2566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/174fe68c179a8af032bfcdd04fb3ffe6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250450&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 1997 to 2021, the defendant Wang Binli served as the deputy secretary of the party group and deputy president of the Jiangxi Branch of the Agricultural Development Bank of China, the party committee secretary and president of the Beijing Branch of the Bank of Communications, and the president of the Bank of Communications. Member of the Party Committee and Vice President, Chairman of BoCom International Trust Co., Ltd., Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of China Taiping Insurance Group Co., Ltd., Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of China Life Insurance (Group) Company and Chairman of China Guangfa Bank, etc. Facilitation and the formation of convenient conditions of authority and status provide assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as loan financing, project cooperation, personnel arrangements, etc. I have illegally received property directly or through my relatives, totaling more than RMB 325 million. Starting from January 2012, Wang Bin violated the national foreign exchange control system and the overseas deposit declaration system for state personnel by depositing a total of more than 56.42 million yuan in foreign currency into bank and securities accounts opened by his relatives in Hong Kong, without concealing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jinan Intermediate People’s Court held that defendant Wang Bin’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes and concealing overseas deposits. The amount of bribes Wang Bin accepted was particularly huge, the circumstances of the crime were particularly serious, the social impact was particularly bad, and the interests of the country and the people suffered particularly heavy losses. He should be sentenced to death for the crime; Wang Bin committed the crime of concealing overseas deposits and surrendered, so he may be given a lighter punishment and be separated from the people he belongs to. The crime of accepting bribes shall also be punished. Since Wang Bin truthfully confessed his crimes after being brought to justice, confessed and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods, he had legal and discretionary circumstances for lenient punishment. He was sentenced to death, but it may not be executed immediately. At the same time, based on the facts and circumstances of Wang Bin&#39;s crime, it was decided that after the expiration of the two-year suspension of his death sentence, which would be commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he would be imprisoned for life without commutation or parole. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[学生不订牛奶要医院证明：别都把锅甩在老师身上丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256542]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news about “teacher asking students to order milk” has attracted attention. On September 7, parents in Suiping County, Zhumadian, Henan Province broke the news that a primary school teacher posted a message about students ordering milk. A screenshot of the chat in the online post showed that a teacher sent a message saying that if a child cannot drink school milk due to a certain disease, Parents need to provide proof of diagnosis and treatment from a county hospital or above medical institution. The teacher also said that there are 53 students in the class, 15 of whom have completed the registration process, and he hopes that the parents of the remaining 38 students will &quot;actively cooperate with the work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This news triggered a wave of public opinion as soon as it was exposed. The teacher&#39;s words are suspected of &quot;forced ordering of milk&quot;, which seems to be &quot;unsightly&quot;. The style of &quot;forced buying and selling&quot; has also aroused doubts and ridicule from netizens, awakening everyone to &quot;order milk&quot; and &quot;order teaching materials&quot;. &quot;Childhood memories&quot; of ordering designated books. In particular, the words &quot;unless you prove to be sick, you must order milk&quot; and &quot;do you expect the teacher to treat 53 children equally&quot; were even threatening, which attracted a lot of negative comments from the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant departments in Suiping County stated on September 8 that the County Education Bureau had investigated clearly on the 7th that the matter was the &quot;personal behavior&quot; of a class teacher at the Central Primary School in Shenzhai Town, Suiping County. &quot;Medical Certificate&quot; is also an inappropriate statement by the teacher personally. At the same time, only this class has mandatory requirements, and other classes are voluntary. At present, the county education bureau has criticized the teacher and asked the teacher to apologize to the parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the only &quot;milk ordering incident&quot; in Zhumadian recently. On September 7, a parent in Zhengyang County broke the news that a primary school teacher said that he &quot;actively orders if there are conditions, but creates conditions to order if there are no conditions.&quot; Judging from the screenshots of the WeChat group posted online, the teacher posted &quot;Milk Man&quot; in the WeChat group Everyone needs to order!&quot; message, and said that &quot;taking into account the financial pressure of parents&quot;, the &quot;milk ordering quota&quot; for each semester has changed from the original &quot;440 yuan for a full portion of 4 boxes&quot; to &quot;per school consultation&quot;. People only order 3 boxes for a total of 330 yuan.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 8, the principal of the school said that ordering milk was on a voluntary basis, and the teacher’s wording was wrong, and a meeting would be held again to study it; a staff member of the local education bureau said that the higher-level department required ordering milk for the healthy growth of students. , but following the principle of parent voluntariness; the Education Bureau stated in a briefing on September 8 that the problems reported by netizens were basically true, and that the class had deviations in its interpretation of the spirit of superior documents and was suspected of violating the principle of voluntary subscription, so it would immediately suspend the promotion of drinking milk. work, rectify and standardize it, and investigate and deal with relevant responsible personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost at the same time, two &quot;personal acts&quot; of teachers forcing students to order milk occurred in Zhumadian. Looking at the timeline of the two incidents, it can be said that they are similar; the same trend followed. The &quot;mandatory ordering of milk&quot; was considered to be the teacher&#39;s &quot;personal behavior&quot;. At the same time, it was insisted that the milk ordering work for students followed the principle of voluntariness. However, upon careful review of these two incidents, there are still some questions that need to be analyzed and questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, when teachers ask students to order milk, is it really their &quot;personal behavior&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the screenshots exposed in the two incidents, the Zhengyang County teacher mentioned that &quot;after consultation with the school&quot;, the Zhengyang County Education Bureau clearly stated in the briefing that this was a &quot;deviation in interpretation&quot; of &quot;superior documents&quot;. Without these &quot;documents&quot; being suppressed, what motivation would a mere elementary school teacher have to turn into a salesman? Why would there be any need to issue vague intimidation and inducement to many parents such as &quot;create conditions if there are no conditions&quot; and &quot;order milk if you are not sick&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the two incidents, if the teacher risked misinterpreting superior documents to do something that prompted parents to report it, what was the purpose behind it? If there is no profit motive to support it, the argument of &quot;personal behavior&quot; will obviously be more difficult to establish. In the case of conflicts between &quot;superior documents&quot; and &quot;voluntary principles&quot;, how can teachers grasp &quot;personal behavior&quot; in order to satisfy both superiors and parents at the same time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary for the education department to publish the original text of the &quot;superior document&quot; originally issued, or to announce to the public what the specific instructions for the &quot;project&quot; of milk subscription are, so that it can be clearer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the two &quot;forced milk ordering&quot; incidents also show that grassroots teachers bear too many non-teaching burdens in their daily work, which is a major root cause of many similar incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the current education system, teachers, as actual grassroots personnel and the end of the power chain, have a rather embarrassing situation of &quot;little power but big responsibility&quot;: this &quot;responsibility&quot; is to be responsible to the superiors, not to the superiors. Responsible to parents and students; the &quot;higher-level departments&quot; are responsible for issuing instructions and issuing notices, but in practice they have &quot;great power but little responsibility&quot;. They have great power but are not responsible for students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, grassroots teachers have taken on too many additional tasks that are not part of teaching. The DingTalk group on the left, the WeChat group on the right, check-in today, receipt tomorrow, cultural performance here, textbook subscription there, resulting in a considerable amount of time and energy being occupied by non-teaching tasks, seriously affecting the duties of teaching and educating people. Even grassroots teachers often have to transmit top-down pressure to parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take these two incidents as an example. Regardless of whether the subscription of milk for students is reasonable or not, this task should not be left to teachers in the first place. There are a lot of administrative staff in the education system. It would undoubtedly be much better for them to be responsible for taking care of students&#39; health and choosing better dairy products than to impose an irrelevant responsibility on teachers out of thin air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers in primary and secondary schools should be freed from the imposed non-educational burdens, focus on teaching and educating people, and better serve students rather than superiors. Otherwise, teachers will be allowed to do all kinds of things if nothing happens. When something has nothing to do with teaching, it is regarded as &quot;teacher&#39;s personal behavior&quot;. This is too bullying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“骂醒恋爱脑”服务：当情感变成生意，爱真的能骂醒吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256554]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvljJ6IFmUtgobDkg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;950&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvlj J6IFmUtgobDkg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The TV series &quot;Xue Pinggui and Wang Baochuan&quot; broadcast in 2012 has recently been reinterpreted by netizens. The plot In the novel, Wang Baochuan and Xue Pinggui ate wild vegetables to satisfy their hunger for eighteen years, and are known as the &quot;originators of the love brain&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Come on, how do you want to scold me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just joined the Southern Weekend reporter Go to a friend and Z sends a message in the chat box. After confirming the request of &quot;be more direct&quot; and &quot;don&#39;t use curse words&quot;, without even asking about the gender, Z began to type:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She doesn&#39;t love you, why do you love her?&quot; , no one wants to talk to you, but you still act like an ATM machine?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Followed by a yin and yang emoticon, and then asked politely: &quot;Do you listen? If not, I will change it. species.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z asked about the specific situation only after the Southern Weekend reporter informed him of his gender and gave a negative answer. In this chat world, the Southern Weekend reporter is a &quot;love brain&quot; who gave up the postgraduate entrance examination for her boyfriend. Now she is deeply in the pain of &quot;being broken up&quot; and longs to be &quot;scolded to wake up&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, why keep it and give him money to fall in love?&quot; After listening to this &quot;story&quot;, Z tried his best to persuade him to break up and launched a series of questions: &quot;Why don&#39;t you understand, why are you still looking forward to it?&quot; , Why should you expect from him, he is handsome? Rich? Will he be gentle to you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paying money to scold you may sound a bit unbelievable. Around Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, this service, known as &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain,&quot; became a booming business on e-commerce platforms, and then became popular on social platforms such as Xiaohongshu and Douyin. Many users took orders on their own and paid for scolding. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;767&quot; height= &quot;1695&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In a Taobao store with over 10,000 sales, a Southern Weekend reporter ordered the &quot;Scolding to Wake Up Your Love Brain&quot; service. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Rongrong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who originally coined the term &quot;love brain&quot; may not have expected that after countless interpretations , spread, this label may make some people who are already in emotional struggle more suffering, intensify their self-denial, and even declare it to the people around them becomes difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, with the release of the movie &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot; and the launch of the TV series &quot;My Earthly Fireworks&quot;, the protagonist&#39;s series of &quot;love brain&quot; behaviors aroused active discussion among the audience. Nowadays, &quot;anti-love brain&quot; has evolved from a word of mouth to a business, and many people who are stuck in the mud are reaching out, eager for some stranger to pull them out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can find many stores that provide services by searching for &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; on Taobao. In a Taobao store with tens of thousands of sales, different levels of escorts correspond to different prices. The Southern Weekend reporter selected a &quot;blind box&quot; that could only specify gender, and was assigned female escort Z. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z provides services using WeChat text or voice, charging 15 yuan for 20 minutes. Her avatar is that of a beautiful female Internet celebrity, and her circle of friends looks very life-like, sharing her feelings and thoughts. In this short chat, Z left a motto: &quot;Put away your tears, no one will like a girl who likes to cry, and he will not feel sorry for you crying.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Southern Weekend After the reporter expressed the pain of not being able to escape, Z persuaded him to &quot;put a filter on him&quot; and &quot;sick&quot;, and then reminded him that the time was up. Z started timing the moment he added a friend, regardless of the fact that the conversation actually started five minutes later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You can do it, believe me. All the love brains I talked to before said it&#39;s okay.&quot; The 15 yuan service came to an abrupt end. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Take the initiative to place an order, &quot;Love Brain&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Qing&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Half awake&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the store owner Li On the price list provided by Yu, the large characters &quot;Eliminate Love Brain&quot; are very eye-catching on the pink background, and a line of small characters underneath reads: &quot;Online guidance from the emotional master&quot;. The price list shows that &quot;Love Brain&quot; is divided into three levels: light, medium and heavy. Customers can choose according to their own level. The service time of an escort ranges from 15 minutes to 1 hour, and the price ranges from 20 yuan to 180 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu is 26 years old. After graduating from high school, he worked as a game companion and managed the companions and companions under his guild. Later, the guild was disbanded, and she found that there was a huge market for chatting. At the end of 2021, she opened a Taobao store to provide chatting and emotional counseling services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, the news about &quot;cursing to awaken the love brain&quot; caught her attention. According to reports, this service can earn tens of thousands of yuan a month. Li Yu, sensing a business opportunity, changed the name of his existing emotional counseling service and launched a new business called &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the official launch of the service, Li Yu went to other stores to place orders and experience it. She placed two orders. One of the escorts started scolding her as &quot;too stupid&quot; before she finished telling her story. Li Yu felt that her emotional intelligence was too low and wanted to leave a bad review at the first reaction; the other almost Just chatting, not helping with analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these experiences, Li Yu told the customer service staff in his store to try their best to send orders to escorts who are experienced in emotional counseling. They can get started quickly. In addition, the escorts are reminded to pay attention to their emotional intelligence. Although it is called a &quot;scold wake-up&quot; service, they must also be careful about their attitude, unless the client demands straightforwardness and toughness. In general, Li Yu concluded that it is a type of &quot;relatively strong emotional counseling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Lu is one of the first batch of shopkeepers to carry out &quot;cursing to awaken the love brain&quot;. In April, short videos of emotional persuasion became popular on Douyin, usually accompanied by provocative music. Bloggers were excited and launched a series of questions: &quot;To be sentimental is to humiliate oneself&quot; and &quot;If you are not proactive, you don&#39;t like it.&quot; It’s almost meaningless to hang you up.” Xiao Lu was inspired to try to develop a &quot;scolding to wake up love brain&quot; service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The escorts in his store have different backgrounds, including full-time mothers, corporate HRs, and professional psychologists. He lets them watch Douyin videos to learn the &quot;waking up&quot; technique. In this industry, the voice of the chatter is very important. Xiao Lu pays more attention to emotional intelligence and experience. Those who are older and experienced are usually not too bad in chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many shop owners interviewed denied that this service can earn tens of thousands a month. At its peak, Meng You&#39;s Taobao store could receive forty or fifty &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; orders every day. At its peak, it earned several thousand yuan a day, but it only lasted a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many stores that engage in &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; are derived from the chatting business, and are provided by the original chatting teachers. Meng You claims that there are about 600 escorts in the store, most of whom work part-time, and the male to female ratio is about 2:8. The escorts in Meng You&#39;s store are divided into six levels: blind box, gold medal, town store, male and female goddess, chief, and koi. They are arranged according to the frequency of orders, academic qualifications, customer preference and other conditions. The higher the level, the higher the charges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Meng You’s observation, more than 90% of the customers who placed orders for “cursing to wake up your love brain” are women. Most of the customers are between 18 and 28 years old. About half have relationship problems themselves, and the other half order for friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Meng You’s view, if a customer can take the initiative to place an order, his “love brain” is already half awake. “People who are not awake can’t order because they don’t want to be scolded.” Meng You said Southern Weekend reporter said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1972&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Scolding to wake up the love brain&quot; has become a booming business on the e-commerce platform. Some shop owners said that the daily income was several thousand yuan at the peak. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Whether it has any effect or not, he said it&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Just started&quot; During the service of &quot;Scolding to Wake Up Your Love Brain&quot;, Li Yu tried to take an order in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The client is a girl. She discovered that her partner has been chatting with others on other social software. After the two broke up, she has been unable to get out. After hearing this, Li Yu did not scold her. She felt that the other party was already feeling very uncomfortable and &quot;there is no need to attack others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu helped analyze with a straightforward attitude: The girl&#39;s partner just likes to chat everywhere. If the girl can accept it, then go to retain him and continue to be together; if not, then love yourself well. The girl did not give an answer on the spot and said she would go back and think about it. Later, the girl found the store&#39;s customer service and left a reward for Li Yu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The escort, Xia Lin, has a neutral and steady voice. She is studying for a Ph.D. and her expressions are very logical. In life, she is good at giving advice to friends and dealing with emotional problems. She has been working part-time as a chat companion for more than three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She considers herself to have a strong &quot;sense of separation&quot;. Although she can empathize with customers when &quot;scolding her to wake up her love brain&quot;, she is more accustomed to rational analysis, &quot;What I want to do is to help you solve the problem.&quot; . Li Yu also emphasized that you can&#39;t just scold, you should focus on the other person&#39;s situation, and you can&#39;t give strong suggestions right from the beginning. You should at least listen to their story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlene will usually first understand the basic situation of the client and let the other party talk. &quot;If this girl or boy has something he wants to talk about, he doesn&#39;t need you to guide him, and he will want to talk for two hours.&quot; Charlene said that it is important to guide the other party to explain the details clearly, which is helpful for analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She received an order. A boy had been dating online for a year, and they started talking about marriage without ever meeting him. Only after they broke up did he realize that he had been cheated. He places orders with Charlene almost every day. Charlene advised him not to compete with her. Although the other party cheated during the relationship, she did not defraud him of money. She also provided a lot of emotional value, hoping to make him feel relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Frankly speaking, many people are willing to listen to the truth, not necessarily to hear lies.&quot; Charlene told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Escortist Chen Qing has been engaged in escorting since January. When she first heard stories from customers who were &quot;scolding to wake up their love brain&quot;, her mood was also affected. Sometimes she just couldn&#39;t persuade her. &quot;Move&quot;, she felt a little weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As she received more and more orders, she gradually became disinterested, &quot;That is their life, and their life has nothing to do with me. I am just a bystander, so I can&#39;t go there no matter how powerless I am.&quot; Help them do anything. That&#39;s their life, choice and attitude.&quot; Chen Qing said, &quot;That&#39;s his life, why do you want to interfere? Tell him that you must break up. If something goes wrong, you still have this responsibility. I can&#39;t afford it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xiao Lu&#39;s view, &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain&quot; actually only provides a supporting role. Many orderers just want to find someone to talk to and vent their inner emotions. &quot;Actually, it&#39;s just a confession.&quot; He said, &quot;No matter whether it has any effect or not, he said it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking orders for a long time, Charlene found that most of the cases were similar. &quot;The commonality is that they may all have obsessions, and they may have suffered emotional harm, mental control, and PUA. They may have it all, but they refuse to give up.&quot; She said, &quot;Thinking and doing are two different things. You can&#39;t get rid of emotions.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Charlene once took on a case where a forty-year-old woman fell in love with a married man who was over seventy years old and could not get away for several years. Charlene felt that the other party was not going to give up, so she did not ask the other party to give up. &quot;Respect individual feelings. She has her own choice. She is an adult.&quot; She said, &quot;She just needs to reconcile with herself. She does not have to be responsible to anyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Charlene It seems that it is useless to analyze the general principles. &quot;Can you not know the general principles?&quot; A customer once said to her that among so many people, Charlene was the only one who could consider it from his point of view. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“When it’s time to be in love, you’re also in love”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Yu has been a companion for five years and has heard many other people’s love stories. She considers herself to be quite smart and gentle in relationships. cautious. But she hasn&#39;t always been like this. &quot;When it&#39;s time to be in love, she&#39;s also in love.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her last relationship, in her words, &quot;just lost her IQ.&quot; During that period of foreign love, when the relationship was still ambiguous, the other party suddenly disappeared for two months. During that time, she often called the other party, but the other party never hung up or picked up the phone. Her friends advised her that she had met a &quot;scumbag&quot; who cheated on her feelings. She couldn&#39;t believe it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One time, the other party finally picked up the phone. Faced with Li Yu&#39;s questioning, he explained that he was traveling on vacation and knew that Li Yu had been trying to contact him, but &quot;just didn&#39;t know what to reply to.&quot; After Li Yu believed and forgave him for his &quot;disappearance&quot;, they were officially together. A few months later, when the boy returned to China, Li Yu discovered that he had another girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu feels the same way for people who place orders to &quot;swear to wake up their love brain&quot;. She knew that the process of coming out &quot;would be very sad.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, emotional problems are difficult to control rationally, &quot;I think everyone is a love brain. In a relationship, no one is so rational, and emotional emotions lead to love. Brain tendencies.&quot; Li Yu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the breakup, Li Yu couldn&#39;t get out for a long time. When talking to her friends, she pretended to be cool and did not dare to confess her pain. Because her friends have already tried to persuade her many times, but &quot;there is nothing to be persuaded&quot;, they may decide that she deserves it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu can only order online and ask someone to &quot;scold her&quot; to wake her up. She doesn&#39;t dare to go to the escorts in her store. They all know her. &quot;You can&#39;t lose this face in your own home. You have to find some strangers to throw it away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu told the unfamiliar escort that if she felt her behavior was silly or had other feelings, she could tell her true thoughts directly without worrying too much about hurting her. Some escorts directly scolded her for being stupid, &quot;There are so many men in the world, why do they hang on a tree?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After hearing this, Li Yu was torn in her heart. In fact, she knew these truths very well, but she just couldn&#39;t get out of them. She could calm down temporarily only when she was scolded. She placed the order many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after Zhou Ningning broke up, she tried to find someone on Douyin to &quot;scold&quot; her. She feels that her ex doesn&#39;t like her very much, but she still wants to keep him. The escort analyzed all the shortcomings of her ex, and for a moment she felt that she was &quot;sick&quot; and would actually put down her dignity to save him. But a few days later, she couldn&#39;t help but send another message to her ex to save her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is a staged thing, and it cannot be solved once or twice.” Li Yu said that maybe the customer figured it out at the time, but then “went into the abyss of emotion.” There may be many recurrences, which are normal, and the &quot;wake up&quot; service cannot be solved once and for all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking out may be just the first step. In Li Yu&#39;s view, the most important thing to get out of the love brain is to rely on yourself. It took her half a year to really get out of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After a person is tempted, it takes time to get out of the relationship. Time is a necessity.&quot; Li Yu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Xiao Lu and Meng You are the names in the industry, Li Yu, Xia Lin, Zhou Ningning, Chen Qing (pseudonym)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>