<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[迄今最全面的人类脑细胞图谱丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258680]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 15:20:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/YITFib0yT0s4rxY2Bs1TS5zYtbV9xqDzqrtGnZze.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1408&quot; height=&quot;698&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/YITFib0yT0s4rxY2Bs1TS5zYtbV9 xqDzqrtGnZze. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254152&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Technical News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/collections/brain-cell-census&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【01】The most comprehensive human brain cell atlas to date&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;On October 13, &quot;Science&quot; released the special topic &quot;Brain&amp;nbsp;Cell&amp;nbsp;Census&quot;, and 21 research papers were simultaneously published in &quot;Science&quot; and its sub-journal &quot;Science&amp;nbsp&quot; Advances) and Science Translational Medicine (12, 8, and 1 articles were published respectively), sharing the most comprehensive brain cell atlas of human and non-human primates to date. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These results come from the &quot;Brain Project-Cell Census Network&quot; project, abbreviated as BICCN (BRAIN&amp;nbsp;Initiative&amp;nbsp; Cell&amp;nbsp;Census&amp;nbsp;Network). The scientific research team used advanced molecular biology techniques to conduct a series of studies, especially analyzing the organizational structure of the human brain at an unprecedented granularity from the single cell level, including the adult brain and the developing human brain during the embryonic period, identifying and describing The amazing diversity of cell types in the human brain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : In October 2021, the BICCN project published 16 papers in &quot;Nature&quot; to comprehensively map the characteristics of mammalian primary motor cortex cell types at the molecular level. This series of research results two years later not only provided cell type diversity It provides new insights into the role of regional and species-specific differences in the human brain and also informs the development and selection of models to study different scientific questions and will help address fundamental scientific questions about the human brain and its genetic organization. (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ustc.edu.cn/info/1055/84845.htmhttps://journals.aps.org/prl/issues /131/15&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[02] &quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Nine Chapter Three&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Refresh the world record of optical quantum information technology&lt;/strong>;&lt; /a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, a research team composed of Pan Jianwei and Lu Chaoyang of the University of Science and Technology of China cooperated with the Shanghai Institute of Microsystems and Information Technology of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the National Parallel Computer Engineering Technology Research Center at The internationally renowned academic journal &quot;Physical Review Letters&quot; published a paper announcing the successful construction of a 255-photon quantum computing prototype &quot;Jiuzhang-3&quot;, once again refreshing the technical level of optical quantum information and the world of the superiority of quantum computing. record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/KEtffk0L2bUyQmv2qGJc53qj5ZlxM1CaA5sx9JVQ.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height= &quot;258&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/KEtffk0L2bUyQmv2qGJc53qj5ZlxM1CaA5sx9JVQ.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254150&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Caption: The international competitive situation of optical quantum computing&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;Image source: University of Science and Technology of China website&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team designed a new photon detection method for space-time demultiplexing, built a high-fidelity quasi-photon number resolvable detector, and improved photon detection. In terms of control level and quantum computing complexity, &quot;Jiuzhang-3&quot; can process Gaussian Bose samples one million times faster than the previous generation &quot;Jiu-Zhang-2&quot;. &quot;Jiu-Zhang-3&quot; can calculate the most complex data in 1 microsecond. Sample, currently the world&#39;s fastest supercomputer &quot;Frontier&quot; (Frontier) takes about 20 billion years. &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font- weight: bold;&quot;>;Comment: Quantum computing is a new computing paradigm in the post-Moore era, and it is also the technological frontier that scientific research teams from various countries are chasing. &quot;Nine Chapter Three&quot; further consolidates China&#39;s leading position in the field of optical quantum computing. (Li Yiyi)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06594-4&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[03] Accept pigs Primates with kidney transplants can survive&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;2&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 11, &quot;Nature&quot; ) published online the collaborative research paper Design&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;testing&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;humanized&amp;nbsp;porcine&amp;nbsp;donor&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;xenotransplantation, an American biotechnology company eGenesis and Harvard Medical School. The research team designed a genetically modified pig kidney donor that can be used clinically. and successfully achieved xenotransplantation and long-term survival in non-human primates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To overcome the obstacle of immune rejection of xenogeneic organs and improve the safety of transplantation, researchers performed 69 genome edits on Yucatan mini pig donors, including knocking out genes thought to cause immune rejection Three glycan antigens (3KO), overexpressing 7 human transgenes (7TG) to reduce rejection by the primate immune system while simultaneously inactivating all copies of porcine retroviral genes (RI). Experimental results found that transplantation of donor kidneys carrying human transgenes into cynomolgus monkeys can significantly extend survival time. A cynomolgus monkey that received a transplant of a pig kidney containing knockout and human transgenes simultaneously received a clinically relevant immune transplantation protocol. Survival time exceeds 2 years (758 days). The experiment is still ongoing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The above research results prove that genetically modified pig kidneys can survive for a long time after xenotransplantation, showing the prospects of transplanting pig organs into humans. In January 2022 and September 2023, based on the U.S. FDA’s “Compassionate Use” program, the University of Maryland School of Medicine completed two cases of living human transplants of pig hearts. Although large-scale clinical application of xenotransplantation is still far away, scientific exploration continues. (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(23)00981-9&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【04】 A new mechanism for plants to achieve distant hybridization through sexual reproduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, Peking University School of Life Sciences, Peking University-Tsinghua Joint Center for Life Sciences, New Cornerstone Scientific Experiment The Murogo Reika/Zhong Sheng team published a paper on Antagonistic RALF peptides control an intergeneric hybridization barrier on Brassicaceae stigmas at the molecular level, analyzing the Arabidopsis stigma recognition and acceptance of its own pollen and recent The mechanism of receiving pollen from distant relatives but not pollen from distant relatives clarifies the mechanism of interspecific/intergeneric reproductive barriers. Using this result, they successfully achieved distant hybridization between two plant species that began to diverge 27 million years ago and now belong to two different genera and obtained hybrid embryos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : New species are important for maintaining biodiversity on Earth. Hybridization between different species is an important mechanism for the formation of new species. Many important economic crops such as wheat, cotton, and rapeseed are all derived from hybridization between plants in nature. This discovery explains the mechanism of reproductive barriers in hybridization between different species of plants, reveals the molecular basis of key reproductive hybridization barriers at plant stigmas, and thus finds a simple and effective way to break key reproductive barriers. This has important theoretical significance and broad application prospects for realizing distant hybridization of plants and creating new germplasm resources for agriculture, horticulture and other fields. (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2023.09.012&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[05] A method that can promote wound healing Nanofiber hydrogel&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, the team of Professor Wang Xiaoying of South China University of Technology, the team of Associate Professor Zhang Huantian and Professor Zha Zhengang of the First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Published a paper Collagen&amp;nbsp;fibril-like&amp;nbsp;injectable&amp;nbsp;hydrogels&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;self-assembled&amp;nbsp;nanoparticles&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;promoting&amp;nbsp;wound&amp;nbsp;healing&amp;nbsp; strategy to develop a collagen fibrillar injectable hydrogel with low hardness, high compressive strength, anti-swelling, drug loading and biodegradability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This study used the self-assembly between methacrylated hydroxypropyl chitosan (HM) and hectorite (LAP) to form nanoparticles, and then prepared a kind of nanoparticles through inter-particle photo-cross-linking. Injectable, soft yet tough and anti-swelling nanofiber hydrogels are used to promote wound healing. The hydrogel has good biocompatibility and biodegradability, and accelerates wound healing by accelerating cell migration and promoting the formation and maturation of new blood vessels. &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2023.09.012&quot;>;&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments: This new biomimetic hydrogel It has great potential in various soft tissue engineering applications such as wound dressings, and provides a general strategy for the development of bionic nanofiber soft hydrogels and rapid healing of perioperative incisions and wounds, which has clinical translation value. (Li Yiyi)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/full/10.1126/science.adg7921&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【06】Discovering the Ocean Key pigment synthase for photosynthesis&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, Li Xiaobo’s team from the School of Life Sciences of West Lake University published a paper A&amp;nbsp;chlorophyll&amp;nbsp;c&amp;nbsp;synthase&amp;nbsp; in Science widely&amp;nbsp;co-opted&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;phytoplankton, the gene encoding chlorophyll c synthase and the mechanism of action of the enzyme were revealed for the first time. The research team selected dozens of candidate genes from the Phaeodactylum tricornutum genome based on the expression levels of each gene under different growth conditions, and sequentially carried out knockout and phenotypic testing, and discovered chlorophyll c synthase (Chl&amp;nbsp;c&amp;nbsp;synthase, (referred to as CHLC); combined with Tara&amp;nbsp;Oceans global marine biological survey data, the research team found that CHLC homologous genes are widely distributed in the global ocean; phylogenetic analysis results show that brown algae may use unknown, independently evolved enzymes to synthesize chlorophyll c. This result also shows that the current evolutionary theory of photosynthesis mechanism still needs to be revised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Photosynthesis is the basis of all life on earth. It is a complex process that humans cannot yet fully decipher. The above research solves a problem that has long plagued the field of marine photosynthesis and opens the door to the synthetic biology application of the light-harvesting mechanism of marine algae. (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Corporate News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://global.toyota/en/newsroom/corporate/39865919 .html&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[07] Toyota Motor and Idemitsu Kosan cooperate on all-solid-state batteries&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, Toyota Motor and Idemitsu&amp;nbsp;Kosan ) announced that the two parties will cooperate to develop large-scale production technology for solid electrolytes, improve productivity, and build a supply chain, with the goal of commercialization in 2027-2028, followed by mass production. Idemitsu Kosan has invested in basic technology research and development of all-solid-state batteries since 2001, while Toyota started in 2006. The focus of this cooperation between the two parties is sulfide solid electrolytes, which are considered to be ideal materials for power batteries that achieve high capacity and high output. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : All-solid-state batteries are seen as the next generation of batteries, with higher energy density and faster charging. In recent years, Toyota has been criticized by the outside world for not being active enough in the field of vehicle electrification. It turns out that it is already laying out next-generation technologies. (Li Yiju)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maersk.com.cn/news/articles/2023/10/12/maersk-signs-deal-with -starlink-for-its-ocean-fleet&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[08] Maersk will add Starlink to container ships&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 12 On September 1, Danish logistics giant Maersk announced that it would add SpaceX’s Starlink satellite network to more than 330 of its own container ships, providing high-speed Internet services exceeding 200 megabits per second. The installation is expected to be in 2024. Completed in the first quarter of the year. Starlink is a global communications network that Elon Musk&#39;s SpaceX has been building and has launched more than 5,000 satellites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-speed internet will enable seamless streaming and high-definition video calling for crews and will also facilitate cost-saving measures by migrating business-critical applications to the cloud and enhancing remote support and inspections of ships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Satellite networks are breaking the limitations of ground base stations and helping people better access high-speed Internet. This cooperation with Maersk is a breakthrough in the ocean, especially in the high seas, from ocean to high altitude, from special equipment to portable Smartphones, the commercial value and application scenarios of satellite networks are continuing to expand. (Li Yiyi)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amd.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2023-10-10-amd-to-acquire -open-source-ai-software-expert-nod-.html&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[09] AMD&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Acquisition&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;AI&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Startup&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;Nod.ai&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, AMD announced the acquisition of AI software startup Nod.ai to expand its open source artificial intelligence software capabilities, but The purchase price was not disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nod.ai, founded in 2013, is an artificial intelligence and machine learning systems company that provides key open source technologies for artificial intelligence systems. Nod.ai has developed code generation technologies such as SHARK&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;Torch-MLIR and OpenXLA/IREE, which have been widely deployed in the cloud, edge and endpoint devices, and can help enterprises quickly deploy optimization for AMD chips artificial intelligence model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comment: Software and software developer ecology are also battlegrounds for chip manufacturers. Before acquiring Nod.ai, AMD also acquired French AI startup Mipsology in August 2023, firmly seizing the rapid growth opportunities of artificial intelligence technology and products to better catch up with competitor Nvidia. (Tang Jiale)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schaeffler.com/en/media/press-releases/vitesco-voluntary-public-tender-offer/&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【10 ] Schaeffler acquires Vitesco Technology&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, Schaeffler Group announced the acquisition of Vitesco Technology with a cash offer of 3.64 billion euros (91 euros per share) (Vitesco) to strengthen the Schaeffler Group&#39;s competitive position in the electric mobility industry. Vitesco Technology has core components and advanced system solutions for electric vehicles, and both parties have a highly complementary technology portfolio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vitesco Technology was spun off from Continental’s powertrain division in 2018 and will be listed on the Frankfurt Stock Exchange in 2021. The Schaeffler family is its largest single shareholder. The family also holds controlling stakes in Schaeffler Group and Continental AG. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The transaction has been submitted to the German Federal Financial Supervisory Authority for approval and is expected to be completed in the fourth quarter of 2024. By then, the new Schaeffler Group will become a parts giant with more than 120,000 employees, 44 R&amp;D centers and more than 100 production bases around the world, with revenue of approximately 25 billion euros. &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schaeffler.com/en/media/press-releases/vitesco-voluntary-public-tender-offer/&quot;>;&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold; &quot;>;Comment: The automobile industry is about to give birth to a new auto parts giant. The electrification transformation of the automobile industry has also made the mergers and acquisitions and reorganization of the auto parts industry chain exciting. (Li Yiyi)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation-at-amazon/amazon-project-kuiper-latest-updates&quot;>; &lt;strong>;[11] Amazon launches the first two space Internet test satellites&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, two prototype satellites of the Amazon Space Internet Kuiper Project (Kuiper Project) KuiperSat-1 and KuiperSat-2 were launched from Cape Canaveral Space Station in Florida on United Launch Alliance (ULA) Atlas V rockets and deployed at an altitude of 311 miles (approximately 500 kilometers) above the Earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first satellite launched by the Kuiper project. Amazon launched Project Kuiper in 2018 and received a license from the U.S. Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to deploy and operate satellites in July 2020. &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation-at-amazon/amazon-project-kuiper-latest-updates&quot;>;&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;u>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic , italics_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comment: In April 2022, Amazon announced that it had signed a space agreement with Arianespace, Blue Origin and United Launch Alliance (ULA). The launch agreement will carry out 83 launches for the Kuiper project in the following five years, deploying 3,236 satellites in low-Earth orbit. This launch officially opened Amazon’s space communication infrastructure, and satellite communications will also launch a new round of competition. (Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fda.gov/media/172726/download&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[12] New treatment for common cancers in infants and young children obtained&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;FDA&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Expert Committee Support&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 4, the US FDA Oncology Drugs Advisory Committee voted 14:6 The results support the efficacy of eflornithine (DFMO), an investigational therapy from US pharmaceutical company US World Meds, in reducing the risk of recurrence in pediatric patients with high-risk neuroblastoma. US&amp;nbsp;WorldMeds did not use randomized clinical trials (RCT) when developing eflornithine, which is expected to create a precedent that does not rely on RCT to support the approval of new drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Neuroblastoma is one of the most common cancers in infants and young children. It is an extremely aggressive tumor. The 5-year survival rate of conventional treatments is only 10&lt;span>;%&lt;/span >;—20%. eflornithine is an oral, irreversible inhibitor of ornithine decarboxylase (ODC). In a Phase 2 clinical trial, patients treated with eflornithine showed no significant improvement compared with an external control group selected based on historical data. Both event survival and overall survival were significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : RCT is a common choice for the clinical development of new drugs, but in patients with rare diseases or serious, fatal diseases, randomized controlled clinical trials may face challenges and ethical issues. The support of the U.S. FDA Oncology Drugs Advisory Committee recognizes the effectiveness and safety of eflornithine in the treatment of neuroblastoma. It also provides more support for the clinical application of this drug, so that patients can have more treatment options and hope for survival. . (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“伞买票了吗”：明明错了，为什么坚决不认错？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258515]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;If you know your mistakes and can correct them, there is no greater good. We have been taught since childhood that it is a virtue to have the courage to face mistakes and correct them. However, in real life, some people regard virtue as a broom. Not only do they not correct their mistakes, but they also make them knowingly and add to their mistakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It rained in the afternoon, so I went to take the bus and found that the seat I wanted to sit in was occupied by a wet umbrella, so I had to find another seat. The same thing happened to the passengers who came up later. They wanted to sit in that seat but had to find another seat when they saw an umbrella. One of the old men had difficulty moving and had to stumble to the last row to sit down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sight of the old man walking with difficulty made people feel pitiful. An old man couldn&#39;t stand it anymore and asked the umbrella owner why he didn&#39;t pick up the umbrella. The umbrella owner explained that there were no other passengers when she got on the bus. She was answering the phone at the time, so she conveniently placed the umbrella on the seat. The old man continued to question, saying that the umbrella was wet and it was common sense not to put it on the seat. The owner of the umbrella argued that the seat was wet anyway and he couldn&#39;t sit on it. The two argued over and over again. After the surrounding passengers lined up for the old man, the umbrella owner suddenly changed her face and said arrogantly that she could put her umbrella wherever she wanted and that it was none of the old man&#39;s business. She also mocked the old man for not being able to afford an umbrella. Fortunately, the surrounding passengers reconciled the situation and the bus happened to arrive at the platform where the old man got off, otherwise a bigger dispute might have erupted between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the old man got off the bus, the old man sitting in the last row criticized him for being meddlesome, and some of his words were unpleasant. This really surprised the passengers. The old man obviously complained about the grievance when he saw that he was also an elderly man and had difficulty moving. Unexpectedly, he didn&#39;t appreciate it and even stabbed him. Seeing that someone was helping her, the umbrella owner talked about her reasons for letting the umbrella go, emphasizing that she had always been a rule-abiding person outside. She didn&#39;t shut up until a passenger asked her if she had bought a ticket for the umbrella, but she still didn&#39;t pick up the umbrella. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s a very small thing. I believe that most people will pick up the umbrella immediately when they are reminded that they should not put the umbrella on the seat. A simple action can avoid a heated dispute. Why wouldn&#39;t the umbrella owner refuse? There were no other passengers when she got on the bus. The umbrella was placed on the seat and it was not in the way. She thought it was reasonable to put the umbrella up. This was her first explanation. This is also the first reaction of some people when faced with their own mistakes. They do not correct the mistakes immediately, but look for rationalizations for the mistakes from their own perspective, standpoint and safeguarding their own interests. The more sufficient the reason is, the more self-justifying it is, the more it feels that it should be understood, and the more it feels that it is not wrong, so naturally there is no question of correcting the error. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second explanation given by the umbrella owner is that the seat has been wet and cannot be sat on. Fait accompli cannot be changed. Although it seems reasonable on the surface, it actually implies arrogance. This arrogance is related to environmental shaping. From childhood to adulthood, it is common for children to admit mistakes to their parents, students to their teachers, employees to their leaders, and subordinates to their superiors, but not vice versa. The subconscious mind that the strong and the powerful are justified is deep-rooted. From the umbrella owner&#39;s subsequent words, we can see her superiority and arrogance, that is, it is normal for my umbrella to be placed on the seat, and none of you have the right to criticize me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes courage to admit mistakes and correct them, and it takes even more courage to find mistakes and point them out. The historical allusion of Wei Zheng&#39;s blunt remonstrance has been passed down to this day, and we also know that &quot;it is enough to have one admonishing friend in life.&quot; However, in real life, people like flowers and applause far more than good medicine and criticism. Those who correct errors are often lonely, because their coming forward not only makes the wrongdoers feel resentful because they have no way to hide their mistakes, but also reflects the cowardice and cowardice of bystanders and beneficiaries, making them feel ashamed. The old man’s criticism is an example. If the old man heard what he said, would he come forward to correct his mistakes next time? If there are fewer people correcting mistakes, there will be more people making mistakes, so that even though they are making mistakes, they don’t know they are wrong, and they don’t know the difference between right and wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone has flaws and no one is perfect. It’s okay to make mistakes; mistakes are part of growing up. Whether a child or a parent, a student or a teacher, an employee or a leader, a subordinate or a superior, if you make a mistake, just face it bravely and make corrections sincerely. Give firm support to those who correct mistakes and sincere encouragement to those who correct mistakes, so that mistakes can generate the power to nourish virtue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a staff member of a public institution in Southwest China)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2349名缅北电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人一次性移交我方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258688]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 15:37:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The public security organs have always been keeping a close eye on telecom network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar and have continued to carry out multiple rounds of On the basis of crackdown operations to resolutely eradicate fraud dens and arrest fraudsters in accordance with the law, the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau of Yunnan recently carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar, and captured 2,349 Chinese telecommunications network fraud suspects and handed them over to us. square. This is the largest number of people transferred in a single time since the launch of the crackdown on telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, including 111 online fugitives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the preliminary work, the Yunnan public security organs and relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar have continued to strengthen border police cooperation, continue to report the latest identification of fraud dens and personnel clues, and have carried out intensive arrest operations in recent days. A large number of telecommunications network fraud suspects have been arrested one after another. On October 14, 2,349 suspects were handed over to us and were successively escorted back by the public security organs in Kunming, Yunnan, Jiangsu, Henan, Shandong, Hunan, Chongqing and other places to fully carry out case investigation work. So far, thanks to the unremitting efforts of public security agencies in many places in Yunnan, 4,666 suspects of telecommunications network fraud in northern Myanmar have been handed over to us, including 205 online fugitives. Since August this year, the number of telecom fraud cases nationwide and the number of property losses caused have dropped by 24% and 20.5% respectively year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the public security agency said that recently, in response to the situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the public security agency has continued to increase its crackdown efforts, continued to organize special crackdowns, and achieved remarkable results. The public security organs will continue to exert their efforts to clear out fraud dens, publicly arrest and arrest fraudsters in accordance with the law, and unswervingly eradicate the &quot;cancer&quot; of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, and effectively safeguard the property safety and legitimate rights and interests of the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一个理性的人爱上航海，这是我做的最疯狂的事——对话徐京坤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/e8ZUobY9rhBEcl4R2T5EDttgP3LOyDzNF0griYOd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/e8ZUobY9rhBEcl4R2T5EDttgP3LOyDzNF0 griYOd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;In 2021, I will come to Brittany again to start my IMOCA plan. Offshore sailing is still in its infancy in China. Due to budget constraints, I once again live on my boat, but this time my boat is 60 feet&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interview Provided by the author/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When there are friends around him, Xu Jingkun is often a listener. &quot;I seem to have very few friends of the same age. All the friends I have are older brothers.&quot; He likes to listen to big brothers. The buddies chatted about everything, &quot;You can learn a lot.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past two years, the eldest buddies often got together because of his return to China, and the topics mostly revolved around him and his circumnavigation and transatlantic sailing race. And his IMOCA60 super racing boat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if everyone is talking about himself, Xu Jingkun is still used to silence. When he is not talking, his face, which has been tanned by the sun all year round, looks particularly calm. &quot;Actually, I often do this at sea. I don&#39;t speak, but I enjoy it in my heart. The lack of expression does not mean that I am unhappy, but I have such a habit of being &#39;lazy in talking&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that he is a &quot;Stupid&quot;, this is absolutely not the case. He is sensitive, humble and well-measured. When we politely asked the eldest brother to &quot;exit&quot; and started a two-and-a-half-hour in-depth conversation in a big brother&#39;s quiet and undisturbed office, he opened himself up to us with accurate and moving expressions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/VjJv1LH5mWRi07GYyWBWZYHqxoQfW4ugxzvvUdSq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/VjJv1LH5mWRi07GYyWBWZYHqxoQfW4ugxzvvUdSq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253638&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun&#39;s old childhood photos, the accident has not happened yet, he is a lively and healthy mountain child&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sailing makes me feel comfortable, which is the biggest gain&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did you feel particularly comfortable and at ease? Many disabled people use sleeves to cover their missing parts, or wear prosthetics when going out, but you just naturally expose your left arm and even use it as a hand or an arm. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Jingkun: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I am very calm and I am very free. When I first started training at Shandong Sports School, it was not possible. Even though you were training as a disabled athlete, when others looked at you, you would feel uncomfortable and nervous yourself. Later, I joined the national sailing team and slowly began to change. But what really liberated me was that after the national team was disbanded, I started sailing on my own. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sailing really changed me completely. When many people talk about me, they always say that I am successful now and have changed my destiny. In fact, the biggest gain for me is this kind of freedom. Sailing makes me live very freely. I can choose what I want and my current situation, which is very good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the time I decided to sail, from the time I first sailed around the China Sea, my life began to change. Whether it&#39;s loneliness at sea, wind and waves, or even some fears sometimes, after you experience it too much, you will gain that kind of freedom and become very comfortable, not caring about external things or what others think. In this way It&#39;s very comfortable to be alive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the &quot;one-armed captain&quot; given to you by others? Label? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Jingkun: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I gave it to myself, haha. When Ajiu (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun’s wife and partner Xiao Shuyao&lt;/span>;) wrote my biography &quot;The Humble Dreamer&quot;, I told She, you need to write &quot;one-armed captain&quot; in the title. The media teachers we have contacted over the years are also very professional. Many times they will ask very politely, &quot;Shouldn&#39;t we write like this, or what kind of title is more appropriate?&quot; I will tell them to just write &quot; One-armed Captain&quot;. I don’t think there’s anything that shouldn’t be said. On the contrary, one-armedness is a very unique thing about me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You dare to face it only if you dare to speak, right? I don’t care about this at all now. In fact, there is no need to talk about whether I care or not. If you are still thinking about whether you care or not, it means you still care. (Laughs) Let’s put it this way, I think my left arm is great. When I have children in the future, I will be the most unique father in their eyes, which is cool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/NxSHzppQbBvqiojKcnTyOurdXvkbp7ctiri8h4p6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/NxSHzppQbBvqiojKcnTyOurdXvkbp7ctiri8h4p6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253637&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun used this J24 to start a circumnavigation of the China Sea from the northernmost point to the southernmost point of China. It was the first ship in his life and also his first time. Solo voyage&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not easy for you to fully reconcile with the accidental injury caused by the explosion when you were 12 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Jingkun: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, this matter has completely turned over and is completely over. The damage and shadow in my life have been completely wiped out. Expelled. This is what sailing has brought me, including my growth and experiences along the way. I am very lucky! An accidental injury is like a devil appearing in life. It wants to hurt me, but before it can really hurt me, I have already defeated it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back now, I can feel that if I had not stepped out in time to defeat it, I would most likely have been defeated by it. I can also feel that many friends with physical disabilities have been deeply hurt physically and mentally due to their disability, and I always want to give them some encouragement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people outside the sailing circle know you from &quot;Ten In that episode of &quot;Three Invitations&quot;, when you were talking to teacher Xu Zhiyuan, you said that you &quot;have never felt at ease in the first half of your life.&quot; What time are you in now? Is it the previous life or the next life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Jingkun: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s still the first half of my life, and I’m still not at ease. I actually don’t have particularly big ambitions, I just don’t like falling to the bottom. The so-called bottom does not mean material life. I am very adaptable to life.现在我也还是经常一天只吃两顿饭，不是没有钱，是没有时间，在船上有很多活儿要做，手上的工作中断了很麻烦，我宁可不吃饭也要干完。不喜欢底层是不喜欢那种没有目标、不能自己掌控自己的生活的感觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从确立了参加2024旺代环球这个目标之后，生活就变成了一场战役。 2022年朗姆路单人跨大西洋、2023年咖啡路双人跨大西洋都是为了获得旺代环球的资格，我们没有那么多财力慢慢来，只能把一个赛季当成3个赛季，把一个人当成10个人用，我们赛队就5个人，德国赛队50个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为这个是我自己的目标，我喜欢这个目标，所以我也没有觉得生活多苦，自己的牺牲有多大。一般人过我的生活会很难适应，会苦死，但我觉得这是我梦寐以求的生活。在一个非常美丽的码头，在一条非常棒的赛船上，做自己最愿意干的事情，做自己专业的事情，不用受任何人的支配、指挥和控制，我就觉得这已经非常好了，对吧？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/ps9YjERLoV0uQbWm6Z3XYKpkeQoZib9Sx4Oymdk1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1436&quot; height=&quot;1078&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/ps9YjERLoV0uQbWm6Z3XYKpkeQoZib9Sx4Oymdk1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;环中国海的途中，徐京坤曾经落水漂流到中国台湾东引岛，当地的小朋友们在徐京坤离开时带着岛上难得的糖果牛奶来为他送行&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我是一个“笨人”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;航海最吸引你的是什么？是冒险的刺激感？远离人群深入大洋的自由，还是搏击风浪后回归大陆拥抱家人朋友的渴望？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实我也在尝试从更深层面认识自己，我到底想要什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;航海跟我的天性甚至是相悖的，我特别稳妥、谨慎。我喜欢一个房间门窗关得严严实实的，没有任何小偷能悄悄进来这种。但是航海偏偏是四面漏风的，无论你在岸上做多么万全的准备，海上总是有状况出现，你就要拿着“盾牌”四面抵挡，很狼狈，我其实不喜欢那种意外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也没有那么浪漫。有一种人是真的喜欢海上航行的孤独，比如法国传奇航海家伯纳德，对城市对人群他感到厌恶，疯狂热爱自由和航行，享受孤独。我不是那种人，我没有那么疯狂。我是一个“假疯子”，我也不是文艺范儿的那种。在海上，我总是会很想岸上的家人和朋友们，想靠岸后跟他们喝啤酒吃烧烤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论是以前作为国家帆船队的专业运动员，还是现在自己从事极限航海竞赛，我也不是那种非要拿冠军、崇尚金牌和胜者为王的竞技心态。有一些极限航海竞赛的人他们参加比赛就是为了赢，竞技策略很激进，如果不能赢，可能宁可选择退赛。我也不是这种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/yST5LtCmWEI4dPPdC6KCdhDzm7YrmfK5wjv3OAfV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/yST5LtCmWEI4dPPdC6KCdhDzm7YrmfK5wjv3OAfV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2015年9月19日，单人横跨大西洋极限帆船赛Duarnenez起航，梦想号第一个冲出起航线，朋友穿着当地服饰来送徐京坤&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你不疯狂，你很理性。航海看起来是你这个理性的人做的最疯狂的事了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，我非常理性。但似乎干着一件好像很不理性的很疯狂的事。环中国海、环球航行，驾驶6.5米的小船跨越大西洋，现在又买赛船参加世界上最难的极限环球航行竞赛。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;只能说明这个事情你真是特别喜欢。作为一个理性的人，你能对航海付出这么多，对你来说，这样真是已经疯狂到极致了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，是这样的。现在过的生活完全是一种疯狂状态。 2015年单人小船跨大西洋后，其实在国内就已经算是很顶级的了，当时在深圳一个游艇俱乐部做副总，收入和待遇都非常棒。放着好日子不过，2017年到2020年，跟阿九一起完成了为期三年的环球航行。结束后我们在海南也过得挺不错的，我又有了参加旺代环球的目标。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;青岛航海人才很多，在你前面已经有好几位传奇人物，为什么你能越走越远，特别是从2022年开始自己的世界顶级职业赛船船长之路？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我是一个“笨人”！一方面我很理性，还有一方面我不会想太多有的没的，当我觉得一个事儿很好，值得去做，我就不会想做了这个没做那个如何如何，不做这个去做那个怎样怎样……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我买了IMOCA60赛船后，开始回过味来了，因为理性开始分析了：咱一个普通农民家庭出身的人，每年不赚这些钱，还花这么多钱……就这种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那个船光从岸上吊到水里，下水就要15000欧元，所以没有什么试乘试驾。钱付了，我第一次上船，真的感觉不真实，跟我以前开过的所有船都不是一个概念。那个船在海面上飞的时候，让我见识到为什么它被称为世界最顶级的赛船，“我终于站到了这条船上，这条船属于我们了！”心里这种感受刚升起来，下一秒就感觉到好大的压力，这条超级赛船好多的缆绳配件，真的很难在短时间内去学会，而且一个操作失误就会造成巨大的损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我一看太复杂了，心想这根本搞不定啊，接手后就没有离开那条船，就在码头上停着，天天研究，两个月后才自己独自出海。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不是很聪明的人，而且我很健忘，怎么也想不清楚当初买船的时候咋想咋算的。算了咱不想了，明天再说，明天又忘了这些事了，你又不想了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我喜欢机械的东西，对船可能有一点天赋吧。我们那个赛船特别复杂，欧洲很多船长都是有工程师学位的，同时还配有团队和教练，我就一个人去买的船。我初中都没有毕业，英语也是自学的，但是我不怵，花点儿时间我都能弄明白。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大部分时间我和赛船一起的感受都是愉快的，只是它太贵了，维修保养的账单都很昂贵。每次付账单的时候我很心疼，但我的理性就告诉我，赶紧付了得了，然后又忘了这个不开心了哈哈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/x2HEJrLwLBk7baJ6HnQgmSBo8lwDGmiNb3L1ZLHG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/x2HEJrLwLBk7baJ6HnQgmSBo8lwDGmiNb3L1ZLHG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253650&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在马达加斯加，徐京坤把船上的蓄电池送给没有电的当地学校。整个村子的孩子都跟着他走过村落&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我想做自己的小小英雄&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们普通人一靠近大海就会感到心情愉快，你对大海的感情比我们要复杂一点，好像没办法轻松简单地说一句“我喜欢大海”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我和大海之间是什么感情连接，我真得想一想。很长一段时间，我其实已经没有时间思考了，这种状态让我特别不舒服。海上航行是我的工作，我自己是喜欢这个项目的，但是这个事情现在确实让我很累，想到要回法国，我心里会有点抗拒，那边就像一个战场一样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想要找到一个理性的原因，我不想轻易地说出来我为什么喜欢和为什么不喜欢。我需要想一想，我想找到一个真正的让我自己觉得能接受的答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;环球航行和极限越洋竞赛完全不是一回事，极限竞赛你面对的是资金和速度的多重压力，还有竞赛策略的制定和执行，不能像环球航行那样去享受远航和大海。有过三年环球航行的幸福体验，是否会在现在这个高压阶段反哺你，让你始终对大海和航行有感情，不至于全是大赛带来的压力和消耗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;的确是。在天海之间行船是非常美好的享受，去过那么多海面连接的地方，看到的体验到的，都会让人觉得美好。但我其实可能还更喜欢极限航行比赛这种具体的目标感，让我一直漂在海上，我也会不满足。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是一个完美主义者，还有点英雄主义。我不是说要做一个人拯救地球的那种超级英雄，我想做自己的小小英雄。在极限航行中顶住压力，跨越大海，每次完成回来，我会觉得我是一个小小的英雄。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于我来讲，从赛季开赛前的艰苦准备、开赛后的承受高压，到最后到岸时的那种释放，是我最享受的一个过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/PRfAyTagmNJJWaGCsrssaVZ8gjAGh0PyPOXZ40sm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/PRfAyTagmNJJWaGCsrssaVZ8gjAGh0PyPOXZ40sm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253651&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;遇见世界各地的音乐家，在大溪地赶上海瓦节，街头乐队的演奏让水手们忍不住随之起舞&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了自在感和成就感，航海还对你的个性有什么塑造？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;航海拓展了我的身体能力和意志，我的身体特别好，都是在极限要求中发展出来的。我能感觉到自己身体的强大适应性和康复能力，身体的极限在极限环境中被激发出来了。这也是我特别喜欢航海的原因，我能感觉自己是人类中的强者，对我来说，这令我内心更加强大。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;航海不是浪漫向往或者一味勇猛就行的，要完成极限挑战，还要把赛船平安地带回来，要上岸给等待的家人一个拥抱。出发前需要做很多具体艰苦的工作让赛船有一个完美的状态，任何问题都要考虑到，有两套甚至更多预备应急方案。航海让我养成了超强的执行力，“说到做到”，目标有多高，自己就付出更多的努力，这个也刻在我骨子里了。凡事认真，绝对不会说说就算了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经历过独自航行的孤独和风浪后，我更加喜欢日常生活，发自内心地爱自己的环境和朋友。就像现在这样平静安稳、没有风暴的日常，都让人珍惜，让人想要赞美美好的天气和美好的氛围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你有过非常孤单艰难的日子，青少年时代常有一种走投无路要掉到底层的恐惧和无望。 2012年独自启航开始环中国海的时候，抱着大不了一死的念头，心里很多愤懑。这么多年航行，你跟自己和命运都和解了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2012年那时候真的是带着一种跟命运赌气的感觉，心里有种壮士一去不复还的那种悲壮，甚至也带着一些怨念，说为什么我这个人一辈子要这么难，你们不相信我就拼死一搏，我要让这个事情去发生，对，带着这种劲。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在这些都被医治了，完成一个一个目标对我来讲很重要，你慢慢知道自己是可以掌握自己的命运的。小时候在农村，我又少了半条胳膊，周围真的是一个没有目标、生活漫无目的的环境。你不知道你的目标在哪，你也从来没有达成过一个目标，你会厌恶那个懦弱又不堪一击的自己，渴望充满斗志和勇气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过航海，我有了一个又一个目标，这也是自我医治和成长的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从我用7个多月修好了一条要报废的小船，把它命名为“梦想号”，并且实现了环中国海这第一个目标后，我学会了相信自己、相信梦想。其实如果那一次失败，可能我这一辈子也不会再起来了，可能就彻底被打垮了，不光是被外界的东西打垮了，自己那道防线也没了。现在回头看，真的也觉得当时别人说我不切实际是可以理解的，自己可以说太幸运了，那个开始让我学会了相信，这种信念帮助我一步步走到现在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;离岸远航，深入海心，在离两边大陆都有1500海里的那种场景，你会有什么感受？大海对水手来说，是善意的还是恶意的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我其实没有什么特别文艺的感受。对于我这条赛船来说，在大洋中心的时候反倒不害怕，它的安全性能特别好，设计出来就是为了对抗风暴的，只要你自己不操作错误，非常安全。反倒是靠近沿岸，渔网啊往来船只等各种东西都会对这条船构成威胁。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大海它没有善意，也没有恶意，它无意伤害你，它就按照自然法则客观存在着。在海上人自然会平静下来，不会那么愤世嫉俗。我说实话，我觉得我更怕人。有时候专心忙航海的事情不看新闻，心很定，一关注社会新闻，感觉自己无所适从。西方社会制定的规则是针对东方的，东方又要针对西方做些制衡，对吧？好多事情都没有一个客观裁定的规则，混成一团，超级复杂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/sHh7XjhhF6fTr6VquWLzIvx8bI30sFUYjc6vvFgX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/sHh7XjhhF6fTr6VquWLzIvx8bI30sFUYjc6vvFgX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253647&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;徐京坤和英国船长迈克·戈丁合作试航&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;外界对你的期望极高，你对自己要求又很苛刻，你自己也知道你的橡皮筋已经拉得非常紧了，在达成2024旺代环球参赛并完赛的这个过程中，你会做什么改变，让自己更加舒展从容，不至于被拉断？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实我现在已经在开始做调整了，因为我知道确实这个东西压力太大了，真的会把人压断的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调整的前提还是船的状况一定要极致，在岸上把船照顾好，到深海里，船才能把我照顾好，这一点是肯定的。咖啡路开赛在即，各个赛队非常紧张忙碌，而我却能回国休整，就是因为前面没日没夜做了很多工作，船已经处于最佳状态了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生活上也做一些调整。有一段时间我们都住在船上，方便工作，老外看我们也是很吃惊，早晨、晚上这俩中国人都在干活。前段时间刚租了一个房子，生活稍微正常一点。有一段时间，压力真的大到我看到那条船都已经厌恶了，失去乐趣了，我心里知道这肯定不行的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对接下来旺代环球那种魔鬼航程，你如果没有真诚的热爱，没有真诚的信念，你的初心如果丢失的话，你是不可能坚持下来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;旺代环球被称为“海上珠峰”，是地球上最难的极限航海赛事，你现在的目标还在顺利拿到旺代环球的入场券上，等到你最终顺利跑完旺代，回到并没有那么具体明确目标的日常生活，到那时候，已经完成了最难赛事目标的你有信心可以投入到寻常生活中吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;确实我有这个问题。每次完成一个赛事目标，停下来以后，我确实有时候不知道怎么应对生活里边的事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的天赋是我能够去管理好一个单一的事情，我把这条船打造到极致，做得非常好，全力以赴，不偷懒不耍滑，这是我的一个性格。但一回到生活当中，需要应对一些规则，有时候我就觉得不公平，就会让我很不舒服，我不喜欢被压抑，但有时候你又无力反抗，包括对于人事会觉得很头疼，对人事我非常不敏感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如你看我那么多好朋友和大哥，其实每次回来我经常会忽略了给他们带点东西或者是多一些关心回馈什么的。在这方面我是一个弱智，经常到了人家门口了才想起来今天什么也没有带，你又不是说不懂这种人情世故，你也一把年纪了你又懂，但是反应过来的时候总是晚了，生活中就总是不那么灵光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;咖啡路你和英国传奇船长迈克·戈丁搭档，1200海里的资格航程，比去年朗姆路资格赛快了17个小时。迈克有过三次旺代参赛经验，十夺咖啡路亚军，你驾驭赛船也越来越娴熟，除了参赛完赛是否对名次还有更高预想？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐京坤：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从我自己还有赛船的能力上，的确是可以冲击更快的速度的，我的船到现在还只释放了百分之七十的性能，没有往极限去狠跑。但是我们的策略还是安全完赛，拿到积分。说实话，我手上连大修一次的钱都没有，没有任性跑的资本。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一点我跟迈克·戈丁船长也有过明确沟通，他非常理解，他也经历过这种资金有限的困难时期。策略非常明确，但执行到位不犯错仍然会是一个挑战，我天天告诫自己千万别激进，别贪快！一定要慢，一定要慎重！但是在海上很多时候都是瞬间决断，那一瞬间很难说自己认为正确的决定是真正明智的。希望我和搭档能够配合好，在具体情况中能够做好平衡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[遭“恐袭预告”，法国缘何被恐怖组织盯上？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258676]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 12:52:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/Dvkztk8oPl2cxtEL0mOldqVov5K6Q99PqsajhnCD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/Dvkztk8oPl2cxtEL0mOldqVov5K6Q99PqsajhnCD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年10月13日，法国阿拉斯，一名持刀男子在一所高中杀害了一名教师，并打伤了另外两人。反恐官员表示，他们正在牵头调查这起持刀袭击事件。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在国际局势极为紧张之际，恐怖主义再次袭击法国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间2023年10月13日，在北部城市阿拉斯发生持刀袭击事件后，法国称处于恐袭警戒状态，将威胁等级调至最高。这次袭击事件导致一名教师死亡，三人重伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅仅一天后，法国卢浮宫博物馆、凡尔赛宫、里昂火车站等多处地标建筑因安全威胁而发布“紧急疏散令”。一些卢浮宫博物馆的参观者在社交媒体上发布消息称，在疏散过程中，现场有巨大的警报声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在上个月，阿拉伯半岛基地组织通过内部刊物向法国、瑞典发出了“恐袭预告”。法国内政部长热拉尔-达尔马宁（Gérald Darmanin）接受《法兰西西部报》（L&#39;Ouest-France）专访时称，当局将一如既往认真应对，因为“恐怖主义的风险仍然很高”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年前“11·13巴黎恐袭案”的恐惧浮上心头。为什么法国总是被恐怖分子盯上？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;恐袭风险死灰复燃&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;八年前，“11·13巴黎恐袭案”发生后，人们走上街头，在遇袭地点摆上哀悼的蜡烛和鲜花。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年11月17日晚上，在靠近巴黎国王喷泉街的悼念地点，摄影师本杰明·费拉尔斯基在哀悼人群中发现了一名悲伤的警察正伏在同事肩膀上哭泣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本杰明抓住时机、摁下快门，定格了让人心碎的一幕。他在社交媒体上发布了照片，命名为《哭泣的警察》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;八年后，这一代表了法国伤痛记忆的警察哭泣场景，却在新一轮的“恐袭预告”中出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据法国商业调频电视台（BFMTV）9月14日报道，阿拉伯半岛基地组织（AQAP）最新一期出版物《战斗之声》中，向法国、瑞典发出“恐袭威胁”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿拉伯半岛基地组织（AQAP）刊发的一张宣传画中，蒙面人手持长枪，居高临下。冷酷的目光下，两名法国警察相拥哭泣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，该宣传物的文章通过多种互联网平台传播。刊文还提出，瑞典在发生一系列烧经事件后，“带领欧盟国家打击伊斯兰教、穆斯林国家”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿拉伯半岛基地组织是一个激进的伊斯兰主义组织，主要活跃在也门和沙特。2015年1月巴黎《查理周刊》恐怖袭击发生后，该组织“宣称负责”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“犯罪前科”与赤裸裸的挑衅，引发了法国当局的担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很长一段时间里，我们以为这种情况不会再次发生。然而阿富汗、黎凡特和非洲等正在为其提供资金，这意味着威胁可能发生。”2023年9月20日，法国内政部长达尔马宁在受访时警告，该国的恐袭风险可能死灰复燃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;达尔马宁指出，目前主要的危险仍然来自法国本土的激进分子。这些人通常是在互联网上逐步激进化，他们极度孤立，乐于接受圣战宣传，响应仇恨号召。由于宗教激进化、模仿或精神脆弱等原因，他们使用非常有限的手段实施行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，基地组织和“伊斯兰国”分支在一些地区重建。在萨赫勒地区，尤其是在黎凡特和阿富汗，毒品网络正在重建，并有可能为恐怖主义提供资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有了钱，这些组织就可以通过渗透移民潮等方式，就地培训圣战分子。就像2015 年11 月13 日袭击事件中的一些行凶者一样。他们还可以远程培训其他人。”达尔马宁说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;罩袍禁令&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;拉锯战&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据法国BFMTV 9月15日报道，该恐怖组织呼吁“让穆斯林儿童独处”“在父母的保护下成长”。这段文字，加上针对“巴黎某个部级政府部门”的威胁，暗示基地组织指的是与最近法国国内的“Abaya禁令”相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很难不把它与最近法国学校禁止穿Abaya联系起来，尽管根本没有提到这一点。”报道称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿巴雅（Abaya）是一种宽松的长袍，可以遮罩女性身体曲线。在法国学校中，常常可以看到女性穆斯林学生穿着阿巴雅上学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月末，法国政府以政教分离原则为由，禁止学生穿这种有着明显宗教标志的服装。据教育部门指令，9月开学时，穿阿巴雅到校的学生禁止进入课室，之后由校方向她们“解释禁令的意义所在”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国总统马克龙在此项问题上强调，政府在这个关系世俗主义原则的问题上“绝不让步”。他表示，“我们知道会有违规的情况出现……有些或许只出于一时疏忽，但相当一部分是想要挑战共和价值。我们决不能妥协。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管法国政府就禁令表现出了强硬姿态，但依然有穆斯林学生身穿罩袍到校。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据法国教育部统计，9月4日开学时，全国有298名学生穿着罩袍上学，其中只有67名学生坚持不愿脱掉罩袍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间9月7日，法国克莱蒙费朗高中一名女孩因坚持穿着罩袍上学而被禁止入校。随后，女孩父亲向校长发出了“割喉”死亡威胁。校长报警后，该名家长当晚被警方扣留。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了学生群体外，也有很多穆斯林支持者以多种方式反对“罩袍禁令”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国政府颁布禁令后，包括巴黎南方教育协会在内的三家机构提出上诉，他们要求中止禁令，称禁令违反了“基本自由”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月19日，十多名穆斯林女性聚集在法国驻奥地利大使馆门外，就阿巴雅禁令对法国穆斯林妇女表示声援。在线传播的抗议视频中可以看到，一位身穿橘色长袍、头戴头巾的女性高举抗议标牌，上面写着“Abaya，我们的身份，我们的权利”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“法国的穆斯林政策，其实是其针对所有族群公民基本要求的组成部分。”上海外国语大学中东研究所研究员钮松告诉南方周末记者，就宗教服饰而言，其所涉及的也不只是头巾问题，其他宗教包括基督教的相关服饰或标志也在限制之列。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“换言之，法国在公共领域对于宗教服饰、标志的限制，并不是针对特定的宗教，但宗教信仰者的抗争也一直伴随着政策推行的过程。即便是法国社会内部，也存在着对共和同化与政教分离原则的理解和执行方法上的不同看法。总之，围绕头巾、abaya服装的激烈对抗不仅撕裂了法国社会，而且也必然激怒保守的穆斯林群体。”钮松说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;争论持续多日后，法国最高法院9月25日作出裁定，政府对穆斯林服饰长袍的禁令是“合乎法律”的。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;为什么&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;总&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;是法国？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2015-2016年，法国巴塔克兰音乐厅枪击案、《查理周刊》袭击案等接连发生，暴力恐怖袭击愈演愈烈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年7月14日，造成至少84人死亡的“尼斯海岸恐袭案”发生后，英国安全智库“现实主义研究地缘政治与安全中心（CGSRS）”刊发名为《为什么总是法国》的报告，试图分析法国境内恐袭高发的内在逻辑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报告称，虽然其他欧洲国家也经历过恐怖主义，但是“法国正在呈现出一种明显的模式”“受到的影响尤为严重”。同时，虽然袭击者宣称“效忠极端组织”，但大多数人都是年轻的法国公民，且呈现小团体式活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么法国成为本土伊斯兰恐怖主义如此突出的目标？报告对此作出了多个解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是外交政策。报告称，法国长期以来一直干预穆斯林世界，特别是中东和北非（MENA）地区。因而伊斯兰主义者经常把法国视为“合法目标”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，法国人口构成增加了伊斯兰恐怖袭击的可能性，比如7%-9%的人口是穆斯林，远高于德国或英国等其他欧洲大国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，来自中东和北非地区的移民缺少流动机会，长期生活在贫困之中，由此带来对法国本土人民和机构的“不信任和仇恨”。最后，法国有着悠久的世俗主义传统，许多公民对任何形式的宗教都持非常消极的看法。这让一些穆斯林群体感到宗教自由受到了攻击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于法国缘何被极端组织“盯上”，多名中国国际关系学者也向南方周末记者作出解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钮松认为，在西方阵营内部，法国针对多元族群和信仰群体的态度较为“严苛”，强调族群平等并捍卫世俗化原则，不允许宗教元素在公共领域过分展示。因此，围绕头巾问题、abaya服饰问题等所产生的矛盾与冲突便会周期性呈现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，外来移民、难民与欧洲社会存在着结构性矛盾，这既包括经济实力上的显著差距，更包括文明背景上的迥异。德国与意大利等国对穆斯林移民的态度与政策相对温和，而法国因其严格的世俗化政策而更容易在宗教服饰等问题上激化早已累积的矛盾，并因问题的涉教性而难有回旋余地。法国自然成为恐怖组织在欧洲展开袭击的“优先”选项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国人民大学国际事务研究所所长王义桅告诉南方周末记者，法国是近代欧洲文明的发源地。法国大革命的自由、平等、博爱理念影响了整个欧洲。但是，自由的泛滥也带来了对其他文明的冒犯，这会引起保守主义者的不满。同时，法国穆斯林人口众多，针对外部穆斯林世界的行为也会引起内部的反弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如《为什么总是法国》报告中预测，“由于问题的复杂性和深度，法国未来可能面临更多恐怖袭击”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;这&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;不是新鲜事&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;除了法国外，瑞典也是这场“恐袭预告”中的袭击对象。这与瑞典国内数月来激进主义者焚烧经书风波有关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2023年6月起，瑞典多地发生焚烧、亵渎伊斯兰宗教典籍事件，主要参与者为伊拉克难民萨尔万·莫米卡（Salwan Momika）和萨尔万·纳吉姆（Salwan Najem）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二人多次公开反对伊斯兰宗教典籍《古兰经》，并举行示威活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，在这次“恐袭预告”之前，瑞典就因“烧经”事件被其他极端组织“点名”恐吓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，基地组织媒体平台“As-Sahab 媒体基金会”（The As-Sahab Media Foundation）在一份题为“攻击侵略民族的义务”的公告中呼吁，对丹麦和瑞典在过去几个月中发生的焚烧经书行为展开“报复”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月13日，英国外交部发布出行警告，称瑞典很有可能发生袭击事件，其安全当局已挫败了多起袭击企图。中国驻瑞典使馆也提醒，中国公民应关注瑞典当前安全形势变化，提高安全意识，保持高度警惕，加强安全防范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月17日，瑞典将该国恐怖主义威胁等级从3级提升至4级“高威胁状态”，这是2016年以来的首次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瑞典当局称，这一决定是基于瑞典安全形势不断恶化而作出的“综合性、长期性和战略性判断”。此后，瑞典多个部门在边境、机场、公共交通等多领域加强安全措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于瑞典遇到的“恐袭威胁”，英国国王学院瑞典恐怖主义研究员汉斯·布鲁恩（Hans Brun）认为，这些威胁“并不是新鲜事”，没那么重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他告诉瑞典TT新闻社，“你可以把它看作是对个人行动的号召。如果这是他们自己组织的，他们就不会这样提前宣布。你还应该记住，基地组织如今已被大大削弱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布鲁恩表示，基地组织的声明不会影响整体安全局势，最大的影响可能是在中东工作的丹麦和瑞典外交官，他们可能需要采取额外的预防措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布鲁恩的“预言”并非空穴来风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，激进分子在瑞典首都斯德哥尔摩一座清真寺外焚烧经书后，伊拉克抗议者冲进瑞典驻伊大使馆，驱逐了大使并烧毁了使馆。伊拉克总理苏达尼甚至因此驱逐了瑞典大使，并暂停了瑞典电信公司爱立信的工作许可。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至目前，瑞典政府正在寻求法律手段限制近日来愈演愈烈的经书焚烧事件，以缓和与伊斯兰国家的紧张关系。然而，支持者们则提出，这可能违反该国宪法。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;他们会采取行动吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自2023年9月8日橄榄球世界杯开幕以来，法国一直在举办大型活动，包括查尔斯三世国王来访、教皇来访等，而这些活动将一直持续到2024年巴黎奥运会。正如法国内政部长达尔马宁在受访时感慨，“恐怖主义风险很高，重大事件接踵而至”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;达尔马宁表示，为了做好奥运会安保，法国已经增加了14000名警察和宪兵，并与多个部门合作，以应对不同的风险。“我们已经为此努力了两年。”达尔马宁说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伴随着恐袭预告的发出，不少民众担心极端组织是否会付诸行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国情报研究中心副主任阿兰-罗迪埃在接受BFMTV采访时称，阿拉伯半岛基地组织威胁《查理周刊》两年后才采取行动，“这表明基地组织有能力等待”“当他们发出威胁时，随后往往会采取行动”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月28日，南方周末记者通过邮件联系到阿兰-罗迪埃，他透露了该组织的诸多细节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兰-罗迪埃表示，2013年，阿拉伯半岛基地组织通过线上出版物《Inspire》公布了11名“通缉人物”，其中包括《查理周刊》漫画家斯特凡·沙邦尼尔(Stéphan·Charbonnier）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两年后，两名自称来自基地组织的恐怖分子谢里夫·库阿奇(Cherif Kouachi) 和赛义德·库阿奇(Saïd Kouachi) 兄弟袭击了《查理周刊》，导致包括周刊主编在内的至少12人死亡，多人受伤。而肇事者之一赛义德曾于2011年在也门接受了军事式训练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兰-罗迪埃认为，自2015年袭击事件以来，极端组织发起的圣战运动似乎不再把西方国家作为直接目标，而是“通过广告招募”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这些组织似乎没有足够的手段派遣活动分子到欧洲实施恐怖行动。我们必须确保他们的演讲不会被内生的恐怖分子所利用。”阿兰-罗迪埃说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海外国语大学中东研究所钮松认为，在全球协同反恐的攻势之下，基地组织的影响力大不如以前，但其仍具有实施暴力恐怖主义袭击的动机与能力。因此，此次基地组织威胁对法国与瑞典展开袭击仍不可掉以轻心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钮松表示，事实上，包括法瑞在内的国际社会一直对基地组织的当前动向和活动能力保持高度关注和应有的警惕，不会对其口头威胁无动于衷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有人对这场恐袭预告持怀疑态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国苏凡中心(Soufan Center)资深研究员瓦西姆·纳斯尔在接受法国《观点》杂志（Le Point）采访时呼吁，民众应该保持理性，“恐慌的时刻还没有到来”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为，该杂志内容共17页，重点关注也门，对瑞典和法国的威胁只出现在第14页。“威胁当然存在，我们必须认真对待它，但目前没有理由更加恐慌。”纳斯尔说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生李金澳对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴赫：国际奥委会正考虑创办奥林匹克电子竞技运动会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258672]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;电竞能否入奥，或许不久将有一个新的答案。国际奥委会主席巴赫14日晚在这里透露，国际奥委会正在考虑创办属于电子竞技的奥林匹克运动会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴赫是在当晚举行的国际奥委会第141次全会开幕式上致辞时作上述表示的。他说：“我已经要求新的国际奥委会电子竞技委员会研究创办奥林匹克电子竞技运动会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/c802d6c41ee832ef334118874cf8eb40.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/c802d6c41ee832ef334118874cf8eb40.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254123&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据统计，全球有约30亿人玩电子游戏，其中超过5亿人对电子竞技特别感兴趣，包括虚拟体育和模拟体育，他们当中的大部分为34岁以下的年轻人。巴赫表示，这一点让国际奥委会非常看重，因此自2018年以来，国际奥委会一直以全方位的姿态介入电子竞技项目的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴赫说：“我们选择了一种方式，让我们既能活跃在电子竞技领域，又能忠实于一个多世纪以来我们所遵循的价值观。在电子竞技领域，价值观一直是我们不会逾越的红线。我们清晰的立场也赢得了电竞界越来越多的尊重。为了符合奥林匹克价值观，一家行业内领先的发行商对他们的一款热门游戏重新进行设计——这样玩家就可以射击目标，而不是人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，国际奥委会举办奥林匹克虚拟系列赛。这是国际奥委会在电子竞技领域的首个试点项目。基于奥林匹克虚拟系列赛的成功经验，国际奥委会在今年又举办了首届奥林匹克电子竞技周，结果大受欢迎——包括预选赛在内，电子竞技系列赛吸引了超过50万名参与者，比赛在所有频道上的直播浏览量超过600万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴赫说：“这是一个充满希望的开始，但这仅仅是一个开始。就像在任何运动中一样，即使在一个充满希望的开始之后，真正的比赛仍然在前面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴赫在当晚的致辞中还谈到了人工智能，他说:“我们的持续成功取决于我们如何拥抱不断加速发展的数字技术，特别是人工智能。这使得我们的《奥林匹克2020议程》更加紧迫——&#39;要么改变，要么被改变&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴赫强调，国际奥委会必须掌握主动权，“我们必须对人工智能的机遇和风险进行全面分析，然后立即采取行动。我很高兴地告诉你们，这项工作已经在进行中。如果事情进展顺利，你们可能会在巴黎（奥运会）看到一些初步的结果”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际奥委会第141次全会将持续至17日。此次全会的主要议程包括就《奥林匹克宪章》修正案以及2028年洛杉矶奥运会的项目设置进行表决，选举产生若干名新的国际奥委会委员。此外，全会将对《奥林匹克2020+5议程》的中期实施情况进行评估，并听取2024年巴黎奥运会、2028年洛杉矶奥运会、2032年布里斯班奥运会、2026年米兰-科尔蒂纳丹佩佐冬奥会以及未来两届青奥会筹备工作进展的报告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高速服务区外来师傅修车受阻：背后是“独家经营权”带来的垄断收益丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258660]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;如果车辆在高速公路服务区里坏了，只能让服务区里的维修厂修理吗？服务区维修厂的员工威胁阻拦外面请来的维修师傅修车，竟然“合理合法”？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据极目新闻报道，一辆运送水果的货车在沪昆高速江西丰城服务区休整时发生故障无法启动。在服务区汽车修理厂表示无法维修后，司机自己请了货车厂家在附近的指定维修店的师傅来到服务区准备修车。不料却遭到服务区修理厂工作人员的阻拦和恐吓。请来的维修师傅无奈之下只能离开。货车司机又联系了当地多家修理厂，但他们都不敢安排人员到服务区修车。没办法，司机只能选择把车拖下高速才得以修好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为修车与高速服务区修理厂发生冲突的事并不少见。一个多月前，湖南吉庆服务区发生了一起类似的事件，货车司机在检修自己的货车时被服务区修理人员阻止，在被告知是司机自己修理后，还口出狂言。社交网络上，涉及高速公路上修车、拖车冲突的类似吐槽不是。一些服务区修理厂的工作人员甚至对自行修车的司机施以暴力或暴力威胁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高速公路上，只有服务区里的修理厂才能修车吗？丰城服务区负责人在接受媒体采访时，表示服务区修理厂的做法“合理合法，有法可依”。该负责人口中所依的法，指的是公路法、公路安全保护条例等相关法规中“禁止在公路、公路用地范围内摆摊设点”的规定。这显然是一种曲解。所谓“摆摊设点”，指的是长时间设置相对固定的摊点，等待客户上门。对其禁止的目的，是为了避免“损坏、污染公路和影响公路畅通”。接到客户邀请后临时上路修车，恰恰是为了尽快修好车辆以避免长时间停车在路上，保障公路畅通。无论是从“摆摊设点”的定义，还是法规的立法目的来看，司机自行修车或者邀请修理人员临时到路上修车，都是完全合法的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上文中提到的湖南吉庆服务区冲突中，服务区修理人员声称是省交通厅有文件规定“下面的人”（指高速公路以外的修理厂）不能到高速上来修车，但最终没能出示相关文件。是不是有些地方的交通管理部门确实有出台这样的规定？如果确实有这样的文件，应该予以公开，并进行合法性审查。如果政府部门没有这样的规定，那这是高速公路管理部门的内部规定，还是服务区修理厂撒谎？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在车辆维修服务中，司机、车主是消费者，他们当然有自由选择修理服务提供者的权利。服务区汽修厂阻止司机自行修车或者其他修理师傅修车，强迫司机到他们的修理厂修车，是被消费者权益保护法明令禁止的“强迫交易”行为。刑法也规定，以暴力、威胁手段强买强卖商品，强迫他人提供服务或者强迫他人接受服务，情节严重的，构成强迫交易罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明显违法的行为，为什么普遍存在？问题的根源，还在于一个“利”字。正如丰城服务区负责人所说，路外汽车维修人员上服务区修车，“有损服务区修理厂的利益”。而服务区修理厂的利益，其实也是服务区、高速公路管理者的利益。高速公路服务区作为高速公路服务设施的一部分，是由高速公路管理者建设和运营的。修理厂要在服务区开业，当然要给高速公路管理者缴纳场地租金。而这些租金，一般要高出高速公路之外的场地租金，因为这不仅仅是场地租金，还暗含着“独家经营权”的溢价。正是因为高速公路管理者也从修理厂的“独家经营权”中获益，自然会尽力维护修理厂的利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种“独家经营权”溢价，在封闭的场所中非常普遍。机场候机厅、高速公路服务区的餐饮价格普遍比市区贵很多，就连中小学校内的小卖部都能拍卖出天价，背后都是因为“独家经营权”带来的垄断收益。更关键的是，这些溢价收益，并不是通过市场竞争所获得的，而是依赖于行政力量所赋予的特许经营权。对于这些具有行政垄断性质的基础设施运营商，各国的普遍做法是严格限制其利润率，在吸引社会投资和避免暴利维持公益性之间维持平衡。为此，要对其进行严格的监管，避免其依靠垄断地位损害公众利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，广东某高速公路服务区也发生过司机自行修车被修理厂员工威胁的事件。在舆论和相关部门介入下，该服务区汽修厂被停业整顿。这次江西丰城发生同样的事件，公众期待当地市场监管等部门及时出手，查处强买强卖、强迫交易，维护消费者利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[身份证、退伍证、婚姻信息、家庭住址……当一个明星被“开盒”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258670]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 12, Chen Muchi, who plays the role of Prince Yin Jiao in the movie &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot;, He posted a statement on Weibo, responding that he &quot;did have a marriage.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a4e19d459cf53705edb203836a30d784.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a4e19d459cf53705edb203836a30d784.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why suddenly Admit that you have been married? It turned out that before Chen Muchi released his statement, a screenshot purporting to be his marriage registration information had been quickly circulated on the Internet. The screenshot contains very detailed information, including not only the registration certificate number, registration institution, registrar’s name and registration date, but also personal information such as the ID number and household registration location of both men and women. Some netizens even circulated an unmosaic version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the melon-eaters discussed with enthusiasm was nothing more than: getting married and divorced at a young age? There was no response to rumors about a relationship on the Internet before, so why did you come out to respond when it was revealed that you were married? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens pointed out that Chen Muchi had to respond because he was &quot;opened&quot;. Because not only his marriage registration information is spread on the Internet, but also his ID card photo, veteran information and personal contact number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/e216e7cb88a5f40d47751c7ce1ddfeef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/e216e7cb88a5f40d47751c7ce1ddfeef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot; Open the box”? &quot;Unboxing&quot; is not essentially different from &quot;human flesh&quot;. It is an act of publicly exposing the privacy of others on the Internet with the purpose of &quot;breaking the other party&#39;s hypocrisy&quot;. It is actually an act of cyber violence that infringes on personal privacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, celebrities, like ordinary people, have the right to marry and love freely, and they can choose to do so publicly or not. Although celebrities, as public figures, will be exposed to the public eye and accept comments from the outside world, can their personal privacy be exposed at will and involuntarily? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of personal privacy leakage reflected in this incident is more serious than many people imagine. Nowadays, any ordinary person will receive sales calls from different banks, credit, and real estate companies every day, and the leakage of personal contact information has become a common occurrence. For celebrities, their ID numbers are almost an open secret. Taking airport pick-up and drop-off as an example, how do fans learn about a celebrity’s travel itinerary? Most of them have the ID numbers and itinerary information of celebrities, and this information usually comes from illegal &quot;scalpers&quot; selling it for a few yuan to dozens of yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/18a2b1484d42333596d077e3559bf7b8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height= &quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/18a2b1484d42333596d077e3559bf7b8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/208f5fa16d95e7cd3c26e368dbbbbe9a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;505&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/208f5fa16d95e7cd3c26e368dbbbbe9a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this information, they can not only grasp the star&#39;s schedule, They can also book air tickets and steal their mileage at will. Artists such as Li Chen, Wu Lei, and Jiang Yingrong have all experienced situations where their airplane seats were changed and their mileage was stolen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the desire for voyeurism is infinitely magnified, some people will even use public power to satisfy such dark desires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Chen Muchi&#39;s marriage registration information was exposed, many netizens questioned the source of the screenshots - from which channel did such detailed personal privacy information leak out? Was it the work of civil affairs system staff? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, on January 31, 2023, Hu Ge announced that he was getting married and had a daughter. However, because his wife was not a public figure, Hu Ge did not disclose her identity. Someone also exposed Hu Ge&#39;s marriage registration information, allowing netizens to discover that Hu Ge&#39;s wife is a staff member close to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/ae1f0a396113d36fa7ceeb8745b50d52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;630&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/ae1f0a396113d36fa7ceeb8745b50d52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have a lawyer Popular Science: In real life, no matter lawyers, courts, public security, or procuratorates, they cannot access citizens’ information at will. Citizens’ private information must not be accessed or leaked for non-public needs. Any access will leave traces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/26785e53c02b4b9149ebd6f7b7a5f1bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;791&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/26785e53c02b4b9149ebd6f7b7a5f1bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to respond to a Celebrities are &quot;hunting&quot; for privacy, and abusing their power, ignoring the law, and wantonly spreading personal privacy is the most terrifying part of the whole thing. The act of spreading other people&#39;s privacy based on the mentality of taking advantage of others will not only cause secondary harm to the victim, but is actually illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 1032, paragraph 1, of the Civil Code stipulates: &quot;Natural persons enjoy the right to privacy. No organization or individual may infringe on the privacy rights of others by means of spying, intrusion, disclosure, disclosure, etc.&quot; The right to privacy protects the privacy of natural persons. It can be seen from the word privacy itself that it has two characteristics: one is &quot;hidden&quot;, that is, it is not a public state. If it has been disclosed by a natural person on his own or legally disclosed, it is not private; the second is &quot;private&quot;, That is, private matters have nothing to do with other people&#39;s rights and interests, public interests, etc. It is from these two aspects that Article 1032, Paragraph 2 of the Civil Code defines privacy as: &quot;A natural person&#39;s private life is peaceful and he does not want others to know about his private space, private activities, and private information.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Article 1033 of the Civil Code stipulates that, unless otherwise provided by law or with the explicit consent of the right holder, no organization or individual may commit the following acts:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;( 1) Intruding on the private life and peace of others through phone calls, text messages, instant messaging tools, emails, leaflets, etc.;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) Entering, photographing, and peeping into other people&#39;s homes, hotel rooms, and other private spaces;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;(3) Photographing, peeping, eavesdropping, and disclosing the private activities of others;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(4) Photographing, peeping at the private parts of others’ bodies;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(5) Process other people&#39;s private information;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(6) Infringe on the privacy rights of others in other ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter whether you love or hate a person, you should not use the &quot;open box&quot; method to make other people&#39;s legally protected privacy and personal information public, and you must never do anything illegal. Blind tolerance and helplessness will only encourage the voyeurs&#39; desire for control and arrogance, allowing them to hide in dark corners and continue to do whatever they want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you are a celebrity or an ordinary person, your right to privacy is protected by law. Legal experts also emphasized that when the legitimate rights and interests enjoyed are illegally infringed, one should immediately call the police and use legal weapons to protect one&#39;s own rights and interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国足协换届选举产生新一届主席、副主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258674]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 10:13:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 16, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held in Beijing to elect new members. A term of executive committee and chairman and vice-chairman. Song Kai was elected as the new Chairman of the Chinese Football Association, and Sun Wen, Yuan Yongqing, Yang Xu, and Xu Jiren were elected as the Vice Chairman of the Chinese Football Association. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“两弹一星”元勋钱学森｜那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258622]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“灵神星”探测器升空：星际采矿还是建立基地？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258664]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;October 13, 2023, 10:19 U.S. Eastern Time (22:19 Beijing time on the same day), carrying NASA The SpaceX &quot;Falcon Heavy&quot; launch vehicle of the &quot;Psyche&quot; probe was successfully launched from the 39A launch pad of the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Base. The probe successfully entered orbit. The two first stages of the launch vehicle All thrusters were recovered and the launch mission was a complete success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the whole mission has just begun. According to NASA: The probe will have to fly 2.2 billion miles (nearly 3.6 billion kilometers) to reach &quot;16 Psyche&quot; in the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter in 2029, and orbit the asteroid for 26 months. scientific investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The magnetometer on board the probe will search for evidence of the asteroid&#39;s ancient magnetic field to prove the theory that it is the remnant of a fragmented planet&#39;s core. Gamma-ray and neutron spectrometers will help scientists determine the chemical elements that make up asteroids. A multispectral imager will provide information about its mineral composition and its topography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This exploration mission includes many first-of-its-kind scientific and technological innovations: This is the first time a human spacecraft has used Hall-effect thrusters (electromagnetic propulsion) in deep space beyond the lunar orbit. vehicle), driven almost entirely by solar energy, flew to the junction of the inner solar system and the outer solar system; it was also the first time for humans to explore the first M-type asteroid metallic body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA emphasized: This project is the result of comprehensive cooperation between the American scientific community and industry. The main research team is led by Lindy Elkins-Tanton of Arizona State University, and more than a dozen other universities and research institutions participate. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory and Caltech in Southern California assist NASA with scientific management, systems engineering, integration and testing, and mission operations. Maxar Technologies&#39; team in California is responsible for the solar power system and the &quot;Hall electric pusher&quot;. SpaceX&#39;s Falcon Heavy launch vehicle is responsible for the probe launch mission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to NASA&#39;s scientific expedition mission, this project is of great significance to the future development of mankind. It can be said to be the first step in the exploration journey of &quot;interstellar mining&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;16 Psyche&quot; is located in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter. It was discovered by the Italian astronomer Gasparis on March 17, 1852. It was named after &quot;Greek mythology&quot; by humans. Named after Psyche, the wife of the soul and Eros, the god of love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The long axis of its ellipsoidal body is 225 kilometers, and it is almost entirely made of metal. Its mass is astonishingly large, about 272 million tons, accounting for about 0.6% of the total mass of celestial bodies in the &quot;asteroid belt&quot;. The metal proportion of this asteroid reaches 82.5%, and its main components are iron, nickel, and precious metals such as gold, platinum, and copper. &quot;Forbes&quot; and others value it at between US$1 billion and US$100 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists are curious: Why is the metal content of this asteroid so high? One theory is that it is the remnant core of an early planet in the early stages of the formation of the solar system. During the growth process of a planet, it was hit by other celestial bodies, and its outer crust and mantle were shattered into countless fragments, leaving only bare metal material. The original planetary core. The reason for this speculation is that the small &quot;Psyche&quot; actually has two large impact craters, and there is no sign of water or hydrated minerals on its surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, human research on the planet’s core is still extremely limited. We have not even drilled through 1/3 of the thin crust, the outermost layer of the Earth’s structure. Research on the mantle and core can only be done. Make inferences based on seismic waves. If &quot;Spirit Star&quot; is indeed proven to be a rocky planetary core, then this cooled planetary core will allow humans to intuitively understand the structure of the planet&#39;s core and gain a deeper understanding of the planet&#39;s origin, evolution, and development. This will further promote the rapid development of geophysical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA’s launch of a probe to the “Spirit Star” is undoubtedly paving the way for the commercialization of space resources in the future. This kind of investment in technology and capital is very long-term. Just like Prince Enrique in the early days of the &quot;Great Navigation&quot;, he continued to invest in the ocean for decades, but it took several generations for the Portuguese royal family to get feedback from the ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With human aerospace technology, the cost of mining from extraterrestrials and transporting it back to earth will be so high that 1 kilogram of pig iron is more expensive than the same weight of top-quality diamonds. So, why do NASA and Musk conduct such research and exploration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author believes that their idea is not to smelt iron on the &quot;Ling Shen&quot; and then send it back to the earth, but to &quot;colonize Mars&quot;. &quot;Ling Shen&quot; is extremely far away from the earth, but relatively close to Mars. &quot;Mars colonization&quot; requires a large amount of building materials. If iron, nickel and other metals from &quot;Spirit Star&quot; are used, it will be much cheaper than transporting materials from the earth to Mars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Iron and nickel are the basic materials for making stainless steel. Using solar energy, space metallurgy is directly performed in a vacuum space environment. The production process is completely different from that on the earth, and no carbon-based energy and catalysts are needed. Musk insists on exploring the application of stainless steel in his &quot;Starship&quot; research and development, rather than the carbon fiber aerospace materials used by other countries. This can be explained logically: they have considered the selection of materials for large-scale infrastructure and manufacturing on extraterrestrial planets. question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Musk has also invested in Solar City to develop solar energy. This can be explained by NASA taking great technical risks to use solar-powered &quot;Hall thrusters&quot; in the &quot;Psyche&quot; mission. pass. In the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, solar radiation is already weak, so why choose a less efficient solar drive? It seems that NASA is exploring technology to improve the efficiency of its use under the conditions of low solar energy in deep space. This is the exploratory spirit of &quot;knowing that there are tigers in the mountains, and prefer to travel to the tiger mountains&quot;, which shows his great determination, firm will and action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I played the video game &quot;StarCraft&quot;, and &quot;interstellar mining&quot; was the first step in building a base. Unexpectedly, before reaching old age, human beings have already begun to try to realize their dreams. It can be said that thousands of sails are racing against each other and hundreds of teams are competing against each other. The vision of humanity becoming a space-faring species is getting closer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 09:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>