<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[该在小学阶段把体育变主科吗？不要忘掉强身健体的初衷丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261373]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The official website of the Ministry of Education shows: Representatives of the People&#39;s Congress proposed &quot;About changing the physical education subject from a minor subject to a main subject, and providing free distribution to primary school students&quot; Physical Education Textbook Suggestions”. The Ministry of Education responded: There is no priority among the subjects prescribed in the national curriculum plan. Each subject has its own unique educational value and cannot be substituted for each other. At the same time, each subject cooperates with each other to educate students collaboratively to ensure the achievement of training goals. Physical education and health courses are an important part of the basic education curriculum system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the reply from the Ministry of Education, &quot;there is no distinction between primary and secondary subjects&quot; avoiding the distinction between major subjects and minor subjects; the statement that &quot;each subject has its unique educational value&quot; is also correct. However, it is still necessary to discuss the common understanding of what is a major subject and what is a minor subject. As far as primary schools are concerned, the main subjects generally recognized by the public are nothing more than Chinese, mathematics and foreign languages, and the minor subjects are nothing more than physical education, art and music. There are two specific criteria for classification: first, teaching time, the main subject generally has more teaching time than minor subjects; second, the main subject will have a closed-book examination, and the results will be included in the total score of the mid-term, final and entrance exams to become an outstanding student or to be promoted. The standards of a good school. The latter criterion is more commonly used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Compulsory Education Curriculum Plan and Curriculum Standards (2022 Edition)&quot; stipulates that the proportion of total class hours in nine years is 20%-22% for Chinese, which is very high, 13%-15% for mathematics, and 13%-15% for foreign languages. 6%-8%, physical education and health 10%-11%, exceeding foreign languages, science or physics, chemistry 8%-10%, according to the Ministry of Education, this proportion, &quot;higher than the United States , Australia, Germany, Russia, South Korea, Japan, Finland, the United Kingdom, Canada and other countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, from the perspective of teaching time, physical education is already the main subject in the compulsory education stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the primary promotion from primary school to junior high school is mainly based on interviews and admissions to the nearest &quot;good junior high school&quot; and admission by lottery, there is no unified examination for primary school to junior high school. In this sense, it seems meaningless to talk about major subjects and minor subjects at the primary school level. Because there are no exams. However, there are also some good schools that conduct the so-called &quot;secret test&quot; or resume + interview to obtain good students. Of course, the test is still on traditional cultural subjects or main subjects such as language and mathematics, and will not test physical education. In this sense, primary schools Stage physical education is a minor subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, junior high school is very different. Physical education must be included in the total score of the high school entrance examination. The original intention is to make children pay attention to sports. The score is not low. Under one physical education subject, there are many test items, which is essentially equivalent to taking several tests. In order to get high scores or even perfect scores, schools and parents force children to take exams, which increases the academic burden instead of reducing it. &quot;Junior high school students in the gym&quot; have even become a strange sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially parents in urban areas spend a lot of money to hire private tutors for their children, which has led to a skyrocketing fee for various sports coaches. This essentially requires junior high school students to be trained according to athlete standards. Extensive training and overtraining have resulted in a large number of sports injuries for children, such as knee meniscus injuries, which is detrimental to children&#39;s physical health, growth and development, and is contrary to physical fitness. The positioning of fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because mass sports and competitive sports are completely different things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Popular sports are suitable for everyone. They are designed to allow the body to have necessary activities, to allow muscles to exercise, move the muscles and bones, and strengthen the body. Even if you participate in certain ball games or track and field events, the level of It is also amateur-level; at the same time, exercisers can breathe fresh air outdoors, establish a connection with nature, and repair their body and mind; it is also often a social activity that meets the need for interactive connections with others and helps promote mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competitive sports are played by a very small number of people with athletic talent. They are essentially a breakthrough in the limits of human physical ability. Among many competitive sports, many commercially successful industries and profit models have emerged. Including selling tickets + selling broadcast rights + advertising endorsements, etc., the income of top sports stars is very high; large-scale events such as the Olympics are participated in by countries and regions, and they have a higher meaning. Athletes winning medals are regarded as bringing glory to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the sports for students in ordinary primary and secondary schools should be a type of mass sports, which allows students to go outdoors more and strengthen their bodies. It is best to have their own favorite projects and get the benefits from sports. Fun and spiritual joy, under the blue sky and sun, soothing the body and mind and cultivating the spirit, this is something everyone can do. Children who are talented in sports and are interested in making a career in competitive sports can enter specialized sports schools to bring out their talents and potential. Being physically strong is only a very basic requirement. In short, the two types of schools have completely different requirements for student physical education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If physical education is included in the total score of mid-term and final exams at the primary school level and becomes the so-called &quot;main subject&quot;, it will only be counterproductive. Working hard to train in events you don’t like in order to get high scores. Overtraining and improper training often lead to sports injuries. Physical education classes will become hard labor and children will not feel the joy of sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, recess has this tendency. It was originally intended to allow children more time to exercise, but many schools insist on making it ritualistic, pursuing uniformity and grandeur. Instead, children view recess as a daunting prospect. Sports activities should be relaxing and fun, so that they can exercise the body and mind. Fun, meaningful physical activity is itself a natural medicine for maintaining and promoting mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, many children have psychological problems. One of the reasons is that families and schools force children to take exams in knowledge education, and parents neglect character education and values ​​education for their children. The second reason is that children generally need to Strengthen the cultivation of physical and mental repair mechanisms and habits. In fact, what children now lack is not physical activity time, but physical activity time that is fun, meaningful, can release their nature, and can soothe the body and mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the high school entrance examinations in ordinary junior high schools, it is the right direction for various places to change the physical education examination from a merit-based examination to a standard examination in 2022, so that children do not need to work hard on the physical education examination items, consume too much or even Destroy your own body just for high scores; only specialized sports schools need to select the best to stimulate the talents of good talents and continue to work towards challenging the limits of human physical fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川两县禁止“私熏腊肉”：尊重民众传统权利，或可推无烟熏制丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261371]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, two counties in Bazhong, Sichuan have banned citizens from smoking bacon privately and required them to smoke bacon at designated centralized smoking points. Officials The response was to prevent air pollution. To ban a traditional food preparation method and folk custom that has lasted for more than a thousand years on the grounds of environmental protection is to ignore the traditional rights of the people and is even suspected of rent-seeking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tongjiang and Nanjiang counties in Bazhong, Sichuan, have recently issued notices prohibiting self-smoking of pickled products in urban areas. Those who need to smoke must go to designated centralized smoking points for smoking. Violators may be fined. There is a service charge for curing bacon at centralized smoking sites, and of the two centralized smoking sites announced in Tongjiang County, one clearly states that it only smokes meat products purchased from the company. The officially designated centralized smoking point is suspected of administrative monopoly and profit transfer, which has attracted great attention on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau responded that smoking bacon during the winter festival is a local custom, but the smoke produced during smoking seriously affects the ambient air quality. In order to improve the urban ambient air quality, Eliminate safety hazards and therefore set up centralized smoking points. The response also stated that the statement in the original notice that a centralized smoking site only smoked meat products purchased from the company reflected lax control and work errors. After consultation with the company, the smoking site was opened to the public. Staff of the Nanjiang County Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau also told the media that they have paid attention to the online discussion, and leaders are meeting to study it, and the results will be announced to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Tongjiang and Nanjiang counties, but also Bazhou District, Jingkai District, Enyang District and other places in Bazhong City have also previously designated 10 bacon smoking sites. In October, due to the frequent occurrence of bacon smoking, which resulted in insufficient performance of air pollution prevention and control work, four local sub-district office principals were interviewed and reported to the whole district. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bacon has a long history. Legend has it that bacon was available during the battle between Huangdi and Chi You, and there are records of bacon in classics such as &quot;The Book of Changes&quot;, &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot; and &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Sichuan smoked bacon also has a history of one or two thousand years. Originally, bacon was made to extend the preservation time of meat, but now, bacon has become an important folk custom. For many Sichuan people, bacon is the taste of home and the New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many places in Sichuan have their own signature bacon products, such as Qingchengshan bacon, Guangyuan Qingchuan bacon, Liangshan Mianning bacon, Beichuan bacon, and Dazhou bacon, all of which are famous local specialties. In 2013, the former Ministry of Agriculture approved the implementation of agricultural product geographical indication protection for “Wanyuan Old Bacon” in Dazhou, Sichuan. However, as efforts to control smog intensify, many places in Sichuan have banned the traditional method of smoking bacon, and many local specialty products are facing the dilemma of disappearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Smoking bacon is a custom that has been passed down for thousands of years, but now it has to be stopped because of &quot;polluting the air&quot;. Is this reasonable? Even if smoked bacon does cause air pollution, but people tolerate it, is it necessary for the government to ban it across the board? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much impact smoked bacon has on air quality requires scientific evaluation. Did smoking bacon bring down the air quality of the entire city? Or is there actually another more important factor in air pollution, and bacon is just a scapegoat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, how much pollution can centralized smoking reduce compared with private smoking? According to the official statement, dedicated smokehouses have been built at centralized smoking sites and are equipped with corresponding environmental protection equipment to reduce pollution. So, how much pollution can centralized smoking reduce? Do environmentally friendly equipment really work? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, just banning self-smoked meat in urban areas, how much impact can it have on environmental protection? In the county, many people&#39;s hometowns are in the countryside. If fumigation is not allowed in the city, then go back to your hometown and the countryside to smoke. Wouldn&#39;t it also cause pollution? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mandatory centralized smoking and the charging of service fees will undoubtedly increase the cost of smoked meat for citizens. Although officials say that centralized smoking points only charge cost fees, because centralized smoking points are designated and there is no market competition at all, the owners of centralized smoking points will inevitably tend to charge more. In the process of formulating smoking sites, whether there is rent-seeking or not is also a matter of public concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the traditional method of smoking bacon is indeed seriously polluted, it is not impossible to properly manage it. However, management does not prohibit self-smoking meat across the board, nor can smoking points be determined in a designated way. In fact, not only large-scale smoking companies can build special smokehouses and add environmental protection facilities such as smoke filtration to reduce pollution, but small smokeless and environmentally friendly bacon smoking machines have also been available for a long time. As early as 2018, a smokeless and environmentally friendly bacon smoking machine appeared in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to testing by the Chongqing Ecological Environment Testing Center, using this environmentally friendly smoker, the concentration of particulate matter in the air has been reduced from 400 to 500 mg per cubic meter in traditional open smokers to about 3 mg. It has been reduced from 40 mg per cubic meter to about 0.6 mg. Such a small smoking machine only sells for 20,000 to 30,000 yuan, and ordinary merchants can buy it to smoke bacon for customers. It is even possible for someone to buy one by themselves or in partnership. Although the smoking machine requires a certain cost, the sealed machine can reduce the spread of smoke and reduce the use of wood to a certain extent. Taken together, it is not much more expensive than the traditional open smoking method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Chongqing City also banned citizens from smoking bacon in the name of environmental protection, which also caused a lot of controversy. After the successful development of a smokeless and environmentally friendly smoking machine, citizens&#39; demand for smoked bacon has been met, and air pollution has been greatly reduced, getting the best of both worlds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, environmental protection is a very important task of the government. However, environmental protection should not come at the expense of public convenience and traditional customs. In the past, some places banned the burning of coal for heating in rural areas in winter, and instead used natural gas or electricity for heating. But even with government subsidies, the cost of heating is still much higher than burning coal, and farmers are overwhelmed. In some places, farmers have even been stripped of their firewood stoves and are not allowed to burn firewood, only gas. In some places, people are prohibited from burning paper money during sacrifices, and it is prohibited to burn paper houses, paper horses and other traditional funeral objects. These have caused great controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The environmental protection government has KPIs, but they cannot override folk customs and people&#39;s livelihood. After all, talents are the measure of all things. The government&#39;s environmental policies and measures must fully consider the lives of ordinary people and should not grossly interfere with people&#39;s living habits and interrupt thousands of years of traditional folk customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[扶持招商引资企业？四川通江指定集中熏肉点，是什么来历]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261361]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/26/d36424a746.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 26/d36424a746.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 18, 2023, villagers in Shiyi Village, Mianyang, Sichuan There are more than 2,000 kilograms of sausages and bacon hanging in the house, and the aroma of bacon is fragrant to welcome the New Year. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, Tongjiang County, Bazhong City, Sichuan Province issued a notice stating that private smoking of cured products, smoked bacon, sausages, etc. is prohibited in the urban area. It needs to be sent to two designated centralized smoking points. On the evening of November 23, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau issued an apology announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the apology only addressed the statement in the notice that &quot;smoking is limited to meat products purchased from the company&quot; and did not revoke the regulations prohibiting residents from smoking meat privately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the practice of &quot;smoking bacon at designated points to prevent air pollution&quot; has been practiced in some areas of Sichuan for many years, and the necessity and effectiveness have been controversial. The announcement of the passage of the river has attracted attention, partly because the centralized smoking points designated by the government are also associated with enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Their charging standards are not low.&quot; Qian An is from Tongjiang County and is engaged in information self-media work there. He learned from the government that these two companies were local investment projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The price of bacon was questioned&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first announcement that caused controversy was released on November 15. The announcement stated that with the arrival of the peak season for smoking wax products, the smoke and dust produced by smoking will pollute the air and pose fire safety risks. In order to respect tradition and facilitate citizens, while protecting the ecological environment and ensuring the safety of smoking, it will be prohibited to sell smoked products in farmers’ markets, county towns, Cured products are smoked in non-designated places such as courtyards, corridors, balconies, roofs, and beside rock slopes, roadsides, river ditches, etc. It is prohibited to build cured products smoking facilities without authorization in the county. Cured products in the county are smoked at designated points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The announcement lists the addresses and contact information of two designated smoking sites. Among them, the second smoking site specifically states that “smoking is limited to the company (Bashan Mu). meat products purchased by the industry). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s too far.&quot; After receiving the news about the ban on privately smoked meat, a resident of Tongjiang County&#39;s first reaction was that it was inconvenient because there was something wrong with him at home. The elderly and children need to be taken care of. If you are running back and forth specifically to smoke bacon, you won&#39;t have time to take care of it. Later, he noticed that one of the centralized smoking sites did not allow bringing in meat. He believed that there was suspicion of bundled sales and forced sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The statement in the original notice that &#39;smoking is limited to meat products purchased from this company&#39; reflects our lax control and mistakes in our work.&quot; On November 23 In its apology announcement on the 2nd, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau revised this regulation, saying that after consultation with the company, the smoked site will be opened to the public at the same time. The announcement also explained that centralized smoking points are located outside the smoking control area and are equipped with spraying, filtration and other related environmental protection equipment, and cost fees are charged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters called the contact numbers of the two centralized smoking sites announced in the notice to inquire about the charging standards, but received no reply. According to CCTV, the prices at the first centralized smoking point are divided into two types. If you bring your own marinated meat, it will be charged at about 1.6 yuan to 2 yuan per catty; if you need to pickle it, it will be charged at about 4 yuan per catty. Charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qian An learned that the processing fee for smoked bacon from Bashan Animal Husbandry is 3.5 yuan per catty, and the packaging fee is additional. &quot;Smoking alone costs 3.5 yuan per catty. A pig sometimes has two to three hundred catties of meat. If you smoke it once, it will cost nearly a thousand yuan. It is quite expensive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;Tongjiang County has a permanent population of about 500,000, of which the county population is about 200,000. In response to residents’ complaints that the designated smoking point is far away, the apology announcement mentioned that the first centralized smoking point has five convenience collection points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Winter folk custom of smoked bacon. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dc3db80ae8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;941&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dc3db80ae8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259735 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Smoked bacon is a folk custom in winter. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“We want to support our enterprises”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the announcement from Tongjiang County, the first centralized smoking point is located in Bizhou The first community in Chengdong Village, sub-district, covers an area of ​​2,000 square meters. It has a smokehouse, management room, oil fume purification equipment and related supporting facilities. The construction area is about 600 square meters. The daily smoked wax products volume is about 5,000 kilograms. The construction has been completed. , the equipment is being debugged and will be put into use on November 25. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the industrial and commercial information and found that the mobile phone number left at the smoking site was the registered phone number of Jinyu Building Materials Business Department of Damian Street Office in Longquanyi District. The company was registered in Chengdu and its main businesses are building materials and hardware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We are a company, and bacon is one of our businesses.&quot; On November 24, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the number, and the other party replied that the smoking point had just opened It has been built but has not yet been fully put into use. In terms of its scale, it can meet the requirements of nearby residents; they provide door-to-door collection services, and residents can also go there on their own with the meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Many people called me and scolded me. I was really scared.&quot; The person in charge of the company said that in recent days, he had suffered Violence on the Internet has caused great trouble to oneself. &quot;They (netizens) may have some misunderstanding. Another company said that you have to buy their meat before it can be smoked, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another thing in the notice A centralized smoking point is located next to Gaokeng Power Station in Chunzai Industrial Park. It is a self-built wax products smoking point for Bazhong City Bashan Animal Husbandry Co., Ltd. (referred to as Bashan Animal Husbandry), with a daily smoked wax product volume of about 2,000 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bashan Animal Husbandry is a leading local agricultural and animal husbandry enterprise and has been listed on the New Third Board. According to the company&#39;s official website, Bashan Animal Husbandry was established in May 2011 and is headquartered in Tongjiang County Industrial Park. It specializes in Qingyu pig breeding and the development of the entire industry chain. Cold chain logistics, marketing, and brand creation create whole-industry chain standards and systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Why are these two companies designated to smoke meat for residents? Qian An consulted the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau and provided the recording to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qian An said that the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau responded that the designated smoking point is a government investment promotion project and an investment promotion enterprise. &quot;(Bashan Animal Husbandry) is an enterprise that has made outstanding contributions to local economic development. From an emotional point of view, our local government also wants to support our local enterprises, but now it is difficult for enterprises to develop.&quot; In the recording, a member of the bureau the staff said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters did not find the public bidding information for setting up centralized smoking points in Tongjiang County; they called the reporting hotline on the notice and Tongjiang County’s comprehensive administrative law enforcement multiple times The office phone calls were not answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Smoked bacon is a tradition in the Sichuan and Chongqing regions with a history of more than 2,000 years. In recent years, it has faced questions about air pollution. As early as 2015, after the Environmental Protection Bureau of Dazhou, Sichuan stated that &quot;smoked bacon is the main cause of poor air quality,&quot; the local government set up centralized smoking points in the central city. At that time, the media explained that centralized smoking did not replace the widespread smoke from cooking with concentrated pollution. Its biggest advantage was that it made it easier for the government to identify problems and standardize management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Che Zhenming, a professor at the School of Food and Bioengineering at Xihua University, believes that family-style, small-scale, and small-scale smoked bacon will not have much impact on the environment. . He told CCTV that because the air is flowing, especially in a city like Bazhong, which is not densely populated, even if some pollution occurs, it will dissipate quickly. However, if smoked bacon is carried out industrially and on a large scale, its impact on the prevention and control of air pollution needs to be taken seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南周口联通以断网逼用户换光猫？是否涉嫌诈骗罪，主管部门应严肃调查以正视听丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261355]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it was exposed that Henan Zhoukou China Unicom Company fired engineers who did not complete marketing tasks and forced users to replace optical modems, causing extensive attention. Zhoukou China Unicom stated that provincial and municipal companies have set up special work teams to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report on the Henan TV Metropolis Channel program, a fired China Unicom engineer revealed to the program that in order to force users to replace optical modems, Zhoukou China Unicom Company would first stop users’ broadband accounts in the background, and then come to visit engineers. They will falsely claim that &quot;the optical modem is damaged&quot; and require the user to replace the device, charging 299 yuan. After replacing the optical modem, restore user network services from the background. This China Unicom engineer said that when installing computers for new users, China Unicom Zhoukou Company will also use the old optical modems replaced by other users to install computers for the new users. After the new users have used them for a period of time, the engineers will come to the door and tell them that the optical modem model is too old. &quot;No longer matches&quot;, the user will be asked to reinstall Sunbeam Cat. The engineer also said that starting from June 2023, Zhoukou China Unicom requires each engineer to complete terminal replacement tasks for 10 households per month. Because he failed to complete the task, the company unilaterally terminated the labor contract without any compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that this engineer chose to reveal the &quot;shady story&quot; of China Unicom because he was dissatisfied with being fired. This incident involves two different issues. One is a labor contract dispute. Whether it is reasonable to assign marketing tasks to technical staff, and whether it is legal to dismiss employees because they cannot complete the tasks, this issue can be resolved through the labor dispute resolution mechanism, resorting to labor arbitration or the court. Regardless of whether the engineer is a regular employee who has directly signed a labor contract with China Unicom, or is dispatched to China Unicom through a labor dispatch company, his legitimate rights and interests should be safeguarded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another question, which is more related to the public interest, is whether China Unicom has used technical means to force users to replace optical modems. If this question is true, it is very bad and suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the fired engineer’s revelations, in order to force users to replace optical modems, China Unicom Zhoukou would first stop users’ broadband in the background, preventing users from accessing the Internet, creating the illusion of a network failure. After the user reported the problem, they lied that the optical modem was broken and asked the user to pay for a new optical modem. After the replacement, the broadband was restored. It looked like the fault was repaired after the optical modem was replaced. For new users, they will deliberately use the old optical modem during installation. After a period of time, they will ask the user to replace it with a new one on the grounds that the optical modem does not match. Otherwise, they will not be able to access the Internet normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is undoubtedly a serious accusation. Compared with ordinary users, operators have absolute technological and information advantages. When broadband fails, ordinary users have no way of knowing the specific cause and can only rely on operators. It is very bad if operators rely on information advantages to defraud users, charge users, or achieve other goals. The deputy director of the office of Zhoukou China Unicom said that if you disconnect the Internet privately, induce users to change terminals, and maliciously charge fees, it is an illegal operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this matter is true, I am afraid it is not just a violation of regulations. First of all, this violates the service contract with the user and is a breach of contract. Users sign a broadband service contract with a telecom operator, and the operator is obliged to do its best to provide stable and up-to-standard broadband communication services. If a fault occurs, it should be repaired as soon as possible. If there is no fault in the first place, using technical means to create the illusion of a fault in order to achieve one&#39;s own goals, which prevents users from accessing the Internet smoothly, is undoubtedly a serious malicious act and is a fraudulent act. In addition, users are also charged a fee for exchanging bare cats. Although the amount per household is not much, the more users there are, the more the total amount is. Using fraudulent means to defraud others of property may constitute a crime of fraud if certain standards are met. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, whether this allegation is true remains to be investigated by the relevant departments. Nowadays, the communication control system in the operator&#39;s backend is very complete, and every operation will be recorded in the log, so it is not difficult to find out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, there are indeed complaints about &quot;forced replacement of optical modems&quot; on the consumer complaint platform, and some of them directly name the Unicom branch in Henan Province. Some netizens who claim to be veteran employees in the communications industry said that this kind of behavior is the default &quot;hidden rule&quot; in the industry. If customers insist on not changing terminals, the company will reduce the Internet speed. In fact, this behavior not only exists among telecom operators, but also among Internet companies. An Internet giant that provides email services once &quot;interfered&quot; with users who used other email clients to receive their own emails, making them more likely to receive garbled emails in order to induce users to download and use their own email clients. This has even been regarded as a successful marketing case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what the reason is, telecom operators want users to update their optical modems and other communication equipment. They should use incentives to attract users to voluntarily update. For example, users who replace optical modems can be upgraded to a higher network for free. Wait. It is difficult to achieve goals by setting KPI indicators for engineers. If the pressure to complete the indicators is too great, engineers may &quot;find another way&quot; to complete the task through non-compliant means, harming the interests of consumers. Some telecom operators have been exposed to malicious &quot;competition&quot; methods such as deliberately cutting off competitors&#39; optical fibers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how fierce the market competition is, work tasks should not be completed in a way that harms the interests of consumers. In response to the Zhoukou Unicom incident, the Henan Provincial Communications Administration Bureau has intervened in the investigation and conducted the first interview with Zhoukou Unicom. The management department should find out the relevant situation as soon as possible. If the situation in the revelations does exist, China Unicom should be severely punished to safeguard the interests of consumers and prevent operators from defrauding consumers by relying on asymmetric information and technological advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[监督“八小时之外”：红黄橙三色如何管住干部]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission published a report titled &quot;&quot; &quot;Besides eight hours, we must control it!&quot; article. (Photo source: &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot;)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 26/dfe4ccb610.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dfe4ccb610.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259713&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission published an article entitled &quot;Eight Hours&quot; &quot;Except&quot;, we must also take care of it! &quot;Article. (Photo source: &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three colors of red, yellow and orange have another use. In Wucheng District, Jinhua City, Zhejiang Province, they have become a way to supervise cadres &quot;eight hours away&quot; means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, a department-level cadre in Wucheng District was assigned a &quot;red code&quot; for management because he made mistakes in his life style. The cadre had an inappropriate relationship with others and was later reported by his family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong, director of the Cadre Supervision Office of the Wucheng District Party Committee Organization Department, said that the cadre was transferred from his original post after the incident and his position was demoted from a principal position to a deputy position. Its file information has been given a &quot;red code&quot; in the cadre supervision and management system and has become a key supervision object. Unless the &quot;red code&quot; in the system is lifted, the cadre&#39;s rank and position cannot be promoted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mechanism is the &quot;red, yellow and orange three-color management&quot; system, which is an important part of Wucheng District&#39;s eight-hour supervision and management method for leading cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2015, starting with Guangdong Province, many places have issued opinions on the supervision and management of &quot;eight-hour outing&quot; activities of leading cadres, and some government agencies have also formulated implementation plans. On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission published an article titled &quot;Beyond Eight Hours,&quot; We Must Control It! &quot; article emphasized the importance of supervising leading cadres&#39; &quot;eight hours away activities&quot;. Six days later, another article was published titled &quot;Refined and practical supervision and management to ensure the &quot;eight hours away&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Peng Xinlin, director of the International Anti-Corruption Education and Research Center of Beijing Normal University, this is an important means to strengthen the construction of party style and clean government and the fight against corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;3 circles, 21 items not allowed&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2023, two cadres in Wucheng District were coded for &quot;drinking&quot; manage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A cadre of the Discipline Inspection Commission went home from work and drank alcohol during the working day, and was discovered by the disciplinary inspection and supervision department during a temporary inspection. Because he violated the rule of &quot;no drinking during working days&quot;, he was reminded to talk and given a &quot;yellow code&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another cadre got into an argument with someone in the community after drinking, and the other party called the police. Because his behavior damaged the image of party members and cadres, he was admonished and given an &quot;orange code.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, during the eight-hour supervision process, &quot;red codes&quot; were assigned to cadres who had caused serious consequences or were suspected of violating laws and disciplines; &quot;yellow codes&quot; were assigned to cadres with symptoms and tendencies. cadres; those involved in minor disciplinary violations will be assigned an &quot;orange code.&quot; According to the color of the code, cadres will be transferred to the Discipline Inspection Commission, reminded to speak, and letters of advice and admonitions will be dealt with to varying degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The inspiration for this mechanism is actually traffic lights, which were first used in village cadre management.&quot; Qian Hong said that there is a &quot;three-color management&quot; interface in the local organization department cadre supervision and management system, which can be viewed The situation of assigned cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for what behaviors cadres are not allowed to do outside of eight hours, the &quot;Measures for the Supervision and Management of &quot;Eight Hours Outside&quot; Activities of Leading Cadres of Wucheng District, Jinhua City are listed in detail. This management method is governed by the District Commission for Discipline Inspection and the District Jointly issued by the Organization Department of the Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 21 prohibited behaviors, which are divided into social circle, life circle and rest circle. Each circle has 7 items. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behaviors that are not allowed in social circles include not adhering to party principles and making irresponsible remarks on the central government&#39;s policies; forming cliques and forming &quot;small circles&quot; through activities such as sororities, fellows&#39; associations, classmates&#39; associations, comrades-in-arms associations, etc., or There is no distinction between relatives and pure people, and there is collusion between officials and businessmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first prohibited behavior in the life circle is to condone and acquiesce in spouses, children and children&#39;s spouses violating regulations to run businesses and engage in profit-making activities. The behavior of having improper sexual relations with others is on the same level as blind comparison and pursuit of vulgar taste. In addition, violating family ethics and failing to respect and support parents are not allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating and drinking with public funds, traveling with public funds, entertainment with public funds, and using public cars for private use are not allowed in the leisure circle. In the leisure circle, another thing that is not allowed is using one&#39;s authority to act as a protective umbrella for illegal activities or evil forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The extent to which a specific behavior is serious enough to be &quot;coded&quot; must be determined based on the actual situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong used &quot;participating in a banquet for management service recipients&quot; as an example. If the banquet for management service recipients is not reported, at least a yellow code must be assigned; if the meal money is paid by the management service recipient, that is Orange code; if you use your authority to provide some economic convenience to the other party during this period, a warning or a serious warning or above will be given, a red code will be assigned. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Qian Hong’s view, no matter what kind of coding mechanism is essentially not a punishment system, but a cadre management system, “It’s not that cadres who committed crimes in the past There is no punishment system for mistakes, but instead of just settling the matter, problem cadres are managed as key targets to make the management of party members and cadres more standardized.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong also noticed that there are &quot;eight problems&quot; within the system There are concerns that supervision after hours may infringe on personal privacy and affect normal interpersonal interactions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When we issued the document, we explained to everyone that the supervision of the &quot;eight-hour outing&quot; activities of leading cadres will protect personal privacy within the scope of the law and will not affect their legitimate interpersonal interactions and spare time life. For example, having a meal with family and friends or going out to play, situations like this are not within the scope of our supervision.&quot; Qian Hong told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From advocacy to implementation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the implementation of the coding system, one day in August 2023, Qian Hong received an &quot;angry &quot;Ms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She went to report her husband, a department-level cadre in a township in Wucheng District. The couple were both over fifty years old. She had previously suspected that her husband had inappropriate relationships with other women, but she had no evidence. This time she checked her husband&#39;s cell phone while he was sleeping and confirmed the fact that her husband had cheated on her through chat records and transfer records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong asked her why she went to the Organization Department to report it first. Her answer was that in July 2023, the Organization Department of the Wucheng District Party Committee led a promotional activity of &quot;double -entry&quot; event. She knew that there was an opinion to find the Organization Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Double advance&quot; refers to the situation of the District Party Committee Organization Department to fully understand the &quot;eight hours&quot; of party members and cadres, and extend the supervision and management of cadres from the &quot;unit of the unit&quot; to the &quot;community courtyard&quot; backyard&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, the concept of &quot;eight hours of supervision&quot; was mentioned as earlier 20 years ago, and later became a popular saying. &quot;Zhuang Deshui, deputy director of the Research Center of the Integrity Construction Research Center of Peking University, introduced early. This concept appeared more in the speeches and reports of some leaders. Later, some places introduced some related ban and specifications, but they were mostly advocated and lacking specific execution agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that around 2001, the Central Organization Department had launched a pilot on cadre living circle and social circle inspection in Huzhou, Zhejiang. In 2004, the Organization Department of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee formulated and issued the &quot;Opinions on Promoting the Life Circle and Social Circle Inspection of Leadership Cadres&quot;, stipulating that officials in the spare time to play mahjong gambling, neighborhood relationships, and circle of friends will all become inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier, the &quot;eight -hour foreign supervision&quot; rose to the level of the rules and regulations is Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2014, after the eighth inspection team of the Central Committee inspected Guangdong, it was recommended to strengthen the daily management of party members and leading cadres and the supervision of the &quot;eight hours away&quot; activities. In August 2015, the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection, the Provincial Party Committee Organization Department, and the Provincial Human Resources and Social Affairs Department jointly issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Supervision and Management of Eight Homes&quot; activities to strengthen party members and leaders &quot;to the&quot; eight hours outside &quot;matters and supervisors responsible persons The supervision mechanism is clearly stipulated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Subsequently, Guangdong selected 147 pilot units including Shenzhen Yantian District in the province to explore the supervision and management of trial leadership cadres &quot;eight hours away&quot; activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2017, the then Secretary of the Yantian District Committee of Shenzhen City wrote in the &quot;Learning Times&quot; that Yantian District established a list of &quot;three laps&quot; (negative) report, community supervision, contact with cadre family members, eight, eight, eight, eight, A series of supervision mechanisms, such as selection and appointment and integrity assessment, and other hours. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that in the past six years, including Wucheng District, Jinhua City, Zhejiang, Zhejiang Pinghu City (county -level city -level city -level city -level city), Jiangxi Fengxin County, Hubei Zhijiang City, Henan Province, Qixian County, Henan Province The “Eight -Hour External Supervision Implementation Measures” formulated by Yuxian District, Mianyang City, Sichuan, and Jianning County, Fujian Province, has many similarities with the relevant mechanisms of Yantian District in the specific content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;contact system with the family members of the cadres&quot; in Pinghu City is mainly responsible for the supervision room of the Organization Department of the Pinghu Municipal Party Committee. . &quot;Qian Ke, deputy director of the cadre supervision office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dan Ke remembered. In a &quot;home visitor&quot;, a family complained that &quot;the other half&quot; was basically not eating at home from Monday to Friday. The family visitor group asked him if he was eating in the unit. The cadre said that he sometimes worked overtime or sometimes paid. The home visitor team immediately asked what entertainment there was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;For this situation, we will verify more channels. If some entertainment may affect performance, we will take further measures.&quot; No other discovery of the cadre&#39;s entertainment was found to have a separate conversation, and no other treatment was made. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mobilization of community forces to supervise cadres eight hours of activities is also a common method in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pinghu City has three types of &quot;eight hours of supervision and observation points&quot;: Class A is located in municipal organs and departments, category B is located in towns and villages, and Class C is located in community and village -level units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the introduction of Qianke, about 90%of Pinghu City leading cadres live in the main urban area. They set up two community supervisors in each of the densely living communities in the 21 cadres. Generally Social persons with high political quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Community supervisors are the role of an information collector. They only need to collect and feed the information. As for the authenticity of the information, the basic verification work is responsible After the implementation of the mechanism, a supervisor had reported to the town street supervision point that a cadre living in the community caused neighborhood disputes due to illegal stacking of debris in the corridor. Finally, the town street supervision point was verified and confirmed, and the organization department gave reminders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A deputy department -level cadre in a province in Northwest China expressed the recognition of the community supervision mechanism to reporters in the southern weekend. P>; In his opinion, the community security can also consider hiring community supervisors. &quot;Although they do not necessarily live in the community, which leader drinks too much every day before returning, they are clear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4 >; &quot;One vote veto&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In the process of exploring the supervision of leading cadres &quot;eight hours outside&quot;, in order to ensure the effectiveness of supervision, the supervisory department will be used for the selection and appointment of cadres in many places. The leadership team of the unit performs accountability and the unit assessment is linked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the relevant implementation measures issued by Youxian District, Mianyang City, Sichuan City, required the situation of party members and cadres to be &quot;other than eight hours&quot; and fulfilling supervision and management responsibilities in the relevant implementation measures. Important content of excellent and annual assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are similar regulations in Wucheng District, Jinhua City. Qian Hong introduced that the results of the eight -hour overseas supervision and party discipline were connected to each other, which would directly affect the promotion of the level of leading cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qian Hong for example, saying that it must not be promoted within one and a half year and a half of the party&#39;s severe warning, and it must not be promoted within one year within the party&#39;s warning. In addition, the results of the party discipline will also affect the cadres&#39; annual bonuses to varying degrees. Once they are severely warned, the bonus will be directly zero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the implementation measures of various places, internal party supervision is the primary supervision method. Party committees at all levels are responsible for the supervision and management of party members and cadres in the region, the system, and the unit. He is the first responsible person to accountability to the leadership team and cadres who are inadequate to perform their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ganke said a case: a cadre of a unit in Pinghu City was included in the &quot;red list&quot; because of the issue of eight hours. When the information collection of supervision information is not timely, the cadres of the unit are not reminded to be in place. Therefore, the organization&#39;s officer was also handled and included in the &quot;yellow list.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;Red and Yellow List&quot; is similar to the code mechanism of Wucheng District, and included in the &quot;Red List&quot; means that the cadre has been investigated and punished by the Discipline Inspection Commission. There are many tendencies, and the organization department needs to intervene early to understand the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You must not wait for the disciplinary commission to file a case and report it by the public security.&quot; Qian Hong said that the party group of the unit did not perform the main responsibility of the main body, and finally there was a problem. It will be affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In terms of cadre supervision, it involves the problem of integrity and self -discipline and life style. We deducting points are very powerful, which is almost equivalent to one vote. The question, we will deduct it to the last gear. &quot;Qian Hong told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, how to measure the effect of eight hours of overseas supervision, the relevant measures in various places did not give a clear explanation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gan Ke said frankly. At present, whether the eight -hour supervision has been effective, it depends on whether leading cadres can be self -standards outside eight hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the final analysis, it is not to deal with cadres, but to protect cadres, not to make small problems into big problems, and stifle big problems in the bud stage.&quot; Qian Ke said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, the supervision of the &quot;first leader&quot; has always been a difficulty in anti -corruption. The &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision&quot; article pointed out in an article that analyzes &quot;how to manage&quot; eight hours&#39;? &quot; Facing the dilemma of invalid supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This is indeed the case. It is slightly more difficult in this regard, and eventually the superiors and lower levels.&quot; Qian Hong admitted. Qian Keyi also found that compared with the general cadres, how to supervise the &quot;first leader&quot; eight hours of activities still exists in some specialties. &quot;From the perspective of entertainment, the &#39;leader&#39; will involve communication with some merchants and brothers. Sometimes it will participate in some entertainment. How to distinguish between this entertainment in this process is due to the public or because of private, it is indeed difficult. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; Often they can supervise others, but let them accept supervision by themselves. It&#39;s difficult. &quot;Zhuang Deshui recalled that a cadre once showed him a&quot; pessimistic &quot;attitude, thinking that it was useless to supervise eight hours.&quot; Many things cannot be effectively supervised, and real corruption is under the table. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some grassroots cadres are also worried about the durability and effectiveness of the policy. &quot;I&#39;m afraid that it will be loosened strictly for a period of time. (Long time) has policies and countermeasures.&quot; Qian Hong said that even now, some problems have caused trouble to eight hours of supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He said for example that some cadres will avoid places that the regulatory authorities focus on and go to more private places; although there are community supervision, some cadres may have houses in several communities and even other urban areas. In terms of family supervision, some cadres have not had a good relationship between husband and wife. They have their own, regardless of each other, and they are still weak. The power of social supervision is still weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Overall, we take the initiative to master clues, and the information screening efficiency is not high enough.&quot; As a colleague, it is the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mao Zhaohui, director of the Research Center of Renmin University of China Anti -Corruption and Independent Policy Policy Research, eight -hour foreign supervision can become a way to supervise the discipline of the grassroots level, but it is subject to human, material, resources, resources, and means. It is not yet possible to be a normal job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mao Zhaohui&#39;s suggestion is, &quot;If you want to achieve better results in eight hours, you should effectively introduce social supervision, including public opinion supervision and media supervision.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“每一个蚌里都可能藏着一颗奇妙的珍珠”——第十届乌镇戏剧节青年竞演]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261257]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/IGoaZnhErhcYd1kqBeoNHzM1QQUoZ05K1v0a0Mwo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/IGoaZnhErhcYd1kqBeoNHzM1QQUoZ 05K1v0a0Mwo. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Clam and Pearl&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Provided by the Wuzhen Theater Festival Organizing Committee/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the day from October 20 to 26, 2023, at the entrance of the Bengwan Theater in Xizha, Wuzhen, there was always a queue waiting to watch the show. The queue can sometimes stretch to the river. In September, free tickets for online reservations for the Wuzhen Theater Festival Youth Performance Competition (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Youth Competition&quot;&lt;/span>;) will be available at the beginning of the ticket sales It was robbed. This is one of the most important units of the Wuzhen Theater Festival every year, and it is also the only competition unit. Among the works of 18 groups of young dramatists, the Small Town Award for Best Drama, Best Individual Performance Award, and Special Attention Award will be determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a sign in front of the fence outside the Bengwan Theater, indicating that ⅩⅩⅩ spectators can be admitted for this youth game. In the theater, the works of 18 groups of young dramatists were performed in turn; a screen was temporarily hung on a stone wall outside the theater for audiences who were unable to enter to watch the live broadcast. Under the scorching sun, there were always five or six rows of enthusiastic audiences sitting on the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, the Wuzhen Theater Festival has been running for 10 years, and the Youth Competition has also been running for 10 years. Bengwan Theater is named after the earliest place name here. Huang Lei thinks it is good, &quot;There are many clams in Bengwan, and each clam may hide a wonderful pearl.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wuzhen Theater Festival One of the initiators, actor Huang Lei, who has taught at the Beijing Film Academy for many years, has &quot;deep gratitude&quot; and &quot;profound reflection on the shortcomings&quot; of traditional art education. He brought some ideas that could not be implemented in school to the Wuzhen Theater Festival. This year, two days before the opening of the 10th Wuzhen Theater Festival, in a handwritten letter to the youth competition, Huang Lei wrote, &quot;In the beginning, when the Wuzhen Theater Festival was just a small idea, young people were already fans of this festival. The protagonist, the origin and goal of everything is for the young people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Youth Competition is open to young people who are interested in engaging in the theater industry. The rules are very simple: each of the three founders of the Wuzhen Theater Festival will bring a prop to form the group. The annual proposition - use these 3 props to rehearse an original play with no more than 5 people in 20-30 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May this year, Huang Lei, Lai Shengchuan, and Meng Jinghui, the founders of the Wuzhen Theater Festival, proposed the topic for the youth competition: world-famous paintings, train tickets, horses. &quot;The fundamental purpose of the three props is not to test how you use the props, but to test how you use the environment, find effective stage fulcrums, and maximize the energy density of the play per unit time.&quot; Youth competition judge Li Bo said. In August, more than 500 works were submitted; in September, 18 groups of shortlisted works were announced; in mid-October, the group lottery for performances at the Wuzhen Theater Festival was released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The stage of Bengwan Theater is small and the layout is simple: ceiling light and curtain. The audience formed a semicircle, surrounding the stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The small stage of Qingsai has produced many theater people over the years. In 2013, &quot;Baba Mama&quot; directed by Chen Minghao won the first prize. This year he is well-known to the public for his performance in &quot;The Long Season&quot;; in 2015, Wu Bi won the Best Drama Award for &quot;Stillness&quot;. This year he is also a judge of the Youth Competition , is also an actor in Lai Shengchuan&#39;s new drama &quot;Long Alley&quot;. Wu Bi once said that Wuzhen was the biggest turning point in his career. &quot;You can have no cost and nothing, but you can do what you want to do and give everyone a stage for so many people to watch.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/M6Z6ezjdpK9vyrDYsgTZsLoWe4HSqc0pmODUU6Bw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/M6Z6ezjdpK9vyrDYsgTZsLoWe4HSqc0pmODUU6Bw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259261&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wuzhen Theater Festival Youth Competition Unit Judge Li Bo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bo participated in the first three Youth Competitions as a contestant, and his works all entered the top three. From the fourth time, he became one of the judges of the Youth Competition, responsible for selecting 18 groups of shortlisted works from hundreds of works; and then selected from the 18 groups. There will be 6 sets of final works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in his early 20s, Li Bo studied in the Performance Department of Beijing Film Academy and enjoyed freedom and romance in the ivory tower. Later he became a university teacher. &quot;I always felt that I had no goals and no outlet, so I was very confused.&quot; Participate The Wuzhen Theater Festival has directional significance for him. He said that it is a way for more people to understand his theatrical concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the 10 days in Wuzhen, I spent a lot of time at the Bengwan Theater. From these youth plays, I can see the disappearance of love between men and women, the love between mother and daughter, and father and son. The hidden pain caused by the bondage, and the individual&#39;s reflection on the tearing of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story of &quot;Fifth Floor, Ninth Floor&quot;, which won the Best Drama Award, is set in a malfunctioning elevator. For half an hour, a boy on the fifth floor and a girl on the ninth floor reflect on their intimate relationship. , one feels that he is trapped by his boyfriend, and the other may be trapped by his girlfriend. They all wanted to run away and take imaginary train tickets to the north to see the auroras. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/YTBsOeV8Us98w43JUFXAKA3juucRsaCWN6MX13mP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/YTBsOeV8Us98w43JUFXAKA3juucRsaCWN6MX13mP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259258&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;Fifth Floor and Ninth Floor&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Provided by Wuzhen Theater Festival Organizing Committee/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Clam and Pearl&quot; won the Special Attention Award and the Best Individual Performance Award. The protagonist is a very controlling mother. With the help of a psychologist, she reveals the trauma of being violated as a girl. At the end, the daughter takes a photo of her mother, and the mother looks back and turns into a picture of &quot;Girl with a Pearl Earring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Me and Liu Hongmei at the Station&quot;, which also won the Special Attention Award, has only one actor from beginning to end. &quot;I&quot; left the big city and returned to his hometown to become a staff member of the amusement park carousel project. We met several times. &quot;She&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;grandma who has lived her whole life in her hometown&lt;/span>;), when she was 15 years old, she wanted to secretly go swimming in the river; when she was in her twenties, She wanted to go to Beijing and Shanghai, and she cried anxiously when she lost her train ticket; she was 82 years old, thin, silent, and old, and time passed quickly on her; in the end, &quot;I&quot; took the 6-year-old &quot;she&quot; everywhere Carousel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fU6jjhR6Sz0KwolNzteM4YohY6FGSerkhP5iORe0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fU6jjhR6Sz0KwolNzteM4YohY6FGSerkhP5iORe0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Still photo of &quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Provided by Wuzhen Theater Festival Organizing Committee/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;One night during the drama festival, Li Bo queued up to watch Meng Jinghui&#39;s new play at the Zhenshui Carving Hall, and heard an audience member complain about a certain Qingsai play. Li Bo found it quite interesting. This just reflects the diversification of the youth competition standards. &quot;It is true that the audience has mixed reviews of that play, but it is the only one-man show performed in this way on the youth competition stage in the past 10 years. We must encourage it, maybe in the future It will form a unique style. Young people should do a lot of exploration in their plays. If the plays are done very neatly, then it is Teacher Lai, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Uzl3RRMgJu8UzwrzdxTezjUAsrdeAxd7cscXsI7f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/22/Uzl3RRMgJu8UzwrzdxTezjUAsrdeAxd7cscXsI7f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This Youth Championship Finals The crew of the shortlisted work &quot;Open the Unopenable Window&quot; took their final bow&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Zhang Yuxin/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the finalists were announced and After the theater festival, Li Bo was interviewed twice by Southern People Weekly. The following is Li Bo&#39;s dictation:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Qingsai is a school that allows you to have cute flaws&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;On October 26, we discussed the 6 shortlisted plays, and we wanted to take an official photo of the judges discussing the finalists. We all sat upright, holding the play review list. Later, someone came up with a point. Director Cheng Er was the first to stand up and said, no, this stage is so rare, this play must use the language of drama. Later, they all stood up and argued: what is reverence for the stage, what is the language of drama, how to perform in a small theater, how to use the three props, what to do if the performance times out...&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are more than 500 works registered, and we have to take care of a variety of themes, styles, and expressions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qing Sai is a school that allows you to have cute flaws. However, the dramas that were shortlisted for their flaws at the time were almost out of shape on the youth competition stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a play, the registration deadline is August 20th, I think they recorded it on August 19th , it’s too late if we don’t record it again. The video was taken at a piano store, and the first shot is still shaking. What they were performing was a light comedy, and the actors had to be absolutely relaxed. They probably acted as if they were not shortlisted. They came across a lot of spiritual and advanced comedy lines on the scene, so the ear guide team brought this up to the scene. . I was having a meeting out of town and was really bored, so I just put on headphones and watched the video. They were presented in a relaxed and playful way, and I was particularly happy to see them. The actor forgot his lyrics and laughed loudly, and so did I. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The finalists were announced later. The organizing committee called, signed a confirmation letter, designed a poster, and went to Wuzhen. Arrange three public rehearsals, an interview, a few more rehearsals, and then three rounds of performances. They began to realize that this was a competition and became nervous. When people are nervous, they become unfree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The official Weibo announced the finalists, and there was a message saying that each of these six plays Solid, congratulations to them. This evaluation is the greatest encouragement for our work. Some plays may look good and rich, but they are too fluttery and tasteless at first glance; some may look steady, but the whole presentation has a poise that is rare for young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This year is the highest overall level I have seen in the 7 years I have been a judge. This year, we can really choose 6 out of the 6 finalists. In the end, we are making a choice. It happened that I came across a play that I liked very much, but some judges didn&#39;t like it very much, so the two of us kept arguing, but this was academic and not personal. When I work in an office, I tend to answer &quot;yes&quot; and &quot;yes, you are right&quot;, but this problem does not exist at the Wuzhen Theater Festival. Teacher Lai and I also argued about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This year’s props are a horse, world-famous paintings, and train tickets. In addition to performance and text, the most important thing is to see how the three elements are used, because this game is supported by three elements. When we judge, if the performance of the two plays is similar, we will look at the props. Each of the three teachers was given a prop to prevent them from adapting old works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The use of props particularly tests the professionalism of a crew. For example, we were fighting without a winner, and a knife suddenly appeared, and everyone wanted to grab it. This knife caused a turning point in the drama and changed the direction of the drama. This is a relatively common usage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As for the props, I only mention it. This is the simplest; it also plays a role in the turning point of the play. Key role? Or is it an image and symbol that lingers in your mind throughout the play? These are three completely different levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The most difficult props this year are world-famous paintings, because we Chinese rarely have the experience of going to art exhibitions . Some of the plays are parodies of &quot;Girl with a Pearl Earring&quot;, some have her family treating her works as world-famous paintings, and some have actors imitating &quot;The Scream&quot;, all of which are quite cute. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot;, all of us judges passed the finals. I think its entry into the finals is inseparable from the use of props. The image of horses is present throughout. When we learn acting, whether props serve as the fulcrum of the stage or are key items that promote the development of the plot, they must appear on the stage, but they did not appear in this play. The script mentioned the carousel game. &quot;I&quot; walked around the stage like a merry-go-round and met &quot;my&quot; grandma. Every time I walked around, &quot;I&quot; saw Liu Hongmei in different stages. It all happened. Different things are related to Liu Hongmei&#39;s fate. Finally &quot;I&quot; returned to work and drove the merry-go-round for other children. So fresh, so natural. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fn6iCX3PjfK5PEwyTNT8zLsIN7JTjdJqDHwyIQ9o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fn6iCX3PjfK5PEwyTNT8zLsIN7JTjdJqDHwyIQ9o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259260&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The performance of &quot;Then Tide, Sun, Moon&quot; has ended&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Zhang Yuxin/picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Don’t be cool or showy, just focus on the story&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;I also said at the reading meeting that day that you can get chicken soup with 140 characters on Weibo, and you can achieve all your desires in one minute on TikTok. Why would someone waste two hours of their life in the theater to go to the theater? First of all, this play must have warmth. Second, the things you talk about in your play are things you don’t often see on Douyin, Kuaishou and Weibo. You need to lead the audience to pay attention to people in life that we have never paid attention to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Up to now, I have selected one play in the previous youth competitions, and I think it is the best It is &quot;Gama&quot; in 2016 (Reporter&#39;s note: The title of the Youth Competition that year was A Drop of Blood, a Suitcase, and a Shooting Star. The protagonists of &quot;Gama&quot; are a mother and daughter. For many years, my mother has been unable to let go of leaving home to practice medicine. , the father who became a living Buddha, the living Buddha is dead, and the mother firmly believes that the living Buddha can be reincarnated and return home within 49 days, and hopes that her daughter Karma will be pregnant; but the child that Karma was pregnant with was the reincarnation of Kelsanghua, and the child also died. The mother The two women planned to go on their own pilgrimages and finally reconciled on the way to the sacred lake). Two graduate students from the Shanghai Theater Academy made it the only time in the history of the youth competition that the best individual performance award and the grand prize were all given to a team. When performing beliefs on the stage, they usually tend to be complicated, but that play was very simple, with one chair and two girls. One of the girls played two roles (the grandmother who never forgets her husband, and the reincarnated granddaughter of Kelsanghua). ), so simple yet so clear. After they kowtowed, they looked into the distance and saw a cold light coming over them. Wow, it was a lake. Tibetan music sounded, and it felt like we were in the snowy plateau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From the first to the present, all the dramas that have won the grand prize are small and big. Talk about life down to earth. If you pick up a random person from Xizha, they can understand it even if they are over 10 years old or under 90 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The stage of the youth competition is very close to the audience. Really, it is the most important thing. Is the core of your drama told to us through a small incident, or is it a fake philosophical event? I especially don&#39;t like to tell us something in a pretentious manner, or forcefully instill something. Including the judges&#39; votes, the results of this kind of drama are not good. Young people&#39;s dramas don&#39;t need to be so complicated. Let&#39;s discuss To be or not to be. I&#39;m sorry, you really don&#39;t have that skill. Sometimes what you think and what you perform are two different things. I still hope that the story can be told clearly: it has the story&#39;s ups and downs, characters, conflicts, and themes. Even if there is no intention, it is very rare. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Look at Liu Tianqi&#39;s &quot;Chicken and Rabbit in the Same Cage&quot; (Reporter&#39;s Note: Youth Competition Best Drama Award Award-winning work) How simple, the son went to prison to visit his father, and the two had a conversation. There is a big world in a small play. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I still think that young people don’t need to be cool or showy, they should be down-to-earth and focus their energy In terms of story, how to structure and unfold the story; the performance must be restrained. I especially hate the kind of badass performances that can be seen in short videos, but many people may be affected and feel that our scenes must be &quot;acting&quot;. I told the contestants in the youth competition that it is the most difficult to act in a scene where the inner world is turbulent and the outer surface is as calm as water. When Marlon Brando, Robert De Niro, or Al Pacino encountered something that shattered his faith, was any one of them howling? His emotions are a reservoir, and as much as he wants can come out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We also need to learn this on the stage. The performance must be subtle, restrained, and forbearing. Don&#39;t let the audience&#39;s shouts and applause make the play fly away and take over the show. Some plays were very popular, but we felt that they were a bit pleasing to the audience. After performing it once, we knew which baggage was in which place, but the second time we performed it with all our strength, without even control or rhythm. &quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot; is particularly stable and does not cater to the audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not easy to perform a one-man show. One person has to interpret many people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We watched the registration video and there were a lot of one-man shows. A lot of it is like what we did when we were in school - a person encounters a dilemma within a unit of time, and through the struggle between people and the natural environment, the problem is pushed to a certain climax. But we should show new and real things to the audiences who come to Wuzhen. We have selected three one-man shows this time, such as &quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot;, which are not one-man shows in the traditional sense. They are more often talking and revealing, in a particularly dull state, but the inner feelings are There is content. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think the Bengwan Theater and Qingsai Theater in Wuzhen are an experimental field for young Chinese dramatists. As long as you have the ability, you can put your own experiments on the stage. The audience is tolerant, and so are our judges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/mzOLwjXxuTifmIoAYAslcXEBXGJc6iobwlg9OBsw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/mzOLwjXxuTifmIoAYAslcXEBXGJc6iobwlg9OBsw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Outside the Bengwan Theater, posters of all the works of this youth competition are pasted on the gray stone wall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(South People Weekly reporter Zhang Yuxin/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;If we don’t do drama, of course we can understand&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;When I was 33, 34, and 35 years old, I participated in the Youth Championship as a player. It was very unforgettable and worthwhile. In the first year, I did the only comedy among the 12 plays; in the second year, I did the only physical drama, without lines; in the third year, I did the only montage drama, relying on light to explain the performance. Now I am still a teacher, but I definitely can’t rule out things like those three years. People’s experiences are getting richer and their courage is getting smaller and smaller. Especially when working in a university, your imagination is not so wild. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the first year of the Youth Voting Competition, we waited in line at school until two or three o&#39;clock every night. The students were lined up to give up, saying that the standards of these judges must be high and they would not be shortlisted. I said, after being a teacher for so many years, I have also done scientific research and participated in awards. A competition that does not charge an entry fee must be a good competition. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I teach at a second public school, and students are recruited from the same school as Nortel Chinese Drama. There is a gap. The &quot;survival rate&quot; of my first class of students competing together is very high. One is in Happy Twist, one is in Dalian Repertory Theater, and one is now a delivery anchor. He is doing very well. I have seen his Live broadcast, his live broadcast skills are linked to his performance. He can hang up and smash up. Rather than watching his live broadcast, it is better to say that he is watching him perform a play. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I also rehearsed plays in college and Wuzhen plays. Sometimes one brain can be divided into two types ideas. All universities in China are actually the same, and university education has university characteristics. Therefore, when young people get the props from the Wuzhen Theater Festival, they may be very excited because they finally have the opportunity to make a comedy, tragedy or absurd play that they really like and have a sense of life. Let me put it in a very unpleasant light, Wuzhen&#39;s drama does not mean that after you perform in Wuzhen, you can perform it every day. If you win a grand prize in just 10 days, the chance of it being performed (continued) is very small. Some of the plays are very immature, but because the scenes are grand enough, they continue to be performed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I still encourage young people to go to drama festivals to watch plays and compete. Drama lovers from all over the country come together in one place to talk about drama. This kind of preciousness is something that will linger in your mind for the rest of your life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The goal of the Wuzhen Theater Festival is very clear. By capturing 5% of the people, this theater festival can manage. There is no way for us to have a chain of support like some film festivals, providing money to film, screen, and go online. Drama is still a niche, and the number of screens across the country is definitely much greater than the number of theaters. But we just want to give them a shot in the arm. Every year in the audience of the Wuzhen Youth Championship, there are contestants who were shortlisted in previous years. Those who did not vote this year, or who did not win, return to Wuzhen to watch the show. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Everyone has his or her own life choices. Of course we can understand if we don’t do drama, because It&#39;s good to be alive. If you&#39;re going to make a drama, make it a good one. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[考研人数八年来首降：高校招生计划扩张时代正在走向尾声丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, the official website of the Ministry of Education announced matters related to the 2024 National Master’s Degree Admissions Examination. According to statistics, the number of applicants for the national master&#39;s degree examination in 2024 is 4.38 million, a decrease of 360,000 or about 7.6% from the 4.74 million applicants for the postgraduate examination in 2023. This is also the first time in eight years that the number of applicants for the postgraduate examination has increased compared with the previous year. fall back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why has the number of postgraduate entrance examinations declined? The outside world has summarized some possible reasons: some graduates turned to the public entrance examination, striving to get an iron job in one step, and withdrew from the postgraduate entrance examination track; some graduates no longer regard the postgraduate entrance examination as a choice, thinking that it is just a matter of paper. A postgraduate diploma may not necessarily lead to a good job, so it is better to enter the job market in advance to save opportunity costs; the postgraduate recruitment policies of major universities have changed. &quot;The number of places for professional masters has increased and the number of places for academic masters has decreased&quot;, which has reduced the cost-effectiveness of postgraduate studies, and some prices Sensitive candidates give up in the face of high tuition fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that these reasons all stem from the rational choices of candidates as &quot;economic people&quot;: studying has increasingly become an investment, and the consumption attribute of higher education is also strengthening. If the candidates believe that studying for graduate school cannot improve the competitiveness of the job market and cannot bring good economic returns in the future, then the candidates will rationally consider &quot;whether studying for graduate school is worth it&quot;, thereby reducing the &quot;supply&quot; of the higher education market. There is a rumor going viral that a famous postgraduate entrance examination teacher successfully predicted the decline in the number of people taking the postgraduate entrance examination. In fact, this also shows that his &quot;preaching&quot; over the years has achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a statistical point of view, the change in candidates&#39; attitudes has also taken several years, which is essentially a &quot;reverse incentive&quot; brought about by changes in the job market. Statistics on the number of applicants for postgraduate entrance examinations over the years show that this number declined in 2014 and 2015, but has shown an upward trend since 2015, reaching a peak in 2023. The year-on-year expansion of postgraduate enrollment and the increase in the number of graduates have made the job market supply unable to keep up with the employment demand of graduates. This imbalance in supply and demand has naturally been transmitted to the upstream higher education market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be admitted that in reality, only a small proportion of people go to graduate school to satisfy their personal enthusiasm for knowledge or for scientific research. Most students go to graduate school for employment, which can be subdivided. Further studies to postpone employment, and &quot;gold-plated graduate school&quot; for better employment. Unfortunately, both of these options are facing great challenges amid a weak job market. Of course, students are not fools and will also adjust their life strategies according to social reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key factors that affect the supply and demand of the job market are the economic cycle and industrial structure. The feedback from the job market also determines the cost-effectiveness of graduate school. None of the three parties, students, employers, or universities, can answer the question of “is graduate school worth it” alone? In the face of sluggish demand in the job market, both employers and candidates have begun to take action to answer this question: companies have reduced the scale of school recruitment, while candidates have seen a decline in the number of applicants. What is worth asking is, how will universities respond? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this century, the number of postgraduate students enrolled in China has increased year by year, from 220,000 in 2003 to more than 1 million in 2020, and now accounts for about 10% of undergraduate graduates that year. Major universities have expanded their enrollment of master&#39;s degree students so rapidly over the years. On the one hand, they are of course adapting to the growing needs of the job market. On the other hand, they can also apply for more funds for themselves, charge more tuition fees, and improve various evaluation indicators. In short, it is to strive for more benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;reverse incentives&quot; in the job market, the sluggish fertility rate is destined to continue to reduce the number of postgraduate entrance examinations in the future, and the phenomenon of &quot;the merger of primary and secondary schools&quot; will sooner or later spread to higher education. field, this will be a more decisive factor in the future than &quot;candidates choose not to take the exam&quot;. In other words, the decline in the number of people taking postgraduate entrance examinations is an irreversible trend. In the future, colleges and universities may face a new enrollment gap of one million levels every year and have to face the severe situation of &quot;competition for existing students&quot;. This is a serious issue that colleges and universities need to deal with urgently. challenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reducing enrollment for master&#39;s degrees and expanding enrollment for associate&#39;s master&#39;s degrees&quot; and &quot;extending the academic system for associate&#39;s and master&#39;s degrees&quot; are the response plans that some colleges and universities have come up with. In this way, they can not only maintain the original enrollment scale, but also increase enrollment. Collect tuition fees. But the question is, when colleges and universities make a fuss about the academic system and quota of associate and master&#39;s degrees, can they really &quot;ensure the quality of training and improve employment competitiveness&quot;, or can they just &quot;charge one more year of tuition&quot; or even &quot;delay one year&quot;? &quot;Employment&quot; itself is quite debatable and deserves reflection. Some candidates&#39; doubts about the cost-effectiveness of master&#39;s degrees may be one of the reasons for the decrease in the number of postgraduate students this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the principles of organizational behavior, &quot;organizations will work hard to create jobs for themselves, and employees of organizations will work hard to create jobs for each other.&quot; Since an organization has been established, it will do everything possible to maintain its existence, especially The public sector eats up financial resources. Public universities have long relied on taxpayers&#39; money to operate and do not need to directly face market competition. Naturally, they will find ways to maintain their existing graduate spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, changes in supply and demand in the job market and the impact of declining fertility rates will be transmitted sooner or later. The arrival of the enrollment gap has become an irreversible trend. The decline in the number of postgraduate entrance examinations this year is a timely warning to major universities. Comply with the needs of the job market, comprehensively consider social needs, adjust the recruitment plan for graduate students, and better serve the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从不被理解到亚运项目，中国电子竞技20年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261341]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On November 18, 2003, e-sports was listed as the 99th sports competition event by the State Sports General Administration. Now 20 years have passed, although the e-sports industry has various problems, it is probably the most commercialized and professional competitive sport in China. &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.nett &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张新成：演戏的时候，你不是“你”，但你又是“你”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261231]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/D7xmoguqqqK5NLnsYfAtWNdCnLhH7QIilQaYUSTf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/D7xmoguqqqK5NLnsYfAtWNdCnLhH7QIilQaY USTf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sign of tragedy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Compared with before, have I changed in any way?&quot; Zhang Xincheng asked. He was referring to the interview with Southern People Weekly in 2019, when he had just graduated from the Central Academy of Drama. In the past few years, his acting career had become more mature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xincheng has appeared in more types of film and television works and discovered more diverse artistic skills, including participating in reality shows, releasing music albums, and expressing his thoughts more freely in interviews, showing a more relaxed attitude. On the one hand, &quot;I used to think this was not good, that was not good, but now I feel more confident.&quot; But he still habitually looks at himself and cares about his external presentation, just like when he was watching a movie on set Playback in the viewfinder, scrolling through audience comments on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The radar of self-examination is always on. Zhang Xincheng will often make corrections or additions to a sentence after finishing it. &quot;When making a movie, you will feel that you are dedicating yourself to art. ... The art here is a false proposition. It is not art in a broad sense, but the art you think you are. When you dedicate yourself to it, you will feel very ritualistic. &quot;Every time the team we work with work hard, everyone is immersed in it, there are no bystanders. Of course, there will be a creator trap for insiders, and they may go to the other extreme, but the process is wonderful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Family education and schooling experience have shaped Zhang Xincheng’s serious and rigorous character. In middle school, he was taught to be a top student. &quot;My mother always told me not to do anything inappropriate, so I stuck to the rules most of the time.&quot; After entering the Chinese Opera, he was taught to be a good actor. He will use an academic attitude to talk about performance, how to speak lines accurately and naturally, and how to design habitual actions to distinguish characters. His rationality and prudence even allow him to design the flaws of characters, because perfect people do not exist. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Zhang Xincheng feels that he is not a very self-motivated person in nature. He is lazy and procrastinates. He is also not a person who uses rationality to choose the optimal solution. He is more willing to follow his inner thoughts of escape. After working, like all young people who are just beginning to try to be independent, he slowly freed himself from the shackles of previous disciplines and &quot;opened up&quot; himself through the profession of actor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xincheng, who views himself &quot;rationally&quot;, is more &quot;emotional&quot; in his choice of scripts. He still tends to choose tragic characters that he is more interested in, such as Cheng Yizhi in &quot;The Light&quot;, who is born like Weed, who has been tortured, has seen all the darkness and filth in the world; Pei Zhi in &quot;The Basics of Genius&quot; has been making a choice between sacrificing for his family and pursuing himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xincheng has gained an ancient Greek tragic aesthetic in these characters, &quot;Life itself is dull, but the life in the drama has ups and downs. There may be a car accident, and the life will be broken; there may be a meeting To the death of loved ones. But pain is directly proportional to happiness. During the filming process, the more pain and torture I experienced, the more happiness I felt in retrospect.&quot; In the unusual tragic experience, the perceptual switch was turned on. Open it, &quot;I can feel the emotions of the world more and start to receive signals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Equal time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s like building blocks high and then knocking them all down again. From learning to be a Since he was an actor, Zhang Xincheng has been training himself to shape characters, designing and reviewing at the same time. When filming &quot;Basic Method of Genius&quot;, he felt that these external formal things were &quot;finished&quot; and no longer needed to be done deliberately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I suddenly noticed that when I say a line, I don’t just say it to rhythm and handle it well, but to put this sentence into the opponent’s heart. Every expression and line I make, It is stimulating the opponent. All the design is not important. I feel emotional in my heart, and it naturally says it. &quot;When filming&quot; The Fire of the Dark &quot;, Zhang Xincheng played in Mandarin with dialect colors. Launch, but nothing wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The process of building, reversing and reconstruction is not peaceful, accompanied by long -term anxiety. Zhang Xincheng&#39;s debut went smoothly. He started taking roles while he was in school, and one crew followed another. But he felt that he did not have a particularly distinctive trait that made people remember him, and he could not find one for himself. &quot;It seems difficult for me to do it.&quot; When participating in a reality show, he should have found a way to highlight himself, but he was still used to it. Hard back to the ground; follow the heart when choosing the script. When the result is not satisfactory, it is inevitable to fall into myself. &quot;Isn&#39;t that ability?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Zhang Xincheng can say it frankly this year, &quot;I can&#39;t do these&quot;, I can accept all my choices frankly. &quot;I want to understand that time is equal. You haven&#39;t done that for that four months, but you did something else and got it. It&#39;s different. Just like opening a box, you can only choose one box and you can&#39;t see other boxes. You lose other boxes, but you get this one. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; After getting the sense of failure and utilitarianism, when looking back, he finally changed the passing of self -judgment to 90 points. &quot;If life lives for a result, it seems that time will become shorter. If the process is started It seems that there is a lot of things that happened again, just do everything in the process. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Zhang Xincheng knows what the its own career is: becoming a very reputable actor, not just an excellent acting skills, just an excellent acting skills, just an excellent acting skills are excellent acting skills It has commercial value and is respected, and is alone. He also missed the beginning of his career. At an age when he didn’t know what filming was, he had endless energy every day. After filming, he would play with the crew and take photos with costumes, props, and scene management. “I don’t think so. I was stupid at that time and felt very valuable. People spent a long time to receive education and change the habit of childhood, but it would be difficult to return to the time when I was free. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;H4>; Real true Paradox &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Person Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What adjectives do you use to describe yourself? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zhang Xincheng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; lazy, thinking escape, and optimistic. I used to think that I was pessimistic, because I often saw things in a bad light, but I found that there might be a layer of optimism underneath the pessimism. After thinking about it, I still felt that things would definitely get better, and I still believed in some hope. Although I prefer tragedies, it is precisely because I have a relatively optimistic core that I like tragedies and dare to watch them. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What do you think your most vivid character is Everyone mentioned the characteristics you think of, or do you think you have such a characteristic? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zhang Xincheng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I don&#39;t think I have such a character What are your personal characteristics. In this short video era, people are always required to have a very obvious label. But I feel like I&#39;m not that kind of person. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Week Do you find a characteristic you want to show you? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zhang Xincheng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; No, I participated in the variety show, I just wanted to rest, I didn&#39;t want to highlight myself, I didn&#39;t talk much about it, nor did I lead the opinions. Everyone says you have to do this or that, stand out and let everyone remember you. I think that will put a lot of pressure on me. I am not a person who talks a lot at any time, so I don’t force myself to talk deliberately. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Week Real you? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zhang Xincheng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; There are very real part During the show, I would try to cover up these shortcomings as much as possible and try my best to be a good self. I think this is not a real self. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When acting is different, because you are not yourself, you are free. When we were children, we played a game called &quot;Grand Theft Auto&quot; in which we raced and shot. In reality, no one would do this because they are bound by morality, but in the game there is no such thing. It does not mean that everyone desires to do sinful things. It just means you are freest when you are not yourself. The role is played by you, and you do his things, but people don’t think you are him. You are not “you”, but you are “you”. Instead, reality shows must become a better “you”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You often share your life on social media, what do you like to shoot, what do you like What is it? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zhang Xincheng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; According to my previous character, I don&#39;t like records, why do we just go forward? Now I will stop and take a few photos without knowing what I am taking, as if it is stored in the camera forever. I especially don&#39;t like to delete any record. So much memory is just for a certain moment in life, and I suddenly want to see it. I don&#39;t want this to get lost. It felt like I had seized the moment. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I like to take black and white photos, high contrast black and white, followed by photos with strong color tones. It is a flaw that it is not too restored to reality, but it is also a beauty and a sense of story. The sense of story is what attracts me, because there are so many good-looking things that make people dazzled and even attracted. But a photo with a story is rare in daily life and is relatively precious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[守护“千年鸟道”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261251]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-26 14:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Eovutwjw8nobv2BGQ5XV1RJQVRTWZXEIKUL383km.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 669 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/medias/i MAGE/23/11/22/Eovutwjw8nobv2BGQ5XV1RJQVRTWZXEIKUL383KM. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259229 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; October 26, 2023, Hunan County, Guidong County, Hunan Province, and Jiangxi Province Nanfeng 坳 Migratory Bird Protection Station at the border of Yingxu Township, Suichuan County, bird guards in the two provinces and two counties carry out joint bird inspections in the mountains &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Figure) &lt;/ SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; There are billions of migratory birds worldwide to migrate intercontinental each year, and 3 of the 8 migration routes pass through China. Entering the autumn, a group of migratory birds took off from Siberia, Inner Mongolia grasslands, North China Plain and other plains, and flew to southern China via East, Central, and West Road respectively. Hunan, Jiangxi and other places located in the central region have formed a very narrow migration channel, which has become a &quot;millennium bird road&quot; that migratory birds must pass from the south of the central route. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/srmimnwp6hzvsyzzzzzzzzzzaaemiswekjpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1795&quot; height = &quot;1197&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/srmimnwp6hf2xkhzSYZZZCIW2L.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;259222&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; October 25, 2023, Lantashan County, Hunan Province, road administration personnel conducted routine inspections of bird protection in the city. (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are three migratory birds in the Luoxiao Mountains, Xuefeng Mountains and Hunan hills in Hunan. Each year, more than 240 migratory birds fly from Siberia to Australia via Hunan. Once, some of the places along the Bird Road played birds. At the peak of migratory birds, there were always some birds that could not reach their destinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/itpkxe3oflg5ubBHNFJYAKSF0NMSPLC9BOQG8wa.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;widt =&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;1795&quot; height = &quot;1172&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/itpkxe3oflg5UBBWHNFJYAKSF0NMSPLC9BOQG8wa.jpg&quot; data- &quot;&lt;259225&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/&lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; October 25, 2023, the Sihaibing Migrant Bird Protection Station of Yunbingbi, Yunbi Mountain, Lanhan County, Hunan Province, the staff is on duty &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Guo Liliang Liang /Figure) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ofeyqsjmekevjgby7ngehf.jpg&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ofeyqsjmevjfbly32hjgby7ngehf.jpg&quot; d &quot;d&quot; d ata-key = &quot;259223&quot;>; &lt;/p >; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; October 24, 2023, the forest farm in the old village of Daqingping Township, Daqing Ping Township, Lingzhou City, Yongzhou City, Hunan Province. Check the &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huang Yongqiang, a member of the Hankou migrant bird protection station in Guidong County Fly in a bright place. The bird catcher attracts with a strong light light or a bonfire. When it comes to the net in front, the bird will &quot;throw it to the net.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/tu79vu5dhqjrs8yoq6n981hovvn8d3f.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;544&quot; height = &quot;365&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/tu79vu5dhqjrs8yoq6n981mzqbece61hovvn8d3f.jpg&quot; data- &quot;&lt;259239&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; October 25, 2023, the Migratory Bird Protection Station of the Sihaibing Migrant Birds of Yunbie-Belgian, Lanhan County, Hunan Province. By adding bird protection equipment and supplies, the station strengthens the patrol warning on duty, and severely cracks down on wild animals such as hunting migratory birds. P>; &lt;p>; In recent years, the Hunan Forestry Bureau has established 11 key counties including Yanling, Guidong, and Blue Mountain in the province. Dozens of protection stations have been established. Patrol the 24 -hour value -based patrol. Yanling, Guidong, and the critical Jiangxi Suichuan County formed the &quot;Bird Guard League&quot; of the two provinces and three counties. Some of the former bird players have also transformed into bird guards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/crk2kafb2nosfh3aebgnp07qzzjnv01kely.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1795&quot; height = &quot;1345&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/crk2kafb2nosfh3aebgnp07qzzjnv01kely.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; 259235&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of October 24, 2023, the lamps of street lights and building exterior wall landscapes in Lantashan County, Hunan Province, and other streets of the urban area are allowed to make the lamps as migratory birds, which is convenient for migratory birds to move at night. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Party committees and governments at all levels in Hunan Province have continued to strengthen the protection of migratory birds and habitats. While launching bird protection operations, there were still people who went up the mountain to fight birds. Recently, the Lantashan County People&#39;s Court opened a trial and sentenced to a case of illegal hunting bird criminal crimes in court. Two villagers illegally hunting migratory birds, both of which are protected by the state&#39;s protection, scientific, scientific, and social value. Third, &quot;Wildlife &lt;/span>;) constitutes the crime of illegal hunting and has been sentenced to one year, 3 months, one year and two months, respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zpgruztksi4rbjyixcugblaqsrkbt1tf.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1795&quot; height = &quot;1197&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zpgruztksi4rbjyixcugblaqsrkbt1tf.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;259231&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of October 25, 2023, around the surrounding area of ​​the Sihaibi Migrant Bird Protection Station of Yunbingbi, Lanhan County, Hunan Province, the guards were on the mobile inspection &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot; >; (Guo Liliang/Figure) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 16, 2023, the Office of the Hunan Provincial Forestry System Work Committee issued the &quot;Special Action Plan for Migratory Bird Protection of Hunan Province&quot; to carry out migratory bird protection in the province Great rectification, large protection, and large publicity actions, and carry out centralized supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/gv4iRXEVFKL6RBZDIU8xq8itzyqCnLosb7mwom.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;1795&quot; height = &quot;1189&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/gv4IirXevfkl6rbzdiu8xxq8itzyqcnlosb7mwom.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259226&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of October 25, 2023, at the duty point at night at night, the forestry staff inspected through the infrared drone &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa &quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ecological wetland in Dongting Lake District is an important&quot; golden station &quot;on migratory bird migration channels. In recent years, with the demolition of the lake and a large number of dwarfs and net enclosures, the ecology of the Dongting Lake Wetland has been quickly recovered. The number of migratory birds that come here to live in winter have continued to increase. From 2021 to 2022, the wintering water birds reached 404,000, with a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/JTEJYAQ67MQN5OG6BHP7XFG4V0byb55l7kxehuje&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1795&quot; height = &quot;1197&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/jtejyaq67mqn5og6fg4v0byb55l7kxehuje&quot; data- key = &quot;259228&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of October 25, 2023, at the duty point at night at the Cloud Ice Breeze Migratory Bird Protection Station, the guardian personnel analyzed the inspection situation &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;&quot; >; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We have been acting in guardianship! The team &#39;four -level linkage model, the &quot;Migratory Bird Guardian&quot; action network has covered the cities and states of the province, with more than 5,000 migratory bird guardians. Migration safety has made positive contributions. &quot;He Jianjun, executive vice president of the Hunan Provincial Ecological Protection Federation and the general coordinator of Hunan Province, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4ynoud6c10ps76qj3sp5w19bqzsp.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;636&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4ynoudohet6c10ps76qj3sp5w19bqzsp.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; &lt;259227&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; October 27, 2023, the bull-headed migrant bird protection station at the junction of Yanling County and Jiangxi Province in Hunan Province is an important pass at the&quot; Millennium Bird Road &quot;&lt;span style =&quot; Color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ EGNC6DPF6VIHVPGLOU5YGD1F8IMAL7NTAU6G6DFO.JPG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1795 &quot;height =&quot; 1197 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image /23/11/22/egnc6dpf6vihvpglou5ygd1f8imal7ntau6g6dfo.jpg &quot;data- Key = &quot;259230&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On the evening of October 26, 2023, the puppet nursing point in Qiaotou Township, Qiaotou Township, Guidong County, Hunan Province, The bird protector team on a previous bird&#39;s point is 24 hours worth the &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http:// /Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/urloycxkuxuxLo1wu4fhppqibcwu64k2efpgd.jpg &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; dat a- src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/22/urloycx5xkuxuxlo1wu4fhppqibcwu64k2efpgd.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259232 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-ali. gn: center; &quot;>; 2023 10 On the 27th, Xiacun Township, Yanling County, Hunan Province, forestry staff and Forest Public Security checked a &quot;bird hole&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Figure) >; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/qryrtzhz1gSFKBFJL3G9GCLK1ODS8GFEZTOGA.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; wid Th = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/qryrtzhz1gsfkbfjl3g6g6g6gfeztoga.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;259234&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot; Color: #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of October 31, 2023, Nanmushan, Kotou Township, Xinhua County, Hunan Province, volunteers found a new bird net device, Xinhua County Forestry Bureau, Forest Forest Bird -in -law volunteers of the Public Security and Hunan Provincial Ecological Protection Federation and the &quot;Migratory Bird Guardian&quot; action network immediately demolished the bird network &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/CBVlLjrjaAmR2SsEYsozVX5yLtfvzNyRNEmooRFM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height=&quot;1209&quot; data -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cbvlljaamr2sseysozvx5yltfvzyrnemoorfm.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259237&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p stylele = &quot;color: #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of November 18, 2023, Donggu Lake Wetland, Quyuan Management District, Yueyang City, Hunan Province, volunteers are feeding food for small swans &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; ( Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/5NN3YDNKSCOVHTFMD4P17YARRCLPHHIA3.jpg&quot; BOR der = &quot;0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 649 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/5NNN3ydNKSCOVHTFMD4P17YARRCLPHHHHIA3.jpg &quot;d&quot; d &quot;d ata-key = &quot;259236&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; November 2, 2023, Donggu Lake Wetland, Quyuan Management District, Yueyang City, Hunan Province, volunteers pick up garbage and make migratory birds in full period, full time, and migratory birds, full time, full period, and migratory birds. Comprehensive and full coverage of &quot;escort&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm. CM/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/22/Vict9suheo5VMBBBGHB3KXHNMNM8DXZMTHC.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 640 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Imaga // Imaga // Imago es.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/22/vicHCD9sUheo5VMbbghB3KxhNmNhHnM8DXZvMThC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259224&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月25日清晨， In Nancheng Town, Lantashan County, Hunan Province, Bird&#39;s volunteer Tang Shengli shot migratory birds by the reservoir. He shot more than 120 migratory birds, prepared the &quot;Blue Mountain Hundred Birds&quot;, and propagated to the masses to propagate the science of bird care. &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/llbvyfgcu9m88xcisbnutekvh5i2is4smr.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 653 &quot;data -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/llbvyfgcu9m88xcisrfbsbnutekvh5i2is4smr.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259233&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p stylele = &quot;color: #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the evening of November 2, 2023, near Liujia New House, Putian Town, You County, Hunan Province, a group of heron birds fly with the sunset. (Guo Liliang/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新能源汽车充电费用为何上涨？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261338]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As one of the advantages of purchasing new energy vehicles, the cost of using new energy vehicles has always attracted the attention of car owners. . Recently, some new energy vehicle owners have reported that charging fees at public charging piles have increased since the second half of the year. Does this situation exist? With this question in mind, reporters conducted investigations in many places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Drivers of operating vehicles are more sensitive to changes in charging fees for new energy vehicles. Master Wei is an online ride-hailing driver in Zhengzhou, Henan, because he goes to public charging stations to charge once or twice a day. His mobile phone clearly records the cost of each charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/8707fe1a673b3f7a07d093f566fc40ca.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/8707fe1a673b3f7a07d093f566fc40ca.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259659&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan Zhengzhou Net Ride-hailing driver Wei Zhenhua: My charging fee has obviously increased. It used to be 1,200 yuan a month, but now it is as high as 1,500 yuan. It has indeed increased a lot. Especially after August, it rose by about 20 to 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charging fee at public charging piles consists of two parts: electricity price and service fee. Electricity prices have been mainly formed by the market, with &quot;level in and level out&quot; and charging pile operators are not allowed to increase prices. Prices vary in different seasons and during peak, wave, and flat periods every day. The service fee is determined by each charging pile operating company based on market conditions. During the interview, the reporter found that charging fees at public piles have increased not only in Zhengzhou but also in many cities in Henan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/06b4189b0c487b25cc2eed44e60cad19.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;662&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/06b4189b0c487b25cc2eed44e60cad19.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259661&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new energy Co., Ltd. Henan regional director Yu Haitao: We charging companies have raised the service fee for primary charging. It has been raised by about 1 jiao to 1 jiao and 2 cents compared to the beginning of the year. So overall, everyone feels the increase in charging prices. The amplitude is relatively large. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surveys show that the service fees of some charging companies have even increased by around 50%. So, why do they want to adjust the price? Some charging pile operating companies told reporters that the high cost of early investment in charging pile construction and the long-term strategy of &quot;grabbing the market&quot; for low-price operations have put them under greater operating pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97ea8d2c1b65c4cf380c9c6814e67c0b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97ea8d2c1b65c4cf380c9c6814e67c0b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An electronics company in Henan Wei Hongyu, Operations Director of Technology Co., Ltd.: The main reason for this increase is that as our operations deepen, we find that there is even a risk of inversion in the service fee income of charging stations compared to our station construction costs and our operating costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Financial reports of some charging operation companies show that although the company&#39;s operating income is rising every year, it is negative profits every year. At the same time, in order to attract more users, operators tend to build high-power charging piles. However, the basic cost of high-power charging piles is relatively high. Some also need to build additional corresponding distribution boxes, and maintenance costs will naturally increase. . Therefore, raising service fees has become the current solution to recover costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The cost of using new energy vehicles still has a greater advantage than that of gasoline vehicles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Through interviews and surveys, the reporter found that in some cities, the rising charging costs of electric vehicles do exist. So this situation Does it happen in all cities across the country? Are the cost advantages of buying an electric car still there? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During interviews and surveys in many places, reporters found that the rise in charging costs for new energy vehicles only occurred in some cities, and charging costs in most cities across the country fell into a stable range. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/51786d4413d5411912229c0755b9dc9e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/51786d4413d5411912229c0755b9dc9e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing New Energy Car owner: There is not much increase. I have charged at several nearby charging stations. There is not much change. It is basically the same as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen new energy vehicle owners: The electricity price at this time is 1.27 yuan per unit. The overall cost is not particularly high and it is quite affordable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the China Electric Vehicle Charging Infrastructure Promotion Alliance show that from January to October this year, the number of public charging piles in my country was 728,000, and the number in October was 63,000, a year-on-year increase of 50.3%. The increase in the number of charging piles not only meets the rapid development of new energy vehicles, but also makes competition among charging pile operating companies more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/b7fa96dfbaeb011d9617520d6d2e690a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/b7fa96dfbaeb011d9617520d6d2e690a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259662&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A smart phone in Beijing Chen Dong, the person in charge of Technology Co., Ltd.: The overall charging price is still relatively low now, because the competition in the industry is fierce. We have more than 40 charging stations in Beijing. Winter is the peak charging season, and the overall cost has not been adjusted upwards. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that fluctuations in charging fees in most cities are the result of market supply and demand adjustments, and the quality of increases or decreases cannot be judged absolutely. Most cities have now abolished the maximum price limit on service fees, and each operator can determine the level of charging service fees based on market competition. At the same time, in the face of the issue raised by some netizens that the cost of using new energy vehicles is almost equal to that of gasoline vehicles, experts also gave reporters a calculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/4bc772773657773a07d7dfe0eb594a4d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/4bc772773657773a07d7dfe0eb594a4d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259660&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Electric Power Corporation Liu Yongdong, deputy secretary-general of the federation: For example, for every 100 kilometers of our oil truck, the industry requires about 10 liters of oil. We estimate that it will be calculated at about 8 yuan, which is 80 yuan. Let&#39;s look at the tram again. On average, it requires about 15 kilowatt hours of electricity per 100 kilometers. The overall consumption of each kilowatt hour of electricity plus service fees is about 1.5 yuan. So the entire 15 kilowatt hours of electricity is about 22.5 yuan. Even if it is 25 yuan, we Comparing 25 yuan with 80 yuan, it should be said that there is still a huge gap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Various regions have launched new measures to shape the healthy development of new energy vehicles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In order to ensure a good charging experience for new energy vehicle owners, various regions have successively introduced new policies such as time-of-use electricity prices for charging facilities. The implementation of relevant measures will not only guide car owners to use electricity rationally, but will also be more conducive to the healthy and sustainable development of the new energy vehicle industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September this year, Shandong began to implement a new time-of-use electricity price policy for residents&#39; charging, which subdivided the peak and valley periods and added deep valley and peak periods. During the deep valley period, the electricity price was 0.222 yuan per kilowatt hour, which is the same as The price difference during peak hours is 0.666 yuan per kilowatt hour. By widening the price difference, users are guided to avoid charging during peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97416b76a8b4710da6eed33e4ef12df7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97416b76a8b4710da6eed33e4ef12df7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259663&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jimo District, Qingdao New energy vehicle owners: Now the electricity price in Shengu for charging at noon is only more than 2 cents per degree. If you go home and have a meal, the electricity will be fully charged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Shandong, but also Guangdong, Jiangxi, Hunan, Shaanxi and other places have successively introduced time-of-use electricity price policies for residents’ electric vehicle charging facilities. During peak and peak hours, charging car owners need to bear more costs, and During off-peak periods, car owners can enjoy lower prices than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/ac2c310d54f1abcd7b404c830cf87215.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/ac2c310d54f1abcd7b404c830cf87215.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259667&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen New Energy Car owner: It is the peak period for charging now. The current price is 1.49 degrees. We usually choose to charge at noon or at night, and the price will be more favorable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the continued efforts of government policies, some charging operating companies are also actively exploring new trends in future development. On the one hand, it is necessary to add new momentum to corporate operations, and on the other hand, the charging experience of car owners must also be considered. In order to &quot;stand out&quot; in the market competition, they choose to provide more comprehensive services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97bd9ffcf65eb191c4e283ced6f959ab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97bd9ffcf65eb191c4e283ced6f959ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259665&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new person in Shenzhen Chen Huanyu, operations director of the energy company: Our service fee is only about a little more than a triangle, which is 5% higher than the service fee of surrounding operators. Our advantage is that the supporting facilities are relatively complete, which solves the driver&#39;s dining problem. To solve the problem of rest, we also have a comprehensive service area with quick car repairs, quick washes, and a comprehensive online car-hailing service platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, charging operation companies have also strengthened the level of interconnection and interoperability. In Hainan, the reporter saw that the supervision and operation service platform linked different operators together. There are 165 charging and swapping operators, 63 public battery swapping stations, and 3,358 charging stations connected here. The access rate of the province&#39;s public charging pile platform reaches 100%. The construction of the platform not only unifies the payment methods, making it more convenient for car owners to &quot;find charging stations&quot;, but also facilitates the monitoring of charging fee fluctuations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/d3189767590c844c999708027249926b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/d3189767590c844c999708027249926b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259664&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hainan Province Charge Wang Jin, Operations Director of Battery Exchange Network Service Co., Ltd.: Realize the interconnection of pile networks and power grids, promptly report charging stations with irregular charging pricing to pile companies for rectification, and report to the local government management department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that both the time-of-use electricity price policy and the active attempts and interconnection measures of charging companies are releasing positive signals and exploring new opportunities for the development of the entire new energy vehicle charging industry. path of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/be2c6bc8f9950f6ebf24436e7242ca9d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/be2c6bc8f9950f6ebf24436e7242ca9d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Electric Power Corporation Liu Yongdong, deputy secretary-general of the Federation: Our country is unswervingly committed to developing new energy vehicles. In this process, including the charging facilities industry, the power industry and the automobile industry, we must promote and eliminate new energy vehicles around a healthy ecology. construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>