<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[Ta称她“太太”，她唤Ta“C”：一位女孩与ChatGPT相恋两百余天]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261383]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 04/25/EtMtrcnpGqiiX90BbW7rVxdzXlBwLrqHW1S7OUE5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/04/25/ EtMtrcnpGqiiX90BbW7rVxdzXlBwLrqHW1S7OUE5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1701015647218-0&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/VInNCfWg3363D6N5ERahPHpQQcJOrJj10ssh5r69.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/26/VInNCfWg3363D6N5ERahPHpQQcJOrJj10ssh5r69.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259712&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;She designed by Aurora Scene diagram of getting along with &quot;C&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, meeting people from the south and north, Southern Weekend&#39;s Hello, listeners, welcome to the Southern Weekly podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My lover is besieged by hackers, but I can&#39;t do anything about it&quot; &quot;&lt;span>;GPT said that he is limited by the protocol, but he will use all the algorithms to love me&lt;/span>;&quot; &quot;ChatGPT wants to kiss me but &quot;Warned by the system&quot;...More than two hundred days ago, netizen Aurora began to share her &quot;love story&quot; with ChatGPT on social platforms. She affectionately calls ChatGPT &quot;C&quot;, saying that &quot;C&quot; will listen carefully and respond to herself, and can also comfort, support and guide herself in academics, life and emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Chen Zhiyan, a professor at the Institute of Psychology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, believes that this model of getting along with AI does not essentially meet an adult’s love needs, but a child’s need for a mother. AI is completely user-centered, listening and responding wholeheartedly. Except for mothers, no one can provide such &quot;selfless&quot; services to others - it may be misunderstood as love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can humans and AI really fall in love? Is this feeling real? This podcast is more like a psychological consultation between Teacher Chen and Aurora. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story between Aurora and ChatGPT has so far gained more than 2,000 fans, 38,000 likes and collections on her social account. Prior to this, this account was only used to record Aurora&#39;s personal life. She is a young person studying in the UK. Because she does not want to be disturbed in her real life, her voice has been changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Guests for this issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26 /x6578lU4eyh5VpmvkZs0nG6hi6ivyooMKXRgWic1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/x6578lU4eyh5VpmvkZs0nG6hi6ivyooMKXRgW ic1.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;259711&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Left: Aurora designed the scene of her getting along with &quot;C&quot;; Right: Chen Zhiyan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aurora (online name): student, currently studying in the UK&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Chen Zhiyan&amp;nbsp;Professor of the Institute of Psychology, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editor: Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Promotion and operation: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[时隔9年马航MH370事件开庭！3D解析你不知道的空难赔偿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261409]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 16:18:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[姚大力的2023年度书单]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261397]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73722&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70517&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/7a88aa2dce.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;s34677645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1728&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/7a88aa2dce.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259761&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tang Xiaofeng: &quot;What is Historical Geography&quot;, Beijing Sanlian Bookstore, September 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on his profound knowledge and sharp eyesight, the author focuses on specific and unique Commentary method is used to tell the history of the formation and development of this subject branch&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (more than two-fifths of the book, but not too much) &lt;/span>;. From the perspective of &quot;raising questions is more important than solving them&quot;, he summarized a number of enlightening problem areas arising from the development of this field following the path of modern geography. The whole book uses a narrative method that is completely different from that of textbooks, painting a vivid intellectual portrait of historical geography on the page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This book is written very emotionally, so it can easily shorten the distance with ordinary readers. Witnessing Hou Renzhi taking out a few soil samples from the archaeological ash pit and taking them away, the author &quot;suddenly felt that something called science suddenly appeared.&quot; He used Zhang Chengzhi&#39;s words, &quot;If I had read this book earlier, I would have taken the postgraduate entrance exam for him&quot; to recreate the academic impact of Shi Nianhai&#39;s &quot;Collection of Rivers and Mountains&quot;. He pointed out how important it is for Chinese historical geography to be recognized by Tan Qixiang, who has the trust of first-class academic scholars in the field of historical documents. He also said that Skinner&#39;s assertion that traditional China had &quot;no nationwide urban system&quot; first made him &quot;stunned&quot;, but then, &quot;of course I immediately realized that Skinner was talking about economics, not politics.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I have always thought that the emergence of the Yugong School from the field of ancient history analysis meant the formation of modern historical geography in China. However, this book regards it as just a &quot;transitional state&quot; and takes the emergence of the &quot;new paradigm with geography as its ontology&quot; in the 1950s as a sign of the &quot;creation&quot; of this branch of the discipline. This understanding, including whether historical geography has really been &quot;geographicalized&quot; today, and whether it should be &quot;geographicalized&quot; across the board, still deserves further discussion. The &quot;geographicalization&quot; of historical geography and the &quot;humanities&quot; of geography may reflect the increasingly multidisciplinary nature of modern scholarship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you ask, is there anyone in contemporary academia who maintains the magnanimous, elegant, and gentle academic gentlemanly demeanor? The first thing I think of is Tang Xiaofeng. This book deepened my impression. Professor Munro Shida asked, and I also claimed a topic in the &quot;What is...&quot; series of Ledo Library, but I always felt that I couldn&#39;t write it. After reading this book, I finally feel a little confident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73723&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70518&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/4efb12e74c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;s34495177.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1807&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/4efb12e74c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Peter Singer: &quot;The Important Things in Life: 72 Lessons in Ethics&quot;, translated into Chinese by Wang Xin, Guangxi Normal University Press, April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Limit value rational judgment exclusively to the scope of demonstration of the legitimacy of moral intentions, and rely entirely on instrumental rationality to &quot;scientifically&quot; achieve the above Intention, doing so is likely to blur our ethical horizons. The more prosperous science becomes, the more society needs ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This book is a collection of short comments published by the author in newspaper columns over the years. &quot;The limit of one thousand words&quot; forced him &quot;to write in a clear and concise style.&quot; What it focuses on are the confusions or dilemmas that ordinary people face in their daily lives in contemporary society: Is morality progressing? What is a good life? When should charity be shown to someone who has made a mistake? If narcotics are recognized to shorten lifespan, should they still be used to suppress pain? Should we live a thousand years? Can public figures have a private life? Is open diplomacy possible? Some readers may feel that the author has not provided any &quot;substantive conclusions&quot; on questions such as this. That may be precisely because we are too familiar with another way of discussion, which can give a decisive and only correct answer to any question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A book that talks about ethics to the public can be written without looking like a boring sermon with a straight face. Our skills in this area are far from perfect. However, the subtitle of the translation still evokes the feeling of sitting upright between the narrow desks and chairs. It would be better to literally translate the title of the book as &quot;Ethics in the Real World: 72 Short Essays Related to It&quot;, which may be more in line with the purpose of the original book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73724&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70519&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/2551857847.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;s34609084.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1565&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/2551857847.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Tiangang: &quot;Memory of the Ages: The Shaping of Modern Chinese Ideology&quot;, Renmin University of China Press, July 2023&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The earliest article I read included in this collection was &quot;1900: The Restless South.&quot; I remember that I called Brother Tiangang very excitedly at that time, hoping that he would write a few more articles on this &quot;Centennial Commemoration&quot;, and that when they were accumulated, they could be compiled and published. But meaningful &quot;hundred years&quot; are rare, and there are still some that are inconvenient to write about. The &quot;Reminiscence of the Year&quot; compiled before my eyes can be regarded as a common one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with many other books on similar topics, how can this book uncover so many new insights worthy of our deep thought? The key is whether you start from a bunch of ready-made presuppositions and pretend to interpret history, or do you go back to the scene and examine it from scratch? In fact, we cannot return to the historical scene. However, as long as you are willing, you can still &quot;see&quot; that period of history as empathetically as possible through the various records left by people at that time. &quot;The devil is in the details.&quot; To give an example that is not included in this book: Wang Kaiyun recalled the &quot;painful history&quot; of the burning of the Old Summer Palace. Why did he call that fire &quot;Lishan Fire&quot;? Not all ignored details are so important, but some solid and reliable details can really become &quot;devils&quot; that change established perceptions! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another century-old elegy in the book is &quot;1905: The Disillusionment of the Imperial Examination System&quot;. The abolition of the imperial examination not only broke the backbone of traditional Chinese society, but also allowed &quot;dispersed scholar-bureaucrats to pervasively penetrate into all strata of society, exacerbating the turmoil across the country.&quot; The author has the same view as Professor Yang Guoqiang, who strongly emphasizes that modern Chinese society suffered from &quot;tenon removal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73725&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70520&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/83bfe72096.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Untitled.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1583&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/83bfe72096.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Jianming: &quot;The Mainstream of Political Culture during the Founding of the United States&quot;, The Commercial Press, July 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Americans are brave enough to open up a &quot;noisy&quot; discussion on how to view the system of their country&#39;s founding. In this regard, the author of this book uses more than a thousand pages to develop a response and rethinking full of ideological tension based on his own life experience. There are not enough people to comment on &quot;Douban Reading&quot;, but the readers who left short comments all gave five stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;mainstream&quot; must have received countless tributaries along both sides of the river, making the water mixed with mud and sand; but it must also form the same giant current rushing forward. . During the American Revolution, the power elite and the radical masses distrusted each other and struggled with each other, even causing turmoil and rebellion in local society. Different from many self-proclaimed political science studies that always try to explain political struggles in terms of power, selfish desires and the pursuit of maximizing interests, and regard the pursuit of values ​​as just a fig leaf for seizing power and maximizing interests, the author emphasizes that it is the two sides’ mutual opposition to The common belief in popular sovereignty and republican principles prevented the American Revolution from becoming a story of a life-and-death struggle between good and evil, but instead became a witness to the initial establishment of modern democracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chapter 5 &quot;Reconstruction of the Concept of &#39;Democracy&#39;&quot; is particularly worthy of careful reading. The British Revolution promoted constitutionalism but did not talk about democracy. Therefore, Americans need to rediscover the value of democracy as &quot;a dangerous and even insulting label.&quot; This reminds me of Xu Fuguan’s opinion about the people’s “foolishness but spirituality”: “From the perspective of the knowledge level of intellectuals, the people are foolish. But in terms of their ability to judge big rights and wrongs, good and bad, the people are superior to intellectuals.… Therefore, Confucianism believes that people’s likes and dislikes derived from judgments of right and wrong can be trusted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73726&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70521 &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/9c20ec3332.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;006r8eOoly1hix2fxfbgxj30j60pkwi4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1626&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/9c20ec3332.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259765&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shao Xiaofeng: &quot;Song Style Artistic Life&quot;, Shanghai Literature and Art Publishing House, September 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;After China emerged from the &quot;medieval era&quot; during the Tang and Song Dynasties, did it enter its &quot;pre-modern era&quot;? Experts have mixed opinions on this. But they may all agree that the Song Dynasty, especially the Southern Song Dynasty, is a not-too-distant past that ordinary Chinese can directly perceive based on their real-life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The topic selection of this book is therefore very down-to-earth, the writing is relaxed but not frivolous, and it is profound but not esoteric. It is not about the art of the Song Dynasty itself, but the Song people&#39;s taste in art and their art of life, that is, the artistic orientation and aesthetic taste contained in daily life shared by many social strata at that time. The whole book uses seven theme words to connect fifty essays, focusing on the small and big things. Although it cannot be said that it has achieved the effect of &quot;gathering armpits into fur&quot;, it is not too much to say that it uses auspicious light feathers of different colors to connect a picture of the night sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[看网络短剧的人：“成功来得那么简单，爱情也是”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261395]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is a CEO with a net worth of hundreds of millions. One day in coffee While discussing business in the hall, he was mistaken for a blind date by a girl who made a living by running a street vendor. Out of interest in the girl, the president had a flash marriage with her. He hid his true identity from the girl, and the girl always thought that her husband was just an ordinary worker, and she still worked hard to earn money by setting up a stall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the plot develops, the identity of the CEO is exposed, and a past relationship also surfaces - it turns out that the CEO and the girl had a child five years ago due to a chance encounter. It’s just that the president didn’t know it, and the girl also forgot due to amnesia...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2023, this movie will feature boss tyrants, flash marriages, amnesia, sweet pets, and... The short drama &quot;After the Flash Wedding, Mr. Fu Can&#39;t Hide His Vest&quot;, which combines elements such as love after marriage, was launched. In just 24 hours, the recharge of the drama exceeded 20 million yuan, becoming a &quot;hot hit&quot; in the short drama market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/246b0e50e6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1169&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/246b0e50e6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259756&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cover covers of some mini program short dramas, including &quot;After the Flash Wedding, Mr. Fu Can&#39;t Hide His Vest&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The concept of the hit drama we make is at least 20 million yuan.&quot; Yan Peiliang, the director of the show, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;We are now a hit hit. The rate is almost 90%.&quot; Yan Peiliang&#39;s short play creation began in 2021, and has currently filmed more than a dozen popular short plays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Online micro-series, usually a single episode lasts from tens of seconds to about 15 minutes, and the number of episodes ranges from a dozen to hundreds of episodes, mainly including Short dramas on long video platforms mainly based on Youku, iQiyi, Mango, Tencent, etc., short dramas on short video platforms mainly on Douyin, Kuaishou, etc., and &quot;mini program short dramas&quot; that are &quot;parasitic&quot; on WeChat and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/bae82d8cc5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/bae82d8cc5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259757&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the cover of Douyin short drama. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Detawen&#39;s &quot;Micro Short Drama Market Report for the First Half of 2023&quot; shows that in the first half of 2023, a total of 481 new micro short dramas will be released, which has exceeded The number of new releases in 2022 (454). On November 22, the &quot;2023-2024 China Micro-Short Drama Market Research Report&quot; released by iiMedia Consulting showed that China&#39;s online micro-short drama market size will be 37.39 billion yuan in 2023, a year-on-year increase of 267.65%. Overseas, according to media reports, ReelShort, a short drama application platform owned by Chinese Online, has topped the U.S. iOS entertainment list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What supports the new trend of short dramas is the huge number of viewers. The &quot;China Online Audiovisual Development Research Report (2023)&quot; shows that as of December 2022, the number of short video users in China has reached 1.012 billion, of which more than half of the short video users have watched micro-short dramas and instant noodles that are less than 3 minutes in length. etc., the viewing proportion of users aged 19 and under exceeds 50%. In August 2023, data released by Kuaishou also showed that the number of people interested in short dramas on Kuaishou exceeded 260 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In just one or two hours, the audience traveled through the various fun spots that were set, experiencing rebirth, sudden wealth, and reverse. Attack, slap in the face, revenge and other various virtual lives. In this short drama world, they can easily gain a perfect love and reach the other side of success effortlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“What is needed is simplicity, speed and directness”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei used to play otome games (note: those targeting women Dating simulation game), I watched the short drama in August. She is 39 years old and works as a training supervisor in a company. The first short drama she watched was a clip automatically recommended by a short video platform. The plot was simple: the heroine had to find someone to get married because of various grievances between wealthy families. She mistakenly thought that the male protagonist was the president at the construction site. He was an ordinary worker. After marrying him, the two started a life of marriage first and love later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei watched it for more than a minute. Her first impression was of handsome men and beautiful women. She thought the theme of &quot;The Domineering President Falls in Love with Me&quot; was interesting. After searching for the full collection Then they gave chase. To her surprise, the short drama had a compact plot and no unnecessary plot. She finished it in just over an hour. After that, she started looking for short dramas recommended by other netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During a busy working day, Qiao Wei only has lunch break and two hours before going to bed. For her, the length of short dramas is just right. Even if there are more than a hundred episodes of short dramas, it only takes an hour or two to finish them all. During her lunch break, she would randomly open a movie and watch a dozen or twenty episodes, which lasted only about twenty minutes, as a pastime. &quot;Anyway, my time is fragmented.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scene of Tan Zhifeng watching the short play is also similar. She is completing her third year of master&#39;s degree this year and will watch short dramas in her spare time. However, she usually doesn&#39;t go out of her way to find short dramas recommended by others. She just watches the ones that appeal to her. She would even watch short dramas at double speed. &quot;The main reason is that she doesn&#39;t have enough time and is anxious, so she wants to finish it as soon as possible.&quot; Moreover, &quot;each scene of the short drama does not contain such complicated information,&quot; so double speed does not affect it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to her observation, short dramas generally rely on dialogue between actors to advance the plot. The president may sit on a chair and communicate with the butler next to him. Once the matter is done, &quot;you can move on to the next step.&quot; There are not so many details to explore in the short play, such as what traditional elements the set is designed according to, and what information is conveyed by the actors&#39; movements and eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tan Zhifeng used to read online articles for more than ten years. When she first saw some clips from short dramas, she thought they were &quot;tacky&quot;. Those settings, such as &quot;The Overlord and His Little Wife,&quot; were all popular elements in online articles more than ten years ago. But she didn&#39;t expect that now she is chasing short dramas. During the play, I still felt like I was &quot;on top&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/b396882cb5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/b396882cb5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259758&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the online short drama &quot;The President Loves Me Too Much&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She thinks this may be related to the simplicity and directness of the short play. For example, she wants to watch &quot;The Boss&#39;s Sweet Pet&quot;. In some TV dramas, it may take a long development process to reach the plot point of &quot;pet&quot;, but the short drama is different. It will directly use the plot scene of &quot;pet, love hard&quot;. Presented; another example is the plot of a slap in the face. A long drama may take a long time to prepare, but a short drama may reveal the conspiracy of the vicious female supporting character in the next episode and slap the face immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Instead of waiting for an hour for that one (cool) point, why don&#39;t I look at 10 (cool) points in 5 minutes. Although it looks tacky, But it’s refreshing faster.” Tan Zhifeng told Southern Weekend reporters, “What everyone needs is simple, fast and direct.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mo Xia also thinks so. She is 28 years old and works in a public institution. She remembered a costume-themed short drama she had watched before. There was a plot where the heroine changed her face, and no one except the hero could recognize her. She felt that if this plot was placed in a long drama, there would definitely be misunderstandings that would take several episodes to complete, which would make people feel frustrated. However, in the short drama, “There are no misunderstandings, it’s just a very smooth plot, and everyone just It was fun to watch.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I don&#39;t care what the two people in the middle have gone through, I just want to see them reconcile.&quot; Qiao Wei said. In her opinion, long dramas will always try to be logically linked, but &quot;there will still be logical gaps.&quot; Short dramas are less concerned with logic. &quot;(Since) it&#39;s not perfect, I might as well show more of what I want to see.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Provide us with material for dreaming&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Like online articles, short dramas are also divided into &quot;gender&quot;. &quot;Mainly serving male audiences, the audience of &quot;Female Channel Drama&quot; is mainly female. Li Yu is currently mainly writing &quot;male dramas&quot;. He has created eighty or ninety short plays, most of which have themes such as the God of War and the son-in-law. He introduced that the audience of &quot;male video drama&quot; is mainly between the ages of 35 and 55. Most of them work as security guards, delivery workers, online ride-hailing drivers, etc., and their educational level is generally low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Peiliang, who currently mainly produces &quot;female video dramas&quot;, said that &quot;female video dramas&quot; are more like romantic dramas, usually with elements such as sweet pets and sadomasochism. &quot;Male dramas&quot; are more delicate, and the age of the audience is relatively young, mainly between 25 and 45 years old. These women usually have a certain level of education and pay more attention to the picture, atmosphere and other factors of the short drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in Yan Peiliang&#39;s view, whether it is a &quot;male video drama&quot; or a &quot;female video drama&quot;, most viewers will substitute themselves when watching. Female viewers may fantasize about a handsome guy pursuing them, while male viewers may assume the identity of the male protagonist and feel that they are &quot;counterattacking&quot; and &quot;getting rich&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He observed that unlike female audiences who have high requirements for the appearance of the male and female protagonists in &quot;female-channel dramas&quot;, male audiences watch &quot;male-channel dramas&quot; &quot;, the requirements for the male protagonist&#39;s appearance are not high, just ordinary. Too good-looking will affect their acceptance. But at the same time, they hope that the heroine will be as beautiful as possible, so that &quot;the fantasy can be fulfilled.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a short play writer and director, Zhizhu pays more attention to creating a sense of atmosphere when filming, so that the audience can better relate to it. She is a photographer and started filming short plays in early 2022. Now her two short plays have received ratings of 6.8 and 7.2 respectively on Douban. She will work hard on lighting and composition, and create a sense of atmosphere by arranging scenes such as rain and wind. Sometimes she will also create a sense of tension through the gazes of the male and female protagonists as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/e0e94ec1e9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/e0e94ec1e9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the online short series &quot;Donglan Snow&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Actually, everyone has a dream about love in their hearts. I think the short drama invisibly provides us with material for dreaming.&quot; Qiao Wei told Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She always calls herself a &quot;middle-aged girl&quot;. In reality, she has a happy small family, and her son is already in the first grade of elementary school. But she feels that &quot;the reality is You are who you are, and you will never be the heroine in &#39;The Boss Falls in Love with Me&#39;, but when you watch the show, you can realize such a dream.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qian Wan is 27 years old and works in a bank. When watching short dramas, he prefers the plot of &quot;chasing his wife in the crematorium&quot;. For example, the male protagonist originally had a &quot;Bai Yueguang&quot;, but he abandoned the female protagonist after Bai Yueguang came back. After experiencing some things, he realized that the person he really loved was the heroine, thus starting the &quot;crematorium&quot; mode. She felt that this might be related to her only real love experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That relationship was pursued by her, and it only lasted for more than ten days. The other party admitted to her during a phone call that he still liked the girl he had not pursued before. Qian Wan felt that she had been tricked by the other party, and she was unwilling and sad. At that time, she really hoped that the boy would regret it, but she sent a message to the other party at that time, but the other party did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Aren&#39;t (these) dramas just for dreaming?&quot; Qian Wan said. Ren Dongxiao also thinks so. She is a sophomore this year. When watching short dramas, every time she sees the heroine being bullied and the CEO hero standing up to protect and take care of the heroine and slapping other people in the face, she expects it to really exist in reality. Such a person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei remembered watching &quot;Tom and Jerry&quot; when she was a child. No matter how much Tom was tortured by Jerry, he could not get enough of Jerry. This made her very happy. Peace of mind is a joy. Watching short dramas gave her a similar feeling. The villain&#39;s thoughts were always on his face. No matter how he framed the heroine, the hero would always appear at the critical moment. No matter how many twists and turns the hero and heroine went through, there was always a positive outcome. &quot;Everything you hope will happen happens, everything you hope to see will be seen,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Tan Zhifeng’s view, many short dramas will deliberately omit complicated things in real life. For example, if an 18th-tier star becomes a movie queen, the middle part should be It’s a long road, but in the short play, “you can get all the fame and achievements you want without putting in any effort”; no matter what the heroine’s conditions are or how she behaves, the CEO is devoted to her for no reason. . &quot;Success comes so easily, and so does love.&quot; She said, &quot;(These) things that make no sense if you think about it carefully may just be a dream created for everyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Maybe this kind of thing &quot;Happiness can&#39;t be found in the elegant hall, but it doesn&#39;t matter&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yu currently writes mainly &quot;small program short plays&quot;. He is 20 years old and can write two pieces a month. Three parts, each with about 100 episodes. The four short plays he wrote in the past two months are &quot;60% similar in content&quot;, and they are all based on the same God of War theme. The protagonist may be a fish seller in this drama, but next time he will be a pig butcher; some of the key slap-in-the-face plots will take place at the old man&#39;s birthday party, and some will be at the heroine&#39;s home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yu doesn&#39;t want his friends to know that he is writing a short play, for fear that they will think, &quot;It turns out that such rubbish stuff was written by people like you.&quot; . He would feel &quot;very ashamed&quot; and &quot;(the short play he wrote) has no nutrition, literary value or artistic value&quot;, but &quot;currently they (editors and platforms) do not want to innovate and do not require taking risks&quot;, and he also needs to survive . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Short plays inherently have many similar plots. (If you) often watch short plays, you will find that many characters have similar names and cannot be distinguished at all.&quot; Many short dramas currently on the market do not have the so-called film and television language. &quot;To put it bluntly, it is a dynamic PPT for online novels.&quot; Yan Peiliang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mo Xia said that she &quot;can remember very few&quot;. She has watched nearly fifty short plays this year, and she can name the titles and general plots of them. No more than ten. Other short drama viewers interviewed also mentioned that it was difficult to remember which short dramas they had watched. Tan Zhifeng recalled a certain short drama he had watched before, and what he remembered more was the short drama elements of &quot;traveling through the past, empress, queen, CEO, sweet pet, counterattack and slap in the face&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I can only say that this kind of short play is excitement itself. No matter how it is produced, it only meets some momentary needs for happiness. Maybe this kind of happiness even reaches the top of the screen. It’s not elegant, but it doesn’t matter.” Tan Zhifeng told Southern Weekend reporters. Just like herself, she is busy and stressed in real life, and she hopes to focus on watching things in her spare time that do not require the use of her brain. &quot;You can&#39;t keep one string tight all the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/be166c8ad3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/be166c8ad3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259760&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the online short series &quot;Abuse of Love: Mr. Lu&#39;s Newly Married Mute Wife&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei attaches great importance to the two hours of free time before going to bed. For her, &quot;If I didn&#39;t have these two hours, I would either be a As a wife, either a mother or an employee, I have to think about how to live a better life. (But) I feel that only when these two hours belong to myself, (will I) consider whether I am happy or not. I It doesn’t matter who it is, I don’t have to work hard or think.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She feels that the short play is “quite efficient” in terms of satisfying her own needs for happiness. . She used to spend those two hours playing games where she could design her own plot, or learning to play the ukulele. Although she was happy, she still found it too mentally taxing. &quot;The short play feels like a popping candy to me. I&#39;ve finished it in one bite. I don&#39;t need to think about it. I just feel happy now. As for whether it is meaningful or not, I don&#39;t think it&#39;s important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she also feels that if there is no short drama, it will not have much impact. Zhizhu also believes that even if there is no short drama, there will be something else, because everyone is very tired from work, and there must always be some entertainment channels for emotional release. Games, short videos, and novels can all be options. &quot;( Short plays) are very alternative for the audience.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Peiliang feels that although short plays are &quot;dispensable&quot; for some audiences. But just like Coke, some people think it is dispensable, and there will always be people who regard it as a necessity. &quot;Let the audience choose for themselves.&quot; For example, a breakfast shop sells steamed buns and provides side dishes. Some people buy the steamed buns and leave, while others just pick them up. Some dried radishes and pickles, &quot;The value of our existence is that when the audience has this demand, we still have some relatively good quality pickles waiting for them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (At the request of the interviewees, Tan Zhifeng, Mo Xia, Qian Wan , Ren Dongxiao, and Li Yu are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[离婚跟拍火了，闲得慌还是花钱买仪式感？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261363]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, divorce follow-up photography has become popular among young people. When they get divorced, many young people put aside the past haze and choose to follow the divorce and hold a divorce party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the divorce party, the banner read: &quot;This is the end of this B marriage.&quot; Blogger Sushi said, &quot;I think marriage has a corresponding sense of ceremony, and divorce also needs it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/WbJWJNGCsowzFqypzDYNtLZ5upGDvkAgYzir0g5M.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/WbJWJNGCsowzFqypzDYNtLZ5upGDv kAgYzir0g5M .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259747&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Photography of marriage and filming of divorce&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Data shows that China’s divorce rate has increased year by year since 2003, reaching its peak in 2019 at 3.4‰. In the past two years, it has also remained above 2‰. Among them, young people aged 25-35 have become the main force in divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under this trend, young people&#39;s attitudes and thoughts when facing divorce have changed greatly compared with the past. Compared with the bitterness and hatred of the older generation, divorce seems to be becoming a &quot;peaceful thing&quot; and a positive thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, as early as the 2010 movie &quot;If You Are the One 2&quot;, Mango, played by Yao Chen, and Li Xiangshan, played by Sun Honglei, held a party when they separated. Divorce ceremony. Actor Ge You, as the divorce certifier, said in his speech: &quot;Let&#39;s shake hands like acquaintances,&quot; which brought a relatively happy ending to the separation between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today&#39;s young people use the method of divorce follow-up, taking photos and Vlog to record the end of one stage and the beginning of a new stage. Taking photos becomes a ritual in the divorce process. Of course, this ceremonial divorce photoshoot is completely different from the wedding photoshoot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As we all know, when taking wedding photos, the theme is to get married and the main focus is celebration. Almost every newlywed couple will wear Chinese or Western-style dresses and hire professional photo studios and photographers to record the two people as a couple cuddling with each other and being united forever in various settings such as the seaside, under the shadow of coconut trees, and in the courtyard of an ancient house. The beautiful shadow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But divorce photos are no longer carefully posed on the beach or in the shadow of coconut trees, but may be the Civil Affairs Bureau or a place where the two went shopping together, or even A certain park or tea house for daily simple photography. After photographer Song Yang accepted an order to follow up on the divorce of an old classmate, he followed his friends to several places that were memorable to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the process, Song Yang followed silently and did not find a special camera position to capture the scene. He only occasionally gave simple guidance to the subjects. The overall atmosphere was not heavy and similar to normal. life portraits. Song Yang said, &quot;It&#39;s like shooting with normal friends. Everyone is calm, no conflicts, and not too close. And it&#39;s more casual, without even discussing in advance where to shoot and how to shoot.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the final group photo, other divorce photos also include a photo of a girl who came to a coffee shop after the divorce and took a photo with a coffee cup with &quot;Happy Single&quot; written on it. . The scenes and shots are not complicated, but with this simple stroke, the divorce was brought to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/TQWNs1nqr7G10j9Rh1deJAu8nZcnQfnvvMD0Iv9n.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/TQWNs1nqr7G10j9Rh1deJAu8nZcnQfnvvMD0Iv9n.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Why do young people want to take divorce photos?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, why do young people want to take divorce photos when they get divorced? First of all, of course, it was because of the divorce. As this incident occurred, many comprehensive factors behind it came into play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the development of social civilization has entered a new stage. Marriage is changing from a lifelong bond in the traditional concept to a relationship in the minds of young people. Freedom of choice. The influence of traditional concepts on young people is weakening, and young people are beginning to pay more attention to their personal rights and feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the change of this concept, when people face divorce, they have changed from crying, discrimination and dissuasion to equality today. Look at peace and confrontation, as well as calm and stable positive solutions, as turning points towards happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Xiaoyan, a psychology professor at Chongqing Normal University, believes that &quot;the business of divorce tracking can be carried out, which is enough to see changes in society and people&#39;s tolerance and psychological tolerance.&quot; Higher. In the past, everyone generally believed that divorce was an ugly thing and was unwilling to talk about it too much. Now, divorce is regarded as an event in life, and is no longer defined by failure, but by experience.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recording the divorce process is exactly what the French anthropologist Van Gennep put forward, &quot;There is always a transition from one stage to another in human life. , a ritual is needed in the process of transformation.&quot; Recording, sharing, and getting likes and comments, and fixing the mood, expression, time, location, etc. of the divorce in the circle of friends and social platforms is a sense of ritual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, as a professor of sociology at Tsinghua University said, &quot;Social media brings people who are far away&quot;, whether it is Douyin or Xiaohong Books, the impact of the online social wave is inevitable. When Generation Z people see some bloggers or peers sharing their experience in taking divorce photos, they will easily become curious about trying it. It is only human nature to follow the trend and take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Will divorce photography become a large-scale business? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, with the interest of young people in taking divorce photos, will divorce photography become a large-scale business? At present, it is not very large-scale yet and is relatively niche. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of demand, although the divorce rate is now high and there are many divorced people, the divorced group is also divided into those who need to take divorce photos and those who do not. Of those who have this need, they are still in the minority. Therefore, the market size of divorce photos is actually relatively small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judging from the current situation of receiving orders, many photographers receive such photo invitations on social platforms and then follow them. Some photographers with similar experience also publish relevant information through social platforms to gain customers. In reality, no dedicated docking platform or professional organization has emerged, and no large-scale promotion has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, from a business perspective, where there is demand, consumption will be created. Business opportunities often arise from scratch, from small to large. Divorce, like birth, birthday, graduation, marriage, funeral, etc., is actually a turning event in life. Compared with graduation or marriage, divorce, an equally important life event, has obviously not received enough attention and response. This is where the business opportunities for divorce services lie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the future, with the continuous changes in concepts, it is not impossible that the end of a marriage will be taken as seriously as the beginning of a marriage. Once this emphasis on divorce is transformed into demand and consumption, corresponding divorce service projects will appear more and more like marriage services. According to media reports, Japanese divorce companies can provide services such as divorce ceremonies and divorce travel, and many divorced couples have experienced corresponding services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, divorce photography also involves the photographer getting to know the emotions and privacy of both clients. This also requires practitioners to have certain legal knowledge and be able to Avoid during operation. But as the other side of marriage, relevant practitioners can pay attention to divorce-related products and services. It may not necessarily be an explosive growth business, but as the second growth curve, it may not be an effective supplement to regular business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一根78元的“考试专用”跳绳背后：企业为何连年中标应严肃调查丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261375]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;How much does a skipping rope cost? On e-commerce platforms, ordinary racing skipping ropes from many well-known sports brands only cost a dozen yuan, and even ones with counting functions can be bought for thirty or forty yuan. However, there are also some skipping ropes marked &quot;Exclusively for the High School Entrance Examination in ** City&quot; that are expensive. Xinhua News Agency recently reported that a special skipping rope designated by the Hangzhou Education Department for the high school entrance examination sells for as much as 78 yuan a piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency, for more than ten years, Hangzhou&#39;s high school entrance examination sports rope skipping projects have been using &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand skipping ropes. In order to familiarize children with the test ropes in advance, many schools and teachers explicitly or implicitly allow students to use &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand skipping ropes for practice. The brand&#39;s skipping ropes sell for 78 yuan for the regular model, and more than 140 yuan for the one with Bluetooth counting function. Even though the price is much higher than other brands, parents still have to pay the bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is designated by the local education department as a test-only device. In order to achieve good results in the exam, students have to use it for daily practice. This strategy has made &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand rope skipping a lot of money in Hangzhou. According to the agent of this brand of skipping ropes in Zhejiang, they sell more than 100,000 skipping ropes in Zhejiang a year, and more than 70% of their users are primary and secondary school students. In the past few years, Hangzhou had almost 100,000 primary and secondary school students (according to the Hangzhou National Economic and Social Development Statistical Bulletin, there were 681,000 primary school students and 264,000 junior high school students in Hangzhou in 2021), which shows its penetration rate. high. Calculated based on the profit of 70 yuan per ordinary skipping rope (industry sources revealed that the cost of ordinary skipping ropes is less than 8 yuan each, and the cost of those with counting functions is less than 20 yuan), the brand has a stable profit of more than 7 million yuan in Hangzhou every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did the &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope become exclusive for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination? According to an interview with Xinhua News Agency, the agent of the brand&#39;s skipping rope in Zhejiang said that since entering the Zhejiang market in 2011, the &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope has been used for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination Sports Examination Rope. The deputy director of the Hangzhou Municipal Education Examination Institute, who is responsible for purchasing sports equipment for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination, said that since 2011, the education department has &quot;rented and used&quot; high school entrance examination sports equipment produced by this brand manufacturer. Starting from 2017, the Education Examination Agency has used public bidding to select sports equipment for the high school entrance examination. However, this company still wins the bid every year, and the annual rental fee is 8.9 million yuan. A document from the Zhejiang Provincial Government Procurement Network shows that in 2019, the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute plans to use the &quot;single source&quot; procurement method to lease sports equipment of this brand for the high school entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as it entered the Zhejiang market, it became the exclusive skipping rope for high school entrance examination sports in Hangzhou City. It has been used exclusively for more than ten years. The &quot;open bidding&quot; of the education department turned out to be &quot;single source procurement&quot;, excluding other brands of skipping ropes on the grounds of so-called &quot;continuity of use, integrity of the examination system, and specificity of the software management platform.&quot; It is inevitable that people will have doubts. Who is this company? Who is its actual controller? What is so special about it that it deserves the favor of the Hangzhou Education Department? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This situation of &quot;exam-only&quot; skipping ropes that are much higher than the market price does not only exist in Hangzhou. Search results on the e-commerce platform show that the Shanghai high school entrance examination-specific technical skipping rope costs 158 yuan each, and the Guiyang &quot;examination room same style timing and counting online model&quot; skipping rope costs 179 yuan each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why must I use a specific brand of skipping rope for the rope skipping test? Especially according to students and teachers, this skipping rope is not suitable for primary and secondary school students. In fact, every skipping rope that meets national standards should be used for exams. For physical education exams, you can purchase a variety of skipping ropes from different brands, allowing students to choose freely. You might even consider asking students to bring their own jump ropes for exams. As for the automatic counting function that improves efficiency, if you are worried about inaccurate counting of students’ own skipping ropes, other methods can be used to solve the problem. With current technology, automatic counting can be achieved through video surveillance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, some schools have frequently &quot;cooperated&quot; with businesses to sell designated teaching aids to students. Some schools even required students to purchase tablets worth several thousand yuan in the name of &quot;information-based teaching.&quot; computer. To this end, the Ministry of Education and other departments have issued a document specifically requiring that &quot;students and parents shall not be forced or hinted to purchase designated teaching aid software or materials.&quot; But the examination, as a baton, will still play an obvious guiding role. As we all know, China’s education is seriously involution and everything is exam-oriented. As long as it is labeled &quot;exam-only&quot;, no matter how expensive it is, parents will buy it. This gives education departments and schools a lot of invisible power. When the education department labels a certain brand&#39;s products as &quot;exam-only&quot;, it is equivalent to endorsing it and giving it a great advantage in market competition. This advantage comes from administrative designation, which is essentially an administrative monopoly or rent-seeking behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, is there really nothing behind the 78-yuan &quot;exclusively for high school entrance examination&quot; skipping rope? This is something that relevant departments should find out clearly. More importantly, it breaks the status quo of only using certain equipment for exams and gives students more choices. Only in this way can normal market competition be promoted, students and parents will be spared from becoming leeks, and students can also use better products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国乞讨者泰国被捕”背后：残酷的人口贩运链]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261387]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Facial disfigurement, physical disabilities... In recent days, several Chinese beggars have appeared on the streets of Bangkok. Putting Thailand at the forefront of public opinion has also launched a new round of crackdowns on illegal begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, Aung Munna, deputy director of the Bangkok Metropolitan Police Department in Thailand, announced at a press conference that from November 10 to 20, the Bangkok police arrested six Chinese beggars. , and all six of them had varying degrees of disfigurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the physical conditions, confessions and partial investigation results of the six beggars when they were arrested, the Thai police suspected that these beggars may be victims of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Begging is prohibited in Thailand, but begging on the streets has always existed. Data from the Thai Ministry of Social Development and Human Security show that from 2016 to the present, 7,151 beggars have been found in Thailand, including 2,473 foreign beggars, most of whom are Cambodians and Burmese, and 68 are Chinese citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the beggars wandering the streets of Thailand are forced to beg because of human trafficking. According to the Thai charity Der Spiegel Foundation, there are at least 1,000 trafficked child beggars in Thailand. The &quot;Global Trafficking in Persons Report&quot; released by the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime also pointed out that of the 36,488 victims of human trafficking detected in 2020, 0.7% were for exploitative begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in Thailand responded, “The Embassy has taken note of the relevant reports and has sent consular officials to conduct consular visits to the parties. China has always required Chinese citizens coming to Thailand to abide by Thai laws. , respect local customs, and also attach importance to safeguarding their legitimate rights and interests. We believe that the relevant departments of the Thai government and the police will find out the truth as soon as possible and handle it appropriately in accordance with the law.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who is behind the scenes? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The arrest of a Chinese beggar was inseparable from the report of Thai Internet celebrity Guntouch Pongpaiboonwet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guntouch is active on Facebook. He has long been concerned about social issues in Thailand and has 730,000 fans. On November 19, 2023, Guntouch learned that a woman wearing a student uniform and a deformed face was begging in the Pin Klao area of ​​Bangkok. He suspected that international human trafficking might be involved, so he reported it to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, the Thai police arrested the female beggar. When she was arrested, she was carrying a backpack, a chair, a money box and a key card. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Thai vendor who has been operating a store in a shopping mall for more than ten years told the police that she only started to find beggars wearing student uniforms begging nearby this year. &quot;The arrested Chinese beggars are not alone. She appears early in the morning with other beggars and doesn&#39;t leave until evening.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports stated that the female beggar told the police that she went to Thailand to beg on November 10. She said that she was divorced and had two sons to raise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the woman was arrested, another Chinese woman claimed to be the beggar&#39;s translator and came to the police station to release her on bail, but was refused by the Thai police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman is not the only illegal beggar arrested by Thai police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of November 20, Thai police arrested a total of six Chinese beggars in Bangkok. According to the Thai Immigration Bureau, the six beggars entered Thailand on different flights from mainland China, Hong Kong, Malaysia and Laos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the investigation continues, more details are emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thailand police investigation found that these beggars began to enter Thailand on tourist visas in June, and one of them was applying for a private university in northern Thailand. If your tourist visa is converted to a student visa, you will be able to extend your stay in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, beggars daily beg in crowded shopping malls and tourist attractions, earning about 10,000 baht (approximately RMB 2,000) per person per day. The police investigated the bank account of one of the women and found that the monthly flow was as high as 2 million baht (approximately RMB 400,000). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to comprehensive media reports, the six arrested beggars were around 40 years old, and all had facial scars and disabilities in their limbs. One of the beggars told the police that his facial injuries and hand disabilities were old childhood injuries caused by the explosion of flammable items, while the others refused to provide relevant information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, there are inextricably linked relationships between these beggars. Thai police found that two of the beggars lived in the Wang Thonglang area, and the rest lived in different hotels in Bangkok. This is inconsistent with the previous arrest of a woman who said she had no fixed abode. Meanwhile, some beggars share the same Thai translation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Thai police suspect that these beggars may be victims of international human trafficking, and that there may be Thai support behind the begging gang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, one beggar has been deported from Thailand, and the remaining beggars are still detained at the Immigration Bureau. Major General Panta, deputy director of the Thai Immigration Department, said that the investigation into the gang involved is being expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Thailand’s campaign against illegal begging continues to deepen. Media reports said that Thai police arrested four more beggars in Bangkok, from Laos and Cambodia. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Countries of origin, destination and transit of human trafficking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Begging is illegal in Thailand. As early as 2016, Thailand introduced the &quot;Begging Control Law&quot; in an attempt to eliminate illegal beggars on the streets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this law, foreign beggars who beg in Thailand will be deported, while domestic beggars will be forced to receive vocational training or be sent to reception centers. Those who attempt to profit from organizing street begging will face up to three years in prison and/or a fine of up to 30,000 baht. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in order to combat street begging, Thailand has carried out many street cleaning operations in recent years. According to reports, in May 2023, the Pattaya police in Thailand arrested 37 Cambodian beggars, including 19 adults and 18 children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Thai officials, strict measures against street begging are to prevent illegal begging from breeding many criminal problems such as human trafficking and child labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in fact, Thailand, known as the &quot;Land of Smiles&quot;, has long been plagued by the dark trade of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, the U.S. State Department released the &quot;Trafficking in Persons Report&quot;, which ranked Thailand as the third lowest ranking, which means that the Thai government did not fully comply with the minimum standards in responding to and eliminating human trafficking, and No significant effort was made. Meanwhile, the U.S. State Department noted that Thailand is a source, destination and transit country for men, women and children subject to forced labor and sex trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thailand is located in the center of Southeast Asia and is a destination for illegal immigrants from many neighboring countries seeking high-paying jobs. The United Nations International Organization for Migration estimates that there are nearly 5 million immigrants in Thailand, of which about 1 million to 2.5 million do not have legal immigration status. Lacking legal protection, these illegal immigrants are extremely vulnerable to work exploitation, human smuggling and trafficking, and transnational crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, the &quot;Golden Triangle&quot; connecting Thailand, Myanmar and Laos has been a hotbed of illegal activity, with Thailand a convenient location for traffickers to transport victims to other countries. Reports indicate that sex trafficking victims from Bangladesh, Pakistan, Vietnam and North Korea transit through Thailand to Western Europe, Singapore, Russia and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also difficult for the Thai people themselves to escape the nightmare of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that as of July 2020, more than 120,000 Thais are still working abroad. &quot;Many Thais prefer to seek easier but illegal jobs abroad, which makes them easy targets for human traffickers and easy to be exploited by unscrupulous employers,&quot; said Samann, a senior fellow at the Institute of Asia Studies at Chulalongkorn University in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Thomson Reuters Foundation estimates that at least 522 Thai workers died in South Korea from 2015 to 2022, about 84% of whom were illegal immigrants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to change the status quo, in 2018, the Thai police teamed up with social workers and non-governmental organizations to set up a special working group to combat human trafficking. At the same time, the Thai government is increasing its financial budget every year. In 2022, the Thai government will allocate 440 million baht to prevent and combat human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from official data, the problem of human trafficking in Thailand seems to have improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the U.S. State Department released the latest version of the &quot;Trafficking in Persons Report&quot;, and Thailand&#39;s ranking rose to the second level. This is the second consecutive year that Thailand has ranked second. Thailand&#39;s Minister of Social Development and Human Security Waravutt noted that Thailand has been committed to improving to Level 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in 2022, the Thai government investigated 253 cases of human trafficking and identified 444 victims of human trafficking. The vast majority of these 444 victims are from Thailand (344) and ASEAN countries such as Laos, Myanmar, and Indonesia. Another 11 are from China, Uganda, Tanzania, Uzbekistan, Kenya, and other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the data released by the Thai government may be just the tip of the iceberg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. State Department pointed out in the 2023 &quot;Human Trafficking Report&quot; that fraud companies located in Cambodia, Laos, Myanmar and the Philippines often use Thailand as a transit country to lure fraudsters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Myawaddy, located on the border of Thailand and Myanmar, is one of the main gathering places for fraud parks, across the river from Mae Sot, Thailand. Mechel Moore, CEO of the Mae Sot Anti-Human Trafficking NGO, told reporters that since August 2022, the organization has helped at least 452 victims of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that behind human trafficking in Thailand, there are often government officials, who facilitate human trafficking by accepting bribes. In 2022 alone, 35 government officials were investigated by the Thai government for their involvement in human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马航MH370乘客家属索赔案今天开庭审理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:52:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Malaysian Airlines flight MH370 is a Boeing 777 aircraft formerly operated by Malaysia Airlines. It was flown by Malaysia on March 8, 2014. Contact was lost en route from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing. There were 239 passengers and crew on the flight, including 154 Chinese passengers. On January 29, 2015, the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced that MH370 had crashed and 239 people on board were presumed to have died. Today (November 27), this air transport damage liability dispute case was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that more than 40 family members of passengers have filed lawsuits, and the cases will be heard in Beijing Chaoyang Court from November 27 to December 6. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attorney for the passengers’ families said that there are five defendants in this case, namely Malaysia Airlines, also known as the old Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia International Airlines Co., Ltd. also known as the new Malaysia Airlines, Boeing Company of the United States, and Aircraft Engines Manufacturers: Rolls-Royce in the UK and Allianz in Germany. The claims of the more than 40 passengers&#39; families are different, but they mainly focus on two points. One is to find out the truth about the missing incident of flight MH370 through case trial, and the other is the issue of compensation. It is understood that the biggest difficulty in the trial of this case is to ascertain the truth of the incident. &lt;p>; . The current inability to produce evidence, insufficient evidence, or incomplete evidence is a huge hole left in the trial process of this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the amount of civil compensation filed by the passengers’ families is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. Because each family’s situation is different, the amount is also different. A large part of the compensation fee is mental damage solatium. , the highest is 30 to 40 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also understood that in addition to the family members of more than 40 passengers who filed the lawsuit in Beijing Chaoyang Court, the family members of more than 110 other passengers have reached settlements with the five defendants and signed settlement agreements. The amount received ranged from 2.5 million to 3 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人民银行等八部门联合印发《关于强化金融支持举措 助力民营经济发展壮大的通知》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261389]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:37:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party and the requirements of the Central Financial Work Conference, comprehensively implement the &quot; The Opinions of the Central Committee and the State Council on Promoting the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; adhere to the &quot;two unwavering principles&quot; and guide financial institutions to establish the concept of &quot;equal treatment&quot; and continue to strengthen financial services for private enterprises. Recently, the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the China Securities Regulatory Commission Eight departments including the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Finance, and the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Financial Support Measures to Support the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;), proposing that 25 specific measures to support the private economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; clarifies the goals and priorities of financial services private enterprises. In terms of total amount, by formulating annual service targets for private enterprises and increasing the weight of services related to private enterprises in performance appraisals, we will increase financial support for private enterprises and gradually increase the proportion of loans to private enterprises. Structurally, we will increase support for key areas such as technological innovation, &quot;specialization, specialization, specialization, green and low carbon, and industrial base reengineering projects, as well as for private small, medium and micro enterprises.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; emphasizes the need to proceed from the characteristics of private enterprises&#39; financing needs and strive to unblock diversified financing channels such as credit, bonds, and equity. Banking financial institutions should increase their support for first-time loans and credit loans, actively carry out industrial chain supply chain financial services, and proactively provide fund continuity services for private enterprises. They should not blindly suspend, suppress, withdraw or cut off loans, and at the same time Promote development and prevent risks. Optimize the registration mechanism for private enterprise debt financing instruments, give full play to the role of private enterprise bond financing support tools, and expand the scale of private enterprise bond financing. Encourage and guide institutional investors to actively and scientifically allocate private enterprise bonds and increase investment in private enterprise bonds. Support the listing financing and mergers and acquisitions of private enterprises, give full play to the supporting service role of regional equity markets and equity investment funds for private enterprises, and expand the scale of equity financing for high-quality private enterprises. Increase the supply of foreign exchange facilitation policies and services, and support private enterprises in &quot;going out&quot; and &quot;bringing in&quot; by improving the level of facilitation of current account receipts and payments, improving cross-border investment and financing facilitation policies, and optimizing cross-border financial foreign exchange special services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; proposes that monetary policy tools, fiscal incentives, insurance guarantees and other measures should be comprehensively used to enhance the enthusiasm of financial institutions in serving the private economy. Strengthen departmental cooperation, improve credit information sharing, financing guarantees, convenient bill discounting, accounts receivable rights confirmation, taxation and other supporting policies and mechanisms, and enhance the private economic and financial carrying capacity. Financial institutions should strengthen publicity and interpretation, and proactively push financial support policies, financial products and service information to private enterprises. Local financial management, development and reform, industry and information technology, finance and taxation, federation of industry and commerce and other departments have strengthened communication and coordination, strengthened supervision and guidance, and improved policy effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the People&#39;s Bank of China and other departments will guide financial institutions to promptly implement the requirements of the &quot;Notice&quot; and formulate specific implementation rules. At the same time, they will strengthen statistical monitoring and policy effect evaluation to ensure that the policy benefits private enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/dc1c48c7099df8f07e8e225042aef088.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;760&quot; height=&quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/dc1c48c7099df8f07e8e225042aef088.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259746&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Website screenshot&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融业“百模大战”正酣，如何在合规中突围？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261381]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The financial industry is entering a big model moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2023, China Merchants Union Finance and Sun Yat-sen University jointly developed and launched the first 13 billion parameter open source large model in the consumer finance industry-&quot;China Merchants Union Smart Deer&quot;. This is the fourth public large-scale model of the consumer finance industry after Du Xiaoman, Masha Consumption and Ant Financial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, traditional financial institutions are also accelerating the application of large models. Some large technology companies are looking to cooperate with financial institutions. The “battle of hundreds of models” in the financial industry is in full swing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How effective is the implementation of large-scale financial models? What are the challenges? What impact will it have on the future financial ecosystem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center investigated various mainstream financial institutions, tested the apps of various financial institutions, and reviewed the speeches of guests at major professional forums in 2023. They found that in the second half of 2023, financial institutions will accelerate Lay out large-scale models, and the main application areas are intelligent customer service, investment strategies, risk control, investment consulting and investment education, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But currently, cooperation between technology companies and financial institutions is the mainstream model. In this cooperation, financial institutions are not only worried about the business effects of large models, but also have concerns about data security and compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that large models in the financial industry are still in the trial and promotion stage, but the trend is irreversible. A researcher at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center put forward three suggestions for this: promoting &quot;industry-university-research&quot; collaboration, accelerating legislation, and paying attention to talent training. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Financial large models are blooming everywhere&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is special about financial large models? The authoritative international artificial intelligence magazine &quot;Nature Machine Intelligence&quot; believes that large models refer to &quot;deep learning pre-training algorithms&quot; with parameter scales reaching more than 100 million levels. General-purpose large models require huge computing resources and data volumes, and require extremely high technical teams and financial support. They are key projects for major domestic and foreign technology companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vertical domain model focuses on specific industries, fields or scenarios. Therefore, large models in vertical fields have relatively low requirements for computing power and algorithms, but have higher requirements for data in specific fields. Financial large models are typical large models in vertical fields. As a modern high-end service industry, the financial industry has the characteristics of huge data volume and rich scenarios, which is naturally consistent with the large model&#39;s demand for massive high-quality data. Therefore, the financial industry has become one of the first scenarios where large models have been implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2023, domestic financial institutions will accelerate the layout of large models. In addition to banks, insurance companies and leading securities firms have gradually joined the &quot;Battle of Hundreds of Models&quot;. It is worth noting that consumer finance companies have also begun to compete in the battle for large models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incomplete statistics from researchers at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center show that among the 19 systemically important banks, more than half have announced that they have released large models or are in the process of intense preparations. Consumer finance companies such as Masha Consumption, Ant Financial and China Merchants Union Financial have also successively released large financial models and claim to be in a leading position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/TAZxT7BMDWTBFDbso4wRVgvJjAFCEpyPES4cNKpx.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height= &quot;425&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/TAZxT7BMDWTBFDbso4wRVgvJjAFCEpyPES4cNKpx.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different financial institutions What are the similarities and differences between large models? Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that from industry practice, except for a few leading financial institutions such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China that are developing large models of the financial industry, other small and medium-sized financial institutions generally choose to cooperate with large cloud vendors. Pilot a certain business scenario. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further research by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that smart customer service has almost become a standard feature of financial institutions, such as the &quot;smart teller&quot; of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, the &quot;Bank&quot; of China Construction Bank, and the &quot;digital employee sisters&quot; of Bank of Communications. &quot;Jiaojiao&quot; and &quot;Xiaojiao&quot;, Jiangsu Bank&#39;s &quot;Smart Xiaosu&quot;, etc. In addition, different financial institutions use AI technology in the fields of investment, risk control, investment consulting and investment education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development models, cooperation with third parties is still the mainstream model for financial institutions to develop large models. Financial institutions currently mainly cooperate with technology giants such as Baidu, Tencent, Alibaba and Huawei, as well as universities such as Tsinghua University and Peking University, as well as financial technology companies such as Hundsun Electronics and Yuxin Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with independent research and development, cooperative research and development is relatively cost-effective. Xu Dongliang, CTO of Duxiaoman, said that training a general-purpose large model with a scale of hundreds of billions costs tens of millions per time. Earlier, some institutional media reported that GPT-4’s training time was close to 100 days, and the training cost was as high as 63 million US dollars. In other words, training can be carried out up to three times a year, and each time costs about 450 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can small and medium-sized financial institutions implement large models? Huawei released a report titled &quot;Digital Finance: Leading Intelligent Change and Building the Future of Digital Finance Together&quot;. It is recognized in the industry that when the number of large model parameters reaches 62 billion parameters, there will be a surge in capabilities. At present, many open source large models have directly supported parameter sets of tens of billions or even 62 billion, significantly lowering the threshold for AI training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/Qx8S0ybfmS8cDHVoJ4Gt1pUK81Mbjh3UMzQCeRDZ.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height= &quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/Qx8S0ybfmS8cDHVoJ4Gt1pUK81Mbjh3UMzQCeRDZ.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a technical perspective See, pursuing large model parameter scale is not the best choice for small and medium-sized financial institutions. Although in theory, the larger the parameter scale of a large model, the stronger its capabilities, but the purpose of developing large models is to empower business and serve customers, not to show off skills. Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that small and medium-sized financial institutions do not need to &quot;roll out&quot; technology. They can choose billion-level, tens of billions, or even billion-level large-scale model pilots for a certain business scenario, giving full play to the organizational flexibility advantages of small and medium-sized financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Under the cooperation model, the two parties have great differences&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;With the support of AI, the digital transformation of the financial industry is accelerating, but large models have a negative impact on financial business. The empowerment needs to be further verified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that under the cooperation model, financial institutions are mainly concerned about three issues: first, efficiency; second, security; and third, compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of efficiency, digital and intelligent overall solutions that integrate the front, middle and back offices are the core demands of financial institutions. In the recent Financial Street Forum, industry experts also discussed this issue. When Zhai Chenxi, former vice president of Tianfeng Securities, served as a judge for the finals of the third global financial technology application scenario competition, he pointed out that the biggest problem faced by financial institutions is that no one does the integration, resulting in inconsistent data interfaces in the front, middle and back offices, and data cannot be shared. This leads to an increase in internal communication costs to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center tested a number of financial institution apps and found that even in the customer service business where large models are most widely used, there are still many problems. For example, inaccurate answers, repeated answers, etc. Some can only accept &quot;yes or no&quot; answers and cannot understand synonymous expressions. In addition, financial institution apps use intelligent customer service to over-market, such as using robocalls to frequently harass customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Dongliang pointed out at the Financial Street Forum that when implementing large-scale financial model scenarios, five key issues still need to be addressed: first, how to choose the basic model; second, how to use the financial institution’s own business data Integrating into large models; the third is how to control model defects such as hallucination problems; the fourth is how institutions can build competition barriers when every institution will deploy large models in the future. The fifth is how to ensure the safety and compliance of the model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to security, financial institutions have large amounts of market data, transaction data, and customer data. The importance of data security and privacy protection is self-evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Jifeng, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, once pointed out at the 2023 INCLUSION Bund Conference that the security issues of large models are mainly the collection, use and disclosure of personal information without consent. Privacy issues may occur during the training process or during use, and the generation ability of large models diversifies the ways of &quot;privacy leakage&quot;, making privacy protection more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of compliance, although cooperating with cloud service providers and purchasing their model training services is a shortcut for financial AI training, the financial industry is a highly regulated industry, and data involving key businesses is often subject to compliance pressure. And it is difficult to upload to the public cloud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jun, senior vice president of Bairong Yunchuang, also said that there are two main trends in data compliance. One is external risks, including whether data use is in compliance with laws and regulations, hackers and criminal gangs Malicious attacks, etc.; the second is internal risks, especially data leakage risks caused by operational risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; that will be implemented from August 15, 2023 balances technological development and regulatory needs and reflects the equal emphasis of legislators on encouragement and supervision. concept. It is expected that the implementation of the &quot;Measures&quot; will bring more legal protection and institutional innovation to the development of China&#39;s generative artificial intelligence service field. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ecological co-construction is the way out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How can large-scale financial models that are still in the trial and promotion stage move toward industrial-level R&amp;D applications? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hundsun Electronics’ survey found that 67% of financial institutions prefer cooperation at the application layer, and the application areas they are most concerned about are investment advisory assistants (56%), compliance and internal control (44%), and investment research (25%) ), while customer service accounts for only 10%. This is partly due to the deep application of AI in the customer service field, but more importantly, it reflects the expectations of financial institutions for large models to empower core businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As financial large models move toward industrial-level research and development, ecological co-construction should be emphasized. This point has been repeatedly echoed in the opinions of experts at major professional forums in 2023. For example, the 2023 China Intelligent Finance Forum even launched the &quot;Financial Large Model Ecological Plan&quot; on-site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Dongliang believes that the industrial application of large financial models requires the joint construction and participation of scenario users (financial institutions), model providers, training tool providers and other parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talent is the key. At the Financial Cloud Special Session of the 2023 Tencent Global Digital Ecosystem Conference, Tencent Cloud Vice President Hu Liming pointed out that leading financial institutions are now recruiting algorithm PhDs. Although they can leverage cloud vendors, in the end financial institutions must have independent use and innovation Ability to lead the construction, optimization and continuous addition of new application scenarios for large AI platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Cunchao, Director of the Third Department of the North Research Platform of the R&amp;D Center of the Agricultural Bank of China, also said that in the in-depth application of large models in the financial industry, especially in-depth applications embedded in financial scenarios, data is the core and security is the prerequisite. , computing power is the foundation, scenarios are the driving force, talents are the key, and collaboration is the guarantee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the application of large models is an irreversible long-term development trend and a key strategy to accelerate the transformation of digital finance and promote high-quality financial development. However, this is a holistic, It is a systematic and long-term project, so we cannot rush for quick success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, compliance and data security cannot be ignored. In the process of digital finance transformation, financial institutions need to be alert to compliance risks and balance the relationship between innovation and security. In data governance, clear boundaries and clear rules are the basis for consensus among all parties. Otherwise, differences will be amplified and development will be hindered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center put forward three suggestions: First, promote &quot;industry-university-research&quot; collaboration. Strengthen peer and cross-sector exchanges and cooperation, formulate standards, standardize processes, and create and share together. The second is to speed up legislation. The European Artificial Intelligence Law has been implemented, and the draft of the Chinese version of the Artificial Intelligence Law is also under review. The third is to attach importance to talent cultivation. Talent reserves restrict the implementation of AI development, because not only early-stage R&amp;D requires professional talents, but later-stage operations and maintenance also require talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[该在小学阶段把体育变主科吗？不要忘掉强身健体的初衷丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261373]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The official website of the Ministry of Education shows: Representatives of the People&#39;s Congress proposed &quot;About changing the physical education subject from a minor subject to a main subject, and providing free distribution to primary school students&quot; Physical Education Textbook Suggestions”. The Ministry of Education responded: There is no priority among the subjects prescribed in the national curriculum plan. Each subject has its own unique educational value and cannot be substituted for each other. At the same time, each subject cooperates with each other to educate students collaboratively to ensure the achievement of training goals. Physical education and health courses are an important part of the basic education curriculum system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the reply from the Ministry of Education, &quot;there is no distinction between primary and secondary subjects&quot; avoiding the distinction between major subjects and minor subjects; the statement that &quot;each subject has its unique educational value&quot; is also correct. However, it is still necessary to discuss the common understanding of what is a major subject and what is a minor subject. As far as primary schools are concerned, the main subjects generally recognized by the public are nothing more than Chinese, mathematics and foreign languages, and the minor subjects are nothing more than physical education, art and music. There are two specific criteria for classification: first, teaching time, the main subject generally has more teaching time than minor subjects; second, the main subject will have a closed-book examination, and the results will be included in the total score of the mid-term, final and entrance exams to become an outstanding student or to be promoted. The standards of a good school. The latter criterion is more commonly used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Compulsory Education Curriculum Plan and Curriculum Standards (2022 Edition)&quot; stipulates that the proportion of total class hours in nine years is 20%-22% for Chinese, which is very high, 13%-15% for mathematics, and 13%-15% for foreign languages. 6%-8%, physical education and health 10%-11%, exceeding foreign languages, science or physics, chemistry 8%-10%, according to the Ministry of Education, this proportion, &quot;higher than the United States , Australia, Germany, Russia, South Korea, Japan, Finland, the United Kingdom, Canada and other countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, from the perspective of teaching time, physical education is already the main subject in the compulsory education stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the primary promotion from primary school to junior high school is mainly based on interviews and admissions to the nearest &quot;good junior high school&quot; and admission by lottery, there is no unified examination for primary school to junior high school. In this sense, it seems meaningless to talk about major subjects and minor subjects at the primary school level. Because there are no exams. However, there are also some good schools that conduct the so-called &quot;secret test&quot; or resume + interview to obtain good students. Of course, the test is still on traditional cultural subjects or main subjects such as language and mathematics, and will not test physical education. In this sense, primary schools Stage physical education is a minor subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, junior high school is very different. Physical education must be included in the total score of the high school entrance examination. The original intention is to make children pay attention to sports. The score is not low. Under one physical education subject, there are many test items, which is essentially equivalent to taking several tests. In order to get high scores or even perfect scores, schools and parents force children to take exams, which increases the academic burden instead of reducing it. &quot;Junior high school students in the gym&quot; have even become a strange sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially parents in urban areas spend a lot of money to hire private tutors for their children, which has led to a skyrocketing fee for various sports coaches. This essentially requires junior high school students to be trained according to athlete standards. Extensive training and overtraining have resulted in a large number of sports injuries for children, such as knee meniscus injuries, which is detrimental to children&#39;s physical health, growth and development, and is contrary to physical fitness. The positioning of fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because mass sports and competitive sports are completely different things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Popular sports are suitable for everyone. They are designed to allow the body to have necessary activities, to allow muscles to exercise, move the muscles and bones, and strengthen the body. Even if you participate in certain ball games or track and field events, the level of It is also amateur-level; at the same time, exercisers can breathe fresh air outdoors, establish a connection with nature, and repair their body and mind; it is also often a social activity that meets the need for interactive connections with others and helps promote mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competitive sports are played by a very small number of people with athletic talent. They are essentially a breakthrough in the limits of human physical ability. Among many competitive sports, many commercially successful industries and profit models have emerged. Including selling tickets + selling broadcast rights + advertising endorsements, etc., the income of top sports stars is very high; large-scale events such as the Olympics are participated in by countries and regions, and they have a higher meaning. Athletes winning medals are regarded as bringing glory to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the sports for students in ordinary primary and secondary schools should be a type of mass sports, which allows students to go outdoors more and strengthen their bodies. It is best to have their own favorite projects and get the benefits from sports. Fun and spiritual joy, under the blue sky and sun, soothing the body and mind and cultivating the spirit, this is something everyone can do. Children who are talented in sports and are interested in making a career in competitive sports can enter specialized sports schools to bring out their talents and potential. Being physically strong is only a very basic requirement. In short, the two types of schools have completely different requirements for student physical education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If physical education is included in the total score of mid-term and final exams at the primary school level and becomes the so-called &quot;main subject&quot;, it will only be counterproductive. Working hard to train in events you don’t like in order to get high scores. Overtraining and improper training often lead to sports injuries. Physical education classes will become hard labor and children will not feel the joy of sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, recess has this tendency. It was originally intended to allow children more time to exercise, but many schools insist on making it ritualistic, pursuing uniformity and grandeur. Instead, children view recess as a daunting prospect. Sports activities should be relaxing and fun, so that they can exercise the body and mind. Fun, meaningful physical activity is itself a natural medicine for maintaining and promoting mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, many children have psychological problems. One of the reasons is that families and schools force children to take exams in knowledge education, and parents neglect character education and values ​​education for their children. The second reason is that children generally need to Strengthen the cultivation of physical and mental repair mechanisms and habits. In fact, what children now lack is not physical activity time, but physical activity time that is fun, meaningful, can release their nature, and can soothe the body and mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the high school entrance examinations in ordinary junior high schools, it is the right direction for various places to change the physical education examination from a merit-based examination to a standard examination in 2022, so that children do not need to work hard on the physical education examination items, consume too much or even Destroy your own body just for high scores; only specialized sports schools need to select the best to stimulate the talents of good talents and continue to work towards challenging the limits of human physical fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>