<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[211高校女硕士遭杀猪盘被骗138万：财务决策与婚恋决策分开是防骗关键]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;211 female master&#39;s degree was defrauded of 1.38 million in two weeks&quot; became the first hot search topic . The client, Xueer, joined a bank in Shanghai after graduating from a 211 college in Jiangsu with a master&#39;s degree. In May and June this year, she posted about choosing a spouse on a social platform. A man took the initiative to contact her, saying that he lived in Wujia Plaza, Yangpu District, Shanghai, graduated from Shanghai University of Finance and Economics, worked in a major Internet company, and was on a business trip in Beijing. After communicating online for a period of time, the other party sent Xueer a link and asked her to click to download an app called &quot;luno&quot; and teach her to buy coins on it, and then use the coins to buy up and down to earn some extra money. At first, Xueer made some money. Later, the other party asked Xueer to invest more than 1.3 million yuan for various reasons. In the end, Xueer found out that she had fallen into a scam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The endless emergence of &quot;pig-killing plates&quot;, killing all kinds of people, naked chat traps for men, and marriage and love traps for women show that scammers have a precise grasp of the psychological differences between the sexes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although they have high education, high income, and good looks, many women are also trapped in it. The reason is that some highly educated women often fail to make good financial decisions and marriage decisions during marriage, especially when they mix them up, giving scammers an opportunity to take advantage of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called financial decision-making involves financial expenditure, investment and other behaviors. It is necessary to comprehensively consider the reasonable feasibility of the investment project, investment scale, investment stop-loss standards, and the consequences of investment failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;pig-killing plate&quot; cash-out routine often uses high interest rates to induce victims. However, what you want is high interest rates, and scammers are targeting your principal. People should establish a common sense about investment. The expected return of investment products is positively related to investment risk. Just like the daily purchase of various financial products, financial products will be marked with different grades. Financial products with low expected annualized yields but marked with low risk mainly invest in high-credit-rated bonds (such as treasury bonds), money market and other low-risk financial products. , and financial products with high expected annualized returns but marked with medium and high risks will have a high proportion of high-volatility financial products such as stocks, commodities, and foreign exchange in the investment product portfolio. When customers purchase products, financial management institutions also conduct personal investment risk assessments and recommend investment varieties that are more in line with their risk preferences based on past investment categories, income status and other information reported by them to avoid blind investments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, when the woman hears the other party introducing investment products that &quot;guarantee no loss and interest rates far exceed the market average&quot;, she should be alert. Guo Shuqing once reminded the majority of financial consumers and investors: high returns mean high risks. If the return rate exceeds 6%, there will be a question mark. If the return rate exceeds 8%, it will be very dangerous. If the return rate exceeds 10%, you will be prepared to lose all your principal. In addition, do not trust unknown information, do not disclose personal information at will, do not open unknown network links, and do not transfer money easily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whenever you encounter a large amount of capital investment, learn more about investment and financial management expertise in advance, or ask people or institutions with relevant experience to provide advice, and then make investment and investment decisions based on your own risk tolerance, funding level, etc. Decisions on whether, the amount of investment, and how to stop losses promptly when problems arise should become the &quot;financial intelligence&quot; possessed by everyone. Especially as highly educated women, they should have minimum learning ability. Xueer in the above case works in a bank. Although she is engaged in IT work, it is not difficult to find a few colleagues who understand financial management for advice. However, she was deceived by her husband, especially the initial profit from &quot;investment&quot;, and stepped deeper into the trap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, men and women also need to make good decisions about marriage and love. Generally speaking, in the marriage and love market, men and women have different demands. Men tend to pay more attention to women&#39;s appearance, age, etc., while women focus on men&#39;s wealth, family background and other criteria. For Kochi women, there are many men who are excellent in certain aspects in the marriage and love market, but there are very few rich men. The tall, rich and handsome people with both appearance and wealth are a typical scarce group. Their choice space is huge, so they are interested in the &quot;rich and handsome&quot;. The competition for &quot;handsome&quot; is actually very fierce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why scammers create rich and handsome characters is that they know that this group of people is in a seller&#39;s market, and women are often hard to find. Once they meet, some women are eager to capture Prince Charming tightly, have a serious dependence mentality, and are prone to obey the tricks of scammers. Some women are too pursuing the perfection of love and high returns on investment, and ignore the risks and uncertainties in reality. When faced with the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; scam, he was tempted by emotions and interests, and fell into the scammer&#39;s trap, ultimately losing both his life and money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you are a man or a woman, when making a marriage decision, you must make at least three prior assessments: First, objectively evaluate your own conditions. What is your approximate ranking in the marriage market? Don’t just think about winning five million by buying a lottery ticket for two yuan. He who knows others is wise, and he who knows himself is wise. The ancients are honest and do not deceive me. Secondly, if the other person&#39;s words, deeds and person make you feel comfortable, like bathing in the spring breeze, then don&#39;t be too proud. You should blow a cold breeze and judge rationally. Is this the other person&#39;s character or is he always catering to you? It&#39;s understandable to covet emotional value, but the price the other party secretly bids may be too expensive for you to bear. Third, even if you decide that the other person is the right one, don’t tie your marriage and love decisions to your financial decisions. More and more men and women who have reached the stage of marriage are beginning to emphasize the &quot;AA system&quot; of property and living expenses after marriage. How can you give your hard-earned money to the other party to help invest before marriage? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 10:25:34 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳门街坊的横琴生活：粤澳合作区两周年记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdw CKSbR0bN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251169&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn, accompanied by the crisp prompts when passengers cleared customs, the new passenger inspection building standing at Hengqin Port once again ushered in a busy moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every day, about 12,000 Hong Kong and Macao residents travel between Hengqin and Macao through the Hengqin Port. Macao resident Huang Huixia is one of them. Almost two years ago, she moved to the Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone in Hengqin and became a &quot;new Hengqin native&quot;; now, she lives in Hengqin and returns to Macau three or four times a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The transportation is more convenient, the house is more spacious, the living environment is more comfortable, the community services are better, and more and more Macao people come to the cooperation zone...” Talking about the two projects in Hengqin Huang Huixia has a treasure trove of her life experiences over the years. In the future, as the Macau light rail extension Hengqin Line project comes into use, the transportation from Hengqin to Macau will become more convenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 5, 2021, the &quot;Overall Plan for the Construction of the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot;) was issued, giving Hengqin &quot;a new platform to promote the moderately diversified development of Macao&#39;s economy&quot; It has four major strategic missions: &quot;a new space to facilitate the life and employment of Macao residents&quot;, &quot;a new demonstration to enrich the practice of &#39;one country, two systems&#39;&quot; and &quot;a new highland to promote the construction of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area&quot;. Twelve days later, the management agency of the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone was officially unveiled, and the construction of the cooperation zone has entered the &quot;fast lane&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the issuance of the &quot;Hengqin Master Development Plan&quot; in 2009, the country has successively introduced a series of innovative policies to draw a bright blueprint for the development of Hengqin.&quot; Dean of the Institute of Regional Opening and Cooperation at Sun Yat-sen University Mao Yanhua told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone has multiple advantages such as superior location conditions, solid cooperation foundation, and strong support. The current development momentum is strong, and the future will definitely be more promising.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;&lt;strong>;Macao Neighbors in Hengqin&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“My original house in Macao was very small, only about 60 square meters. After moving to Hengqin, the living area suddenly increased. 150 square meters.&quot; After two years of moving to Hengqin, Huang Huixia has the most vivid feelings about the changes in Hengqin&#39;s living environment, transportation conditions, community services, medical care, and customs clearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early autumn, the water of Tianmu River is shining, with green trees and lush vegetation on both sides. Strolling along the 7.2-kilometer-long ecological corridor along the river, rhythmic urban waterfront landscape belts such as ecological community areas and park-like communities gradually unfold, and across the water are the Macau Tower and the Grand Lisboa Tower. , MGM Hotel and other Macau landmark buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Huixia moved to Hengqin Shangcun from Macau two years ago, where 60% of the residents are Macau residents. Shangcun is only about ten minutes&#39; walk from Tianmu River. In her free time every day, she would go for a walk by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Huixia still clearly remembers the situation when she first moved to Hengqin. At that time, due to insufficient flow of people and few bus lines, it took a long time to go back to Macau. &quot;Now I travel to and from Macau three or four times a week. There are several buses to Hengqin Port after leaving the community.&quot; Huang Huixia told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hengqin Port is located on the west bank of the Cross Gate Waterway on Hengqin Island and is connected to the Macau Bridge. It is at the intersection of &quot;one country, two systems&quot; and the junction of &quot;internal and external radiation&quot;. At present, Hengqin Port has achieved &quot;cooperative inspection and one-time release&quot;. Entry-exit personnel only need to &quot;stand in the same hall, line up once, and undergo inspection once&quot; to complete the entry-exit procedures for both the mainland and Macao. The average customs clearance time per person is only 30 About seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customs clearance time has been greatly shortened and the process has been optimized, allowing Macao residents traveling between the two places to live a more comfortable life in the twin cities. Huang Huixia clearly feels that more and more Macao residents are passing through customs and entering the cooperation zone every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics, there are currently more than 7,000 Macao residents settling and working in Hengqin. The average daily passenger flow of Hong Kong and Macao residents entering and exiting through Hengqin Port will increase from more than 5,900 in 2022 to nearly 1.2 in 2023. Thousands of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to major improvements in the living environment, daily life and transportation conditions, the elderly care, medical and community services in the Hengqin Cooperation Zone are also constantly moving closer to Macau standards. In 2019, the Macau Federation of Neighborhood Associations set up a service center in Hengqin and formed a professional service team to provide Macau-standard home care home care services for seniors aged 60 and over in the cooperation zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As of the end of August 2023, we have provided services to more than 960,000 residents in Qinzhou and Macao.” A person in charge of the Macau Neighborhood Association told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to the continued advancement of the cross-border practice policy, there are currently a total of 67 short-term medical practitioners from Hong Kong and Macao practicing in Hengqin. &quot;New Hengqin residents&quot; including Huang Huixia can seek medical treatment from familiar Macao doctors without leaving the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We can participate in local insurance in Hengqin and enjoy the same medical insurance treatment as Zhuhai citizens. It is very convenient to buy medicines and see doctors, and the personal expenses are not high.” Huang Huixia said, “Follow-up’ Macao New After the completion of the Neighborhood project, a Macau medical team will be stationed and a large medical service center will be equipped, making life more convenient in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Macau New Neighborhood&quot; mentioned by Huang Huixia is a cooperation area The first comprehensive livelihood project for Macao residents, it will be equipped with various Macao standard public services and social welfare, and will create a high-quality and livable community for more than 10,000 Macao residents. Currently, the project has entered the acceptance stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Life in the cooperation zone will definitely get better and better in the future.” Huang Huixia told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Four New Industries&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Taking advantage of the rapid development of the Hengqin Cooperation Zone, Wang Ruiming came to Hengqin to seek development. In the past few months, he acquired an Australian-funded company and plans to establish a new company, mainly engaged in the financial and Internet industries, which is expected to be officially opened at the end of September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because he is engaged in the financial industry supported by the cooperation zone, his company can enjoy a 15% tax preferential policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ruiming is a &quot;third generation overseas Chinese&quot;. In recent years, attracted by the business policies and environment of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, he has been actively deploying in the Bay Area and has registered financial companies in Hong Kong and Shenzhen, focusing on funds, trusts, insurance and other businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Hengqin’s financial industry is highly open and cross-border capital flows freely. It is the most active area for cross-border RMB settlement. Many Fortune 500 companies have settled here. It is very promising to become China’s financial industry in the future. A new highland for opening up to the outside world.&quot; Wang Ruiming told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, the added value of the financial industry in the cooperation zone reached 8.8 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 40% of &lt;span>;GDP&lt;/span>;, with a year-on-year growth of 2.9%, showing a trend of accelerating agglomeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The cooperation zone has made solid progress around the &#39;Four New Industries&#39;. Not only has the industry positioning become clearer, but a system and mechanism for consultation, construction, management and sharing has also been initially established.&quot; Mao Yanhua pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Macao has a small land but a large population. There are more than 680,000 people living in less than 33 square kilometers of land, with an average of more than 20,000 people per square kilometer. It is one of the cities with the highest population density in the world. Problems such as insufficient land resources and a single industrial structure have always plagued Macao&#39;s development. Hengqin, across the water from Macau, covers an area of ​​106 square kilometers and has significant spatial advantages, providing sufficient space to support the diversified development of Macau&#39;s economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 2009, the State Council approved the implementation of the &quot;Hengqin Master Development Plan&quot;, clearly stating that Hengqin should be used as a carrier to jointly create a cross-border cooperation innovation zone, in order to gradually change the economic structure of Macao. Single questions provide new space. With the gradual advancement of high-quality development in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and the introduction of the &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot;, the integration of Hengqin and Macao has reached a new level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the beginning of development, Hengqin has been given the mission of serving the diversified economic development of Macao. In more than ten years of development and construction, this mission has not only remained unchanged, but has become more prominent.&quot; Mao Yanhua pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its inauguration and operation, the Hengqin Cooperation Zone has focused on the &quot;four new&quot; strategic positioning and vigorously developed the &quot;four major&quot; technological research and development and high-end manufacturing, Macao brand industries such as traditional Chinese medicine, culture, tourism, exhibition and trade, and modern financial industries. Industry&quot; and launched a series of new policies targeting the integrated circuit industry, financial industry, cultural tourism and exhibition industry, etc. In the past two years, a number of key projects have been accelerated, and the integrated development pattern of Macao and Macao has been initially established. The supporting role in promoting the moderately diversified development of Macao&#39;s economy is gradually emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023 alone, there will be more than 40 integrated circuit companies actually operating in the cooperation zone, initially forming an integrated circuit design industry ecosystem covering intellectual property (IP), third-generation semiconductors and other fields; Guangdong The Australian Cooperative Traditional Chinese Medicine Science and Technology Industrial Park contributed nearly 80 million yuan in corporate tax revenue in the first quarter, a year-on-year increase of 59%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With industrial agglomeration and policy dividends, the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone has become a new platform and new highland for Australian people and enterprises to invest and start businesses. Currently, there are more than 5,600 Australian-funded enterprises in the cooperation zone, an increase of 22.3% compared with before the cooperation zone was established, and the registered capital exceeds 148 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot; opens a new chapter in the construction of Guangdong-Macao in-depth cooperation zone.&quot; Mao Yanhua said, &quot;The construction of the future cooperation zone should continue to focus on the original intention of serving the diversified development of Macao industries, starting from building first-class industries Starting from the functional park, we will vigorously develop the real economy, make good use of the innovative system, and further attract the full flow and agglomeration of factors inside and outside the park, thereby creating a new growth pole for high-quality development on the west bank of the Pearl River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Italics , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Huang Huixia and Wang Ruiming are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[接连停运，有轨电车真的没“出路”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256990]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rS zHzGpQrZ3O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2019, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram in operation was nicknamed &quot; Dangdang car”. In June 2023, Zhangjiang trams will be suspended. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retro, good-looking, fresh... City trams once had such Internet celebrities label, but in the past few months, news of tram outages have appeared frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, an announcement circulated on the Internet stating that due to difficulties in operating funds, modern trams in Honghe Prefecture, Yunnan will cease operations on August 10, 2023. On August 11, the chairman of Honghe Prefecture Modern Tram Co., Ltd. responded that the announcement was false news. At present, the local tram has not been suspended and is operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the Tianjin Development Zone Guide Tram Line 1, which had been in operation for 16 years, announced that it would cease operation and started procurement of demolition projects. In June, Shanghai Zhangjiang Tram No. 1, which had been in operation for 13 years, was suspended and the tracks were quickly dismantled. Two years ago, in 2021, the trams in Zhuhai, Guangdong, were suspended and planned to be dismantled after more than three years of operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram was out of service, and workers were dismantling the track. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Shijun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, 3 of the 39 rail lines across the country have been suspended. According to the &quot;Urban Rail Transit 2022 Annual Statistics and Analysis Report&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Report&quot;) released by the China Urban Rail Transit Association, as of the end of 2022, a total of 39 tram lines in 23 cities across the country have been put into operation, with an operating mileage of 578.3 kilometers. , equivalent to half the distance from Beijing to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The primary reason for the suspension of operations is low passenger flow. This is not the first time such news has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2015, after the opening of the Chengdu Tram Chengdu Tram Line 2&#39;s first section, the line was not connected to the urban rail transit network and the passenger flow was low, which led to great pressure from public opinion and suffered &quot;some problems&quot;. &quot;Trams are useless&quot; controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are trams frequently suspended? How to avoid the &quot;chair transport&quot; situation? Compared with subways with large passenger flows, trams are &quot;urban rail transit low-capacity systems,&quot; Li Hongchun, an expert and deputy director of the academic committee of the China Urban Rail Transit Association and vice president of the Modern Tram Branch, told Southern Weekend that doing a good job Line network planning achieves a high degree of integration of multiple transportation modes, and low-capacity systems can develop systematically and healthily. There are also many successful cases in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Low passenger flow is the key to the suspension of trams&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Insufficient passenger flow and serious losses are the key reasons for the suspension of trams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jiemian News, before the suspension, the daily passenger volume of Shanghai Zhangjiang trams had dropped sharply to about 1,000 passengers. Wang Qingfeng (pseudonym), a bus enthusiast who works in Zhangjiang, recalled that sometimes “when we get on the bus from the starting station, there are almost no passengers on the bus along the way.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 25, 2022, at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on a working day, there were almost no passengers in the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram car, and there was only one conductor. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The operating pressure of the Honghe Prefecture tram, which denies rumors of suspension, is not optimistic either. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the tram passenger intensity in Honghe Prefecture was 0.01 (10,000 passengers/km·day), ranking at the bottom in the country. The passenger volume that month was only 26,000, with an average of less than 900 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 29, 2018, a tram was undergoing joint debugging and testing in Honghe, Yunnan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low operating frequency is an important reason that affects passenger flow. The longer the departure interval, the lower the attractiveness of passenger flow. Low passenger flow further affects the departure interval, forming a vicious circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval between Zhangjiang tram trains before they stop running is 15 to 20 minutes. For commuters, the waiting time is too long. &quot;Instead of waiting for the tram, it&#39;s better to buy a shared bicycle.&quot; Wang Qingfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only shared bicycles, but also the opening and operation of many subway lines such as the eastern extension of Shanghai Metro Line 2, Line 11, and Line 13, have dispersed the passenger flow of trams. Before the suspension, in February 2023, Zhangjiang trams reduced their operating hours from 17 hours a day to only 4 trips during the morning and evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pudong Modern Rail Transit Co., Ltd. stated in the announcement that in recent years, the public transportation system in Zhangjiang area has been continuously enriched and improved. Multiple urban rail lines have been put into operation, and ground bus lines have been optimized and adjusted many times. The passenger flow of Zhangjiang Tram 1 has been declining year by year, and ground buses will replace the connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Insufficient technical applicability and high maintenance costs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to low passenger flow and long departure intervals, the trams in Tianjin Development Zone and Shanghai Zhangjiang are subject to The vehicles are imported products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both use the Translohr system produced by the French company Raul, which has rubber wheels, single track and a small footprint. However, not many cities around the world use this system. With the gradual decline of Raul after its acquisition, the production of related parts has been greatly reduced, resulting in high vehicle maintenance costs and long maintenance cycles, and some parts are facing the risk of &quot;supply interruption&quot;. Difficulties in purchasing parts have also led to difficulties and high costs in maintaining trams in Shanghai Zhangjiang and Tianjin Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qingfeng recalled that when he was riding a tram in Zhangjiang, he discovered that there was a thick wooden pole in the driver&#39;s cab. The tracks are sometimes blocked by debris, and drivers need to get out of the car and use wooden poles to clear the debris, which greatly affects traffic efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Zhuhai tram, Li Hongchun mentioned in an interview that the TramWave ground power supply system it used lacked engineering practice, and the builders had insufficient understanding of the applicability of the technology, resulting in system problems after the line was opened. The failure rate is high and the operation service is unstable. At the same time, factors such as low passenger flow and high maintenance costs have directly affected the remaining section of Line 1 that was originally planned to be rebuilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being low in frequency, the out-of-service trams were also considered too slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Report&quot; shows that the average travel speed of subways in 2022 will be 36.47 kilometers/hour, the average travel speed of trams nationwide is only 22.3 kilometers/hour, and the travel speed of Zhangjiang trams is only 19 kilometers/hour Hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the maximum design speed of Zhangjiang trams is 70 kilometers per hour. The reason for the slow running speed is that trams do not have dedicated right of way - they share the road space with all vehicles and are still subject to traffic lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height= &quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Zhangjiang tram does not have a dedicated right of way. It shares the road space with all vehicles and is still subject to traffic lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long trams waiting for traffic lights exacerbate congestion. For example, the Zhangjiang tram passes by Pudong Foreign Languages ​​School Affiliated to Shanghai International Studies University. Parents will park their private cars on the roadside when picking up their children. When the tram comes in, it will occupy the entire road. One citizen said: &quot;You can either use the non-motorized lane next to it to overtake, or you can only follow the Dangdang tram.&quot; Dangdang tram is the nickname given to Zhangjiang trams by Shanghai residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Planning issues, not standard issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking around the world, trams are not a niche issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;China Tram Development Report (2020)&quot; released by the Modern Tramway Branch of the China Urban Rail Transit Association shows that subways and trams are the mainstream systems of urban rail transit in the world, of which subways account for 47 %, trams account for 42%, and light rail accounts for 11%. In Europe, trams are the mainstream public transportation mode in many cities. For example, in Berlin, Germany, trams account for as high as 55.6% of the rail transit mileage. In China, this proportion is only 5.71%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some voices pointed out that the tram was &quot;unacclimated&quot; after it came to China. But Li Hongchun reminded that many tram projects are operating well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In very large and megacities, trams can be used as extension lines and encrypted lines of large and medium-sized transportation systems such as subways. For example, Beijing&#39;s Xijiao Line, as an extension of Metro Line 10, starts from Bagou Station and connects tourist attractions such as Xiangshan Park, National Botanical Garden, Yuquan Country Park and the Summer Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Western Suburb Line is positioned to be “mainly for commuting, supplemented by tourism,” Li Hongchun added. The Xijiao Line is the first tramway in the country to be operated with multiple connections - two train sets are connected together to increase passenger flow. During the &quot;Xiangshan Red Leaf Festival&quot; in 2019, the maximum daily passenger flow reached 94,700, making it the first single tram in the country. The daily passenger flow is the highest recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the May Day holiday in 2022, in order to reduce the full load of the carriages, the Beijing Xijiao Line will adopt a multi-connection operation mode. A single train will change from 5 carriages to 10 carriages, with 8 groups per day. Heavy-duty trains are put into operation with a minimum departure interval of 5 minutes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(China News Service reporter Jia Tianyong Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Huai&#39;an, Jiangsu, trams even serve as the city&#39;s backbone public transportation, ensuring Passenger flow demand. Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is the first tram line in China that enters the core area of ​​the city, and its passenger flow has always been at the forefront of tram lines in the country. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the passenger flow in Huai&#39;an was 580,000, reaching nearly 20,000 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 16, 2020, in Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province, modern trams that were suspended due to the epidemic resumed operation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In tourist areas, trams can also play the role of special tourist buses, such as the Nanping Wuyi New District Line in Fujian , connecting Nanping City High-speed Railway Station to Wuyishan Station, seamlessly connecting with Wuyishan Scenic Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the experience of successfully operating trams, unlike large-capacity systems such as subways, trams, as low-capacity systems, are redeveloped on existing road resources, which is difficult and needs to be adapted to local conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that the suspension of some trams does not reflect problems with the tram system itself, but problems in planning and design. For example, the area near the first phase of the Zhuhai tram project is mostly high-end communities. Residents mainly travel by car. Moreover, the north side of the line is dominated by mountains. The development intensity along the line is low, there is little residential land, a lack of commercial facilities, and the line radiates from one side. , resulting in low passenger flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to plan rationally? Li Hongchun believes that trams are positioned as an environmentally friendly transportation system that fills the gap between large-capacity subways and conventional buses. First, we must ensure a clear level of public transportation planning and strengthen integration with comprehensive transportation. For the connection of hubs, the division of labor between trams and conventional bus systems must be properly handled, and the line network layout must consider the integration of large-capacity systems and medium- and low-capacity systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 26, 2020, the first tram in Wuyishan City, Nanping City, Fujian Province slowly drove out of the Xiandian depot and entered the trial operation stage. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Sanya tram is located closest to the entrance and exit of Sanya Railway Station, and the Jiaxing tram The station is directly connected to the newly developed campuses on both sides by pedestrian tunnels, making these designs more convenient for residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Site selection needs to be supported by a certain population density. Li Hongchun mentioned that it is necessary to accurately predict the passenger flow in the line corridor to avoid the situation where the actual passenger flow does not reach the estimated amount. In terms of construction timing, &quot;we must first consider what needs to be built most, not where it is easier to build.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the first section of Chengdu Rong Line 2 was opened, the low passenger flow was questioned because it had not yet been connected to the urban rail network. After the opening of the second section, it was connected to the subway, and the passenger flow reached nearly four. Ten thousand people, an increase of dozens of times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of operations, regarding the issue of tram rights of way, Li Hongchun believes that priority signals should be provided for trams to ensure the safety, speed and efficiency of tram operations. For example, Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is equipped with three major systems: tram signal priority control system, intersection red light electronic police and road section checkpoint system, and intersection video surveillance system, and arranges traffic coordinators to realize tram priority at intersections. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that under the dual influence of my country&#39;s rapid urbanization and the substantial increase in private car ownership leading to congestion, the development of public transportation is an inevitable trend in history. The construction cost of the subway is at least ten times higher than that of the tram. Compared with the bus, the tram has the advantages of large transportation capacity, high comfort and punctuality. Under the trend of carbon neutrality, tram It is an important option for public transportation construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[哈尔滨：黄昏缄默的时候，建筑在说话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 9:30 am on October 26, 1909, Congkuanchengzi (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changchun&lt;/span>;) Ito Hirobumi, who arrived in Harbin by special train, stepped off the train. A short man wearing a peaked cap and western clothes calmly touched his chest, ribs, and abdomen. He fired three shots and then fired four shots at the accompanying Japanese officials, shouting &quot;Ula Golia!&quot; in Russian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened suddenly, and everyone was still dreaming. Ito Hirobumi was put on a special train and died 30 minutes later. The man with a resolute face, An Zhonggen, was captured in an almost tragic manner; the seven gunshots fired over the Harbin Railway Station, which was built in 1899 and named in 1903, rapidly and profoundly changed the 20th century. The situation in Northeast Asia at the beginning - Although the train station was demolished and rebuilt in 1959, there are still vivid traces of this incident in the station, including the Ahn Jung-geun Memorial Hall and the platform where the incident occurred: the &quot;Δ&quot; and &quot;□&quot; on the ground , respectively, where Ahn Jung-geun and Ito Hirobumi are standing, about 5 meters apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old scene of Harbin Railway Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Ruo Ge As Li said, &quot;When poems and legends are silent, only buildings speak.&quot; - Around the train station, everything is completely different from what it was more than a hundred years ago. Only the Church of Saint-Iver still quietly &quot;leans&quot; on it. Stand aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Street: &quot;The Cross-Communication of Multiculturalism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Old Harbin&quot; without city walls is actually neither ancient nor modern - it is The &quot;modern city&quot; grew up amid the roar of trains. China&#39;s defeat in the Sino-Japanese War and many factors such as Tsarist Russia&#39;s use of alliance with Japan as bait to seize more interests in Northeast China gave birth to the construction of the Middle East Railway. In 1896, Russia obtained the right to build the Middle East Railway. In June of that year, Russia&#39;s Middle East Railway The General Administration of Construction moved from Vladivostok (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Vladivostok&lt;/span>;) to Harbin. At the same time, the railway was divided into The six ends of the east-west and south-west lines are being constructed in opposite directions at the same time. As the center of the 2,500-kilometer &quot;T&quot;-shaped railway that runs from Manzhouli in the west, Suifenhe in the east, and Lushun, Dalian in the south, it has quickly become an international city with &quot;sky-high buildings, merchants, soaring land prices, and every inch of land is precious.&quot; - &quot;The desolate wilderness turned into a prosperous port in an instant.&quot; Capitalism has become the &quot;power&quot; for Harbin&#39;s rapid growth and rise, but at the same time, foreign capital has inhibited and hindered the development of national capitalism, making it an &quot;alien&quot; between traditional Chinese cities and modern capitalist cities; a railway has even more influence on Harbin. The local architectural culture has had a huge impact, with a wave of compulsory and replacement architectural design trends - integration, addition, mutation... In the silent dusk more than a hundred years ago, in this city with wonderful characteristics, it began Continuously “cultivating”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Harbin Railway Station and St. Iver&#39;s Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Red Army Street, which shoots out straight from Harbin Railway Station, was originally named Horvat Street. It is the starting point and germination of Harbin&#39;s city construction. It spreads outwards with it as the axis, showing the annual rings of the city&#39;s growth. The original site of the Longmen VIP Building was built in 1907. At the other end, there were the Russian Consulate General in Harbin and the Officers Club of the Russian Trans-Amur Military District, as well as the &quot;famous&quot; Yamato Hotel in the Northeast; the Sino-Russian Daosheng Bank, built in 1920, is now It is the Heilongjiang Provincial Research Museum of Literature and History, still maintaining the original French Renaissance style; the Cheschakov Tea House’s mixed classicism, baroque and Renaissance style exterior bay windows, overhanging awnings, and open-air balconies are set among the Among the green trees, looking at the signboard of &quot;HSBC Camera Company&quot;, it is difficult to imagine that it was designed by Zhdanov, a Russian Jewish architect who has lived in Harbin for 37 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Red Army Street and the east-west Dazhi Street once intersected at the ancient Gothic wooden structure St. Nicholas Church. Nowadays, there is no trace of the Church of San Nicola. The International Hotel built in 1937 looks like a huge accordion. Opposite it is the former Italian Consulate, the Gibelosso building built in 1919, which is full of exquisite reliefs. The octagonal exterior walls are stacked upward layer by layer to form a lovely eclectic building dominated by Baroque style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another group of &quot;solemn vs. cute&quot; buildings is on Dazhi Street. The famous &quot;big stone house&quot; Harbin Railway Bureau Office Building was completed in February 1904 as the Middle East Railway Administration. Magnificent, majestic and dignified, it is like a &quot;huge castle&quot;; the Harbin Railway Museum, just across the street, has a simple interior decoration, while the exterior maintains the yellow and white colors from its days as the Middle East Railway Club, full of joy. breath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lama Terrace&quot; where St. Nicholas Church is located is the highest point in Harbin. It can be protected from floods when the Songhua River rises. Therefore, starting in 1899, Russia began to regulate the location of this place. The Qinjiagang area (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Nangang District&lt;/span>;) is undergoing large-scale urban construction. Within five years, the China Eastern Railway Administration Building and the Moscow Shopping Mall Building were built. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Heilongjiang Provincial Museum&lt;/span>;) and other European-style buildings were completed, and the east-west axis of Qinjiagang - Horvat Street, Dazhi Street and Main streets such as the New Business Street (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today&#39;s Guogol Street&lt;/span>;) were built. In the 1930s, the Qinjiagang area had &quot;grand buildings, neat streets&quot;, &quot;fresh air and fragrant flowers&quot;. Most foreign consulates were concentrated here, becoming Harbin&#39;s administrative center and a gathering place for foreigners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qiulin Company located in Nangang District today&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;East and West The various subsystems of Fang civilization collide, rub, infiltrate, and blend with each other here. The unprecedented integration of the architectural culture of various ethnic groups in the world presents a &quot;cross-communication of multiculturalism.&quot; The Middle East Railway brought a large number of overseas Chinese - according to statistics, in 1923, the total population of Harbin reached 400,000, with nearly 200,000 overseas Chinese and more than 180,000 Chinese. Twenty or thirty years after the Russo-Japanese War, Harbin has become an international city. It brought Russian culture, Jewish culture, Japanese culture, Tatar culture... and nearly 70 churches including St. Nicholas Church, St. Sophia Church, and the Church of the Annunciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhdanov is to Harbin what Hudec is to Shanghai. Among the three churches &quot;clustered&quot; on Dongdazhi Street, the Church of Our Lady of Saints and Saints designed by Zhdanov (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Church of Our Lady of Protection&lt;/span >;) is the most eye-catching. This Byzantine-style church is said to have preserved the 2,600-kilogram bell that was cast in Moscow in 1899, but it is not available to see now. What can be seen is the notice board erected next to the church: &quot;Please pay attention to your behavior, God is working.&quot; Watching you”. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Church: Bells Echoing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike the Virgin Mary Church, which is located on the busy main road of the city, the Tatar Church, also designed by Zhdanov The Tai Mosque is hidden among the residential buildings on Tongjiang Street. The red and white walls are full of Byzantine style of quiet and dignified temperament. It is like a &quot;mysterious little castle&quot;. Especially at dusk, it has a sense of simplicity. From 1899, when the first Russian Jew, S. I. Berzeri, came to Harbin to the 1940s, countless Jews came to this &quot;second home&quot; and built buildings here, including a hexagonal church with a dome holding up the Shield of David. Many Jewish buildings including the Star Synagogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tatar Mosque&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least a hundred years ago, the majestic The bells once echoed over Harbin. In the sound of the bells, expatriates from all over the world, adventurers and exiles of all kinds stopped to listen and found a moment of solace in their hometown in this foreign land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The symbol of Harbin - St. Sophia Church, the melodious bells played on important religious festivals can be said to be the deep memory of the city for the older generation of Harbin people. It is said that in the church on a snowy day in winter, the Byzantine-style appearance can allow more snow to stay on the surface of the building. The wind blows the snowflakes, which are like the ultimate romance in a crystal ball; on a snowy night, the church will turn into gold bricks. The castle with bright tiles and the towering cross are like stars in the night sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hagia Sophia on a snowy night, the scenery is as dreamy as a crystal ball. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to observe the details of the church quietly, the best time is at dusk. The full dark green dome full of momentum is lifted very high by the main body of the clear red brick building. The golden cross shines brightly, showing a dynamic beauty of rising successively. Viewed from the side, the tops of the four tents are staggered, and the slanting light shines on it. The architectural details cast mysterious shadows, honest and simple. Step into the church and enjoy the daily rotating concerts, as well as the mottled walls and Roman-style arched windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The setting sun reflects on the top of the church, which reminds people of its sister with the same name on the other side of the Eurasian continent, and also allows people to relive the rich history of the city&#39;s past. In fact, this church had &quot;humble origins&quot; and was only the military chapel of the 4th Infantry Division of Tsarist Russia in Eastern Siberia. In March 1907, it was renovated with funds from the Russian businessman Cheschakov, whose home was on Red Army Street. In 1912 A layer of bricks was laid on the original foundation. In 1923, the Russian architect Kasikov re-selected a site in the southeast corner of the old church and built it. It was completed in November 1932, giving it what it looks like today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Concert in Saint Sophia Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saint Sophia The architectural style and decorative style of the church draw on the Russian brick carving art of the 17th century. The St. Alexeev Church at the corner of Gogol Street and Shikes Street organically combines a huge building volume with facade brick decoration. Giving it a strong Russian accent and unique mood. Although this century-old building, which was originally an Orthodox church and was converted into a Catholic church in 1980, also has a majestic and scattered beauty. Even under the clear blue sky in the northeast, it can be regarded as the appearance of the city&#39;s architecture, but it is not as lively as Sofia Square. There are very few people around after sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lights&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: Chinese Baroque&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Qiulin Kvass rustles after opening the bottle cap. This famous drink looks like Beer, slightly red in color but with only 1% alcohol content, is very suitable for &quot;bottle blowing&quot; when traveling and hiking - such as walking from Alexeev Church, along Gogol Street to the L-shaped building built in 1908 A grand building with a light green tone - Qiulin Yangxing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many old buildings on Gogol Street, but while maintaining their former glory, they have inevitably declined and become dilapidated - just like Daowai District. To the north from the train station, east of the railway across the river, is the Daowai District, formerly known as &quot;Fujiadian&quot;, where immigrants from Shandong and Hebei settled in Guandong. Although it is one of the earliest urban centers in Harbin, due to the lack of complete and precise planning, in the 1930s the streets here were &quot;narrow and uneven&quot; and &quot;everywhere you go is so disgusting that you have to cover your nose and avoid it.&quot; &amp;nbsp;——The folk proverb at that time said: &quot;Nangang is heaven, inside the road is the world, and outside the road is hell.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unique &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; architecture also grew here. Along the street, the Western Baroque facade is used, while incorporating the auspicious decorative patterns of traditional Chinese architecture. Iron railings or &quot;Guanyin bottle&quot;-style concrete railings are set up on the edge of the protruding platform. Stepping inside, it is purely a northern courtyard. The architectural shape combines earth and western elements, giving it its own charm. The Chinese Baroque neighborhood, which is mainly located on South Second and Third Streets and has been renovated into a tourist attraction, is lackluster. Many of the green brick streets and wide courtyards have been transformed into catering shops. They are more organized but lack the liveliness and prosperity of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, the &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; on Dong Jingyu Street in the neighborhood is the most authentic. Originally built in 1890, this long street was originally called Zhengyang Street. It is also the birthplace of Harbin&#39;s national commerce: Zhengyang Tower, Laodingfeng, Shiyitang, Daluoxin Department Store, Hengdeli, Tongji Shopping Mall... every inch of land Jin&#39;s Old Street used to be lined with businesses. At the intersection of Jingyu Street and Nantou Street, the four-story brick and wood structure Purification Hospital was built in 1920. It was formerly known as Tongyi Qinghuo Store. It is one of the masterpieces of &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot;: the swaying reliefs of vine flowers from Ioni The exterior walls of the sub-column and Corinthian columns are winding all the way down, and the gorgeous and luxurious style is unforgettable, fully reflecting the hope of fame of the national industrial and commercial people at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Purification Hospital located outside Laodao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All famous, Prosperity and bustle have their end. Today&#39;s Laodaowai has lost its popularity due to large-scale construction, and its decline is fully visible: dilapidated buildings can be seen along the street, and the roofs are covered with decaying grass, as if the old buildings are sighing; the cats and dogs wandering on the street look full of vicissitudes of life. Feeling; beside the ruins, you can occasionally see small electric cars with the sign of &quot;darning&quot;, which is a common livelihood for middle-aged and elderly women in the Northeast - sewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In old Harbin, if the window of &quot;Zhong&quot; is &quot;Zhengyang Street&quot;, the epitome of &quot;West&quot; is Central Street - in Xiao Hong&#39;s pen, the city street is like a &quot;complex and unclear color&quot; &quot;Map&quot;, Harbin today has similar characteristics - it is also a commercial street, Jingyu Street outside the road has become a large construction site, and Central Street inside the road, at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning, there are tourists wandering around carrying kvass bottles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Laodaowai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Night, spring night, Central Street is a night full of music. Music from homeless people, music from Japanese dance halls, music from foreign restaurants... After 7 o&#39;clock, in the middle of Central Street, at a crossroads, the loud loudspeaker screamed, this The singing almost resounded throughout the street.&quot; Xiao Hong once wrote about Central Street in &quot;Spring Hangs on the Treetops&quot;, with a lot of irony and banter; however, the &quot;gradually countless&quot; things she recorded were &quot;like long ropes pulled in the sun&quot; The bright lights, like a string of yellow copper bells, seem to be still hanging on the 1,450-meter-long Central Street, which starts from the Songhua River Flood Control Victory Memorial Tower in the north and ends at Jingwei Street in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;On some side streets, it is quieter. The light of the street lamps imprints the shadows of the leaves on the road. The aging Russians are talking about the good days that no longer exist. ... In You may think it is ugly during the day, but on a beautiful night, you put beautiful clothes on everything, and everything seems to be beautiful.&quot; The shorter streets in Jin&#39;s works form a fish-like formation with the Central Street. The bone-shaped street layout supported the &quot;enchanting&quot; appearance of this street after the completion of the China-Eastern Railway in 1903, where foreign merchants gathered and shops were dotted; especially in 1924, the Russian engineer Komut Rashok was responsible for the design and supervision of the construction. After the rectangular bread-shaped granite pavement was replaced, the bread stone road replaced the muddy dirt road. The appearance of the street was greatly changed, and it became rich and luxurious. In the 1930s, Central Street had become an architectural art gallery and an international architectural expo. Both sides of the street Most of them are Baroque, Gothic, Renaissance and other styles of buildings, creating a beautiful skyline; there are many foreign stores, dance halls and cinemas, restaurants and bars... At that time, Central Street became a place of pilgrimage for commodity fetishism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;China Street (today’s Central Street) is beginning to take shape&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the streets paved with square stones, the sound of Victorian carriages has long since passed into the twilight of history. Only the pieces of breadstone that have been worn away by the passing years are still shining brightly on today&#39;s pedestrian streets. Visitors tell stories about the smoky past of the long street - on summer evenings, the brilliant sunset shines slantingly on more than 70 European-style and imitation European-style buildings, and they seem to have their own unique character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Music: Soul of the North&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is also the Madiel popsicle that is essential when visiting Central Street - Matsuura 1918 West, which was renovated in the Matsuura Yoko Building. Diagonally across from the restaurant is Madiel&#39;s cold drink hall. Nowadays, &quot;Madiel&quot; can be eaten all over the country at different prices, but it is said that they are all &quot;a bit uninteresting&quot;. You still have to buy 5 yuan a piece here, which is made in the front store and in the back factory, without wrapping paper, which is the most authentic: In winter, the daily sales here start at 10,000 sticks, and sales usually explode on New Year&#39;s Day, with 30,000 to 40,000 sticks sold a day. During the peak tourist season in Harbin, &quot;Naked Madiel in the North Wind&quot; is one of the features of Central Street. Everyone wants to &quot;cool themselves down to the bottom.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After nibbling on the popsicles, you can turn around and taste the hot red cabbage soup, mandarin fish in milk and delicious canned shrimps at the Madier Western Restaurant - since the Russians started cooking pots in Tianjia in 1898 With the opening of railway canteens, Russian-style Western food began to take root in China. In the Central Street area alone, there are Tadaos and Huamei (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;former Mars There are more than 30 Western restaurants such as Western Food Tea Shop&lt;/span>;) and Madiel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The food and delicacies are endlessly memorable, especially when accompanied by music - whether in Matsuura, Huamei, or Madiel’s own Western restaurant on the first floor, Madiel can often be heard in the summer The music show on the balcony on the second floor of the hotel includes violin music, saxophone performance or bel canto solo. Artists who appeared to be from Central and Eastern Europe took turns performing hard, attracting tourists to stop and adding a lot of excitement to Central Street. It was also reminiscent of their &quot;predecessors&quot;, the foreign musicians who gathered here in the first half of the 20th century. : In 1936, singers Alexander Wilkinsky and Fedor Chaliapin came to Kazakhstan to hold a concert; in 1938, 10-year-old Helmut Stern came to China with his parents, and at the age of 14 He held a concert in Harbin and later joined the Harbin Symphony Orchestra, which was founded in 1908 and was once known as the &quot;First Symphony Orchestra in the Far East.&quot; After going to Israel in 1948, he became the chief violinist of the Berlin Philharmonic... Starting in the 1920s, Foreigners in Harbin have founded nearly 30 music schools. The strong music atmosphere that has lasted for a century has become an important cornerstone for Harbin to be awarded the title of &quot;City of Music&quot; by the United Nations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old view of Madier Hotel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Madiel Hotel Er&#39;s balcony music show is just a small note in the &quot;Music City&quot;. &quot;In the Madier Hotel, that hotel with a big stage and a luxurious hall, a play was organized between the movie screenings and a dance program was started... I happily put aside the boring rehearsals of the troupe and went to them specifically There.&quot; Dancer and poet Larisa Angell lived in China for 34 years and often performed at the Madier Hotel founded by Russian Jew Joseph Kasper in 1906. Her beautiful figure and summer Photos of Ryabin and Wilkinski, as well as tableware, lamps, electrical appliances, accessories, and promotional posters of Madier Cinema, together form the &quot;historical and cultural corridor&quot; in the hotel; during her years of activeness in Harbin , this very ancient building on Central Street is regarded as &quot;having the most luxurious ballroom and restaurant, the most modern and comfortable guest rooms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the scenery of the Madier Hotel was unparalleled, until the &quot;Casper Kidnapping Case&quot; that shocked Harbin in 1933 came to an abrupt end. On the evening of August 24 of that year, after dining at the Madier Western Restaurant, Simon, the son of Joseph Kasper Sr., was kidnapped by the Inspector General of the Kazakhstan Police Department, Martinov, and 15 gangsters; on December 3, Simon’s body was found It was discovered in Xiaoling near Harbin, causing an outcry. The following year, the sad old Joseph took his wife and children and left for France. Soon he died of illness in Paris. Madier also declined from glory to glory. Only the leather bag left by Casper in the &quot;Historical and Cultural Corridor&quot; of the hotel can be traced. Talk about being a witness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 25, 1948, representatives of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and democrats such as Shen Junru and Zhang Bojun in Kazakhstan reached an &quot;Agreement on Various Issues Concerning the Convening of a New Political Consultative Conference&quot; in the No. 1 conference room of the Madier Hotel. . At that time, the 73-year-old &quot;Heng Lao&quot; Shen Junru lived in a hotel and often went for walks along the Songhua River. He saw the rare scene of the river freezing and then thawing again, so he wrote a poem: &quot;After the river freezes, I see rushing water and snow. Even the tide is not full. The atmosphere of the earth also changes with people and events. From now on, geese from the north no longer have to go south.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/ MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Dormition Church in the Cultural Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south bank of the Songhua River at the end of Central Street is Stalin Park, a narrow and long &quot;riverside&quot;. From here you can You can enjoy the scenery of the river that is sometimes rapid and sometimes gentle, touch the soul of the northern city, and feel the carnival atmosphere of the &quot;Harbin Summer&quot; concert that has been held for more than 60 years in the summer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rivers and songs flow into the distance, deposited over hundreds of years. Harbin is like a sponge, absorbing all sounds, while those mottled old buildings become witnesses of the city&#39;s historical changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原副主任龚建华一审被判有期徒刑15年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, the Intermediate People’s Court of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province publicly announced the verdict of the original party group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress In the case of member and deputy director Gong Jianhua accepting bribes, the defendant Gong Jianhua was sentenced to 15 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 5.5 million; the bribery income of Gong Jianhua and his The interest shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251237&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 2004 to 2020, the defendant Gong Jianhua used his position as deputy secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, executive deputy mayor, leader of the Nanchang Municipal Planning Land Operation Leading Group, deputy secretary of the Yichun Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, and municipal Chairman, Secretary of the Fuzhou Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, Member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, Secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee, Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers or status, provide relevant individuals with land listing, project contracting, and project development. Provided assistance with matters such as job promotion and job promotion, and illegally received property equivalent to more than RMB 83.61 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the defendant Gong Jianhua’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes, and the amount of bribes he accepted was particularly huge. In view of the fact that Gong Jianhua truthfully confessed his crime after voluntarily surrendering to the case, and voluntarily confessed some bribery facts that were not yet known to the case-handling agency, he had the circumstances to surrender, confessed and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the bribery proceeds and their accruals have been sealed, detained, and frozen in the case, which is legal. , determine the circumstances of lenient punishment, and he may be punished leniently in accordance with the law. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次本不公开的学术不端自查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3 nh27B3yxPJUsd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, during an academic conference, Li Wei (pseudonym), a professor at the School of Physical Education of Shihezi University, casually agreed to a friend’s request for a paper name. It was a paper related to swimming. In 2021, a third-party agency discovered that the paper was suspected of being synthesized by reverse translation software and reported it to the Ministry of Education for confirmation, and the Ministry of Education fed back the situation to Shihezi University. The school launched an investigation and sent a letter to the other school, and found that Li Wei, the corresponding author, had not previously known about the existence of this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wei was punished and could not participate in various project applications and evaluations for three years. During the ongoing self-examination of academic misconduct in college theses and the cleanup of false claims, Li Wei was reported again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in late May 2023, many universities have successively announced the launch of self-examination and cleanup of academic misconduct in papers, requiring self-examination and cleanup of academic papers since January 2018. Previously, on April 27, 2023, the General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology issued a self-examination notice, requiring universities and scientific research institutes to self-examine and clean up common academic misconduct including plagiarism, plagiarism, forged peer reviews, ghostwriting and investment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main purpose of self-examination is to reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers and strive to curb the increase. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a self-examination operation that was not intended to be made public. Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the notice only became known to the outside world because two universities posted the notice as an attachment online. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The self-examination document is “not public &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the notices issued by each school, the main objects of this self-examination are These are all academic papers published by teachers and students of the school as the first signed unit. The focus areas of self-examination are basically the same, and they are all relatively common academic misconduct. It mainly includes six categories: plagiarism, plagiarism, and duplication of publications; forging corresponding authors, forging or manipulating peer reviews; forging, fabricating, and tampering with experimental data and pictures, using one picture for multiple purposes, and selective use; buying, selling, and ghostwriting papers; and purchasing experiments. Research data; nominal phenomena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the notice of the Ministry of Science and Technology, universities and scientific research institutes in all provinces should carry out self-examination and clean-up work. However, according to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, only nearly 30 universities, including Shihezi University, Qinghai University, and Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture, have issued this notice on their official websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice was originally a non-public document, but it became known to the outside world after two universities posted it online as an attachment to the notice. In fact, the notice documents issued by the Jiangsu and Anhui Provincial Science and Technology Departments did state &quot;This matter will not be made public&quot; at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a top-down campaign to investigate academic misconduct. Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact nearly 30 universities that publicly released the notice. Among them, Shihezi University, Qinghai University, Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University were interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, different universities have slightly different self-examination methods. However, they all adopt the method of teachers filling in forms and reporting by themselves. The content of the form mainly contains the personal information of the self-examination teacher, such as position, school, research direction, etc., as well as paper information, including paper title, DOI/PMID, publication time, publication journal, author category, academic violations, etc. The college’s statistical researchers are required to screen academic papers published within the verification period, identify academic papers with the above six conditions, put forward rectification suggestions, and form a self-examination work summary report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specific inspection methods can be roughly divided into focused spot inspections and comprehensive inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University and Yanshan University adopted a comprehensive inventory approach. A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University told Southern Weekend reporters that they had comprehensively checked 8,671 papers signed by teachers at the school within the time limit. The school organized an investigation team. The teachers first filled in the self-examination form, and then the college compiled and submitted it. Finally, the school&#39;s scientific research office reported it to the XPCC Education Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Social Sciences Office of Yanshan University said that after the announcement, the secondary college organized teachers to conduct self-examinations and submit self-examination forms and commitment letters. The college issues a self-examination report based on the self-examination situation, which is finally summarized and reported by the Social Science Office. Southern Weekend reporters contacted some colleges of the school to inquire about the implementation status. Among them, a staff member from the office of the School of Construction Engineering and Mechanics confirmed the statement of the aforementioned person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinghai University and Southwest University of Science and Technology adopt focused spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that the school&#39;s Science and Technology Office takes the lead and adopts a two-level system. First, the college&#39;s professor committee organizes self-examination, and then the school inspection office conducts random inspections. Specific to different disciplines, the degree of rigor varies. For example, due to the subject characteristics of medicine, academic misconduct is prone to occur. The school conducted a census of more than 150 papers published by teachers from the clinical medical school between January 2022 and May 2023, while other disciplines were Spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the requirements in the notice are from January 2018 to May 2023, the aforementioned teacher in charge said that Qinghai University has two inspections every year, at mid-term and at the end of the year, so this time it will be from 2022 to the present. Check the thesis again as a key point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why he adopted the method of focused spot checks was that Qinghai University’s strong disciplines are mainly agriculture and forestry. “Due to the plateau specificity, many papers do not have experiments and data, and cannot be copied from other places. Therefore, The probability of academic misconduct will be relatively small.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spot checks are conducted on a proportional basis. He gave an example, based on the total number of papers published by the college within the period, for example, 50 papers were published, and 10 papers were randomly checked, including the original data of the scientific research and whether the person named on the paper was a member of the research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology said that they mainly screen key papers, and others mainly rely on feedback and reports from school teachers and other staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Almost no problems were found&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of large-scale self-examination has little impact on This is the first time for many universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant officials from Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University stated that similar large-scale system self-examination work had not been carried out before. The person in charge of Southwest University of Science and Technology emphasized that issues such as academic misconduct and pseudonymity were previously mainly investigated and handled through reports from others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in most notices, the self-examination time left for teachers is about one month. At present, the self-examination work has basically been completed at the school level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some self-examination window periods are shorter. The Science and Technology Office of Shijiazhuang Railway University issued a notice on July 26, 2023, requiring each college to complete the self-examination and cleanup work before July 30. If problems are found, a summary form should be filled out in a timely manner and submitted to the Science and Technology Office, and remedial measures such as corrections and retractions should be taken, and &quot;no feedback after the deadline will be deemed as a paper without academic misconduct.&quot; They gave each college only four days for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback from the four schools interviewed, the result of the self-examination was “almost no problems.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers at Yanshan University said that the self-examination work was completed at the end of July and &quot;no problems were found&quot;, and emphasized that the relevant results have been reported to the Provincial Department of Education. Teachers from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology also said that the school has completed a preliminary screening and found no relevant violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether a self-examination report needs to be issued, a staff member from the office of the School of Architectural Engineering and Mechanics of Yanshan University said, “The school only requires us to fill in a self-examination form and issue a report if there are any problems, but our school should no problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, the teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that since inspections were organized twice a year before, no serious academic misconduct was found this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only exception is Shihezi University. They self-identified three illegal articles. The violations were improper naming, purchasing data, and repeated publication. They belonged to the School of Physical Education, School of Medicine, and School of Animal Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the improper listing and purchase data are illegal articles that have been investigated before this inspection. Although notices from the science and technology departments of many provinces stated that papers that have been investigated and dealt with may not be included in the scope of this self-examination. However, the teacher in charge of the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University believes that it &quot;still serves as a warning.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to punish after investigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology stated that if problems are found during self-examination and cleanup, scientific researchers must promptly report to the unit and take remedial measures such as corrections and retractions. Those who comply with the lenient treatment circumstances specified in Article 34 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; may be given lenient treatment in accordance with the regulations; those who conceal or make false reports shall be punished in accordance with Article 3 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; Article 15 and other relevant regulations will be dealt with seriously and publicly announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University explained that the school has criticized and educated the teachers involved and required them not to apply for projects within three years. They are not allowed to be prioritized and receive talent titles, nor can they apply for science and technology projects. award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University will take lenient treatment for those who took the initiative to report in this self-examination.动物科技学院张小千、李劼在2019年发表《培养温度对嗜热链球菌抑制法检测结果的影响》一文。涉事老师当时分别向《黑龙江畜牧兽医》和《中国奶牛》两家期刊投递论文，其中《黑龙江畜牧兽医》为核心期刊。 2019年5月，《中国奶牛》率先将论文发表，4个月后，《黑龙江畜牧兽医》刊出此文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发现重复发表后，论文作者曾反复与《中国奶牛》期刊负责人交涉，要求对方撤稿，但被拒。直到2023年7月，论文作者借由科技部的相关通知进行协商，对方最终同意撤稿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石河子大学科研处的老师表示，由于论文作者主动报告，且此前数次联系杂志社撤稿，因此处理方式上就从轻，仅批评教育。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;为何自查？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为何会有此次自上而下的大规模自查？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前述科技部通知中对此的解释为，压实各单位主体责任，削减学术不端论文存量，着力遏制增量，引导科研人员强化科研诚信意识等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;简而言之，自查的核心在于消除存量、遏制增量。前述接近科技部的人士解释，比如某位科研人员十年前买了一篇文章，要么已经发表用以申报职称获利，要么一直没用。如果没用的话，现在各种严打，只能憋着，一旦发表，没准哪天就会爆雷。不管怎样，他们都会忐忑不安。而自查清理是很好的机会，“就是给这些犯过错误的科研人员一个机会，不论当时是无知也好、侥幸也罢”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，也是给科研人员一个自查梳理的机会。 “梳理一下总归是好事，增强诚信意识，摸清家底，不至于出现被挂名却不自知的情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于遏制增量，“如果知道大家都在盯着这个事，他们以后也不会再干了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，前述接近科技部的人士提及，由于是自查，有从轻减轻情形，“如果没有从中获利，甚至可以不予追究，不过批评肯定是要的”。他认为，自查更多起到教育和震慑的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，这并非首次开展清查。南方周末记者了解到，2022年也曾在部委层面开展过这项工作，目的是让相关部门和地方层面了解到部委对科研诚信工作的重视，但当时“并未公开”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于可能存在瞒报情况，前述接近科技部的人士表示，如果自查时没问题，而将来查出问题，且处于2018年至今的时间段内，那一定会加重处理，“这相当于对抗诚信检查”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果拉长时间线看，自查背后，是近年逐渐多发的论文撤稿情况和趋严的科研诚信管理措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年4月20日，学术出版巨头施普林格发布声明称，107篇已发表于《肿瘤生物学》的论文因涉嫌同行评审造假而被撤稿。而这些涉事论文全部来自中国，发表时间为2012-2016年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国科协当时发表意见，希望施普林格出版集团能够尽快完善内控机制，加强对期刊的管理，把问题论文处理在发表前，而不是发表之后一撤了之，同时高度警惕以经济利益为目的、与“第三方”机构有勾结的“掠夺性期刊”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月15日，美国恒祥咨询（Healsan Consulting LLC）发布《2022年SCI论文撤稿简报》。简报显示，截至2022年12月31日，全球范围内总共有41642篇SCI撤稿，其中中国19421篇。具体到2022年1月1日至2022年12月31日期间，全球有5488篇SCI撤稿，其中中国的撤稿数量为2879篇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对科研诚信的重视程度也日益提高。 2018年5月，中共中央办公厅、国务院办公厅印发《关于进一步加强科研诚信建设的若干意见》。意见强调，要严厉打击严重违背科研诚信要求的行为，建立终身追究制度，一经发现，随时调查处理。这是首次以中央发文的形式，将科研诚信工作的重要性提到极高程度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，2020年，科技进步法修订，进一步明确了科研失信的相关惩戒措施。 2022年，科技部等22个部门对《科研诚信案件调查处理规则（试行）》进行修订，使得科研失信行为的调查处理工作有了更为具体的处理规则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，从2018年开始，科技部每年陆续公布科研失信行为调查处理结果，2017至2019年各有一批处理结果，2020年有两批，2021年和2022年则公布了四批。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此轮自查之后将有后续。前述接近科技部的人士表示，尤其是一点问题都没查出来的，恰恰在重点关注范围内。 “这次盖着单位的红章来，一篇有问题的文章都没有，但如果之后频繁撤稿，或者被调查出现问题，那单位的主体责任肯定落实不到位，到时一定严肃查处。”他表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医生频频被举报，“飞刀”为何难合规？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257002]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;目前，会诊和多点执业是让“飞刀”正规化的两条主要道路，但二者酬劳标准都要向着主要执业机构内的薪酬体系看齐。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;病没看好，手术费是否应该退还？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月底，河南杞县的一位患者家属马先生称，其父亲7月“脸上长了一个包”，于是来到杞县中医院治疗。医院告知需由开封的专家来做手术，并要支付3000元现金作为费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外院专家执刀、高于市场价的手术费用、现金支付等形式，都提示马先生父亲经历了一次“飞刀”手术。“飞刀”，顾名思义，“打着飞的去开刀”。医生们在闲暇时间离开所在医院前往外地出诊，多以执刀外科手术为主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有意思之处在于，患者的病没看好，马先生希望讨还执刀医生收取的3000元手术费，依据的是2005年原卫生部发布的《医师外出会诊管理暂行规定》中关于会诊费用应统一支付给会诊医疗机构的规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该事件经由河南都市频道报道后，旋即引发业内关注：“飞刀”手术是否应当存在？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有医生认为，“飞刀”手术当前缺乏制度保障，给患者和医生均带来了风险，应予以禁绝。也有医生持反对意见，认为“飞刀”手术帮助专家获得了收入，病人获得了便捷的治疗，基层医院获得技术经验，地方医保基金得以留在本地，应予以支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到今天，“飞刀”手术仍处于法律的灰色地带。能让“飞刀”合规的政策在医院内部管理以及制度流程上遭遇诸多障碍，在基层庞大的市场需求之下，私自开展的“飞刀”一直存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;收入问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对医生而言，“飞刀”长盛不衰的核心原因是“增收”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，会诊和多点执业是让“飞刀”正规化的两条主要道路，但二者酬劳标准都要向着主要执业机构内的薪酬体系看齐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年的《医师外出会诊管理暂行规定》中提到，会诊中涉及的会诊费用按照邀请医疗机构所在地的规定执行，可在当地规定的基础上酌情加收。加收幅度由省级价格主管部门会同同级卫生行政部门确定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“酌情”的幅度注定不会太高，北京市一家二级医院的科室主任成胜对南方周末记者表示，北京市内的院际会诊，专家到手费用大约是300至500元，“哪个专家愿意这样跑一趟浪费时间精力？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于多点执业的薪酬，原国家卫计委2014年发布的《关于印发推进和规范医师多点执业的若干意见的通知》中规定，多点执业医师的薪酬根据实际工作时间、工作量和工作业绩等因素，由执业地点医疗机构与医师协商确定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于操刀本院的日常手术，医生能获取的收入情况，上海一位呼吸科医生曾向南方周末记者透露，其每台手术的酬劳约为300元，勤劳的医生每天开展两三台手术，每月绩效奖金收入约3万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与之对应的是“飞刀”收入。从事“飞刀”中介工作的王贵向南方周末记者透露，患者接受一次“飞刀”手术的费用从3000元到9000元不等，中介抽成10%，剩下都归医生所有。决定费用高低的主要是医生等级、手术难度、执业距离，万元价位的手术可能需要多位医生跨省支援，手术时长7至8个小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中介往往会对专家分层。顶级专家一般是学科带头人、硕博导师、所在城市顶级医院的科室主任，这些医生是省会城市大医院外援的首选。普通专家的年资和知名度都较低，一般“飞刀”地点是县级医院。“普外、眼科、胃肠、肝胆、胸外、骨科的飞刀医生是比较多的。”王贵说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若没有王贵这样的中介牵线，“飞刀”则多发生在有私交的医生之间。邀请方的医生多来自区县医院，或曾在专家所在科室进修学习，或师出同门。“双方一定是知根知底的。”北京一家三甲医院的胸外科主任程磊表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，无论哪种形式，相较上述《规定》和《通知》，“飞刀”手术费用不菲。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;正规化努力从未停止&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在一些医生眼中，除了经济利益以外，“飞刀”还能展示自己的技术，提升“江湖地位”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程磊告诉南方周末记者，自己曾在手术器械厂商的组织下到外地医院展示技术，帮助一项肿瘤消融手术在全国范围内落地，“与其说是飞刀，更像是带教”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便是胸外科主任医师，程磊也得求助能应对高难度手术的同行“飞刀”。程磊的父亲在江苏一家医院检查出主动脉夹层，怀疑存在主动脉瘤。当地医院没有条件手术，而前往上海治疗有数百公里，一旦瘤体在路上破裂将危及生命。最后，“飞刀”医生解决了燃眉之急。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在医疗资源分布不均的现实之下，各级政府将“飞刀”带入正规轨道的努力从未停止。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年的《医师外出会诊管理暂行规定》提出了院际会诊制度，2009年的《卫生部关于医师多点执业有关问题的通知》则回应了社会各界关于允许多点执业的呼声。2020年以来，医联体建设加速，同一医联体内医院的会诊、培训、转诊制度也日渐成熟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以理解为，如果专家要长期在同一家医院做手术，一般会办一个多点执业备案。如果是一次性的就采用会诊的方式。”京衡律师事务所高级合伙人，曾当过6年医生的章李对南方周末记者如是解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多点执业制度诞生之初，曾有过“一名医生不得在三个以上医疗机构执业”的限制性规定，但2017年颁布的《医师执业注册管理办法》允许医生跨省多点执业。还规定医生在主要执业机构的同一省级行政区内多点执业，只需在这些执业机构备案即可。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从注册制改为备案制，意味着医生无需主要执业机构和当地卫生部门许可，即可多点执业。在这样的政策加持下，国家卫健委2020年10月公布的一组数据显示，国内多点执业医生的数量已达26万人，是2016年的4倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“医院不希望看到自己的医生到处飞”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前来看，多点执业推进依旧存在诸多障碍，这也为“飞刀”创造了现实土壤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位受访者提到了医院的软性管束。南方周末记者获得的西南某知名医院在院内实行的《医师多点执业管理规范》，其中要求医生完成多点执业备案之余，还要在当地所在区的卫生健康局备案，并向本院提交照片、医师资格证、执业医师执业证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;繁琐的院内审批流程并非孤例。据自媒体“看医界”公开报道，2020年，长沙市第一医院发布的《医师多点执业管理办法（试行）》规定，多点执业医生要求是中级及以上职称，所在科室须在上一年度科室年终KPI考核成绩位列中等以上水平等等。文件还表示，非指令性任务的外院医疗机构执业活动，必须经科室主任同意，并报备医务科、分管院领导，并经医院办公会批准后，方可办理注册。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述西南地区医院的《医师多点执业管理规范》中要求，多点执业医师应签订劳务协议，与多点执业机构就执业类别、执业范围、聘用期限、工作任务、医疗责任、时间安排、考核方式、薪酬、保险福利待遇等进行明确，并将该协议在本院医务部进行备案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京一家民营医院的外科医生庞梁对南方周末记者表示，一些医院明令禁止医生外出执业，理由之一是担心病人被分流到其他医院，影响收入。深圳市非公医疗机构协会名誉会长谢汝石则从单纯的管理者心理角度分析，“医院不希望看到自己的医生到处飞，这很正常”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;飞刀”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;纠纷不断，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“民不举官不究”？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;未经许可开展的“飞刀”手术，可能被定性为非法行医而遭到严惩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医疗事故技术鉴定认为构成医疗事故并且承担主要责任的，在行政层面上，“飞刀”医生可能会被暂停执业甚至吊销医师执业资格证；如果触犯刑法，医生还可能因涉嫌医疗事故罪而遭起诉。如果医疗事故是同等责任及以下，“飞刀”医生可能会承担行政责任。至于民事赔偿部分，法律规定赔偿主体是医疗机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很大程度上，“飞刀”相关纠纷仍属于“民不举官不究”，患者的意志对案件发展影响很大。章李代理过的一起案件中，“飞刀”专家在进行一场胸部结节手术时，患者出现大出血，“没能从手术台上下来”。事后医生上门道歉，家属也认为国家培养一个医生不容易，选择放弃行政投诉及刑事举报，所以“飞刀”医生没有涉及行政与刑事处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在另一起案件中，医生进行一场胸部整形手术，患者术中同样出现大出血，康复之后告到了专家所在医院的卫生主管部门。最后专家被行政撤职、调离工作岗位、被罚暂停执业三个月。这是章李所接触过的处罚结果最严重的一起“飞刀”案件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使不发生医疗事故，医生也可能被病人“闹”。一个广为人知的例子是，2019年，一山西患者请到了北京天坛医院医生对其进行神经外科支架植入手术。据中国青年报报道，事后患者家属在支付1万元现金“飞刀”费用时，偷偷录像并举报，导致涉事医生和该医院帮忙收钱转交的医生均被停职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个隐忧是，“飞刀”医生开完刀后拂袖离去，将术后护理留给基层医院，但后者可能缺乏相关知识，对病人福祉构成隐患。庞梁提到了2019年的一起医疗事故：一位男性患者在某医院进行了胃减容手术，由一位参加学术交流的外地医生执刀。术后5天，患者猝然离世。尸检报告显示，患者在术后继发胃漏、急性化脓性腹膜炎、腹腔脓血性积液，导致感染中毒性休克、多脏器功能衰竭而死亡。这可能是当地医院缺乏合适的术后护理的结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“病人觉得效果没到预期，要退钱，不退钱我就告你，一告一个准。”程磊表示，“飞刀”手术的灰色属性是医生们的天然软肋，高额的费用是上不得台面的。遇到纠纷，发出“飞刀”邀约的基层医院大多不会去找专家的麻烦，而是默默出钱“把事平了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;合法合规难题待解&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看似很美好的“飞刀”，仍未走出不合规的本质，这意味着身处其中的患者、医生的抗风险能力都极其脆弱。比如，一些医院会给医生投保医疗事故责任险，帮助减少发生事故后的经济损失，但未经备案的“飞刀”手术显然不在理赔范畴内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生们也逐渐摸索出一种“半合规”的院外会诊操作路径。出诊前先让基层医院出具邀请函，在自己院内完成备案。会诊完成后，再在正常收入的基础上加收一笔钱。后者不计入财务流程，也不会由病人直接付给专家，而是经由邀请方医院转手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目前日常中都是这么干的，需要有一定的补充收益这样才有人愿意去会诊。”谢汝石告诉南方周末记者，如此一来，“飞刀”行为本身是合规报备过的，属于合法的医疗行为，但收入的部分属于红包，仍然见不得光，可能面临院内纪检部门的查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于自我保护，医生们也会筛选“飞刀”病例，避免参与风险太高的“飞刀”手术。王贵表示，患者提出请院外专家执刀的要求后，管床医生会评估该患者家属是否“比较敏感”，容易挑刺，经济条件是否宽裕等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在庞梁的设想中，为了让“飞刀”收入走到阳光下，大医院应该建立一个公开的专家库，按照科室、级别对每位专家明码标价，供患者和基层医院选择。这一价格可以与日常执业的薪酬拉开差距。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是让“飞刀”真正获得名分。王贵所在的机构具备齐全的诊疗营业资质，控股民营医院。专家均在这家医院注册多点执业，再由该医院派遣出去提供咨询服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在章李看来，如此一来医生便能绕开公立属性的主执业地医疗机构，合法地进行外出会诊。在一篇教医生如何合法“飞刀”的文章中，他将这个做法称为“远程导弹”，而“洲际导弹”则是创建或加入医生集团、诊所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生集团主要是对接会诊供需双方，派遣集团医生前往基层医院提供服务。但医生集团不属于医疗机构，医生仍隶属于一个主执业医疗机构——或为医生的老东家，或为医生集团内的民营医院。本质上，医生集团只是中介平台，医生走的仍是多点执业或会诊道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾参与创办多个医生集团的谢汝石表示，医生集团可以与患者或派遣地医院签订告知协议，确定“飞刀”手术的价格，并且以医生集团名义收费。如此操作，使得处于灰色地带的“飞刀”费用合规。不过，医生集团面临的问题是，通过招投标形式与派遣地医院达成合作关系十分困难，而和患者一个个单独洽谈合作又不能形成商业模式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使资质齐全，王贵所在的机构依然十分谨慎。他们对外宣称的商业模式是提供医生的咨询服务，包含术前评估、术后康复方案制定等，但不包含手术执刀。“实际上是会执刀的，但不能这么说，因为没有文件允许我们这么做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中程磊、王贵、庞梁是化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新冠疫苗：每年秋天来一针？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些国家，新冠疫苗可能要像流感一样每年推荐接种了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月12日，美国疾病预防控制中心（CDC）发布建议，六个月以上的所有人都应该在今年秋冬季注射一针新版新冠疫苗。几天前，美国食品药品监督管理局（FDA）批准了莫德纳（Moderna）和辉瑞（Pfizer）的两种新版疫苗，新版疫苗针对的是名为XBB.1.5的奥密克戎病毒变体，这一毒株在全世界大部分国家广泛传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接种疫苗依然是预防新冠病毒住院和死亡的最佳措施。疫苗还可以减少长期的新冠影响。根据CDC发布的建议，近两个月没有接种过新冠疫苗的人，都可以接种这一新版疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们拥有了更多的工具来预防新冠病毒带来的严重后果。”美国CDC主任、医学博士、公共卫生硕士曼迪•科恩（Mandy Cohen）表示。发布这一建议的原因在于，新冠病毒仍在不断变异，新的亚型接连出现，而疫苗的保护作用随着时间急剧下降，接种新版疫苗能更好地保护大众健康。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CDC的独立咨询委员会以13∶1高票同意建议普遍接种这一疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赞成者之一、美国埃默里大学医学院副教授桑德拉·弗莱霍夫(Sandra Fryhoffer) 博士认为，新冠重症可能发生在所有年龄段包括没有基础疾病的人身上，加上很多人此前没有接种加强针，意味着对新冠病毒的整体免疫力都在下降，因此应该推荐全部人接种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;普通人打还是不打&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;鼓励接种新冠疫苗已逾三年，但疫苗策略正在悄然发生改变，大部分国家没有像美国一样，推荐所有人接种加强针。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，英国政府宣布，新版加强针免费提供的对象是65岁以上的老年人及一线医务人员和脆弱群体。法国不建议非脆弱群体接种加强针。德国压根没有秋季加强针计划，尽管它之前建议高危人群应该每年接种一剂新冠疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员普遍认为，由于新冠疫苗的主要作用是预防重症而非感染，因此高危人群接种受益最大。而低风险人群和未成年人要不要再接种，科学界仍存在争议。 “对于老年人、有基础疾病和免疫缺陷的人群接种加强针非常有意义。”约翰斯·霍普金斯大学健康安全中心传染病专家艾米什·阿戴尔贾（Amesh Adalja）表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;新冠病毒蔓延三年多来，不少人对病毒的感染逐渐麻木，选择接种疫苗的人数也逐渐下降。但事实上，无论在美国或是中国，反复感染新冠的人不在少数。美国CDC科学家报告称，自7 月中旬以来，因新冠住院的人数一直在增加，虽然其中大多数为幼儿和老年人，但住院的五岁以下儿童中有一半没有潜在的健康问题，这提醒人们即使其他方面健康的人也可能有罹患新冠重症的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在即将到来的秋冬病毒流行季，流感病毒、呼吸道合胞病毒和新冠病毒很可能交叉感染，这会对脆弱人群造成比较严重的后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;在冬季来临前做准备&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在我国，整体疫情处于局部零星散发状态，但新冠病毒并未消失，病毒在人群中的传播现象仍持续存在，身边不乏有人几个月前才经历“二阳”，现在又遭遇“三阳”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基于新冠的传染性极强，得过新冠后抗体自然衰减及没有绝对的保护性新冠疫苗，基本上多数人每年会感染1-3次。”深圳市第三人民医院院长卢洪洲教授解释，“对于免疫功能正常的人群，不会造成特别大的影响。”但对于高龄、糖尿病、肿瘤基础病等免疫功能低下人群，卢洪洲建议每年定期接种新冠疫苗。接种疫苗的策略，可以包括鼻喷疫苗和皮下注射疫苗联合免疫、多价新冠组合疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月25日，国务院联防联控机制综合组印发的《近期重点人群新冠病毒疫苗接种工作方案》提出，对老年人等重点人群实施针对性新冠病毒疫苗接种。明确在新冠病毒XBB变异株流行期间，重点是今年秋冬季，优先推荐接种含XBB变异株抗原成分的疫苗。专家呼吁已感染且未完成基础免疫的人群，应该在感染3个月后接种1剂次疫苗，这将有利于在后续可能发生的疫情中为重症、死亡高风险人群提供更好的保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有专家预计，9月开学后新冠病毒感染人数会增加。按照免疫力周期推测，下一波新冠流行可能出现在今秋11月左右。而此时也正逢流感季，新冠叠加流感，可能导致呼吸道感染相关重症增加，因此建议同时接种流感疫苗和新冠疫苗，这也是世卫组织的推荐——两种疫苗叠加可以最大限度地预防重症和减轻病毒交叉感染带来的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“住院和死亡人数增加表明，冠状病毒病将会长期存在，世界仍然需要预防、检测和治疗新冠的工具。”世卫组织总干事谭德塞博士在2023年9月6日的媒体通报会上强调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天降烟头烫伤女婴，DNA比对锁定嫌疑人：胜于住户连坐多矣！丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256968]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some time ago, a baby girl in Zhengzhou was burned by a cigarette butt falling from the sky in a community. The police collected blood from all the residents upstairs and compared the DNA on the cigarette butts, and successfully identified the suspect who threw the cigarette butts. This is another case of using high-tech means to identify the suspect of throwing objects from high altitude. It also reminds you again that throwing objects from high altitude is extremely harmful and the probability of police intervention to solve the case is greatly increased. Don’t take chances and try the law yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, at the end of August, Ms. Huang was taking her 4-month-old baby for a walk downstairs when an unextinguished cigarette butt fell from the sky and burned the child&#39;s shoulders and neck. Although the surveillance cameras in the community only cover one floor of the ground and there is no high-altitude surveillance, it is impossible to find out who threw the cigarette butt through the video. However, the police successfully found the suspect who threw the object at high altitude by collecting blood from all the residents upstairs to test DNA. Not only will this person be liable for civil torts, but he is also likely to be subject to criminal penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tall buildings provide us with more living and working space and have become a symbol of modernization. However, they also bring the risk of throwing and falling objects from high altitudes. Carrying high-speed kinetic energy converted from high-altitude potential energy, even an egg weighing tens of grams may cause serious injury, not to mention other dangerous items. In recent years, there have been constant news about vehicles being damaged by objects thrown and falling from heights, killing and injuring people. In 2016, an iron fitness ball fell from the sky in Suining, Sichuan, killing a baby girl under one year old; in 2020, another 14-month-old baby in Shaoxing, Zhejiang was hit in the head by a brick thrown from upstairs. Causing brain death...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is unlikely that an unextinguished cigarette butt will injure someone, the risk of causing a fire or scalding someone is not small. In addition to the recent case in Zhengzhou, a similar case occurred in a community in Luzhou, Sichuan in 2021. A cigarette butt dropped from a high altitude burned through the roof of a baby car and almost burned the baby. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, casualties or property losses caused by falling objects from high altitudes were usually dealt with as civil infringements, and the victims had to collect evidence on their own to prosecute. Unless the impact was extremely serious, the police generally would not intervene in the investigation. The individual&#39;s ability to collect evidence is naturally very weak, and in most cases the perpetrator cannot be found. What to do?之前的法律规定，这种情况下由所有“可能的加害者”给予补偿，也就是说，一旦发生了高空抛物伤人事件，找不到肇事者，楼上所有的住户（除了有证据证明自己不是肇事者的，比如楼房空置没住人等）就要“连坐”。 Although this provision allows the victim to receive compensation, it is very unfair to those who did not throw things downstairs. It may even condone the perpetrators, because the consequences of the evil are shared by many people. This legal provision and related court decisions have caused great controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to solving the problem is to find the perpetrators and punish them severely.这一方面有赖于技术进步，比如高空视频监控、DNA比对等技术，都有助于锁定肇事者。 On the other hand, there are changes in legal provisions.如果还是让受害人自己去收集证据，基本上还是走不通的。 Because individuals do not have the right to collect DNA from others for identification, there are no legal provisions, and properties have no incentive to install high-altitude surveillance systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Civil Code and Criminal Law Amendment (11), which will be implemented in 2021, has changed this rule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the civil side, although the &quot;simultaneous sitting&quot; provisions still exist, the Civil Code requires the police to investigate in a timely manner in accordance with the law and identify the person responsible. The &quot;continuous sitting&quot; rule applies only when the police are unable to find out. As a result, it has become the legal duty of the police to identify the person responsible for falling objects from heights. The police have greater power and ability to conduct investigations. For example, they can narrow the scope of investigation based on the mobile phone signal at the location of the incident, and can force &quot;possible perpetrators&quot; to provide biological samples for DNA comparison. Through these technical means, the police can basically make the perpetrators invisible. Especially the DNA comparison is extremely shocking. In the case of a cigarette butt falling from the sky in Luzhou, Sichuan, which almost scalded a baby, the perpetrator voluntarily surrendered after the police completed the DNA analysis on the cigarette butt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Civil Code also stipulates that property management companies and other building managers should take necessary safety measures to prevent infringement incidents of falling objects from high altitudes; otherwise, they will bear tort liability for failing to perform safety guarantee obligations. In this way, the property management company will have the motivation to do a good job in prevention, monitoring and other tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of criminal liability, the judicial interpretation issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court in 2019 stipulates that intentional throwing of objects from high altitude and negligent falling of objects from high altitude can be classified as &quot;crime of endangering public safety by dangerous means&quot; and &quot;negligence causing casualties.&quot; Convicted and punished for crimes such as &quot;serious accident crime&quot; and &quot;major liability accident crime&quot;. The Criminal Law Amendment (11), which took effect on March 1, 2021, has added the crime of &quot;throwing objects from high altitudes&quot;. Although the penalty for this crime is lighter than the penalty for &quot;crime of endangering public safety&quot;, the police must open a case to investigate the crime regardless of the severity. This also means that under the new criminal law, the threshold for criminal offenses for throwing objects from high altitudes has been lowered, and the police have greater legal responsibilities to conduct criminal investigations. In this way, the probability of the perpetrator being discovered will be greatly increased, the possibility and intensity of punishment will also be greatly increased, and the deterrence of high-altitude missiles will also be greatly increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;用技术让法律长出牙齿，形成足够的威慑力。 Those who throw objects from high altitudes will be caught and severely punished. Those who throw objects from high altitudes will have nowhere to hide. With fewer people daring to test the law, the sky above our heads will be safer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[坚守大山十年，月薪不到三千：支教老师“中年危机”何解]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国铁集团：不可能给第三方平台“优先购票权”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 18:31:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Today, the railway department began to sell train tickets for October 3, with sufficient tickets left in all directions. From September 28th to October 2nd, there are still tickets left. For tickets sold during the pre-sale period on and before September 27, there are sufficient remaining tickets in all directions. Based on passenger flow demand, tickets for the more than 100 additional passenger trains that the railway department will open during the holidays have been on sale since September 18, which can increase the passenger capacity by more than 70,000 seats per day. From September 13 to 18, the railway department sold a total of 111 million train tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on passenger travel demand, the railway department has arranged to open more than 100 additional passenger trains during the National Day holiday. These trains will run on September 28, and tickets will go on sale on September 18. The main directions for adding trains are: Nanchang to Guangzhou, Wuhan to Guangzhou, Changsha to Nanchang, Nanchang to Shanghai, Xiamen to Shanghai, Shenzhen to Changsha, etc. Based on train ticket pre-sales, waitlist ticket purchase data and railway transportation capacity, the railway department will also open additional passenger trains in popular directions and hot time periods in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Passenger travel is highly concentrated during the holidays, and train tickets in some popular directions and hot periods are in short supply. Passengers can choose to buy tickets by waitlisting, transfer, etc., or according to the remaining tickets at different times and directions. , choose to travel during off-peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, EMU train fares have implemented a differentiated floating pricing mechanism, which is mainly based on market supply and demand and passenger flow patterns, with the published fare as the maximum price, and is implemented in time periods, seats, and sections. A multi-tier, high and low ticket price floating strategy. During this year&#39;s National Day holiday, high-speed rail still implements differentiated fares. For example, the fare for EMU trains between Beijing and Shanghai is as high as 667 yuan and as low as 404 yuan for second-class seats. Passengers can choose according to their needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Railway 12306 has never authorized any third-party platform to sell train tickets, and it is impossible to give third-party platforms the so-called &quot;priority to purchase tickets.&quot; Third-party platforms will retain user information during the ticket purchase process of passengers and friends. Not only do they have traps such as surcharges, acceleration packages, and bundled sales services, but they may also risk personal information leakage. Passengers please be sure to purchase tickets through official railway channels, look for the railway 12306 website (including the client), and pay attention to protecting legitimate rights and interests and the security of personal information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>