<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[浙江温州一处楼房垮塌，有人员被困]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260440]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 22:24:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765547162&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;A building collapsed in Wenzhou, Zhejiang, and people were trapped.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/8087253e3270835011765547162/sampleSnapshot /sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/8087253e3270835011765547162/B3qOFQgNxDQA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640 &quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/8087253e3270835011765547162/B3qOFQgNxDQA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 11th, A building collapsed in Qiaotou Town, Yongjia County, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, and people were trapped. On-site rescue was underway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7abc43256d6e42c52d765584dd8e2345.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4096&quot; height=&quot;3072&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7abc43256d6e42c52d765584dd8e2345.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257960&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/28117402f14f581f61b1f25ff2928406.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;4096&quot; height=&quot;3072&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/28117402f14f581f61b1f25ff2928406.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/93b4c598e8a28f9dab0fb5722e973c0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 2737&quot; height=&quot;2128&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/93b4c598e8a28f9dab0fb5722e973c0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[甘肃平凉一小学校长奸淫多名学生被执行死刑？当地回应：属实]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 22:26:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a notice titled &quot;Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Gansu Province&quot; has attracted attention on the Internet. Zhang Longji, the principal of a primary school in Jingning County, Pingliang City, was shown raping and molesting many students in public. He was executed on November 7. On November 11, local government office staff confirmed to Nandu reporters that this notice was indeed issued by the Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court, which had previously heard the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3b8ad1bc0bbb52159853539a5c14831e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1135&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3b8ad1bc0bbb52159853539a5c14831e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257973&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Court Notice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement of Pingliang Intermediate Court, Zhang Longji, male, Han nationality, was born on February 24, 1979 in Jingning County, Gansu Province, with a university education. From 2010 to June 2019, when he served as the dean, principal and teacher of a primary school in Jingning County, he used corporal punishment and other means to form a mental coercion on primary school students who lacked sexual defense ability. He used opportunities such as explaining exercises and students to hand in homework to He repeatedly raped five young girls aged 8 to 12 in his dormitory, and molested 17 children aged 8 to 14 in public in the classroom or in his dormitory. The Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court found Zhang Longji guilty of rape and sentenced to death and deprived of political rights for life; he was found guilty of child molestation and sentenced to ten years in prison. He was punished for several crimes and decided to execute him and be deprived of political rights for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the verdict of the case was pronounced, Zhang Longji appealed, but the appeal was rejected by the Gansu Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court and the original death sentence was upheld, which was approved by the Supreme People&#39;s Court. On November 7 this year, Pingliang Intermediate People&#39;s Court followed the execution order issued by the President of the Supreme People&#39;s Court, identified Zhang Longji, took him to the execution ground, and executed him by injection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters learned that Article 236 of the &quot;Criminal Law&quot; stipulates that anyone who rapes a girl under the age of fourteen shall be treated as rape and shall be severely punished. Anyone who rapes a woman or rapes a young girl with multiple persons, if the circumstances are abominable, or in public in a public place, shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than ten years, life imprisonment, or death. On May 25 this year, the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate jointly issued the &quot;Interpretation on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in the Handling of Criminal Cases of Rape and Molestation of Minors&quot;, reaffirming the judicial philosophy of adhering to the word &quot;strict&quot; and severe punishment. The relevant severe and aggravated punishment clauses have been further clarified and refined to ensure that the punishment is suitable for the crime, the punishment is worthy of the crime, and the punishment is sufficient to control the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次误杀，引来一次次误杀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260434]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The new Korean film &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot;, in some The plot setting is very reminiscent of Bong Joon Ho&#39;s &quot;Parasite&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/8a8a72b85cc0cbc139587fdc901c0d35.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1282&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/8a8a72b85cc0cbc139587fdc901c0d35.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257924&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;played by Kim Seo-hyung The heroine Wen Jing is a low-level domestic worker who takes care of an elderly couple with limited mobility. The latter comes from a wealthy family, and the old gentleman Li Taijiang is also a highly respected writer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an accident, Wen Jing accidentally killed the hostess. In order to cover up the truth, she took her elderly mother with dementia to the Li family, pretending to be the hostess, and planned to get away with it. At the same time, it also allows the mother who has been in the nursing home for a long time to be &quot;parasitized&quot; gracefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/eb640bc40cca98a7758e85cfccacdc9e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;486&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/eb640bc40cca98a7758e85cfccacdc9e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same disparity The two classes of &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot; and &quot;Parasite&quot; also involve the sharp social topic of &quot;parasitism&quot;, but the human background and expression concepts of &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot; and &quot;Parasite&quot; are completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Parasite&quot; is about the struggle between evil and evil. Neither the Pu family, who is in the upper class, nor the Jin family, who is the lower class, is a good opponent. The Pu family are polite on the surface, but in fact they regard the Jin family as servants and ants, and dislike their &quot;strange smell&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/a679d19de46b185c21598113a7968e1b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/a679d19de46b185c21598113a7968e1b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金家看He seems pitiful, but he is very good at trying to flatter people. He relies on his cleverness and pretense to obtain better living conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, the Park and Jin families both live under the law of the jungle, but one is grabbing profits from the open side, and the other is picking up leftovers in the dark. They are two incompatible factions, hostile to each other and never sincere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/436e5a804ed3734422f69bb5544669d8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/436e5a804ed3734422f69bb5544669d8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Plastic Greenhouse &quot;Different, the film never reveals the snobbishness of the Li family from beginning to end. On the contrary, Li Taijiang cares deeply about Wen Jing. No matter in terms of attitude or treatment, people can&#39;t find any fault. The same goes for Wen Jing. She doesn&#39;t covet or hate the old couple of the Li family. Although the old lady often behaves inappropriately towards Wen Jing because of Alzheimer&#39;s disease, she can always repay evil with kindness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Jing accidentally killed the old lady, which was purely accidental. She did not call the police and surrender because she wanted her son to have a complete family after he was released from prison; the reason why she took her mother to the Li family for &quot;parasitism&quot; was not for gain, but because Wen Jing, as a &quot;stupid person&quot;, was the safest thing she could think of. A way to cover up the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e1b4e2f73fd7691d777ffc33dcc4e323.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e1b4e2f73fd7691d777ffc33dcc4e323.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257926&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Full movie Looking at it, you will find that this is a silent killing between &quot;good and good&quot;. They do not hate each other, but they slip into the quagmire of sin by accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Wen Jing kills the old lady, the film is attached to the dark absurdity of the Coen brothers, and the plot is full of ups and downs, making people caught off guard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Wen Jing was disposing of the old lady&#39;s body, Li Taijiang went home, but due to his blindness, he could not see his dead wife&#39;s body on the floor. As a result, Li Taijiang was humming a ditty leisurely while cleverly missing Wen Jing and his deceased wife. This scene arrangement revealed a hint of thrilling and a hint of paradoxical absurdity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ed9007d788d0b02592c3f1a292fb9e63.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;453&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ed9007d788d0b02592c3f1a292fb9e63.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257927&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following plot , similar bizarre plots were staged one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blind Li Taijiang became more and more suspicious of the &quot;wife&quot; next to him, especially when he touched the latter&#39;s hands and face, he became more convinced of his suspicions and called an old friend to identify and confirm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My old friend didn’t take Li Taijiang’s suspicion seriously. Firstly, it was too outrageous to suddenly suspect that the person next to him was not his wife; secondly, Li Taijiang also suffered from Alzheimer&#39;s disease, and it was normal to be inaccurate in recognizing people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/b7e45b737e959efb6d8eb6dba6dda637.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/b7e45b737e959efb6d8eb6dba6dda637.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257932&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this premise Next, Wen Jing escaped another disaster. But can she always have good luck and survive until Li Taijiang&#39;s death, relying on her old mother&#39;s replacement? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ending was unexpected again. Li Taijiang suddenly came to his wife&#39;s room, strangled the sleeping &quot;wife&quot; by the throat, and eventually strangled her to death. He himself hanged himself in the bathroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sudden double death has already been explained clearly in Michael Haneke&#39;s masterpiece &quot;Amour&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/865919357072f605e6e51c99884b3b0f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/865919357072f605e6e51c99884b3b0f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257929&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old writers cannot Taking care of his deceased wife, he could not face the gradual dementia in his old age. In order to prevent the dignity of his life from collapse, he decided to die with his wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Taijiang never imagined until his death that his wife had already died in Wen Jing&#39;s hands; and what Wen Jing also didn&#39;t expect was that his old mother would become the hostess&#39;s &quot;scapegoat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gears of death did not stop. Wen Jing’s son, whom Wen Jing missed so much, was released from prison early. However, the latter and a group of teenagers came to the plastic greenhouse where they used to live, drinking and talking nonsense. What they didn&#39;t know was that there was a corpse hidden in the cabinet of the greenhouse. This corpse was Li Taijiang&#39;s late wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2969590142efb878d9fdebbe840a1fc6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2969590142efb878d9fdebbe840a1fc6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Jing came suddenly He went to the shed and planned to destroy the body and eliminate traces of it. Wen Jing&#39;s son and his friends hid in order to avoid Wen Jing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the gasoline was poured on the greenhouse, it quickly caught fire. Wen Jing finally breathed a sigh of relief. She thought that after destroying the evidence, she would be ushered in a new life, but what she didn&#39;t know was that her son was hiding inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title &quot;Plastic Greenhouse&quot; is very meaningful. On the surface, it points to the plastic greenhouse in the wasteland where Wen Jing ended up, but its deeper meaning is a mixture of Wen Jing&#39;s kindness and evil, her tragedy and the death she caused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/fc74edd0909394f1dafc9bf6d83a9c30.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/fc74edd0909394f1dafc9bf6d83a9c30.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257931&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first feature film The curtain is a plastic greenhouse in the dusk, like a huge coffin, making people unable to breathe. Crows flying through the sky add to the atmosphere of death, while the gloomy color of the sky makes it difficult to tell whether it is the morning light that symbolizes hope or the dark night that represents despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this plastic greenhouse, Wenjing accepted a girl with the same fate, Chunnan, and temporarily escaped the harm of her sexual predator; but it was also here that Wenjing tore away the scars of Chunnan’s past. , sprinkle salt on its wounds. Not to mention, Wen Jing hid and destroyed corpses in this greenhouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d39cd3457c0176fc3e5e0b374c75ffaf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;449&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d39cd3457c0176fc3e5e0b374c75ffaf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257930&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, Li Cangdong&#39;s &quot;Burning&quot; uses the action of the rich to &quot;burn down their warehouses&quot; to show the tragedy and anger of the lower class and the arrogance and indifference of the upper class. Then, in &quot;Plastic Shed&quot;, &quot;burning the barn&quot; is replaced with another symbolic meaning: the person in the film is driven by the subconscious to take revenge on the entire society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why it is said to be subconscious is that, as mentioned above, we have never seen Wen Jing&#39;s humble anger, nor have we glimpsed Li Taijiang&#39;s superiority. They are so harmonious that it is hard to believe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/131b5d3e8d52c620c2598b92b46145e5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/131b5d3e8d52c620c2598b92b46145e5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Plastic Greenhouse 》The most interesting part is this. It constantly uses editing techniques to cover up part of the truth and hide the true emotions of several characters, making us think about what caused this series of tragedies. We can only watch as the gears of their fate begin to turn and slide step by step into the abyss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This can&#39;t help but remind people of the Korean film &quot;The Next So Hee&quot; that caused a lot of discussion in the first half of the year. In this movie, how did So Hee, who was lively and optimistic by nature, lead to suicide step by step? This becomes the question that detective Wu Youzhen keeps searching for in the second half of the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the school where she graduated to the company where she worked, from her native family to the social environment, Wu Youzhen discovered that it was not a certain person who &quot;killed&quot; So Hee, but the entire Korean society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7ca121b2f95e1fa4be552b9b0d8e0e08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7ca121b2f95e1fa4be552b9b0d8e0e08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257934&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Plastic Greenhouse &quot;In &quot;Chun Nan&quot;, a mentally retarded girl was abandoned by her mother since she was a child. The inaction of welfare institutions left her pathologically dependent on sexual predators; the upper-class writer Li Taijiang gave up the desire to live due to the torture of the disease. Heading towards a tragic death; the heroine is quiet and simple, but she eventually becomes a murderer and destroys all traces of her body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These characters in the film obviously just long for a touch of warmth and freedom, but in the rigid system, their humanity is distorted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c6b5027565afc4d9f42fce6a3aa9060f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c6b5027565afc4d9f42fce6a3aa9060f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a new director Lee Sol Hee&#39;s debut film did not cause much response in South Korea. It only had a score of 7.1 on Douban and only a few viewers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But whether it is its completion or the expression of the theme, it is calm, powerful and well organized. In the generally sluggish momentum of Korean movies this year, it is a niche masterpiece that should not be missed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:25:14 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[裴宜理：研究中国革命，如此复杂，如此迷人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260431]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/i8KBYscFjFPs8YglDmRNV4A1OQY9MjMa33O656xl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/i8KBYscFjFPs8YglDmRNV4A1OQY9M jMa33O656xl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pei Yili looking at files in Jiangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（ Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among American scholars who study China, Elizabeth Perry has a special life experience: she was born in Shanghai in 1948, and her parents were both Shanghai Saints. Professor at John&#39;s University, but her family left China shortly after she was born due to changes in the current situation. She later joked that maybe she had been closely associated with the word &quot;revolution&quot; since she was born, so she has been interested in the Chinese revolution throughout her life. &quot;Without the revolution, I would probably have grown up in China. I have always been curious about the Chinese revolution, and wanted to know why the revolution happened and what consequences it would bring to China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili also spent his youth in China. She survived the surging global &quot;revolutionary&quot; wave of the left-wing movement, which further strengthened her future academic ambitions. After China&#39;s door opened, she became one of the first foreign scholars allowed to enter China for fieldwork and research. Her research interests mainly focus on modern popular resistance and grassroots politics, spanning the fields of political science and history. She has written Generous and award-winning, the American Historical Review commented that she &quot;combines a social scientist&#39;s love of order with a historian&#39;s eye for great stories.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili has taught at the University of Arizona, the University of Washington and the University of California, Berkeley. Since 1997, he has taught in the Department of Government of Harvard University. In addition to her teaching work, one of Pei Yili&#39;s greatest characteristics lies in her participation in public affairs. She once served as the director of the Fairbank Research Center at Harvard University and the president of the Association for Asian Studies. Since 2008, she has served as the president of the Harvard-Yenching Institute, cultivating a group of outstanding students and scholars for China studies. Our interview took place in the office of the Harvard-Yenching Institute. The office is small, and the black-and-white photos that mark important moments of this academic institution in the past century hung on the wall exude a deep sense of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Since I became president, I have spent half of my time at Harvard-Yenching Institute and the other half as a professor at Harvard.” Pei Yili is still active in teaching, every Wednesday at 1:30 p.m. At 3:30, she is open to students. Each student had to make an appointment with her in advance and explain their questions succinctly. After learning that she had given me more than three hours of interview time, her students all expressed their envy that I had such a &quot;luxury&quot; opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili has a hearty personality and is quick to talk. During the interview, he burst out laughing from time to time. Even if he fell into a gloomy look when recalling the twists and turns of his family&#39;s experiences, he would immediately ignore this emotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China has undergone too many changes in the past hundred years. This may be what attracts Pei Yili, a political scientist who studies China. &quot;Studying their successes and failures is exciting and fascinating.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/QbYnyZoZXxiMPOUMUeZHcmbriNWr2fsheyj1zA8Q. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/QbYnyZoZXxiMPOUMUeZHcmbriNWr2fsheyj1zA8Q.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pei Yili&#39;s parents&#39; wedding photo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Birth under revolutionary fire&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Were you born in China?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&quot;Why were you born in Red China?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the time I was a girl, for a long time, every time I followed the whole family back to the United States, whether at the airport or the dock, Immigration After the officer opened her passport, there was always a conversation like the one above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I would say that when I was born it was not red, just a little pink.” More than half a century later, Pei Yili was sitting in his office at the Harvard-Yenching Institute, recalling the past and couldn’t help but He let out a hearty laugh. Then, her expression became solemn. &quot;Yes, my parents both lived in troubled times in China; without the revolution, I would probably have grown up in China, so our family does have constant ties with China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili was born in a He has a strong religious family, and his parents are both missionaries of the Episcopal Church. Her father, Charles Perry - Pei Yili later learned that his Chinese name was Pan Xuesi - had studied Chinese and Japanese at Harvard University in his early years and had a special liking for East Asia. In 1931, Pan Xuesi traveled across the ocean and arrived in Shanghai to teach at St. John&#39;s University. St. John&#39;s University was founded in 1879, formerly known as St. John&#39;s College. It is sponsored by the Episcopal Church in the United States and is the earliest church university in China. After the September 18th Incident broke out, Pan Xuesi made a special trip to Northeast China. &quot;He also wrote a very interesting diary about his travel experience in Manchuria. He was very interested in this period of history.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Pan Xuesi met his future wife Kai Rui (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Note: the Chinese name is Kong Kaili&lt;/span>;) in China. Both later taught at St. John&#39;s University. Interestingly, Pei Yili never heard his parents communicate in Chinese when he was a child, &quot;because his father only knew Mandarin and his mother only knew Shanghainese.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mEjKBtDqsDC3yeb1YmoZRw1ZwdF5aOBW6lYCyaBM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;672&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/08/mEjKBtDqsDC3yeb1YmoZRw1ZwdF5aOBW6lYCyaBM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bae Yi-ri and her father as a girl&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili’s parents got married in the summer of 1937. Because Pan Xuesi has been interested in Japanese culture for a long time, he chose to go to Japan for his honeymoon. &quot;When they were on their honeymoon, they heard the news about Japan&#39;s invasion of China, but they didn&#39;t dare to confirm it, so they went to the U.S. Embassy in Tokyo to ask whether the rumors were true. The embassy staff may not want to take responsibility and did not tell them the truth. They just said : No, there is no problem in China now. You can go back to China! So they boarded the ship from Nagasaki back to Shanghai as originally planned.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili said that his father liked water sports when he was young and was very fond of boats. The performance is very clear. Not long after their ship left Japanese port, my father became acutely aware that something was not quite right. He said to his wife: &quot;Strange, why is the waterline of the ship so low?&quot; He ran to the bottom to find out what was going on, and found that the bottom was full of Japanese soldiers with live ammunition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the soldiers Pei Yili&#39;s parents met back then were the regiments that had been reinforced from Japan after the Battle of Songhu began - they had inadvertently become witnesses of history. As soon as these soldiers on the same ship arrived in Shanghai, they joined the war of aggression against China and became a link in the brutal machine. What awaited the young couple who returned from their honeymoon was Shanghai burned by the war. &quot;My mother later recalled that when the ship entered Shanghai, she could smell the smell of dead people everywhere. This was something she had never experienced...&quot; The parents returned to their residence at St. John&#39;s University and discovered that they were married. The chapel has been attacked by the Japanese army, the home has been ransacked, and all the wedding gifts have been stolen by Japanese soldiers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the current situation, the mother left Shanghai and returned to the United States for a while with her newborn son, while the father chose to stay at St. John&#39;s University. In 1941, the &quot;Pearl Harbor Incident&quot; broke out, the Japanese army invaded the concession, and Shanghai fell completely. Except for those who have returned to China, the rest of the foreign teachers at St. John&#39;s University were imprisoned in concentration camps, including Pei Yili&#39;s father. He was not released back to the United States until two years later when the U.S. and Japanese governments exchanged detainees. When his grandmother picked him up at the New York port, she could no longer recognize her emaciated son. But before long, Pan Xuesi hoped to return to China again. &quot;With the help of the U.S. Navy, he returned to China as he wished and helped the National Government fight the Japanese.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1945, after World War II ended, his mother also returned to China. For this family, this was a brief peaceful time in China - Pei Yili, who was born in Shanghai in September 1948, was the fruit of this life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1949, the Chinese Communist revolution had reached a decisive moment. &quot;My mother took me and my two brothers and left China first, but my father once again wanted to stay.&quot; A few months later, the situation became even more turbulent. Pan Xuesi had no choice but to bid farewell to the country where he had lived on and off for 18 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to the United States, Pan Xuesi returned to the university where he once studied and taught for several years, but the distant East has always been a place he has never forgotten. In 1951, their family moved to Tokyo, and Pan Xuesi taught at Rikkyo University, founded by the Anglican Church. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Thanksgiving night in 1959, the whole family was sitting together to eat and celebrate this traditional American holiday. Suddenly, they heard the dog barking in the yard. My father went out to check, but an accident happened unexpectedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two young Japanese students came in drunk. They both practiced karate... It only took a few minutes to beat my father to death... There was no plan to attack me. My father&#39;s, they were completely drunk at the time and didn&#39;t know who my father was.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This American, who had a strong interest and concern for the East throughout his life, ended his life in a sad way life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her father died, her mother used her understanding of the world to deal with the tragedy - although her way of handling it may not be understood by most people: instead of asking for a heavy sentence for the two Japanese students, she Instead, he interceded for them. As a result, one of them was released and the other was sentenced. During his sentence, his mother not only visited him frequently, but also went to the court to fight for a commutation of his sentence. The young man only stayed in prison for two or three years before regaining his freedom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother and her family lived in Japan for several more years until they returned to the United States in 1962. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/5p8loEN1xkHBDkKV03QuMmhVUAu8H61h4WBf7px0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/5p8loEN1xkHBDkKV03QuMmhVUAu8H61h4WBf7px0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1981, Pei Yili took a photo with the interviewee in Songjiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;Political Awareness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Popular protests were one of her later academic interests and directions. Her initial perceptual understanding of this came from her early experience in Japan. In the early 1950s, the Communist Party of Japan and the Socialist Party of Japan would organize labor protests every May Day. That day, Pei Yili&#39;s father happened to pass by. When the protesters saw the American, they started knocking on his car window. The car was surrounded by crowds... After his father returned home, his family found that almost all the car windows were broken, and The shocked father was almost shaking. After calming down, the father tried to explain to his daughter what &quot;May Day&quot; was and what those people were protesting... This made little Pei Yili become very interested in this form of popular protest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 11, 1960, nearly 6 million Japanese took to the streets to protest against the new Japan-US security treaty. The US Embassy in Japan was surrounded by nearly 200,000 Japanese protesters. Among this huge crowd of protesters was 12-year-old Pei Yili. She skipped school, took to the streets, and participated in demonstrations against the Japan-US security treaty. In Pei Yili&#39;s understanding, the essence of this event is not &quot;anti-American&quot; but in support of peace. &quot;People seem to be very happy to have an American child participating.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a sense, this is her The first time she participated in a &quot;mass movement&quot; was also the first time she experienced the power of mass movements - the bulletproof car in which the then US Ambassador to Japan Hagerty was also surrounded by demonstrators, and the ambassador himself had to sneak in through the back door. Eisenhower, who was scheduled to visit Japan on June 19, had to postpone his visit indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a child, Pei Yili also curiously observed that in some protests, the expressions of the people were very similar to the rituals of celebrating religious festivals. For example, during religious festivals in Japan - similar to China, people will take part in a procession with a sedan chair in which a god sits and then moves around in a kind of snake dance. &quot;I loved this kind of ritual, so I often attended Japanese folk festivals in our neighborhood. Part of my interest in political protest in Japan also came from this kind of folk ritual.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This early experience, later It became a unique perspective for her to observe political activities. For example, during her investigation into Anyuan, Jiangxi, one of the birthplaces of the Chinese revolution, she discovered how Li Lisan intelligently used traditional techniques to achieve the purpose of mobilizing workers to participate in the revolution: On May 1st, International Labor Day, Li Lisan organized a workers&#39; march. &quot;In the procession, there was a large sedan carried by eight people. Generally speaking, in this kind of local celebration, the sedans are carried by the gods of the earth and other folk religions, but this time, inside the sedan was a statue of Marx. Like.&quot; This detail was used by Pei Yili to analyze the relationship between national political mobilization and traditional culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1965, 16-year-old Pei Yili entered William Smith College. She was quickly thrust into another turbulent political environment. Pei Yili later concluded: &quot;Although my intuitive interest in popular protest comes from my experience in Japan, my left-wing thoughts come more from my college days.&quot; She was very active in college and participated in sailing clubs, drama clubs, Political Club...but &quot;politics&quot; was her more enduring interest and more devoted concern. She remembers riding the bus to Washington with college classmates to march in front of the Pentagon to protest the Vietnam War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also during this time that the seemingly weak connection between her and China, where she was born, became stronger in some way. William Smith College is small, but it has a &quot;Mao Zedong Thought Study Group&quot;, of which Pei Yili is a member. She studied Mao Zedong Thought with her classmates and developed a strong interest in Chinese politics. Soon, she became determined to learn Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there were no Chinese classes at her university, so she could only start learning Chinese by herself with the help of a tape recorder and a few tapes in the library. She asked the school if she could get credits for self-study in Chinese. The school’s answer: We don’t have Chinese classes, how can we evaluate your learning level and give you credits? Unwilling to give up easily, Pei Yili proposed to the school: &quot;If I learn by myself to a certain extent, I can ask a Cornell professor to test me. If I pass, can I get credits?&quot; The school had no choice but to agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pei Yili later contacted a professor at Cornell University, who said: You should study by yourself for three months through tapes and language books, and then come to Cornell to take my test. Three months later, Pei Yili successfully passed the exam. Interestingly, she later went to Taipei to study Chinese for a period of time. The Chinese teacher in Taipei grew up in Beijing. She was very surprised by the American student’s accent. One time she couldn’t help but ask: “Where does your accent come from?” Are you here? Is your teacher in the United States from the Northeast?&quot; &quot;I deny it. I want to say that my teacher is a &#39;recorder&#39; and not a Northeastern, but at that time I didn&#39;t know how to say the word &#39;recorder&#39;!&quot; Recalling this incident , Pei Yili was overjoyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese name &quot;Pei Yili&quot; was given while studying in Taipei. Much later, when she was looking at her father&#39;s book and saw the Chinese stamp on it, she discovered that her father&#39;s Chinese name was &quot;Pan Xuesi&quot;. &quot;So my surname should be Pan instead of Pei.&quot; Speaking of this matter, Pei Yili showed a trace of regret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WA5K5OwMwAXvSYgB2p4r65LJ0k64mD4kkdoi24OA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WA5K5OwMwAXvSYgB2p4r65LJ0k64mD4kkdoi24OA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pursuit The Origin of the Chinese Revolution&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When he was studying for a doctorate in political science at the University of Michigan, Pei Yili&#39;s original idea was to use China&#39;s &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; as the topic of his doctoral thesis, but he was opposed by a supervisor. The teacher thinks the time is not yet ripe. She instead determined to explore the origins of the Chinese revolution using perspectives and methods that were different from the prevailing views at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如何理解农民革命，这是一个被许多关注农民问题的各科学者所忽略的问题。”她解释自己的研究动机时说，“农民以革命的面目登上世界历史舞台这一事实，推动了许多试图解释农民叛乱原因的社会科学理论的发展。人类学家、历史学家、社会学家和政治学家都对这个重要问题提出了他们各自的答案。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时的裴宜理已经流露了自己的“学术野心”：她决定通过对一个地区的研究来考察造反者与革命者之间的关系。这一计划必须集中在一个地区，这个地区必须既有农民造反的传统，又是1949年前共产党的基地。她把这个地区选在淮北。淮北还曾是著名的白莲教活动中心，这一松散的民间宗教组织曾在该地区发动过多次叛乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时中国的大门仍是紧锁的，像其他学者一样，她当时的选择是赴台北故宫博物院看档案，期间也穿插着去日本，在东京的图书馆做资料收集工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我当时是那么年轻而天真，完全不知道这个选题的难度——不然我绝不会蠢到选择这个方向做论文。”又是一阵爽朗的大笑。虽然她幸运地得到很多人的帮助，包括同在那里做研究的几位美国历史学家给了她很多建议，密歇根大学另一位研究中国历史的著名学者费维恺（Albert Feuerwerker）教授也细心地告诉她明清各种档案的位置，但是，“我完全不知道关于这个问题的原始资料是如此分散，它们的类型如此不同。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个障碍是语言。虽然读研究生的时候，她系统学习了两年的中文，包括文言文，但她从来没有像那几位来自美国的历史学家那样，接受过专门的阅读清代文献的训练。所以当她第一次在台北故宫博物院看到清朝档案的时候，几乎被绝望的心情击垮：“我永远无法读懂这些档案！”导师在回信里以不容退缩的口气说：“你得完全做原始档案的研究，而且得看所有的东西。”裴宜理也知道，导师不懂文言文，对阅读梳理明清档案的难度毫无概念，但她还是听从了他的建议。这下没了退路。她发现真正投入进去后，竟然完全有能力阅读那些档案。 “我们当年在台北几乎可以看到你所知道的所有原始档案。比如，你可以拿着两广总督给咸丰写的奏折，上面有咸丰皇帝的批示&#39;知道了&#39;。当你有这种感受的时候，档案内容再晦涩也无关紧要了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;靠着扎扎实实的工作，裴宜理完成了她的博士论文。 1980年，以论文为基础的专著《华北的叛乱者与革命者》在斯坦福大学出版。这部专著被视为海外中国研究第三代学者的代表作。裴宜理将自己的第一本书献给父母，“没有他们，我就不会从事中国研究。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDBAeBrYfBKDdVmYZ9OQbRemzezD2UyCKWonhdJJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDBAeBrYfBKDdVmYZ9OQbRemzezD2UyCKWonhdJJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;重返中国&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“你是在中国出生的？”每次回到美国，入关时的盘问一度让裴宜理感觉自己是一个“二等美国人”。这个场景直到1972年——也就是尼克松总统访华那年——之后才发生了突变。裴宜理记得非常清楚，那一年她从日本旅行回来，入关美国时，像往常一样，移民局官员打开护照，不出意料地问了这一句，裴宜理照例予以肯定的回答。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我在等待下一个问题：&#39;你为什么出生在红色中国？但没想到，这一次对方的反应是：&#39;噢，真了不起！那你会说中文吗？&#39;我说：&#39;是的，我会说一点。&#39;他说：&#39;我们国家需要你这样的人。&#39;那是我第一次为我出生于中国这件事感到高兴。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美关系解冻后，美中关系协会全国委员会（National Committee on Us-China Relations）开始陆陆续续派代表团访问中国，每个团都挑选一位研究中国的学者陪同，以帮助成员们理解中国。 1979年6月，裴宜理被选中参加美国的大城市市长代表团，访问上海、北京、南京、广州和杭州等城市，亲眼看到了长城、故宫、西湖……她兴奋无比。 “我每天早早起床，去公园和当地老百姓交谈，我很喜欢这种感觉，”但另一方面，她又觉得她所看到的中国，不是之前充满革命浪漫想象的那个中国。裴宜理还去上海找到了他们当年在圣约翰大学的老房子，拍了很多校园的照片，带回美国给母亲看。不出意外，母亲在格外震惊之余也格外伤心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几个月后，裴宜理再次来到中国，这一次她的身份是访问学者，获得了在华学习一年的机会——她也是第一批被允许进入中国进行田野调查研究的外国学者之一，与她同时来中国的学者还有周锡瑞和黄宗智，后来都成为海外中国研究的中坚力量。她也经历了计划经济下的“票证年代”，“我们互相之间以同志相称，还在学术问题、政治问题的争论中经常引用毛主席语录。”但在革命热潮的背后，她渐渐发现了另一个侧面。比如，作为外国人，她可以坐软卧，普通中国人享受不到；对外营业的餐馆非常少，但像她这样的“访问学者”可以在餐馆的特别区域享受“特供”，普通中国人享受不到，也支付不起。 1980年春天，在南京大学蔡少卿教授的陪同下，裴宜理第一次去安徽调查，在涡阳与蒙城的实地探访，让她对中国农村的真实生活有了更为切身的感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一年，裴宜理来上海开会时遇到了时任上海社科院院长张仲礼——张早年毕业于圣约翰大学，碰巧是她父亲当年的学生。见面后，他们互相介绍自己正在进行的工作。听到裴宜理下一本书的工作计划之后，张仲礼打趣说：“你是上海人——我很多年前就看到你爸爸在校园里抱着你的样子。为什么不写上海的故事？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张仲礼的建议下，自1990年代起，裴宜理的研究目光从遥远的淮北农村转向世界大都会上海，研究重点也从农民革命问题研究变为工人运动研究。她完成了专著《上海罢工：中国工人政治研究》，在这本书里，她也用不少笔墨写了杜月笙、黄金荣这些我们并不陌生的人物，挖掘了他们在工人运动中所扮演的一些真实的角色。这本书获得了1993年美国历史学会费正清奖。 《美国历史评论》评价她兼具“社会科学家对秩序的热爱”与“历史学家捕捉精彩故事的眼睛”。在写这本书时，裴宜理对涉及的劳工阶层做了详尽的调查和分析，其中也包括英美烟草公司。快要结束这本书时，她突然意识到，英美烟草公司在浦东的工厂，就是父亲当年被关押的集中营。 “我没想到，我所研究的对象在某种程度上与我自己家族的历史有非常密切的联系。所以我后来在《上海罢工》英文版序言里的第一句话写道：&#39;对我来说，写作本书有一种回家的感觉。&#39;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nmo7yEYcHen9ErQmaxrlIictm9QBHdxe28utFf3H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nmo7yEYcHen9ErQmaxrlIictm9QBHdxe28utFf3H.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;裴宜理与南京大学教授周晓虹在安徽历史博物馆参观&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不能忘记“大问题”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;实际上，无论是早期对农民革命的兴趣，还是后来转向对城市工人运动的研究，那些改变了无数人命运的革命，始终是裴宜理关注的大问题。著名历史学家周锡瑞在接受采访时，提过这样一个细节：2007年，裴宜理当选亚洲研究学会主席发表演讲时说，“我们不能忘记中国革命，不能忘记这些大题目，不能忘记如何来理解中国这个大转变到底是怎么发生的。”周锡瑞后来将自己的一本专著送给裴宜理，请她提意见。裴宜理回信给他，再一次说：“我们应该多思考中国的大问题。”——这其实既是裴宜理对同时代做中国研究的学者的期待，也是她对自己时时刻刻的告诫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了学术研究，裴宜理还积极参与公共事务和社会活动。 1999年，到哈佛大学不久，裴宜理即出任海外中国学研究重镇费正清中国研究中心（Fairbank Center for China Studies）的主任。在她名字之前，是费正清、史华慈、孔飞力、傅高义等一系列著名学者；自2008年起，裴宜理又成为另一个分量颇重的学术机构的掌门人——哈佛燕京学社社长。作为最著名的中西学术交流机构之一，哈佛燕京自1928年创立以来已经历了七任社长，从叶理绥、赖肖尔到杜维明等，每一任都是德高望重的学者。裴宜理在学界的地位和影响力可见一斑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;裴宜理的研究重点是“中国革命”，这在西方的中国研究学界也许有点“非主流”。所以她当选后面对记者的采访，也有感而发：“在很长一段时间里，美国专门研究中国革命的只有区区十几人。这几年，研究中国革命的人又多了起来，毛泽东、&#39;大跃进&#39;、&#39;文革&#39;、抗日战争……都成了热门。”她打趣说：“否则，像我这种研究冷僻课题的家伙估计成不了哈佛燕京的新社长！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美大门打开、中国重新融入世界大家庭之后，商业和经济上的复兴与繁荣或许是最显性最直接的成果。但裴宜理感受更多的，是它在知识与学术交流上产生的巨大意义。过去的一个多世纪，从大清帝国时期到中华民国时期、再进入中华人民共和国，这块土地上发生了太多太大的变化，这或许正是吸引裴宜理研究中国的地方，“它们是如此复杂，又是如此迷人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陕西回应强砍国槐树事件：属违规占用永久基本农田]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260438]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 19:24:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;针对网传“陕西丹凤县强砍3万多棵国槐树”一事，当地已成立由县农业农村局、县资源局、县林业局等单位组成的调查组实地调查。丹凤县有关部门11月11日发布调查结果如下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经查，反映问题地点位于丹凤县蔡川镇太子庙村。 2023年7月3日，蔡川镇接到丹凤县田长办《永久基本农田疑似图斑问题整改交办单》，反馈太子庙村3个卫星图斑疑似违法占用永久基本农田，要求限期整改。经实地调查，反馈图斑涉及的耕地上栽种有核桃树、国槐，确属违规占用永久基本农田。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接到整改通知后，镇村工作人员多次向涉及群众宣讲耕地保护政策，动员配合支持耕地保护工作，并根据《土地管理法》《基本农田保护条例》法律法规，当场下发限期整改通知书，其中3名群众拒绝限期整改。随后，镇村干部多次到地块实地查看，帮助对接销售，减少群众损失，但因其栽种苗木密度过大，且大面积形成干腐病，无企业采购。之后，镇村干部多次上门沟通未果，上述3名群众拒绝限期整改。 11月2日，蔡川镇政府会同县农业执法大队，对在永久基本农田上违规种植的核桃树、国槐苗木进行清除复耕。因在涉及地块上种植苗木属违法违规占用永久基本农田，不涉及赔偿事项。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[台剧这十年，内卷+外卷]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260427]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;在10月底落幕的第58届金钟奖上，可以看到台剧神仙打架的盛状：《模仿犯》《她和她的她》《村里来了个暴走女外科》……精品众多，竞争激烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，台剧自2019年以来就呈现出全面复兴、类型多元的态势，彻底逆转了2010年左右因偶像剧衰落所致的颓势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它是如何走出如今的新格局？今天，我们就来一起聊聊台剧这十年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;内卷：老牌电视人的自救&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在很多观众心中，台剧一度与“偶像剧”划等号。千禧年后，《流星花园》《王子变青蛙》《恶作剧之吻》《公主小妹》《命中注定我爱你》等青春洋溢的偶像剧霸屏播出，土中带甜的纯情梦幻风格捕获了一众年轻观众的心，也成为许多人的青春回忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e295fca9ac060796c53c5306d316b9c6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e295fca9ac060796c53c5306d316b9c6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5d3af5f82213fe907ee7f9bbcd2a0d63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;769&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5d3af5f82213fe907ee7f9bbcd2a0d63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但好景维持了不到十年，随着内容的复制粘贴与观众的审美疲劳，台剧走向了低迷沉郁期。偶像剧拍不出新意，乡土剧留不住观众，再加上人才外流，台剧呈岌岌可危之势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，知名电视人王小棣联合蔡明亮、陈玉勋、瞿友宁在内的8名导演成立公司，发起了“植剧场”与“QPlace”计划，意在打造平台，“给予有想法的编剧、演员、导演与后制人员一个得以滋养与发挥的空间。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“植剧场”主要分为爱情成长、惊悚推理、恐怖灵异、戏剧改编四个板块，《恋爱沙尘暴》《荼靡》《天黑请闭眼》《花甲男孩转大人》等剧集打响了台剧革新的第一枪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《荼蘼》脱胎于偶像爱情剧，混搭平行时空的元素探讨爱情故事的不同走向，在2016年的时间节点上确有新意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/6b932ede0feef3a482a4e13ed7afbe8a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;483&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/6b932ede0feef3a482a4e13ed7afbe8a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《花甲男孩转大人》和《恋爱沙尘暴》根植于家庭剧，主打以情动人的日常风，少了《台湾阿诚》《意难忘》式的抓马，多了生活流的温馨。在动辄40集、200集的传统台剧面前，“植剧场”的小体量短剧模式，显得浓缩皆是精华。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/16852e4bffbe38ab732831c217b55e53.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/16852e4bffbe38ab732831c217b55e53.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“植剧场”采用明星带新星模式，启用吴慷仁、杨丞琳、蓝正龙等知名演员，带着他们挖掘的新人一道演戏。如今已星光闪耀的许光汉（《想见你》）、刘冠廷（《火神的眼泪》），以及逐渐在新生代里站稳脚跟的孙可芳（《孤味》）、陈妤（《我们与恶的距离》）等人，都是在这种模式中成长起来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2e0c16691b6093f7b15be2265ca265be.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2e0c16691b6093f7b15be2265ca265be.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，“植剧场”升级为“茁剧场”，在原类型剧上加入报告文学与人物传记，筹划拍摄《滴水的推理书屋》《绿岛金魂》《走过爱的蛮荒》《谁说妈妈像月亮》等剧集。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，老牌电视台也蓄势而发，推动传统题材剧的纵深发展。公视的《一把青》（2015）改编自白先勇的同名短篇小说，由导演编剧修建枝蔓、填补血肉，飞行员家属村的爱恨纠葛折射出时代痼疾，谱写了一曲荡气回肠、哀婉动人的年代往事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ae351f9ce4641ad0c32041c414a1a9e9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ae351f9ce4641ad0c32041c414a1a9e9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;华视的《俗女养成记》（2019），创下近十年来华视自制剧的最佳成绩。它并置了台北与台南的空间、童年与中年的时间，聚焦于40岁女性的人生选择，完美击中在都市漂泊自嘲为“loser”的观剧群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5ebcc3d9264824785423719cc3e03b8e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5ebcc3d9264824785423719cc3e03b8e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TVBS的原创剧集《有生之年》（2023）被称为“男版《俗女》”，讲述了一个失败的中年男子决定去死的故事，治愈暖心，还切合了全职儿女、中年失业等共鸣性社会议题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/36149784d72d77a2281adf518c4ea3b1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/36149784d72d77a2281adf518c4ea3b1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;外卷：流媒体平台的业务拓展&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;本土发力形成了良性竞争，而向外的业务拓展为则台剧带来了新动能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，HBO、Netflix、Disney等均大力拓荒海外业务，台湾成为了合拍华语剧的首选地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外国流媒体带来的是工业化拍摄模式，快节奏、短剧集、前两集高投资吸引人的美剧风吹到了台湾。用制片人刘瑜萱的话来讲，和成熟的工业模式相比，之前拍剧的方式无异于“土法炼钢”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HBO是首个在台湾吃螃蟹的流媒体。 2017年它与公视合作了《通灵少女》，这部融合奇幻灵异和少女成长元素的剧集创下了收视奇迹。 2019年双方再度联手，打造扎根现实主义的《我们与恶的距离》，这部从不同立场讨论无差别杀人案的剧集成为了年度爆款。 2020年，底层平民题材的剧集《做工的人》再度掀起热潮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c1cbbc89cd33f8cfc37e9d9dfa82c785.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c1cbbc89cd33f8cfc37e9d9dfa82c785.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257943&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netflix于2018年推出《你的孩子不是你的孩子》，对东亚教育问题的深入探讨在播出后引发广泛共鸣。 2019年的《罪梦者》、2020年的《谁是被害者》和2023年的《模仿犯》则主打大尺度悬疑，剧集品质不是一流，但热度与话题度齐飞。 2021-2022年的《华灯初上》较好地完成了群像塑造，复古的年代质感和厚重的人生悲剧使其不同于普通奇情剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab84f678d8ad4eaa60683992f4a3587a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab84f678d8ad4eaa60683992f4a3587a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257944&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FOX提供技术支持的《想见你》是近年来的现象级爆剧，且长尾效应显著，不仅让许光汉跻身一线，还衍生了同名电影。倘若拆解来看，它是在校园台偶剧的基础上做了加法，丝滑地融合了平行时空的奇幻元素，给人耳目一新之感。当然，看到最后，莫比乌斯环一般的叙事线索已经不重要，其底牌仍是擅长以细腻感情动人的本土优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3555ee32ddb4ce49a0018ec6cd3a0c58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;635&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3555ee32ddb4ce49a0018ec6cd3a0c58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外国流媒体在题材选择上偏向于类型融合，有时会有堆砌热门元素之感，如集悬疑、犯罪、灵异于一体的《罪梦者》不乏网络热传的高光桥段，但整部剧看下来劳累且混乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/616c2deebca29768dc10519ee6e576f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/616c2deebca29768dc10519ee6e576f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257947&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;筹备阶段往往是大数据为主导，所以有自以为踩中high点实则不然的黑帮梦幻偶像剧《极道千金》、中西灵异混搭剧《彼岸之嫁》、黑暗悬疑邪教家庭剧《谁在你身边》等不太成功的尝试。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e56bf0fe61d21154e84e13e494dd430e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e56bf0fe61d21154e84e13e494dd430e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观察合拍剧的爆款不难发现：它们皆是较凸显在地元素的剧集，如《我们与恶的距离》改编自台湾社会真实案件，《华灯初上》则触及了日殖时期以后台湾特殊的条通文化。如何在中西文化交手时尽可能地发挥所长，是参与合拍的台湾电视人需考虑的重点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab1939a869b6f7561f2e39b29513e610.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;605&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab1939a869b6f7561f2e39b29513e610.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/4f83e45663cf1e49c4b04bf40c3a2a35.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/4f83e45663cf1e49c4b04bf40c3a2a35.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除此之外，腾讯、爱奇艺等视频平台也积极开展“出海”策略，向亚洲地区投拍影视剧，文化上同根同源且拥有成熟影视链的台湾无疑占据合作的先机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大陆视频平台给台湾带来的是产业化行销模式，不会太干预其剧集创作，剧集在视频平台同步播出，引发两岸同追剧的热潮。平台精心挑选有潜质的台湾省新艺人，帮助其拓展岛外业务，似有捧出华语新偶像的计划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;腾讯WeTV推出的《永远的第一名》《第二名的逆袭》是同性题材的标杆。姜瑞智与林子闳等年轻艺人也因此获得了极大关注度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爱奇艺国际站涉及的类型更多，既有禁忌师生恋题材的《第九节课》，揭露暗网的悬疑犯罪剧《逆局》，还有凸显兄弟CP的灵异奇幻都市剧《不良执念清除师》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;剧集热播后，老牌男神周渝民再度翻红，新晋小生曾敬骅、陈昊森在《刻在你心底的名字》后各自拥有了代表作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5482da2c9b92aa2cb3d50b61c64e7a8b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5482da2c9b92aa2cb3d50b61c64e7a8b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257948&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体而论，台剧复兴是多方合力的结果，内部在不断推陈出新，外部也伸来了机会的橄榄枝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也使得近年来观看台剧的观众节节攀升，优质台湾艺人的待播剧也往往被高看一眼，寄予更多期待，这便是良性循环的嘉奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而当这些优质台剧卷至内娱，我们又该交出一份怎样的答卷呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“上岸”成了年轻人的执念？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;2023年武汉市文联所属事业单位芳草杂志社公布了专项招聘名单，青年作家班宇、陈春成、王苏辛、淡豹（刘雪婷）在列。“作家考编”再次引发网友“宇宙的尽头是考编”的感叹。 近年来，随着考编考研报名人数的持续上升，“上岸”这个词也总被年轻人挂在嘴边。</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她年少成名，十四年后拍出新片再得大奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260408]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年8月底，为了电影《不虚此行》的宣传，导演刘伽茵第一次注册了微博。为了学会如何熟练使用，她还特别请一位朋友在线教学，写出了第一条推文，并忐忑地给片方账号留言：“我好像#（标记）错了内容，怎么和你们的不一样？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《不虚此行》是刘伽茵的第三部长片，但她却说“某种程度上，这部才是我的处女作”。这部电影是她第一次与专业演员和摄制团队合作，需要进行大量的沟通工作，性格内向的刘伽茵需要踏出全新的一步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JOgJRXabKSXRlbZ1QshfSkuDgbg7YvsEQMbBRIbh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JOgJRXabKSXRlbZ1QshfSkuDgbg7YvsEQMbBRIbh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年，导演刘伽茵时隔十四年推出了她的电影长片新作《不虚此行》。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘伽茵是北京电影学院文学系的老师，从教十七年来她经常被同事和学生问同样的问题：“什么时候再拍电影？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一定程度上，刘伽茵算得上年少成名，研究生一年级，刚刚24岁的她就凭借DV拍摄的长片《牛皮》获得柏林电影节青年论坛单元的重要奖项。28岁，她又因为《牛皮2》入围戛纳电影节导演双周单元，成为国际影坛十分关注的青年导演。但此后十四年，因为各种各样的原因，她再无新片推出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“周围的人都在问，为什么不拍了？压力带来的动力是巨大的。”刘伽茵说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在前两部电影中，刘伽茵几乎一人包办了剧组所有事务，她是导演、编剧和摄影，也是制片和主演。“当时是DV的时代，特别感谢这个时期，我绝对是它的受益人，这种设备非常适合我&#39;一个人闷头干&#39;的性格。”刘伽茵回忆道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，刘伽茵开始正式创作《不虚此行》的剧本，最终完成的版本长达六万多字，比一般剧本篇幅的两倍还多。刘伽茵还为剧本里的人物创作了一部十多万字的小说，更加详细地描写了小说主人公闻善的生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初《不虚此行》的片名是“倾听”，既因为片中闻善的工作需要倾听来完成，也源于刘伽茵在生活中的感悟，“倾听不是听见，而是要理解对方，学会站在对方的立场上去思考”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《不虚此行》的主人公闻善是一个失意的编剧，他因为写不出甲方需要的故事放弃了原本的行当，阴差阳错成了一个写悼词的人。这份新职业需要他学会倾听他人的故事，并且还原生者对逝者的情感，他自己的人生也因此有了转机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每接到一单，闻善都会走访逝者生前的亲友，并做大量笔记，尽可能了解逝者。他采访过心疼哥哥总是充当“老好人”，直到其去世还不能释怀的妹妹；遇到过忙于工作，老父亲健在时疏于沟通，只能抱憾余生的儿子；也结识了千里迢迢从甘肃到北京探寻去世网友真实状态的执著女孩……在闻善的众多客户中，还有一位早早为自己预订悼词的癌症患者方阿姨——在得知自己罹患癌症后，她选择积极地“向死而生”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这份工作中，闻善治愈了客户，也治愈了自己。主演胡歌告诉南方周末记者，闻善所做的工作在于影响他人，“以逝者滋养生者”，让活着的人感受人生的意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片最后，闻善终于有勇气面对曾经的失败，他又可以面对曾经那个怎么也完成不了的剧本，写出自己相信的人物。“最重要的是，生活认可了闻善。”刘伽茵说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年6月，第25届上海国际电影节将最佳导演奖颁给了刘伽茵，她再度获得A类电影节的肯定。9月，《不虚此行》正式上映，这是刘伽茵第一部公映的电影。电影上映后，她的微博真的起到了“倾听”的作用，她收到了来自观众的好几百封私信，人们将自己的观影感受以文字形式分享给导演，倾吐内心对亲朋深藏的情感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3xag3euF7p72ekhzeSAG05CHQ01sjah9F058FATw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3xag3euF7p72ekhzeSAG05CHQ01sjah9F058FATw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;执导新片过程中，倾听与合作对刘伽茵（右二）有了新的意义。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一对年近七旬的老年姐妹，分别罹患肺癌和乳腺癌，一边积极治疗互相鼓励，一边陪伴95岁的母亲终老。姐姐在看过四遍《不虚此行》后在私信里写道：“我们为母亲写悼词，但在她面前羞于表达爱；与闻善一样，落魄时迷茫自卑，又挣扎不甘……你的故事让我们看到自己。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有位年轻的女孩分享了自己的故事，她母亲饱受癌症折磨长达八年后离世。“如果妈妈也能将她短短一生的痕迹留在纸上就好了，我也是一名电影工作者，希望有一天我能够让妈妈的故事被好好记录下来……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分享的人里有后悔在奶奶生前过于叛逆的，有没赶上见亲人最后一面的，还有因为这部电影和家人打开心结的……这些故事纷纷飞进刘伽茵的信箱，她会在工作的间隙尽量一一回复。“这些陌生人给了我很大的鼓励，这才是电影最有意义的部分。”刘伽茵说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“非常具体的恐惧”带来巨大的创作动力&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你最初拍电影，选择一个人把所有的事情都做了，这种方式似乎不是很常见？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果是以前那种电影机器，我不见得付得起那个钱，也不懂得如何和别人合作。我当时用的是一台DV机，那时候用这样一种特殊的方式拍电影，还是会有很多质疑的声音。所以我就选择不去听，觉得自己做出来就行。我是在30岁之后慢慢成长的，开始学习如何去沟通。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《不虚此行》最早的名字就是“倾听”，你是怎么理解这个命名的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我工作后慢慢发现生活里真的需要去听，听不是听见，而是要真正地了解对方。我在生活中不但被人误解，也会误解别人。在一次次发生这样的事情后，需要不断地校正自己对别人的看法，这些都需要去倾听。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;很多人可能都会关心在《牛皮》之后，为什么隔了十四年才拍电影，又为什么是这部《不虚此行》？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我本身不是做事特别快的人，有自己的节奏，可能也没有等到自己特别想要讲的故事。日常生活每天遇到的事情都很具体，也有一些收获和乐趣，我就多了很多“借口”先不创作了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来有了闻善这个角色的雏形，中间又花了好几年时间。当时这个角色还没有名字，但我感到他经常出现在我的生活里，甚至房间里，我会老是想起他，于是我给他起了一个名字，下定决心写出他的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你之前的两部电影和你本人的生活是很接近的，你和家人都直接出镜了，《不虚此行》是一部完全虚构的片子，它和你本人生活的关联是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;之前的创作还是比较有实验性的，《不虚此行》方方面面都不太一样，它一定程度上是我的处女作。但是这部电影和我个人的经验还是有非常大的关联，是我前面十多年生活的总结，我想说的东西都在里面了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;回望这十多年，你觉得自己的变化是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;拍《牛皮》那时候年龄小，一咬牙就把片子拍了，现在心态更复杂，需要更大的驱动力，也会更理性一些。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很久不拍电影，大概率来说就不会再拍了，但我几乎没有停止思考这件事。随着年纪增长，我意识到时间是有限的，也会因此恐惧，再不做一些事情，我都能预测以后的样子，这是一个非常具体的恐惧，也因此带来了巨大的动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从2006年至今，你做了十七年大学老师，教学的经验对你有什么影响？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;想要把课上好，我就必须了解我的学生。这个过程对我并不算特别容易，尤其是我非常不擅长和人交往，每到新学期推开门认识新的学生，我都需要做心理建设。但我教的就是如何写故事，必须知道学生们为何写这样的东西，不能只是简单地说好不好，需要通过故事去了解他们。经过慢慢调整，我才大概知道要用什么样的方式去表达，尽可能照顾到每一位学生。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“认真生活就能找到答案”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;闻善工作中需要接触各种各样的人，电影里出现了他的几位顾客，都有各自的故事，这些人物有生活原型吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没有什么原型，主要源于日常对生活的观察以及编剧的功底，一个编剧就是应该写得让人相信。其实我也没有什么创作技巧，就是认真地生活。委托人的故事，每个人的年龄、与离世亲友的关系、对情感的理解都不太一样，和我们在生活中遇到的情况差不多。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;闻善无法做一个好编剧，你觉得问题卡在哪里？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;人有天性的部分，再加上从小到大的经历，它们一起塑造了我们，让我们变成今天的样子。我觉得闻善在之前的编剧工作中遭遇了太多次否定，被认为写的东西太普通，不够这样，不够那样，总而言之就是他写的那些人物“不配”做主角。闻善经过一次次的否定，渐渐就会怀疑自己。尤其是毕业几年后，还是交不上房租，要开口问父母要的时候，这种感觉是非常艰难的。这种失败感，不仅仅是否定工作，也是否定了价值观，会觉得“我看待生活的方式是不是不对”？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想闻善不是没有试图维护过自己，但是他的声音太小了，在这种情况下，人的性格也会改变。但某种程度上，一个编剧没有维护自己的故事就是没有维护自己。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你认为生活最终认可了闻善，具体是什么样的认可？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;写悼词之后，他发现之前被否定的东西在生活里找到了答案。我们是可以被一些小事情影响的，也可以和其他人建立真正的联系，这些人不是剧本里那些非常具有戏剧性的人，就是普通到不起眼的人，但他们对身边的人非常重要，对他们自己也是很重要的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这之后，闻善还是会继续写故事，不再会有心中的障碍了。我们很多时候也会这样，总是被一些看不见摸不着的东西困扰，但我确信只要认真生活就能找到答案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你希望通过这部电影让观众看到什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对于大部分人来说，否定自己比肯定自己要容易得多，这可能就是成年人的生活。但人最终还是要在乎自己。《不虚此行》讲的就是闻善开始在乎自己的过程，他意识到，自己的感受，所做的事情都是重要的。这或许也是很多观众给我留言说在电影里看到自己的原因。看完这部电影完全无感的人是幸运的人，因为这部电影里没有一个真正顺利的人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《不虚此行》的出现，能够一定程度上解决你此前的一些生命困惑吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘伽茵：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得是我解决了这些困惑，才有了这部电影。换句话说，认识自己之后，更要接受自己。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[担心被称“普信”，不敢接触异性：一位大学老师对男生女生的观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近期一个周五，下午两点半，在广州大学停车场停好车，我发现操场上有两个男生在打球，这么早居然来打球，好奇心驱使我凑了过去。我和他们一边投球，一边聊天。他们是来自外语学院的大一新生，不仅是同班同学，还是湛江老乡。恰逢周五下午没课，也没有作业，闲得无聊，就相约打会儿篮球。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;男女泾渭分明&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我一边走一边问他们班有多少人，他们答复我女生34个，男生5个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“怎么没有想着约班上的女同学外出游玩？”我随口一问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于我的建议，他们颇感诧异：“老师，班上的女生，我一个也不认识。”“老师，我认识我们班两个女生，但让我约她们玩，这绝对没有可能。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“34个女生，你们俩加了多少人的微信呢？”我接着问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我加了5个，但不怎么联系的。”同学A说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“3个，且都是班上的干部，但只是有事时才联系一下。”同学B答复我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你们现在是大一的，应该课程不少吧，应该有很多一起上课的机会啊。”我继续追问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对啊，我们几乎天天一起上课，问题是上课虽在一个教室，但男生与男生坐一起，女生与女生坐一起，上课主要听老师讲课；下课了，就各自散，相互之间很少交流与互动。”同学A说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无论男生女生，大家都刻意保持距离，大家都默认一进教室，就男女生分开坐。”同学B补充说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，大学生应该有相对自由的支配时间，身体与心理发育已经成熟，对异性的交往需求相对旺盛，与异性拍拖、谈朋友是再正常不过的事，但现实并非如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个班的同学虽然可以天天见面，有不少的接触机会，但有接触机会不必然意味着现实生活中就一定发生了实质性的熟悉、认识与了解，其中的“梗”在哪里？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;见我一脸的疑惑，同学B向我说出了事情的原委，“老师，你听过一些网络热词吗，譬如&#39;舔狗&#39;&#39;下头&#39;&#39;普信&#39;？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经他一番解释，我才明白，男女生之间，主动提出加对方微信或索要对方联系方式的一方会被少部分异性认为是“舔狗”“下头”，这种情况之于主动的男生而言相对多一些。换言之，一个男生面对自己感兴趣的或觉得有趣的女生，主动提出加好友，部分女生会觉得这是一个奇怪的事，“你想干嘛呢”“你有什么企图”“你是想追我吗”，倘男生不是女生看对眼的人，女生会觉得男生“普信”，意指“普通但自信”。问题还在于部分女生或许不这么想，但男生为了规避女生这样想，不想自己被误会，不想背负“普信男”的污名化标签，宁愿或干脆不积极、不主动，以免尴尬，哪怕面对再心动或再心仪的女生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“老师知道&#39;校园墙&#39;吗？”同学A问我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我当然不知，他这样给我解释：“就是一个供同学发布信息的公共平台，好像每个高校都有。打个比方，一旦我加人家，被拒，人家把我加人家的截图发上&#39;校园墙&#39;，那样全校学生都知道我了，我在学校就斯文扫地，抬不起头了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我没办法控制对方的思维、想法和举动，我更加没办法面对与规避这种风险的发生，所以我不会做主动亲近异性的事。”同学B无奈地说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;无形的墙&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这令我想起：一年前一次与大四毕业班的几个男生打球，他们告诉我，四年了，他们都认不全一个班的同学，或叫不清同班同学的名字，一个班或一个专业的异性学生，在他们眼里，仅仅是“同班同学”而已，而非“朋友”“密友”“闺蜜”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据我的观察，一个基本的感觉是，当下大学生同专业或同班同学之间尤其是异性之间的友情或情谊非常淡薄，他们要么各自忙，要么各自闲，各忙各的，或各闲各的，哪怕有可能对某个异性同学有好感，也断然不会主动或积极地表达交友或交往的需求或意愿。换言之，进大学之后，男生与女生之间，突然出现一堵“无形的心墙”，这堵墙禁锢着少男少女，谁都不想主动拆掉这堵墙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进大学之前当然是高中，高中时期的同班同学关系普遍很好，天天朝夕相处，一起讨论做题，一起玩娱解压，男生递个暧昧的纸条给心仪的女生，女生多看几眼心仪的男生，下晚自习在校门口某个角落见面约着一起回家，激动的时候牵牵对方的手，给对方以温暖、力量或鼓励，这是多么正常的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我的大学时代&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我不禁想起我的大学生涯，那是1997-2001年。军训结束后第一周的第一次上课，班主任老师花了整整两节课的时间让每位同学上讲台做了自我介绍，然后大家一起去校门口一家餐厅共进午餐，彼此迅速熟络起来。男生女生约着一起晨读、早餐、上课；晚饭后，大家一起上晚自习，下自习后就在学校一条宽阔的马路打上一小时的羽毛球。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候的公开示爱，也是极其常见的事。对于心仪的异性，大方开朗的人就直抒胸臆，“我可以约你看电影吗”；腼腆内敛的人则托个中间人做媒，通过小纸条或信件的方式表达约会的意愿。如果两个人一起吃了饭，看了电影（通常是通宵电影），然后牵了手，那基本上就宣告“亲密的男女关系”基本确立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;换言之，喜欢谁，中意谁，表达这种情绪或情愫，是很正常的事。我记得很清楚，我们班共计42人，男生22，女生20，大四毕业那会儿有多达5对情侣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;关切当代大学生的价值观及真实心理&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当下的男生普遍对恋爱没有兴趣，不想认识与了解女生吗？抑或相反，当下的女生普遍对恋爱没有兴趣，不想认识与了解男生吗？我感觉都不是。面对就业压力普遍大的整体环境，一些人从大一就开始紧张起来，忙碌于考研、考公、大学英语四六级、驾驶证、教师资格证等，但在“日理万机”之余，他们的内心还是有孤寂或孤独的时候，他们也渴望邂逅或拥有一份唯美的爱情，问题是谁都不想被认为是“舔狗族”“下头族”或“普信族”，谁都不想主动出击去接触与了解异性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当代大学生与同班同学相对生疏，那么，他们与谁相对熟稔呢？据了解，相对于上公共课或专业课的同学，他们与有相同或相似兴趣或爱好的人熟络起来更容易一些。打个比方，街舞社团、文学社团、篮球社团、戏曲社团等社团内部的同学关系，要亲密过上同一门专业课的同班同学。究其原因，各类社团更吻合同学们的兴趣或爱好，这是他们内心喜欢或中意做的事，大家一起交流与切磋技艺，一起密切配合与协作，往往能酝酿出感情的种子，而在专业课课堂上，或许课程本身难度相对大，大部分同学没有多大兴趣一起研讨或交流，亲密关系的建立自然相对漫长。从空间角度看，专业课堂是正式、正规与严肃的空间，各类社团则是非正式、非正规与闲适空间，后者让人相对松弛、轻松与自然，此即非正式空间（informal space）的功效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让大学生们轻松与轻盈一些，让他们身心愉悦一些，让他们敢于和勇于做吻合他们这个年龄段的“分内之事”，让同学情谊回归纯真与深厚，让谈情说爱成为理所当然的事，这是当代大学生新气象的应有之义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了达致上述目标，余以为有关方面当多一点关心与关切当代大学生的价值观及真实心理与心态，各大学开设关于大学生心理方面的公共必修课，鼓励与崇尚构建开放包容与和谐的男女关系，破除制造性别对立与敌意的各种观念藩篱与阻梗。课程学习方面，任课老师不妨多鼓励同学们进行小组讨论，且建议男女搭配成组，营造异性讨论的良好氛围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，有关方面要在课余时间方面寻找突破口，要用尽量多的公共活动填充同学们的课余时间，创造机会让男女同学彼此接触、了解与认识，譬如组织同学们开展校园游、都市游、郊游、秋游、周末徒步或聚餐等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[辛柏青：适度的，饱满的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260363]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK2zBnv225d7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK2zBnv225d7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;时间&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2020年，导演张律从韩国回北京，按当时的新冠疫情防控政策，在广州的酒店隔离两周，期间他写了一个剧本，发给辛柏青，说主角谷文通是为他写的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷文通是北京人，离了婚，女儿寄养在姐姐家，自己住母亲留下的老屋，和一个年轻的女孩儿暧昧又分开，少年时最好的朋友在他乡自杀。这位曾经写诗的人，如今靠写美食文章为生，在北京的大街小巷游走，孤零零的，有种无法稳定下来的漂泊感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;演员辛柏青此前跟张律合作了《漫长的告白》（2021）——立春和立冬兄弟俩从北京去日本，找与二人年少时都有羁绊的姑娘柳川，大家各怀心事。辛柏青演的立春已有家庭，人到异国，通过满不在乎的方式掩藏自己的孤独和不自在。他说，“张律导演比较偏爱写这种有漂泊感和孤独感的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青在片场休息或者出神的某一瞬间，让张律看到了这种感觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷文通家住白塔旁边，辛柏青也在北京长大。张律说过，辛柏青身上有一种老北京人的“不急”。不急的人，看似慢半拍，身上时间的痕迹更重，和过去的关系比不停往前奔的人要紧密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《白塔之光》中的谷文通一出场像被困在时间里的人，穿懒汉布鞋，只有一件姜黄色条绒外套和一个软塌塌的双肩包，多数时候走路、偶尔坐公交车，吃“五十岁以上老人儿才惦记”的卤煮，与当下发生的一切隔着一层，习惯对所有人说不好意思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么这样的人会让我多看几眼呢？”张律接受《看电影》采访时说，“因为在这种人身上，过去的时间还在，现在的时间发生了微妙的变化，两个时间的东西挤压在了他的身上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于谷文通来说，过去的时间和现在的状态都与缺失的父亲有关：五岁那年，父亲被指控在公交车上猥亵妇女，被母亲赶出家门。等他人到中年，突然有了父亲的消息，当年的“流氓罪”是冤案，这么多年，父亲一直远远注视着他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父子和解的场面很短暂，两人在简陋的房间里伴着上世纪的DVD画面跳了一段交谊舞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个大男人一起跳舞，不是中国人的情感表达方式，更不是辛柏青的。他问张律，怎么跳？张律说，到时候就能跳。他又问饰演父亲的田壮壮，剧本里所有的戏他都能理解、都能想象得到最后呈现的样子，可跳舞这场戏，怪怪的。田壮壮也说，到那天会有办法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了那天，辛柏青先说一句台词：爸，你站起来。两个人身体僵硬地跳了几下。辛柏青对田壮壮说，爸，你手上的血管像蚯蚓——这是女儿之前对谷文通说过的话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田壮壮看了眼自己的手，接着顺势把手搭到辛柏青肩上。跳舞的戏水到渠成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太对了，辛柏青感叹。 “就通过这一个动作，父亲那么多年的情感落到手上，放到了我的肩膀上。这个动作很小，但是内容太多了。”他想，“当你直奔结果、直奔目的而去的时候，会觉得怎么这么难？但是把这个结果和目的忘了，享受过程、表达过程的时候，结果自然呈现。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影《白塔之光》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人保戏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月27日，《白塔之光》上映。这部电影在年初入围了第73届柏林电影节主竞赛单元。 4月，导演张律在北京电影节参加《白塔之光》映后活动，评价说，“辛柏青表演是含着的。努着劲的表演容易拿奖。辛柏青太应该拿奖了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从名气上看，辛柏青可能不算一线的明星演员。有几年，他的影视作品不多。但到电影《妖猫传》（2017），寥寥几个镜头，观众完全被他演的李白吸引住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;剧本里他只有一场戏：高力士把李白扛到极乐之宴，李白醉醺醺作了首诗，“云想衣裳花想容。”醉是基调。辛柏青想，真的要演醉吗？ “我对李白的认知，那是李白特别清醒的时期，因为他对仕途的所有幻想都已经破灭。所有人都在夸他可以当大官，他太清楚，到此为止了。”要有醉态，但一定要特别清醒，不能演醉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在片场，导演陈凯歌说，待会儿不用走戏，直接拍。太好了，辛柏青后来说，“我愿意碰撞最鲜活的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个镜头，一遍就过了。到监视器那儿，陈凯歌先说了句题外话，“咱以后还得合作”；然后给辛柏青看监视器：辛柏青上来一坐，很舒展，还在金龟上蹭蹭，然后悠悠冲着杨贵妃问，你是谁啊？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈凯歌说，这就是李白。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电视剧观众可能通过早些年的《幸福像花儿一样》（2005）或者近年的《大秦赋》（2020）认识了辛柏青。真正让他被记住的角色是年代剧《人世间》（2022）里的周秉义——东北普通家庭里的大哥：下乡知青，考上北大，后成为改革开放时期有突出贡献的官员，有特殊时代很多人的影子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;编剧王海鸰接到改编邀约，看梁晓声的原著小说，觉得描写周秉义的笔墨相对单薄，比如他主政一方之后，拆迁自己长大的棚户区“光字片”的过程，几笔带过。在王海鸰的故事里，弟弟周秉昆代表的家（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;基层百姓&lt;/span>;）、哥哥周秉义代表的国（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;政府官员&lt;/span>;）是主干。于是她下了大力气写周秉义成为领导干部之后的戏。 “非要说的话，这个剧的前半部分是周秉昆的主场，后半部分是周秉义的主场。”她说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《人世间》播出大约一半时，王海鸰和辛柏青在一次活动中遇上。周秉义的重头戏还没播出，王海鸰不知道辛柏青能演成什么样，双方只泛泛客套几句，她似乎听辛柏青说了句“这个剧本的文学性很强”，她想，这不过是人家客气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等到看完全剧，王海鸰后悔没多跟辛柏青聊聊，“这是一个太好的演员了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“略举一例：看剧中棚户区拆迁那场戏前，我心情是有点紧张的，那场戏我给了周秉义一段几千字的台词，剧情到那了只能那么写，想拍摄时导演也许会有办法减少这段戏的表演难度——不敢期待演员能达成心愿，那时我印象中辛柏青是一个文艺片的小众演员——不承想，那十几分钟的戏就那么一镜到底一气呵成地拍下来了，辛柏青用他对人物的理解、气质上的天赋、台词功底成功赋于了一个执政者应具有的真实的高尚。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;距离《人世间》首播已经一年有余，周秉义在棚户区拆迁现场处理纠纷、给从小认识的邻里朋友讲政策的片段，还在自媒体上流传，成为表演也是演讲的经典范例。王海鸰写小说出身，后来调入总政话剧团做戏剧，她说，“彼时常听前辈老师们说，戏保人，人保戏。周秉义这个角色的成功，当属人保戏。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一个人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《人世间》之后，辛柏青接到大量官员类角色。但他不想被类型化，新鲜的角色才能激起他的好奇心。他拍了纪录片导演徐童的首部剧情片《三个十年》，演反角闫永刚，和演警察贾国志的段奕宏搭戏。在春风得意的年代，闫永刚于一次追捕行动中打伤警察贾国志，贾没死，闫也没被捕，结了血仇，但是生出了棋逢敌手的惺惺相惜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童在自己的原著小说《珍宝岛》里是这样写官员子弟闫永刚的：出手黑，人白净，带着一股阴气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童和辛柏青一起去作家阿城家讨论《珍宝岛》的改编，那是他第一次见辛柏青，刚停车下来，看到后面辛柏青开着一辆SUV也到了，一个人，没有团队，没有助理。 “当时我就觉得很舒服，他是很自然的、一个人的状态。没有演艺圈的习气，或者说演员的做派。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿城家见过面之后，阿城跟徐童说，你注意看，柏青含胸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童后来仔细观察，辛柏青一点儿也不含胸，一米八几，挺直溜个人。徐童问辛柏青，一直就是这个形体？辛柏青说是，几十年一直这样，一点儿没胖，也一点儿没瘦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童明白了，阿城指的并不是形体，而是辛柏青给人一种含胸的印象。 “因为他的消瘦气质，他身上的含蓄。”类似的，徐童发现辛柏青有一种特殊的眼神，“他看事物看东西，不是那种眼睛放光，直接看，而是感觉好像隔着一层东西，光往回收，含在里面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意识到这两点，再看辛柏青塑造的角色，徐童觉得，“他的表达是适度的，同时也是饱满的，饱满是说他背后的东西是饱满的。”陈凯歌对辛柏青有类似的评价，他说辛柏青“吃得很深，吐得很少”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年春天，《三个十年》在陕西开机。辛柏青答应徐童提前进组，推掉了别的安排。 “他说过完春节之后，我就溜达过去了。”徐童回忆，“至今回想起来我们那一段时间的工作，我都觉得他不是一个演员，他没有把我们这个合作当成一个项目，他就是创作一个人物。熟悉环境，进入空间，然后进到这个人物当中去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开机前有剧本围读，大家谈得不多，徐童说，辛柏青和段奕宏已经把人物翻来覆去吃透，再谈多，反而影响现场的即兴感。他用“非常刺激，又非常惊喜”形容两位演员的表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然合作愉快，但徐童和辛柏青在那部戏之后的交往并不多。部分原因是徐童有意为之，“我需要跟演员保持一个距离，是为了产生一种陌生感，私交多了会影响未来对人物的想象力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他觉得辛柏青更懂这个道理，所以在角色之外很少露面，“如果观众对你这张脸太熟悉了，当你再去塑造一个人物的时候，那个人物的可信度就会降低，或者说冲击感就会降低。”好演员需要保持相当程度的孤独状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“三板斧”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们找到的辛柏青的合作伙伴都很愿意谈论他的表演，但是要和他本人聊表演并不容易，像张律说的，他是含着的；或者像徐童说的，他是往回收的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比起细致地讲述心路历程，他更愿意这样总结：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我的工作方法就是尽量把文学描述变为可视化的形象。第一步，我的形象从哪而来？他是什么样子的，大概什么发型，穿什么衣服，戴不戴眼镜，他走路的姿势，他说话的方式，他有没有习惯动作，这其实都是上学的时候学的最基础的。然后，剧本的一些背景，剧本没有写的，但是我要给他丰富的一些情感关系，或者是一些经历，自己去更多地为这个人物想象更深的一个维度。这样演出来以后这个人物就没有那么片面和单一化，观众就会觉得他可能有更多的侧面和立体。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这演员的基本功是观察生活，没别的技巧，没有什么新的内容，全是三板斧，但是这三板斧你要扎扎实实地做好，那就是演员武装到自己的牙齿。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就是靠着这三板斧，他一次次离开自己的舒适区，迎接新角色的挑战。 “我接戏只考虑我感不感兴趣，而不会考虑我能不能掌控。我看到一个新角色，我掌控不了，就不演了，永远没有进步。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乍一看，《漫长的告白》中的立春和辛柏青一点都不像。制片人徐佳含回忆，剧组最早定下的演员是张鲁一，演弟弟立冬，一个有点执拗的罹患癌症的文艺中年。他们问张鲁一，你给自己找个哥哥，看谁合适？哥哥立春有点像立冬的反面，世俗、外放。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张鲁一回答：辛柏青。他觉得辛柏青有点“闷骚的感觉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是有了辛柏青和导演张律的第一次合作。一场戏，在日本的民宿，立春和年少的恋人柳川相对而坐，说话，辛柏青眼泪唰地流下来，“那是在诉说，在悔悟。那种表现我觉得特别清晰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张律喊咔，再来一条，让辛柏青冲着墙说台词。 “我当时就想，刚刚那个不好吗？当然我没跟导演探讨，既然已经有表达强烈一点的了，我就来一遍导演说的。”下一条，辛柏青背对镜头，喃喃自语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成片里，张律用了后一条。辛柏青想，也对，立春也许是对柳川有感情，也许只是为了寻找自我来到此地，“而我那种表演把所有的可能性局限在了一种，反而让路子更窄了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青迅速理解了张律的风格，他说，看张律的电影像读诗，没有标准答案。 2020年底，我采访张律时，他确实说，电影应当像诗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凭借立春这个角色，辛柏青获得了中国电影金鸡奖最佳男配角奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到《白塔之光》，两人已经非常默契，没有过多的讨论。张律会问他，演得舒服吗？挺舒服的。那就行了，拍下一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“所谓的舒服（就是），我觉得都对了。这场戏没有&#39;个个楞楞&#39;的，没有那种很难受的、过不去的动作、行为、语气。是波澜不惊的、静水深流的表达方式，而不是哪个音符蹦出来了，变得强烈了；哪个音符又变得低沉了。可能用在这个电影里，舒服的感觉是这个样子的。”辛柏青说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;背负着时代和家庭的不如意，在暧昧的两性关系和戏剧化的父子关系里，谷文通这个角色可演的地方很多。但辛柏青知道张律要的是不外化的表演，甚至是不演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他就经常说，生活当中人是多面化的，你也许上一秒还在挺高兴地说一件事，下一秒可能就陷入到一种很自我的情绪里边了，不知道为什么。人也会经常跑神，也会说一些不着边际的话，这都是真实的生活状态。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这就对表演者提了更高的要求，不演，需要特别强大的内心定力，要不然会觉得，我没演，是不是不对？但恰恰是我不怀疑自己、内心特别笃定的时候，可能生出来另外一种无法言说的状态。观众会捕捉到。不演反而可能内心需要更充实，这种充实不是说目的性更充实，而是你的过往人生、阅历，你的气质、思想内涵在那一瞬间，都会让人能够感受得到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月29日，北影节闭幕式暨颁奖典礼举行，如张律所说，辛柏青果真拿了奖。他凭借《白塔之光》获得“天坛奖”最佳男主角。这是他拿到的第一个影帝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;话剧《狂飙》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;游戏感&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;影视角色之外，辛柏青一直是国家话剧院的演员。第一部大剧场戏是导演田沁鑫的《狂飙》（2001），他演主角田汉，戏里有打破第四堵墙的自述，有和表妹、和妻子、和红颜的情感，还有若干戏中戏，比如田汉翻译的《莎乐美》中的叙利亚少年、写的剧本里的关汉卿，都由辛柏青演。后来在《红玫瑰与白玫瑰》（2007）中，他演个全上海都知道的“柳下惠”。 《四世同堂》（2010）里，他演胡同里汲汲于名利、向日本人求官的冠晓荷——拿了话剧金狮奖表演奖。到《青蛇》（2013），他演法海，有人性，有神性。 2023年他还在排田沁鑫的新戏《苏堤春晓》，演苏轼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青记得多次合作的导演田沁鑫的一句话：戏剧和影视最大的不同，或说戏剧最大的魅力在于，可装扮性更强。影视剧不会找辛柏青的，田沁鑫会找。 “去装扮这个角色，就特别有游戏感，这一下让我豁然开朗。这件事变成了一件好玩的事儿，不是说我要苦大仇深地去塑造一个什么，戏比天大，这么大一个枷锁给你套上，不是的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在舞台上二十多年，辛柏青的角色不算多，两只手数得过来，现在回看，每一个角色的故事他都还能想得起来。与影视相比，戏剧离名利远，辛柏青自己有时候也想为什么一直没有离开戏剧呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“名利可能就是某一瞬间，我这戏播火了真好，被这么多人认可了，很享受，但很快就会过去。但是演话剧，在排练场里天天连滚带爬地排练，这种简单的快乐太难得了。岁数越大，面临的事、社会环境、关系也越来越复杂，（演话剧）这事儿就是不复杂。我能回到简单的地方，找到小的时候的状态就会特别快乐。”辛柏青说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他身上有一种非常干净的气质。这份干净是很难得的。”田沁鑫说过，在排练场，她有时会突然被辛柏青感动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，新版《狂飙》上演，辛柏青作为观众去看，觉得年轻一代演员比自己当年演得好。 “我年轻的时候有点没心没肺，每天就是乐呵、傻玩，并不过脑子，事儿不往心里装。因为装多了以后挺痛苦的，你知道吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但是没办法，生活就硬往怀里塞，这么多年也塞了不少了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生活给他塞了什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“柴米油盐，都往里装。具体你真的说不出来。这就是活着，过日子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青演的那版《狂飙》，有一段，田汉在东京看戏，一段自白，大意是，找到了自己热爱的志业，像是行星找到了轨道一般：“小时候我就有些迷障，我大概是无法悟道了。我只热爱我要的颜色，我会听凭它牵引出一条轨道，引我自由公转。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说出这段台词，问辛柏青在年轻时是否很有共鸣，他否认了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小的时候真的不知道这是什么意思，只是把这词念出来了，为赋新词强说愁的一种状态。什么人生，什么牵引，什么我的颜色，到底我要什么，我不知道。现在到了这个岁数了全都知道了，反而也可以不用说这样的话了，一切感悟都在，却道天凉好个秋了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过作品，很难寻觅到他在表演上爬坡的轨迹。他也没有给出所谓的“开窍时刻”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我明白你的问题，但是没有一个具体节点。因为生活本身没有节点，我的生活四平八稳的，但是四平八稳的生活，愿不愿意去用心体会？用心体会了，年龄、岁月带给人的就会潜移默化、一点点积淀。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他只说，如果现在再演田汉，应该是不一样了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;钝&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2008年，导演姜伟拍《潜伏》，最先考虑的是请辛柏青和朱媛媛两口子出演余则成和翠平，他觉得辛柏青身上有文人气。不巧赶上朱媛媛怀孕，姜伟说辛柏青一个人去也可以，辛柏青为了陪产也没去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《潜伏》播出之后，成了现象级电视剧，全国各地拿奖。辛柏青有遗憾，但不后悔。与喜爱的角色擦肩而过，这不是唯一一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾经辛柏青最想演的角色是浮士德。在歌德的戏剧《浮士德》里，这位博闻的学者与魔鬼梅菲斯特做交易，出卖自己的灵魂以换取无尽的学识和智慧，甘愿在死后投身地狱。后来真的有人来找他演《浮士德》的时候，他拒绝了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么这个机会到我手边的时候，我又不去演了呢，我纠结了好长时间，后来发现我想演的不是歌德的浮士德。”他无法用只言片语解释自己想演的浮士德是什么，但是他清楚自己不要什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我给人感觉挺钝的，生活当中给人感觉反正也不大灵光不大聪明的。”辛柏青这样说自己。但他有自己的小世界。特别累的时候，或者坐车赶路，他在网上看别人下四国军棋，有时候看到棋出得太臭，他也说，这看不下去，给关了，过会儿再点进去看看。 “就诸如此类，我自己心里边玩得特别高兴，但是跟别人一沟通起来，又变成了一个特别无聊的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青喜欢潜水。把生命搁在水底，杂念被迫压缩到最少，氧气含量、潜水深度、方向，都没问题了，终于可以放下心来看一眼海底的时候，他觉得，可能跟到了太空的感觉差不多，心情一下就变得开阔了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做演员的人都敏感，但是敏感有时候会伤害自己，作为“内向的、不善于表达的人”，辛柏青用这种方式让自己放空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐佳含是《漫长的告白》和《白塔之光》的制片人，她说，“柏青老师在现实生活中，跟剧组人员都特别客气，特别融洽。”《漫长的告白》到日本拍摄，辛柏青不懂日语，但是“会尽量适应，不愿意给别人添麻烦”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但你总觉得他有点小秘密，恰好在剧本里找到了一个出口。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1997年，中央戏剧学院表演系1993级本科生临近毕业，排练的间隙，十来个同学跟着老师去蹭饭。走在学校门口的东棉花胡同里，老师问了一句，你们毕了业谁还能坚持演话剧？本来欢快的气氛一下子安静了。那个时候演话剧意味着清贫，谁也没吱声。辛柏青接了一句，“要让我一辈子演话剧我都乐意。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，辛柏青50岁了，当年的老师有的已经离世。每当排话剧、同学聚会、给老师扫墓，他都会回想起那一幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[微短剧的“危险”狂飙]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260414]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 14:33:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;微短剧从各种层面都在狂飙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从市场规模看，据中文在线援引第三方研究报告数据，2022年短剧全年市场规模在100多亿元，2023年微短剧规模预计突破300亿元。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从市场供给来看，据广电总局数据，2021年微短剧全年备案数398部，而2022年备案数接近2800部，同比增长600%；2023年3月-8月，全国重点网络微短剧规划备案通过剧目部数，基本在260部以上，且7/8月分别为361部/401部，供给显著增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从公司看，中文在线、华策影视、芒果超媒、华谊兄弟、柠萌影视、掌阅科技、长信传媒均在此块加大投入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但另一头，基于题材“媚俗化”，微短剧市场监管不确定犹存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月10日，中文在线报收25.40元/股，跌幅9.19%。此前11月2日到9日，该公司股价短短6个交易日翻倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杨蓉主演的微短剧《二十九》在抖音短视频平台正片总播放量超8亿次。图片来源：剧方海报&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“爽点密集”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;微短剧最大特点是，回收效率高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当红微短剧概念股中文在线在投资者交流纪要中表示，短剧特点在于，内容短、集数多，一般是80-100集，每集两分钟以内，剧情带有较强戏剧性，创作内容更加贴合群众需求，故事快反转，剧情爽点密集。更多依托平台广告推流，实现C端客户触达。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此基础上，微短剧商业验证周期短，回收效率高，主要靠广告投流，投流方只要能够实现首日回收目标，就可以继续优化投流的策略，然后实现高额的ROI回收。一部作品从剧本打磨到拍摄、制作、投流验证， 短时间内就可以完成验证和闭环，资产中转率高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，微短剧制作周期短， 制作成本低，拍摄周期一般在一周以内。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不行就换题材，成本太低了。就是打一枪换一炮。”有微短剧创业者对21世纪经济报道记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这让影视基础薄弱的中文在线迅速切入核心赛道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“公司拥有海量IP优势。目前短剧剧本主要来源于网络小说改编，公司拥有550万种IP，可源源不断提供优质短剧IP改编剧本，长时间赛跑能力突出。”中文在线称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老牌内容巨头华策影视也在迅速进军这一市场。该公司对外披露，从去年下半年开始研究短剧赛道，今年6月开始建团队， 目前已有6 支队伍，也在引进编剧、制片人，和投流公司合作。 “ 未来的定位是进入微短剧的前五。”华策称。其自认为的优势，显然是制作能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客观上，影视巨头布局这一赛道还是有优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据柠萌影视披露，2023年初，其打造的微短剧《二十九》在抖音短视频平台的正片总播放量超8亿次，集均播放量超4000万次，相关话题全站总播放量14.5亿次，为抖音短视频微短剧的最高水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当下，微短剧最大特点是“爽感”，对精品制作需求似乎不多。从微短剧创业者到头部影视公司中层，均向21世纪经济报道记者坦承，目前头部影视公司在这一市场优势相对有限。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;譬如，《二十九》第二季播出即登上微短剧最热榜TOP1 ，连续5周占据抖音微短剧榜TOP1。可是，热度相对第一季有着明显下滑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;平台变迁&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大火微短剧背后是，落寞的长视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位影视公司项目负责人均向21世纪经济报道记者感慨，随着平台“降本增效”，挣钱越来越难了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财报显示，爱奇艺在2022年内容成本为165亿元，同比下降20%。此外，该公司还在力推自制剧。当下，爱奇艺自制内容资产占比持续上升，从2018年的32%升至2022年的63%。爱奇艺还披露，每年上新的重点剧集中，原创内容占比从2018年的20%提升至2022 年的50%以上。以上种种，都挤压了影视项目的利润空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此种变化诱因为，长视频脆弱的盈利模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年二季度，爱奇艺营收78.02亿元，同比增长17.2%；归母净利润3.65亿元，去年同期净亏损2.14亿元。但从环比来看，爱奇艺营收处在下滑区间。受《狂飙》推动，一季度，其营收达到83.49亿元，同比增长15%；归母净利润6.181亿元，而上年同期净利润为1.691亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长视频业绩如此波动在于，用户需求走向碎片化以及相对低的变现效率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据易观千帆数据，2023年9月，爱奇艺月活用户减少至5.6867亿人，腾讯视频月活用户减至4.5017亿人。同期，抖音月活用户减至7.9767亿人，快手月活用户减至5.2236亿人。长短视频差距明显。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另从广告来看，基于更高的变现效率，广告主们纷纷奔向短视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香飘飘就对外披露，上半年其冻柠茶销量同比增长547.09%，线上渠道同比增长235%，抖音渠道占比约30%且累计复购率维持高位。劲仔食品也对外表示，线上渠道方面，该公司抖音等新媒体渠道表现亮眼，同比增长约600%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有头部饮品市场部负责人告诉21世纪经济报道记者，相对爱奇艺等长视频平台，短视频推销效果更直接，变现效率要强得多。 “对长视频变现基本没报太大预期。”他说。另有头部户外运动产品创始人也表达了类似观点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流量与营收双重夹击下，长视频生态走向存量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是，内容公司们也不得不奔向微短剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“不确定性”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;然而，微短剧市场也面临着种种问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大量影视公司乃至平台，目前并不愿意在这块业务上过于高调，核心在于微短剧在政策上依旧存在不稳定性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;短剧的规范化监管可追溯至2020年8月，广电总局在重点网络影视剧信息备案系统增设了网络微短剧快速登记备案模块，标志着微短剧正式纳入监管体系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年4月，广电总局发文明确将包括短剧在内的国产网络剧片审查纳入行政许可事项管理，需要取得相关广播电视行政管理部门的发行许可才能播放上映; 当年11 月，针对小程序微短剧，发文开展专项整治。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在引导规范化发展的同时，广电总局也给予短剧必要的支持，2022年12月，《关于推动短剧创作繁荣发展的意见》提出要培育壮大短剧创作主体，在资源、人才、营销、排播、宣传等方面对短剧进行倾斜性支持。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必须注意的是，目前，爽剧仍是该市场主流。据巨量引擎，当前短剧以“爽”为内核，90%的题材都以“爽”为主，爽的方式多样，包括战神、穿越、逆袭、重生等题材。由此，呈现“媚俗化”倾向。据21世纪经济报道记者了解，对于大量“擦边”内容，监管层正在关注中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“市场走向充满着不确定性。”多位行业上下游参与者如此表态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另从市场规模来看，微短剧相对长视频还是有限。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2022年，单爱奇艺一家营收就达到290亿元，同比下滑5%。这一数据，远超同年微短剧总体市场规模，且接近2023年微短剧预计规模。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当下，短剧终端盈利主要分为三种。分别为会员付费、广告变现和电商带货。会员付费包括定期的会员费和单部剧集购买，主流长视频平台单月会员价格在22-25元，短剧专属平台会员费更高，在30元左右；单剧付费收费标准为1-3元/集，爆款剧单集收费可达10 元。广告收入也是短剧收入的重要组成部分，包括贴片广告、广告植入、IP 授权营销；其中，贴片广告是长视频平台的专属，软广植入是短视频平台的常用方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体来看，此种盈利模式依旧趋向短平快，离真正的成熟商业模式还有距离。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>