<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[长沙欢迎研发：一场以研发为名的“双转型”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/KpQ4bok8YdveVizq9XBCdcLO6aGmzuqVS6fUixGi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/KpQ4bok8YdveVizq9XBCdcLO6aGmzuqVS6fU ixGi. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There is a surging crowd outside Cha Yan Yuese&#39;s shop. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2018, Hu Biliang, who had studied and worked in the United States for more than ten years, decided to return to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2007, Hu Biliang has studied at the University of Southern California and the University of Pennsylvania, studying under the &quot;father of CAR-T cell therapy&quot; Carl June. After receiving his PhD in the field of cellular immunotherapy, Hu Biliang is also paying close attention to the development of the domestic biopharmaceutical industry. In June 2018, having already started a family in the United States, he decided to return to Changsha with bare hands and start from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, another summer, four kilometers away from Hu Biliang&#39;s office, a new R&amp;D institution with the functions of talent gathering, cutting-edge research and achievement transformation - Peking University Changsha Computing and Digital Economy Research The institute (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Peking University Changsha Research Institute&quot;&lt;/span>;) was opened. Bai Zengding, who has been recognized as a high-level talent in a certain first-tier city, decided to give up a subsidy of nearly one million yuan and join the institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha, an Internet celebrity city, is extremely popular on social media, especially in summer. As a popular summer travel destination, there is even a joke circulating here that &quot;Yuelu Mountain was stepped down by 2cm due to tourists.&quot; However, somewhat unexpectedly, as tourists are coming in droves, top scientific and technological talents are also coming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Changsha welcomes research and development.&quot; This unwritten city attitude has been regarded as a guideline by local politicians before, and finally made its highlight debut in the summer of 2023. On June 19, Shen Xiaoming, Secretary of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee, announced at the opening ceremony of the Yuelu Internet Summit that Changsha is planned to become a global R&amp;D center city. On July 30, the Changsha Municipal Government issued relevant policies and implementation opinions. On September 1, a group of scientific and technological R&amp;D institutions from universities, scientific research institutions, and leading enterprises unveiled their names on site or signed contracts to start construction at the first opening ceremony of Changsha&#39;s efforts to build a global R&amp;D center city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A research and development craze began to stir up this central city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the craze, there are more mysteries of urban development worth studying. After investigation, Southern Weekend found that Changsha’s plan to build a global R&amp;D center city and the micro-innovation practices of this long-established construction machinery capital reveal two transformation models currently taking place in Changsha: First, the integration of manufacturing centers into R&amp;D centers Transformation; second, the integration and transformation from production center to life center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by the &quot;dual transformation&quot;, Changsha&#39;s urban functions and innovation levels are quietly undergoing spiral advancement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/6SXRBhrbyDeoO8GPXQ62tjSsf51l3OfWzy3kWnuE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/6SXRBhrbyDeoO8GPXQ62tjSsf51l3OfWzy3kWnuE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The smart mobility chassis developed by Changsha Automobile Innovation Research Institute can realize functions such as four-wheel independent steering and four-wheel independent drive, and can easily complete U-turns and lateral driving on the spot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Changsha Evening News all-media reporter Yi Yi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Interactive network of developers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I personally have always I am doing research and development in the direction of biopharmaceuticals, hoping to develop a better innovative drug through my own technological innovation.&quot; Having been engaged in virus-related research and gene therapy for more than ten years, Hu Biliang has always regarded the research and development of innovative drugs as a professional pursuit and life goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people did not understand his decision to return to Changsha from the United States to continue this research career, but Hu Biliang had his own considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Hunan’s biopharmaceutical industry does have a weak foundation compared to the United States. But if an innovative drug can be produced here, it will not only bring better treatment options to tumor patients in our hometown, but also I can also contribute to the development of the biopharmaceutical industry in my hometown, which is also the core value and significance I pursue in my technology research and development journey.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With such fighting spirit and expectations, in the summer of 2018 , Hu Biliang returned to Changsha alone with bare hands to make preliminary preparations for starting a business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, he was no longer alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here we have support from colleagues in terms of laboratories and equipment, discounts on factory buildings in industrial parks, and assistance from government talent and entrepreneurship policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Biliang detailed the help he received from many parties during his entrepreneurial journey and attributed it to &quot;luck.&quot; But in fact, behind this &quot;luck&quot; is the entire city&#39;s respect for the high-tech industry, its preference for high-tech talents, and its expectations for the achievements of high-tech wisdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such an environment, the implementation process of research and development is relatively smooth. In 2023, Hunan Siweikang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. founded by Hu Biliang received clinical trial approval for a national Class 1 new drug. This is the first biopharmaceutical IND approval in Hunan Province, which is of great significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hu Biliang’s plan, in the next three years, the first clinical trial of cell drugs will be completed, and the cell drugs developed by the team can be successfully launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only a technological milestone breakthrough, but also the starting point for the vigorous development of a regional industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are new research and development forces, and they also chose Changsha, but Peking University Changsha Research Institute is the starting point of a different story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an important platform for the transformation of Peking University’s scientific research results, the institute’s research centers fully considered Changsha’s local industrial characteristics when they were first established to “get closer to the market frontier and industrial needs.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Digital Transformation Promotion Center where Bai Zengding is located conducts applied research around data elements and is committed to serving the national strategy of enterprise digital transformation and traditional industry upgrading; the Industrial Intelligence Research Center next door is oriented towards intelligence. The digital transformation needs of manufacturing, logistics and transportation, supply chain and other fields enable the digital transformation and upgrading of enterprises through data, algorithms and models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha is a big manufacturing city. From hardware, software to cloud services, as well as the huge amount of data in the manufacturing production and processing links, it provides us with a very rich material library, which is why we chose to come here. The reason for being a platform for the transformation of scientific and technological achievements.&quot; Bai Zengding said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to overseas R&amp;D teams and new R&amp;D institutions, there is also a third type of &quot;foreign force&quot; worthy of attention—foreign-funded R&amp;D centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On one side are newcomers. In 2019, Schaeffler established the second R&amp;D center in Greater China in Xiangjiang New District, and closely interacted with local enterprises Xiangjiang Intelligent and Xidi Intelligent Driving. Through collaborative R&amp;D and information sharing, it accelerated the development of Changsha&#39;s intelligent connected automobile industry. Development process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One is to increase investment. For example, Soenger China plans to invest a total of 3 billion yuan and continue to increase its R&amp;D investment in Changsha. The newly built Soenger Global New Energy Products and Technology R&amp;D Center has a construction area of ​​tens of thousands of square meters and is expected to be put into use within the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the influx of new foreign R&amp;D forces, R&amp;D paradigms of local companies are also sprouting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry is the source of innovation, and enterprises are the core subject of innovation. According to Du Debin, dean of the Institute of Global Innovation and Development at East China Normal University, Changsha, the capital of central China, needs to build a global R&amp;D center city based on its own advantageous industries, conduct differentiated competition, cultivate global R&amp;D centers in subdivided industries, and then spread through innovation. The effect gradually moves closer to the target. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take construction machinery as an example. In 2007, when Hu Biliang went abroad for further study, Shi Wenbing graduated from Huazhong University of Science and Technology majoring in mechanics. Full of longing for the future, he got on the bus to recruit students from Sany Heavy Industry School. Soon after, Lu Chuang, who came from Yichang, Hubei Province, decided to continue his studies in the mechanical major of Central South University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Here is the most active market and the most cutting-edge technology in the construction machinery industry.” With the same expectation, the two came to Changsha one after another. Since then, the paths of fate have secretly marked their intersection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifteen years later, Shi Wenbing became a senior engineer of Sany Heavy Industry, leading a number of major R&amp;D projects, constantly breaking through technical bottlenecks, and going global with the company, using global innovation resources to carry out technological research. It is understood that SANY Group’s overseas business now covers more than 160 countries and regions, and it has 13 overseas manufacturing centers in the United States, Germany, India, Brazil, and Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working at the State-owned Enterprise Research Institute for 8 years, Lu Chuang joined an upstream company that provided products and services to Sany Heavy Industry and served as the general manager of Hunan Zhongji Shenyi Testing Technology Co., Ltd., establishing a testing center from scratch. The test base fills the gaps in some testing and pilot service projects for construction machinery and core components. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same industrial chain, in different positions, the chain owner enterprises and supporting enterprises each perform their own duties and jointly contribute to the industrial iteration of construction machinery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Top overseas R&amp;D teams have settled in Changsha, laying the foundation for building chains for emerging industries; new foreign R&amp;D institutions are highly consistent with local industrial clusters; foreign-funded R&amp;D centers continue to increase their presence and interact closely with local companies; at the same time, Changsha Leading companies go global, supporting companies collaborate with each other, and the chain has close relationships and collaborative research. The panorama of Changsha’s R&amp;D entities has basically emerged. Various types of R&amp;D entities show their talents and release the energy of innovation. This is a real and frequent innovation story happening in Changsha. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Wang Fan, director of the Science and Technology and Standards Institute of CCID Research Institute, Changsha’s innovative practices coincide with his views. Wang Fan believes that in building Changsha into a global R&amp;D center city, chain owners should play a leading role, promote in-depth cooperation between large and small enterprises in the chain, continuously strengthen and optimize the chain, and form leading enterprises, supporting enterprises, colleges and universities, and scientific research institutions. An ecological development pattern of collaborative linkage, competition, cooperation and symbiosis among institutes, third-party platforms, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of their existence, the goal of becoming a global R&amp;D center city is not unrealistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the prosperous R&amp;D panorama, what is the driving force that nourishes its vigorous growth? In other words, why does Changsha need R&amp;D so much? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ICcdKzLORYoraEapZrlBHrva0dplbH8IVfOb9GKC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ICcdKzLORYoraEapZrlBHrva0dplbH8IVfOb9GKC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shenyi researchers are conducting simulation assembly experiments. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Two-way drive of R&amp;D and manufacturing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Want to answer the above questions , we must first understand Changsha’s industrial background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are seven major 100-billion-level manufacturing industry clusters here, including engineering machinery, automobiles and parts, new materials, electronic information, and energy storage materials. The total digital economy has exceeded 450 billion yuan, and high-tech industries have increased. The average annual growth rate is more than 10%, accounting for 29.6% of GDP. It is also home to the third largest construction machinery industry cluster in the world. The other two are Illinois in the United States and Tokyo in Japan. It is known as the &quot;Construction Machinery Capital of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCID Consulting&#39;s &quot;Research Report on the Top 100 Advanced Manufacturing Cities (2022)&quot;, Changsha ranks eighth in the development of advanced manufacturing, ranking first among cities in the central and western regions. This city, which is famous for its soft power of &quot;entertainment&quot;, is also closely related to the hard-core &quot;manufacturing&quot; industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at the same time, a background of the post-epidemic era that cannot be ignored is the dramatic changes in the international economic and trade pattern, the weakening of the domestic demographic dividend and the tight industrial space. The combined effects of multiple factors have led to the transformation and upgrading of China&#39;s manufacturing industry. Imminent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the views of many researchers, this boom in scientific and technological innovation in the name of research and development, taking place in the manufacturing city of Changsha, has a certain inevitability: strengthening technology research and development innovation, increasing the localization substitution rate, It is not only a &quot;charge battle&quot; for the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry, but also a &quot;battle for dominance&quot; in core technologies. It is also a &quot;pursuit battle&quot; for the ranking of central cities in the new round of industrial revolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;R&amp;D means &quot;research and development&quot; and refers to the key links in the manufacturing industry from laboratory technology to new product development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha’s proposal to build a global R&amp;D center city is actually a signaling mechanism with a very clear goal, and has a clear intention of leading the way in industrial transformation and upgrading.” Chen Ling, director of the Industrial Development and Environmental Governance Research Center of Tsinghua University, said Now, Changsha is the first city to specifically focus on the &quot;R&amp;D link&quot; as a brand building. In a sense, it takes advantage of local manufacturing advantages to take the lead in manufacturing transformation and upgrading driven by R&amp;D breakthroughs or innovation. Judging from the local government&#39;s strategic planning, Changsha City does not intend to leave this transformation and upgrading completely to the market&#39;s own trial and error, but to carry out large-scale planning, layout and investment through the government&#39;s organized approach. This is a comparison Outstanding features. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The source of the government’s organized and planned leadership behavior still comes from enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 National People’s Congress and the National People’s Congress, Liang Wengen, then chairman of Sany Group, once proposed that in the face of the digitization of construction machinery and manufacturing, the group would “either turn over or capsize.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Sany Heavy Industry Changsha Factory No. 18 was rated as a &quot;Lighthouse Factory&quot;. This is the second one in Hunan Province and represents the highest level of intelligent manufacturing and digitalization in the global manufacturing field. All equipment in the factory is connected to the Internet, and the flow of production information, usage, and assembly line information is completely connected. All parts transfers in the factory are carried out by AGV (Automated Guided Transport Vehicle) automatic distribution robots. Industrial robots replace manual work, and &quot;cost reduction and efficiency increase&quot;, a synonym for high-quality development, is supported by vivid scenes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaudi, who has been deeply involved in the field of robotics for more than ten years, has long-term observations and thoughts on how technological research and development changes traditional manufacturing industries. Changtai Robotics, where he works, takes it as its mission to explore manufacturing technology upgrade scenarios and meet application needs. In Gaudi’s view, if Changsha wants to achieve a global leadership position in the field of industrial robots, Changsha may be able to focus on the software and industrial Internet tracks to create differentiated advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Gaudi focuses on recruiting high-tech talents in the field of artificial intelligence. Guo Dongni, who is also from Northeast China, is one of the good candidates. This seemingly fair and well-behaved female engineer born in 1995 is actually the leader of the machine vision and artificial intelligence algorithm research and development project team. She once led a &quot;women&#39;s army&quot; with master&#39;s degrees with an average age of less than 30 years old to develop cloth defects with independent intellectual property rights. The inspection system - &quot;ZTVT tire base non-woven fabric self-learning vision system&quot; uses artificial intelligence to liberate workers&#39; eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhangtai Robot is not an exception. A number of specialized and new enterprises such as Super Robot and Dingli Technology are relying on Changsha&#39;s scientific and educational resources and industrial advantages to explode with vigorous innovation vitality in many fields such as robots, intelligent equipment, and new materials. Accelerate the industrial upgrading process through technological breakthroughs in subdivided fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Technological innovation actually includes two aspects. One is to spawn new products through technological innovation, which may eventually form a new industry; the other is to promote industrial upgrading through scientific and technological innovation. . The demand for the latter will always exist, and the volume is larger.&quot; Du Debin analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, Changsha’s construction of a global R&amp;D center city requires a series of measures to gather a large number of R&amp;D centers, including those of multinational companies, local R&amp;D centers, new R&amp;D centers, etc. Type, promote innovation in business models and technologies, thereby driving industrial upgrading and transformation of urban functions, transforming Changsha from a product production center to a knowledge production center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many international city cases for the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry. Judging from the relationship between product production centers (manufacturing centers) and knowledge production centers (R&amp;D centers), they can be roughly divided into three types: &lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The first is the model represented by Hong Kong. Due to the rising cost of production factors, since the reform and opening up, Hong Kong has transferred manufacturing to the Pearl River Delta region through the &quot;three to one supplement&quot; model. However, it has not turned to the development of R&amp;D, but has transformed into a financial industry and modern service industry. International financial center - South Korea, Singapore and Taiwan, also the &quot;Four Asian Tigers&quot;, have established their own R&amp;D networks. However, Hong Kong has always paid attention to R&amp;D. In the 1990s, it explored government actions to promote R&amp;D such as the &quot;Cyberport&quot; plan. Now it is vigorously developing innovative technology and creating a &quot;Northern Region&quot; that integrates Shenzhen&#39;s scientific and technological resources. metropolitan area.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the &quot;unitary system&quot; model represented by Detroit. As the heartland of the U.S. automobile industry, Detroit once experienced rapid population loss and rapid industrial decline due to the pace of transformation and upgrading that was slower than market changes. After being stimulated and guided by a series of recovery plans, Detroit has now transformed into a research and development center for the automobile industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munich, which also has the automobile industry as its pillar industry, has taken a completely different industrial path from Detroit. There is BMW&#39;s oldest factory here, as well as the R&amp;D headquarters of automobile companies such as Audi and MAN Group. It is a &quot;dual integration&quot; model that combines production and R&amp;D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Du Debin’s view, faced with an industrial structure dominated by the real economy, many cities in China should refer to the development experience of Munich’s automobile industry and encourage companies to conduct technology research and development while retaining production centers and R&amp;D centers. &quot;Integration, transformation, and both are the goals for the healthy development of our city&#39;s industries.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to Changsha from overseas cities, it is not difficult to find that with manufacturing as the priority, we are now building a global R&amp;D center Isn’t Changsha a latecomer to the “Munich Model”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A variety of R&amp;D entities come together and are closely linked with each other. Its essence comes from Changsha&#39;s good industrial foundation. New technologies have huge market demand and application scenarios here, thus urging rapid iteration of technology; and new R&amp;D results will empower the manufacturing industry to upgrade and promote its transformation from scale to R&amp;D and brand. Wait for the two ends of the smile curve to shift. The two-way drive between R&amp;D and manufacturing works together to improve urban competitiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, we have seen the full picture of Changsha&#39;s first &quot;transformation&quot;: from a manufacturing center to a R&amp;D hub, from a product production center to a knowledge production center, and it is not a one-way transformation from &quot;you &quot;To &quot;I&quot;, it is the fusion of two centers, the synergy of &quot;manufacturing&quot; and &quot;R&amp;D&quot;, and the symbiosis of &quot;product production&quot; and &quot;knowledge production&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more valuable is that in Changsha, this &quot;integrated transformation&quot; model not only occurs in the production of products and knowledge, but also occurs in the balance between the &quot;production center&quot; and the &quot;life center&quot; middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/FM1Ft4HE3SUe23WhfemVZKpDJ0Rl7Xib6mxHmjTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1181&quot; height= &quot;2067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/FM1Ft4HE3SUe23WhfemVZKpDJ0Rl7Xib6mxHmjTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The secret of &quot;attracting and retaining&quot; talents&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;The balance and integration of production center and life center is Changsha’s unique urban advantage. The direct impact of this feature is to attract a large number of talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, Changsha’s permanent population has grown by 32.3%, ranking among the top cities in China in both absolute value and rate of population growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ling introduced that according to the &quot;Global Innovation Hubs Index 2022&quot; released by Tsinghua University&#39;s Center for Industrial Development and Environmental Governance (CIDEG) and Springer Nature Group (Nature Research) Index, GIHI2022) report, Changsha performs well in talent-related indicators, such as the inflow of professional talents per million people, the number of active scientific researchers per million people, the number of highly cited scientists and other indicators, almost all of which are in the 50-70% range globally. Ranking of names. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talent is the core element of innovation, and those who get talents will win the future. Many data show that the city of Changsha has advantages over other cities in terms of talent attraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only the return of Hunan talents such as Hu Biliang and Bai Zengding, but also the promised land for Hubei talents such as Shi Wenbing and Lu Chuang. It is also the common choice of fellow Northeasterners from different generations such as Gao Di and Guo Dongni... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pace of talent has already broken through the restrictions of geographical areas and shown new flow patterns. Many experts have pointed out that the secret of &quot;attracting and retaining&quot; talents lies not only in the existing law of &quot;people follow the industry&quot;, but also in the balanced integration of urban production centers and life centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to the latter is whether it can meet the material needs of talents for career growth and labor returns; whether it can meet the needs of talents for housing prices, education, medical care and other public services; Meet the spiritual needs of talents for culture, leisure, consumption and other public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Satisfying three needs at the same time is not an easy task. However, a new trend has emerged in Changsha, which is transforming from a single production center to a space integrating production and life centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Fan’s view, the integration of production centers and life centers is the trend of the times. It requires more emphasis on people’s subjective initiative and responds to people’s demands. It reflects the concept of comprehensive, coordinated and sustainable development. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Dongni, who was born in 1995, fell in love with Changsha&#39;s delicious food and friendly housing prices as early as when she was studying at Hunan University, and decided to stay in &quot;this happy city&quot; in the future. Nowadays, she is a professional and rigorous female engineer at work, but she is an energetic girl who loves hip-hop dancing in life. During her breaks, she drives to the Xiangjiang River to camp with her colleagues; The snack street is attractive, so you can enjoy a late-night snack. This is the energy given by fireworks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Chuang, born in the 1980s, seems to be living a parallel life with Guo Dongni. Fifteen years ago, Lu Chuang chose to come to Changsha for its educational resources and employment opportunities. While studying, whenever he was confused and confused, he would climb Yuelu Mountain alone. Sit for a while, the mountain will not speak, and the people will understand. Nowadays, he is not interested in commercial malls, but he still takes his family to visit his hometown from time to time to experience the changes in his mentality at different stages. This is the nourishment given by nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, after Hu Biliang returned to Changsha, he received strong support from the local talent policy. In the exchange with relevant leaders, he deeply felt the government&#39;s cherishment and respect for talents, and the carefulness and thoughtfulness of policy service talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha City’s talent policy has really helped me solve some practical problems, especially the problem of children enrolling in school.” Hu Biliang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, 22 items of Changsha’s talent policy were released; five years later, the “45-item upgraded version” of Changsha’s talent policy was released, proposing 45 policy points from 7 major aspects; two months later, The 26 supporting implementation measures of the New Deal have been upgraded again based on the original policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 22 to 45 and then to 26, there is no optimal, only better; there is no constant success in the credit book, only greater confidence and stronger determination. Practical welfare policies such as housing subsidies and tax rebates protect the rights and interests of talents and make it worthwhile for them. What this “two-way rush” achieves is double surprises for people and the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People of different ages and personality traits have different definitions of ideal life, but they make the same choice. The only reasonable explanation is probably that this place meets most of the needs and imaginations of each individual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trend of integration and transformation from production center to life center has built Changsha’s “life-friendly” urban characteristics, while “life-friendly” continues to empower “R&amp;D-friendly” and “manufacturing-friendly”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talent policy is rich and comprehensive, the cost of living is low, public services such as medical education are high-quality, the cultural creativity is deep and dynamic, and the combination of various characteristics jointly builds a research and development space, a production space, a cultural space, A balanced and appropriate comprehensive urban system such as consumption space and cultural tourism space promotes the gathering of R&amp;D and innovative talents, and then intellectual achievements are born and transformed here, further promoting industrial transformation and upgrading, and forming a virtuous cycle of spiral advancement of industry and population. It will serve as a basis for improving urban supporting facilities and improving the quality of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about how to view the topic of &quot;Changsha building a global R&amp;D center city&quot;, Chen Ling said that Changsha will elevate the &quot;global R&amp;D center city&quot; to the level of the city&#39;s business card and carry out systematic development through policy measures. Comprehensive operation and layout will inevitably produce a brand effect and attract the attention of enterprises and talents. This approach is very consistent with the city&#39;s traditional image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, Changsha has always been a city that encourages cultural creativity and tolerates emerging things. The spirit of leisure and entertainment and the atmosphere of human life rooted in the hearts of every citizen have led to the birth of Mango Channel, which dominates the prime time slots of satellite TV, and the birth of a number of new consumer brands such as Cha Yan Yuese and Wen He You. Its unique urban temperament and diverse tourism resources continue to attract a large number of tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuese Tea, a must-visit for tourists, recently announced an investment of 520 million yuan to build a brand R&amp;D and production base, focusing on product technology R&amp;D and product flavor R&amp;D. Compared with the secondary industry, the research and development link of the tertiary industry has a broader meaning, including not only the exploration of front-end products and technologies, but also product and service innovation in the terminal link, starting from the details to improve the consumer experience. In addition, Cha Yan Yuese also deeply explores the local culture of the city and promotes the spread of traditional tea culture and regional culture through packaging, logo, store design and many other elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wanxing, who proposed to &quot;get a salary as high as Shenzhen, live in a livable house in Changsha, and work in the global software industry&quot; is another example of Changsha&#39;s increased research and development in the creative field. In 2022, Wondershare&#39;s global operations headquarters and creative software global R&amp;D center will officially settle in Changsha. Additional investment in the 3.0 project has been initiated, and it is planned to build a &quot;Wanxing Creative World Industrial Park&quot; of nearly 100,000 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the &quot;double-sided Changsha&quot; image of culture, entertainment and hard-core manufacturing is connected by the link of &quot;research and development&quot;, forming a superimposed effect in the field of public opinion. Changsha welcomes research and development, regardless of track. , come if you dare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two transformations&quot; are going on at the same time, and the &quot;three friendships&quot; are interrelated. The innovative practices carried out in central China and their next steps will not only drive the rise of a new innovation center, but also influence The transformation of manufacturing cities is of exemplary significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha, which welcomes research and development, will also be welcomed in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend researchers Tang Jiale and Li Jing also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/ a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[合作25年，一朝决裂：石榴集团“宫斗”祸起境外架构]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257194]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/qYTwUTUzpFC3i0UZdd3SK9eiBsZFmeTTJ4JXWhsL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/qYTwUTUzpFC3i0UZdd3SK9eiBsZFmeTTJ4 JXWhsL. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pomegranate Group’s Beijing headquarters is located in the Fengtai Branch Center of Zhongguancun Science and Technology Park, also known as the Pomegranate Center. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now both parties are retreating, guaranteeing the delivery of housing, protecting the interests of owners and investors, and not giving the government Cause trouble, so try not to occupy public issues anymore.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter interviewed Cui Wei, chairman and major shareholder of Pomegranate Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Pomegranate Group) At that time, the company gave this reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a media communication meeting held 4 days ago, Cui Wei knelt down in public, hoping that financial institutions would not withdraw loans due to the company’s chaos. If financial institutions cause real losses, I will jump from the 22nd floor of the Pomegranate Center where we are.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, nearly three months have passed since internal strife broke out in this private real estate company, which ranks among the top 100 private real estate companies in China. During this period, incidents such as Cui Wei &quot;stealing the official seal&quot; and the dismissal of vice chairman and second shareholder Sang Chunhua frequently aroused public opinion. Sang Chunhua was also involved in a scandalous news. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Cui Wei held a media communication meeting, Sang Chunhua also held a media communication meeting on September 14 and released a reconciliation signal at the meeting. He shouted to Cui Wei: &quot;I am still willing to give in and let you get more until we reach an agreement and stop the dispute.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two sides have been at odds for some time. In 2021, Pomegranate Group failed to go public in Hong Kong. The next year, Sang Chunhua proposed a separation, believing that Cui Wei had not made the right decision in more than ten years and did not want to be held hostage again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei proposed that his equity would require a 30% premium when the company was separated, but Sang Chunhua refused to accept it. Conflicts accumulated over the years are about to break out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Exposing each other&#39;s shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2001, Cui Wei and Sang Chunhua cooperated to establish Beijing Agile Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Agile) in Beijing; in 2008 , the two parties also established Huamei K2 Real Estate Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Huamei K2), named after K2, the world’s second highest peak; in 2016, the company was renamed Pomegranate Group, aiming to be the “Apple in the real estate industry.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than 20 years since its establishment, Pomegranate Group has developed more than 90 projects in more than 30 cities across the country, focusing on mid-to-high-end residential products. At the press conference on September 11, Cui Wei once stated that the company has not had a single uncompleted building, a financial bad debt, or a bank overdue payment so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How difficult it is to achieve such results, so why do we have to come out like this on June 21st?&quot; Sang Chunhua once shouted to Cui Wei from a distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, a drama of &quot;stealing for official seals&quot; was staged in the conference room on the 16th floor of the Pomegranate Group&#39;s office building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the statement of a company employee signed by &quot;Zhang Yongkai&quot;, Cui Wei believed that &quot;Vice Chairman Sang Sir (Sang Chunhua hopes to be as capable and efficient as the Hong Kong police) has violated the company&#39;s system and affected the company&#39;s operations and other illegal acts &quot;, forcing members of the seal team, including Zhang Yongkai, to stamp documents that could not see the full text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Cui Wei put the official seal into his pocket and said, &quot;Not only does he have to stamp it, but he also needs to take the seal home. This is his own company, he is the chairman, and this is his right. No one else can control it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After struggling until 4 a.m., the members of the seal team were allowed to go home. From this day on, Pomegranate Group announced that Sang Chunhua would be terminated from his labor contract and all his duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei said that the company’s dismissal of Sang Chunhua was legal and “a serious, legal and regulatory adjustment and defense of corporate governance rights.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the dismissal of Sang Chunhua was that Sang arranged for relatives, classmates, fellow villagers, etc. to enter the company. The company was internally controlled by relevant interest groups. He was sidelined as the chairman, and the company&#39;s internal management and cost control were extremely chaotic. . Moreover, Sang had problems with his lifestyle, which caused damage to the company&#39;s goodwill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 6, Liu Xia, CEO of Yunhe Variable Group, an investment company, reported Sang Chunhua on Weibo with his real name, saying that he invited many people to participate in unhealthy activities in Beijing on the pretext of eating. I was abused on WeChat and over the phone for dozens of minutes.&quot; It was later revealed that Li Guangtian, president of Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai regions of Pomegranate Group, and Ding Qingwei, president of Jiangsu region, were also involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 8, Sang Chunhua issued a statement saying: &quot;The dissemination of my unverified and untrue remarks by online platforms and individuals has seriously violated my right to reputation. I demand that the slander be stopped immediately.&quot; stigma, and reserves the right to pursue the legal responsibilities of online platforms and individuals. I have entrusted a lawyer to initiate relevant legal procedures.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with Cui Wei&#39;s many accusations, Sang Chunhua also held multiple press conferences, Fight back against it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to disclosing the situation on June 21, Sang Chunhua claimed that the dismissal was without legal decision-making procedures of the company. He also accused Cui Wei to the media of improperly occupying company property and refusing to return it, and installing bugs in the vehicle he was riding in. device. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also attending the press conference with Sang Chunhua on September 14 was Lin Xinwu, the former general manager of the Risk Control Center and Chairman of the Board of Supervisors of Pomegranate Group. He said that Pomegranate Group launched an A-share listing plan in 2016, and 62 core members paid in 216.8 million yuan as partners to participate in the share reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the A-share listing was blocked, Pomegranate turned to Hong Kong stocks in 2021, but still failed, and the partners’ funds were not returned. It wasn&#39;t until the official seal incident broke out on June 21 that Cui Wei, the working partner, &quot;collectively forced the wife to marry&quot;, asked for part of the money back. But the five partners, including him, were not only fired, but also did not receive refunds, totaling 33.5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sang Chunhua also disclosed that Cui Wei had firmly refused to agree to dividends for 25 years, and the two borrowed money from the company when they needed it. In recent years, Cui Wei has borrowed hundreds of millions of yuan from companies in public names, and his whereabouts are unknown. Cui Wei also used company funds to speculate in Shougang stocks, resulting in a cumulative loss of 6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;崔巍亦指责桑春华存在“巨大的、突发性的”外部个人债务，危及公司经营安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;徒弟还是股东？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;你来我往的攻击背后，实际上是双方隐藏的股权分歧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到8月4日，桑春华依然进不去办公室。在公司楼下，他手持一份国家企业信用信息公示的报告对着镜头介绍，称自己是石榴集团董事、总经理，持有42%股份。公司只有两名股东，崔巍持有另外58%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;镜头里，桑春华梳平头短发，戴一副黑框眼镜。他给崔巍连打两个电话，均无人接听，之后拨打了110，对警察声称，“我是这公司老板，他没有资格解聘我”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，石榴集团股权穿透后，是两家注册于香港的公司，国家企业信用系统无法看到二人持股情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但2021年石榴集团曾赴港上市，南方周末记者获取的招股书显示，公司搭建了境外股权架构，由崔巍持股57.42%、桑春华持股41.58%、投资者陈健勇持股1%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张永刚在石榴集团任职近十年，目前仍在桑春华身边工作。他告诉南方周末记者，陈健勇是桑春华的朋友，上市失败后退出了股份，现在公司由崔巍、桑春华分别持股58%、42%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因上市未果，目前石榴集团招股书已失效且无法查看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对媒体，曾任地理老师的崔巍总是将桑春华称为自己“最好的学生”，“就像曹云金之于郭德纲”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他称自己1993年国企下海，次年在南京创办了中信房屋经纪公司（编者注：公开资料无法查询），从事二手房房产经纪工作。 1998年，他招聘了20岁零4个月的桑春华，当时桑没有任何房地产销售经验，月工资300元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那年正值法国世界杯，有一晚桑春华独自守店看球，遇上来查店的老板崔巍。两人边看球边聊了很久。崔比桑年长10岁。此后两人一起上青岛、进北京，将公司逐渐做大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;崔巍称，直到他对销售代理业务进行股份化改造，将一部分股份无偿赠予桑春华，桑才成为股东。随后公司进军房地产开发业务，他又将桑持有的销售代理公司股份平移进开发公司，先后授予其总经理、副董事长职位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，分股权被崔巍视为巨大错误，为今日纠纷埋下隐患。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但对于崔巍称其为学生和员工的说法，桑春华并不接受。他声称25年来，是“俩人创业，白手起家”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在9月14日的记者会上，桑春华介绍，他于1996年参加工作，1998年认识崔巍时，他已经是南京一家房地产公司的销售主管，做一手房业务，也是他动员当时还在做二手房的崔巍进军一手房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照桑春华的说法，北上青岛创业时，两人已确定股权比例70：30。2001年山东队伍解散，他和崔巍又来到北京，同年注册成立雅居乐。当时在恒基中心谈判股份，最终达成58：42的比例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“所谓赠送股份，无稽之谈，没出钱更是笑话。”桑春华直言。张永刚向南方周末记者提供了雅居乐的工商资料，显示公司注册资本1000万，崔巍以货币方式投入580万元，桑春华以货币方式投入420万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张永刚向南方周末记者介绍，2008年崔和桑成立华美乔戈里，将雅居乐的股份平移过来，依然延续58：42的比例，即为石榴集团前身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在9月14日的记者会上，桑春华表示，9月8日他曾主动约谈崔巍，提出停止纷争，但对方坚持大股东溢价30%。 “还是要抢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;境外架构的麻烦&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;石榴集团之所以出现公司治理乱象，是因为涉及境外架构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桑春华指出，2021年公司上市未果后，崔巍也不同意拆除境外架构。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企查查显示，石榴集团由北京岷江科技有限公司（下称岷江科技）100%持股，后者法定代表人为崔巍，股权穿透后是两家香港公司，香港公司又被注册于英属维尔京群岛的公司持股。在这一境外架构下，两大股东均不直接在境内持股。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;股权律师卢庆华曾代理过与石榴集团类似的股权纠纷，著有《公司控制权》一书。她向南方周末记者分析，境内公司石榴集团由岷江科技100%持股，岷江科技的法定代表人崔巍有权决定石榴集团董事会人选。在公司章程没有特殊约定情况下，法定代表人也有权管理公章。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月以来，石榴集团管理层大换血。辞退桑春华、林新武后，公司一天内新增4个董事、1个监事。据桑春华介绍，新任董事包括崔巍妻子祝艳华，其任职并未经过作为二股东的自己同意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在卢庆华看来，境外股权架构下，桑春华不直接持有石榴集团股份。这意味着，桑春华即便起诉崔巍解除其职务未经过合法程序，胜诉难度也较大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专注公司治理研究的中国人民大学财政金融学院教授郑志刚持不同看法。他向南方周末记者表示，股权结构最后依然要还原真正出资的个体，反映真实的出资方意愿。公司董事的任命和罢免都需要经多数股东表决同意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但他也同意，在境外架构下涉诉的话，境外裁决的实际法律效力可能会面临挑战，诉讼过程可能是艰难的拉锯战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑志刚介绍，石榴集团的纠纷反映了民营企业治理中的一些共性问题。不少民营企业在早期创业阶段以投入为主，创始人之间不分彼此，以亲情、友情等维系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司做大后，有些企业未能通过股权、薪酬等制度化方式处理好利润分配问题，或不重视通过引入外部投资者形成规范的公司架构，公司治理引发的问题往往导致其难以基业长青。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受纠纷影响，石榴集团开始面临银行抽贷风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兴业银行率先向石榴集团发送告知函，要求其在2023年8月12日前，将18亿元贷款本年度剩余应还本息金额7400万元存入监管账户。否则，兴业银行有权宣布全部贷款提前到期，并追究借款人及担保人违约责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石榴集团2022年公司债券年度报告显示，截至2022年末，石榴集团有息负债总额为166.78亿元。其中，1年期以内的银行贷款为3.75亿元，一年期以内的信托借款为11.46亿元。共计三个有息债券为存续状态，合计金额为29.16亿元，均将在2024年到期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而截至2022年底，石榴集团的货币资金仅有28.64亿元，其中5.36亿元为受限金额。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中张永刚为化名。南方周末记者施璇对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[槟榔可抗疫？清代岭南槟榔是如何传入湖南的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257184]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e3omQSpv9dvANv9zp23MpwIIPDQCbcg8IXxCkuDt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e3omQSpv9dvANv9zp23MpwIIPDQCbcg8IXxCkuDt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251274&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017年10月26日，海南万宁一槟榔加工厂，农户正在整理刚收购的槟榔。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岭南地区嚼食槟榔的习俗，与其药用价值有极深关系。湖南湘潭人嗜食槟榔，最初也是出于治病抗疫需要，只是一旦形成习惯就不能停。湘潭为清代岭南槟榔北上的主要集散地。乾隆四十四年至同治二年的几次湘潭大疫，促成了嚼食槟榔的习俗。据业内传说，引进槟榔的关键人物是湘潭知县白璟，白璟之父白为玺曾任广东英德知县，这是岭南槟榔被引入湘潭的特殊机缘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;辟瘴即是防疫&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;槟榔的药用价值，古人早有认识，东汉南海人杨孚《异物志》已记载食槟榔可以“下气”助消化，此后有关槟榔可以下气、消胀、驱虫、辟瘴、治疫的文献记载，层出不穷。湘潭大学张恩迅、申玲玲《瘴气、瘟疫与成瘾：地方社会变迁中槟榔食俗的传播与重构》一文，全面梳理了历代有关槟榔药用价值的论述，并指出：“唐宋时期槟榔是伴随中央政权开发岭南的除瘴工具，清（代）民（国）时期槟榔是见证近代中国商贸网络发展与地方社会变迁的治瘟药材。”此处的“治瘟”“除瘴”，换言之就是防疫治疫。无论是闽粤还是湖南，嚼食槟榔，最初的正当理由是防疫治疫，这并不排斥一些人为寻求快感、出于礼仪需要而食用槟榔，三者可以同时并存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古人多用药用植物辟瘴防疫，明末清初有人传播吸烟可以辟瘴的说法。清代湘潭文人朱声亨写过一篇《蔫说》：“吕宋产蔫叶，剉而吸之，谓能辟瘴。”湘潭人把烟叶叫做“蔫叶”。该文认为，吕宋烟在清初传入福建，很快就风靡全国，但最初人们吸烟的理由是“辟瘴”。朱声亨对吸烟的危害有深刻认识，指出“蔫之害与鸦片埒”。 （何歌劲辑注《湘潭历代文赋选》下册第504-505页）值得注意的是，烟草与槟榔都能成瘾。正如清廷把鸦片称为“洋药”，烟商、槟榔商人强调药用价值，是要消除人们对成瘾性食品的心理障碍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;嚼食槟榔能成瘾，浪掷金钱，与明清时期儒家价值观相违背。湖南社会长期崇尚节俭，主流文人对此十分排斥。湘潭知名学者罗汝怀就觉得嚼食槟榔浪费钱：“盖潭人之于槟榔，虽孩童时用咀嚼。尝闻之人云，其壮盛时日需百钱，而一家终岁之费，常在二三十缗，不亦傎（颠diān）乎？”（《罗汝怀集》第262页）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经营槟榔的商家，必须有冠冕堂皇的理由，抵挡儒生阶层的批评，诱人消费，治病、防疫就是最正当的理由。现代医学普及以前，人们普遍认为南方各省存在“瘴气”，岭南、湖南、贵州等地都曾被认为是“瘴区”，感染“瘴气”经常可以致命。那么，吸烟、嚼食槟榔，如果能辟“瘴气”，正当性就无可置疑，毕竟保命还是第一位的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乾隆四十四年湘潭大疫，知县白璟用槟榔治疗居民的“鼓胀病”，由此形成嚼食槟榔习俗，此后历经几次大疫而全面普及，这个解释似最为合理。乾隆朝两部《湘潭县志》还没有提到槟榔，嘉庆《湘潭县志》则明确记载“槟榔、蔫叶，所在酷嗜”，可证明此俗形成于乾隆朝晚期与嘉庆朝前期之间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jCrzhRxq7xXdSOsG8coxqKII3uojM8yiaKJ0hOlx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;833&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jCrzhRxq7xXdSOsG8coxqKII3uojM8yiaKJ0hOlx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251273&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;曹雨《一嚼两千年：从药品到瘾品，槟榔在中国的流行史》书影。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;湘潭知县白璟的推动&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;青年学者曹雨《一嚼两千年：从药品到瘾品，槟榔在中国的流行史》一书，尝试对湖南湘潭嚼食槟榔习俗的由来做新的解释。他综合各方研究成果，揭示湘潭既是米市也是药材集散中心，同治年间槟榔存货充足、湘军回乡促使消费能力提升。岭南槟榔北上的陆路贸易，原本有东线（经江西）、西线（经湖南）两条线路，太平天国战争使东线受阻，湘潭的商业中心地位在太平天国战争期间得到强化。岭南槟榔越岭而北，都先聚集到湘潭，再分销各地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹雨将目光聚焦于1864年湘军遣散一事，在书中下了这么两个结论：“湘潭地区嚼食槟榔的习惯，很有可能就是这两股力量——积压了槟榔的商人和持币待购的退伍士兵——共同推动而形成的。”“湘潭嚼食槟榔习俗大兴于1864年至1880年间，在此期间湘潭并未发生过大范围的瘟疫，因此嚼食槟榔避疫的传说不是历史事实……”曹雨挑选了光绪《湘潭县志》记载的疫症空白时段作论证，但嘉庆《湘潭县志》记载嘉庆前期湘潭槟榔消费已十分盛行，这个记述被无视了。如果一定要考虑遣散湘军的作用，我认为这些退伍士兵只是将槟榔食俗传播到湖南各县。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/RcwjQ3vjzJX6sZUqrKPfwet1YlrZrwuoxkQGBOnP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;601&quot; height=&quot;911&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/RcwjQ3vjzJX6sZUqrKPfwet1YlrZrwuoxkQGBOnP.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251272&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《湘潭县志》关于槟榔食俗的记载。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王闿运总纂、光绪十五年刊行的《湘潭县志》，是研究湘潭槟榔食俗的基本史料。该书卷九《货殖》称：“广商则银朱、葵扇、槟榔为大，家日剖数十口，店行倍蓰焉。……计每日得百钱之利，月当糜钱五六百万，如此岁费钱二百余万万……为费甚矣。”银朱、槟榔是以药材身份来到湘潭，只是槟榔的成瘾性使消费者一经接受即甚难停止。王闿运作为本地文人领袖，对槟榔消费十分厌恶，他在县志序文中抨击“槟榔之费，拟埒稻粱”，意谓湘潭人买槟榔的开销与粮食开支差不多相等。职是之故，王闿运在志书中，只谈槟榔生意规模，不乐意探讨湘潭槟榔消费的起源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;笔者认为，湘潭槟榔消费习俗，是清代几次大疫所推动，关键年份则是乾隆四十四年。光绪《湘潭县志》卷九《五行志·疫》记载“乾隆四十四年大疫”“道光十六年四月大疫” “（道光）二十二年大疫”“同治二年七月疫”。乾隆四十四年为1779年，这是槟榔食俗在湘潭形成的关键年份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湘潭槟榔业元老黄俊良记录了这样一个传说：乾隆四十四年大疫，许多居民患鼓胀病，吃药无效。县令广东人白璟，谙医理，明药性，将赴任带来的药用槟榔分给患者嚼之，嚼后均觉腹部舒服，再多次嚼之膨胀消失，病痛解除。尔后，原患者嚼之，未患者也随之而嚼，习惯逐渐形成，“不过那时把槟榔当作一种药物。”（黄俊良：《我所知道的湘潭槟榔业》，载《湘潭文史》第12辑）黄俊良自1926年入槟榔店当学徒，他所了解的白璟事迹，属于业内共同记忆，不可忽视。周大鸣、张恩迅、申玲玲等学者，因发现白璟籍贯奉天而怀疑业内传说的真实性，可以理解，但他们没有留意到白璟与广东的渊源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白璟字希宋，号璞斋，奉天镶白旗汉军旗人。他在湘潭知县任上，自撰《燕喜亭碑记》一文称：“予奉家慈就养于署，时勖予曰汝父宰英德，有善政……”（嘉庆《湘潭县志·艺文》）也即白璟的父亲当过广东英德县知县。查道光《英德县志》，乾隆十五年至十九年的知县白为玺，镶白旗人。据此可大体确定，白为玺就是白璟的父亲。官员眷属多随任居住，白璟应在广东居住过，由是被误会为“广东人”。笔者认为，正是他们父子在广东的经历，使白璟在湘潭大疫、“鼓胀病”流行时，用从广东带来的药用槟榔给居民治病。王闿运对白璟有成见，或者就是因他引入槟榔一事而起。在《湘潭县志》官师传里面，王闿运议论白璟施政“稍任己意，或有所偏颇，至今论者异同”，在《五行志·疫》“乾隆四十四年大疫”下面，王闿运写上“牧令主其休咎也”，表明他对白璟非常不满。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道光十六年（1836）、二十二年（1842）、同治二年（1863）湘潭又发生几次大疫，促成槟榔食俗在湘潭真正普及。湘潭人嚼食槟榔习俗的形成，供货充足只是充分条件，几次大疫的发生才是必要条件，而习俗形成的关键人物则是知县白璟。湘潭槟榔食俗，于乾隆四十四年得白璟的提倡开始形成，经过几次大疫进一步普及，而有关槟榔辟瘟防瘴的传统医学学说，则将二者成功串联起来。现代医学证明，嚼食槟榔有引发口腔癌的危险，至于其防疫作用则见仁见智，但古人是相信的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博主用无人机跟踪女性被抓，高科技产品何以沦为隐私“刺客”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257244]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 23:22:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[引资、清欠、对接客户，民营经济发展局的地方经验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257186]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Rvy8q7luPDejmkqUB9hN86ERPv2YIOGA9TsHDna4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1123&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Rvy8q7luPDejmkqUB9hN86ERPv2YIOGA9TsHDna4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月4日，国家发展改革委副主任丛亮介绍，中央编办正式批复在国家发改委内部设立民营经济发展局。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;民营经济发展局，一经设立，便吸引了全社会的目光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月4日，国家发展改革委副主任丛亮介绍，中央编办正式批复在国家发改委内部设立民营经济发展局。它是促进民营经济发展壮大的专门机构，作用在于加强相关领域政策统筹协调，推动各项重大举措落地见效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丛亮介绍，该局的主要职责是制定促进民营经济发展政策，建立与民营企业的沟通交流机制。在百余字的职责表述中，未见“管理”相关字样，以“服务”为主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是国家部委层面首次设立民营经济发展局，但地方上，对它并不陌生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者搜寻企查查和各地政府官网发现，国内各地高峰时曾有民营经济发展局、民营经济发展促进局、民营经济发展服务局等相关机构200余个，现在仍有民营经济发展局180余个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它们分属于各地的不同部门。如地方的工信部门会设有中小企业发展机构、市场监管部门也有推动民营经济的内设机构，人社、税务、司法、金融监管部门也会根据需要设有相应服务处室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;起点在2000年左右，那时部分省、市、区县开始设立民营经济发展相关部门，并加挂乡镇企业管理局或中小企业局的牌子，而后名称也会多次变更。2019年后，各地中小企业局在机构改革调整下撤销，现已成为地方工信局、经信局或市场监管局的下设处室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大部分相关机构，是在已有的机构上加挂一块牌子，即一套班子、两块牌子，仅有少部分地区，单独设立了“民营经济发展局”作为市政府组成部门，比如青岛、雅安、济南、重庆北碚区、重庆九龙坡区等，它们普遍在2019年以后成立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些地方经验，能为国家级部门提供怎样的探索经验和启示？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;多地早有民营局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在2000年前后，部分省政府一级就已设有负责民营经济的机构，名称为乡镇企业管理局、民营经济管理局、中小企业局等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在多次机构改革后，它们的身影已经模糊了，现在只能通过政府官网的干部履历、当年的预决算、单位简介、职能介绍等公示文件窥得其发展脉络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，山东德州市禹城市工信局的一位干部履历写着，1997年至2013年供职于禹城市民营经济发展局，此后，供职单位变为禹城市经济和信息化局，2019年后再变为禹城市工业和信息化局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又如，山西吕梁离石区中小企业服务中心在官网简介中详述了自己的发展历程，其前身为1976年的离石县社队企业管理局，1984年改为离石县乡镇企业管理局，2002年机构改革后成立了离石市乡镇企业服务中心，挂牌离石市民营经济发展局。这一机构开始负责全区中小企业、乡镇企业和民营经济的监督、指导、协调和服务。2004年8月，再度更名为“离石区中小企业局”，保留“离石区民营经济发展局”的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《山西经济：改革开放四十年》一书中介绍，2003年，山西省调整组织结构，将省级的乡镇企业管理局过渡至民营经济发展局，次年，加挂了山西省中小企业局的牌子。自此，山西省11个地级市、119个县市区均成立了中小企业局，职能也由原来的乡镇企业扩大到县域经济、民营经济、中小企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东青岛市民营经济发展局办公室主任李晓峰告诉南方周末记者，2019年机构改革前后，全国各地中小企业局撤并转，原中小企业局职能并入当地工信局、经信局、市场监管局，在这些部门加挂中小企业局牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，山西省太原市、朔州市、吕梁市、阳泉市、运城市等地工信局都加挂了民营经济发展促进局的牌子，下辖的区县也在工信部门加挂民营经济发展促进局的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温州是在市经济和信息化局加挂了民营经济健康发展促进局的牌子。四川省的广安、自贡、资阳也在经信局挂了民营经济发展局的牌子，内江、阿坝州、凉山州则是在市场监管局挂牌民营经济发展局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十余年来，民营经济发展局在地方政府机构设置中的成批出现与中央推出鼓励民营经济发展的政策波峰大致吻合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，“非公经济36条”是新中国成立以来首部促进非公经济发展的中央文件。2019年，中共中央、国务院印发《关于营造更好发展环境支持民营企业改革发展的意见》，多方面支持民营经济。2023年，《中共中央&amp;nbsp;国务院关于促进民营经济发展壮大的意见》公开发布，提出31条政策措施，鼓励促进民营企业做优做大做强。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;需要综合协调部门&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2015年，李晓峰就职于青岛市工商局下属的企业注册局民营经济发展处，做民营企业综合协调的工作，包括制定全市民营经济工作要点和将原来散落在各个部门的关于民营市场主体的相关数据归拢。“还是做宏观梳理的工作，了解面上的情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工商局对民营经济的工作范围也仅限于此，其他部门虽也有跟民营经济相关的工作，但都是在各自范围内落实职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，青岛市政府进行机构改革，在限额38个工作部门的条件下，将民营经济发展局和海洋局加入改革方案，这两个局成为了市政府的组成部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时，李晓峰调任至民营经济发展局，先后任协调指导处处长、办公室主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他向南方周末记者解释，以往不同单位虽都有服务民营经济的部门，但由于职能限制，关注点各有侧重。比如，工信部门更关注工业企业及其产业，科技、商务等部门则关注高新技术、消费类企业及其行业发展，必须要成立一个专职部门才能涵盖民营经济发展各个方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比在原先的机构，李晓峰发现，民营经济发展局这一专设部门更能发挥协调作用，“我们现在就是做综合协调、平台搭建等服务工作，不是行业主管部门，更接近综合部门的角色”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一角色的优势在于方便协调各个部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“民营经济工作涉及面宽、政策性强，需要各个部门密切协作配合，形成工作合力。”国家发改委副秘书长兼人事司司长张世昕接受采访时也有类似表述，在国家发改委设立民营经济发展局，也为了能更好发挥统筹协调、综合施策、促进发展的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但李晓峰认为，在国家层面，民营经济发展局属于国家发展改革委的内设机构，对于地方上已经单设但没有放在发改委的相关部门，没有必要撤并。“服务民营企业本就涉及多部门协调配合，职能上也不会存在交叉、冲突的问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在青岛民营经济不是支撑半边天，而是主力军。”李晓峰告诉南方周末记者，2019年到2020年间，青岛的民间投资依旧能保持两位数增长。2023年1月-7月，青岛民间投资增长6.1%，高于出全国6.6个百分点。民间投资在建项目拉动投资3.6个百分点，对全市投资增长贡献率77.3%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南市民营经济发展局办公室书面回复南方周末记者：该局于2019年3月设立，2019年上半年济南民营市场主体数量为99.33万户，目前为150.5万户，占全市市场主体数量的98.6%。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;服务符合产业需要的民营企业&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;做好服务的第一步是让民营企业和当地民营局相互了解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛民营局一方面通过街道区市掌握民营企业情况，设置了由政府人员和企业服务机构组成的300名企业政策服务专员，另一方面通过梯度培育管理为民营企业设置不同成长赛道，发掘有发展潜力的中小企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛云路股份（688190.SH）项目负责人耿润儿告诉南方周末记者，获评政府给予的荣誉称号是对企业的肯定，为投资机构、金融机构判断企业价值提供衡量标准，一定程度上有助于企业融资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;云路股份从事先进磁性金属材料设计研发及销售，是一家有央企持股的混合所有制企业。耿润儿主要负责项目申报等工作。她说，公司在当地政府支持下已成为独角兽企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在青岛市2023年创新型中小企业公示名单中，获评企业多为高新技术等新型制造业，偶有一两家食品、服饰行业相关企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家青岛制衣厂的负责人告诉南方周末记者，“我们可能接触过民营局，但了解不多”。目前企业面临的主要困境是用工成本高，行业内的服装工厂很多转移至人力成本更低的东南亚、印度等地。她的企业主要承接代工的外贸订单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多人宁愿到市区办公室里挣三千的工资，也不愿意在厂里工作，（工资）开到六千多都没人来。”她说。她现在也在为企业寻求转型，不再走代加工模式，尝试通过网络平台经营自主品牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓峰说，每个地方政府都有其着重发展的产业。青岛市有24条重点产业链，与青岛城市产业规划和发展需要相契合。纺织服装更是24条产业链中的优势产业链，如青岛酷特智能企业，就是在服装个性化智能定制上找到了转型路径。“还是要看企业的模式和核心竞争力是否适应社会形势的发展变化，以有效应对市场化的优胜劣汰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在济南，民营局的主要做法包括搭建民营经济监测分析服务系统，监测分析营业收入、利税、研发投入等综合指标，动态掌握民营企业发展情况。该局也提请市政府出台《关于开展攀登行动支持民营企业跨越发展的若干措施》，明确实施融资促进等5大行动21条培育措施，开展为期5年的精准培育。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家位于济南的密码企业的工作人员表示，济南市政府相关部门曾为他们解决过办公场地产权、对接融资需求等问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一家位于济南的生物医药企业的工作人员告诉南方周末记者，他们在当地是龙头企业，济南近些年营商环境发展力度大，市里成立专班服务龙头企业，“毕竟大企业体量大、贡献大”。他肯定了政府的工作，但也表示企业个性化的问题难以面面俱到、服务到位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，济南四大主导产业分别是大数据与新一代信息技术产业、智能制造与高端装备产业、生物医药与大健康产业、精品钢与先进材料产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;企业什么时候需要政府？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;由于工作缘故，李晓峰常能接触到各种规模的民营企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，过去企业与政府打交道，希望政府最好无事不扰，但在企业发展初期和瓶颈期等关键时期，也需要政府出手，提供资源上的支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耿润儿曾代表公司参与过民营经济发展局组织的创意会，企业以创意方案提出发展诉求。云路股份与下游企业共同提交的方案是非晶高效节能变压器，主要面向的客户是各地供电局和城市轨道交通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一场创意会将邀请3-5家企业分享提案。到场的除了企业代表外，还有政府工作人员、项目评审人员和受邀前来的客户代表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在政府的平台上向国企用户推介产品无疑是快速打开客源、建立双方信任的一条捷径。创意会结束两个月后，云路股份顺利参加了后续项目落地的沟通推进会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓峰告诉南方周末记者，参加创意会的企业各类规模都有，前期会遴选企业提出的创意，入选创意由民营局联系专家和政府有关部门做充分论证，符合青岛产业发展方向的项目则能进入后续的推进会，并协调各相关部门解决项目和产业发展所需的资源，如企业普遍关注的土地、人才、资金等。自2019年至今，已举办十多场，吸引到落地的投资金额约四百亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耿润儿说，由于他们处于关键材料技术这类“卡脖子”的行业，人才需求迫切，民营局曾连同人社局帮助企业引进一名日籍专家，并为专家解决了人才绿卡问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;资金方面，李晓峰介绍，除了部分企业上市后有一定奖补外，民营局融资合作处也会组织“政银企”等对接会活动，引导有需求的民营企业对接金融机构，企业提金融需求，金融机构推介产品。“相比企业自己挨家挨户找银行机构对接，他参加对接活动一次就能接触八到十家金融机构。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南民营经济发展局在书面答复中也提到，他们设立万家潜力企业培育库、千家重点企业培育库和百家投资机构库，对接本市民营企业获得280轮次基金投资。同时，也推动企业融资需求与银行对接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁盛是一家为政府部门提供服务型产品的企业负责人，他的企业曾在全国多地开展业务，主要通过竞标获得政府采购项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，大多数向政府提供服务类产品的民营企业，免不了遇到“要账难”的问题，账款迟迟难以到位时有发生，部分民营企业还会碰到“新官不理旧账”的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，国家发改委等多部门出台28条具体措施，推动破解民营经济发展中面临的突出问题，其中包括加大对拖欠民营企业账款的清理力度，重点清理机关、事业单位、国有企业拖欠中小微企业的账款等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓峰介绍，青岛民营局从成立初期就关注到这一问题，2019年开始为中小企业清理欠款。只要企业提出来，对于经过排查后确认存在拖欠账款情况的政府部门，民营局牵头下发督办单，督促其分期分批清偿拖欠中小企业的账款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中梁盛为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[室同道合？一份包含MBTI的大学宿舍分配问卷背后]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257236]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WMQEIGA7Wvi4EPEkbHyFT4Z5APMlsNC8bZMa7Kli.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;753&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WMQEIGA7Wvi4EPEkbHyFT4Z5APMlsNC8bZMa7Kli.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（农健/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;距离开学还有一周，2023年8月10日晚，北京理工大学知艺书院2023级115名本科新生收到一份问卷，内容包含MBTI、喜欢的“爱豆”（idol，指偶像艺人），以及作息习惯。这份问卷是为新生宿舍分配准备的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二天天还没亮，宿舍名单就出炉了。受委托设计问卷的是他们的学姐，知艺书院2022级学生吕嘉慧，她的设计初衷是，希望依据问卷结果把相同圈子的人聚集在一起，“让他们更快乐地度过大学四年”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吕嘉慧自己的宿舍经历有些遗憾，舍友们爱好各自不同，“基本相当于没什么话聊”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很快，这张问卷被发上社交媒体，“北理工宿舍分配统计MBTI”的话题登上热搜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，高校的宿舍分配往往采取随机方式。如今，越来越多高校开始探索其他方法，MBTI只是最新的一种。南京大学、成都大学用问卷收集新生信息，再通过算法为他们分配或推荐舍友；而中国传媒大学、珠海科技学院（原吉林大学珠海学院）等一些学校将选择权完全交给学生，让学生自发组织，将写有自己生活习惯、性格与爱好的“简历”公开，用以寻找契合的舍友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看似五花八门的分配方式，多多少少是为了规避可能发生的大学宿舍矛盾。江西财经大学人文学院讲师王青对大学宿舍关系有过研究，她觉得，“如果在编排宿舍时考虑到这些因素的话，会在一定程度上减少矛盾。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宿舍矛盾背后又有另一番更深入的青年社交文化变迁。王青也认同：宿舍分配只能解决一部分矛盾。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“北理工宿舍分配统计&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;MBTI”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这份宿舍分配问卷上，最受关注的问题便是MBTI，这是如今最流行的一种性格测试。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MBTI是迈尔斯-布里格斯类型指标的简称，测试结果由4个字母组成，指代一个人在注意力方向、认知方式、判断方式和生活方式4个维度上的倾向性。制定者是一对美国母女，她们的姓氏分别为布里格斯和迈尔斯，在这对非心理学专业背景的母女眼中，用四把标尺，就可以把复杂的人性归类成16种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MBTI测试已被广泛应用在公司招聘和团队建设，但对它的科学性的质疑亦不断，有研究发现，一半以上人在隔了几周或一年多后重新测试，会得到不同的结果，因此其一致性、稳定性及可靠性存在缺陷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为115名新生分配宿舍的吕嘉慧是“朋辈导师”，即在新生群内答疑解惑的学长。她相信MBTI的准确性。她的MBTI类型是“entj”，被称为指挥官型人格，这类人往往决策迅速，行动力强。仅用一个半小时，她就完成问卷设计，10日晚上七点半发出，11日凌晨四点半，全年级的宿舍分配结果就被发到了群里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问卷很快被发到网上，8月12日，吕嘉慧发现，“北理工宿舍分配统计MBTI”词条在热搜榜挂了近十个小时，最高第二位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了MBTI，问卷被讨论的内容还包括是否打呼噜、说梦话、起夜、追星、“二刺螈”（二次元）等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问卷也在北理工内部引发关注。“我（辅）导员的电话被其他院（辅）导员打爆了。”接着，问卷实现了校内普及，有人在吕嘉慧的社交媒体留言一张同款问卷截图：“经管书院也有啦！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这股潮流还传到了更多高校。8月29日，广东财经大学智能财会管理学院一名学生发现，她所在学院为分配宿舍收集的问卷只包含MBTI类型，最后的分配结果，也主要以“i人”（内向）和“e人”（外向）区分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西南政法大学法学院辅导员茹婧斐，则在自己的就业指导和心理健康课上寻找灵感。她设计的问卷除了MBTI，还有向毕业生征集的“宿舍生活中容易引发矛盾的问题”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，很多高校都开始拒绝过往的“开盲盒”方式，也就是随机分配的宿舍分配方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以往的宿舍分配，主要考虑将相同专业、班级，相邻学号的学生分在一起，而学号的排序通常参考姓氏拼音、笔画等。也有学校按照报到顺序安排宿舍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，成都大学让新生填写包含“你是社牛还是社恐”“你是否接受榴莲、螺蛳粉等异味食品”等问题的问卷，来为新生匹配舍友。同年，据兰州大学公众号介绍，为了“让同学们能选到自己志同道合的舍友”，一些学院推出了互选舍友的分配宿舍方法，学生像“写简历”一样在群内发布自我介绍和对舍友的期待，以此双向选择。电子科技大学2023级新生在网上自主选房时，可以查看某一房间中已选舍友的起床、睡眠习惯信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zO1vXlylqmdxb8XSjKWbv3lP67K8DLqIsXTODMm5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;988&quot; height=&quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zO1vXlylqmdxb8XSjKWbv3lP67K8DLqIsXTODMm5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月16日，学长在浙江省湖州学院指引2023级新生办理报到手续。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;有&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;i有&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;e&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;更有趣&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;争议声也随之而来：用MBTI分到的舍友是否靠谱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在吕嘉慧的构想中，MBTI并不是最重要的。她优先考虑的是问卷中一道关于“其他需求”的开放性填空题，之后的考量次序是：个人作息习惯、兴趣爱好，然后才是MBTI。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那道开放性填空题，有些人按提示填了想和谁在一起住，双方都愿意，就会被分在一起；有人填了“不想和追星的人在一个宿舍”。而通过收集到的问卷答案，吕嘉慧没法判断谁能接受这些预料外的需求，但她设置了一道关于“包容度”自评题，满分为5分——自评分数高的人，被认为有更大概率接受舍友的个性化需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在广东财经大学智能财会管理学院的宿舍分配中，一名新生观察到，配置大概是一个宿舍“两i两e”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;茹婧斐没有直接判断哪些人格适配，她提醒学生们考虑各自需要性格互补还是相似的舍友，又建议，“有i有e会让宿舍生活更加有趣”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同的分配方式与不同的需求相关，即便是在生源地这一指标上，不同人也有不同考量。西南政法地处重庆，茹婧斐不建议一个宿舍的人都来自同一个地方，并认为“一个宿舍里最好有一个川渝人，这样出去玩的时候会方便很多”。而吕嘉慧最害怕的，是南北饮食习惯差异，“吃不到一块就挺难受的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰州大学主张“多元文化交融”，有学院规定“每个宿舍均有来自南方与北方的同学”“生源省份不少于3个”。“多元”还有另一层意味，2022年，该校法学院为了避免“早八”集体迟到，为每个宿舍分配了一位习惯早起的同学，担任着每个宿舍的“报晓公鸡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;方案各有不同，但大部分设计者在意的点，其实是舍友之间能不能聊到一块。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“关起门来，宿舍就是一个圈子。”一个显著的对比是，吕嘉慧好朋友的大学宿舍全是“二次元”，能玩得很好；而她自己的舍友，有追韩娱的，有喜欢赛车的，“基本相当于没什么话聊”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南京大学从2017年开始设置调查问卷，不仅统计兴趣爱好，还通过算法在不同爱好之间找到潜在关联。该校学生工作处老师郭亚敏曾向媒体介绍，“00后”兴趣爱好广泛，分散度高，学校的“隐语义模型”算法能够通过一些隐含特征，从学生已有的爱好，推算出他可能感兴趣的方面，再匹配室友，比如把喜欢戏剧的和喜欢历史的，喜欢生物的和喜欢物理的放在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并且，南京大学的问卷每年都在调整，郭亚敏对南方周末记者解释，“孩子一代一代的，关注点不一样”。在2023年的问卷中，新生被问及舍友一起出去消费更倾向于AA制（所有人平均分担所需费用）还是轮流请客，能否接受舍友邀请其周末与朋友一起出行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭亚敏表示，“现在孩子从小到大都是自己单独住的，一下子进入集体生活，总有很多不适应的地方。”而学校的做法是希望尽量减轻“不适应”，不要把差距过大的人分在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;一场宿舍关系干预实验&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;江西财经大学人文学院讲师王青，曾试图通过自己的实验找到一套大学宿舍关系磨合的方法论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王青从2016年起担任了5年班主任，主动或被动地介入不少宿舍矛盾。有学生私下向她求助：和宿舍的某某关系很不好，造成了很大困扰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年之前，江西财经大学采取班内随机的方式分配宿舍。到了2020年，王青决定抽取一部分宿舍，人为地干预宿舍关系的走向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚开始，考虑到人文学院女生多，王青决定先从女大学生宿舍入手。她在4个班级的大一女生中抽选了38名学生，以宿舍为单位，入学后每月开展1次“舍情相约”的小组活动，总共开展了三次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来却发现，男生的宿舍矛盾问题更严重，只是他们不善于求助。王青调研得知，男生宿舍肢体冲突率更高，亲密融合程度、对宿舍人际关系满意度也都低于女生宿舍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;活动的主题与宿舍关系的机制相关。王青分析，宿舍是公私属性混合在一起的空间，个人在里面吃饭、睡觉，但又把陌生人组合在一起生活。在这样的空间里，学生需要学习如何把握好尺度——什么是个人可以发挥的地方，什么是要尊重他人的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次活动的主题就是公共秩序。王青模拟了一个场景：晚上11点，你很累了想睡觉，闭上了眼睛，舍友正在焦急地赶作业，噼里啪啦地打电脑。王青希望通过换位思考，让宿舍集体产生第一条公约：严格遵守作息制度，不干扰他人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，她制定了一本27页的干预手册，当中规划了每一次活动的流程，其中提到“小团体”等常见的宿舍危机。她尝试引导学生思考，当这些情景发生在自己宿舍时，应该如何解决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三次活动结束，学生的反馈达到她预期的效果。她们接受了两次测试，对比活动举办前后的宿舍人际关系质量发展，调查内容包括发生冷战、口角冲突等紧张的情况，以及宿舍内部的集体活动、情感交流情况，学生们还被问到，对宿舍关系的满意程度，和是否希望申请调换宿舍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另有36名没参与过活动的女大学生，也接受了这项测试。两相比较下，王青得出结论：合适恰当的沟通干预，的确能够提前消除人际之间的矛盾与疏离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年之后，王青不再担任班主任。而当了七年辅导员、带过1200多名学生的茹婧斐发现，大学生的宿舍矛盾问题越来越多，且趋向于在低年级爆发。她曾半夜被叫到学生宿舍处理一起打架事件，“能调和就调和，实在不行只有换（宿舍）”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王青介绍，目前中国针对大学生宿舍矛盾的干预一般以事后修复、补救为主，从学校管理的层面来说，可以定期筛选出一部分关系不太好的宿舍进行干预。不过，王青也很清楚，随着时间推移，原本的干预所产生的效果，还是会越来越弱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个原因在于，新一代的学生，观念、心理和行为逻辑，都在发生变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;卧谈会成传说&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在如今的学校管理者构想中，对宿舍分配的干预，能更早避免一些可预见的矛盾。上海海洋大学一份对全国3875名大学生的调查显示，学生对宿舍关系不满意的主要原因依次是作息习惯、个人卫生、内/外向性格、是否玩游戏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但干预宿舍分配并非一劳永逸，茹婧斐认为即使目前已经优化分配方式，也只可能解决作息这类表面矛盾。她和其他辅导员常讨论：学生的自我意识变强，接触的信息变多，都给宿舍关系带来变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位辅导员和王青聊天时说到，70后、80后的学生会认为，舍友可能是人生里很重要的伙伴，不仅在读书阶段给人很大影响，毕业之后还能成为情感、事业上成长的助力。但现在，很多孩子进入大学以后有很明确的目标：保研、出国……从大一开始，他们就会遵从目标来安排自己的生活，不参与聚餐等集体活动，宿舍可能只是自己的歇脚地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数字化也在加剧这种个体孤独。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约二十年前王青上大学时，手机还只用来打电话、发短信，那时很重要的宿舍活动是熄灯以后的卧谈，“现在孩子其实很多没有卧谈了，每个人都很忙，手机能满足很多需求，人和人之间的联系，亲密度、融合度就会降低很多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京化工大学心理中心2019年曾对该校400名学生展开调查，80%以上的学生认为宿舍关系和谐，但将近一半的人承认在相处过程中存在摩擦。当被要求用一句话来描述宿舍关系时，40%选择了“亲如一家”，而更多人选择“普通朋友”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不再担任班主任的王青，仍然对学生们的状况忧心。“每年（宿舍矛盾）都会出现，所以我觉得这不是一个偶然问题，有很大一部分群体在读书期间都会有这样的问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吕嘉慧也拿不准分配宿舍的效果。她准备在9月中旬验证宿舍分配的效果，对愿意接受采访的新生进行线下或线上的匿名调查，问问他们与舍友相处得如何。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些更尖锐的问题，靠宿舍分配无法规避。王青举例，比如宿舍里的两个人，正好是参评奖学金的两个人选，他们就可能有潜在的利益矛盾，此外，专业上的看法、为人处世等，也都可能引发冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王青把2020年的这次实验写成《女大学生宿舍人际关系小组工作干预效果分析》一文，文章中她总结道：大学生宿舍人际关系质量在相处之初最高，后续会逐步变差。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名学生对王青说过的话，让她印象很深：“舍友不是我朋友，我们只是搭伙在一起住宿而已。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 22:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[发明了火药的中国，为何明清时火器技术落后了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257188]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;火药是中国古代四大发明之一，但围绕火药也有一些争议，比如鲁迅说“外国用火药制造子弹御敌，中国却用它做爆竹敬神”，又如近年网上有人主张19世纪出现欧洲人发明的黄火药才是真正的火药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两种说法是值得商榷的。中国发现火药后，很早就用来制作各种火器用在战场上。世界从中世纪进入近代，整个过程也全都靠的是黑火药，黄火药在近代晚期给这一进程大大加速，但不能忽略黑火药的意义，而且如果没有黑火药做基础，欧洲人也无法发明黄火药。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国火器的巨大潜力&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;火药最初出现在道士的炼丹炉中，是当成药物来使用的。古代医学认为硝石可以治内热、胃胀，硫磺可以“化金银铜铁”，二者合起来是一种治病的药物，所以叫火药，《本草纲目》认为“火药可以驱虫辟邪”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成书于唐代中期的《真元妙道要略》记录了最早的火药的威力，硝石、硫磺、雄黄与蜜一起烧可以引起爆燃，很快就能把房屋烧个干净。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;火药发明后，很快被用于战场，唐末的军阀混战中就有人使用“飞火”。北宋《武经总要》记载了当时火药的配方，爆炸要用到的硝石含量很低，倒是各式助燃剂如油、松脂、沥青的含量很高，可见此时的火药在战争中的作用是燃烧弹而非炸弹、子弹，此外，这时的火药有时候还会加入砒霜来燃烧，让敌军中毒，可以说是世界上最早的化学武器。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个唐代和北宋，中国的火药常用来制作燃烧武器，如火药箭、火蒺藜、火毬、毒药烟球、火炮（裹了火药的炮石，由投石车抛射）等，都是燃烧性火器，其中宋初冯继升研发的火药箭利用火药燃烧的后坐力来推射箭矢，堪称是今天火箭的雏形。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，就技术含量和效能而言，这些火器没有超越同时代的欧洲。公元678年，东罗马帝国面对阿拉伯帝国二十万大军围城，使用铜管喷射“希腊火”焚烧敌舰，全歼了庞大的阿拉伯海军。“希腊火”的配方已经失传，但应该是石油为主的化合物，可以在水面燃烧，配合机械喷射威力巨大。“希腊火”此后长期成为守卫君士坦丁堡海面的秘密武器，诸多强敌折戟于“希腊火”之下，毫无办法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了宋金对峙的时代，因为宋金之间战争频繁，双方分别发明新火器辅助作战，中国火器获得巨大发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋将陈规发明了火枪，虽然此时其作用接近喷火器而非枪械，但管形竹筒的设计为枪械准备了条件；宋将魏胜发明了安装火枪的“如意战车”，用畜力拖动。南宋给所有战船都安装投掷火炮（燃烧弹）的抛石机，完颜亮侵宋时，宋将李宝率水军奇袭金军的水师基地陈家岛，就是利用火箭、火炮等燃烧火器全歼规模巨大的金军舟师，可以说此时中国的水战武器也达到了“希腊火”的水平，南宋炮船可以算世界上最早的炮舰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金人则发明了世界上最早的大炮——攻城用的铁火炮；比竹竿火枪燃烧效果更佳的飞火枪，堪称单兵喷火器；还有用铁罐装火药制成的震天雷，点火后扔出去，声音吓人，炸裂的铁罐碎片对四周溅射伤害，可谓世界上最早的炸弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋蒙战争中，宋人又发明了最早的枪械——竹制的突火枪，发射子弹杀敌，最远可到一百五十步，元代则将突火枪从竹制改为金属制，打造出金属火铳，到了元末，已经在军中普及开来。不过直到元初，中国的火器仍是以燃烧性火器为主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从南宋到元代，中国火器基本上涵盖了直到现代仍在使用的所有门类的热兵器。不过，伊斯兰世界很快就学会了各种门类的中国火器，在研发上甚至更胜一筹，传到欧洲之后，欧洲火器更是飞速发展，把世界其他部分远远甩开。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中东和欧洲后来居上&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;宋代是中国和伊斯兰世界商贸、文化交流的黄金时代，许多阿拉伯人、波斯人、中亚人定居中国，甚至受雇于宋军，他们很快就把火药和火器的知识传回阿拉伯。另外，蒙古西征时对伊斯兰世界广泛使用了火器，也促进了他们对火器的学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1240年，植物学家、安达卢斯（今西班牙南部）的伊本•贝塔尔在其著作《医方汇编》中介绍了中国的硝石，将其称为“中国雪”“焰硝花”，介绍了其爆燃属性。1256年，忽必烈之弟旭烈兀在波斯建立伊尔汗国，效力于伊尔汗国的叙利亚人哈桑•拉曼撰写了一部兵书《马术与战争策略大全》，详细介绍了中国的火器、火药配方和硝石提纯等技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西亚、北非本来盛产硫磺，但是不知道硝的用处，所以没能发明火药，一旦知道火药怎样合成，伊斯兰世界的火器就迅速发展起来。统治埃及的马穆鲁克王朝就在突火枪的基础上创造出新式火器“马达法”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“马达法”用较大的木筒取代了中式的竹制枪筒，用石球取代了中式的弹丸，实际上把突火枪改造成了近代火炮的雏形；还有一种是在木筒里装箭，用火药推射铁箭攻击，可能是来自环地中海地区弩炮的传统，后来欧洲最早的火炮也是推射铁箭攻击，应该就是受此影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马达法实际上已经优于元朝和蒙古各汗国的火器，而且，中世纪的阿拉伯人喜欢做实验，从炼金术生发出来的化学非常杰出，火药提纯也胜过中国，堪称后来居上，也就是说，日后欧洲人向伊斯兰世界学习火器，起点比中国更高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲最早记载火器的文献是1326年伦敦主教为英王爱德华三世作的加冕辞，加冕辞下方就画着瓶型火炮，用火药发射巨箭。在欧洲，争霸不休的意大利城邦最先掌握了火器的制造技术，随后，火器也被英法德掌握，并且在英法百年战争中大放异彩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正是在百年战争中，欧洲的大炮把目标从杀伤人员转向攻城，欧洲人开始制造能够轰塌城墙的巨炮，并且在竞赛中造出越来越大的火炮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1375年，法国的铸炮师在卡昂铸造出重达2000磅（大约900公斤）的巨炮，两年后，勃艮第国王勇敢者腓力用巨炮轰开了英国人的奥德雷克城堡，证明了巨炮的价值。百年战争的后半段，英王亨利五世用巨炮夺取法国数十个城堡，其后法王查理七世更是建立起欧洲最高效的炮兵，横扫英军，收复了被英国占领的大半个法国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲人又将这种巨炮装到船只上，在大航海时代无往而不利，达•伽马率领几艘炮舰就可以纵横东非和印度，配备数十门巨炮的船只往往可以轻松击败几倍、十几倍甚至几十倍的敌人。在殖民扩张中，欧洲人又在殖民地修筑棱堡、配置巨炮，令成千上万的土著军队望而却步，毫无办法。欧洲人通过炮舰和要塞，轻易取得整个世界的制海权，主导了近现代历史。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西欧的火炮也回流到东欧，俄罗斯人用先进的枪炮把蒙古诸汗国炸得人仰马翻，向东方急速挺进。而伊斯兰世界也引进西欧先进枪炮，出现了奥斯曼帝国、波斯萨法维帝国、印度莫卧儿帝国等三大火药帝国，即便是近代相对闭塞的中亚，也因为奥斯曼帝国的传授，拥有自制火绳枪和轻型火炮的能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1453年，奥斯曼苏丹穆罕默德二世攻陷君士坦丁堡，消灭拜占庭帝国，口径夸张的乌尔班大炮起了重大作用，苏丹亲军耶尼切里也是一支精良的火枪军队。1526年，帖木儿帝国的孑遗巴布尔进军印度，在帕尼帕特战役中用火炮大破德里苏丹国的象兵，杀进印度，建立莫卧儿帝国，后来莫卧儿帝国设置了炮厂，拥有70门炮的常备军。波斯因为路况较差，难以使用巨炮，火器使用滞后一些，但18世纪前期，取代萨法维王朝的纳迪尔沙运用从欧洲引进的先进火枪和骆驼载的小黄蜂炮，横扫波斯、印度、中亚，多次大败奥斯曼军队，成为历史上最后一个大征服者。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;明清体制令中国火器辉煌不再&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;全世界火器日新月异之时，发明火器的中国却被甩在了后头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;清朝康熙帝对准噶尔火器“赞巴拉克”的性能感到惊异，雍正帝时期更是大规模仿造，给清军装备，日后发展为抬枪。而这种“赞巴拉克”也就是骆驼载的小黄蜂炮，不过在康熙帝之前三四百年的马穆鲁克王朝发明的过时武器，虽然在波斯、中亚的地理环境中仍有一定的独特作用，但比西欧先进火炮已经落后了好几个时代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中东和欧洲火器反超中国是在元代，主要是因为当时的战争烈度不高，不需要像无日不战的欧洲人那样改进火器。到了元末，起义军令火器得以复兴。不过，朱元璋等元末群雄的火器都是走的重量不重质的路数。虽然洪武年间明军的火铳装备率达到10%，拥有十几万火铳兵，但火器水平未必能达到宋朝的高度，更不用说与同时期的欧洲相比了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱元璋在鄱阳湖与陈友谅决战时，用的“大碗口筒”是杀伤人员的霰弹炮，“没奈何”是燃烧弹，所谓“火炮”是用投石机抛射燃烧弹，焚毁敌方战船。在攻打张士诚最后的据点苏州时，朱元璋用来攻城的也是投石车而非巨炮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见，在元末乱世的火器使用中，看不到欧洲火器向巨炮的转型。美国汉学家欧阳泰认为，这是因为中国的夯土城墙太厚，巨炮轰不垮，所以没必要制造巨炮，但朱元璋攻城时都使用了威力比巨炮小得多的投石车，可见攻城器械未必要奔着轰塌城墙去，没有理由放弃开发巨炮，应该是因为朱元璋的军队整体技术水平太低，不会造。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夺取天下后，朱元璋一方面闭关锁国，另一方面打压戮士人，导致知识、技术出现断层，许多技术可能因此失传。明军的火器配备率虽高，但明朝从开国就严禁民间持有和研发火器，地方政府想要自制也不行，必须通过朝廷统一调配，因此抹杀了社会自行改进火器的可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上种种原因，令明朝的火器十分落后。到了中期，当葡萄牙人出现在东南沿海后，他们预先装填、能够连续发射的鹰炮被明军视为神器，称之为“佛朗机炮”并加以仿制，但这种炮在当时的欧洲已是过时的二流货色。后来荷兰人的普通舰炮，更是成了明军在跟建州女真的战争中拿来救命的“红夷大炮”，最早明军还是从海里捞的沉船上的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就连性能明显不如欧洲的奥斯曼帝国火枪，也被明人赵士贞改装为“鲁密铳”（鲁密意为罗马，奥斯曼以罗马自居），视为利器，可见明朝火器水平之低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;女真人在明军的红夷大炮下连吃苦头之后，自行开发火炮，加上投降的明军炮队以及欧洲传教士的指导，其火炮运用一度领先东亚。不过，随着满清向明朝学习，走向闭关锁国，这些可喜的变化也渐归沉寂。1724年，雍正帝驱逐传教士，满清引进西洋科技的步伐大幅减缓，1776年，乾隆帝平定大小金川后，达成十全武功，认为海内无事，为防止火器流入民间，大量销毁战争中赶制的火器，中国火器革新的步伐至此戛然而止。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些海外汉学家认为中国的大一统体制不像欧洲那样战争频繁，是中国火器发展迟滞的最大原因，但实际上明清时代平定民变、改土归流的战争并不少，有些规模还很大，但也并没有促进火器的发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最主要的原因还是明清一反唐宋开明之态，在防范社会的专制上达到了巅峰，是秦制的集大成者，试图垄断目力所及最先进的火器技术，既闭关锁国、切断与西方的经济技术交流，又不愿让民间推动火器的研发和更新换代，整个社会自然也就没有研究火器的热情和动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当明清皇帝感到王朝陷入军事危机时，也会大力引进欧洲先进火器，说明他们具备学习先进技术的能力，如果一直这样，就算研发差些，也不至于跟欧洲差距过大。但一旦危机过去，又会切断跟海外的联系，无视域外火器的蓬勃发展，直到欧洲人用满清无法想象的坚船利炮敲开国门为止。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不只得一微，证监会系统离职人员为何扎堆IPO？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257196]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/IxjlclwEZfHBM4nqcCpIhyvliHeh3Kh4DvTA8tRH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;986&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/IxjlclwEZfHBM4nqcCpIhyvliHeh3Kh 4DvTA8tRH. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In April and May 2021, the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued documents and regulations to strengthen the system. Supervision of employees who have left their jobs investing in companies to be listed. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A company planning to be listed on the Science and Technology Innovation Board has a rare appearance of 8 China Securities Regulatory Commission (hereinafter referred to as the China Securities Regulatory Commission) Will) Employees who have resigned from the system hold shares indirectly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deyi Microelectronics Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Deyi Micro), which is the focus of heated discussion, was established in 2017. Its main business is the research and development, design and sales of storage control chips and storage solutions. The application for IPO was accepted on November 29, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sending the first round of inquiry letters, the Shanghai Stock Exchange believed that Yiwei’s explanation of the stock purchase matters by employees who had resigned from the China Securities Regulatory Commission system was still insufficient, and asked Yiwei again to elaborate in the second round of inquiries. Please ask sponsors and lawyers to verify and issue clear opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deyiwei responded twice and stated that the above eight people did not engage in improper shareholding and did not need to be liquidated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, 2023, the relevant person in charge of the Shanghai Stock Exchange also responded that these eight people mainly invested indirectly through employee stock ownership plans, equity incentive plans and other methods established by relevant investment institutions, and did not involve The investment behavior is led by employees who have resigned, and the number of shares they indirectly hold in the issuer is less than 1 share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, employees who have resigned from the China Securities Regulatory Commission system have taken shares in companies to be listed, which will arouse the sensitive nerves of the market. In April and May 2021, the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued documents and regulations to strengthen the supervision of system resignation personnel’s investment in companies to be listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who are the eight employees who have resigned from the China Securities Regulatory Commission system? Why did they gather even a little bit? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Omissions to disclose&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At first, Deyiwei did not fully disclose the stockholding status of personnel who left the CSRC system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the prospectus submitted on November 29, 2022, Deyiwei only briefly stated that 5 former employees of the China Securities Regulatory Commission system held less than 1 share of the issuer, and there was no improper shareholding. In addition, there are no other situations in which system personnel who have resigned from the system acquire shares as specified by the Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the announcement of the second round of inquiry responses showed that among the indirect shareholders of Deyiwei, there are 8 people who have resigned from the China Securities Regulatory Commission system. Among them, three of them, Wang Jun, Luo Haobin, and Yue Xinyu, were the first round of inquiry responders ( Added after June 30, 2023). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Yiwei failed to clearly introduce the identity of the new indirect shareholder Yue Xinyu, and only introduced him as a &quot;leading cadre not above the department level&quot; in the first round of inquiry responses, saying that he was &quot;relevant Shareholders have not provided information on Yue Xinyu’s specific employment status in the China Securities Regulatory Commission system; according to searches by sponsors and issuer lawyers, there is no relevant public information.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following inquiries from the Shanghai Stock Exchange, Deyiwei checked public information and an announcement from another company that was earlier than the release date of its first-round inquiry letter reply, and only confirmed it in the second round of inquiry responses. Yue Xinyu’s identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that when submitting the prospectus, Deyiwei omitted to disclose that three resigned personnel from the China Securities Regulatory Commission participated in the shares, and did not verify the identity of one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Guidelines on the Application of Regulatory Rules - Issuance Category No. 2&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guidelines&quot;) issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission on May 28, 2021, issuers and intermediaries are submitting issuance application documents. When doing so, a special explanation should be submitted to explain the situation of system personnel who have left the company to join the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the above eight resigned personnel, Liang Yuyin, Wang Jun, Luo Haobin and Yue Xinyu indirectly hold the equity of E Fund through the shareholding platform of E Fund Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as E Fund), and then indirectly hold the equity of E Fund. Get a micro-share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Announcements from multiple companies show that Liang Yuyin worked at the Shenzhen Stock Exchange from July 2011 to August 2016. He was the assistant manager of the fixed income department of the exchange when he left, and is now the deputy director of the infrastructure investment department of E Fund Fund. General manager. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun worked at the Guangdong Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission from June 2011 to June 2017, serving as chief staff officer at that time. After leaving his job, he joined E Fund Asset Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as E Fund Asset Management), and then joined E Fund in March 2020. He is currently the managing director of E Fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Haobin worked at the Guangdong Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission from June 2013 to September 2019 as the chief clerk. He is now the assistant to the general manager of the Operations Compliance Department at E Fund. He, Wang Jun and Liang Yuyin participated in the E Fund Employee Stock Ownership Plan in October 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Xinyu worked at the Henan Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission from July 2011 to January 2018 as the chief clerk. He now works at E Fund as the general manager of the institutional client department. He and Wang Jun participated in the E Fund Employee Stock Ownership Plan in November 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yu, Wang Guiyuan and Huang Xunyun from Minsheng Securities also received Yiwei shares indirectly through participating in the employee equity incentive plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to company announcements and public information, Liu Yu, Wang Guiyuan and Huang Xunyun left the China Securities Regulatory Commission system in March 2018, July 2017 and May 2016 respectively, and were then directors of the Corporate Supervision Division of the Heilongjiang Securities Regulatory Bureau. Staff member, seconded by Shenzhen Stock Exchange to be a pre-reviewer of the Sixth Division of the Issuance Department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission and an executive manager of the Listed Company Supervision Department of the Shanghai Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Wang Guiyuan is the managing director of the investment banking department of Minsheng Securities, and Huang Xunyun is the assistant to the president and general manager of the strategic account headquarters of Minsheng Securities. According to Caixin, Liu Yu is currently the general manager of the compliance department of Minsheng Securities and has intention to leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yu, Wang Guiyuan and Huang Xunyun participated in the Minsheng Securities employee equity incentive plan in May 2020, June 2020 and December 2021 respectively, and invested in the employee stock ownership platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last one among the 8 people is Peng Junheng, the &quot;old man&quot; of the China Securities Regulatory Commission system. He has worked within the China Securities Regulatory Commission system since 1996. He served as deputy director of the Futures Department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, deputy general manager of the Shanghai Futures Exchange, and director-level inspector of the Shanghai Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. He resigned in December 2017 and in 2018. Joined Shanghai Fuyou Financial Services Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Junheng invested 10 million in Tianjin Feixuan Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tianjin Feixuan) in September 2019, and the latter indirectly held Yiwei shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Junheng is also the only cadre above the division level among the eight resigned personnel. According to the &quot;Guidelines&quot;, employees at the deputy director level (middle level) and above have a three-year ban on equity participation after leaving the company, and other employees have a two-year ban. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The time when Peng Junheng invested in Tianjin Feixuan was less than three years after he left the China Securities Regulatory Commission system. However, because Peng Junheng was a person who had resigned before the release of the &quot;Guidelines&quot;, the prohibition period on investment does not apply to his investment behavior. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Wang Jiyue, a senior investment banker, most of the shares held by the above eight resigned personnel in the company to be listed come from the equity incentives of their companies, and they are all indirect shares after multi-layer penetration, and the proportion is very small. , has little say in the entire investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s not that these people have discussed and invested in this company in disguise, it’s just a coincidence.” Wang Jiyue told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Not only Deyiwei&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact, not only Deyiwei has gathered the above-mentioned personnel who have left the CSRC system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through E Fund’s employee shareholding platform, Liang Yuyin, Wang Jun, Luo Haobin and Yue Xinyu also indirectly hold shares in the proposed listed companies Feiyu Technology, Wangyuan Technology and Qihui Pharmaceutical. Liang Yuyin personally also holds indirect shares in Shenzhen Anke, a company to be listed, and Kangwei Century (688426.SH), a listed company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Minsheng Securities Liu Yu, Wang Guiyuan and Huang Xunyun indirectly hold shares in the companies to be listed, Hengye Microchip and Dehe Technology. The first two also hold shares indirectly in Shenzhen Anke. Peng Junheng indirectly holds shares in Shenzhen Anke and Kangwei Century through Tianjin Feixuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, Shenzhen Anke is a place where Peng Junheng and people who have left the China Securities Regulatory Commission system who worked for E Fund and Minsheng Securities gather again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company’s official website shows that Shenzhen Anke High-Tech Co., Ltd. was established in 1986. It is one of the earliest companies in China to develop large-scale medical imaging equipment and minimally invasive treatment equipment. Its products are exported to more than 50 countries. and regions, the GEM IPO application was accepted on June 30, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the response to the first round of inquiry letters, in addition to the above-mentioned resignations from the China Securities Regulatory Commission system with indirect shareholdings, Shenzhen Anke also disclosed four other resignations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Henian, Zhang Jie, Xu Rong and Fang Jie, who left the China Securities Regulatory Commission system between 2015 and 2017, worked for Minsheng Securities and indirectly held Shenzhen Anke shares through Minsheng Securities. However, as of the date of issuance of the inquiry letter reply (January 29, 2023), the above four people have withdrawn from the Minsheng Securities employee shareholding platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of the China Securities Regulatory Commission shows that Feng Henian, then chairman of Minsheng Securities and former party secretary and director of the Shandong Securities Regulatory Bureau, underwent disciplinary review and supervisory investigation in June 2022 for suspected serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 6, 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission stated in a notice that Feng Henian was expelled from the party that Feng Henian had completely lost his ideals and beliefs. He actively planned a &quot;way out&quot; while he was in office, and continued to use his original position and status to amass money after leaving his job. , is a typical example of the &quot;revolving door&quot; corruption in politics and business. He has no bottom line in discipline and law, uses his former position and status to influence the issuance review work, seeks benefits for others, illegally accepts huge amounts of property, and accepts bribes from management service objects in the name of others. Extremely huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 30, 2023, Shenzhen Anke suspended the listing review process for the third time, and applied to withdraw its issuance and listing application on June 16. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Liang Yuyin and Wang Jun both participated in the E Fund Employee Stock Ownership Plan in October 2019 and invested in the same employee stock ownership platform Zhuhai Juningkang Equity Investment Partnership (Limited Partnership) According to Qichacha, Wang Jun holds 2.3747% of the shares and Liang Yuyin holds 1.0067%. However, Shenzhen Anke and Kangwei Century, which Liang Yuyin indirectly holds shares, did not disclose Wang Jun&#39;s shareholding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the information disclosed by the above-mentioned companies, the way for the above-mentioned seven employees who have resigned from the China Securities Regulatory Commission to invest in the company to be listed is to invest in the securities firms and fund companies where they work through employee equity incentives, and the latter indirectly invest in Shenzhen Investment Holdings Donghai Small, Medium and Micro Venture Capital Enterprise (Limited Partnership) (hereinafter referred to as Shenzhen Investment Holdings), a number of private equity funds jointly funded by the Jiangsu provincial and municipal governments and the National Small and Medium Enterprises Development Fund Co., Ltd., these private equity funds eventually invested in companies to be listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, E Fund Management is a shareholder of the National Small and Medium Enterprises Development Fund. The latter was decided and deployed by the State Council in May 2020. Under the leadership of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology and the Ministry of Finance, it was jointly established by the central finance and Shanghai Guosheng, China Tobacco and other social investors as a parent fund. Through investment and establishment of sub-funds, etc. The total scale of the fund has reached more than 100 billion yuan, focusing on solving the medium and long-term equity financing problems of innovative small and medium-sized enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;E Fund and Minsheng Securities both indirectly hold shares in the private equity fund Shenzhen Investment Holdings. The actual controller of Shenzhen Investment Holdings is Shenzhen State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianjin Feixuan, which Peng Junheng invested in, also indirectly holds shares in the above-mentioned private equity funds and Shenzhen Investment Holdings, thereby indirectly investing in the company to be listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the above-mentioned shareholding paths, there is another situation in which Minsheng Securities personnel who receive equity incentives hold indirect shares in companies to be listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dehe Technology and Hengye Microchip, which are indirectly held by people from Minsheng Securities, Minsheng Securities is not only a sponsor, but also holds shares in the companies to be listed through subsidiaries. In Hengye Microcrystal, Minsheng Securities Investment Co., Ltd., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Minsheng Securities, was a new shareholder 12 months before the company&#39;s initial listing application. The shares directly held accounted for 1.44% of the company&#39;s total pre-issuance share capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission stipulates that the red line for sponsor institutions to hold shares in an issuer is 7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the above-mentioned companies, only Kangwei Century was successfully listed. Shenzhen Anke and Qihui Pharmaceutical both withdrew their listing applications, and the remaining companies are still in the IPO process. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Going in both directions&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not new for the personnel of the China Securities Regulatory Commission to leave their jobs and join market institutions, and major fund companies and securities firms are highly favored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to incomplete statistics from the &quot;Beijing News&quot; in 2020, nearly ten CSRC officials have &quot;went overseas&quot; to work in financial institutions in the past three years. Compared with the situation a few years ago, when officials who &quot;went overseas&quot; were more inclined to fund companies, in recent years, most of the CSRC officials who &quot;went overseas&quot; worked for securities firms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in early 2020, Huatai Securities announced the appointment of Jiao Xiaoning as the company&#39;s chief financial officer. Jiao Xiaoning served as deputy inspector and deputy director of the Accounting Department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission from January 2014 to January 2020. In May 2020, Guosen Securities appointed Deng Ge as the company&#39;s president. Deng had served as the director of the fifth supervision division of the First Department of Supervision of Listed Companies of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. He later served as the first batch of full-time spokespersons of the China Securities Regulatory Commission and the deputy director of the Listing Department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s a two-way street.” A brokerage person explained to Southern Weekend reporters that in brokerages and fund companies, employees who leave the China Securities Regulatory Commission system can get relatively high salaries without having to hold high-level positions; These companies recruit ex-employees to use their connections with regulatory agencies to learn more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The brokerage firm believes that the problem of the revolving door of politics and business cannot rely solely on legal supervision, &quot;but also on the invisible hand of the market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiyue previously told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;In a mature registration-based market, if the listed entity cannot attract investors, it will have no value, and the situation of power rent-seeking will be alleviated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In their prospectuses, most of the above-mentioned companies have no or only one sentence brief description of the personnel who have left the CSRC system. Most of the details of the shareholdings of the resigned personnel gradually became clear after inquiries from the exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the release of the &quot;Guidelines&quot;, regulatory agencies have tightened the verification of employees who have left their jobs to invest in companies to be listed, but there are still companies that take risks and conceal all the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shadow Innovation, which was approved to accept IPO applications on October 28, 2020, is just one step away from being listed on the Science and Technology Innovation Board after more than two years of preparation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2022, Shadow Stone Innovation received a 115-word inquiry from the China Securities Regulatory Commission, requiring it to provide additional information on the shareholding status of the natural person &quot;Chen Bin&quot; and the procedures for transferring shares to external parties. Background, motivation, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the disclosure of IPO application materials (including inquiry response materials), Shadow Stone Innovation has never mentioned Chen Bin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Economic Information Daily&quot; investigation found that Chen Bin was a person who resigned from the China Securities Regulatory Commission system. He worked at the Shenzhen Stock Exchange from August 1999 to March 2012, serving as senior manager, assistant to the director of the Comprehensive Research Institute, and deputy chief researcher. He also served as the chief representative of the Shenzhen Stock Exchange in Fujian Province and a listed company on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange. Head of the company&#39;s research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through layers of nesting and cross-shareholdings, Chen Bin’s shareholding in Shadow Stone Innovation appears to be quite complicated and hidden. During the IPO filing period of Shadow Stone Innovation, Chen Bin also transferred his holdings. Equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, Shadow Stone Innovation has not responded to this, and there is no latest progress on the IPO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[六问六答丨广州楼市部分放开限购，将会带来哪些影响？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 19:49:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 20, Guangzhou issued the &quot;Notice on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot; (Part 2 (called &quot;Notice&quot;), taking the first step in partially relaxing purchase restrictions in first-tier cities across the country. This new property market policy has the characteristics of large intensity and wide scope, striving to promote the transformation and high-quality development of the city&#39;s real estate market in an orderly and effective manner. At the same time, the &quot;Notice&quot; aims to implement classified and precise policies, continue to increase the construction and supply of affordable housing, better meet residents&#39; rigid and improved housing needs, and resolutely curb speculation and speculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, in the critical period of structural adjustment of the real estate industry, Guangzhou City actively responds to and implements the national real estate macro-control policy. In recent days, Guangzhou has taken the lead in implementing the &quot;recognize the house but not the loan&quot; policy in the first-tier cities. Mortgage interest rates were the first to break through the lower limit of LPR. This time, Guangzhou still took the lead among first-tier cities and opened up a new development situation in the real estate industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; mainly includes three parts: including relaxing purchase restrictions in some areas, relaxing the qualifications for non-household registered persons to purchase houses, and adjusting the value-added tax exemption period for personal sales of housing from 5 years to 2 years, etc., and many measures. At the same time, we will promote the recovery of the real estate market. In addition, yesterday, the Guangzhou Municipal Bureau of Housing and Urban-Rural Development issued the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Further Strengthening Housing Security for Household Registration Households (Draft for Comments)&quot;, which will jointly improve Guangzhou&#39;s &quot;rental and purchase&quot; housing security. mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New Deal Questions and Answers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Q: What are the specific purchase restriction and non-purchase restriction areas in Guangzhou City in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The &quot;Notice&quot; states that households registered in Guangzhou are located in Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, and Baiyun (excluding Jianggao Town, Taihe Town, Renhe Town, and Zhongluotan Town), Nansha and other areas still limit the purchase of two houses. This means that except for the areas mentioned above, purchase restrictions are no longer set in other areas of Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: Can families who are not residents registered in this city enjoy the liberalized regional dividend? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The &quot;Notice&quot; clearly states that non-local resident households are limited to purchasing one house in the above-mentioned areas. The conditions for purchasing a house are that they must have paid continuous personal income tax payment certificates or social insurance certificates for 2 years in Guangzhou before the date of purchase. Year. Previously, non-registered residents in Guangzhou were required to meet proof of continuous payment of personal income tax or social insurance certificate for five years to purchase a house in Guangzhou. This new policy lowers the threshold for non-registered residents to purchase houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;Notice&quot; stipulates that in addition to calculations based on family units, adult single (including divorced) people with household registration in this city in Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Baiyun (excluding Jianggao Town, Taiyuan) Hezhen, Renhe Town, and Zhongluotan Town) are still limited to purchasing one house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: Will the new policy have any impact on foreigners buying houses in Guangzhou? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: Overseas institutions and individuals purchase houses in accordance with the &quot;Opinions on Regulating the Access and Management of Foreign Investment in the Real Estate Market&quot; (Jianfanghuang [2006] No. 171), the &quot;Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development and other departments on the adjustment of foreign investment in the real estate market&quot; &quot;Notice on Relevant Policies for Access and Management&quot; (Jianfang [2015] No. 122) is implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: After the issuance of this &quot;Notice&quot;, what will be the timetable for policy implementation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The policy adjustment will be implemented from 0:00 on September 20, 2023. If the applicable policy for house purchase qualification review is inconsistent with this notice, this notice shall prevail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: The value-added tax exemption period for personal housing sales has been reduced from 5 years to 2 years. How to implement it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The value-added tax exemption period for individual sales of housing in Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Baiyun, Huangpu, Panyu, Nansha, Zengcheng and other districts will be adjusted from 5 years to 2 years. The applicable determination of the policy is based on The specific review opinions of the tax department shall prevail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: Does the issuance of the &quot;Notice&quot; mean that Guangzhou will realize that everyone has a place to live in the future, and the commercial housing market will be more dominated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: Guangzhou City has always adhered to the housing security system of &quot;both renting and purchasing&quot;. During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, Guangzhou City proposed to add 660,000 units (rooms) of affordable housing, which is higher than The number of newly added commercial houses (650,000 units) during the same period made it the city with the largest supply of affordable housing among first-tier cities in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant departments of the Guangzhou Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau introduced that next, the city will further increase the construction and supply of affordable housing, and accelerate the establishment and improvement of public rental housing, affordable rental housing and allotment of affordable housing. A housing security system with housing as the mainstay and both renting and purchasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, we will continue to provide basic guarantees for public rental housing, raise the income threshold and rental subsidy standards for public rental housing in a timely manner, further expand the scope of public rental housing security, and guide some security targets to solve their housing problems by receiving subsidies. Difficult issues and improve public rental housing security methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vigorously developing affordable rental housing will provide policy support for land, finance, taxation, etc. from the government, and guide various market entities to participate in raising affordable rental housing to alleviate the housing difficulties of new citizens and young people. Accelerate the establishment and improvement of supporting policy systems for allotment of affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;[Voice]&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In response to this new policy in Guangzhou’s real estate market, Southern+ reporters immediately contacted experts to explain what impact it will have on the city’s real estate industry in the subsequent stages after the new policy is released. ? Hear what the experts have to say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Jiangbo, director of the Economic Research Institute of the Guangzhou Academy of Social Sciences and deputy director of the Expert Committee of the Guangzhou and Guangdong Real Estate Association:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This adjustment and optimization of real estate development policies is very necessary. And importantly, it will play a very good role in boosting and promoting the real estate market and economic and social development of Guangzhou. Mainly reflected in the following three aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Conducive to the stable and healthy development of Guangzhou’s real estate market&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the huge changes in the development environment at home and abroad and the lagging impact of the three-year epidemic, the current real estate market There is indeed great downward pressure on the market and the macroeconomy, and relevant policies are in great need to be adjusted and optimized. The policies introduced in the early stage, such as &quot;recognizing a house but not a loan&quot; and &quot;lowering interest rates and lowering down payments,&quot; are generally indirect and mild, and the policy strength and effect are not enough. The relaxation of the &quot;purchase restriction and foreign purchase restriction&quot; policy introduced this time is a relaxation of administrative control policies. It is direct, substantive, very important, necessary and timely. I believe it will definitely boost and promote the market. effect. As a national central city and a first-tier city, the steady and healthy development of Guangzhou&#39;s real estate market will also serve as a good example and driving role for other second-, third-, and fourth-tier cities in the country. Therefore, Guangzhou’s policy optimization and adjustment this time is of great significance and deserves high recognition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Conducive to the coordinated and balanced development of the real estate market and housing security&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that this policy optimization and adjustment not only optimizes and adjusts the real estate market policy, but also further strengthens the The safeguard policy emphasizes the proper separation, balanced efforts, and mutual promotion of the market and safeguards. It clarifies fuzzy thinking conceptually and strengthens the direction and intensity of work in action, which is conducive to making the market bigger, stronger, and better, as well as better safeguards. It is conducive to the high-quality coordinated development of real estate, economy and society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. It is conducive to the coordinated and integrated development between various districts in Guangzhou and between Guangzhou and surrounding areas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This policy optimization and adjustment is mainly aimed at the peripheral areas of Guangzhou, while the central urban area and Nansha District are still The implementation of relatively strict purchase restriction measures fully considers the actual conditions of industry, population and real estate market in each district, which well reflects the principle of &quot;implementing policies according to districts&quot; and is conducive to better coordinated development among various districts in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, with the strong implementation of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area plan, the integration of the Greater Bay Area is accelerating. Currently, more than 50% of the working population in Guangzhou is non-locally registered. Guangzhou is a very open city. , a dynamic city, the appropriate relaxation of policies such as &quot;purchase restrictions and foreign purchase restrictions&quot; fully meets the objective needs of the integrated development of the Greater Bay Area. This optimization and adjustment of real estate policies will not only have great significance in promoting real estate in Guangzhou, but also be of great benefit to the long-term economic, spatial and social development of Guangzhou and the Greater Bay Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[悬疑推理作家访谈录丨法医秦明：真正高智商的人不会犯罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257192]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among contemporary Chinese writers of detective novels, &quot;Forensic Physician Qin Ming&quot; is a very unique existence. On the one hand, there are actually many contemporary writers with police work experience, such as Remy, Ah Yi, etc., but authors like Qin Ming who combine their work experience and professional skills with detective novel writing so closely can be called &quot; Unparalleled.” On the other hand, if &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; is regarded as a cultural phenomenon in a broader sense, it started from novels, and later gradually extended to different cultural forms such as film and television, variety shows, and even became the profession of &quot;forensic medicine&quot; in many people&#39;s minds. synonym. Among them, the intertwining of the forensic profession and literary creation has created an amazing cultural communication power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/c7tnNmyPxBgUYScX14uWqfeo1s7mGgALr6L6XBT2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/c7tnNmyPxBgUYScX14uWqfeo1s7mGgALr6L6XBT2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qin Ming is a front-line public security forensic doctor who has examined thousands of corpses for 26 years. He is also a suspense writer and has written the Forensic Qin Ming series, the Hummingbird series, the Night Watch series, and the popular science book series. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Yi/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a forensic doctor, I am full of awe and curiosity: why did he choose This career? After working in this somewhat mysterious profession for decades, how has your mentality changed? Faced with the large number of literature and film and television dramas about forensics or ghost stories today, what new perspectives can his profession provide? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have many questions about Qin Ming as a writer: How does he deal with the issues of fiction and reality in novel writing? How does he view the ethical boundaries of writing in crime novels? What is his reading tendency and self-identity towards the genre literary tradition of detective novels? And when I learned during the interview that Qin Ming’s favorite Chinese detective novel writer was Hai Yan, many of my previous questions were answered, and a genealogy of the development of Chinese public security literature gradually became clear before my eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, in the latest novel &quot;White Scroll&quot;, we get to know Qin Ming as a father. Compared with the &quot;bad boy&quot; narrative that was popular in detective literature in previous years, &quot;White Scroll&quot; is about Qin Ming. The way children imagine the weak may be more traditional, but it is also more in line with the real concerns and anxieties of contemporary parents. In this novel, the forensic doctor is still the main body of action in the novel, but the father is more able to convey the author&#39;s inner voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The chat with Qin Ming lasted less than two hours, but I felt a sense of solidity, trust and security on the other end of the phone. This may be due to the simplicity and sincerity revealed in his words and voice, or it may be due to his many years of professional experience in front-line police work. And during this chat, I also vaguely felt the possibility of another understanding of the sense of reality in the novel &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot;. This sense of reality does not lie in whether the story itself is &quot;purely fictional&quot;, but in a kind of Perseverance in writing attitude and inner belief in justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Forensic Medicine in Reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qin Mingyou Well, since the publication of your first novel &quot;Corpse Whisperer&quot; in 2012, through the publication of more than a dozen novels, the adaptation of many film and television dramas, and now the very popular variety show &quot;Jobs -&quot; Forensic Season&quot;. Forensic medicine, which was originally a relatively niche and somewhat mysterious profession, has now gradually become well-known to the public. Why did you choose the profession of forensic medicine in the first place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was in middle school, I basically didn’t know much about forensic medicine. My father was a policeman and my mother was a nurse. My father had a special interest in me. I had the complex and expectation that a son should inherit his father&#39;s career and become a police officer. However, my mother felt that being a police officer was too dangerous. Later, when I applied for a volunteer, I compromised and applied for a forensic medicine job. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you take an anatomy class for the first time, What are the scenes and feelings like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I went to college in 1998 and began to study in the professional field of forensic medicine. In the process of studying and working, I gradually realized the forensic medicine importance. For example, the first story in my novel &quot;The Corpse Whisperer&quot; tells the story of a fight between several young people, and one person was stabbed to death. It was originally a very simple case, but it required forensic identification of the tools that caused the injuries in order to accurately determine their respective legal responsibilities. The key point is that the deceased in this case was an acquaintance of mine, so it posed a great psychological challenge to me. This was my first anatomy class, and I was very impressed. I was deeply shocked by the importance of forensic work, and from then on I set my life ambition: I must be a good forensic doctor in my life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you later engaged in forensic work, Will there be any changes in your mind? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At first I would feel very angry with the criminal and hate the evil as much as I hate them. But the sign of a true maturity of a forensic doctor is his indifference. He will not pay too much attention to things other than the case. Instead, he will put all his energy on the autopsy and try his best to find clues. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That is, as forensic doctors continue to accumulate work experience, Not only has the professional and technical level been improved, but also the entire personality has been tempered and changed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it should be like this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before, I thought forensic medicine was a type of doctor. The main task is to perform an autopsy. But through your novels and the &quot;Forensic Season&quot; program, I discovered that forensic doctors also have to undertake a lot of work in on-site investigation, physical evidence identification, and even case reasoning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ACJAPjfdzIYaZVxRhcxS9mLdD2WvZgY9LZ5lBvRy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ACJAPjfdzIYaZVxRhcxS9mLdD2WvZgY9LZ5lBvRy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, forensic doctor Qin Ming will participate in the reality show &quot;Forensic Medicine Season 2&quot; as a guest. The picture shows the poster of the show. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, our Chinese public security organs have set up As a forensic department, public security forensic doctors must participate in case scene investigation and case investigation. In some Western countries, forensic doctors, as independent inspection agencies, usually only need to identify three pieces of information: cause of death, time of death, and instrument of injury, and generally will not express opinions on other than these three issues. However, in our investigation process, all police types must play their maximum role within their professional scope, so that they can solve the case most efficiently. We often say that the center of a murder scene is the corpse, and the forensic doctor is the only police officer who comes into contact with the corpse, so the forensic doctor will have the core information of the entire scene. Therefore, our forensic doctors often have to participate in more case analysis and reasoning processes. This also ensures that our various police departments work together as a whole to maximize the effectiveness of the team and solve cases with the highest efficiency. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote a story in my book about the murder of a family of five. The murderer used knives to kill the host and hostess, the host’s mother, nanny and children. The five bodies were all covered with knives. The injuries were fatal. Only the nanny and the old lady&#39;s heads still had scars from the hammer, and they were still injured after death. When encountering such a case, many Western forensic institutions will feel that the cause of death, time of death, and the instrument of injury are very clear when conducting examinations, and will not proceed to the next step of reasoning. But our forensic doctors will continue to reason based on these clues: Why did the murderer hit these two people&#39;s heads with a hammer after they died? The biggest possibility is that it is reinforced damage, just to ensure that the deceased will die, and if she is not dead, she will be hit twice. So under what circumstances would reinforced damage be used? That means the deceased knew the murderer. So why only use reinforced damage on old ladies and nannies? It means that only two of them in the family of five know the murderer, and no other family members know him. Who could the murderer be? We speculated that he might be a vegetable vendor in the market, who usually only has contact with old ladies and nannies. As a result, we greatly reduced the scope of investigation and improved the police&#39;s efficiency in solving crimes. Therefore, I say that allowing forensic doctors to be more involved in the entire process of investigation, reasoning and solving cases is actually an institutional arrangement that is more suitable for our country&#39;s national conditions and can greatly improve the efficiency of solving cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What a wonderful reasoning. In many other current criminal investigation dramas, suspense films, or mystery novels, the role of forensic doctors is also set up, and they are given important functions in solving crimes. However, most of the forensic characters in these film and television dramas or novels are women - such as the female forensic doctor Gao Yanan in the TV series &quot;White Night&quot; (2017), and the female forensic doctor in Hu Yanyun&#39;s novel &quot;Sweeping Rat Ridge&quot; (2020). Forensic doctor Lei Rong et al. I wonder what the gender ratio is between men and women in the real forensic profession? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Movies and TV dramas may be based on dramatic considerations, so many female forensic roles are set up. However, in the actual gender composition of the profession, the majority of forensic doctors are men. The ratio of men to women in Anhui Province is about 10:1.男性从事法医的优势可能在于，很多尸体解剖其实是力气活，而且有时候需要三更半夜到深山老林里面出现场。但女性法医也有其自身优势，比如她们往往更细致，一些细节处理会做得更好。同时法医平时很多的工作是伤情鉴定，面对女性伤者，女法医也有自身的便利之处。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;提到法医题材影视剧，除了都市题材之外，现在法医这个职业愈发走入大众视野也反过来带动了另一种题材影视剧的流行，就是以古代仵作或验尸人员为主角的作品。从早年的《大宋提刑官》（2005年）到近年的《御赐小仵作》（2021年），甚至包拯身边的公孙策，也多少要具有一点验尸的能力。在我看来，这其实是在用某种现代的法医技术和精神来重新想象一名古代的仵作，你平时会看这些影视作品吗？你对这些作品有什么看法？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;正如你所说，这些古装影视剧中的“提刑官”或者“仵作”，其本质还是依照现代法医所进行的艺术形象加工。举两个例子，一个是依照古代的风俗习惯，大部分情况下是不能解剖尸体的，只能通过尸表检验来断案。当然对于很多案件来说，尸表检验也能大概明确案件的基本情况。除非遇到尸表检验无法处理的疑点，才能解剖尸体。另一个就是古代的仵作只有清洗、搬运尸体的职能，没有鉴定的职能。官员才有资格进行验尸和鉴定，仵作在古代的身份等级划分中，往往是贱民，不具备这样的资格，他甚至没有权力填写尸检记录，而我们现代的法医是有鉴定权的。所以你说的两部古装影视剧，其实差别又很大。 《大宋提刑官》中的宋慈是正四品的提点刑律官，《御赐小仵作》中的主角是个小仵作，两个人的工作职能、权力范围其实都是不同的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;就是说古代仵作受到封建社会阶级等级秩序观念的束缚，不能充分发挥自己的专业知识和职业技能。这构成了一个很大的局限性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;写小说“完全源于委屈”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了是一名法医，你另一个重要身份就是一名作家，你最初为什么会选择把法医的经历写成小说？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我写作完全源于委屈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;怎么说？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;就是我在从事法医这个职业之后，一方面会感到这个职业的重要，甚至是伟大和崇高。但另一方面，在日常生活中，法医也会遭到一些误解和歧视，比如有人知道我是法医之后，不愿意和我握手、不愿意和我同桌吃饭，觉得晦气。在公安系统内部，法医作为一个警种也需要被更多地关注和重视，我们往往容易看到最后抓捕罪犯的警察，而容易忽略背后默默奉献、做了大量鉴定和推理工作的法医。同时我写小说也是为了普及一些基本的法医知识，这样真遇到案件发生，网民们具备更好的法医学素养，就不容易被谣言所蒙骗。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/IbzSDdVqLa25EXgvR7DppuaXEGEgG2ooKfVooyjB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/IbzSDdVqLa25EXgvR7DppuaXEGEgG2ooKfVooyjB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;法医秦明。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（ELLE杂志/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相当于获得了正确的法医知识，在一些情况下就提高了对谣言的鉴别力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对的，同时我还希望能够震慑犯罪。有人之前问我，你不担心读者看了你的小说之后会去效仿犯罪吗？我说我不怕，我写小说不是为了吸引眼球，而是希望我的读者在看完我的小说后都能明白，我们有最专业的法医和最高的破案率。在这里“犯罪伸手必被捉”。我希望我的小说可以让善良的人提高警惕，让心怀恶念的人放下屠刀。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;嗯，其实创作态度决定了小说具体写法的不同，相应地，最后达成的写作效果与读者影响也会不一样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，是这样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你觉得现在社会对于法医的认识有所好转吗？你最初写作时的委屈还有吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在大众对于法医的了解越来越多，也越来越认识到法医这个职业的特点和伟大之处。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“法医秦明”系列小说特别触动人的地方在于其中透露出的这种真实感，那是一种来源于日常工作经验的真实。比如你小说里面讲到法医给死尸剃头发的细节，用手术刀剃，既要剃干净，还要不伤及头皮，一看就是专业从事者才能写出来的细节。那你为什么最初会选择小说这种虚构的文学形式，有考虑过写非虚构纪实类作品吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这里涉及一些写作伦理和案件保密的问题。我写的小说，基本上是虚实结合。法医工作和推理都是“实”的，但是案情本身是“虚”的。就是我可能虚构了一个案件故事，但其中法医工作的日常和核心推理点，又都是实实在在，源于生活的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这样的虚实结合也是很有意思。你平时喜欢读侦探小说吗？有哪些喜欢的侦探小说作家和作品？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我最喜欢的作家这么多年没变过，就是海岩，但准确地说他写的不是侦探小说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;嗯，其实海岩是更广义上的公安题材写作，然后在里面融入了相当多言情小说的类型元素。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对的，他是那种偏都市的风格。我看的第一本海岩小说是《便衣警察》，小说写得很早，但我是在2000年上大学之后才“入坑”的。后来第二本是《一场风花雪月的事》，还有《死于青春》《玉观音》《深牢大狱》，包括后来的《舞者》《长安盗》，我都是第一时间买来读的，最喜欢《深牢大狱》这一本。后来焦俊艳去演电影《长安盗》，她是演我第一部网剧的女主角，而且也是安徽人，我们很熟，所以我听说她去演这部海岩小说改编的电影就很兴奋。除了海岩，我也看雷米的《心理罪》系列、周浩晖《死亡通知单》系列，包括马伯庸的小说，我不知道算不算推理小说，但我也很喜欢看。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;听说你和雷米还有一些有趣的交往经历？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;雷米是刑警学院的老师，我是刑警学院的学生，我是大学毕业之后到刑警学院读了一个双学士，所以虽然我和雷米年龄差不多，但他确实做过我的老师。另外，我写完第一本小说之后寄给他看，他提了三条意见，让我至今印象深刻：一是请搞清楚“的、地、得”的用法；二是少看同类型小说，继续保持自己的风格；三是做一个能写很久的写作者。我觉得他当初提的这三条建议，我基本做到了吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;真是非常坦诚的建议。你会觉得雷米笔下方木的犯罪心理画像更偏幻想和虚构，而你的“法医秦明”系列更偏现实主义吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我并不认为方木这个人物是完全地虚构，一方面，犯罪心理画像技术在具体犯罪研究和破案过程中也确实存在；另一方面，我觉得方木身上可能是集合了很多优秀公安干警的成功案例，并不是完全出于虚构。相比之下，我的“法医秦明”系列，可能因为法医学是自然科学，更容易让人信服。我给你讲科学道理，得出破案结论，你觉得这是可信的。但心理分析，同样也是建立在科学的基础上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“擦掉足迹会留下更多擦拭的痕迹”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果把“法医秦明”系列也放到侦探小说的文学传统中来看，从柯南·道尔的“福尔摩斯探案”以来，其实侦探福尔摩斯具备两项技能：一个是巨细靡遗的现场观察能力，脚印、指纹、血迹、毛发、烟灰，任何一点细节都不会逃过福尔摩斯的眼睛，而这些往往能构成其最后破案的关键性线索；另一个就是其强大的逻辑推理能力，正如福尔摩斯自己所说：“逻辑学家从一滴水就能推测出它是来自大西洋还是尼亚加拉瀑布的，而无需亲眼见到或听说过大西洋或尼亚加拉瀑布。生命就是一条巨大的链条，只要见到其中的一环，我们就可以推想出整个链条的特性。”如果从福尔摩斯小说所开创的这两条文学传统来看，“法医秦明”系列似乎是继承并发展了第一条传统，并将这种传统和一个非常具体的、现代化的职业相结合，写出了某种真实感。你对侦探小说的这两条传统怎么看？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得不同作家有不同的写作侧重和关注点。经常有人问我是本格派还是社会派，我说我哪一派都不属于，因为我写的这些东西不是为了推理而推理，我是为了破案而推理。如果一定要概括一下的话，我认为可以叫“现实推理”。一方面，现实物证是推理的前提和依据；另一方面，物证和推理相结合，最后的目的都是破案。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在本格推理小说中很重要的一个分支就是“密室杀人”。而在你的《幸存者》中，第四案就是“夺命密室”。在《白卷》中，第十案也叫“断肠密室”。当然，我觉得你小说中所说的“密室”，和现在“新本格”小说中的密室概念还是有很大差别。你怎么看待这种推理小说中的密室设计？如果说在“新本格”推理小说中，“密室”往往意味着某种脑洞大开的奇思妙想与严谨的逻辑推理的结合，那么在法医侦探的眼中，密室是可能存在的吗？还是所谓“密室”，一定会留下凶手故意伪造的痕迹和线索？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我非常感动，因为你真的看懂了我的小说，就是这个意思。我们经常说只要有人出现在案发现场，就一定会产生物质交换。比如你设置了一个很复杂的密室，我们一般管它叫“封闭现场”，你可以不留下足迹吗？很多人说擦掉足迹就可以啊，但擦掉足迹会留下更多擦拭的痕迹，犯罪嫌疑人想得越多，在现场多余动作越多，给警方留下的线索和证据就越多。就像经常很多人问我有没有“高智商犯罪”，我说真正高智商的人不会犯罪。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;提到“高智商犯罪”，我想到紫金陈的小说，他有一本小说叫《无证之罪》，其中有一个非常有意思的想象，就是犯罪者是一个精通物鉴和法医两个领域的顶级专家，这样的人去犯罪，现场不会留下一点线索和证据。而破案的侦探则是一名大学数学老师，有着超强的逻辑推理能力，于是形成了“推理之王”解决“无证之罪”这种有点类似于传统武侠小说中巅峰对决的情节设计。你怎么看待这一类的文学想象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不同的小说家都有自己不同的特长和不同的小说写法，紫金陈的小说我也很喜欢读，不过我们的写法可能不一样。他善于做推理的安排，而我的特长是写法医。在我的实际工作中，不存在“无证之罪”，“无证”就是“无罪”。只有找到证据，形成完整的证据链，才能定罪，因此我的小说可能会更注重证据一些。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你早期的小说中，各个故事之间彼此相对独立性更高一些，只是由同一批法医将这些不同的案件、不同的小故事串联起来，某种程度上来看，它可能更接近于一组彼此关系密切的“短篇小说集”。你在《幸存者》的“序”中也说过，“法医秦明”系列的本色之一，就是“以个案为基础，加入穿插全书的主线”。而在最新的这本《白卷》中，我明显能感受到整部小说的整体性设计，首尾呼应、环环相扣，一个复杂的长篇小说的结构已然形成，这样一种从短篇故事连缀到长篇小说的变化是你有意为之的结果吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是的，其实“法医秦明”系列小说是成卷的，前六本《尸语者》《无声的证词》《第十一根手指》《清道夫》《幸存者》《偷窥者》都是“万象卷”，写的是人间万象，所以更接近短篇小说集的写法。然后从《天谴者》开始，《天谴者》《遗忘者》《玩偶》和《白卷》，是“众生卷”，我在写法上会有很大不同，就是每一本书虽然还是有好几个案件故事，但整体上围绕一个社会问题来写。比如《天谴者》主要聚焦的是社会责任感，《遗忘者》主要聚焦腐朽的女德思想，《玩偶》聚焦的是家暴，而这一本《白卷》主要是聚焦的是亲子关系里的沟通问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我写小说另外一个变化在于，我在“众生卷”里减少了命案的篇幅，而增加了其他意外死亡的故事，主要原因有三：一是老秦本身就是写实派的作者，而实际情况中，命案的确是越来越少了；二是法医工作绝对不仅仅是在命案中发挥作用，在死亡方式的判断和整个诉讼过程中都能发挥不可替代的作用，我希望我的读者可以看到法医在其他更多领域发挥作用的故事；三是法医工作博大精深，除了现场分析之外，还有很多其他的案件需要法医贡献力量，我想让我的读者全面地了解法医学专业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在《白卷》里面写的很多是关于父母和子女之间的日常相处、代际隔阂的问题，你这本书对于亲子问题的关注，和你作为一名父亲的身份有关系吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题不太好回答，因为我自己和我父亲一样，在孩子的成长过程中是缺位的。因为工作原因，我以前一年要出差两百多天，现在案子少了，也要出差几十天到一百天。所以平时工作也挺忙的，对孩子的教育过程我自认为还是属于半缺位的状态。但我还是很关注这个问题，希望通过小说引起大家对于青少年的关心，我是想去触发大家的思考，而不想去说教。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[广州多区放开限购，增值税“五改二”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257224]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 18:27:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月20日，广州发布《&lt;span>;广州市人民政府办公厅关于优化我市房地产市场平稳健康发展政策的通知&lt;/span>;》，广州成为全国一线城市中首个部分放开限购的城市。近日来，在“认房不认贷”、商贷利率下调等政策利好下，广州房地产市场出现回暖迹象，本次楼市新政则以“组合拳”方式，进一步有序有效促进房地产行业健康发展。以下为《&lt;span>;广州市人民政府办公厅关于优化我市房地产市场平稳健康发展政策的通知&lt;/span>;》内容：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;穗府办函〔2023〕49号&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州市人民政府办公厅关于优化我市房地产市场平稳健康发展政策的通知&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各区人民政府，市政府各部门、各直属机构：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为深入贯彻落实党中央、国务院决策部署，坚持房子是用来住的、不是用来炒的定位，适应房地产市场供求关系发生重大变化的新形势，围绕稳地价、稳房价、稳预期的目标，分类精准施策，持续加大保障性住房建设和供给力度，更好满足居民刚性和改善性住房需求，促进我市房地产市场平稳健康发展，坚决遏制投机炒作，根据我市房地产市场实际情况，经市人民政府同意，现就有关事项通知如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一、优化住房限购和增值税免税年限&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将本市住房限购政策调整为，在越秀、海珠、荔湾、天河、白云（不含江高镇、太和镇、人和镇、钟落潭镇）、南沙等区购买住房的，本市户籍居民家庭限购2套住房；非本市户籍居民家庭能提供购房之日前2年在本市连续缴纳个人所得税缴纳证明或社会保险证明的，限购1套住房。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将越秀、海珠、荔湾、天河、白云、黄埔、番禺、南沙、增城等区个人销售住房增值税征免年限从5年调整为2年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、加大保障性住房建设和供给&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大力加快推动公共租赁住房、保障性租赁住房和配售的保障性住房发展。提高公共租赁住房保障水平，完善户籍家庭公共租赁住房保障方式；支持各类市场主体积极参与，多主体、多渠道筹集建设保障性租赁住房；建立健全配售的保障性住房体系，稳慎有序开展规划建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本通知自印发之日起施行，原有政策与本通知不一致的，以本通知为准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;广州市人民政府办公厅&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;2023年9月19日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 18:55:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>