<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国务院联防联控机制：做好冬春季新冠等传染病防控]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261223]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 15:22:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Joint Prevention and Control Mechanism of the State Council issued a notice today, requiring all localities to prepare for new coronavirus infections and other key infectious diseases in winter and spring. Prevention and control work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; pointed out that winter and spring are the seasons with high incidence of infectious diseases such as COVID-19, influenza, norovirus gastroenteritis, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. The current COVID-19 epidemic situation across the country is generally stable, but there is still a risk of a rebound in my country&#39;s COVID-19 epidemic in winter. Since October 2023, influenza and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection activities have gradually increased in my country. It is expected that influenza will have a national epidemic peak in winter and spring, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection will continue to be high in some areas in the future. This winter and next spring, our country may face the superimposed epidemic situation of multiple respiratory diseases such as COVID-19, influenza, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice on Preventing and Controlling New Coronavirus Infections and Other Key Infectious Diseases in Winter and Spring&quot; mainly includes 6 key measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, effectively implement port epidemic prevention and control. Ports must strictly implement measures such as temperature monitoring of entry personnel, medical inspections, epidemiological investigations, and medical screening, and carry out new coronavirus mutation monitoring in accordance with regulations. Disease control, health, and customs departments should strengthen data sharing and information exchange, and coordinate risk analysis and prediction and early warning. Strengthen the publicity and interpretation of policies related to active health declaration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to continue to carry out dynamic monitoring and early warning of the epidemic. All localities must coordinate the surveillance of key infectious diseases such as COVID-19, influenza and norovirus gastroenteritis, and closely track changes in the epidemic situation. Strengthen the analysis and utilization of multi-source data such as online direct reporting, fever clinics, sentinel hospitals, laboratory testing, etc., carry out multi-pathogen comprehensive surveillance of acute respiratory infectious diseases based on actual conditions in areas where conditions permit, strengthen the reporting and management of statutory infectious disease information, and ensure information Timeliness and accuracy of reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to strengthen the prevention and control of key institutions and key groups. All localities should strengthen prevention and control in elderly care, childcare, schools, social welfare and other institutions as well as confined spaces, and urge daily protection and health monitoring. Strengthen the vaccination of key groups such as the elderly, patients with underlying diseases, and children against COVID-19, influenza, and pneumococcal vaccines, and strengthen classified and hierarchical health services and management for vulnerable groups such as the elderly over 65 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to strengthen preparations for medical treatment. All localities should coordinate the deployment of medical resources based on the epidemic situation of infectious diseases and the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases in winter and spring, and strengthen the production and supply of relevant treatment drugs. Dynamically monitor the supply situation of retail pharmacies, medical institutions, especially primary-level medical supplies, and strengthen the guarantee of appropriate dosage forms for children&#39;s medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth is to continue to strengthen science popularization and education. All localities must continue to provide health education and publicity guidance, make full use of various media at all levels to carry out publicity and policy interpretation on the prevention and control of COVID-19 and other key infectious diseases in winter and spring, and release epidemic and prevention and control information in a timely, accurate and objective manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth is to strengthen organizational leadership and responsibility implementation. All localities must strengthen the organization and leadership of infectious disease prevention and control in winter and spring, maintain a moderate and orderly prevention and control intensity and rhythm, maintain the effective operation of joint prevention and control mechanisms at all levels, be prepared for transition from emergency to emergency, and report promptly once clustered epidemics are discovered. , quick response and effective disposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电影《我本是高山》陷争议旋涡：“传记片难拍”其实是个世界性难题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261192]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the movie &quot;I am a mountain&quot; adapted from the real deeds of Zhang Guimei, the principal of Huaping Girls&#39; High School, was screened It triggered a wave of online scolding. Some viewers who watched the on-demand screening expressed dissatisfaction, accusing the film online of being &quot;misogynistic&quot; and &quot;smearing Principal Zhang&#39;s beliefs.&quot; In response, the screenwriter responded on social media with &quot;Your grandma, I was born to be a mountain&quot; and also Responding to critics with &quot;Mediocre gully! Humble coward!&quot; also triggered a war of words and controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The disputes between the two parties probably focus on two parts. The first is the discrepancy between the plot and reality. Critics believe that many plots violate real history, such as &quot;Girls go to Internet cafes to stop studying because they fell in love while shopping&quot;, &quot;Principal Zhang forced girls to cut their hair short&quot;, &quot;Principal Zhang looks similar in appearance but not in spirit, like a chicken baby and a tiger mother&quot;; secondly, Regarding &quot;gender issues&quot;, critics believe that &quot;it is the father who is alcoholic, not the mother in the film&quot; and &quot;Principal Zhang insists on running the school because of his faith, not because he misses his deceased husband in the film&quot;, and then accuses the screenwriter and director of &quot;misogyny&quot; Discredit Principal Zhang’s faith.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the controversies encountered by &quot;I Am a Mountain&quot; are similar to those encountered by biographical films on a global scale. These two major controversies can also be reduced to &quot;issues of fact&quot; and &quot;issues of fact&quot;. A question of values”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of film art, &quot;biopics are difficult to make&quot; is actually a global problem, and eye-catching biopics are rare around the world. Especially for celebrities who are very recent, it is indeed difficult to make a biographical film commercially and artistically while respecting the facts. There is no other reason. Celebrities’ life stories are widely known. Any artistic processing and adaptation will inevitably reshape the celebrity’s public image and challenge the audience’s inherent perception of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as this &quot;factual issue&quot; is concerned, the decision-making power on how to collect materials, write scripts, and start shooting should be left entirely to the screenwriter and director. As long as the legal authorization of celebrities and their families is obtained and the potential for infringement is eliminated, the plot adaptation is actually not difficult, and it is purely a matter of choice and judgment in film art. If the director thinks that he cannot get the adaptation permission he wants, he can decide on his own whether to continue filming. For example, Gao Xiaosong gave up the idea of ​​filming the movie &quot;Lin Huiyin&quot; because &quot;Lin Huiyin&#39;s descendants requested that Xu Zhimo not be included.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although many biopics are completely loyal to real history, they have become a piece of history because they dare not let go of adaptation. The failure of &quot;Jobs&quot; falls into this category. The life of the Apple Godfather was filmed in a lukewarm manner; Many biopics hope to make breakthroughs in commerciality and artistry, but they have more or less fallen into the &quot;controversy&quot; and are under certain pressure from reputation. For example, &quot;The Imitation Game&quot; added an &quot;original plot&quot; and was fictional. The controversial plot of Turing, the father of computers, &quot;gives up reporting on fellow Soviet spies in order to prevent his homosexual identity from being exposed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for &quot;I Am a Mountain&quot;, Principal Zhang Guimei and other real people did not object to the screenwriter and director&#39;s processing and adaptation, but only appeared at the screening to say, &quot;I didn&#39;t really think anything of it at the time. how&quot;. Therefore, the film&#39;s factual issues cannot be considered a point of contention. The reason why the online scolding war was triggered was because of the second controversial point - &quot;the issue of values.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Critics believe that there are &quot;gender issues&quot; in the film, such as &quot;the mother is the drunkard, which vilifies women&quot; and &quot;the original theme was female awakening and female independence, but in the end it became the deceased husband of Principal Zhang &quot;Touched&quot; &quot;Girls skipping class, going shopping and falling in love are also vilifying women&quot;; and &quot;China Film Report&quot; sided with the screenwriters and gave an explanation that Principal Zhang not only saved the girl, but also saved the mother and allowed her to study in China. Ping Girls&#39; High School has started a new life, which is obviously the narrative of &quot;Girls help girls&quot; (GHG). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not a phenomenon unique to Chinese movies. The same plot has long appeared in Hollywood movies. &amp;nbsp; &quot;Identity politics&quot; has been entangled in the American literary and artistic circles for many years, so that every movie has Americans spend a lot of energy discussing &quot;whether people with specific identities are given enough roles&quot; and &quot;whether specific groups are vilified&quot;. In the end, every time Hollywood releases information about a new film, people will joke that &quot;the skin color of the protagonist has already been determined.&quot; , and also send a funny P picture of the protagonist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts have proved that this &quot;American political correctness&quot; itself has gone beyond the discussion of art, but has become a complete choice of sides, which has caused harm to the artistic value of movies. If the audience&#39;s focus on a movie should be on &quot;whether it vilifies certain groups&quot; and &quot;whether certain groups have roles&quot; instead of whether the movie itself is good-looking or not and what its artistic value is, then I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s definitely not the luck of the film practitioners. , will also make film criticism out of focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oscar winner Alex Gibney believes that biographical films need to have a unique, sharp and novel angle, otherwise it will be difficult to succeed because of &quot;packing in a lot of big ideas&quot;. The 2016 movie &quot;The First Lady&quot; starring Kennedy&#39;s wife Jacqueline suffered a disastrous box office failure. The reason was not a gender issue, but the lack of skills of the screenwriter and director, who failed to star Natalie Portman. Jacqueline stepped out of the &quot;iconic shell&quot; that Americans are familiar with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the freedom of the director and screenwriter to express whatever truth they want to express. If the film is forced to comply with certain &quot;progressive issues&quot; and &quot;identity politics&quot;, then it will probably bring more artistic value to the film. Big damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“两极分化的印度”，“捡跑侠”难解垃圾顽疾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261174]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Delhi, India, 34-year-old marathon runner Beverly is used to picking up garbage at her feet while jogging. On city streets, on coastal beaches, and on park paths, he picked up plastic bottles, cans, wrapping paper, or fruit peels while running, and put them into the recyclable bags he carried with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sport played by Beverly is called &quot;Plogging&quot;, which was first popular in Sweden. He started promoting this sport in India at the end of 2016, and it has gradually become a popular fitness trend. Beverley is also known as India&#39;s &quot;Plogman&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, garbage piles that can be seen everywhere have become a &quot;sight&quot; on the streets of India and have received &quot;bad reviews&quot; from international tourists. Since Indian Prime Minister Modi launched the &quot;cleanliness movement&quot; in 2014, India has formed a &quot;cleanliness craze&quot; from the government to the private sector, and Indian people including Beverly have also participated in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, nine years later, &quot;urban problems&quot; such as garbage siege and the livelihood of waste pickers have not yet been completely solved. For India, currently the most populous country, the problem of garbage disposal still has a long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“India’s achievement of unmanned landing on the moon has led to an unexpected consensus among G20 members that India has become the fastest growing country among the world’s large economies. However, despite these achievements, India still It has not eliminated the impression that its cities are dirty and the streets are full of garbage.&quot; &quot;Nikkei News Network&quot; published an article on November 8, 2023, commenting that India should pay attention to the issue of cleanliness, which will help &quot;make India&#39;s global image and achievements consistent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;India’s “pick-up-and-run man”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Beverley “pick-up-and-run” with young people on his birthday (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/c7f9977fe3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/c7f9977fe3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverley &quot;picked up and ran&quot; with the young people on her birthday. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 15, 2023 is Beverly’s birthday. Early in the morning, he completed a small pick-and-run in the woods with some young men. Seven people harvested seven big bags of &quot;trophies.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Children and teenagers love activities like this very much.” said Beverly, who has organized pickup and run activities in more than 150 schools. &quot;Even adults enjoy this activity. It gives people the motivation to get up early, get outdoors, exercise and clean the environment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beverley often chooses to jog early in the morning for exercise, &quot;when There are fewer people and there are no cars on the road.” One day at the end of 2016, Beverly picked up the garbage in front of him while jogging. &quot;There was a lot of garbage on the ground, so I picked it up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The word Plogging did not exist in India at that time. Seeing Beverly do this, his friends join in. &quot;I want to change people&#39;s mindset - littering on the road is our responsibility.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beverley is known as India&#39;s first &#39;picker&#39;. He created a set of &quot;trash workouts&quot; that he said could effectively exercise participants&#39; muscles and bones.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Beverly&#39;s demonstration, this set of actions included squats, bows, and squats. Steps, stretches, duck steps, biceps and triceps curls, shoulders and back. If it weren’t for the recyclable trash bag on your shoulder and the discarded plastic box and straw in your hand, this would look like It is a common morning exercise.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the years, Beverly and her friends have launched many “pick-up and run” activities. The largest one was the “RElan&amp;nbsp;Trash-Free India” from September to November 2019 &quot;Long-distance running&quot; was also the activity that impressed Beverley most. In 50 days, Beverley ran in 50 cities in India, covering a distance of 1,000 kilometers on foot.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, Modi The Prime Minister called me and said that the Indian government will do this with us. Today, with the support of the Indian government, more than 10 million Indians have participated in this movement. &quot;It is no accident that Beverly launched the pick-up and run activity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as September 2014, Indian Prime Minister Modi announced a &quot;Clean India Campaign&quot; plan, calling on Indian citizens to create a &quot;clean India.&quot; He also called on, &quot;Everyone spends at least 100 hours cleaning every year. We can no longer tolerate India being dirty. &quot;On October 2, 2014, Modi personally came to a gathering area of ​​cleaning workers in New Delhi, the capital, picked up a broom and cleaned the road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, on August 29, 2019, the Indian National Sports On the same day, Modi also launched a &quot;Fit India Movement&quot; campaign to call on and encourage people to prioritize exercise and fitness in their daily lives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bev Lee &quot;picks up and runs&quot; in the marathon (photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/c59267463a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/c59267463a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259439&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beverley &quot;picks up and runs&quot; in the marathon. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Modi government With the support of , India has launched a &quot;clean&quot; and &quot;healthy&quot; craze from the government to the private sector. Beverley&#39;s &quot;pick-up and run&quot; activities are perfectly in line with these two trends.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Beverley Lee organizes 1-2 pick-up and run activities every week in some cities or small towns in India. These garbage are often sent to local municipal agencies or private recyclers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people think that &quot;pick-up and run&quot; It only maintains short-term, limited cleaning. Garbage disposal requires professional cleaning staff, cleaning companies, financial support, etc., and is a complex project. Beverly agrees with this view.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters, For more than a century, the entire world has struggled with the amount of solid waste generated. Waste management is a complex issue that requires the combined efforts of many stakeholders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, pick-up runs or waste fitness have transformed us Attitude towards garbage. When you bend down to pick up trash, you will stop littering. At the same time, we strive to reduce waste and switch to biodegradable materials to make it sustainable. &quot;Beverley said, &quot;Imagine if 8 billion people on the earth adhere to the concept of sustainability, this will be the key point to solve this crisis. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Polarized India”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;People, including Beverley, have great expectations for a “clean India”, but for a population of 1.4 billion and 2.98 million square kilometers For India, garbage disposal is not a simple issue.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chinese tourists who have traveled to India in recent years, &quot;dirty&quot; is still a high-frequency word during the trip.&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Amo went on a free trip to India on New Year&#39;s Day 2020 and visited three cities: Delhi, Agra and Jaipur.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the famous Chandni Bazaar in urban Delhi, Amo saw many vendors After the business ends for the day, a fire will be set to burn the garbage in front of the store. People gather in small groups to warm themselves by the fire in front of the burning garbage. &quot;There is a smell of burning plastic in the air, which is very unpleasant to the nose.&quot; &quot;Amo recalled to Southern Weekend reporters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;At Delhi&#39;s Chandni Chowk, people warmed themselves around a fire burning garbage (photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/428dbd31e2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/24/428dbd31e2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moonlight in Delhi At the market, people warm themselves around the fires burning garbage. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the short trip, Amo felt that only the scenic spots were relatively clean. Even where Amo stayed On the street in front of the hotel, you can often see piles of garbage that have not been cleaned up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ono traveled to India in 2017 and 2019, and also felt the &quot;polarization&quot; of India.&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In Udaipur, known as the &quot;Venice of the East,&quot; and in the ancient Hindu city of Vananasi, Ono saw the beautiful side of India. In places such as the embassy district, hotels, and some technological cities in southern India, Ono felt &quot;cleaner than Europe.&quot; .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The ground of the hotel is like a mirror, but as soon as I walked out of the hotel door, I saw a pile of garbage piled on the road. &quot;Ono believes that India does not spend money on &quot;infrastructure and the poor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mumbai is the economic center of India. It is home to the richest people in India and has the most expensive housing prices in India. However, Dharavi is also the largest slum in India and Asia. The 2008 Indian movie &quot;Slumdog Millionaire&quot; was shot here. This movie, which won eight Oscars, also made Dharavi famous.&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In March 2019, Ono visited the Dharavi slums on the spot. Many small workshops were opened in the area she visited, such as waste processing, food processing, clothing and leather goods processing, metal processing, etc. The workers During the busy period, &quot;everyone has a friendly smile.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the working environment here is not optimistic. In the video shot by Ono, plastic packages filled with waste are piled on the roadside, low The short houses &quot;shake hands and face each other&quot;, and everywhere there are narrow &quot;alleys&quot; that can only allow one person to pass. &quot;The workers basically live on the second floor, and there is a nearly vertical small wooden ladder to go up, and it is dark and there is no light at all. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In the Dharavi slums of Mumbai, workers live and work in poor sanitary conditions. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/3f3e11d2fa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1340&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/3f3e11d2fa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259441&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Dharavi slums of Mumbai, workers live and work in poor sanitary conditions. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trip was conducted by a guide Accompanying, because Dharavi also has many urban scavengers and unemployed people living in it. “The guide said that foreigners once disappeared because they walked too deep. &quot;Ono said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indian Mu Kejie&#39;s hometown is in Calcutta. When he was learning Chinese, his teacher gave him this Chinese name. From 2017 to 2021, Mu Kejie worked in a Chinese-owned company in Delhi. I have worked in the company for four years and am deeply aware of Delhi’s air pollution and public health issues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Delhi’s air is particularly bad in winter, and there is a very pungent smell in the air. &quot;Mu Kejie told Southern Weekend reporters that Delhi is related to climate, population, and industry, and the garbage problem is also one of them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the raging COVID-19 epidemic, the number of tourists traveling to India decreased significantly, and the flow of local residents also decreased relatively. Reduced. This has actually been a &quot;blessing in disguise&quot; for some cities. &quot;During the epidemic, the garbage and pollution situation in Delhi was much better. Because of the lockdown at home, private cars did not go out, and the air quality was also good. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Mu Kejie has moved to near Mumbai. In his opinion, the sanitation facilities in many cities in India have improved significantly in recent years. For example, it was rare to see trash cans and garbage trucks on the road before. . And now &quot;trash cans are widely deployed in cities.&quot; Moreover, garbage trucks transfer garbage every day, and the garbage of that day will not accumulate near the home for a long time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, more sanitation &quot;stubborn problems&quot; remain Stay in the city.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Mu Kejie visited a landfill in Delhi, which left a bad impression on him. &quot;The experience was particularly bad. &quot;He recalled that the garbage in the landfill was not processed, and many people went to pick up the garbage and sell it to others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The government has proposed to solve these garbage problems, but there has been no progress. ” He said.&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The “stubborn disease” of municipal waste&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2016, a fire broke out in the Deonar landfill near Mumbai, which burned for several months, causing smog in Mumbai all day long. Wandering. The number of patients with respiratory diseases received by local hospitals has surged. The Washington Post compared the landfill to &quot;the city&#39;s silent killer&quot; and &quot;a toxic time bomb.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, in 2023 On March 2, a &quot;garbage mountain&quot; caught fire again in Cochin, Kerala, southern India. The resulting thick smoke and toxic gas filled the sky over the city, causing residents to choke and cough, and many schools were forced to close... A week later , the fire has not been completely extinguished.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If street garbage is only an eyesore, then large-scale landfills located on the edge of cities have become &quot;public nuisances&quot; everywhere, threatening the safety of the urban environment and the health of residents. During the decomposition or decay process of large amounts of garbage and waste, toxic gases such as methane, hydrogen sulfide and carbon monoxide will be released, causing fire hazards.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2021, Modi announced the &quot;Clean India Campaign&quot; vigorously advocated by the government &quot; has officially entered the second phase. This time, the government&#39;s work focuses on the two themes of &quot;garbage-free cities&quot; and comprehensive purification of urban water sources. According to reports, the Modi government plans to invest approximately 1.41 trillion in &quot;Clean India Movement 2.0&quot; rupees (approximately 120 billion yuan).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his public speech, Modi also &quot;named&quot; the Gazipur garbage dump that has troubled Delhi for many years, promising that such &quot;garbage mountains&quot; will be completely eliminated in the future. be removed. India will build a series of landfills and sewage treatment plants to gradually replace the open landfill treatment method, effectively improve the urban environment, and create &quot;green jobs&quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Modi The ambitions are high, but the reality is a little cruel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A 2020 survey by the New Delhi-based non-profit organization &quot;Center for Science and Environment&quot; showed that there are as many as 3,159 large-scale &quot;garbage mountains&quot; in India, and the hoarded The total weight of garbage reaches 800 million tons. The scale and quantity of waste left behind in these landfills has become a &quot;ticking time bomb&quot; and has related environmental impacts, including air, water and soil pollution.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, The landfill in Deonar, a suburb of Mumbai, India, has exceeded 16 million tons, with the highest mountain height reaching 36.5 meters and covering an area of ​​more than 120 hectares.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gan Gan, a person in charge of the &quot;Science and Environment Center&quot; Shyam said that the government&#39;s environmental plan may still be feasible in small and medium-sized cities, but the existing super landfill waste in large cities is too large and difficult to be &quot;digested&quot; by artificial means.&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; “Solid waste management is a global issue. Every city in the world is struggling with it. Regarding the garbage mountain on the edge of Delhi&#39;s city, Beverley said helplessly that some cities are good at managing garbage problems, but Delhi has not been able to manage it effectively.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Delhi Municipal Corporation is formulating a plan to Reduce and hopefully eliminate these mountains of waste through appropriate disposal methods, including waste-to-energy. &quot; He added.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the difficulty of disposal, &quot;urban waste&quot; is also related to the livelihood of many poor people in India. If the Indian government completely cleans up these landfills, millions of &quot;living on the mountain&quot; will &quot;The scavengers are afraid of losing their livelihood.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Mu Kejie&#39;s hometown of Calcutta, he saw many scavengers who made a living by picking up garbage. These people picked up recyclable bottles and used clothes. They have also received help from some public welfare organizations. &quot;Some of them are very young, in their twenties and thirties, and they come out to scavenge because they can&#39;t find jobs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Scavenger&quot; Beverly also proposed that scavenging Collectors are an important group in the clean-up movement, saying they play an important role in helping to recycle large amounts of waste, especially PET plastic bottles. He said, &quot;Many NGOs are working with waste pickers and they should get more recognition and better working conditions. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data disclosed by Indian media, there are approximately 1.5 million to 4 million people working in garbage dumps across India. Most of them are from humble backgrounds, have no decent education, and have few skills. According to international According to data from the non-profit organization Save the Children, in New Delhi, the capital of India, at least 10,000 waste pickers are children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, due to the lack of urban garbage collection services, a large amount of garbage currently generated in India is left unprocessed. is dumped into landfills, rivers or oceans. On the one hand, India is not well equipped to deal with its current waste. On the other hand, with its rapidly expanding economy, the country&#39;s waste generation is expected to grow exponentially. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As media comments said, Indian policymakers currently need to turn their attention to waste and adopt &quot;a stronger commitment to deal with waste management issues.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多地儿科告急！“儿科荒”何时能破]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261215]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/24/GA9G1ObTEyVuxMRK7aUkIRm9AspyiGzacV4JqMBw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/GA9G1ObTEyVuxMRK7aUkIRm9AspyiGzacV4Jq MBw. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259520&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Outside the pediatric clinic of a tertiary hospital in Beijing&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A packed pediatric clinic&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 12, a patient returned from the pediatric emergency room That night, Lin Ling bought a folding stool online. Earlier in the day, she had stood outside the emergency room for more than five hours. She didn&#39;t know whether the child would have a recurrence of the disease in the future, so she had to prepare for a rainy day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Ling’s son suddenly had a fever after lunch. Always active, he first reclined on the sofa, and soon climbed into bed and curled up. Lin Ling quickly took her ear temperature - 38.5°C. Considering that recently some children in schools and interest classes have taken leave due to mycoplasma pneumonia, Lin Ling&#39;s heart is tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Ling’s family lives in Chaoyang District, Beijing. The peak period of mycoplasma infections in Beijing is usually from September to November, and the situation in 2023 is different from previous years. In early November, Yin Yudong, deputy chief physician of the Department of Infectious Diseases and Clinical Microbiology at Beijing Chaoyang Hospital, said in an interview with the Beijing News that under normal circumstances, the weather in late winter is too cold and dry, and the survival of mycoplasma will be restricted. However, due to mycoplasma infections in the past few years, There are too few patients, and the peak incidence this year may be extended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, influenza-like illness cases and positive influenza tests are also increasing. Xu Baoping, director of the Respiratory Department of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital, said in an interview with CCTV News that the viruses currently detected include influenza virus, parainfluenza virus, adenovirus, respiratory syncytial virus, rhinovirus, metapneumovirus, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Lin Ling gave the child antipyretic medicine, he quickly went to the platform to register. She is used to going to a tertiary general hospital near her home. The number of outpatient clinics for the day has been exhausted, but emergency services will be opened at 5 p.m. When she arrived at the emergency room, the doctor had not yet arrived, and there was already a long queue at the door of the clinic. The queue formed a U-shape along the narrow aisle. Lin Ling&#39;s registration number is 36, but unlike the clinics she is familiar with, this place does not use the registration method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An experienced parent explained to newcomers, &quot;Usually there are few people coming here to see the emergency department. When they come, they just go to see the emergency department without calling the number. There are too many sick children during this period.&quot; However, the medical system has not been changed so quickly, and we still only have to wait in line. Moreover, after queuing up to get a blood test order, you have to re-queue to see the results.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Families with sufficient medical attendants often adopt this method. &quot;Team battle&quot; strategy: Arrange two people to line up one at a time, one at a time, and a few people apart. When the person in front arrives, he will take the child to see a doctor first, and issue a blood test order to draw blood. After about 15 minutes, the results will come out, and the second person will follow soon. When the time comes, take your child to the doctor to see the results and wait for the next treatment plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the most efficient. Of course, the &quot;top match&quot; strategy also requires the introduction of a third person. Otherwise, the adults in the queue would have to ask people in front and behind to help reserve seats from time to time, and then rush to the distance to check on the sick child sitting alone on the chair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s okay to raise a child. It&#39;s just Mr. Fei. Even a child is like this. I admire you two-child families.&quot; The two mothers chatted, and one of them brought two children to the emergency room. There are also such examples around Lin Ling. The young son of one of her friends was infected with mycoplasma. In order to avoid infecting the eldest daughter, the grandmother had to stay in a hotel with her grandson for a whole week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/rc77rmNoZqQosf3kCs1OpN7qBwI41OnfUPZis3NS.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;1333&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/rc77rmNoZqQosf3kCs1OpN7qBwI41OnfUPZis3NS.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259523&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of November 12, 2023, parents and children were waiting at the door of the pediatric emergency department of a tertiary hospital in Beijing &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Photo provided by the interviewee /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a staff member in the aisle wearing a blue vest with the words &quot;Chaoyang Mass&quot; printed on it. Because parents queued for too long, he would go to the queue every once in a while to ask if there were any children whose temperatures had not been taken for a long time. If a child&#39;s temperature is too high, has sudden symptoms, or has underlying diseases, he will take the child to &quot;jump in line&quot; and find a doctor for early diagnosis and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents who complained about process optimization to no avail and could only stand and wait began to share their experiences of taking their children to see a doctor these days. Some of them have been transferred to two or three hospitals; some children have been taking cephalosporins and azithromycin for several days, but their fevers cannot be relieved; some test results are normal, but they have high fever and constant coughing; some children have taken various medicines for half a month, but their symptoms are gone. Well, a rash started to appear instead... A parent behind Lin Ling took out his mobile phone to check the pediatric emergency room of another nearby tertiary hospital. The mini program reminded him that it would take at least 6 hours to get to the emergency room there. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the conversation, Lin Ling learned that compared with children’s specialist hospitals, general hospitals have slightly fewer people, but some parents still prefer to stay close to them. Many of them have often visited several hospitals. The child has been in treatment for some time. However, in their view, there are still many &quot;unclear&quot; aspects of this round of infection. For example, the diagnosis cannot be made clearly based on the test results or chest X-ray alone, or the treatment effect is not good after taking medicine for several days. Some parents can only place their hope. The specialized hospital has seen more cases and can make a clear diagnosis, so that the child will suffer less. &quot;It is just to have less trouble.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly three hours later, Lin Ling&#39;s child finally A blood test was done and it was confirmed that it was a bacterial infection. Lin Ling breathed a sigh of relief, &quot;At least I understand.&quot; Because the white blood cells increased significantly and the child was not in good spirits, the doctor prescribed an infusion order. The pediatric infusion room in the emergency room is not spacious. In order to make room for the children undergoing infusion, parents can only stand by the seats and wait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was mid-term exam week. Lin Ling saw a junior high school-looking child with a stack of information on her knees. She was holding an injection in one hand and writing and drawing on the paper with the other hand. There was a mobile phone next to her. Online classes are playing. Another girl was in fourth or fifth grade. After the infusion, she insisted that the nurse pull out the indwelling needle. &quot;We&#39;ll talk about the injection tomorrow. It&#39;s inconvenient to write with this needle.&quot; The girl came with a schoolbag on her back, and her mother stayed by her side. The girl was diagnosed with mycoplasma pneumonia, and the doctor asked for a three-day sick leave, but the mother and daughter insisted on only issuing a leave note for physical education classes. &quot;There are midterm exams on Wednesday and Thursday,&quot; the girl said. While queuing up, Lin Ling learned that when classes resume after taking leave due to illness, the school will require relevant certification documents. There are many parents who choose to send their children to school while sick. &quot;This is also one of the reasons why cross-infection occurs easily in schools.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;It was already past 10 pm when Lin Ling left the infusion room with her child. Walking through the still bustling corridor, Lin Ling glanced at the busy clinic. The long night of the doctor on duty has not yet begun, where she will see patients non-stop until early the next morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Not many choices&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Faced with his daughter’s sudden cough and fever, Li Ang, who lives in Beijing, adopted a different strategy from Lin Ling. She avoided the overcrowded children&#39;s specialty hospital and the tertiary general hospital, and chose a tertiary hospital near her home for initial consultation, follow-up consultation, and switching from traditional Chinese medicine to western medicine. After going in and out of the hospital three times a week, Li Ang herself began to experience symptoms such as sore throat and nasal congestion. And her daughter’s journey of consultation continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/JJtyFeJ2KfxYAZWGTZEycitylEMvCjOeSa9vSoNX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/JJtyFeJ2KfxYAZWGTZEycitylEMvCjOeSa9vSoNX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259522&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Patients and their families waiting for CT scans in a tertiary hospital in Beijing&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Ang, the pediatric department of this tertiary hospital has two doctors on weekdays, one each from traditional Chinese medicine and Western medicine. Traditional Chinese medicine doctors will prescribe traditional Chinese medicine granules according to the child&#39;s condition. Due to the good curative effect, Li Ang&#39;s daughter usually comes to this Chinese medicine doctor for headaches, brain fever, and excessive food intake. For this triage, she also chose Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequent laboratory tests showed: blood routine was normal, mycoplasma antigen was negative, and influenza A and B antigens were negative. Taking into account the relative delay in the emergence of mycoplasma antibodies, the doctor decided to treat the child as &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection&quot; after observing the child&#39;s symptoms. He diagnosed the child as &quot;phlegm-dampness invading the lungs&quot; and &quot;respiratory tract infection&quot; and prescribed azithromycin and traditional Chinese medicine granules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking the medicine for two days, Li Ang&#39;s daughter&#39;s body temperature still did not drop. It usually remained below 37.5℃ in the morning and approached 38℃ in the afternoon and evening. At the same time, there would be severe coughing every few minutes during the day, and symptoms such as diarrhea and nausea also appeared. Li Ang quickly contacted the Chinese medicine doctor who prescribed the medicine online, and the other party suggested adding an antipyretic Chinese patent medicine. That day, the child&#39;s body temperature finally dropped below 37°C. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 20, when Li Ang brought his daughter to the pediatrician for a follow-up consultation, there were obviously more people waiting for the consultation. She learned from the triage nurse that there were only three or four medical staff in the department, and they usually saw 50 or 60 patients a day. Recently, they saw 100 patients every day, and another 20 or 30 patients were needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because diarrhea and nausea were suspected to be adverse reactions of azithromycin, the doctor believed that he had taken enough for three days and could stop taking the medicine. He also prescribed five pairs of traditional Chinese medicine granules for relieving cough and reducing phlegm and a Western medicine for reducing phlegm. Three days later, Li Ang&#39;s daughter&#39;s symptoms improved a lot and she was finally able to resume classes. After going to school for a few days, my daughter felt a little tired when she came home every day, and her coughing sound was quite heavy. It sounded like there was a lot of phlegm in her throat, but she couldn&#39;t cough it out, so she had to take another leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, Li Ang checked the diagnosis and treatment plans of some recent related cases online and found that this wave of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections has the characteristics of long course, easy recurrence, strong drug resistance and the possibility of developing severe disease. When words such as &quot;nebulization, hanging bottle, hospitalization, lung washing&quot; frequently popped up in front of his eyes, Li Ang began to worry that his daughter was at risk of developing pneumonia, and decided to follow up for a follow-up visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She originally considered changing to a tertiary tertiary hospital, but after checking three or four tertiary hospitals for pediatrics, all the appointments for the past week were full, and she was worried about cross-infection when she went to the emergency room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, she could only go to the tertiary hospital where she had been treated for the third time. This time she chose Western medicine. After auscultation, the doctor recommended a CT scan to rule out pneumonia. But here comes the problem. The pediatric department of this hospital cannot infuse infusions. If there is a problem with the film, you have to go to another hospital for infusion treatment. So the doctor suggested that the child should be given aerosol treatment first. If the condition does not improve, then go to a pediatrician in a hospital that can infuse for a CT scan. This tertiary hospital has a limited number of atomizing equipment, but there are many patients waiting for treatment. To avoid cross-infection, the nurse suggested that Li Ang buy a home atomizing machine himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These days, Li Ang has been paying attention to the relevant information and expert interviews about this round of respiratory infectious diseases. He only feels that &quot;everyone has his own thing to say&quot; and &quot;the more he reads, the more confused he becomes.&quot; This feeling seems familiar. At the end of 2022, she also experienced various twists and turns of taking the elderly at home to the emergency room for medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/AUNCnAgIQx7rZZ0uXJnEbNXorW9LK0vgf9RwHcG8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/AUNCnAgIQx7rZZ0uXJnEbNXorW9LK0vgf9RwHcG8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259518&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 23, 2023, in a children&#39;s hospital in Beijing, parents and children waited in the outpatient department&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of the 24th, she came across a &quot;Children&#39;s Mycoplasma Pneumonia Course &amp;amp; Medication Chart&quot; published by &quot;Beijing Daily&quot;, which wrote: &quot;Don&#39;t worry about the antibody test and chest imaging results. , judging by the drop in body temperature and the improvement of symptoms.&quot; &quot;The fever is gone and only the cough is - it&#39;s not a big problem, it means that the recovery is getting better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After several days of messages, she finally saw a message that could Information that reassured her a little. At least using body temperature as the main criterion, my daughter is recovering. But this peace of mind was still fragile, so she finally got a job at a maternal and child health hospital, where the pediatric department could take CT scans and infusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, Li Yuchuan, director of the outpatient department of Beijing Children’s Hospital, told CCTV that the hospital’s internal medicine department currently receives more than 7,000 patients per day, far exceeding the hospital’s capacity. &quot;Currently, influenza, respiratory syncytial virus, and adenovirus have replaced mycoplasma and become the main pathogens at this peak of infection.&quot; Li Yuchuan suggested that parents of children with the disease should provide daily care for their children and do not need to send them to the doctor if necessary; if necessary, If you go to the hospital for treatment, you can also do your own etiological examination first to improve the efficiency of diagnosis and treatment. At present, the seriousness rate of respiratory tract infections is not high. Parents of children with the disease can seek medical treatment online through the Internet to understand the condition and apply appropriate medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Behind the Pediatric Overdraft&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Different from the situation encountered by Lin Ling, Lu Xin The children&#39;s hospital in the area has launched a self-service billing service before diagnosis in mid-2023. High-frequency testing items including five categories of blood routine, urine routine, C-reactive protein, mycoplasma, influenza and other high-frequency testing items can be completed while waiting in line for self-service billing and payment. This initiative has reduced ineffective waiting time, but even so, the local pediatric department is still overcrowded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The emergency waiting time at the Children&#39;s Hospital in Suzhou is several hours, and the waiting time for hospitalization may be more than a week. Many patients are diverted, and even the pediatric departments of private hospitals are overcrowded. The daily outpatient volume of pediatric outpatients in our health center is also overcrowded. Above 150.&quot; On November 23, after a busy morning, Lu Xin finally squeezed out a little lunch break to be interviewed by Southern People Weekly. He works as a pediatrician in a township health center in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Lu Xin’s observation, the local cases of mycoplasma pneumonia infection have been on the rise since the summer vacation. They began to increase significantly in September. In November, there were mixed infections of influenza A and B. Since September, Lu Xin has not only not had a day off, but his night shift has also been extended. Previously, if there was an emergency at night, Lu Xin would see the doctor from 8 a.m. to 1:30 p.m., then take a 3-hour break before starting duty until 8 a.m. the next day. Now that the number of children is increasing rapidly, Lu Xin will continue to sit in the clinic until 11:30 noon after finishing the night shift, and then go home to rest. &quot;I will try my best to limit each patient&#39;s consultation time to three minutes. If it is longer, it will be too long to finish.&quot; Lu Xin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the confusion Lin Ling heard from parents about the &quot;unclear&quot; symptoms, Lu Xin believed that part of it was caused by &quot;drug resistance.&quot; &quot;At present, our local cases are quite &#39;understanding&#39;. According to the situation we receive, a large number of children&#39;s coughs are caused by mycoplasma infection. Sometimes, because the Mycoplasma pneumoniae antibodies appear later, several more tests are needed. Diagnosis. After being diagnosed, some children are still difficult to cure after taking azithromycin. Medication options for those over 8 years old, especially for adults, will be wider, but at present, azithromycin is actually widely used for mycoplasma infections in children under 8 years old.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/gC73ECOTcuwUHcKsh0CvCnzi9qTVeO9h7pB4f6pr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/gC73ECOTcuwUHcKsh0CvCnzi9qTVeO9h7pB4f6pr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259519&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 18, 2023, in the emergency room of a children&#39;s outpatient clinic of a hospital in Shanghai, patients, children and parents came to see the patient&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Resistance has always been the main reason affecting the effectiveness of mycoplasma treatment, but it has attracted widespread attention from the outside world this year.&quot; China has the highest macrolide resistance rate of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in the world In the country, this proportion reaches 60%-70% among adult patients and more than 80% among pediatric patients, Yin Yudong once mentioned in an interview with the Beijing News. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 version of the &quot;Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Mycoplasma Pneumonia in Children&quot; released by the National Health Commission in February 2023 mentions the usage of azithromycin: &quot;For mild cases, 10 mg/kg/d, qd, orally or Intravenous infusion, the course of treatment is 3 days, which can be extended to 5 days if necessary; or 10 mg/kg/d, qd on the first day, and then 5 mg/kg/d, for 4 days. In severe MPP, azithromycin is recommended for intravenous infusion, 10 mg/kg/d, qd. , use it continuously for about 7 days, and start the second course of treatment after an interval of 3-4 days. The total course of treatment depends on the condition, most of which is 2-3 courses.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This means that the recommended medication time for mycoplasma pneumonia It has advanced from three or four days to five to seven days now,&quot; Lu Xin said. Judging from the medical admissions in the past few months, Lu Xin has indeed come into contact with many children who are resistant to azithromycin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lu Xin’s view, there are many topics worthy of long-term attention behind the recent surge in pediatric outpatient and emergency visits in some places, far exceeding the capacity of hospitals and departments. In addition to continuing to implement and improve the hierarchical diagnosis and treatment system and improving the diagnosis and treatment capabilities of primary medical and health institutions for general infections and the efficiency of severe disease identification and referral, the old problem of long-term shortage of pediatric medical resources has once again attracted widespread attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Lu Xin believes that from a local perspective in Suzhou, many children infected in this round can be properly treated in community hospitals or township hospitals, and there is no problem that the examination cannot be done or the drugs are not available. situation, but he also admitted that even in Jiangsu Province, which has developed medical resources, not all primary hospitals are equipped with specialized pediatricians. This is also the problem Li Ang encountered this time. The community hospital near her home currently does not offer pediatrics. She avoided crowded tertiary-level hospitals and specialized hospitals and chose tertiary-level hospitals with relatively few patients. However, the lack of medical equipment and means made diagnosis and treatment more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The fundamental reason why it is difficult for children to see a doctor is that there are too few pediatricians.” In an interview with the People’s Daily in 2017, he was then vice president of the Pediatrician Branch of the Chinese Medical Doctor Association and Party Committee of the Capital Institute of Pediatrics. Deputy Secretary Yang Jian said that compared with developed countries, the number of pediatricians in our country is not enough. With the liberalization of the two-child policy, the number of children has increased, and the shortage of pediatricians has become more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there is a chain of contempt among hospital departments, pediatrics must be at the end. From the perspective of economic benefits alone, pediatrics have fewer examinations and less medication. &quot;For hospitals, Western medicines and consumables are all 0 price difference, and Chinese herbal medicines will have some bonuses. Pediatric medications are based on body weight and the dosage is small. In terms of examinations, daily Basically, it is a routine blood test, and in special cases, a chest X-ray is required. Not only is the income low, but the efficiency is also low. Children cannot express their condition relatively accurately like adults. The time it takes to see a pediatric patient is equivalent to seeing three or four internal medicine patients. Sometimes if it is not handled well, it will lead to quarrels and complaints from parents,&quot; Lu Xin said frankly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pediatrics has always been one of the departments with a high incidence of medical disputes. &quot;People in the industry often laugh at themselves. Pediatrics is like scolding every three days and beating every seven days.&quot; Li Mo, who majored in clinical medicine, changed careers many years ago. It was only half a year after she entered the pediatric department of a hospital in Beijing. &quot;I have forgotten how I received that slap. I only remember that I felt wronged. That slap shattered my medical dream. Because of the love for their children, it is easy for parents to lose their minds in pediatrics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Mo believes that being unable to accept the working status of &quot;having no money and being beaten and beaten&quot; is an important reason why pediatricians, including her, choose to change careers. In 2022, a male classmate of hers during her master&#39;s degree also resigned from pediatrics. &quot;After working for 15 years, I still haven&#39;t persisted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A doctor&#39;s income is roughly linked to the department&#39;s diagnosis and treatment performance. &quot;Pediatrics can&#39;t make money.&quot; When it comes to money, it often loses money because the hospital still has to invest in warehousing and manpower,&quot; Lu Xin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Profitability affects income levels, which in turn hinders the improvement in the quality and quantity of pediatrician resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the reform of higher education in 1998, the undergraduate major of medical school eliminated the pediatric major and replaced it with the clinical medical major. The major of pediatrics was not subdivided until the postgraduate level. In 1999, the national pediatric major stopped enrolling students. The original intention of the policy adjustment was to improve the learning of general medical knowledge, but due to the low overall attractiveness of pediatrics, more graduates who choose pediatrics are relatively low-ranking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If departments like pediatrics and emergency departments, which are tiring, hard-working and have little money, want to attract talents and reverse the talent gap, the most direct stimulus is to increase the investment of resources in the departments. Increase the income of medical staff in the department. However, the current strategy is to reduce the scores for the postgraduate entrance examination and practicing physician examination in pediatrics. The hospital’s recruitment conditions for pediatric medical staff are also looser than those for adult departments. However, the actual effect is not good, and pediatrics is still short of people. , because the crux of the problem has not been solved.&quot; Lu Xin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2015, the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress voted to pass the amendment to the Population and Family Planning Law, and the universal two-child policy will be officially implemented on January 1, 2016. In 2016, after years of appeals from all parties, the National Health and Family Planning Commission coordinated with the Ministry of Education to resume undergraduate enrollment in pediatrics. The &quot;2015 China Health Statistics Yearbook&quot; shows that in the past five years, the total number of pediatricians in China has dropped from 105,000 to 100,000, with an average of only 0.43 pediatricians per 1,000 children, which is comparable to the national average of 2.06 physicians per 1,000 people. Farther than that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The training of doctors takes a long time. The causes and constraints of the &quot;pediatrics shortage&quot; are complex and cannot be solved quickly by resuming enrollment. Lu Xin can only hope that the shortcomings in pediatric resources exposed this winter will draw continued attention from the public and policymakers to the inherent problems in this field and provide more help to alleviate the problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the National Health Commission issued the &quot;Implementation Plan of the National Health Commission on Implementing the Outline for the Development of Women and Children in China from 2021 to 2030.&quot; The plan points out that by 2030, there will be 1.12 pediatric practicing (assistant) doctors per 1,000 children, and the number of beds will increase to 3.17. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Ling, Li Ang, and Lu Xin are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孩子边输液边写作业：卷成这样，责任在谁？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;During autumn and winter, various epidemic viruses are rampant and pediatric hospitals are overcrowded. Pediatric experts have advised parents not to go to the hospital as soon as their children have a fever, but to rest and observe them at home first. Pediatrics has become a petri dish for various viruses, and the risk of cross-infection is not small; in pediatrics, because there are not enough beds, extra beds are added to the elevator room. Some have turned the observation room into a ward, and some have children sitting in rows receiving intravenous drips. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, several pictures of hospitals have attracted attention and heated discussions. In one photo, several rows of long tables are set up, and it looks like children in upper elementary school or junior high school are sitting and receiving intravenous drips. Most of them are doing homework against the clock, and a few are killing time looking at their mobile phones. In the other two video screenshots, there are also words such as &quot;The hospital thoughtfully prepares desks for children with infusions to do homework&quot; and &quot;Parents: I didn&#39;t want (to let the children) write, but the learning atmosphere is too strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first impression this gives people is that the children are so curled up and miserable. A high fever is an alarm for the body, and the immune system is mobilizing to fight the invading enemy. At this time, physical recovery is the first priority, so don&#39;t worry too much. You should rest and relax, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is too inhumane to allow children to study while sick and do their homework. It has reached the point of going against human nature. Let alone humans, let alone human cubs, even mules, cows and horses are not used in this way. Mules, cows and horses are the property of their owners. If they get sick, the owners will take good care of them, take good care of them, treat them in time, and provide them with nutrition. They will not let them work while they are recovering from illness. Otherwise, the gains will outweigh the losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A parent said in the comments: As a parent, I don’t want him to write at all. The teacher won’t let us go. When asking for sick leave, he has to write the same homework as the students in school. If he can’t finish it, he will get sick. Okay, I’ll make it up together. What if I don’t write it down? The implication is that it is the teacher&#39;s problem, and there is nothing parents and children can do about it. This idea is very typical and deserves to be distinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These children who are studying while sick are still minors and have no or limited capacity for civil conduct. They cannot take their own responsibility. As their guardians, parents have the first responsibility. of. Every parent should act in the best interests of their children, be their strongest backing, and protect their children with sharp claws, beaks, and warm wings like an eagle. This is a responsibility that cannot be shied away from, and is engraved in the Instinct in genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, parents must be responsible and don’t forget their responsibilities; they must have courage and don’t lose their instincts. Children&#39;s homework is not the highest rule that cannot be violated. The education department has introduced homework circuit breaker mechanisms. For example, Zhejiang Province’s burden reduction plan for primary and secondary school students stipulates that primary school students can refuse to do homework after 9 p.m. and junior high school students after 10 p.m. There are laws to follow, it just depends on parents if they dare to use them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What if I don’t make up for the homework I missed during my illness? Homework is just a means to consolidate knowledge. In fact, children with different qualifications need different time and means to consolidate knowledge. Schools and teachers will set the same amount of homework for all children across the board, just to standardize and save trouble, rather than teaching students in accordance with their aptitude. What if parents exempt their children from some homework when they think it is necessary? As a parent of a fifth-grade child, I have exempted my children from a large amount of homework in the past. Sometimes it was because the child was sick at home, sometimes because the homework was too heavy, sometimes because it was meaningless homework, but the child did not fall behind due to this. The teacher did not have a significantly negative view of the child as a result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many parents are afraid of offending teachers and fear that their children will be treated differently in school. In the homeschool group, there are many parents who give teachers all kinds of rainbow farts. Although many parents feel tired of the unreasonable demands imposed by schools and teachers, they dare not express their rejection clearly. No, even when my own child was sick and had an intravenous drip, I didn’t dare to ask the teacher to exempt my child from homework. Instead, I let my child study while sick, creating a strange scene in the corner of the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Schools and teachers certainly hope that parents will invest more time and energy. At the lowest level, they will urge their children to study and check their homework, and at the highest level, they will allow their children to learn in advance and learn more deeply. This can reduce the burden on teachers. With this burden, teachers and schools can more easily achieve education KPIs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But parents must understand: the family is not the dispatching agency of the school, parents are not the executors of the teacher&#39;s instructions, family education is not a vassal of school education, and knowledge education is only a small part of the total education. If parents value school knowledge and education above all else, they will feel that high marks are the key to everything. How can they tolerate their children not doing their homework? If parents feel that the teacher is in charge of their children and therefore also in charge of themselves, they will treat the teacher as their direct superior, and they will have to perform well in front of the teacher as if they are afraid of losing their job, and push their children to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, family education is more important than school education to some extent, and it cannot be limited to knowledge education. The more important education is character education and values ​​education. It is meaningless to just preach. Teaching by example is better than words. Much more important. Parents play cards and games every day, but they want their children to study hard and read books. The two cannot add up. If parents want their children to be cheerful and optimistic, interact more with peers, and go outdoors more often, they must lead by example and let their children see the necessity and correctness of doing so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among all character education and value education, courage education is the most important. Only when children have courage can they dare to refuse unreasonable demands, and only then can they be cheerful and full of righteousness to explore, explore and try. . If children devote all their time to knowledge education and neglect character education, values ​​education, and courage education, how can children release their free nature and grow into a mentally strong person? Parents are submissive and timid to their teachers, which makes them appear humble and set a very bad example. How can children relax their nature and cultivate courage and determination? Nowadays, children&#39;s mental health problems are prominent, and there is a problem that schools cannot control them properly, but the responsibility of parents cannot be denied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents are the starting line for their children. Before forcing their children to die, parents should look at themselves in the mirror. It is okay to hope that their children will become dragons and that their daughters will become phoenixes, but they should not put their own unfulfilled ambitions on their children, which will crush them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[告别“三元时代”，饮料集体提价：“都有经营数据压力”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261176]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:55:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/24/243f95be7b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 24/243f95be7b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The price adjustment effect is immediate. Take Coca-Cola as an example. In the second quarter of 2023, Coca-Cola&#39;s revenue increased by 6% year-on-year, exceeding expectations. The important reason is that the price of Coca-Cola increased by 10% compared with the same period in 2022. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverages are bidding farewell to the &quot;Three Yuan Era&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Starting from November 2023, Master Kong&#39;s beverage prices will increase across the board - the retail price of packaging of Master Kong&#39;s tea and juice series products will be adjusted from 3 yuan/bottle to 3.5 yuan/bottle bottle, the retail price of 1L bottle is adjusted from 4 yuan/bottle to 5 yuan/bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Master Kong iced black tea is favored by users because of its low price and high cost performance. Master Kong’s customer service stated that the price increase was due to rising raw material and labor costs, and that retail prices across the country will be adjusted uniformly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the prices of two sizes of iced black tea in many Wumart supermarkets in Beijing have been consistent with the price adjustment notice. The prices in convenience stores such as Lawson are slightly higher. The 500ml package sells for 4 yuan. The price in online channels is slightly lower, but it is also higher than before. The price of 12 bottles of 1L iced black tea sold in Tingyi Tmall flagship store is 54.9 yuan, which is about 4.6 yuan per bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Master Kong is already a latecomer to price adjustments, and this wave of beverage price increases has already begun in the second half of 2022. In February 2023, Nongfu Spring announced that it would adjust the price of 19L bottled water in Hangzhou by 2 yuan, and Yakult also announced that the unit price of original products would increase from 11.7 yuan to 12.8 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Historically, this is the fifth wave of price increases in the beverage industry. Since 2006, the domestic food and beverage industry has experienced four price increases, namely in 2010, 2012, 2017, and 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The effect of price adjustment is immediate. Take Coca-Cola as an example. In the second quarter of 2023, Coca-Cola&#39;s revenue increased by 6% year-on-year, exceeding expectations. The important reason is that the price of Coca-Cola increased by 10% compared with the same period in 2022. It is against this background that Coca-Cola President and Chief Financial Officer John Murphy said that Coca-Cola will continue to increase prices in the second half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Beverage companies are all under pressure from operating data.&quot; Zhang Yi, chief analyst of iiMedia Consulting, pointed out to Southern Weekend reporters that there will naturally be comparisons when beverages are sold at low prices. Good sales data, but profits are relatively disproportionate, so companies need to raise prices to increase profits in financial reports. This is the &quot;most direct way.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sugar prices continue to rise&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yingtao, a partner of Analysys Analysis and Consulting, told Southern Weekend reporters that the rise in sugar prices and packaging bottle raw material prices is the reason for this increase. The reason for the price increase of beverages “is the result of transmission throughout the industry chain.” A Haitong Securities research report shows that among the costs of the soft drink industry, manufacturing and labor on the raw material side account for 20%, white sugar accounts for 15%, and fruit juice accounts for 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Food and beverage marketing expert Yu Runjie told Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, white sugar accounted for 20%-30% of the total cost of beverages, but now many companies choose sweetened sugar. Flavoring agents are used to replace or partially replace white sugar, resulting in a reduction in the proportion of white sugar in costs and a reduction in the correlation between beverage prices and sugar prices. &quot;Of course, the prices of beverage brands and products that still insist on using white sugar will still be greatly affected by rising sugar prices.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the food and beverage industry , The price increase chain is generally transmitted from global commodity price increases to domestic bulk raw materials, then to the manufacturing industry, and then to midstream consumer goods companies, and finally downstream consumers feel the price increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data released by the China Sugar Association in October 2023 show that in the 2022/23 sugar production period, the country will produce a total of 8.97 million tons of sugar, a year-on-year decrease of 590,000 tons. . The cumulative average sales price of finished white sugar by sugar industry enterprises across the country is 6,270 yuan/ton, a year-on-year increase of 516 yuan/ton. The average sales price of finished white sugar in August was as high as 7,035 yuan/ton, while in August 2022 the price was only 5,747 yuan/ton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main sources of sugar production are sugar cane and beets, of which sugar cane sugar accounts for 80%. Due to climate problems such as drought, sugarcane production will drop significantly worldwide in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the case with India, the largest sugar producer. Zhang Yi pointed out that under the influence of geopolitics, energy prices have risen, and more sugar has been used as biofuel. India plans to use 4.5 million to 5 million tons of sugar cane required for sugar production to produce ethanol, which will also occupy part of the sugar cane supply and affect India&#39;s sugar production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is against this background that, according to CCTV news reports, India announced a ban on sugar exports starting in October in response to domestic sugarcane production reductions due to climate change. Sugar supply is tight and prices are soaring. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sugar substitute products are also rising in price&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It’s not just sugary drinks. Southern Weekend reporters found that in this round of price increases, The prices of some sugar-free drinks have also increased.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, starting from January 2023, Yakult not only increased the price of the regular version, but also the low-sugar version with sucralose. It was adjusted from 12.7 yuan to 13.8 yuan, an increase of about 8.6%, which is equivalent to the regular version. In addition, Suntory&#39;s sugar-free oolong tea and sugar-free version of Vitasoy have also raised prices one after another, by about 1 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, sugar substitute products used in beverages include aspartame, sucralose, erythritol, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The September price adjustment letter from the sugar substitute manufacturer Kangbao Biochemical shows that the price of sucralose products has been adjusted to 180 yuan/kg for large packages and 182 yuan/kg for small packages. Kilogram, it was previously 140 yuan/kg; another company, Jinhe Industrial, adjusted its price twice in a row in September. After the price of sucralose increased from 138,000/ton to 150,000/ton, it was adjusted to 180,000/ton. According to data from Haitong International, the market price of acesulfame potassium also rose from 38,000 yuan/ton to 48,000 yuan/ton in September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The increase in the price of sugar substitute products is related to the increase in their raw materials. Herbalife Biochemical pointed out in the price adjustment letter that the price of DMF, the main raw material for glycerol production, has increased by nearly 7,000 yuan/ton, acetic acid has increased by nearly 2,000 yuan/ton, white sugar has increased by nearly 1,000 yuan/ton, sulfoxide chloride and other The price of raw materials generally increased by 300-800 yuan per ton, and all raw materials continued to rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the impact of rising raw material prices, sugar substitute product manufacturers also attribute the increase in sucralose production costs to the approaching heating season, raw material transportation costs, steam energy Consumption costs continue to increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At present, not only upstart beverage companies like Yuanqi Forest, but also traditional beverage manufacturers such as Master Kong and Nongfu Spring have launched sugar-free products to seize the market. Coca-Cola&#39;s annual report shows that the sales growth rate of sugar-free Coca-Cola in 2022 will reach 11%, which is much higher than the regular version of Coca-Cola. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on this, Yu Runjie believes that after the price of sugar rises, many companies will choose to replace sugar with lower-cost sugar substitute products, especially in the &quot; In the &quot;zero sugar&quot; trend, more companies are choosing sugar substitute products, which will also lead to a rapid increase in demand for sugar substitute products and an increase in the price of sugar substitute products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f198ca73ce.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f198ca73ce.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;COFCO Sugar stated in the minutes of the investor exchange meeting disclosed on November 1, 2023 that the current domestic and foreign sugar prices are at historically high levels, and are generally expected to remain high next year. There is a gap between supply and demand, and sugar prices are likely to remain high. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The leader takes the lead in raising prices, and competing products follow up in 3-6 months&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generally speaking, based on market competition Considering that in the face of high-priced raw materials, downstream beverage manufacturers maintain a wait-and-see attitude and choose to postpone the replenishment of sugar stocks or maintain costs through other means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, Guangzhou Langqi stated in its reply to investors that Huatang Food, a subsidiary that operates refined sugar and beverage businesses, carries out arbitrage in white sugar futures and white sugar options. The long-term hedging business effectively avoids and reduces operating risks caused by fluctuations in raw material prices and ensures the relative stability of product costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the continued rise in sugar prices has not stopped. COFCO Sugar stated in the investor exchange meeting minutes disclosed on November 1 that the current domestic and international sugar prices are at historically high levels. It is generally expected that there will still be a supply and demand gap next year, and sugar prices are likely to remain high. Suntory said in the price increase notice that the company has hedged against the increased costs through internal operating cost optimization and other measures. However, the current cost increase &quot;has reached the limit that our company can bear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Manufacturers will also observe the choices of competitors. &quot;If the leading company does not raise prices, it will basically be more difficult for other companies to raise prices, or they will simply not dare to raise prices.&quot; Li Yingtao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take Master Kong as an example. This round of price increases starting in the second half of 2022 has given it enough confidence. Tingyi&#39;s previous financial report was not good-looking. Goldman Sachs also lowered Tingyi&#39;s sales forecast for the second half of the year in October 2023. Tingyi urgently needs to break the current situation of &quot;increasing revenue without increasing profits&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, the timing of price increases is also a consideration. Beverage price increases are usually carried out in the fourth quarter, the off-season sales season. A beverage distributor told Southern Weekend reporters that it would take 1-2 months for price increases to be transmitted to the sales terminal market, and requested that promotion activities be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Runjie said that during the peak beverage sales season from May to September, dealers and channels have more goods. If the price is adjusted at this time, firstly, it will easily lead to The second reason is that the market mixes goods and the channels have random prices, which have a greater impact on sales. Adjusting prices after the peak sales season is over can minimize the impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A research report from Ping An Securities also shows that price increases usually occur after 1-2 quarters of rising raw material costs, with leading companies taking the lead in raising prices. Other competing products will follow in about 3-6 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Use price increases to increase channel profits? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The exact same drink is more expensive to buy in convenience stores than in large supermarkets, and large supermarkets are often more expensive than online channels. This is because of the price increases in different channels. different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverage price increases generally include increases at two levels - an increase in factory ex-factory prices and an increase in terminal sales prices, both of which usually occur at the same time. In addition to rising production costs, channel profits are also an important factor affecting price increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yingtao said that channel distribution fees are also the main cost of beverages, accounting for about 20%. In addition, dealers and agents at all levels in provinces, cities and counties play a major role. Cost also accounts for about 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In supermarket containers, the price of a wide range of beverages is generally above 5 yuan, and the price that dealers are willing to pay for these high-priced beverages is generally higher. Currently, channel push is still an important force in the sales growth of FMCG, especially new beverage brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Runjie believes that the increase in beverage prices not only increases costs, but also increases channel profits through price increases, so as to improve the channel and The competitiveness of terminal stores. Vitasoy directly pointed out in the price adjustment notice that while the price adjustment is being made, it will &quot;reasonably increase channel gross profit and bring better sales profits to customers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Personally, I don’t think that the new beverage brands with higher prices on the market are more high-end in terms of product content, but they just bring more profits to the channel than traditional beverage brands. It&#39;s just higher, which leads to higher selling prices.&quot; Yu Runjie believes that after the price increase of traditional beverages such as Master Kong, the profits at the channel end will increase, the push of the channel will also be enhanced, and the competitiveness of new beverage brands will also be enhanced. From this perspective, price increases will not have a negative impact on sales, and may even increase sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/a058015cf1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/a058015cf1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 18, 2023, consumers were buying juice drinks in a Wumart supermarket in Beijing. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“There is room for price increases in the market, which is the most important thing”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On one side, beverage manufacturers are increasing prices; Consumers are looking to downgrade their spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Chinese Consumer Monthly Tracking Data&quot; released by the consulting company Mintel shows that for non-alcoholic beverages, the proportion of consumers with consumption upgrade plans has increased since 2021. It has been on a downward trend since April 2023 and reached a low of 21% in July 2023, ranking at the bottom among all food and beverage categories. At the same time, the proportion of consumers with downgrade plans increased from 11% in April 2021 to 18% in October 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lu Ruixun, deputy director of food and beverage research at Mintel, told Southern Weekend reporters that this shows that even if the unit price is relatively low, consumers&#39; spending on non-alcoholic beverages has changed. Consumers need to be more cautious as price increases may further influence consumers&#39; purchasing decisions for non-alcoholic beverages. The more positive news is that overall consumer demand for upgrades in non-alcoholic beverages still outweighs downgrades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Aside from all the rhetoric about rising raw material prices, Zhang Yi particularly noticed that beverages such as Master Kong, Coca-Cola, and Pepsi-Cola are significantly priced compared to trendy domestic beverages. Low. &quot;Young people can actually buy these products whose unit prices are one or two yuan higher, or even two or three yuan higher. Theoretically, there is room for price increases in the market, which is the most important thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;iiMedia data shows that soft drink consumers are mainly young people under the age of 30, and this group is generally not sensitive to price. According to its survey data, taking carbonated drinks as an example, young people’s monthly consumption expenditure on carbonated drinks between 50 yuan and 100 yuan accounts for the highest proportion, reaching 46.4%. Those priced below 50 yuan accounted for 36.5%, and those priced between 100 yuan and 300 yuan accounted for 14.5%. This shows that this group’s demand for beverages in daily consumption tends to be rigid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The data of e-commerce platforms also reflects this. Data from the consumption data platform Star Map shows that during the &quot;Double Eleven&quot; that just passed, online sales of food and beverages were 55.8 billion, accounting for 5.7%, an increase of 3.9 billion compared with 2022, an increase of 0.5 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Zhang Yi also found that consumers&#39; brand loyalty to beverages &quot;is generally not too fixed.&quot; The survey shows that consumers usually switch between two to three brands, accounting for 57.8%, and the proportion of consumers who are fixed on one brand is about 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From this perspective, affordable price tags may not be a good thing for brands. &quot;Our survey found that consumers pay more attention to the brand and the taste of drinks than health. For example, Yuanqi Forest and some other new tea products are more expensive than Master Kong, which does not hinder consumer consumption. Brand influence and Trendiness will play a very important role,&quot; Zhang Yi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被告人吴亦凡强奸、聚众淫乱案二审维持原判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261184]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 11:09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 24, 2023, the Beijing No. 3 Intermediate People’s Court appealed against Wu Yifan for rape and gathering for lewdness in accordance with the law. The verdict of the case was announced publicly, and the appeal was dismissed and the original verdict was upheld. ​​​&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/92ddba54b96d991f333ca5ccdc0819da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690 &quot; height=&quot;1739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/92ddba54b96d991f333ca5ccdc0819da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259486&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0 &quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孟庆旸：记住那一抹青绿就好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM5s1DwfYW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM 5s1DwfYW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is probably the busiest year for young dancer Meng Qingyang. On the stage of the 2023 Year of the Rabbit Spring Festival Gala, the dance poetry drama &quot;Only Green&quot; starring Meng Qingyang became popular all over the country and was well known to the public. On multiple social platforms, netizens rushed to imitate her classic dance move &quot;green waist&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Qingyang is a dancer of China Oriental Performing Arts Group and has been dancing for 11 years. She has been the leading dancer in many large-scale national events and foreign affairs events. Dancers are harder to remember than film and television actors. Large-scale dances have a large number of people, a variety of formations, and are covered by makeup and costumes, so most of the dancers&#39; faces are blurred. Now that his work has become popular, Meng Qingyang still maintains his sobriety: &quot;I think labels are not a bad thing. They can help everyone remember the role you played and the image you created. In a few years, people may forget that Meng Qingyang played Qinglu, but they can remember It&#39;s enough to have a touch of green.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the interview, Meng Qingyang performed in Huanggang, Hubei. She is tall and straight, and her dancer&#39;s temperament is fully displayed. Many people rate her as &quot;stable&quot;, which is not only reflected in her stable dancing skills, but also her outstanding personal characteristics. Although during the interview she had to re-answer the questions she had already answered due to equipment problems, she did not show any impatience or displeasure and always kept smiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2021, in the rehearsal hall of China Oriental Performing Arts Group, the main creators talked about the fact that the entire dance drama was based on the Northern Song Dynasty&#39;s masterpiece &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot; and used this as the background to create the dance drama. Prior to this, the actors all knew that directors Zhou Liya and Han Zhen were going to produce a dance drama with our company, and everyone had made full preparations. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s view, working with two directors can improve an actor&#39;s artistic career and enhance his artistic aesthetic, so no matter what drama they collaborate on, everyone is fully committed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Green&quot; is a freehand character. In the dance drama, it is the scroll-roller that connects modern times, leading the audience into the landscape of the Song Dynasty. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s eyes, she is like a connector of time and space. Meng Qingyang also experienced many physical and mental twists and turns in playing such a character that has no reference to reality and is even a bit nihilistic. When she first put on the practice skirt, because it was a very long fishtail skirt, the director said that she looked like a mermaid in a wedding dress, without the simple and quiet feeling of a painting. &quot;You have to feel like you are in this painting that lasts for nearly a thousand years, just like the scene where people in our century see the picture of mountains and rivers thousands of miles away.&quot; Through the guidance of the two directors, Meng Qingyang found the direction little by little. and grippers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To create a character, a dancer must first understand the cultural value and connotation behind it. In addition to directing, Meng Qingyang also learned a lot about the art of the Northern Song Dynasty, and went to the Palace Museum to see the working scenes of cultural workers, such as how to restore a painting bit by bit. A painting may need to be restored for several months or even longer. This spirit of devoting himself wholeheartedly to cultural and cultural undertakings made Meng Qingyang feel a certain kind of &quot;immersion and tranquility&quot;. The creative team also invited a number of intangible cultural heritage experts to explain the selection of silk and pigments in &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;. Every detail contains rich cultural significance. Only by comprehensively grasping the various aspects of that era can we shape the characters for the actors. Add a little &quot;realness&quot; to the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, Meng Qingyang felt that standing there did not look like the person in the scroll that had been sealed in the museum for thousands of years. However, after a long period of immersion and learning, it was a &quot;sudden enlightenment&quot; when she really knew how to play this role. &quot;All of a sudden, it lights up your nerves and makes you catch Qinglu.&quot; When playing the role of Qinglu seriously, Meng Qingyang found that Qinglu also had a special persistence to work hard. That persistence seemed to guide her to the studio and pick up the strokes. Like &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, she had pictures and infinite reveries in her mind. At that moment, she was green, and green was her. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Immersive encounter with characters&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Qinglu is a freehand character. What qualities did you capture to express this character? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The character Qinglu is almost always looking down. When a dancer stands on the stage, the body is the first way to output emotions, and the second is the eyes. But this character lowers his eyes, and there is a sense of alienation as the audience said, and that sense of alienation is very quiet and mysterious. It&#39;s an oriental aesthetic, so it&#39;s quite difficult to grasp this role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Remember which node you thought you found Qinglu Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of the play, the stage design had a large scroll, and I was standing in the scroll. When the music started, the scroll slowly opened, and a very cold light shone on Qinglu. At that moment, she stood there like a scroll that had been sealed for thousands of years. When she moves, the entire space-time scroll moves with it, and then our modern scroll unfolder comes out. At that moment, it is like a human emotion that has been sealed for thousands of years and can only be generated when it moves. I would imagine that my body went from pale to filled with red blood, and gradually gained warmth and human emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think Green will be the most satisfying to you? Works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;So far, I can say that it is my most satisfying work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you choose three keywords to describe yourself, Which three would you choose? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first thing I would choose is freedom, because I think I am a person full of freedom in my heart. The second one I think is determination. I started learning dance when I was 5 years old and am now 31 years old. I have been on stage for 11 years. This persistence stems from my determination for dancers and my dance career. The third one can be said to be faith, because I don’t treat dance as a job, but as a faith. In this way, when you face your dance, face the stage, and face the audience every day, you will feel very happy. status. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a dancer, he is well known to the public through Qinglu , you have now become a new face in the public eye. How do you understand this kind of accumulation and the word &quot;new&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, I am really lucky, because in fact, we dancers and actors are the same. It is very difficult to find a good role. And dancers are always waiting for good roles. After joining China Oriental Performing Arts Group as a dancer at the age of 20, you will absorb a lot of knowledge. At that time, you want to grow up quickly, gain good experience and mature appearance quickly. When you meet Qinglu at the age of 30, you suddenly slow down because of this character, and slowness is also very determined and powerful. I felt very cherished at that moment, and every day of rehearsal was an immersive encounter with her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The perfect score is not afraid of setbacks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How has dance shaped you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think my personality comes from learning dance since I was a child. Since I was 5 years old, I have had to endure physical pain, such as tearing my hips and lowering my waist, so I feel that dance has given me a character that is soft on the outside and strong on the inside. So until now, I don’t think there’s anything that would particularly break me down. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you satisfied with your current status? Can it be called a perfect life? How do you define a perfect life or a perfect state? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am quite satisfied with every situation. Except for the year when I took the college entrance examination, which was quite stressful, I am quite satisfied with the rest. . It’s not like living a perfect life, because I feel that I am only 31 years old, and I have not returned home with a full score, and I still have to keep running. I think it is a psychological state that cannot be satisfied by any material life conditions. I think it is through an experience. I have experienced many setbacks. When I can face these things calmly, it is a very perfect state. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Dance is also a way of expression. Expression is especially important now. Do you think you have been able to express yourself through dance over the years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Dancers do not express themselves through themselves, they must be separated from themselves. For example, when I go on stage at 7:00, I will definitely forget the Meng Qingyang in my life. I will definitely put down my phone and forget what takeaway I ate today, which hotel I stayed in today, where I will go to play tomorrow, everything must be forgotten. The moment you actually get on stage, you&#39;re rendering this character on a blank sheet of paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will you take photos of the performance now? Do you usually like to take pictures? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, sometimes the audience will take some photos. I don’t like taking photos. I don’t like taking selfies and checking in at places to take photos. But I will take photos to record through my perspective, not to photograph me. I think (photography) is like this. All the scenes and states you see at the moment are composed through your eyes, just like painting. Everyone may have different viewing angles and moods. I will use my eyes to compose the picture. When I go to take pictures, there is no need for professional composition or anything like that. I just record them casually. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What kind of photos do you think are worthy of the title? A good photo? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it is a photo with a sense of memory. For example, when flipping through the photo album on your mobile phone, you accidentally turn to this photo, and you will suddenly feel the mood and happiness at that time through this angle and this scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, what kind of mentality should you maintain? Can I leave at any time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t be afraid of the setbacks and difficulties you face. Many people say that setbacks and difficulties are good things. I don’t think they are good things, but I think we must first start from our own mentality and not be afraid of these things. When you really do something and it doesn&#39;t succeed, just accept its failure. I believe that my next thing will be better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[臭虫重启“全球旅行”，人类如何甩掉“吸血鬼”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261156]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 08:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;690&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023 local time, Seoul, South Korea, to prevent Bed bugs are spreading, and railway rolling stock staff in the capital are disinfecting subway facilities to prevent the epidemic. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of a bug, this is a story about restarting the journey in 2023 after being depressed for three years due to the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beginning in France in August 2023, bed bugs have caused panic in many countries in Europe and Asia. According to Yonhap News Agency&#39;s report on November 8, South Korea reported 30 suspected or confirmed bed bug infections, and the government announced the establishment of a joint bed bug response command to declare war on bed bugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bedbugs, also known as bedbugs, are the size of mung beans, have a foul odor, come out at day and night, and specialize in sucking human blood. In the 1960s, it was one of the &quot;four pests&quot; along with flies, mosquitoes, and rats. Later, it disappeared due to the advent of chemical pesticides such as DDT. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a type of wingless insect that feeds on human blood, bed bugs usually travel long distances with the help of suitcases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It identifies the host through carbon dioxide, heat signals and human body odor, follows the &quot;human smell&quot; to get into the gaps in the suitcase, and hides in dirty clothes with sweat. . By the time the suitcase is opened again, the bedbugs may have crossed continents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have never been bitten before, and I thought it was allergies. Now I am very scared, and I completely killed it at home.&quot; On November 11, Zhang Minru came from South Korea When I returned to Beijing from Seoul, I found traces of bed bug bites on my body. It was only after taking into account recent media reports that I discovered that I had been infected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 8, the Food and Environmental Hygiene Department of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Government issued an announcement stating that in order to minimize the chance of bed bugs being introduced into Hong Kong from overseas, it has worked with relevant authorities Departments and agencies have strengthened publicity and education work at different levels and will closely monitor the situation and developments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters randomly interviewed 11 patients who had suspected or confirmed bed bug bites and found that bed bugs often appear in families with a recent history of business travel. In China, it occurs most frequently in the Pearl River Delta region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Jianguo, a professor at Jiangxi Agricultural University and technical director of Nanchang Jiangnong Pest Control Co., Ltd., told Southern Weekend reporters that bedbugs did not suddenly break out, but have always existed in society. In the short term, the possibility of widespread epidemic in mainland my country is low, and whether it constitutes a &quot;crisis&quot; remains to be discussed. On November 21, Chongqing Disease Control and Prevention tweeted &quot;Don&#39;t panic if bed bugs are active again, correct treatment is key&quot;, pointing out that there have been cases of bed bug infestations in Chongqing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Generally speaking, bed bugs do not pose a threat to human safety, but they are a big problem for individuals. After being bitten, the skin is often itchy, and some people will have it. Allergic reactions affect work and life.&quot; Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bed bugs are rampant as tourism recovers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bugs cannot fly, but they can travel with humans around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Changlu, an urban pest control expert and professor of the Department of Entomology at Rutgers University in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that since the late 1990s, due to the increase in the international movement of people, prevention and control Due to insufficient investment and resistance to insecticides, bed bugs are re-emerging around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen, associate professor at the Department of Entomology, School of Plant Protection, South China Agricultural University, has long been committed to research on bed bug biology and comprehensive prevention and control. He told Southern Weekend reporters that currently bed bugs are responsible for many All types of insecticides have developed significant resistance. The increase in resistance is directly related to the insect&#39;s behavioral resistance, resistance gene mutations and body wall thickening. The thickening of the body wall will lead to a weakening of the permeability of the pesticide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), Natalie Bangay of the British Pest Control Association said that bed bugs have been a public health problem in the UK for many years. Found across the UK, having seen a decline during Covid due to a lack of global travel, any growth in bed bugs may now simply be a return to normal as people return to free movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The British &quot;Guardian&quot; reported that France&#39;s national health and hygiene agency Anses found that 11% of French households were plagued by bed bugs between 2017 and 2022. With the 2024 Paris Olympics approaching, the presence of insects suspected to be bedbugs in the Paris subway, trains, cinemas and airports has caused concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many entomology experts told Southern Weekend reporters that bed bugs most often appear in places with dense crowds, high population mobility, and untidy environments, such as dormitories. , train carriages, massage chairs at high-speed rail stations, and movie theaters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thigtaxis and phototaxis require bed bugs to settle in a dark environment where their bodies are surrounded by four sides, so bed bugs usually hibernate in small dark places. After having the opportunity to feed on the host&#39;s blood, the flat body will swell into a ball. They have a pair of stink glands on their bodies that release a foul-smelling fluid when frightened - hence the name bedbugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9f67146102.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;819&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9f67146102.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Symptoms of human body being bitten by bed bugs. Wang Desen | Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A few people with severe allergies will suffer from anaphylactic shock&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another name for bed bugs is bed bugs. After entering the home environment , they will climb up mattresses, sofas and other human resting places along the legs of furniture. If the furniture is against the wall, they will also climb onto the furniture from gaps in the wall. Although this active dispersal distance is very short - a study published in PLOS ONE (&quot;Public Library of Science: General&quot;) found that bed bugs actively dispersal distances are only a few meters to tens of meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Wei, who lives in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that when the bed bugs were at their worst, she used a flashlight to look for them bit by bit in the middle of the night. , &quot;It will appear anywhere, including in clothes, on the bed, stuffed toys, walls, toilets... Its larvae are very small, as small as a needle tip, and will occasionally crawl across your phone screen. Sometimes they are found on the bed It’s something like a fat particle.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen told Southern Weekend reporters that after being bitten and sucked by bedbugs, the human body will experience a lot of discomfort. For example, erythematous papules or blisters may appear at the bite site, and skin damage and secondary infection may occur due to scratching. In severe cases, anaphylactic shock may occur and be life-threatening. Because bed bugs hide and only appear at night, they are more difficult to catch than mosquitoes. Long-term bed bug infestation can cause symptoms such as insomnia, anxiety, neurasthenia, and mental depression. Although there have been no reports of bed bugs transmitting diseases, a large number of studies have shown that a variety of pathogens related to human diseases can be detected in bed bugs, so the bugs are still a potentially important vector of human diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A citizen who lives in Hong Kong encountered bed bugs two years ago. He described the state of being bitten like this: &quot;Every night, I was so itchy that I couldn&#39;t sleep. I was bitten by one. My mood explodes every week. The wound will be very itchy and painful when exposed to hot water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It should be pointed out that it is impossible to judge whether the bite is serious or not just from the traces of the bite. From bedbugs. Natalie Bongay also said in an interview with the BBC that the media or public&#39;s focus on bed bugs often leads to false alarms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen found during the survey that many residents easily confuse bed bugs with cockroaches, fleas, lice, ticks and mites, and some residents think bed bugs and mosquitoes , flies have the same ability to fly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Factory dormitories and group rentals are high-incidence areas&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bugs belong to the family Hemiptera, among which the temperate and tropical bed bugs are more prevalent. Bed bugs are closely related to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The largest bed bug survey in China is currently conducted by Deng Guofan of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and Feng Lanzhou of the Chinese Union Medical College. Deng and Feng collected 81 bed bugs in China between 1950 and 1951. Bedbug specimens from various regions were collected, and the research results &quot;Geographical Distribution of Temperate and Tropical Bedbugs Cimex lectularius L., Cimex hemiptera F. in China&quot; were published in 1953. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above studies show that both temperate bed bugs and tropical bed bugs are found in China. Tropical bed bugs are mainly distributed in Guangdong and Guangxi provinces, while temperate bed bugs are found in East and North China. It commonly occurs in the provinces of , northeast and northwest, and is also distributed in Xiamen, Fujian, Qujiang, Guangdong (belonging to Shaoguan City), Guilin, Guangxi, Mengzi, Yunnan, Guiyang, Guizhou and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Jianguo introduced that bed bugs prevalent around the world usually refer to temperate bed bugs. In China, temperate bed bugs are distributed in the Yangtze and Yellow River basins, but are also found in South China and are a cosmopolitan species; tropical bed bugs are distributed in South China, Taiwan and tropical areas. Wang Desen believes that with the changes in the indoor environment caused by climate warming and the use of northern heating, tropical bed bugs may also appear in temperate areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/543ded6239.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/543ded6239.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Temperate bed bug adults and tropical bed bug adults. Photo by Wang Desen |&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters searched for domestic patients bitten by bed bugs on social platforms and found that most of the patients who shared suspected or confirmed bed bug encounters on the Internet were concentrated in Zhuhai. The triangle area is consistent with some domestic research conclusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Changlu and other researchers published a study on bed bug infestation in Shenzhen in 2013 and found that bed bugs were infested among migrant workers in Dongguan and Shenzhen industrial zones. Dormitories are the worst affected, with an average positivity rate of 52.1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen conducted an investigation on the harm and prevention of bed bugs in some areas of Guangdong Province from 2017 to 2019, and found that Shenzhen, Zhuhai, Dongguan, Foshan, Guangzhou, etc. Bedbugs appear everywhere, and factory dormitories and group rental housing with densely populated people, high mobility, and poor sanitary conditions are high-incidence areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We visited factory dormitories and found that many factories are infested with bed bugs. The movement of employees back and forth between different factory areas can easily cause the spread of bed bugs.&quot; Wang Desen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Avoid prevention and control misunderstandings and recommend non-chemical methods&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although bed bugs are unlikely to pose a &quot;crisis&quot; that threatens human health at this stage, patients &quot; The experience of being bitten with hundreds of red bumps all over the body proves that it still has the power to make people suffer, and it is necessary to take scientific prevention and treatment measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bug prevention and control includes physical control, chemical control, comprehensive control and other means. For ordinary households, it is recommended to use a comprehensive prevention and control method that focuses on physical control and supplements chemical control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Physical control refers to the use of heat treatment, inorganic powders, bed bug interception devices, etc. to prevent and control bed bugs. Since bed bugs are very sensitive to high temperatures, residents can treat bed bug-infested furniture and items by frequently washing and drying bedding and clothing with hot water, and using a hot steam machine (such as a garment steamer). After heat treatment, when the air humidity is reduced, spraying inorganic powder represented by diatomaceous earth in the corners of walls, seams of bed frames, under mattresses and other areas where bed bugs often move can also effectively kill bed bugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bed bug hiding spots. Photo by Wang Desen |&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It should be pointed out that a common misunderstanding in preventing bed bugs is to expose the furniture where bed bugs are found to the sun. Since the temperature of sun exposure cannot instantly reach the lethal temperature of bed bugs (50°C), it may cause bed bugs to spread to other uninfested places, especially in apartments or residential buildings with many rooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Generally, it is not recommended to use chemical agents, because the common pyrethroid insecticides on the market are toxic and should not be used by families with pets and children. It is not recommended to use it. If you need to use it, you should strictly follow the recommended dosage of the drug, and do not use it on sofas, beds and other places that are in direct contact with the human body.&quot; Wang Changlu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For people who frequently travel for business and tourism, Wang Desen recommends always keeping mosquito repellent water sprayed on the suitcase, and promptly checking and cleaning the suitcase and the clothes inside it after returning home to avoid Bringing bed bugs into your home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In densely populated communities, once a bed bug outbreak occurs, all residences in the entire community are at risk of being infested. Therefore, community-wide treatment should be considered during bed bug control. Wang Desen pointed out that after removing bed bugs, it is also necessary to establish a long-term awareness of prevention. You can regularly check the corners of the bed, wall gaps, etc. through visual inspection to determine whether there are traces of bed bug activity, molting or feces; in addition, you can also use traps placed under the bed for long-term monitoring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For crowded places such as hotels, schools, unit dormitories, etc., Wang Jianguo suggested asking PCO (Pest Control) companies to conduct professional monitoring and thorough disinfecting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It is difficult to completely &#39;eliminate&#39; a pest. We can only reduce its population as much as possible on a local scale and prevent it from spreading. Cause great harm. After getting rid of the &quot;four pests&quot; for so long, humans are still fighting against them. But as long as people increase their awareness of bed bug prevention and control, they can avoid large-scale outbreaks of bed bugs. Bed bugs are no longer very common nowadays. It may become a serious pest like cockroaches, flies and mosquitoes,&quot; Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Zhang Minru and Zhang Wei are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陆仙人：从乡村地头走到巴黎时装周]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261166]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/pUiN7Fe8pusqH3OomDLXfM6s07kkkw4jYjgJrc6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/pUiN7Fe8pusqH3OomDLXfM6s07kkkw4 jYjgJrc6h. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Lu Xianren appeared for the first time on the Paris Fashion Week show. He was invited to walk the show, wearing a black silhouette suit, white trousers and a neat hairstyle. He was one of the few non-scientific models present, and his starting point on the catwalk was on a rural road in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Lu Xianren, who was working in Guangdong, quit his job and returned to his hometown in Guangxi to shoot short videos full-time. He always wanted to be a model, so most of the photos he took were of him walking in shows. The clothing is all homemade, made from woven bags, blankets, waterproof plastic sheets, old lampshades, branches, leaves... match the upper body and walk in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He worked hard for more than a month, but the account was not as popular as he imagined. It was already summer, and the sultry weather also affected his mood: Was he unable to achieve results no matter what? It&#39;s better to be more casual and show yourself. So in the high temperature, he put on the red blanket at home as clothes and walked barefoot for a while. This random move immediately brought about a heat stroke and high fever, but it also brought a huge number of likes. Lu Xianren woke up from his sleep and saw the number of likes on the video rising, and even doubted the authenticity of the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, this video became popular on the platform, with more than 2 million likes. He&#39;s on fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The short video era gives everyone the opportunity to experience the &quot;15 minutes of fame&quot;. It has become easy for ordinary people to produce a popular video. In the ocean of traffic, there will always be a point where you can Hit a group of people. However, it is not easy to make this flow sustainable. But Lu Xianren did not hesitate. When he decided to shoot short videos full-time, he had already conceived many ideas. So if it wasn’t because of the red blanket that it became popular, would it also be because of other creative ideas? Lu Xianren laughed at this: &quot;Not necessarily.&quot; He still showed a cautious attitude towards his fame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xianren, whose real name is Lu Kaigang, was born in Heng County, Guangxi in 1999. His parents worked outside all year round, and he was raised by his grandparents. When he was in fifth grade, he saw a modeling competition on TV and was attracted by the models&#39; aura and outfits. It became his dream to walk on the catwalk. From then on, when he got home from school, he would take time to practice Tai step. He was originally a little hunched, but after practicing he opened his shoulders and held his head high. When practicing, hold a book on your head. &quot;The book cannot go away, so the steps are formed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After three months, the book is firmly on the head. &quot;But what I learned more is their confidence on the stage and the way they want to express themselves on the stage.&quot; Today&#39;s Lu Xianren said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dropping out of middle school, Lu Kaigang went to Guangdong to work. He worked as an apprentice in a barber shop and a restaurant, and then worked in a factory. He used his spare time to continue his modeling studies. He recorded videos and compared them with professional models&#39; pace, down to the time to keep his head and the number of seconds to pause when positioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, he started shooting his own videos. When choosing the nickname for his account, he thought of his home in the mountains. Every day when he got up, he could see the mist outside the window. It was &quot;very fairy&quot;, so he named himself &quot;Lu Xianren&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year later, he decided to quit his job and return to his hometown to shoot short videos full-time. &quot;Give yourself half a year, and if it doesn&#39;t work, go back and work honestly.&quot; Hence the subsequent story. After that, his creative juices flowed and his modeling career got on the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xianren is 180 centimeters tall and wears women&#39;s clothing in most of the videos. This time it was not understood. Some relatives saw the video and ran to ask Lu Xianren&#39;s family: &quot;Why is your child like this?&quot; Grandma said: Young people have their own ideas, and they must have their own reasons for what they do, so just leave them alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwNsWIxZetPBREzLyXo9UMpLziZ4l8bAyimNpdE0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwNsWIxZetPBREzLyXo9UMpLziZ4l8bAyimNpdE0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo taken by Honor 100 series)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My current life is not It counts as a full score, but try to go in the direction of full score&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 3 In March, you participated in the Paris Fashion Week catwalk for the first time. You are a new face in the international fashion world. What new characteristics do you think you have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The fashion industry has never lacked new faces. On the international stage, I have been recognized by more people, and the global fashion media have discovered me. A new face, discovering maybe a new strength. Mainly, I (this type) are relatively rare in the fashion industry, and I personally feel more special. And &quot;new&quot; represents a new force, the ability to move forward, and an opportunity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;catwalk on the international stage and in the countryside What&#39;s the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I personally think it is a change in mentality. At the beginning, when I walked the show on rural trails and country roads, I was just enjoying the scenery, which I thought was beautiful. After going to Paris Fashion Week, I felt a little nervous for the first time. I slowly adapted and enjoyed it. I slowly began to interact with the audience and resonate with the designers. I seemed to have a passion for their clothes and their love. Perception, there is a spiritual connection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The show left in your mind What is the first screen? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the final curtain call, the audience waved to the designer and then applauded. I have walked in so many shows, some of which were applauded by the audience, and some of which the audience left immediately after the show. In that show, most of them stood up and applauded. They must have found something they like and resonated with. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The way you appear in the camera is very professional , what kind of training have you received for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;While visiting the scene, I observed some photography teachers. In what state did they take photos? I think taking pictures has something to do with the state. I don’t like to pose in a pose for taking pictures, or to set up a big scene for taking pictures. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I personally take photos more casually. When I encounter good scenery or beautiful things, I will take pictures and record them. I bought a smartphone in 2016. At that time, I was still taking pictures of landscapes, but I didn’t dare to take pictures of myself, and I wasn’t very confident yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think a good photo should look like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first thing is to attract attention, and then have a sense of story and impact. I may not pay much attention to a certain detail in the whole photo, but I will pay attention to the general appearance. A photo cannot be 100% perfect, 98% or 95% perfect, and this photo may be remembered for a long time. I don’t really like to make perfect photos. When I photoshop, I will keep my flaws and spots. I am still satisfied with myself and pay more attention to the quality of the photos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any suggestions for everyone to take photos? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If you are not particularly confident, then you don’t have to look at the camera all the time. The camera is not that important. Taking photos is to record what is happening at the moment. When you are not looking at the camera, you can fully show your relaxed state. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My confidence comes from my love for the lens, plus I like taking pictures - the feeling of the camera clicking out. The moment the camera presses the shutter button, it records the present moment. I think it is a very magical thing. Nowadays, everyone can take a camera and take pictures at any time. When I take pictures, I don’t necessarily mean what kind of pictures I will take. When I take pictures, I record what I want to do at the moment. When you look at it later, you will know that you were quite happy at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How would you rate your current life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the ideal full-scoring life is half life and half the work. But I think it doesn’t have to be perfect to have a perfect life, it depends on the pace of life. For example, I may have been very busy some time ago. After finishing my work, I went home to take a rest, spend time with my grandma, and look for new inspiration. Life and work need to coordinate with each other. My current life is not perfect, but I will try my best to move towards it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从入园难到关停潮，高速增长15年的幼儿园数量迎来拐点丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261170]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>