<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[林旭东谈中国纪录片三十年：不只说发生了什么，还要讲到为什么]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259084]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022480207789&quot; data-media=&quot; audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Lin Xudong talks about thirty years of Chinese documentaries: not only what happened, but also why.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud .com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/06970e325576678022480207789/wTaELxEhscgA.mp3&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251 434507/06970e325576678022480207789/wTaELxEhscgA.mp3&quot;>;Lin Xudong talks about Chinese documentaries three Ten Years: Not Just What Happened, But Why.mp3&lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click Play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single episode introduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to BitCulture. I am the anchor of this episode, Yilan. In this episode of the podcast, we will talk about documentaries. topic. Today we invite Professor Lin Xudong, the great master behind Chinese documentaries, to talk to us about the development history of Chinese documentaries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Teacher Lin Xudong is a painter. He twice planned the symposium of world documentary masters held in Beijing in the late 1990s, and was directly involved in the planning, production and criticism of many folk documentaries. . It can be said that Teacher Lin is the living history, experiencer and witness of Chinese documentaries since the 1990s. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/xfO55HO1lh6JyC3e6XjTdTd1ozUgHvgYjCo0igWH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/xfO55HO1lh6JyC3e6XjTdTd1ozUgHvgYjCo0igWH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254827&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Starting from 1990, China’s independence year&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[他见证了英格兰足球最跌宕的历史丨博比·查尔顿去世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259082]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/22/J2BQzh86HBeKMLNZVPGwCCPeFiZDNCEHpLQ5uNlo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/J2BQzh86HBeKMLNZVPGwCCPeFiZDNCEHpLQ5u Nlo. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Official media social account of Manchester United&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, local time, the Premier League Manchester United club issued an obituary on social media. British football star and Manchester United legendary star Sir Bobby Charlton passed away at the age of 86. He was the last player to survive the Munich air disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bobby Charlton, who was born in 1937 and officially retired in 1976, has a career full of honors. He played 758 games for Manchester United, scored 249 goals, and won several English top league championship trophies. He was also the core player of the England team that won the 1966 World Cup. He is both offensive and defensive, his playing style is tough but not rough, and he is known as a &quot;football gentleman&quot;. He is also one of the very few players in the history of football to have won the World Cup trophy, the Champions League trophy and the Ballon d&#39;Or at the same time, collecting the highest honors at the national team, club and individual levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 145-year history of Manchester United, many stars have emerged, but when it comes to the number one legend in history, the vast majority of fans will vote for Bobby Charlton. He is also regarded as the &quot;Chosen One&quot;. As a survivor of the &quot;Munich Air Crash&quot; of Manchester United, he not only defeated fate and himself, but also became the most critical figure in Manchester United&#39;s emergence from the haze. This is not just luck, but also a testament to hard work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The talented young man from a football family faces the obstacle of a plane crash in his life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bobby Charlton was born on October 11, 1937 in Northumber, England. Lan County, his family can be called a football family: his father and uncle are both well-known local players, and his brother Jack Charlton later became a star of Leeds United and the main central defender of the England team in the 1966 World Cup. Bobby Charlton entered the Manchester United youth team when he was 12 years old. He officially turned professional in 1954 and won three consecutive English FA Youth Cup championships with the Manchester United youth team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1956, Bobby Charlton made his first-team debut for Manchester United. In this game against Charlton, he scored two goals, establishing himself in the first team at the speed of light, and won the league championship with the team in the 1956-1957 season. But what followed was the Munich air disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;February 6, 1958 was the darkest moment in the history of Manchester United. At that time, Manchester United played away against the Yugoslavian powerhouse Red Star Belgrade in the second leg of the European Champions Cup quarter-finals. The two sides drew 3-3. Manchester United advanced with a total score of 5-4 over the two rounds. After the game, Manchester United players, some fans and reporters with the team planned to take a flight back to the UK. However, the plane at the time could not support the direct flight from Belgrade to England, and they had to stop in Munich for refueling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/UMm4zpLGNVn3UBqxNVyDhZrjABZeOx6dlzbTk39u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;632&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/UMm4zpLGNVn3UBqxNVyDhZrjABZeOx6dlzbTk39u.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 30, 1966, London, England, England defeated the Federal Republic of Germany 4-2 in the World Cup final. Bobby Charlton celebrated by holding the Jules Rimet Cup high&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the rested aircraft failed to take off twice due to engine problems at Munich Airport. On the third During the first takeoff, the plane lost control due to snow accumulation, crashed through a fence and crashed into a building, then broke into two pieces. One side of the fuselage collided with a truck filled with fuel and exploded. 23 of the 44 people on board died, including 21-year-old talented star Duncan Edwards, team captain Roger Byrne and many other players. In addition, there are two players who have completely bid farewell to the court due to injuries. Bobby Charlton was injured but luckily escaped death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plane crash changed Manchester United&#39;s development trajectory. Since being coached by Matt Busby in 1945, Manchester United has prospered and many young players have stood out, including the talented youngster Duncan Edwards who later unfortunately passed away in a plane crash. The team quickly grew into a strong team in English football, first winning the league runner-up four times in five years, and then winning the league championship three times between 1952 and 1957. In the 1957-1958 season, Manchester United was regarded as the favorite for the Champions League, but the Munich air disaster brought everything to an abrupt end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the remaining days of that season, Manchester United, which was once involved in rumors of disintegration, did not miss a single game and relied on a group of young players who were temporarily promoted to play the entire season and win people&#39;s respect. Bobby Charlton also returned to the court as quickly as possible. He has experienced as much pain and hardship as anyone else. In addition to the physical pain, there is also tremendous mental pain. Fortunately, the then Manchester United star finally got over this hurdle and became a key figure in Manchester United&#39;s revival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/pPmFBwTZyrAvHQY9yqBG1ZT16Humc1ZLjlixOV2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;954&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/pPmFBwTZyrAvHQY9yqBG1ZT16Humc1ZLjlixOV2C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 25, 1963, Manchester United won the FA Cup. Bobby Charlton (second from right) celebrated with his teammates&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The core of Manchester United’s revival after the Munich air disaster&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nearly a year after the Munich air disaster, Matt Busby came back and began to rebuild the team. The core of his team building was Bobby Charlton. In the next few years, George Best and Dennis Law, who were promoted from the youth team, also became the team&#39;s return. The backbone of the peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following season, Manchester United finished second in the league. But it was not until 1963 that it won its first championship after the plane crash - the FA Cup. Among the players on the final field, only Fulks and Bobby Charlton had experienced a plane crash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Manchester United has officially ushered in a renaissance. In the mid-1960s, it won two league championships in three years, and defeated Portugal&#39;s Benfica in the 1967-1968 European Champions Cup final, winning the UEFA Champions League for the first time in history. To win the Champions League trophy, Bobby Charlton scored two goals in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a reincarnation game. Bobby Charlton and his new teammates used the championship trophy to comfort those who passed away. Ten years ago, Manchester United was not far away from this championship trophy, but the air crash shattered their dreams and even lives. At this moment, Bobby Charlton completed his own redemption and the last wishes of his deceased teammates. Both he and Busby cut their middle fingers, soaked the trophy with blood, and lifted it again and again, chanting the name of a deceased teammate each time. This was the most touching scene in the history of the Champions League. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/Ar0dX4OJgRwncPkSgiMFTEP1Xyw9cgXyhkMiIdqC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;730&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/Ar0dX4OJgRwncPkSgiMFTEP1Xyw9cgXyhkMiIdqC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 11, 1958, Munich air crash survivors Bobby Charlton (left) and Ramon Wood received treatment in hospital&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Bobby Charlton has gradually embarked on a downward slope of his career because he was over 30 years old, and Manchester United has gradually lost its competitiveness. But he is still the absolute main force on Manchester United&#39;s field, with eye-catching performances from time to time. After the 1972-1973 season, Bobby Charlton chose to leave. From 1956 to 1973, Bobby Charlton devoted all his youth and passion to Manchester United. He played 758 games for the team and scored 249 goals, maintaining these two team historical records for a long time. It was not until 2008 that his number of appearances was broken by another loyal legend, Ryan Giggs, and his scoring record was not broken until 2017 by Rooney. He brought three league titles, an FA Cup and a Champions League trophy to Manchester United. More importantly, he was loyal and tenacious, leading Manchester United to rise from the ashes after the plane crash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving Manchester United, Bobby Charlton also briefly played for low-level Preston and Ireland&#39;s Watford United before officially retiring in 1976. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The backbone of the 1966 World Cup winning team&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the Munich air disaster, Bobby Charlton used his best Quickly returned to the club&#39;s battlefield. On April 19 of that year, he was selected for the national team. This was the first time he was selected and made his debut. However, in the 1958 World Cup, Bobby Charlton always sat on the bench and did not have a chance to play for a minute. Although public opinion expressed dissatisfaction with the head coach&#39;s continued abandonment of Bobby Charlton, head coach Walter Winterbottom admitted to the newspaper that he regretted choosing Bobby Charlton to enter the final World Cup squad because he believed that the other side was still Painfully tortured by the Munich air disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1962 World Cup, Bobby Charlton was once again selected for the England team and played as the main player, but the team was eliminated by the eventual champion Brazil in the rematch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/rDrwEdcI8gJuqZkXCE2G70ILXFdzRVqtjybVszFg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;629&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/rDrwEdcI8gJuqZkXCE2G70ILXFdzRVqtjybVszFg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254835&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 19, 1958, Bobby Charlton was recovering from training near home&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 1966 World Cup held in England became the best stage of Bobby Charlton&#39;s national team career. At this time, he was at the peak of his career and was the core of that England team. The team defeated the favorites Portugal in the semi-finals, with Bobby Charlton scoring twice in the game. In the subsequent final, the England team performed the most classic performance in history. Bobby Charlton, as the midfield organizer, helped the team defeat the powerful West Germany 4-2 and win the championship. At this time, Bobby Charlton was already a well-deserved core player. Although his light was overshadowed by Hurst who scored a hat-trick, anyone who knows football knows how critical he is to the team&#39;s offensive and defensive transition. He was named the best player of the World Cup for his outstanding performance. In addition, he also defeated Portuguese superstar &quot;Black Panther&quot; Eusebio in the Golden Globe Award that year, becoming the second English player to win the Golden Globe Award after Matthews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 1970 World Cup was Bobby Charlton&#39;s fourth World Cup appearance. Although the team failed to enter the semi-finals, Charlton was still selected for the best team of the World Cup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in the 1968 European Championship (ie European Cup), Bobby Charlton led his team to third place, which was also the best record in the history of the European Championship for England. In May of the same year, he scored the 45th goal of his national team career in a warm-up match against Sweden, surpassing Griffiths to become the top scorer in the history of the England national team. On April 21, 1970, Charlton made his 100th appearance on behalf of the England team. From 1958 to 1970, Bobby Charlton played a total of 106 times in his national team career and scored 49 goals. The number of goals scored was second only to Rooney later. With the blessing of the World Cup championship, he is the best player in the history of the England national team. There is no doubt about the best player. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/oCjl7vzyXzMkusmysQy7yhFMeHloRWJ78O2ghLa9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;642&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/oCjl7vzyXzMkusmysQy7yhFMeHloRWJ78O2ghLa9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254836&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 8, 1994, Manchester United won the Premier League championship. Bobby Charlton and head coach Ferguson took a group photo in the dressing room&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A true football gentleman&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Once discovered Chinese players&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;In 1984, Bobby Charlton returned to Manchester United and became the team&#39;s director. He is also the team&#39;s best business card. In 1994, he was knighted by the Queen of England. In 2012, he won the Laureus Sports Lifetime Achievement Award, becoming the fifth football player to win this honor. So far, a total of 6 football practitioners have won the award, and the other 5 are Pele, Cruyff, and Bayern. Ken Ball, Zidane and Wenger. In 2016, the South Stand of Old Trafford, Manchester United&#39;s home stadium, was named the Charlton Stand. He ranked 12th among the greatest players of the 20th century selected by World Football magazine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bobby Charlton has been committed to the global exchange of football. In 1988, the Chinese national junior team visited the UK and played against youth teams from many clubs. Bobby Charlton fell in love with Su Maozhen and Wu Chongwen of the Chinese national junior team at a glance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Chongwen has extremely fast speed and ghostly running position, while Su Maozhen has a model center body and confrontation ability, so Bobby Charlton invited the two to go to Manchester United for a trial training. . It is a pity that both of them suffered injuries during the trial training, and due to the institutional reasons of Chinese football at the time, they were unable to stay at Manchester United. After returning to China, Wu Chongwen soon disappeared from everyone, while Su Maozhen grew into a backbone of Chinese football and the &quot;number one golden head&quot; of men&#39;s football in the eyes of old fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with the media, Su Maozhen revealed that after retiring, he wrote letters and phone calls to Bobby Charlton, saying that he wanted to study in the UK. Sir Charlton and Manchester United were very welcoming and helped him pay the fees. Arrangements were made to enroll in the England C-level coaching course, which provided him with a lot of help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;835&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 21, 2023, in the 9th round of the Premier League, Sheffield United lost 1 to 2 to Manchester United. Manchester United players mourned Bobby Charlton before the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of personal conduct, both players Bobby Charlton was perfect both in his era and after his retirement, and was even jokingly called &quot;perfect to the point of being boring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a player, Bobby Charlton does not look like a typical English player. He is a bit thin, but in fact he has great energy and is never afraid of confrontation. His tough confrontation ability allows his delicate skills to be better utilized. He is not only diligent, agile, but also selfless, making him the perfect template for a midfielder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;835&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 21, 2023, in the 9th round of the Premier League, Sheffield United lost 1 to 2 to Manchester United. Manchester United players mourned Bobby Charlton before the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most valuable thing is that in this perfect Behind it, there is a huge pain that cannot be let go. Bobby Charlton once said frankly in an interview: &quot;My life was actually forever fixed on the day of the Munich air disaster, and I never came out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Never came out&quot; He chose not to wallow in pain, but to persevere. He always looks friendly and calm on the outside, treats everyone kindly, and is a true gentleman. He then heals his broken heart without speaking to others. During this period, the people who survived the plane crash with him left one after another, and he became increasingly silent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until now, he has passed away and can no longer appear in the stands of Old Trafford. Manchester United, the Red Devils, has lost its greatest audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国奶茶圈最早的幕后大佬，还得是平南老表]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257208]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A small county with a permanent population of only 1.11 million actually has 265,000 people are making milk tea. If you are a local, at least you will have a relative or friend who is in the milk tea business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This place is Pingnan County, Guigang City, Guangxi. On average, 1 in 5 people here sells milk tea. In Pingnan Normal Street, you can even make milk tea. There is a milk tea shop ten meters away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since Pingnan people opened the first milk tea shop in Guangzhou in 1999, the &quot;Guangxi Gang&quot; in the milk tea industry has continued to rise. The &quot;Guangxi Gang&quot; first learned experience and opened up the market in Guangzhou and Foshan, then continued to strengthen its own strength in Pingnan, and finally spread to all parts of the country. In 2006, Pingnan people opened more than 50,000 new milk tea shops across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pingnan milk tea has also become the carrier of youth for countless netizens. Some netizens who have moved overseas still remember drinking a cup of &quot;Subway&quot; mint milk tea every day in high school. Some netizens are obsessed with the taste of &quot;Dakoujiu&quot; pearl milk tea because it contains memories with their grandmother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, in today&#39;s Pingnan streets, &quot;Subway&quot; and &quot;Dakoujiu&quot; have given way to chain brands such as Heytea and Mixue Bingcheng. The latest rising local brands in Pingnan have also embarked on a long road of imitation. On the brand list of the Pingnan Milk Tea Association, some brands have Heytea logos with afros, while others simply flip the Heytea logo from left to right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the tide of milk tea involution, Pingnan Milk Tea seems to be lost. In 2021, the Pingnan milk tea brand accounted for 22% of the market share, which is a quarter of its peak. Most of the best-selling milk tea brands in Pingnan County on takeout platforms are well-known chain brands across the country. However, the milk tea brands launched by Pingnan County such as &quot;Relixue&quot; and &quot;Qinkou Lemon&quot; only have monthly sales of more than 1,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to return to the top, Pingnan County has launched the &quot;No. 1 Milk Tea County&quot; sign, but not many people buy it. Pingnan County lacks the establishment of milk tea Standard right to speak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although the local milk tea brand in Pingnan has lost its glory, the power of the &quot;Guangxi Gang&quot; is still strong. Grandma&#39;s handmade products, which specialize in &quot;hand-made healthy drinks, cooked on-site using ancient methods&quot;, have been snapped up by the &quot;middle class&quot;. They have also opened a branch in Beijing. The &quot;authentic Taiwanese taste&quot; Tea Dafu from Guangxi now has more than 1,000 customers. Home store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;know&quot; will talk to you about the milk tea business experience of an old man from Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/85b007579b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/85b007579b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/2a753ca2a5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/2a753ca2a5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251301&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e9357efbca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e9357efbca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251302&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/604971ed08.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/604971ed08.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251303&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/b347cc21c0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/b347cc21c0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251304&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/4afcbd0e5f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 20/4afcbd0e5f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当00后涌入老年大学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259069]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjB k6gukrSbaP. png&quot; data-key=&quot;234648&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022203307773&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data -filename=&quot;When the post-00s flocked to the elderly university.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/a4d363e55576678022203307773/KK9Gee1SEBYA.mp3&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src =&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/a4d363e55576678022203307773/KK9Gee1SEBYA.mp3&quot;>;When the post-00s crowd into older universities.mp3&lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center ;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/22/dflDHrQKN93mbx4zvCNoAyYC7vI3m8tbxVSOhmVa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /22/dflDHrQKN93mbx4zvCNoAyYC7vI3m8tbxVSOhmVa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254824&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiaoyu and her students. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, meeting people from the south and north, Southern Weekend&#39;s Hello, listeners, welcome to the Southern Weekly podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although retirement is still far away for those born in the 1990s and 2000s, many young people have already gone to senior universities to experience it in advance: with a few hundred yuan in tuition, they can learn dance, piano, calligraphy, etc. for half a year. , Chinese painting courses are all available, but the biggest difference with the school&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“首个国家标准”发布，事关养老]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259057]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Social Welfare Center of the Ministry of Civil Affairs recently released the recommended national standards for the implementation of the &quot;Basic Specifications for Home Care Home Care Services&quot;. This is my country has released its first national standard for home care services. At a press conference held by the Ministry of Civil Affairs yesterday (20th), the head of the relevant department introduced the status of this national standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/21/2c60a421c8c98a9bd56f3a67ef70b4b1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height= &quot;439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/21/2c60a421c8c98a9bd56f3a67ef70b4b1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254810&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Main content of the standard It is divided into 5 parts: &quot;Terms and Definitions&quot;, &quot;General Requirements&quot;, &quot;Service Content&quot;, &quot;Service Process and Requirements&quot;, &quot;Service Evaluation and Improvement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the &quot;overall requirements&quot; clarify the basic conditions that service organizations and service personnel should have and the basic requirements that services should meet; &quot;service content&quot; includes life care, basic care, health management, and visiting care. , spiritual comfort, entrustment agency, and aging-friendly modification of family living environment, etc., covering the main professional service content required for home care; the &quot;service process&quot; clarifies from consultation and reception, assessment of the elderly&#39;s ability, signing of service agreement, A series of procedural requirements from service preparation to service implementation; &quot;Service Evaluation and Improvement&quot; clarifies the service evaluation form and the requirements for improvement feedback on problems found in the evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/21/0f8230a7d69f31ac327b860f08c43a42.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;888&quot; height= &quot;438&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/21/0f8230a7d69f31ac327b860f08c43a42.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254811&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ministry of Civil Affairs Social Zhen Bingliang, Director of the Welfare Center: The &quot;Basic Specifications for Home Care Home Care Service&quot; will provide basic guidance on the content, service organization conditions and related process requirements of home care home care services. It is of practical significance for promoting the standardization, standardization and professional development of home care services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“回馈投资者，而非不断问市场要钱”  证监会引导上市公司分红]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259086]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/22/vqP0HxRLRJsAeYYpFoFu9SZTN20suo1Vsm0ET1zM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/vqP0HxRLRJsAeYYpFoFu9SZTN20suo1 Vsm0ET1zM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254838&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;An A-share index screen in Shanghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission (hereinafter referred to as the China Securities Regulatory Commission) issued a document stating that, In order to guide listed companies to further increase the level of dividends, increase the frequency of dividends, and standardize dividend behavior, it is planned to revise the &quot;Regulatory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 3 - Cash Dividends by Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Cash Dividend Guidelines&quot;) and the &quot;Guidelines for the Articles of Association of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Articles of Association Guidelines&quot;) relevant provisions of cash dividends are revised and opinions are publicly solicited from the public. The deadline for feedback is November 19, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the &quot;Cash Dividend Guidelines&quot; have mainly revised three aspects: first, to further clarify the direction of cash dividends, second to simplify the mid-term dividend procedures, and thirdly to strengthen the constraints on companies that exceed their ability to pay dividends. The &quot;Articles of Association Guidelines&quot; have revised the contents of Articles 153, 155 and 156 related to cash dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later on the same day, in accordance with the unified deployment of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges revised the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board and Science and Technology Innovation Board, and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange Main Board and GEM Standardized Operation Guidelines for Cash Dividends. Public opinion solicitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This revision is a further implementation of the China Securities Regulatory Commission’s active capital market policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission explained that the main idea of ​​this revision of cash dividend rules is to encourage companies to formulate clear dividend policies in their articles of association on the basis of adhering to corporate autonomy, stabilize investors’ dividend expectations, and ensure that non-dividends and financial Companies with large investment scales but low dividend distribution ratios should be urged to pay dividends by strengthening disclosure requirements; facilitate the company&#39;s mid-term dividend implementation procedures and encourage companies to increase the frequency of cash dividends; strengthen constraints on companies with abnormally high dividend distribution ratios and guide reasonable dividend distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 27, the China Securities Regulatory Commission also regulated the behavior of shareholding reductions and introduced a &quot;linking&quot; policy between dividends and shareholding reductions, stipulating that listed companies have broken shares or net losses, or have not distributed cash dividends in the past three years. . If the accumulated cash dividend amount is less than 30% of the average annual net profit in the past three years, the controlling shareholder or actual controller shall not reduce its shareholdings through the secondary market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The annual dividend amount exceeds the amount of equity financing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In recent years, driven by policy guidance and supervision, the dividend situation of A-share listed companies has continued to improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission stated that in the past five years, A-share listed companies have paid a cumulative dividend of 8.2 trillion yuan, and the annual dividend amount has begun to exceed the amount of equity financing that year. Among them, a total of 3,291 Shanghai and Shenzhen listed companies paid cash dividends in 2022, with a dividend amount of 2.1 trillion yuan, of which 1.6 trillion yuan was distributed to domestic investors, a year-on-year increase of 22.7%, and the number of dividend companies accounted for 67.1%. The dividend payout rate (32.5%) and dividend rate (1.97%) are in the middle and upper reaches compared with major global capital markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Delong, chief economist of Qianhai Kaiyuan, also told Southern Weekend reporters that the cash dividend performance of A-share listed companies has improved significantly compared with ten years ago, and listed companies also hope to enhance investor confidence through cash dividends. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this revision, the &quot;Cash Dividend Guidelines&quot; have detailed regulations and explanations for companies that &quot;evade&quot; dividends and &quot;excessive&quot; dividends. The dividend distribution procedures have also been optimized. The revisions mainly include three aspects: &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it is necessary to further clarify the direction of cash dividends and promote an increase in the level of dividends. The first is to strengthen institutional constraints on companies that do not pay dividends and urge them to pay dividends. For companies that have not distributed cash dividends, disclosure requirements will be strengthened. In addition to disclosing specific reasons, they must also disclose the next steps to be taken to enhance investor returns; second, focus on companies with large financial investments but low dividend levels. Pay attention and urge to increase the level of dividends and focus on the main business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, we should simplify the mid-term dividend distribution process and promote further optimization of the dividend method and rhythm. Encourage companies to increase the frequency of dividends when conditions permit, so that investors can share company growth dividends earlier. Combined with regulatory practice, listed companies are allowed to review and approve the conditions and upper limit for the next year&#39;s interim cash dividend within a certain amount when convening the annual shareholders&#39; meeting to review the annual profit distribution plan. Subsequently, the board of directors will formulate a specific interim dividend plan to facilitate the company&#39;s further improvement. The frequency of dividend payments allows investors to better plan capital arrangements and share corporate growth dividends earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We must once again strengthen the constraints on companies that pay dividends beyond their capabilities and guide reasonable dividend distribution. First, it is emphasized that when listed companies formulate cash dividend policies, they should comprehensively consider their own profitability, capital expenditure arrangements and debt repayment capabilities, as well as investor returns and company development needs; second, it is emphasized that supervision should be carried out on companies with high asset-liability ratios and cash from operating activities. Companies with poor flow and large proportions of cash dividends should pay close attention to prevent adverse effects on the company&#39;s production, operations and debt solvency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This revision also combines the reform of the independent director system and deletes the relevant requirements for independent directors to express opinions in the &quot;Cash Dividend Guidelines&quot;. At the same time, the adaptability regulations have been modified in conjunction with the registration system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Although cash dividends do not directly increase shareholders’ equity, they are of particular significance to the entire A-share market.” Yang Delong explained that cash dividends on the one hand show that the company has profitability and that there is real money in the account; This aspect shows that the company has sincerity and social responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Delong previously wrote that in the A-share market, some listed companies are profitable but do not pay dividends for a long time, which harms the interests of small and medium investors. The China Securities Regulatory Commission has adopted specific regulations to encourage listed companies to pay cash dividends and strengthen inquiries on companies that have not paid cash dividends for a long time. This will help boost investors’ confidence in listed companies. It also urges the management of listed companies to make the company bigger and stronger, and encourages Major shareholders bind the interests of small and medium-sized investors through cash dividends to promote the establishment of a good ecosystem in the A-share market and the overall improvement of the quality of listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is still room for improvement&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When issuing the revised instructions, the China Securities Regulatory Commission also emphasized that “compared with mature overseas markets, the balance, timeliness, and Stability needs to be further improved, investors&#39; sense of gain needs to be enhanced, and some companies pay abnormally high proportions of dividends, which may damage debt solvency and continued operating capabilities, requiring timely guidance and regulation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changjiang Securities is also in the process. A 2023 research report stated that A-share dividend strategies have performed better in recent years, but from a global perspective, there are still differences with overseas mature markets in terms of dividend levels, high dividend yield sectors, and the stability of dividend strategies. The difference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of willingness to pay dividends, the total amount of dividends paid in the A-share market has maintained a high growth rate, and the proportion of dividend-paying listed companies has increased year by year. It has a strong dividend investment foundation, but the sustainability and growth of dividends are still inconsistent with There is a certain gap in developed markets such as the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of dividend payout ratio and dividend rate, the Hong Kong market in China is the highest as a whole, and the willingness to pay dividends and dividend rate levels of A-share listed companies are generally in the middle, while the U.S. market is relatively the lowest, with the dividend payout ratio of A-shares in 2022 being about 32.5 %, and the dividend yield is about 1.9%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of dividends, A-share dividends are mainly concentrated on the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board, and central and state-owned enterprises pay greater dividends. Dividends in Hong Kong stocks mainly come from state-owned enterprise stocks, and the total dividends paid by local companies in Hong Kong do not account for a high proportion. Among U.S. stocks, the New York Stock Exchange’s total dividends dominate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of dividend time and frequency, the frequency of dividends in the A-share market is mostly once a year, and the actual time of dividend distribution is mostly concentrated between May and July. The average number of annual dividends for Hong Kong stocks is about 1.5 times, and it is mostly used for U.S. stocks. Quarterly dividend payment method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Compared with U.S. stocks, the cash dividend ratio of A-shares is still low.” Yang Delong said that many companies in the United States repurchase and then cancel their shares to reward investors. Although the number of repurchases and cancellations in the A-share market has increased, in terms of proportion and amount, it is far lower than that of U.S. stocks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yang Delong&#39;s view, cash dividends plus share repurchases and cancellations are the best way to reward investors and are also a direction for future market reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Yang Delong believes that the dividend mechanism of A-shares can be further increased in guidance and mandatory in the future, especially for listed companies with financing needs, requiring them to pay dividends in excess of the IPO financing amount before they can again Financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This can place certain restrictions on the company&#39;s financing behavior and allow it to truly give back to investors instead of constantly asking the market for money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/ a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[内塔尼亚胡的司法改革：以色列的安全保障还是“拆家怪兽”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259029]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/RVVt5EKyjeJxmmWobYb73JO8APo0UNnqS9BmFTCf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/RVVt5EKyjeJxmmWobYb73JO8APo0UNn qS9BmFTCf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 1, 2023, in Jerusalem, Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu cried during a visit Wall to commemorate the swearing-in of Israel&#39;s 37th government. He placed a prayer note in the gap &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 7, 2023, de facto control of Gaza Hamas in the region suddenly launched the &quot;Operation Al-Aqsa Flood&quot;, a large-scale indiscriminate attack on Israeli territory. It has always occupied the absolute initiative in the Palestinian-Israeli and even Jewish-Arab conflicts and has a sense of security. Israel was caught off guard. The attack in just a few hours resulted in the death of more than 1,400 Israeli soldiers and civilians, and the abduction of at least 155 people. Although Israel&#39;s subsequent air strikes, shelling, blockade and other retaliations cost Gaza nearly 3,000 lives, Hamas&#39;s armed forces have ceased their activities. Israel&#39;s retaliation has increasingly attracted strong international reactions, which has greatly weakened Israel&#39;s &quot;terrorist attack victims&quot;. &quot;the image of the person&quot;. Not only that, the casualties, losses and frustrations caused by the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot; are unprecedented in Israel since its founding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts believe that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu (Benjamin Netanyahu) has always advertised the &quot;judicial reform&quot; that &quot;will bring the greatest safety factor to Israelis&quot;, which has a negative impact on Israel&#39;s attack by Hamas this time. He bears an unshirkable responsibility for invading the mainland and &quot;beating the country&quot;, but Netanyahu himself and his die-hard supporters still insist that &quot;judicial reform&quot; is Israel&#39;s &quot;security guarantee.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what is &quot;Netanyahu&#39;s judicial reform&quot;? Is it Israel&#39;s security guarantee or a &quot;house-destroying monster&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/JI66Q1RpbnwQl5tYA1Z3AdWCdhxR6jCv9c4B6k2S.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/JI66Q1RpbnwQl5tYA1Z3AdWCdhxR6jCv9c4B6k2S.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 10, 2023, rockets fired towards Israel were photographed in Gaza City&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What is &quot;Netanyahu&#39;s judicial reform&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Netanyahu has always been a polar figure in Israeli politics and the international community because of his extremely conservative and hard-line stance. Controversial role. Having stepped down after several elections, he relied on the particularities of Israel&#39;s electoral system and parliamentary composition, and by co-opting several small Jewish parties and fundamentalist parties that were more &quot;right&quot; than the Likud Party to which he belonged, and repeatedly succeeded in making comebacks and winning the election. The government has been reorganized, but the relatively independent Israeli judicial system has posed a more persistent threat to it than the opposition parties: After returning to the prime minister&#39;s seat in November 2022, he will still have to face at least three criminal charges in the judicial system, including corruption. , abuse of power, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to once and for all weaken the judicial system&#39;s ability to constrain administrative power and ensure the authority and continuity of his governance, Netanyahu proposed &quot;judicial reform&quot; as early as during his last administration. After taking office, he systematized, theorized and put it into action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, Netanyahu proposed &quot;five measures to reform the Israeli judicial system and the balance of power&quot;, including changing the selection method of judges; reforming the nature of legal advisors to government ministries; and reviewing the Basic Law Change of powers; empower the Parliament to reject the Supreme Court’s interpretation of the Basic Law; abolish the legal basis for Israeli courts to interfere with administrative decisions of administrative agencies on the grounds of “unreasonableness”; remove the Supreme Court’s power to review and veto government administrative orders, stipulating that as long as the Parliament simply A majority can override this veto. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These measures can be said to be extremely damaging to the judicial system. Take changing the method of selecting judges as an example: the existing nine members of the Judicial Selection Committee include three Supreme Court judges, two representatives of the Bar Association, two MPs and two ministers, the appointment of all judges requires a simple majority of the Judicial Selection Committee, and the selection of Supreme Court judges requires the approval of at least 7 people, which means that for the selection of ordinary judges, the 5 people in the judicial system have a lot of confidence in the selection of the Supreme Court. In the selection of judges, the three Supreme Court judges have the power of blocking with one vote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reform&quot; proposes to expand the Judicial Selection Committee to 11 people, including the Minister of Justice (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chairman&lt;/span>;) , two other ministers designated by the government, the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Constitution, Law and Justice, the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on State Control, the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee, the President of the Supreme Court, two other Supreme Court Justices elected from among the judges and the Minister of Justice. With two public representatives, one of whom is a lawyer, the parliament and the government will control 7 of the 11 votes on the Judicial Selection Committee and have almost complete control over judicial personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, &quot;Netanyahu&#39;s judicial reform&quot; also attempts to weaken the prosecutor general&#39;s judicial decision-making power and transfer power to the cabinet and ministers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZqE71W0Je4E4iVyWNFyPb3BYoTz26LPojsvISGKW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZqE71W0Je4E4iVyWNFyPb3BYoTz26LPojsvISGKW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 27, 2023, people participated in protests on the streets of Tel Aviv, Israel, against Netanyahu&#39;s judicial reforms&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Israel has always adopted a very special proportional representation system + cabinet system since the founding of the country, there are many small parties in the parliament. Since the founding of the country, no party has ever been able to rely on a simple majority in the parliament. Obtaining the right to form an independent government, even if the coalition government has little advantage in the parliament (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example, during the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot;, the current Netanyahu government &quot;Previously, it only held 65 of the 120 seats in the parliament. The &quot;emergency and war government&quot; that was hastily established after the incident only had 76 seats, of which the Likud group only had 32 seats.&lt;/span >;), often just a few seats are enough to change the &quot;color&quot; of the Israeli cabinet. Therefore, some small far-right, fundamentalist parties with only one or two seats have become &quot;kingmakers&quot; by conditionally supporting Netanyahu. Niyahu and Likud formed a government, pushing the latter, already far right, even further to the right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judicial reform came about because Netanyahu and the &quot;kingmakers&quot; hit it off, because through this &quot;reform&quot;, Netanyahu can only rely on single-digit parliamentary seats. Advantages and get rid of the &quot;hunting&quot; of the judicial system, while the far-right and fundamentalist small parties can use the identity and principles of &quot;kingmakers&quot; to achieve &quot;small snacks&quot;, relying on very few seats and votes to make the entire Israeli policy and rule of law Moving in the direction of conservatism, fundamentalism, and Jewish dominance as they envision it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because this &quot;reform&quot; will completely break the balance of the power structure under Israel&#39;s unique system, it will not only give the cabinet and prime minister more unfettered power, but also give small far-right parties with only a few seats It can more easily &quot;hijack&quot; the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood strategies, and even the way society operates, so even within the Likud group, many people disagree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Netanyahu himself, those who actively promote &quot;reforms&quot; include Justice Minister Yariv Levin, a right-wing cadre of the Likud Group, and Chairman of the Zionist Party (Religious Zionist Party) Simcha Rotman, and the very active group behind it is the &quot;Kohelet Forum&quot; composed of far-right figures from the United States and Israel. The forum&#39;s platform is billed as &quot;ensuring Israel&#39;s future as a Jewish nation-state, strengthening representative democracy, and expanding Israel&#39;s personal freedoms and free market principles.&quot; However, it is actually a group full of fundamental religious overtones. There are only about 130 core members of this group, but they operate dozens of large projects and hundreds of small projects. These plans are uniformly code-named &quot;Barkat Plan&quot; (Barkat Plan), named after the core member of the forum and former Netanyahu Named after Nir Barkat, economic minister in Hu’s cabinet, the aim is to “increase the Jewish population in the biblical heartland of Judea and Samaria” – which means implementing more extreme policies than Netanyahu’s, not just in Settlements are being expanded on Palestinian lands, and Palestinians from these lands must be driven away to make room for Jewish expansion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of this, these organizations and individuals are even more determined, tough and extreme than Netanyahu in promoting &quot;Netanyahu&#39;s judicial reform&quot;. Netanyahu has repeatedly criticized various They were pressured to make compromises, but were met with angry resistance from these &quot;teammates&quot; every time. In March 2023, the &quot;reformists&quot; passed legislation that significantly raised the threshold for Netanyahu&#39;s impeachment; in July, when the opposition collectively withdrew, they passed a law that abolished the &quot;unreasonable principle&quot; and The first step of &quot;judicial reform&quot; was completed, and in such an important and critical judicial vote, which Netanyahu hailed as &quot;a manifestation of the people&#39;s will&quot;, Netanyahu only received 64 votes, which was less than a simple majority (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;61 votes&lt;/span>;) only 3 more votes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/0IlQCOc8MmmoloUfCq7g6A0MCwyplOl6ZrhyQaMp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/0IlQCOc8MmmoloUfCq7g6A0MCwyplOl6ZrhyQaMp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, in Gaza City, Palestinians boarded an Israeli military vehicle&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Roaring wave of protests&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since November 2022, large-scale protests against &quot;Netanyahu&#39;s judicial reform&quot; have been held regularly every weekend in Israel. The scale of the rallies has escalated again and again. Ironically, it was the Hamas attack that broke this continuity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netanyahu’s opponents say the reforms will seriously undermine the country’s democracy by weakening the judicial system, which is the only instrument limiting the government’s exercise of power. They pointed out that &quot;judicial reform&quot; will ultimately protect Netanyahu, who is currently on trial for alleged corruption, and give the Israeli far right more &quot;lawless&quot;, unfettered and unchecked power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that the protestors’ camp includes many members of the military, intelligence, constitutional, special and other key departments that are crucial to the security of Israeli society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Lesley Stahl, a reporter for the CBS political commentary TV magazine &quot;60 Minutes&quot; visited Israel in mid-September 2023, he discovered that tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands of people had been organizing weekend weekend demonstrations for 37 consecutive weeks. One of the most influential organizations in the judicial reform protest rally is the &quot;Brothers and Sisters in Arms&quot; (Brothers and Sisters in Arms), which is composed entirely of reservists. Ron Scherf, one of the founders of this organization, pointed out that &quot;judicial reform&quot; will Allowing the far right to provoke the Palestinians more unscrupulously will worsen the security situation in Israel, which will put Israeli reservists who are often called to serve in dangerous situations all year round. The organization said an increasing number of Israeli reservists are expressing their dissatisfaction with &quot;judicial reforms&quot; by refusing to fulfill their reserve obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, Israel Defense Forces Chief of Staff Herzi Halevi said that “judicial reform” has a profound impact on the military. He told the Times of Israel that “a battle within Israeli society” Arguments that leave polarizing rifts are dangerous,&quot; warning that &quot;given the security challenges, allowing such polarizing debates is arrogant, and assuming that the IDF is immune to damaging polarization is a dangerous concept.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The large-scale boycott of reservists from fulfilling their obligations began after the Knesset passed the first part of the &quot;judicial reform&quot; in July. Due to Israel&#39;s small country and high military pressure, including elite commandos, fighter pilots and other front-line combat forces, Both rely heavily on serving reservists for maintenance. On October 2, Motasem A Dalloul Abujomaa, a writer for the Canadian &quot;Middle East Observer&quot; magazine, quoted a September report from the Israel branch of the Associated Press and pointed out that the Israel Defense Forces are &quot;the most well-equipped and powerful force in the Middle East.&quot; The military is facing one of the most serious attacks it has ever faced - an internal battle, &quot;as rifts caused by &#39;justice reform&#39; seep into the ranks,&quot; the report noted, adding that hundreds of New conscripts also refused to serve in protest against &quot;judicial reform,&quot; leading the article to assert that &quot;it is clear that the army is likely to be caught unawares if any tensions arise&quot;—a prediction that only passed It will be fully redeemed within 5 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netanyahu’s opponents pointed out that in order to ensure that “judicial reform” received unreserved support from the far-right and small fundamentalist parties, Netanyahu intensified his efforts to impose restrictions on the Palestinian areas after returning to power. High-pressure and even provocative practices, including repeatedly threatening military action against Gaza, assassinating leaders of Hamas and other radical organizations, &quot;targeted killings&quot; of buildings suspected of being resistance strongholds, and demanding that Qatar and other Middle Eastern countries stop providing humanitarian assistance to the poor people in Gaza. , stop paying for fuel for Gaza’s only power plant, require Egypt to tighten restrictions on the Rafah crossing, and stop trade between Gaza and the Israeli mainland, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Gaza, Netanyahu has also continued to carry out &quot;forced demolitions&quot; in the Palestinian Authority areas of the West Bank, &quot;carried out actions&quot; in sensitive hot spots, expanded and built new settlements, and the West Bank is not Hamas-controlled areas. Opponents further pointed out that these actions have aggravated the conflict between Palestine and Israel and increased Hamas&#39;s support among Palestinians to an unprecedented high. And if it were not for the need to canvass votes for &quot;judicial reform,&quot; Netanyahu would have rarely been so &quot;high-minded&quot; in his previous long political career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/cyCoEHF6ZAWZH5KcAWIAE6MNAl0F5vKOU3YJ5hdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/cyCoEHF6ZAWZH5KcAWIAE6MNAl0F5vKOU3YJ5hdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 16, 2023, at the United Nations Headquarters in New York, the Security Council voted on a draft resolution drafted by Russia on humanitarian issues in Gaza. As the United States, Britain, France and other countries voted against, the draft resolution was not passed &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Conspiracy Theory&quot; It may not be credible, Netanyahu is self-defeating&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot; occurred, some observers speculated that the military, intelligence, police and other departments that are generally opposed to &quot;judicial reform&quot; may secretly &quot; &quot;Let the water go&quot; in order to embarrass Netanyahu and thereby achieve the purpose of messing up the &quot;judicial reform.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering that this battle shattered the myth of Israel&#39;s &quot;invincibility&quot; in one fell swoop, the IDF&#39;s combat capabilities and intelligence system&#39;s early warning capabilities, which had long had a strong aura, were completely destroyed within a few hours. It also caused Israel to suffer the worst attack since the founding of the country. Heavy casualties in a single day and the homeland was attacked. At such a price, it is not just Netanyahu and the administration that have been damaged. The defense forces, intelligence and police systems are also deeply humiliated. Subjectively, the theory of &quot;letting go&quot; may not be credible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the performance of the conflict in southern Lebanon and the last two Gaza battles that the combat strength of the Israel Defense Forces is declining, and Israel’s intelligence capabilities rely more on information from the “Jewish world” spread across various industries. terminal, but due to Israel&#39;s long-term policy of &quot;isolating&quot; from Gaza and Hamas, it has lost the &quot;grey zone&quot; cover necessary for intelligence collection and analysis in the Gaza Strip. In addition, Hamas often adopts more primitive communication methods and With a more &quot;flat&quot; organizational system, it is reasonable for the Israeli intelligence agencies to turn a blind eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The damage caused by the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot; to Netanyahu and his judicial reforms is also heavy and far-reaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Israeli political analyst Akiva Eldar and others have pointed out, Netanyahu has long been promoting judicial reform by creating a &quot;choose me is to choose security&quot; to win votes for himself The biggest reason is to &quot;consolidate the election results and maintain the security of Israelis&quot;, but now all of this has been completely impacted by the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An Israeli public television commentator pointed out in the program that Netanyahu advertised &quot;security&quot;, but after the Hamas attack, he delayed for five days before forming an &quot;emergency unity battle&quot; that included the opposition. &quot;If it were other countries, this process would only take 48 hours,&quot; and the Israeli cabinet did not even hold an emergency meeting on the day of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now even many Israelis who have always supported Netanyahu and favored &quot;judicial reform&quot; are beginning to feel hesitant. Rabbi Eliezer Moshea, a Jewish cleric in the Old City of Jerusalem, said that he had been frustrated because of Netanyahu. Niyahu has repeatedly allocated funds to rabbinical schools and enthusiastically supported him and &quot;judicial reform&quot;, but &quot;when our children are being slaughtered and our women are raped, he is helpless, what use can he use the money he gives to the yeshiva?&quot; He has proven unfit to lead this country.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even Michel Ben-Ami, the director of the office responsible for social issues within the Likud Party, told AFP that the &quot;accountability group&quot; established after the war was aimed at the government and Netanyahu. &quot;Investigation committee&quot; is inevitable. &quot;If he makes a mistake, he will have to pay the price for it.&quot; He believes that &quot;accountability investigation is inevitable and is the consensus of the Likud Group today.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 27 On March 1, less than two weeks before the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot; occurred, the Jewish People&#39;s Policy Institute (JPPI) released the &quot;2023 Annual Assessment&quot; stating that &quot;about 37% of Israelis currently hold or plan to obtain foreign passports and intending to immigrate,&quot; arguing that &quot;this alarming figure highlights the deepening crisis in Israel and raises questions about the country&#39;s ability to recover,&quot; and directly placed the blame on &quot;Israel&#39;s judicial reforms and Turbulence in Religious and National Sphere”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report states that the comfort level of Israelis living in Israel has dropped sharply in the past year, with the proportion of people who feel uncomfortable soaring from 20% to 32%, while those who feel comfortable have dropped from 76% to 65% %. Even among supporters of the traditionally more cohesive right, their comfort level dropped from 55% in February 2023 to 43% in July. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly 40% of Israelis have considered obtaining a foreign passport and leaving the country, a significant portion of the population, and this number is even higher among conservative Israelis and individuals who themselves hold foreign passports Higher - It must be pointed out that the above data were obtained before the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot; occurred, otherwise it might be even worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, many analysts believe that Netanyahu is unlikely to weaken or cancel the intensity of &quot;judicial reform&quot; due to these pressures and setbacks. On the contrary, he is more likely to &quot;brade the wind&quot; to &quot; The reason for &quot;Israel needs a higher security factor&quot; has become even stronger - because if he does not do that, his political life is destined to enter a countdown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不要让县中继续败给“超级中学”丨议教]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259065]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/22/6kr682xhlhaoattdgoedkgvaown8u2ldwqlomfm.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1192 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;795&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/medias/ima/ima GE/23/10/22/6KR682xhlhaoattdgoedkgvaon8u2ldwqlomfm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254820&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;February 12, 2017, No. 4 Middle School in Jianhe County, Guizhou. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Leave a message in the comment area for a chance to win a signed book from the author&lt;/span>;&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, county education as a whole has gradually entered the vision of academic researchers, policymakers and the public, and has become an important issue of social concern. The latest hot topic is whether small rural schools should continue to exist and invest resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;County education is exactly what our Central China Village Governance Research Team partners and I surveyed in counties and townships in many provinces across the country from May 2017 to June 2023. Previously, apart from a few interviews with primary and secondary school teachers, the Huazhong Rural Governance Research Team rarely touched on rural education issues. Until our research expanded to rural governance and rural sociology, rural education became an important part of investigating and writing village governance reports. Around 2017, rural education became an independent research topic, and our research scope expanded from rural areas to the entire county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, our research targets include county and township schools, families, education management departments and grassroots society, trying to analyze a series of emerging phenomena: why the phenomenon of accompanying mothers in county towns is prevalent, and what will happen to them ? What impact do mobile games and online novels have on children in counties and villages? What role does the super high school play in the county? Why have non-teaching tasks in schools increased significantly? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After analyzing these phenomena, we must think about, where is the way out for county and township education? I would like to begin by stating our conclusions. After conducting research in so many places, we have always believed that in the end, it is the county that carries the hope of most children in the county and township. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A &quot;lose-lose&quot; battle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with cities, counties are a weak and complex space, which is characterized by weak resources and poor environment in education. complex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of county education, the development status of county high schools is the most important concern for the development of county education. If the county collapses, local people will lose confidence in the area&#39;s education, thus accelerating population migration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current county is indeed facing a development crisis, and one of the biggest threats comes from &quot;super high schools&quot;. Super middle schools rely on their own advantages in running schools to attract high-quality students and teachers from the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some super middle schools will organize preliminary examinations for outstanding students in counties and cities across the province before the high school entrance examination, go to village communities to persuade parents of outstanding students, or entrust some primary and secondary school teachers to serve as students in advance jobs, attracting experienced teachers in the county to leave their jobs through high salaries, etc. The cross-regional enrollment of super middle schools has gradually eroded the basic structure of county middle school student training - the running of schools in county schools has been forced to adopt some short-term strategic behaviors through constant self-exploitation, such as running out of time. Investment, excessive tilting of high-quality resources to a small number of seed players, and even sending students to some well-known high schools for &quot;training&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The choice among these counties is inappropriate and helpless. The helplessness is that the super middle school relies on its multiple advantages to carry out dimensionality reduction attacks on the county. However, this blow has produced a &quot;lose-lose&quot; result: the county is under increasing pressure due to the loss of high-quality resources; the super middle school has become excessively involved due to the gathering of excellent students, and the relationship between students has become tense and psychological problems have arisen. There are more and more students, and the competition pattern has shifted from reasonable scope to competitive polarization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side of county high school education, the development of county secondary vocational education is also facing many difficulties. On the one hand, the &quot;diversion from general vocational education&quot; policy has increasingly caused anxiety among parents. Most parents generally still cannot accept their children going to secondary vocational schools. In order to avoid falling into the bottom 50% in the high school entrance examination, they try every means to improve their grades. However, for students who go to vocational schools, parents Then there is not much hope for the development of students. On the other hand, secondary vocational schools have poor student training quality due to factors such as weak student foundations, lack of professional teachers, and inadequate facilities and equipment, making it difficult to respond to market demand and social doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the state has gradually increased its investment in secondary vocational schools, due to structural difficulties, the development of secondary vocational schools, especially county secondary vocational schools, is struggling. Some secondary vocational schools are struggling to explore amidst the difficulties. The road to survival and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Cities are crowded and villages are empty”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the context of population migration, what kind of education do rural families need? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking down from the high school, the development of county junior high schools and primary schools shows two extremes: &quot;cities are crowded and villages are empty&quot;. Under the pressure of the government&#39;s &quot;education new city&quot; construction and social education competition, the urbanization of education The pace of education is accelerating, and rural students continue to transfer to urban schools. The county has accepted a large number of students from rural areas. However, because the livelihood model of rural families of &quot;part-time work and part-farming&quot; has not changed, and the county cannot handle the daily care tasks of rural students after they go to the city, this task has to be borne by the families themselves. This increases the cost for rural families to study in cities. On the other end of the spectrum, a large number of small rural schools have too few students. It is already difficult to maintain normal student training, and normal interactions among peers cannot be guaranteed. How can we teach and educate people and make adults successful? Moreover, the scattered resource layout has restricted county-level education. The government’s effective integration of county educational resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rural primary and secondary schools not only face the problem of whether and how to integrate resources, but also face the problems caused by the fragmentation of rural families. Problems such as left-behind children, divorce, and &quot;running mothers&quot; have caused a lack of family education for rural teenagers and brought a series of challenges to school education. When schools face children from broken families, they need to spend more time and effort than children from normal families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family education is lacking. Schools must first change students’ living habits and then guide students to learn. Due to insufficient family education, the foundation of students in rural primary and secondary schools is weaker than that of urban students, and the number of outstanding students is also smaller. For township junior high schools, a very specific issue worthy of discussion is whether key classes should be allocated. Should education be fair, should there be no discrimination or should students be taught in accordance with their aptitude? If there is no distinction in teaching, and all students are divided into classes in a balanced manner, the few outstanding students in each class may be biased by the underachievers with poor habits; if students are taught in accordance with their aptitude, and students are classified into different types of classes, they may suffer To raise social questions and policy accountability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Workers in rural primary and secondary schools often have to face such dilemmas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school is still a quagmire, and the quaint nature of primary and secondary schools in the county can be seen from the phenomenon of campus bullying. The occurrence of school bullying has the influence of family education, but it is more the result of the interaction of peer groups in the school structure. If the school forms a just order on campus, it can better suppress the occurrence of campus bullying; if the just order of the school breaks down, students can only rely on the self-built jungle order for interpersonal interactions, and the phenomenon of strong bullying of the weak will occur. Unfortunately, a large number of schools are subject to strict restrictions and cannot easily impose some of the deterrent penalties of the past on students who violate regulations and disciplines, making it more difficult to rebuild campus order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The spread of network technology and the popularization of smartphones have caused serious Internet addiction among rural teenagers, which has further increased the difficulty of education management for front-line education managers in counties. For example, a girl told us that an online novel describing various crimes went viral among her classmates. We checked and found in the relevant comment area that the concepts of &quot;society is a dark forest of conspiracy&quot;, &quot;others are hell&quot; and &quot;evil is justified&quot; are quite common among readers of this novel. This book has been banned by the school, but students are still circulating it privately. Even if you don&#39;t read it at school, you can&#39;t help but take a look when you go home during the holidays. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adolescent children have unique spiritual needs at this stage. We found that when children read novels during this period, they are not absorbing knowledge, but looking for themselves and the power to grow. They easily bring themselves and their experiences of real life into the novels they read. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Upward Hope&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Under the extremely complex educational situation, administrators and front-line teachers of schools at all stages in the county are still working hard to explore and make positive changes . They try to guide, educate and change children from broken families, children who violate the rules, and children who are psychologically fragile. They want to provide a quiet learning environment for rural children, but they are often restrained by rigid rules. In particular, they also need to resist being &quot;sieged&quot; themselves. Various non-teaching jobs squeeze their educational time, forcing them to cry out for &quot;please give teachers a quiet teaching environment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, we have seen more of the embarrassing side of county education, but in front-line surveys we have also seen that county education also has positivity and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to race against time and gain study time, some children only give themselves 20 minutes to eat, some carry notebooks with them on the way to eat, and some stay up late to read and work hard day and night. When we look at them with sympathy, they look back with determination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some teachers who, in order to reduce the negative impact of students’ family factors, often accompany, listen and give them care. Huang Huaju, an outstanding class teacher at Yushan Middle School in Longhui County, Hunan Province, implemented the &quot;accompanying education method&quot; based on the characteristics of rural students. She observed an introverted girl with poor grades and later learned that the student had run away from home due to domestic violence from her mother. Teacher Huang often talks to the girl and invites her to have dinner with her. He expresses his &quot;preference&quot; and helps the girl build her self-confidence in various ways. There are many teachers Huang in rural schools, and they will explore various educational methods that are beneficial to the growth of students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some school administrators dare to reform, try to activate teachers and students, and reverse the decline of school development. A township school in Chengdu, Sichuan, once ranked last in the city. The young principal who took office in 2019 reinvigorated the school through reforms, allowing the struggling school to achieve a &quot;turnaround&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also rural parents who are working hard to create better educational conditions for their children. When policies fail to respond to demands, they seek change through &quot;self-help&quot;. Some people give up their jobs and their original lives and rent a house in the city to accompany them to school. Some people spend huge sums of money to send their children to private schools. They have one thing in common: they try their best to create a better educational environment for their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there are many development problems in county and township education, although educational resources in counties and townships are more scarce and the situations they face are more complex than in cities, the hope for improvement cannot be dashed. The future development of county education will not only require policy inclinations to make up for the shortcomings of county education development, but also need to activate the existing resources and comparative advantages of county and township schools through system construction to cultivate children&#39;s ability to make future choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these surveys, we wrote the book &quot;Children of Counties and Townships&quot;, which presents the operation of schools, teachers&#39; ideas, parents&#39; demands, students&#39; mentality, policy implementation and other education issues in the form of cases. The frontline situation explores the current situation, problems and future of county education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/8657Um1M0wHguVSf7A2iwK6P86HDjbF2avLOQiML.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;1269&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/8657Um1M0wHguVSf7A2iwK6P86HDjbF2avLOQiML.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254819&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Children of Counties and Townships&quot; Yang Hualei and Wanghong are waiting for China Renmin University Press, September 2023&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In response to the problem, we proposed an education development model for county middle schools, township schools, and village primary schools, believing that the county education system composed of the three is both fair and efficient. Oppose over-investment in small schools and cross-regional enrollment in super middle schools - believing that it is these that create educational competition pressure and national education anxiety. Therefore, we still believe that the hopes of most children in counties and townships will ultimately be carried by the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The author is a lecturer at the School of Public Administration, Central South University&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉嫌杀死邻居女童的少年，是“被剩下”的县中孩子吗丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259063]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The victim&#39;s home (left) and the suspect&#39;s home are very close. Southern Weekend reporter Photo by Gao Yichen&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/fe5c543d75.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;729&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/fe5c543d75.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254817&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;The victim&#39;s home (left) and the suspect&#39;s home are very close. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/256009&quot; title=&quot;The murderous intention and youth of a 13-year-old rural boy&quot;>;A 13-year-old rural boy When I was interviewing for this report, I often felt uncomfortable. The incident occurred in Changning, Hunan, a small city in a remote area. A boy under the age of 14 killed his neighbor&#39;s 11-year-old girl and threw her body into the Xiangjiang River. This is the initial information of this news. The boy&#39;s face is blurred and only his age and basic family composition are known. I had the idea of ​​&quot;visiting Chang Ning immediately&quot; and wanted to know what kind of family background and growth trajectory he had behind those few words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have seen many reports on juvenile crimes, and the one that impressed me most was an arson case involving a juvenile. In Pubei County, Guangxi in 2016, three teenagers met a homeless man on the street in the early morning. They poured gasoline on each other and lit a fire, causing the other person to be severely burned. It was an impromptu act full of malicious intent, and their age The oldest is only 14 years old. The cases also have sad background reasons. Restoring their stories and gaining insight into the impact of environmental factors, family education, etc. may serve as a warning for such juvenile crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, a murder and body dumping occurred in the village, involving two struggling families and their children who stayed at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I arrived in the village, I could deeply understand the helplessness of their parents who had to go out to work: transportation was inconvenient, land was scarce, and they could not make money if they stayed in the village. I have been to many different villages, and the furniture and appliances of these two families are among the simplest. It can be seen to the naked eye that the economic conditions of these two families are poor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although both children are left-behind children, the closeness between them and their families is completely different. The girl&#39;s parents will post photos of her and her brother on social platforms, as well as videos of their daughter dancing at the &quot;June 1st&quot; art performance. Even if a family is separated in three places due to working, they will have frequent video calls. Grandma is also very clear about her performance in school, dancing, practicing calligraphy, and drawing. During interviews, she will bring a certificate or an exercise book from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a psychological perspective, parents are not completely absent from girls’ childhood education. Details of the boy&#39;s family have been revealed in reports. The parents were more &quot;helpless&quot;. When they faced me, they were very friendly and polite, but their words were more like &quot;I can&#39;t do anything&quot; and &quot;I just can&#39;t do anything.&quot; I can do so much” for many reasons: old age, illness, poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One detail impressed me deeply. The boy&#39;s grandparents had no clue about the motive of the crime, but as they talked, the grandfather suddenly said categorically that such a thing happened entirely because of the mobile phone. But he couldn&#39;t tell what his grandson used his mobile phone on a daily basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boy only got a mobile phone when he was in the third grade of junior high school. In the days before there was no mobile phone, he would watch others play with it. After he got the mobile phone, he would not let go. In March 2023, I talked with Xia Zhuzhi, associate professor of Wuhan University, about the problem of mobile phone addiction among left-behind children. Their research team found that 90% of rural left-behind children use exclusive mobile phones or their elders’ mobile phones to play for a long time. They have a lot of free time, and most of the time With no one to control and lack of companionship, it is difficult to resist the temptation of mobile phones. For these left-behind children, they are faced with a large amount of unfiltered Internet information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even so, it is difficult to say that &quot;playing with mobile phones&quot; is the root of the problem. In my understanding, the boy&#39;s grandfather&#39;s words &quot;It&#39;s all caused by the mobile phone&quot; are more about the confusion and helplessness under the impact of this despair. Facing the impact of the outside world, the elderly have no way to deal with and educate their children in traditional ways. At the same time, parents do not see their responsibilities. For them, free-range care may be a normal way of raising children. Food and clothing seem to be enough. They are not suitable for this era of mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After talking to the boy’s family and classmates, I gradually realized the loneliness and monotony of the boy’s environment. A teenager of his age mainly understands the world and learns rules through family and school. However, he entered school earlier than his peers. He had the experience of being bullied at school. He has a somewhat submissive personality and does not like to communicate with others at home. , and had little to say to his grandparents, so he seemed to have failed to acquire these skills at home and at school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He worked as a boarding student in a rural town. The environment he lived in was poor and closed. There were few people to plan for his future, and there was no opportunity to stand out through reading like being a topic writer in a small town. Not only him, but the classmates around him are also facing the crisis of being &quot;left behind&quot; children in the county. The male students I came into contact with were the ones who were screened out in the continuous diversion and screening process of the education system. In their narratives, teachers can express &quot;look down upon&quot; unabashedly, and many students are in a state of &quot;semi-giving up&quot;. As the year of entering higher education approaches, they do not have an intense sprint phase. Instead, they each have their own way of living, asking for leave, skipping classes, fighting, and playing with mobile phones in class. A considerable proportion of them want to go to vocational schools, and some even have problems with their livelihood and family. I don’t even have the money to go to a vocational school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a worrying realization that deserves more social attention than this murder case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[紫薯不是红薯，不能免高速费？绿色通道不是一道生物分类题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259071]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Why are the same purple sweet potatoes treated differently at different high-speed toll stations? A recent news has once again attracted attention to the green channel policy for agricultural products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Morning News, recently, when a truck driver, Mr. Li, was driving off the expressway from Nanying, Yicheng City, Hubei Province, he was told that the purple sweet potato he was pulling was not in the catalog of fresh agricultural products, and he was charged 900 yuan. Travel expenses. When he got off the expressway from Nanchang, Jiangxi and Ezhou, Hubei, the toll collectors believed that purple sweet potatoes were fresh agricultural products and could enjoy the green channel policy for agricultural products without charging tolls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Li was puzzled by this and posted a video complaint online. In this regard, the person in charge of Nanying Toll Station said that they strictly follow the &quot;Catalogue of Fresh Agricultural Products Varieties&quot; formulated by the Ministry of Transport, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Finance, and the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs. Purple sweet potato is not in the catalog. Therefore, you cannot enjoy the green pass policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that this explanation makes sense. A notice issued by the four ministries and commissions at the end of 2022 stated that &quot;sweet potato&quot; is one of the fresh vegetables that can enjoy the green pass policy, and the &quot;aliases and common trade names&quot; of sweet potato include &quot;sweet potato, sweet potato, white potato, sweet potato, sweet potato, sweet potato, red taro&quot; &quot;Wait, &quot;Purple Sweet Potato&quot; is indeed not among them. The Ministry of Transport also made it clear when responding to inquiries on the official website that &quot;purple sweet potatoes&quot; are not included in the &quot;Catalogue of Fresh Agricultural Products Varieties&quot; and are not agricultural products that enjoy the preferential policies of the &quot;green channel&quot;. However, this reply was made in October 2020, 2 years earlier than the new notice at the end of 2022. From this reply alone, we cannot conclude that &quot;the 2022 version of the new fresh agricultural product catalog does not include purple sweet potatoes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the domestic trade industry standard SB/T10029-2012 &quot;Fresh Vegetable Classification and Code&quot; issued by the Ministry of Commerce, sweet potato (also known as potato, sweet potato, sweet potato) and purple potato are indeed divided into different categories. But they are all &quot;fresh vegetables&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the catalog of fresh agricultural products refers to the industry standards of the Ministry of Commerce, it lists more aliases for sweet potatoes in order to minimize possible disputes. However, sweet potatoes and purple potatoes are similar in appearance. The only difference is that purple potatoes are purple in color, and they are both fresh vegetables according to the standards of the Ministry of Commerce. Why do they enjoy different treatment? No wonder disputes often arise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if we strictly follow botanical classification, the standards of the Ministry of Commerce and the catalog of fresh agricultural products published by the four ministries may not be accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information from the website &quot;Plant Intelligence&quot; hosted by the Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences, sweet potato, commonly known as sweet potato, belongs to the genus Magnoliaceae-Lily subclass-Dioscoreales-Dioscoreaceae-Dioscorea in plant taxonomy. A species. The scientific name of the commonly known &quot;sweet potato&quot; is actually &quot;sweet potato&quot;, which is a species under the genus Magnoliacea-Rosoda-Solanales-Convolvulaceae-Tiger Palm Vine. Sweet potatoes also have common names such as goose, white potato, sweet potato, sweet potato, sweet potato, yam, sweet potato, potato, jade pillow potato, Tang potato, red potato, red yam, Ganchu, fanru, golden potato, sweet potato, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this, although sweet potato and sweet potato are often considered to be different common names for the same plant in daily life, from a botanical classification point of view, sweet potato and sweet potato belong to different subclasses and are actually very distantly related. of two species. On the contrary, sweet potatoes and morning glories belong to the genus Tiger Palm and are close relatives. Purple sweet potato is only a subspecies of sweet potato in botanical classification. According to the common name, it should be included in &quot;sweet potato&quot;. Sweet potato is one of the common names of sweet potato, and taxonomically speaking, sweet potato and sweet potato are two very different species, which is indeed confusing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although &quot;purple potatoes are not sweet potatoes&quot;, &quot;hot peppers are not peppers&quot;, &quot;baby cabbage is not cabbage&quot;, &quot;cherries are not cherries&quot; and &quot;cherry tomatoes are not tomatoes&quot; often cause ridicule on social networks, but these The differences between the different names of fresh crops in botany, the Ministry of Commerce’s trade standards, the catalog of fresh agricultural products, and the public’s daily cognition are not the root cause of the dispute over the Green Pass policy. Many times, even for agricultural products whose variety classification is not controversial, toll stations will refuse to implement the green pass policy on the grounds of &quot;not fresh&quot; or &quot;extensively processed&quot; and require payment of fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do toll stations try to find ways to charge card drivers and not give free access to agricultural product transport vehicles? The reason is naturally to reduce losses as much as possible. Currently, the tolls exempted from the green pass for agricultural products are borne by highway operating companies. This is not a small amount of money. According to the &quot;2021 National Toll Road Statistical Bulletin&quot; released by the Ministry of Transport, the &quot;green channel&quot; of national toll roads will reduce tolls by 27.47 billion yuan in 2021, and the reduction in 2019 will reach 35.08 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The green pass policy was introduced by the state to reduce the circulation costs of agricultural products. The expenses thus reduced should have been borne by the government. In 2009, the Ministry of Transport and the National Development and Reform Commission stated in relevant notices on the comprehensive implementation of the green toll policy that the impact of green tolls on commercial toll road companies should be studied, and those with a greater impact would be compensated as appropriate; new batches of tolls When building highway projects, the impact of green traffic must be fully considered and traffic flow reasonably determined. In 2019, relevant ministries and commissions once again proposed to conduct an in-depth assessment of the implementation effects and impacts of the green pass policy, and formulate specific plans to compensate for the loss of legitimate income of toll road operating units caused by the optimization policy. However, these &quot;research&quot; and &quot;evaluation&quot; have so far produced no results, and all the costs of the free green pass have been borne by the toll road operating companies. Without financial compensation, the toll station will naturally have to worry about every detail, trying to provide as little free service as possible and charge as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the green pass for agricultural products, there are many other toll-free policies, such as free passenger cars on holidays, which have also had a great impact on the income of expressway companies. According to the statistical bulletin of the Ministry of Transport, 38.07 billion yuan in tolls for small passenger vehicles will be exempted during major holidays in 2021, which is more than 10 billion yuan more than the tolls exempted under the Green Pass for agricultural products. The total vehicle toll revenue from national toll roads that year was only 663.05 billion. Yuan, with these two reduction and exemption policies alone, the tolls collected are close to 10% of the total revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The basic logic is who pays the bill. Nowadays, the policy is treating the guests, but it is the enterprises that foot the bill, and the promised compensation to the enterprises has yet to be received. Naturally, when companies pay bills, they have to make careful calculations and worry about every detail to avoid losses as much as possible. Therefore, the fundamental way to put an end to green-pass policy disputes is to straighten out the entire mechanism and fully compensate highway operation managers. With the popularization of electronic toll collection methods such as ETC, these are no longer technically difficult. We can also explore more ways to reduce logistics costs, such as directly issuing freight subsidies to transporters or wholesalers of fresh agricultural products, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 13:25:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[出门旅游住急诊省钱？怎么把“假病人”送出医院？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259041]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>