<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[应该关掉各种班级群，给家长“减负”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259533]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a seventh-grade teacher from Zhuge Liang Middle School in Xiangyang City, Hubei Province commented to his students &quot;the best in the class&quot; while correcting homework. Oops, are you an orphan?&quot; He then took a photo and posted it in the &quot;Grade 7 Class 9&quot; WeChat group. Subsequently, the local education bureau issued a notice of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course it seems that the teacher has no teacher ethics when he said this. The real problem in this matter is that the teacher really thinks that it is the parents&#39; business to correct students&#39; homework and teach students cultural classes. She was really angry at the parents: &quot;Why don&#39;t you teach your children or grade their homework?&quot; The reason why she scolded her was not to scold the students, but to scold the parents and put pressure on them. In fact, in today&#39;s education, she is by no means the only teacher who thinks so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the inevitable factor behind this accident, and this is the real problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still remember that when I was a child, the teacher would assign homework. It was always after class. The teacher would write on the blackboard, and I would circle it with my book or memorize it in my notebook. This is something every student can accomplish. Do your homework as soon as you get home. If you don&#39;t know how to do it, you may be asked, or you may leave it alone. Your parents may sign it, but they will definitely not check whether the homework is done correctly one by one. Submit your homework the next day and the teacher will correct it. If you are wrong, ask for correction and hand it in with the next day&#39;s homework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But now everything has changed. Tutoring and correcting homework have become the responsibility of parents. The teacher assigns homework in the group every day, and parents see it and help their children complete it as required. Although the Ministry of Education has repeatedly warned not to assign homework to parents, the effect is not great. Teachers still give assignments, and parents still need to help with homework, correct homework, and attend class. Among these, Internet-based home-school contact plays a big role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are of course many benefits to using the Internet and smartphones to communicate between home and school. Teachers and parents can communicate at any time without being restricted by time and location, which is convenient and fast. Teachers can assign homework in the group to prevent students from forgetting, and can also publish students&#39; learning status, homework completion status, test scores, etc. Parents can also keep abreast of their children&#39;s learning status and provide timely feedback to the teacher. In short, through WeChat groups, QQ groups, DingTalk groups and other platforms, parents and teachers can interact better and participate in their children&#39;s education process together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the advantages and disadvantages of anything actually lie in the purpose. If the purpose is changed, the advantage may become a disadvantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In various home-school groups, privacy issues such as sending wrong messages are not a big deal. The key issue is that these Internet channels are a channel that effectively distributes pressure and work from teachers to parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that love in the past was beautiful. You had to wait repeatedly to send a love letter. Although it was backward, it was romantic. Nowadays, WeChat contact is constant, making many people feel that they have no space of their own. It is said in the movie &quot;Mobile Phone&quot;: Mobile phones are originally for convenience. Without them, people are quite free. With them, people become kites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Channels will affect content, and tools will affect behavior. Efficient electronic channels have forced parents to have nowhere to escape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, parents could say: The child didn’t tell me when he got home, so I don’t know. Now that parents no longer have this space, teachers will shift all the pressure onto parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teacher is the group leader, to some extent the leader of a small organization. When teachers communicate with parents one-on-one, they are relatively equal, but when communicating in a group, teachers will have many supporters. . Whoever the teacher praises or criticizes in the group will create pressure in the class, and then this pressure will be transmitted to parents and children. In this incident, the teacher also took photos and posted them in the group to unscrupulously put pressure on parents. This will force parents to tutor their children, increase the pressure on their children&#39;s studies, and ultimately form a heavier academic burden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, when there are too many WeChat groups and QQ groups, it will also put a lot of pressure on teachers, add some extra work to them, and increase their workload. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reducing the frequency and convenience of home-school contact can reduce the tasks and pressure teachers pass on to parents. Obviously, if there were no electronic channels and groups, it would be impossible for teachers to call parents one by one to assign homework. These tasks and pressures return to the teachers, and the teachers cannot complete them. In the end, the students&#39; academic burden is reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people may worry that without efficient communication and interaction channels, what should we do if our children&#39;s learning declines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, from a large policy level, this choice has been completed. Some people believe that in the process of implementing the &quot;double reduction&quot; reform, on the one hand, it is necessary to &quot;reduce the excessive academic burden&quot;, have more outdoor activities, and have less homework; on the other hand, it is necessary to &quot;study well&quot; and let children learn in their interests. You can learn more, faster, and better in a state of exuberance. &quot;Load reduction&quot; cannot be simplified to &quot;reducing academic work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of strategy of having both fish and bear&#39;s paw is very safe in terms of attitude. Neither side is offended, both sides want it, and they do not bear any responsibility for the consequences. Children&#39;s burdens are still heavy because they have to &quot;study well&quot;; children do not learn well because they have to &quot;lighten their burdens.&quot; There are changes because we need to &quot;reduce the burden&quot;; there are no changes because we need to &quot;learn well&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is impossible to have your cake and eat it too. For most people, learning requires high-intensity brain operation. The more you learn, the less time you have for this high-intensity operation. The only way to reduce the burden on primary school and junior high school students is to lower their academic standards. In fact, the high school entrance examination in many places has lowered the distinction, and everyone&#39;s scores are about the same. This is lowering academic standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people believe that this will drive parents to let their children continue to answer questions and improve their proficiency, but this may not be the actual situation. Some people&#39;s strategy for reducing returns is to invest less. For example, in the past, people who ate from a big pot and worked hard could be promoted and become model workers. However, most people would choose to lie flat in the face of such disproportionate input and output. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having a group to establish close ties can indeed enhance academic performance, but at the same time, it will cause the problem of overburdening parents. Since the main goal of the policy is to &quot;reduce the burden&quot;, it should not &quot;increase the burden&quot; on the children by &quot;adding burdens&quot; to parents. At this time, the advantage of establishing close ties between home and school through groups becomes a disadvantage. Then, it is a logical choice to reduce the frequency of home-school contact, close various class groups, or even prohibit Internet-based home-school contact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[通向世界的小作坊]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259455]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/d1QYAQWbkA9N7KOCeuSnuYX6WDwwSJcgAEI1NnpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/d1QYAQWbkA9N7KOCeuSnuYX6WDwwS JcgAEI1NnpD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Young people working in small workshops in the suburbs of Yiwu&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beilun, Ningbo, the hometown of photographer Wang Shijie, has a port area of ​​Ningbo Port just offshore to the north. Every day, countless containers enter Beilun Port from all directions, and then depart from Beilun Port and flow to all parts of the world, including containers from Yiwu. Regardless of the economic downturn, goods from Yiwu always arrive as usual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/kAfQ0GjaKoFiMwi6I5tlvS628UMPFD29e8F1uvPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/kAfQ0GjaKoFiMwi6I5tlvS628UMPFD29e8F1uvPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A large number of wigs are piled up on the workbench&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020 In the spring and summer, after experiencing a round of strict COVID-19 control, the photographer became curious about the products that were continuously produced in Yiwu and came to Yiwu from Beilun. In the family-style workshop painted with cement and stacked with red bricks, he saw the resilience of the private small commodity economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Small workshops are concentrated on the outskirts of the city, and their appearance is separated from the majestic commercial city in the city by decades: an old house, a few countertops, and a few rows of simple machines are a factory. In order to maximize the use of the space inside the house, the original partition wall and the door to the back room were removed. Standing at the door, you can see the corner of the back room at a glance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/n1966CPc0LEncXp5tBurIuXC8FdJNTCu8HPIsCob.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/n1966CPc0LEncXp5tBurIuXC8FdJNTCu8HPIsCob.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The employees of the small workshop live in a small house of about 10 square meters, and Ajun’s lower bunk is hung with colored lanterns&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a variety of items produced here, most of which are cheap small items, such as toiletry bags, handbags, plastic mats, and party wigs. Their process is simple and only requires repeated manual labor, so the factory can change the products at any time as long as the price is right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pEhw5O5jFmnmy2ec1iFGHrwXdhrSfjXIWm136uHd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pEhw5O5jFmnmy2ec1iFGHrwXdhrSfjXIWm136uHd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The workbench of a small workshop&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original small workshop It is a family style, where the whole family works together. When the business is good, it expands into a small workshop. For a place of the same size, the rent in the suburbs is only half that in the city. Some small workshops have stores in the Trade City or Binwang Market, and can directly contact the international market with customers; those without stores mainly rely on the network of relatives and friends to receive orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yiwu attracts a large number of outsiders to come here to &quot;make a living&quot;. Most family-owned workshops are staffed by foreigners, and even workshops run by locals in Yiwu will hire migrant workers. Some migrant workers also prefer to work in small workshops - to receive wages in a factory, you have to rely on the factory&#39;s income. When the market is not good, it is difficult to get wages; when money is urgently needed, it is difficult for the factory to take care of it alone. One&#39;s life problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vgfrqyuxn10VSwiXRFOpd5NqCI9quTBKM3dh0WlU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vgfrqyuxn10VSwiXRFOpd5NqCI9quTBKM3dh0WlU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The walls of the belt-making workshop are covered with various data&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;During the COVID-19 prevention and control period, workers in workshops put on masks and continued to work. Their lives continued, and the work at hand could not stop either. They could earn two to three hundred yuan by working 12 hours a day. This kind of busyness continues until before the New Year. Young people wrap up their coats, put on scarves and hats, and add a few more notes to the money they send home in the cold windy brick house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/gBadLZGEdobkD7NPsXlwAVQeyvSwHwkKcIP6gY8S.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/gBadLZGEdobkD7NPsXlwAVQeyvSwHwkKcIP6gY8S.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;News is being broadcast on TV&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The life of workshop workers is monotonous Repeat, almost all the waking hours of the day are spent working. The photographer wanted to chat with the young workers, but they had no time for conversation. There is no way of knowing what kind of personality they have and what they like. Only the blue nails on their nails, the false eyelashes on their eyes, the lanterns and celebrity posters hanging in the bedspread, and the graffiti on the wall next to their workstations revealed a corner of their inner world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Cs7bu8mvUm2x8XieJgkB3NPy59bFDkIxFOefWU4d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Cs7bu8mvUm2x8XieJgkB3NPy59bFDkIxFOefWU4d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ajun from Yunnan and Xiaolin from Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pWLsQYXIb4ZW50Dve5duSumv0Maonby4U4dOKbo6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pWLsQYXIb4ZW50Dve5duSumv0Maonby4U4dOKbo6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;Xiaoxia is the person in charge of the small clothing workshop &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/hUWexWEnySSwa92KttSYkpKNMRthlW7ZtkBvcjPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/hUWexWEnySSwa92KttSYkpKNMRthlW7ZtkBvcjPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiao Dong from Sichuan is Skilled workers making belts &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/k2eYP485HTWTUol5Eedk3FeAQMGiKyF7lnoiBTpA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/k2eYP485HTWTUol5Eedk3FeAQMGiKyF7lnoiBTpA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiao Rong from Sichuan makes enameled wire in a small workshop Work&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/ecM1mf66ENbdCdCEaDuhtwKJDOTDJOkVSnUnPbcm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ ecM1mf66ENbdCdCEaDuhtwKJDOTDJOkVSnUnPbcm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiao Zhou and Xiao Lin from Anhui are sealing plastic bags&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /GXa36oex5baZe2bcfOjyi0ttnXknSJcPmEwqLQYb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GXa36oex5baZe2bcfOjyi0ttnXknSJcPmEwq LQYb.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;255427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The young women in the workshop dress up carefully and prepare for a date&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Wang Shijie/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国产科幻剧，走向成熟的一次试错]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259515]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&quot;Mist Theater&quot; under iQiyi, Because it has produced a number of high-quality suspense dramas, it is highly praised by drama fans. Although there are occasional mistakes, the black texture and suspense atmosphere are in place, so that the series overall remains above the passing line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the new work &quot;The Bionic World&quot; launched by this column has attracted a lot of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd58ebed2554817389f53751808c24f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1919&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd58ebed2554817389f53751808c24f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Bionic World&quot; &quot;The behind-the-scenes team is not bad. Chief director Chen Zhengdao has been quite active in recent years, and has directed film and television dramas with good reputations such as &quot;Love Is Delicious&quot; and &quot;Future Summer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/471722ecbc53445f4d068223ecef7c21.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1573&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/471722ecbc53445f4d068223ecef7c21.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other two Directors - Ke Zhennian and Xu Zhaoren, also have excellent works. The former&#39;s &quot;Silence&quot; directed in 2020 is a topical work focusing on the sexual assault of disabled people; the latter&#39;s &quot;Lifetime&quot; directed by Douban has a score of 8.9 , drama fans rushed to get into the trap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Weilong&#39;s good looks and Wen Qi&#39;s smart temperament also make &quot;The Bionic World&quot; look good. Coupled with the blessings of Liu Lin, Liu Dan and other veteran actors in the industry, it is difficult to let People believe that this drama will be so popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Bionic World&quot; is a science fiction theme. The background of the story is explained at the beginning of the series. In the near future, humans will make rapid progress in gene editing technology and create bionic people that are almost the same as humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/931322c2cf6df05f504e735eb747e9a4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;510&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/931322c2cf6df05f504e735eb747e9a4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only difference The reason is that the bionic person is implanted with an &quot;initial obsession&quot;, either to become a lover until death, or to become an obedient and sensible child. Only through special medicine can the unique eyes of the android be tested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3aef049b4f80dd281e3d9ab1d640eef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3aef049b4f80dd281e3d9ab1d640eef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255887&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bionic human The large-scale appearance triggered a series of extreme events, forcing countries to change their strategies and recall the androids for processing. The only one with the ability to investigate and identify the identities of androids is the &quot;Bright Eyes&quot; organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main content of the series tells the story of the male protagonist Cheng Nuo, played by Song Weilong, who, as an investigator with &quot;Bright Eyes&quot;, continues to detect criminal cases related to androids. As a result, the series uses six unit stories to present the joys and sorrows between androids and ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d18b765ab70f48cab8152caa9e825840.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d18b765ab70f48cab8152caa9e825840.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255886&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In narrative mode In terms of gameplay, it is similar to &quot;Crime Hunting Illustrated Book&quot; and &quot;Gate of Rebirth&quot;, using the protagonist&#39;s special skills to connect one strange case after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The undercurrent of the series is that androids encounter serial murders. During the investigation, Cheng Nuo also discovered that the case was related to his mother&#39;s accidental fall from the building, thus uncovering a shocking secret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simply speaking from the human tragedy reflected in each case, &quot;The Bionic World&quot; is remarkable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7928f4ed33e730c2e4fb5ca03e72b3c6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7928f4ed33e730c2e4fb5ca03e72b3c6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255885&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Played by Liu Lin Chen Xinhui, the mother of Chen Xinhui, lacked company for her son Fang Yuan, so she ordered a bionic person who looked exactly like herself to take care of her son when she was busy at work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I didn’t expect was that Chen Xinhui’s harsh attitude toward Fang Yuan was seen as malicious harm in the eyes of the androids. The latter began to deliberately imitate Chen Xinhui&#39;s speech and behavior, and eventually replaced Chen Xinhui and even imprisoned her in the basement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ed9902970e8c08b7afc15da444992380.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ed9902970e8c08b7afc15da444992380.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An accident, Chen Xinhui escaped from the basement and wanted to take her son back from the android, but she died at the hands of the android during the fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Yuan, who had been kept in the dark, finally realized that his mother, whose temperament had changed drastically, turned out to be a bionic person. In order not to lose this &quot;other mother&quot;, Fang Yuan asked Cheng Nuo and others He lied that he accidentally killed someone and the victim was an android. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paradoxical case at the beginning of the chapter depicts Chen Xinhui&#39;s helplessness and desolation as a mother, Fang Yuan&#39;s struggle and loneliness as a son, and the kindness and extreme of the android as the middleman, all of which are tragic and moving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7198c3c26c616e055741ff27eb2369a6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;463&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7198c3c26c616e055741ff27eb2369a6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255888&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Lin is here This person plays two roles without being overstretched. She skillfully grasps Chen Xinhui&#39;s psychological changes of being cold and then angry, and the personality differences of the android who is first calm and then crazy. Although her appearance is short, she leaves a deep impression on people. impression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emotional touch brought by this unit story is also reflected in the touching family bond between the bionic little girl and her adoptive parents, and also in the sweet romance between the lonely sailor and the bionic lover, but in the end In a story that ends in tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/2c9a2a556aeba45da6db1641c5f1b996.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/2c9a2a556aeba45da6db1641c5f1b996.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255889&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course it is Domestic dramas are good at producing many popular dramas. It&#39;s just that &quot;The Bionic World&quot; only focused on forcing tears, forgetting to solidify the foundation of the science fiction setting, and also went out of its way to foreshadow suspense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a science fiction drama, in addition to the future background explained in the beginning, the persuasive style of the main film is close to that of modern urban crime dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting place inside the &quot;Bright Eyes&quot; organization is like a simply decorated office; the crime scene outside the city looks like a shanty town waiting to be demolished. It may seem excessive to use the &quot;cyberpunk&quot; style of &quot;Blade Runner&quot; to ask for it, but using slightly softer science fiction dramas such as &quot;Relative Universe&quot; and &quot;The Handmaid&#39;s Tale&quot; as comparison objects can fully highlight this The show&#39;s perfunctory attitude in setting up scenes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7a42a0253179c920aab4f67ca67eafab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7a42a0253179c920aab4f67ca67eafab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255891&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you zoom in to As for the details of the science fiction setting, &quot;The Bionic World&quot; also has many flaws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie &quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot; with a similar setting, we glimpsed the tragic experience of robots through Spielberg&#39;s lens. Discarded after use, they are slandered as murderers, treated as garbage, and put on the execution ground for humans to vent their hatred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Bionic World&quot; explains the smuggling activities in a few words, and in less than ten minutes of transition, it hints that ordinary people consume the flesh and blood of bionic people. But these pitiful black corners are mostly vague and obscure, unable to provide us with a clear perspective on the unknown world of bionic people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/0640ad6575323f3b716e67858042940f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/0640ad6575323f3b716e67858042940f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255892&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you look If you don&#39;t understand the suffering of a group of people, how can you fully sympathize with and treat each other with compassion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it bluntly, the science fiction setting is just a certain strategy of &quot;The Bionic World&quot;. It uses elements that are extremely rare in domestic dramas to try to explore the human nature motif that has been repeated many times. This also explains that this drama is not only inconsistent in terms of science fiction, but also extremely difficult to grip people&#39;s hearts in the suspense section. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine An Qiu, played by Cheng Nuo and Wen Qi, investigates the serial murderer of androids. During this process, Cheng Nuo gradually discovered An Qiu&#39;s true identity, and the latter was gradually lost under the brainwashing of similar androids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/9fa39f3949d4688ae37ac9e055c55bbb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/9fa39f3949d4688ae37ac9e055c55bbb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255893&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Nuocong An investigator who was prejudiced and jealous of androids finally revealed his true colors and turned into a gray figure who had accidentally killed androids. We can hardly see the changes in his personality and the contrast between before and after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Song Weilong&#39;s slightly immature acting skills prevent him from grasping the details delicately; on the other hand, there are problems with the plot setting. The arrangement and revelation of suspense rely too much on the villain Yin Tianhong played by Li Hongqi in the climax. Part of it is talking to myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for An Qiu&#39;s transformation from a seemingly ordinary psychologist to the most critical role in the whole drama, it was also revealed too early and too hastily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd4d7660d48d6afe60bd8f86db16bc4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd4d7660d48d6afe60bd8f86db16bc4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sixth At the end of the episode, which is also the middle part of the whole drama, we learned the answer to the mystery from the rivalry between An Qiu and Yin Tianhong. Even in many scenes before this, An Qiu&#39;s true identity was clumsily revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You must know that the two biggest mysteries in &quot;The Bionic World&quot; are that Cheng Nuo accidentally killed someone and An Qiunai is a bionic human. These two mysteries involve the emotional tearing of the male and female protagonists, and also reflect the subtle complexity of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ed929dc9f100b6aa2d32f0b58009de0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ed929dc9f100b6aa2d32f0b58009de0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the final Judging from the presentation effect, the reconciliation between Cheng Nuo and An Qiu is more like a &quot;love trick&quot; without the profound speculation brought by science fiction settings such as bionic man and initial obsession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The science fiction works of domestic film and television dramas have begun to show their talents. Whether it is the movie &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot; series or the live-action series &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, they are all outstanding works recognized by the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quality of &quot;The Bionic World&quot; is indeed poor, but I prefer to regard it as a trial and error for domestic science fiction dramas to mature. After all, without enough &quot;The Bionic World&quot;, how could there be more mature &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot; and &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小镇阿姨们想象着法国织的毛线比基尼，真的到了法国]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259464]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIygYcmW1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIyg YcmW1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255441&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 2023, Hu Yinping went to Paris to participate in the Paris Internationale Art Fair (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;International Paris Art Fair &lt;/span>;), this is her third exhibition in France for Xiaofang’s art project. The piece she brought this time was a knitted woolen bikini, which came from the aunties in the small town in Sichuan where she grew up. Since 2015, Hu Yinping has been customizing wool fabric products from her mother and aunts in her hometown in the name of the fictional French company agent &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;. Nowadays, the aunts imagine a woolen bikini woven from an ocean in France, and finally arrived in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this small Sichuan town, the &quot;French company&quot; is the source of imagination for the aunts. They selected their own yarn at the Xiaofang base, mostly green, and initially knitted hats of various shapes. They appeared in the exhibition hall on the Champs Elysées, at the anti-Trump parade in the United States, and at Ireland&#39;s &quot;Cuckold Festival&quot;... …Later, the fabrics became more and more diverse: “Dirty Word Shock Wave” (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;weaves out the curse words that want to scold bad people&lt;/span>;), Pork Shop Aunt The &quot;pig intestines&quot; weaved by each family, the flags of their respective families, and the &quot;banana peels&quot;, &quot;dogs&quot;, and &quot;cactus&quot; weaved to protect the family in the face of danger... In between the busy farming and taking care of the children , these aunts weave their understanding of life with wool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255437&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Snow White Dove&quot; Paris Bikini Exhibition&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &quot;Stop it when it&#39;s good.&quot; In 2016, after Hu Yinping completed the first hat exhibition of Xiaofang&#39;s art project at Beijing Arrow Factory Space, a friend advised her because she was worried that the project would lose money. Hu Yinping graduated from the Sculpture Department of the Central Academy of Fine Arts with a master&#39;s degree. She used the income from sculptures sold as &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; as a commercial sculpture artist to subsidize Xiaofang&#39;s production. The original reason for all this was that she wanted to collect her mother&#39;s time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Hu Yinping returned to her hometown in Sichuan and saw that her mother was packed up by two large bags of hats in a year and purchased at a low price. She wanted to buy her mother&#39;s hat, but her mother refused. After returning to Beijing, she asked a friend to play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; and made up the identity of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; as &quot;the Chinese CEO of a French company&quot;. &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; would come forward to buy her mother&#39;s hat at a higher price. She knitted hats as she pleased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are no secrets in the town. The aunts in the town found Hu Yinping&#39;s mother and wanted to join the production of Xiaofang&#39;s project. In the 1990s, silk cutting was once a way for aunts in the town to make money to support their families. After experiencing collective layoffs from state-owned silk cutting factories, most of these aunts became the eliminated urban surplus labor force. Now knitting wool is a way for them to pass the time and earn pocket money. The way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now the Xiaofang project has expanded to more than fifty knitting aunts, including &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, &quot;Snow White Pigeon&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;, &quot;United Nations&quot; and &quot;Standard Configuration&quot; and other five stages of different years. Proposition creation. Behind the creation lies the complex work of the artist. In sharp contrast to the work utopia created by Hu Yinping, is the cruel art market with clearly marked prices that artists face. Until now, the aunts still don’t know the origin of this “French company”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Yinping&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Hu Yinping&#39;s account: &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The aunt is very happy, the artist is very tired&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will be happier every time I go to Paris to organize an exhibition. Because Xiaofang’s project itself has something to do with France. Every time we have a project, we tell the aunties that the French company needs orders, invite the aunties to make it, and then pay the corresponding fees. This French company has always existed in the hearts of the aunties. At the beginning of production, we told our aunts that there was a beach in France and we were going to do a woolen bikini show on the beach. They imagined a beach and made a set of woolen bikinis for themselves and their families. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang has a lot of such exchanges and work internationally. This French exhibition is aimed at There are more professional art professionals, corresponding to a large number of curators and museum directors. I also hope that Xiaofang will enter into a deeper and more international exchange and dialogue. To the public, Xiaofang may be a relatively warm story, but to me it is a very specific work. Behind Auntie, our entire team works very rigorously and professionally. Everyone can enter and understand this work in any way of their own, but it itself is the background of contemporary art works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The knitted works of the aunts are all placed in my warehouse in a village near Beijing. Aunts are very happy, but artists have a harder time. Xiaofang&#39;s team of six people needs to handle a lot of specific and trivial tasks. The aunties don&#39;t care. The time for their weaving is not fixed. They choose the threads and take them home to make them, and get some fees from it, whether it is to make money, kill time, or the so-called &quot;thinking&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before I called you just now, I was in contact with the art museum about the transportation and goods for this exhibition. Shan, to integrate all the work of Auntie, we need to do some very specific and serious work. In fact, the workload is quite heavy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For Xiaofang&#39;s project, there are too many times when the economy cannot sustain it. Yang Xiaofang spends every year It costs a lot of money, and I rely on selling sculptures of &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; to support Xiaofang, but last year it started to feel a bit flat. After Xiaofang had an exhibition in Shanghai last year, many people may have known more about Xiaofang. Last year, she actually made a profit of 800 yuan. If it could recycle itself, there would be no need to raise it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now Xiaofang’s new project is to open Xiaofang Bank in a shopping mall in Nanjing. Xiaofang&#39;s works themselves are extremely public. In addition to the dialogue in exhibitions in art museums and galleries, what feedback and possibilities it has when facing the real public is extremely important to us. Because the crowds faced by art museums and galleries are actually screened, but in shopping malls they face the real public and reality, without the protection of an incubator. The concept of this bank is that I hope that the banks of the future will be made of wool, I hope that the currency of the future will also be made of wool, and I hope that the weapons of the future will also be made of wool. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before the 1990s, the entire society was lacking in materials, and wool, as a craft of aunts, could make people The family was fed and clothed, and now the value of the wool had changed. Why are there so many people knitting now? When I held an exhibition in Shanghai last year, some people told me that they would do a lot of knitting during the epidemic. Small fabrics can actually bring you a lot of surprises and feedback, because handiwork itself has healing properties. What you exchange for time is a thing, which is an exchange of the most primitive labor force. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s exhibition, I met a girl who imagined her belly when she was pregnant Knitting shoes and clothes for children. I met a diplomat in China who was making some woolen fabrics during the COVID-19 pandemic. She thought she had made an ugly mouse and an ugly little snake. When this silver-haired lady talked about her fabrics, she was as shy as a little girl. I like these things she made so much. , and can feel the warmth and healing in her heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang’s hat has a lifetime warranty. I don’t want it to break after I buy it back. hole, you just throw it away, which is a pity for manual labor. No matter what projects Xiaofang does in the future, it will always include the function of &quot;filling holes&quot;. We will also open hole-filling to the surrounding communities for free, hoping to form this kind of community. It’s not that we throw something away when it’s a little bit broken. I think we all do too much about abandonment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 510&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Auntie knitting bikini&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Surplus labor force in the city, remaining time in the town&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In order to protect my eyesight, most of the wool I gave to my mother was is green. Because green hats don’t have a good connotation in the Chinese context, the aunts still had some doubts when they used green wool to knit various hats. Later, VICE (a new media in the United States) wanted to do an interview for Xiaofang&#39;s art project, and helped find a place to buy cuckolds - St. Patrick&#39;s Day in Ireland. The traditional color of this holiday is green, and ordered a lot of cuckolds for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Ireland, these people wear hats to participate in festival gatherings, and the aunties also see those live photos. very happy. The same thing may have completely different meanings in different cultural backgrounds. I also hope to help aunties realize that the world is very rich. But I think it is more important for them to be happy and make free choices. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I returned to my hometown in 2015 and was timid about being close to my hometown. Because I don’t go home very often, I want to know what my mother does on a daily basis. When she placed two large packages of hand-knitted hats in front of me, I realized, oh, she had knitted these two large packages this year and had been purchased by others at a low price. Moreover, the raw materials are too hard on the hands, and the threads are very hard and extremely rough. She doesn&#39;t have the pleasure and happiness of knitting. She just kills time, and this is the only reason left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think it’s better to collect it myself, but my mother won’t let me, so I invite friends Help me play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; of the French company, ask her to make hats, and let her do whatever she wants. In 2015, WeChat was not so popular, and my mother did not have access to WeChat in her hometown. However, because she had to work with &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, WeChat became a work skill that she must master. Because of her work, she learned to surf the Internet and send express delivery. In the past, my father&#39;s name was written on the express delivery because of &quot;Xiaofang&quot;. Later, when she sent express delivery, she always wrote her own name on the express delivery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, we have conducted research on the aunts who participated in the Xiaofang project. Almost all of them are eliminated urban surplus laborers. Women who work in cities are easily eliminated after the age of 55. Work as a delivery person or cleaner in the city. After a certain age, even if you are a nanny with many years of experience, it may be extremely difficult to find a job in a big city after the age of 55. This is the problem faced by these aunts in the process of urbanization. It is very common in the town for aunts who are almost in their fifties to return to their hometowns because they cannot find jobs. They take care of their children. Those with better financial conditions open small shops and knit with wool to earn pocket money in their free time. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the appearance of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;, the aunts have stopped knitting things for other places. In fact, the aunts all have their own jobs and things. Some aunts will definitely not be able to take care of making our things when the farming is busy. They only plant rice and harvest several times a year, with long idle time in between. Some aunts take care of their children at home. After school is free time. There are also some aunts who have their own small shops. When there is no business, she can do Xiaofang&#39;s business. Xiaofang actually fills up the remaining time of the aunts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s third stage &quot;Security&quot;, the aunt at the pork shop first imagined Not sure what to knit. We would guide her step by step. When she was at her busiest, Xiaofang called her and said, &quot;If someone were to rob your pork shop at this moment, what kind of weapons would you use to protect yourself and yourself?&quot; Benefits?&quot; She was holding a large intestine in her hand and said that if he tried to rob me, I would throw the intestine to him. This is a very direct reaction. When she is not busy, we will repeat her own words to her and encourage her to knit this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;About Xiaofang, everyone is discussing the aunt&#39;s imagination, which is actually the artist&#39;s imagination supporting their work. Aunts are a group without imagination, but they can be guided. All they have to do is face their true selves and their own lives. I actually know what they are doing every time, but I am still surprised when I see what comes out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, Xiaofang sent me those hat packages made by my mother on weekends. I was very surprised every time I opened the package. This kind of surprise has never happened again. As I was very familiar with my mother, I suddenly discovered that she had a skill that I didn&#39;t know about. I knew that she had always been making hats, but I didn&#39;t know her. It was all fancy and messy and made so many fun things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The aunts still don’t know what’s going on behind Xiaofang. In fact, it’s not that clear whether they know or not. It&#39;s important because they don&#39;t care about it that much, but I don&#39;t want my mother to know. Some time ago, my mother went to Beijing and stayed for nearly two months. We emptied the entire studio of fabrics, leaving not a single yarn. My mother couldn&#39;t stay after playing for a week, so I asked &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; to come to the studio to give her some work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Actually, on my mother&#39;s side, I haven&#39;t given her too many themes. What I collected is not Representational fabrics, or requiring her to use her brain, did not require her to do so. I wish to collect a period of my mother&#39;s life. I want her to be more free and not want her daughter&#39;s business to become her business, which would be too tiring for her. It&#39;s good for her to live for herself. At this age, she should live for herself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;Frozen time, undulating waves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 1990s, my mother and the aunts in the town were Work in the town&#39;s silk-cutting factory. But China&#39;s textile industry also underwent a major reshuffle in the 1990s. At that time, a large number of laid-off workers were formed, including my mother and aunts. Silk cutting means that after the cocoons are cooked in a high-temperature machine, the silk is separated one by one, and the eight silks are wound into a thread. The finished silk is finally shipped to other places. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The machines in the factory are always rotating at a constant speed, and people are changing. My mother is on this assembly line. Go to work. My childhood was spent sitting on the big machine in that factory. The aunts would change jobs. One would feed me a bite when eating, and the other would feed me a bite when eating. My entire childhood to elementary school was spent in that atmosphere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That kind of familiarity between people and people is very good, and it is a very important memory for me , later Xiaofang had so many aunts involved, and I felt the familiar intimacy that I felt at that time. When I was a child, my mother’s workplace would give out various benefits, such as a thermos cup and some washing powder. I think this is very good and will make family members have a sense of recognition for her work. We keep this in Xiaofang. got this. In the past few years, we have distributed almost everything to aunties, from cups to fruits, washing powder, pots and pans to all small household appliances. Recently, because winter is coming, we have I bought a lot of quilts for my aunt, and now I don’t know what to give them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I held Xiaofang’s exhibition at Arrow Factory Space for the first time, my friend advised me to “see you soon.” Just take it.&quot; This suggestion is very sincere. As a friend, I advise me to stop the loss in time. But to me, this is not a work. To me, Xiaofang is a very real life scene between me and my mother, so it is not something that I can just accept, even though I know it will lose money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, we all knitted them casually, and I worked hard to collect them. Later I found out that this was wrong. No matter how big a warehouse I rented, it wouldn’t be enough for these dozens of aunts to weave. If they make it, you have to pay. After paying, you have to help them sell the fabrics. Selling requires talent, and I don’t have it. With this talent, how many hats can several art museums sell? This is so cruel. We mainly work in the studio and rarely understand the operating rules of this world economy. In the process of Xiaofang, it was also interesting that we participated in this kind of work very realistically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang&#39;s work is still a very important part of my life. Because actually, for an artist, ten years can produce a lot of works. But Xiaofang and I have a growing relationship together. Xiaofang is implanted into my aunt&#39;s life, and at the same time, she is implanted into my mother&#39;s life and my life. I have also calculated an account. For example, if I make other things, I will also pay the money to the factory and the production unit. But when I pay the aunt, it does not actually form an internal cycle of the art system. Investing this part of the expenses on my aunt, I think, is investing on my own people, which makes me happier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Next month we will go to Mexico to set up an exhibition. Xiaofang has achieved so far, and there are so many reactions from the audience. Some people like it, and some don&#39;t. I&#39;ve used that metaphor from the beginning to now, I&#39;m a toothpick and I&#39;m also an observer. The aunties are jellyfish. I poked the jellyfish with a toothpick, and the jellyfish swayed in different postures in the sea. Whether it is criticism, praise, interviews or exhibitions, they are all part of the butterfly effect in the sea. My job is to watch these reactions and their postures after taking the plunge. Regardless of the posture of the jellyfish or the waves and waves produced in the sea, in my opinion, it is an extremely beautiful thing because it reacts. , rather than something inherently conservative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the future, I hope that many people will show me her works like the diplomat stationed in China. . I hope everyone will not be shy and face themselves bravely. There is really no ugliness in handmade things, they are all extremely high-quality. I want to redefine wool, I want to redefine Xiaofang’s cultural attributes. I am mainly doing this kind of work now, and I am continuing to advance it. In fact, artists work quietly in the audience most of the time. As for being seen or not being seen, what kind of reactions and discussions are caused are all external matters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sichuan is a basin. There is a river over there in our town, which is similar to all small towns in China. The same, a very solid group of people, a very solid time. There are only a few people in the town, but the aunts imagine a French company to do such a thing. I think this thing itself is quite cool. There are a group of aunts in that basin who are thinking about things all day long, and then go about their work in a serious manner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违反一事不能二罚？TST庭秘密何以“脱罪”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259519]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/29/CYLszOgZEkf9sfTtZJimAURqgDipmPMe5iWOlRwx.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/29/CYLszOgZEkf9sfTtZJimAURqgDipmPMe5iWOlRwx.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255901&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2021, Zhang Ting and Lin Ruiyang attended the event . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(TST Secret official Weibo screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, TST Secret’s headquarters in Shanghai came A group of people, they are agents from Malaysia and Singapore, &quot;We are finally back,&quot; someone announced excitedly on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as early as August 24, &quot;Big Brother&quot; Lin Ruiyang recorded a video announcing that &quot;our case has finally been concluded, and it is a very positive conclusion.&quot; He raised his voice and was a little excited. , &quot;After the case is closed, I believe more people will think that they are such a good company.&quot; He is sorry that everyone has been wronged in the past two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until October 26, the &quot;Legal Weekend&quot; sponsored by the &quot;Legal Daily&quot;, the organ of the Political and Legal Affairs Commission of the CPC Central Committee, reported that the Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Court had made a civil ruling and announced the unfreezing of 96 properties under their names and 600 million yuan in cash, this news became widely known, and then the video that Lin Ruiyang posted on Xiaohongshu two months ago became a hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the civil ruling obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, these 96 properties are located at No. 28 Jiangyao Road, Pudong New District, Shanghai, the secret headquarters of Jiting. According to public information from the Shanghai Housing Administration, they spent 1.76 billion yuan to purchase it in 2020, which was the fourth anniversary of TST&#39;s establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Ruiyang was a Taiwanese artist, and later co-founded the micro-business beauty brand TST Ting Mi with his wife Zhang Ting. This brand has been questioned by suspected pyramid schemes in the past. Until April 2021, Shijiazhuang Yuhua The District Market Supervision and Administration Bureau applied to the court to freeze the huge property of a secretly affiliated company of the TST Tribunal on the grounds of suspected pyramid schemes. Only then did the outside world confirm that it was under investigation for suspected pyramid schemes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Right now, from the perspective of the secret side of the TST court, the outcome of the case has vindicated it. So, is it suspected of being a pyramid scheme? Why did the court unfreeze their property? Multiple documents obtained by Southern Weekend reporters provide the answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is indeed a pyramid scheme&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Is there a pyramid scheme in TST Court Secret? The answer is yes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An administrative penalty decision from the Baokang County Market Supervision and Administration Bureau of Hubei Province gave a clear answer: &quot;The Baokang County Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that... the bonuses implemented by the parties for red card members The system requires the person being developed to develop other personnel to join, form an upline and downline relationship, and calculate and pay upline remuneration based on the sales performance of the downline, which belongs to the following behaviors in Article 7, Item (3) of the &quot;Prohibition of Pyramid Selling Regulations&quot;, and is MLM behavior&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person involved here is Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd., the owner of the TST secret brand, and its legal representative is Lin Jirong. This is the real name of &quot;eldest brother&quot; Lin Ruiyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The signing date of this administrative penalty letter is September 3, 2021. That is, as early as two years ago, TST Court Secret had been identified as a pyramid scheme and was punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant national laws and regulations, pyramid schemes are divided into two situations, one is operational pyramid schemes and the other is fraudulent pyramid schemes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Operational pyramid schemes are subject to administrative penalties by the market supervision department in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Prohibition of MLM.&quot; It is only an illegal act. If there is no penalty of revoking the business license, you can continue to operate after accepting the administrative penalties and making rectifications and compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fraudulent pyramid schemes are a serious crime, which falls under the criminal law of organizing and leading pyramid schemes and must be prosecuted by the procuratorate. The main difference between the two is whether there are actual business activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This administrative penalty letter shows that the TST Tribunal secretly belongs to a commercial pyramid scheme. The pyramid schemes identified occurred in Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd. from January 1, 2018 to July 2021, and the illegal gains were confiscated. And impose fines and require &quot;correction within a time limit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, you can continue to operate after making changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2022, the TST Tribunal secretly submitted an &quot;Application for Guidance and Evaluation on the Rectification of the Product Sales System of Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd.&quot; to the Baokang County Market Supervision and Administration Bureau. It listed its rectification measures in detail and believed that &quot;the rectified product sales system is completely in line with normal business practices. There is no bonus method based on team salary, and it should not fall within the prohibited situations stipulated in the &quot;Prohibition of Pyramid Selling Regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters compared the two bonus systems before and after the rectification, the April 2021 version and the February 2022 version, and found that the biggest difference is that there is no team salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bonuses are divided into three parts: one is the sales discount bonus, the other is the batch difference bonus, and the third is the self-media education promotion bonus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the name of the form. It used to be called &quot;Ting Secret Dealer Bonus System-Red Card&quot;, but was later changed to &quot;Ting Live Member Discount Table&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sales discount bonus is mapped to the new table and becomes a &quot;discount&quot;. The difference is not big. This part is a commission for personal performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest change is the discount difference, which is the past &quot;lot-to-retail bonus&quot;. This part is the commission for the team&#39;s performance. For example, the team sold a total of 10,000 yuan, of which 2,000 yuan was sold by the team leader himself. This part is commissioned based on personal performance. The remaining 8,000 yuan must be distributed with subordinates according to a certain proportion. This part is the team salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new rule after the rectification is that &quot;the difference between the sales discounts corresponding to members and their direct members will be accumulated in the form of points or vouchers on the platform or system. The company will ultimately formulate redemption rules and redeem products within a certain period of time. Or deduct the purchase amount (ranging from 2% to 24%).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;self-media education promotion bonus&quot; that used to be extracted in proportion to the team&#39;s performance has now become a &quot;promotion service fee.&quot; The promotion service fee has added conditions for receiving it, requiring that &quot;the member&#39;s own live broadcast product performance is greater than 0 &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the proportion of promotion service fees calculated based on team performance was between 4% and 5%, but now it is unified at 3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After rectification, Tingmi believes that “Tingmi’s sales performance commissions are only generated for directly related superior members, and they are all one-time rewards and are not passed on.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This rectification report also received a reply from the local regulatory authorities, stating that &quot;our bureau will organize relevant personnel to conduct research in a timely manner.&quot; After that, TST Court Secrets has been operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;One thing cannot be punished twice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because Baokang County, Hubei Province has secretly conducted an investigation into the TST Court on May 25, 2021. This made the Market Supervision Bureau of Yuhua District, Baoding City, Hebei Province, which only opened the case for investigation on June 5, 2021, passive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Administrative Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; has clear provisions, firstly, &quot;prior jurisdiction&quot;, and secondly, &quot;no penalty whatsoever&quot;. At the same time, the &quot;State Administration for Industry and Commerce on Further Improving the Investigation and Punishment of Online MLMs The Notice also clarifies the jurisdiction of online pyramid schemes cases, and the competent authority shall apply the principle of full jurisdiction over the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, who has jurisdiction is the first issue that the two market regulatory authorities must resolve. Judging from subsequent developments, Baokang County, Hubei Province did not give up its jurisdiction and imposed penalties four months after the case was filed. The secret rectification of the TST Tribunal was also completed in February 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What really attracted widespread attention to this case was that on December 23, 2021, the Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau announced in a reply to an inquiry letter that “because of its use of financial institutions to transfer or conceal the relevant To transfer the funds, our bureau has applied to the People’s Court to take preservation measures in accordance with the law.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, this application was supported by the Yuhua District Court, which froze 96 properties and 600 million yuan in cash secretly owned by the TST Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This court ruling freezing property has been questioned by the industry. Yang Fan, the attorney representing the case, said on social media, &quot;How can the Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau&#39;s application for court preservation be a civil ruling? The Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau has not made any administrative decision in the past year. How can it be in the administrative agency? Are you going to apply for court preservation while the case is being investigated?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Bing, another attorney in the case and professor of administrative law, also publicly questioned on social media, &quot;Is this a civil pre-litigation preservation or a litigation preservation? The first preservation period was only 30 days, and litigation preservation was even more impossible. No one sued at that time or now, and it is impossible for the Market Supervision Bureau to be the plaintiff.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau stated in an interview with Upstream News that it had set up a task force and more than 400 law enforcement officers participated in the investigation. &quot;Currently, it appears to be a commercial pyramid scheme. Whether it has the characteristics of a fraudulent pyramid scheme is still under investigation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until July 26, 2023, the People’s Court of Yuhua District, Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province issued a civil ruling: “County and municipal-level industrial and commercial and market supervision departments should investigate and handle online pyramid schemes cases before filing or filing a case. At the same time, it was reported to the provincial industrial and commercial and market supervision departments step by step. Now that the report has been revoked, the conditions for this court to continue to implement preservation measures on the suspected online pyramid schemes assets in this case are no longer met.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An insider involved in this case interpreted this paragraph of text to Southern Weekend reporter. He said, &quot;The word &quot;revoke&quot; is used here instead of withdrawn, which means that the filing may have been revoked by the superior department rather than withdrawn. Yuhua District Municipal Supervision Bureau proactively withdrew the report. After withdrawing the filing, we cannot rule out the possibility that the case will be withdrawn in the future.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of this person familiar with the matter, in accordance with the principle of &quot;nothing is dismissed&quot; in the &quot;Administrative Penalty Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, if the Yuhua District Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that Baokang County has taken effect in the administrative decision If the illegal gains are incorrect, it involves the correction of administrative actions and must be submitted to the competent authority for cancellation in accordance with legal procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the administrative penalty letter of Baokang County gives the secret and true business data of TST Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The penalty letter shows: From January 1, 2018 to July 2021, TST secretly developed a total of about 7 million members, including about 6.41 million blue card members and about 650,000 red card members. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main business income of the illegal red card is approximately 9.17 billion yuan, the main business cost is approximately 5.64 billion yuan, the main business taxes and surcharges are approximately 37.44 million yuan, and the actual related expenses incurred are approximately 3.458 billion yuan. billion, income tax expenses were 10.46 million yuan, and profits were approximately 19.27 million yuan. The profits of Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd. should be considered illegal gains. The final penalty was the confiscation of illegal gains of 19.27 million yuan and a fine of 1.7 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd. was on the top 100 companies in Qingpu District, Shanghai was in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, due to the leakage of relevant replies from the Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau, both Zhang Ting and Lin Ruiyang were banned on Weibo because of their involvement in pyramid schemes. As of May 26, 2022, Zhang The court&#39;s Weibo was updated again, stating that &quot;Dalway Company encountered legal disputes and sought legal protection, which fully proves that Dalwe Company respects and believes in the legal environment of the motherland.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[奥纳·泰德斯：从朋克主唱到新晋画家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/M5PEK9Zqmrdwlpq3WJEolkTcZ4PVGsv33dwOWYW8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/M5PEK9Zqmrdwlpq3WJEolkTcZ4PVGsv 33dwOWYW8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (artist and Taylor Gallery Gia Coppola/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before becoming a painter, Honor Titus was the lead singer of a punk band; before becoming the lead singer of a punk band, he was a writer Also a poet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This path may be reversed and said again: because Ona Titus is a writer and poet, and his friend asked him: Hey, you write poetry anyway, why don’t you just write lyrics for us? ? As a result, he became a member of the punk band Cerebral Ballzy. Then, as the band became an instant hit, well-known artist Raymond Pettibon became a fan and designed the cover of one of their albums. Raymond asked Ona: Hey, I like your song, why don&#39;t you come to my studio and help? So Ona became Raymond&#39;s assistant. After familiarizing himself with all the operations of the art studio, he picked up the paintbrush himself and once again became an instant hit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/wRIs9h63HVnEDSnKteQlhyBXor9w2yLe8a6Xcn2O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/wRIs9h63HVnEDSnKteQlhyBXor9w2yLe8a6Xcn2O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ona Titus: Viewing Distance&quot; exhibition view, 2023, Longlati Jingwei Art Center, Shanghai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Longlati Jingwei Art Center/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Asia is Exciting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;No matter which order you listen to this story, Ona is undoubtedly an enviable lucky person. Almost as soon as he painted his first decent work, he was spotted by Taylor Gallery and brought to New York to exhibit. His paintings were hung side by side with the works of the famous Alex Katz. together. The response from the market is also exciting. Although he is just starting out and does not have any transaction records to back him up, more than 20 important collectors have expressed their intention to buy this painting. He also saw similarities in his paintings and Katz&#39;s paintings: bright colors, simple outlines, flat brushstrokes. &quot;Seeing them hang me and Katz together, I realized that people are Understand my creation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is indeed an eye-catching work: a man and a woman are resting in a leisurely manner on the grass covered with petals. The woman has her back to the picture and cannot see clearly. On the face, the man is like a southern yuppie, wearing a suit and a Panama hat, lying on his back. The whole picture is filled with a kind of nostalgic leisure, which is reminiscent of Seurat&#39;s &quot;Sunday Afternoon on the Island of La Grande Jatte&quot; and Manet&#39;s &quot; Lunch on the Grass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gaYOgkQcj7NCl425bcguB0rX24d8cbS2cSBmJoPX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gaYOgkQcj7NCl425bcguB0rX24d8cbS2cSBmJoPX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Kimbella&quot;, 2021, oil on canvas, 121.9cmx152.4cm Private collection, image courtesy of the artist and Taylor Gallery&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I try to write as I go This person, while listening to his song, was frightened by the deafening noise and turned off his headphones three minutes later. I realized that the Ona who painted the painting and the Ona who was the lead singer of the band may be different aspects of the same person. The calmness, alienation, and even classicalness revealed in his paintings are nowhere to be found in his punk music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ona&#39;s recent solo exhibition &quot;Viewing Distance&quot; at Longlati Jingwei Art Center in Shanghai is his first solo exhibition in China. Prior to this, he had just finished an exhibition at Gagosian, and Asia made him particularly excited. “I had a painting at auction two years ago, and it was finally sold for five times the estimate. The collector is from Asia. It makes me feel the acceptance of my works in the East, and I am also curious about how Chinese audiences will evaluate my paintings.&quot; His pictures can&#39;t help but be associated with the atmosphere of Impressionism, which may be due to the two-dimensional attribute - —In this matter, it was Japanese Ukiyo-e that profoundly influenced Impressionism, and Chinese ink painting that profoundly influenced Ukiyo-e—a hidden line of culture that makes it possible to see déjà vu in viewing, and also reminds this kind of viewing distance on. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Two noble men&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It was Raymond Pattybone who introduced him to the door of painting. For Ona, the few people who worked in Raymond’s studio were The year was a time of &quot;information explosion&quot; in his life. Raymond is a comprehensive artist. He was born in the United States in 1957. He is compatible with many iconic American cultural elements and is especially good at integrating images and text. Literature, art history, philosophy, religion, politics, business, fashion, sports, and deviant youth subculture are all sources of inspiration for Raymond. This complexity greatly influenced Ona. Raymond never taught him how to draw, but often discussed literature with him. &quot;Raymond had a library, almost a small library. He often pulled out classic novels and talked to me about the stories in them.&quot; William. · Blake, Proust, John Ruskin and Walt Whitman... Literary nature constitutes Raymond&#39;s visual rhetoric and also profoundly influenced Ona. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8uYgnmSlVfIHSOEOD2IM55hztNR7Kjo48EFaSRTk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;687&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8uYgnmSlVfIHSOEOD2IM55hztNR7Kjo48EFaSRTk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;AP&#39;s Joy&quot;, 2022, oil on canvas, 182.9cmx121.9cm Danjuma Collection, image courtesy of the artist and Taylor Gallery&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in Redmond The studio provided Ona with access to a large number of painting classics. He found that he was interested in the Nabi School of painting, including Pierre Bonnard. The style that emphasized outline and color and eliminated perspective naturally lowered the technical threshold and gave amateur painters a simple and straightforward stepping stone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another of Ona&#39;s great friends in painting was Henry Tylor, a famous artist who also lived in Los Angeles. Taylor is an expert at depicting characters, lively and productive. &quot;Some media previously described Henry Taylor as my mentor, but he was actually just a close friend of mine.&quot; Henry Taylor held an exhibition for Ona in his studio, which was Ona&#39;s first as an artist. appearance. At that time, the COVID-19 epidemic broke out in the United States. Hundreds of guests crowded into Henry&#39;s studio. The gallerist among the guests immediately decided to take Ona&#39;s works to New York. &quot;It was really a sensation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3spC5kJ7sm0AnHOTstxjpylLqCYuCEoK895VcZGC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;852&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3spC5kJ7sm0AnHOTstxjpylLqCYuCEoK895VcZGC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Into the Blue&quot;, 2021, oil on canvas, 214cmx183.5cm Collection of David and Indre Roberts. Image Courtesy of the artist and Taylor Gallery&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Novel Painting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Thanks to a writer’s eye, Ona is most interested in people. Every minute he spent on the streets of China, he was observing the crowds around him and learning to speak Chinese at every opportunity. He enjoys painting people, including people in motion, people feasting in fine clothes, and people living leisurely and alone. He fixes a certain moment of people in a specific situation, and that moment itself is narrative. When he wanders around art galleries, his eyes are always drawn to paintings about people, such as Hopper or Andy Warhol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from those artists who usually accumulate visual materials and are good at photography or sketching, Ona&#39;s pictures are novel-like. He likes to paint fictitious images in his mind rather than copying real moments in life. His inspiration often comes from music or literature. &quot;I did a painting of Miles Davis riding a horse, purely from my imagination.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v1ALTKi3JPH8Ma62koQLTw1QG3Ho1RuykZMp03mD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/18/v1ALTKi3JPH8Ma62koQLTw1QG3Ho1RuykZMp03mD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Summer at Dodger Hall, 2021 , oil on canvas, 152.4cmx182.9cm Collection of Rony &amp;amp; Orly Grushka, image courtesy of the artist and Taylor Gallery&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Legendary musician Miles Davis is an outstanding conductor and performer in the history of American jazz music family, but later fell into drug addiction and bankruptcy, struggling with difficulties. &quot;Miles grew up in the green countryside of St. Louis. He could ride horses as a child. Later he came to New York and entered the Juilliard School and experienced difficult times.&quot; Miles painted by Ona, Galloping horses in New York&#39;s Central Park was the image in his mind, and painting was to create images that might not exist but that the artist firmly believed existed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Ona, painting was an unexpected success, bringing him wealth and a completely different life experience, but it delayed his ideal of becoming a writer. Music, painting, reading, writing... He jumps between different fields like a grid-jumper, with a playful agility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else do you want to draw next?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I will write my novel within five years.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What kind of novel?&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&quot;By no means an autobiography, I hope it is the kind of novel that Fitzgerald and Salinger would write. When the time comes, I will write it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[特朗普用自己的音色讲普通话：AI正在取代配音、口译与英语老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259492]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My sister is a professional voice worker. She previously worked in a radio station for nearly thirty years as an announcer, Host and other jobs, now retired. It is difficult to define the concept of retirement for professional and technical personnel. They usually retire without rest: radio stations build training schools and ask her to teach broadcasting and hosting classes; relevant professional competitions ask her to be a judge and host programs; commercial organizations ask her to dub, Advertising... I used to be busy all day long, as fulfilling as working, and earning more than my pension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But now, I am basically retired, there are fewer and fewer jobs, and the remuneration for labor is getting lower and lower. In the past few years, the remuneration for each service was around 1,000-1,500 yuan, but later it dropped to 500, and then to 200-300 yuan each time. A few days ago, a shopping website asked: Do you want to accept product advertisements worth 20-30 yuan each? She felt exhausted both physically and mentally. This was really pointless. Forget it, she wouldn&#39;t steal the business of young girls and boys. She had a pension after all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I watched the recent AI dubbing and was deeply shocked. I told her: It’s not you taking away the business of young girls and boys, nor is it someone taking away your business. But under the attack of AI, you will basically all be unemployed. Fortunately, I still have a pension. What should those young people who have studied broadcasting for more than ten years do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current AI dubbing can achieve (on the algorithm side) intelligent translation and avoid nonsensical low-level errors; (on the audio side) simulate the timbre and voice of the object, and give it the personality characteristics of spoken language; (on the audio side) Video side) Correct the mouth shape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result is: Swift and Trump actually spoke in very standard Chinese, while Cai Ming’s skit was performed in English. And the timbre is very similar to their own, and even the Mandarin spoken by Trump can be set to Mandarin with a slight southern accent. Not only can the sound be real, but in terms of video, their mouth shapes are highly consistent with the language they speak. Only by observing very carefully can you find traces of video modification in very few links. Based on the current speed of AI development, perhaps in a year, this weak trace of modification will be difficult to detect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of intelligent translation, Call Annie, an intelligent interactive chat system based on ChatGPT launched by Animato, has been applied to Apple 12 and above platforms. As soon as it was launched, the stock price of Chegg, an American education platform, plummeted by 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Call Annie is not only a chat software, but also a fully AI education system. Currently, it can provide language services in English, French, German, Spanish and other major languages, and its teaching content covers professional knowledge in various disciplines such as mathematics, physics, chemistry, biology, programming, and finance. It can be expected that in the next 1-2 years, Call Annie is likely to develop to cover various human languages, including most minor languages ​​​​and even dialects, and the teaching content it can provide will increase exponentially. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s even more amazing is: Call Annie does not require class appointments, is currently free, and can chat 24 hours a day. It does not feel tired, irritable, angry, or needs to get off work like human teachers do. It is more patient and has a good attitude. , He also didn’t criticize or reprimand. Even though I had a poor foundation and was mentally retarded, he still took the trouble to teach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under such a powerful AI attack, it is estimated that many language teachers, basic knowledge teaching teachers, translators, and even university teaching assistants... as long as they are non-original research professors, will be in danger of being eliminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a powerful AI is still evolving day and night. When I fall asleep, it is still learning, iterating, and improving... I don’t know whether I should continue to call it &quot;it&quot; or prepare to change it to &quot;He, she&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attack of AI and the challenge to existing human work are not imminent, but the &quot;wolf&quot; has already arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IBM recently stated that it will suspend recruitment for positions that may be replaced by AI in the next few years, approximately 26,000 jobs. In the next five years, 30% of these positions will be replaced by AI and automation, which will involve the work of nearly 8,000 people. This is just IBM! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;February 2023, &quot;Fortune&quot; survey: 48% of 1,000 companies in the United States are gradually using ChatGPT to replace human employees, which will involve the work and livelihood of tens of thousands of white-collar workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Goldman Sachs analyst Ben Snyder said: &quot;In the next 10 years, artificial intelligence may increase productivity by 1.5% per year. This may increase the profits of S&amp;P 500 companies by 30% in the next 10 years.&quot; % or more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the United States, but also all walks of life in the country have also been impacted by AI. In April 2023, a large number of original animators at game companies were laid off, and some companies even laid off more than half of their original animators. The labor remuneration for a single painting by a freelancer has dropped from 1,500 yuan to about 200 yuan. We predicted in a previous article that arts and crafts designers would gradually lose their jobs, just over a year ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blue Focus, a well-known domestic advertising company, has completely stopped outsourcing copywriting and switched to AI writing. There is an e-commerce company founder who spent 3 months training GPT to write product copywriting and replaced 7 employees. Some Taobao merchants have used AI-generated digital models instead of real ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, my sister’s loss of her former professional voice work was not an isolated case, but just a note in the common fate of millions of professional and technical people in the context of this era. The advancement of AI has developed from the field of engineering technology to the visual arts industry, and then expanded to language and performing arts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even Lu Qi, the former president of Baidu, said: Now there is a time for swearing every week, because I am so shocked by the technology that I can’t help but swear. Because after the emergence of ChatGPT, AI technology has been developing rapidly in days. Under the impact of the AI ​​wave, no matter whether it is science and engineering, liberal arts, or art, whether it is grassroots production personnel, professional and technical personnel, administrative personnel, or even senior executives, all People can stay out of things. Where will the development of science and technology push mankind in the future? This may have exceeded our current cognitive abilities and thinking framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生态环境部答南周：对碳排放数据弄虚作假“零容忍”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259511]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255859&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Youbin, spokesperson of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Ministry of Ecology and Environment | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 27, 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment held a regular press conference. Liu Youbin, spokesperson of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, said that the theme of this conference is to actively respond to climate change, promote green, low-carbon and high-quality development, and release the &quot;2023 Annual Report on China&#39;s Policies and Actions to Address Climate Change&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the launch of the national carbon market in July 2021, the quality of carbon emission data has attracted much attention. Xia Yingxian, director of the Department of Climate Change, made his debut after taking up his new post. When answering questions from Southern Weekend reporters, he said that overall, companies&#39; awareness of emission reduction has significantly improved, their regulatory capabilities have been significantly improved, and the quality of carbon emission data has been significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the measures taken by the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review mechanism for carbon emission data quality plays an important role. After enterprises submit data and certification materials through the management platform every month, national departments are responsible for big data screening and regular spot checks, provincial government departments are responsible for technical review, and prefecture-level government departments are responsible for on-site spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian introduced that the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review mechanism follows the management idea of ​​&quot;using the day to protect the month, using the month to protect the year&quot; to ensure that every day , monthly, and annual data are stable and reliable, &quot;reflecting our cautious and cautious attitude towards data quality.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian, Director of the Department of Climate Change Response of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Ministry of Ecology and Environment | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Do a good job in daily supervision of data quality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian said that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has always attached great importance to carbon emission data quality management. There is &quot;zero tolerance&quot; for illegal and illegal activities such as data falsification. Especially since 2022, a series of measures have been taken to ensure that carbon emission data is accurate and reliable, focusing on comprehensively improving data quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, in terms of the construction of the legal system, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has actively cooperated with the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate to revise and issue judicial interpretations to criminalize the falsification of carbon emission data. Sanction scope. The accounting and verification guidelines were revised and introduced, reducing the formulas involved in carbon emission report verification from 27 to 12, optimizing the accounting methods, and effectively improving the pertinence, scientificity and operability of the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of supervision and law enforcement, since 2021, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has organized supervision and assistance, guided by problem clues, guided enterprises to standardize emission accounting reporting behaviors, and severely cracked down on Engage in deceptive behavior. Xia Yingxian said that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment will severely punish and reduce carbon emission quotas for emission-controlled companies that have verified data to be falsified in accordance with the law; it has exposed a number of third-party verification agencies that violate laws and regulations, which has a great deterrent effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of carbon emission management capabilities, Xia Yingxian introduced that the national carbon emissions trading management platform will be launched online in 2023, realizing inventory management, emission management, and data quality supervision. , verification management, and quota management are intelligent and digital, and big data means are used to enrich data quality management technical means. Since 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has held 5 special training courses on carbon emission data quality management and supervision and law enforcement, with more than 5,000 trainees, and supervision capabilities have been significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian also said that in the next step, we will continue to do a good job in daily supervision of data quality and make full use of the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review working mechanism. Conduct spot checks and reports on data quality management work in various regions, establish and improve daily supervision and technical review systems for greenhouse gas emission data, clarify technical review standards and procedures, and consolidate the main responsibilities of key emission units. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Carbon price is in line with China’s current reality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the press conference , Xia Yingxian also mentioned the progress of the national carbon market construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A total of 2,257 key emission units in the power generation industry have been included in the second compliance cycle (2021 and 2022) of the national carbon market, covering annual carbon dioxide emissions of more than 5 billion tons. . The quotas for 2021 and 2022 have been distributed in August 2023, and payment and compliance are currently underway. Xia Yingxian revealed that the current contract fulfillment rate has exceeded 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian believes that the national carbon market has achieved the expected construction goals. &quot;After more than two years of construction and operation, the overall operation of the national carbon market is stable, the price discovery mechanism has initially appeared, and corporate emission reduction awareness and capabilities have been significantly enhanced, playing a positive role in promoting the goal of achieving carbon peak and carbon neutrality.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian said that the national carbon market has initially established an institutional framework system, breaking through the blocking points in key links such as reporting verification, quota allocation, market transactions, settlement and compliance, etc. Difficulties, and realize full-service intelligence through the national carbon market management platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Regarding the topic of carbon market expansion, Xia Yingxian stated that it is urgent to include more qualified industries into the national carbon emissions trading market to reduce the cost of emission reduction for the whole society. We will insist on making progress while maintaining stability, and prioritize the inclusion of industries that contribute significantly to achieving the goal of carbon peak and carbon neutrality, have serious overcapacity, have great synergy potential for pollution reduction and carbon reduction, and have good data quality foundations, and include each mature industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The expansion of the carbon market requires a good data foundation. Xia Yingxian introduced that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment conducts annual carbon emission accounting report verification work nationwide every year for petrochemical, chemical, building materials, steel, non-ferrous metals, papermaking, civil aviation and other industries, and collects data from more than 6,000 companies. The above-mentioned 7 industries The total direct emissions from the power generation and power generation industries account for more than 70% of the country&#39;s total. In addition, special studies were organized on quota allocation methods, accounting and reporting methods, verification points, and expansion implementation paths for seven industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of October 25, 2023, the cumulative transaction volume of carbon emission quotas is 365 million tons, and the cumulative transaction volume is 19.437 billion yuan. The carbon price after the launch of the national carbon market Maintained at around 50-80 yuan/ton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Recently, the quota price has shown an overall upward trend, maintaining at around 80 yuan/ton. The moderate increase in carbon price reflects the market nature of carbon price.&quot; Xia Yingxian believes that the carbon price is in line with China&#39;s current reality and basically reflects my country’s emission reduction costs. In the next step, we will study the establishment of a market adjustment mechanism and take measures such as early warning of contract performance risks to adjust market supply and demand, enhance market vitality, and ensure the healthy, stable and orderly operation of the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“三吠举报”到“恶犬法案”：美国人怎么养狗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is well known that many people in the United States love dogs. However, these Americans love and raise dogs to achieve a certain balance under the support of their specific natural conditions, social conditions and legal environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, in my opinion, the most important and overlooked point is that the United States is not a rabies epidemic area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 202 human rabies cases were reported in 143 districts and counties in China in 2020. Dogs in the United States hardly carry the rabies virus, and the few rabies cases are caused by wild animals (mainly bats). A total of five people died of rabies in the United States in 2021, the highest number of rabies deaths in the country in 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Differences in natural conditions will cause huge differences in social adaptation. When there are no worries about rabies, the intimacy between humans and cats and dogs will greatly increase, and dogs will not be too taboo about what they eat or lick. Even strange stray dogs don’t have to worry about rabies. This creates a close human-dog relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the living area and living pattern of Americans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the per capita housing area in the United States is 67 square meters, ranking first in the world. In addition to the large average area, there are also structural differences in urbanization rates. The overall average urbanization rate in the United States currently reaches 83%, and the urbanization rate in some metropolitan areas is close to 100%. China&#39;s urbanization rate in 2022 will be 65.22%. The problem of dog ownership is largely an urban problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calculated in terms of per capita housing area in domestic cities, especially large and medium-sized cities, it is about half that of the United States. This is just the living area, not the living pattern. Chinese people mostly live in high-rise buildings and share the green environment of the community, while Americans mostly live in suburban villas. Americans have far more outdoor space per household. Therefore, Chinese people use half of their living area and much less public outdoor area to raise dogs, which naturally creates more conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States also has another characteristic, that is, it is more diverse, has a large place, has many choices, and does not interfere with each other. It not only protects the rights of dog lovers, but also protects the rights of people who do not love dogs. There are many communities in the United States that prohibit pets. Not only are dogs not allowed in these communities, but dogs from outside are not even allowed to &quot;visit&quot;. Have a peaceful time together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Americans love dogs, and although the living area is large, the density is low, and there are many green spaces, it does not mean that American dogs do not bite people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the U.S. National Library of Medicine, approximately 1,000 people in the United States require emergency care treatment for serious dog bites every day, and more than 4.5 million people are bitten by dogs each year, with 30 to 50 People are killed by dogs. Injuries caused by dog ​​bites and attacks result in the need for 30,000 surgeries in the United States each year, including sutures and staples. In 2020, U.S. insurance companies paid $854 million for dog bites and attacks, with the average dog bite insurance claim amount being $50,245. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Humane Society of the United States estimates that 51% of dog bite victims are children, which means more than 2 million children are bitten by dogs in the United States each year. Among dog bite deaths, the highest proportion is among those aged 0-4 years. Since children under 1 year old are often unable to walk and are often looked after by adults, the rate of bites is the lowest. After the age of 4, as children get older, the likelihood of being bitten decreases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, although Americans love dogs, they also strictly manage dog ownership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For general harassment, take New York City as an example. If you are reported for not picking up dog poop while walking your dog, the police will issue a $250 (1,800 RMB) fine and may also require you to appear in court. The law also prohibits the harassment of pet dogs in all public and private places. If the dog is not kept on a leash, a fine of 200-400 US dollars will be imposed. For dog nuisance, follow the &quot;three barking report&quot; principle: if a dog of any family barks more than three times in a residential area, it will be considered a nuisance, and neighbors can report it. Under strict regulations, most dog walkers in the United States are self-conscious, and leash-free dog walking is rare. If a dog poops, most dog owners use plastic bags to collect the poop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the law stipulates that people who keep high-risk ferocious dogs must erect signs in conspicuous places in their yards to remind passersby to pay attention. In public places, high-risk ferocious dogs must wear a restraint leash and an anti-bite muzzle at all times. Otherwise, law enforcement agencies have the right to impound or execute the dog. Depending on the severity of the case, the dog owner may be held criminally responsible and may even be sentenced to 90 days in jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For higher levels of physical risk, some states have enacted so-called &quot;vicious dog laws.&quot; A dog is considered a &quot;vicious dog&quot; if it attacks or injures a human or their pet within a two-year period, or exhibits aggressive behavior that requires the police or animal control agencies to stop or drive away. Such dogs must be isolated, prohibited from contact with humans, and undergo mandatory training. If the owner refuses to cooperate, the dog may be euthanized. The Vicious Dog Act requires dog owners to take full responsibility for their dogs. If a dog attacks a person and the owner fails to take strict precautions and deal with it promptly, resulting in casualties, the dog owner must be responsible for all injuries and may even be subject to criminal penalties. If a dog attacks a human after escaping, the owner is still responsible for the dog&#39;s behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are very sound pet shelters and rescue stations across the United States, funded by the government and private organizations, to take in and rescue stray cats and dogs. In shelters, sheltered dogs and other animals are treated well. Americans love dogs, and there are always enough volunteers at shelters. Stray dogs in shelters generally have a 1-2 week deadline for adoption. Non-governmental animal protection organizations also try their best to allow dogs in shelters to be adopted. After that, if no one comes to adopt them, they will be euthanized. Statistics show that of the 8.5 million stray dogs sheltered in the United States in 2010, 82% were adopted and taken away by new owners, while the remaining 1.53 million old, sick, and unadopted dogs were euthanized. Although many civil organizations are trying to change euthanasia and replace it with sterilization, raising funds is still an unavoidable obstacle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All public issues are like this. Rights and obligations cannot be neglected or mentioned only on one side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年度佳作，没有人经得起剖析审视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 22:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;There are many movies about marriage. You can easily pull up a long movie list. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this topic is never out of date, and has different interpretations in the eyes of different people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;No, this year Cannes presents us with another blockbuster work - &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1060&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255204&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier is a female director. Her first two works were &quot;Victoria&quot; and &quot;Sibyl&quot;, both of which were self-written and directed, focusing on female expression. At the same time, Justine Trier is also the third female director in the history of Cannes to win the Palme d&#39;Or for this film. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255201 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The starring role is German actress Sandra Wheeler. In 2006&lt;span>;, at the age of 28, she won the Berlin Film Festival for her performance in &quot;Requiem&quot; Film Festival Silver Bear Award for Best Actress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255200 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talented female director teamed up with powerful actresses to present this masterpiece that cannot be missed this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The heroine Sandra is a well-known writer with strong creative power and very high productivity. Coupled with her androgynous temperament, she has accumulated many readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this day, while Sandra was being interviewed by a young female student majoring in literature, loud music suddenly came from upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reckless and rude interruption announced the existence of another person: Sandra&#39;s husband Samuel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255202&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Samuel was originally a university professor and also wanted to write. However, unlike his wife, who was full of literary ideas, he seemed to always get stuck halfway and find it difficult to write. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The two have an 11-year-old son named Daniel, who is visually impaired. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, this disability is not congenital, but is caused to some extent by Samuel: One day a few years ago, Samuel was supposed to pick up Daniel from school. But he suddenly got inspiration for writing and hired someone to pick up his son. During this period, Daniel had a car accident and damaged his eyes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255205 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The accident not only interrupted their careers, but also put this middle-class family into financial difficulties due to medical expenses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to reduce debt pressure, Samuel suggested moving his family from London, England to his hometown in the suburbs of France. For Sandra, she lost her stable life in London and entered an unfamiliar environment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255203 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra has no one here, and her interview with the female student can only end hastily after being interrupted by Samuel. Soon, Daniel, who was returning from walking his dog, found his father&#39;s bloody body in the snow. He shouted for his mother, and Sandra, who came in a hurry, quickly called the police. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255207 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After identification, the fatal injury to the deceased Samuel was a heavy blow to the head. Although it appears that he fell to his death, he was most likely murdered. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255208 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But their family’s residence was nowhere to be found, and there were no other outsiders present when the incident occurred. Samuel usually had no enemies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thus, the common conclusion in crime movies&lt;/span>; is readily apparent: the murderer is the wife Sandra, and she must be resentful of her husband. Is this really the case? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra was controlled as the first suspect, and Daniel was on the scene The only witness. To prove her innocence, Sandra must convince the judge that there is love but not hatred between her and her husband, and that she has no motive for killing. At this point,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a death case has become a trial of a marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Anatomy of Death from Falling from a Building&quot; also enters into the detailed &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;analysis of marriage relationships: When a person &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; dies In this case, how can the other party prove itself? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255210 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this time, except for Sandra, everyone else was basically in the same blind&lt;span>; situation as Daniel. After all, except for the two parties involved, everyone is an outsider in this relationship. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255206 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So neither the psychiatrist’s testimony, which was heavily psychoanalytic, nor the defense provided by lawyers on both sides, could touch the real Samuel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is no way to reach the core of a living person or a love through words. But this trial has to find the truth through language. This is the contradiction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255209 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because she was in France, Sandra had to use her unskilled language to defend herself. Love&lt;/span>; is not like this: stumbling communication, but in the end it is inaccurate words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255211&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Words always have a certain performance quality, and &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; also presents this through a perfect recording. The film also completely enters the climax after the opening 80 minutes. . Samuel carried Sandra on his back and recorded the heated argument that broke out between the two on the day before her death. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the recording, Samuel accused Sandra of only caring about her career and ignoring her family, saying that she was always aloof, saying that she clearly blamed herself for causing Daniel&#39;s tragedy but refused to admit it. She plagiarized her own ideas and cheated on her physically...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/ 9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 24/9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra was not to be outdone. From the beginning, she calmly advised Samuel not to complain and not to be self-motivated, but later she became unbearable. Gave him a slap...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif &quot; data-key=&quot;255213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a quarrel must have been experienced by most couples and couples who have passed the passionate love stage. It is difficult for outsiders to say that the public is justified and the mother-in-law is justified. Determine right or wrong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But the problem is that this quarrel and physical conflict happened the day before Samuel&#39;s death, which undoubtedly pushed Sandra towards the angry wife who murdered her husband. image. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The troubled media are still chewing on Sandra’s book at this time, believing that her murder of her husband was premeditated. But is this really the case? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255212&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; is a work that analyzes marriage as delicately as a scalpel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a middle-aged female director, Justine Trier has not only gotten rid of the male perspective, but also has passed the stage of young women&#39;s blind longing for marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, she is very creative in placing the marriage relationship in the court scene to analyze, on the other hand, she still has the unique tenderness and pioneering spirit of women. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, in the setting of the heroine Sandra, she has a strong androgynous temperament, which is different from common female images. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255215 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, compared to common settings, the situations and personalities of Sandra and Samuel are also reversed: Sandra has a successful career, a peaceful personality, and is close to her children; while Samuel Not only did I encounter a career development bottleneck, but I also became more emotional and exhausted my creativity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This image and gender setting itself break through the stereotype of male narrative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, the film uses calm and restrained lens language and narrative expression, trying to go deeper into the truth of the death case and give the audience a sense of clarity beyond the case itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are two recordings in the movie, one is the interview of the female student that day, and the other is the quarrel privately recorded by Samuel. These two daily conversations were analyzed and interpreted word for word in public in court, and were even used as evidence of crimes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When the second quarrel started by Samuel appears in court, the gender balance begins to tilt, and Sandra needs to explain all of Samuel&#39;s dilemmas : Why does he have to choose between work and family? Why does he never have time to write novels? Why is his creativity exhausted while she publishes novels frequently? Why is he frigid and she cheats on her physically? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this time, the intimate relationship must be put on the table to experience the scrutiny of others, and then others will give the final conclusion. Sandra was extremely embarrassed. What she encountered was not only a discussion about gender, but also a trial of marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the age of only 11, their son Daniel has already experienced major events such as car accidents, disability, the death of his father and defending his mother. He is actually the avatar of the audience. After listening to the trial half-blindly, he finally chose his mother. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255214 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this choice itself, even Sandra&#39;s innocence itself, cannot achieve complete emotional catharsis, because when feelings need to be judged, it means that there will be no survivors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film&#39;s use of telephoto lenses, soft light, and close-up lenses makes the images presented in the film more cold and distant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255216 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the exquisite narrative of &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot;, the most commendable thing is the performance of the heroine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, she is a talented and famous writer, and on the other hand, she is a wife and mother who is troubled by intimate relationships. The emotions and gestures she expresses directly support her. Played the role itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255218 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the movie, Sandra is well aware of the complexity of language. She refutes others&#39; attempts to define Samuel again and again, and always uses negative statements to retain Samuel. beautiful image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;That&#39;s not him.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This denial itself is an expression of private love, but love cannot be declared to Mouth proves that love is so absurd. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So in the court that tried to convict her, she was the only one who loved the real Samuel. She did not kill him, but she did kill him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[色乡，一段关于救赎的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJInW9oBtSKF5N8j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJ InW9oBtSKF5N8j. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lodro Wolong Temple is built along the cliff, and the huts on the cliff are used for monks&#39; practice. The cave &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tawny and bare, this was my first impression of Luozha County. Luozha County is located in a mountain valley, and the county seat winds along the only mountain road in the middle. I chose to come to Luozha, Shannan City, to visit the Sakagutuo Temple with a history of more than 900 years in the Border Se Township. This is a pilgrimage road often walked by Buddhists. It has a long history and a mysterious place. As for the scenery, although I am not a Buddhist, I am also full of yearning for the beautiful scenery on the border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 9 o&#39;clock in the morning, I set off from the bus station in the northern suburbs of Lhasa and passed through the beautiful Yanghu Lake and rows of snow-capped mountains. When I arrived in Lozha County, it was about 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon. I immediately bought the only daily ticket at the station. A ticket to Sexiang. It still takes nearly two hours to drive to Sexiang. The road begins to narrow and there are more gravels. But I was still attracted by the barren and spectacular scenery outside the window. One side of the car is close to the exposed rocks, and the other side is close to the rushing river. The river is rushing forward happily, as if it is racing with the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Loza County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were only five or six people on the bus An old Tibetan man, a young Tibetan man and me. The young Tibetan man comes from the Garze region and has been traveling to Tibet for more than half a year. This time he went specifically to Lapu Hot Spring in Sexiang. He wore a down jacket and carried a small plastic bag with him, but no other luggage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already 7:30 when I arrived in Sexiang. I quickly found a place to stay before it got dark. The entire township is located on a flat land in the mountains. There are dozens of buildings built along the road. They are all occupied by local people. In order to welcome guests, some have been converted into hotels and some into restaurants. Hotels are either closed or full, and the owner is rarely there, leaving only a phone number. Finally, I finally found a bed at the Sakaguto Temple Hotel. There was a public bathroom, but I couldn&#39;t take a shower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Saika Gutuo Temple in Sexiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;sai Kagutuo Monastery was originally a monastery of the Kagyu sect of Tibetan Buddhism, but later converted to the Gelug sect. It is a must-visit place for Tibetan pilgrims. The main building of Sakagutuo Temple, which has a history of more than 900 years, has been relatively completely preserved. The temple is located in the middle of Se Township, next to the cliff, and the sound of rushing river water comes from the bottom of the mountain, which is quiet and distant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a legendary and touching story of redemption behind the nine-story tower of Sakagutuo Temple. According to legend, in the 11th century, Marpa, the founder of the Kagyu sect, who was known as &quot;one of the seven great translators of ancient Tibet&quot;, had a disciple named Milarepa. He lost his father when he was young, his wealth was seized by relatives, and his family was enslaved. When he grew up, he learned magic and killed 35 people in revenge. Later, in order to atone for his sins, Milarepa came to Sexiang to become a disciple of Marpa. Marpa ordered Milarepa to build Sakagutuo Temple alone (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Means &quot;Nine-story Gongzi Castle&quot;&lt;/span>;). Day after day, year after year, every time he built it, Marpa asked him to overthrow and rebuild it, until it was finally completed the sixth time. The current Sakagutuo Temple was built at that time (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;later repaired and expanded&lt;/span>;). Ancient prayer wheels hang on the outside of the predominantly yellow temple, and murals from hundreds of years ago can still be faintly seen on the mottled walls inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green space by the Sexiang River and a released calf&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There is a small suspended plank road on the top of the 9-story watchtower tower for people to pray for blessings. When I climbed to the ninth floor, a lama said that since I had come up, I should go around the tower. It is said that turning once can wash away all the bad luck in the past life; turning twice can pray for the health and happiness of parents; turning three times will prevent you from falling into hell in the next life. However, except for the steel poles that can be grasped by hand, there are no protective fences around the top of the tower. I was afraid of heights and dared not go up. Finally, I walked around in a circle under the leadership of the lama. The young lama chanted sutras while walking. He walked many times every day and it became a daily routine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sakagutuo Temple is very small and can be completed in less than half an hour. On the top of the mountain south of Sexiang, there is also Lodro Wolong Monastery, which is the birthplace of the Kagyu Sect of Tibetan Buddhism and was built by Master Marpa when he was 29 years old. According to the official website of Luozha County Government, &quot;Luo&quot; means &quot;south&quot;, &quot;Zhuowo&quot; means &quot;beginning of auspiciousness&quot;, and &quot;Long&quot; means &quot;prophecy&quot;. Luozhawolong Temple is where the master predicted and prophesied. place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes several hours to walk to the Luozhuo Wolong Temple on the top of the mountain, and there is no public transportation. I found a ride on the road and met a Tibetan family who drove up the mountain and picked me up. The family came from neighboring Cona County and came to Luozha County for pilgrimage for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sexiang is dozens of kilometers away from Bhutan. Opposite the Sekhar Guto Temple is the Bhutanese commodity store, and the back of the mountain where Lodro Wolong Temple is located is In Bhutan, our ID cards were held at the checkpoint on the way up the mountain. The dusty gravel road was winding and difficult to walk. A couple from Guangdong decided to give up after driving for a short distance, but this Tibetan family did not. After half an hour, we successfully reached the top of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only temples on the mountain, and the landscape is extremely open. Several huge crows are circling overhead, and the shadows of clouds are cast on the mountain. Lodzo Wolong Temple is built along the stone wall on the top of the mountain. In addition to the main temple, there are also many small hermitages scattered under the cliff. A lama who has been practicing for many years has long hair reaching his waist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lamas in Lodro Wolong Monastery are the most enthusiastic lamas I have ever encountered. They explained the story behind the temple to everyone who went up the mountain. Although I was the only Han tourist, after they finished telling a long list of Tibetan words, they would tell it to me again in Chinese. According to them, the old Lodro Wolong Temple was destroyed and was rebuilt in 1992. There is a sky burial platform at the top of the mountain. A lama in his twenties said that it was built based on a stone that Marpa carried back from India where he studied scriptures for 12 years. On the hillside at the foot of the temple, there is a flat area surrounded by prayer flags. The place where stones are piled is Shunyuantian. According to legend, this is the place where Marpa and Milarepa met for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We stayed on the mountain for more than half a day, during which time the temple held a Dharma ceremony and witnessed the Tibetan Buddhist Dharma ceremony. Finally, I went down the mountain with the Tibetan family, and the car went around the zigzag road back to Sexiang. We separated and continued our journeys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>