<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[上海独生女继承两亿遗产被诉离婚？婚姻不应成为财富再分配的工具丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261768]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;November 30, 2023, published by &quot;Shanghai Rule of Law News&quot; The article states: The woman comes from a well-off family and serves as the director of a foreign-funded company; the man is the receptionist at the hotel where the woman’s company’s annual meeting is held. The man pursued the woman fiercely, and later they got married. After the marriage, the woman&#39;s parents died in a car accident while traveling. Half a year later, the man filed for divorce and requested a division of the woman&#39;s inheritance from her parents. The woman&#39;s parents own nine properties and shops in Shanghai, as well as more than 10 million yuan in bank deposits and financial products, with a total value of about 200 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This article once reached the top of the hot search, with a main tag having more than 600 million views, and popular comments including &quot;I even suspected that the car accident...&quot; You can spend 10 million to deal with it, and I guarantee that the man will not get a dime.&quot; He also accused the man of &quot;taking advantage of the poor&quot;, and in short, scolded him for being shameless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This is actually a story told by lawyer Tan Fang. He neither gave a specific timeline nor presented credible evidence including judicial documents. Some netizens discovered that when she shared this story on Zhihu in 2022, she had the label &quot;the content contains fictional creations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For this reason, some media interviewed Ma Lei, a partner at Tan Fang&#39;s law firm, who said that the case was real and only involved the client&#39;s privacy. , will fabricate sensitive information such as names. However, it is very common to use pseudonyms in news reports. Journalists only need to mark it in the text or at the end of the article. They will not consider themselves to be &quot;fictional creations&quot; by using pseudonyms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In summary, the authenticity of this case is doubtful and needs further confirmation. But the emotions and reactions triggered by this story are real and strong: as can be seen from the massive online comments, the public generally does not agree with and find it difficult to accept the legacy left by the man&#39;s parents and the girl&#39;s parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Moreover, there are indeed such cases in judicial practice. In March this year, the Guangxi High Court issued a property dispute case. In 2021, Zhang and his wife Wang agreed to divorce, and their daughter lived with Wang. On the grounds that Zhang failed to pay child support, Wang filed a post-divorce property dispute lawsuit with the court. During the trial, Wang learned that Zhang’s mother died during the cooling-off period of their divorce and left behind a property. Zhang sold the above-mentioned house, and Wang requested to divide the sales proceeds obtained by Zhang from selling the house. In the end, the court ruled that Zhang should pay more than 2.18 million yuan in the sale price of the house inherited by Wang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the relationship between husband and wife, it is legal for one party to request a division of the parental estate inherited by the other party. The marriage and family section of the current Civil Code stipulates that &quot;property inherited or donated&quot; is the common property of husband and wife and owned jointly by husband and wife (Article 1062). This is the default principle; only when &quot;it is determined in the will or gift contract that only one party will own it&quot; &quot;Property&quot; is the personal property of one spouse (Article 1063). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Such provisions in statutory law are intended to expand the scope of joint property between husband and wife, allowing the economically weaker party to have more property to divide in the event of divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The problem is that when marriage becomes a tool for wealth redistribution, both marriage and wealth become unsafe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As far as marriage is concerned, under statutory laws and judicial practices that expand the scope of joint property between husband and wife, if two people with a huge gap in property and income get married, the marriage will become It’s even more unstable because it promotes the stereotype that “marriage is to start a business, divorce is to get rich”. Whether it is adding one&#39;s name to the property before marriage (= giving away half of the property), one of the parents did not make a will and left an inheritance, or one party in the marriage has too strong wealth creation ability or becomes rich overnight, these are only the joint property of the husband and wife during the marriage. One party may not have substantial control and dominance, but as long as there is a divorce, the other party can actually obtain control and dominance of half of the property. If a person obtains a large amount of wealth through divorce, achieves financial freedom, and feels so happy, this will inevitably inspire evil in human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of wealth, a property in first-tier cities often costs tens of millions, and is often the accumulation of wealth for at least two generations. Just because a marriage certificate costs Losing half of a house is very unfair and makes people who hold real estate in big cities very insecure. Therefore, more and more people ask for a match before getting married, or just hold a wedding without getting a certificate, so as to avoid being &quot;exploited&quot; in the event of divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Back to the issue of inheritance, it is natural and reasonable for parents to hope that their property will be left to their children or other blood-related descendants a hundred years from now. Consistent with natural law and customary law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the absence of a will and legal inheritance, in accordance with natural law and customary law, the inheritance left by parents to their children should of course be inherited by their children. personal property. However, as mentioned above, current statutory law and judicial practice stipulate that it is joint property of husband and wife by default. If one parent dies suddenly without leaving a will, the greed of the other parent may be aroused. Through divorce, they can divide half of the other parent&#39;s inheritance, achieve financial freedom, and reach the peak of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Of course, many people believe in love, and also believe that being economically disadvantaged does not necessarily mean being morally despicable, but don’t test human nature, as long as a certain proportion of economically disadvantaged people can make progress Taking this step is enough to destroy the trust that should exist in marriage and make everyone fear marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Elderly people who are knowledgeable, educated and understand the law know what to do. Some media reports: Recently, 85-year-old Grandma Liu came to the China Wills Library to make a will and wanted to give her property to The granddaughter, son and daughter-in-law all know and agree. She said she lived a happy life in her later years and was not afraid of making a will. She was once the coach of a modeling team. The consideration is roughly like this: leaving it directly to the son is natural, but the daughter-in-law may be unhappy and complain &quot;you don&#39;t trust me&quot;; leaving the son directly to the granddaughter perfectly solves this problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;China Will Library White Paper (2022)&quot; shows that 99.8% of the elderly who make wills state that the inheritance will be inherited by the children alone and does not belong to the joint property of the heirs. It is the so-called &quot;protection against daughter-in-law and son-in-law&quot; clause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the final analysis, it is all forced by the current statutory law and judicial practice. The elderly have worked hard all their lives to accumulate real estate, and most elderly people cannot accept it psychologically if &quot;outsiders&quot; who are not related by blood and may divorce and leave at any time take away half of the house. However, more elderly people do not have this awareness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的父亲母亲丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261744]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/TzFsCURKUbpRWt7gkpHYGBoT44F4jGLOalCSSM4m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/TzFsCURKUbpRWt7gkpHYGBoT44F4jGLOal CSSM4m. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Guoguang (1928-2014) Zhejiang, Judge Zheng Ruyu (1930-2022) Zhejiang, Teacher&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bulging key bag suddenly became lighter, and the sale of the parents&#39; house was completed. They moved into this apartment in early 2009, and this house carries every bit of their old age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before his retirement, my father was the vice-president of a district court in Shanghai. He was 1.78 meters tall, handsome in appearance, upright and principled, and full of romantic warmth. Even when he was in pain, he would hold his mother&#39;s hand. The hand said &quot;the hand is too cold&quot;. My mother is the eldest daughter in the family. After graduating from nursing school, she took on the responsibility of raising her younger siblings. She has an easy-going personality and is less than 1.6 meters tall but seems to have endless energy. She was still tenacious before being sent to the ICU. Swallow food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let us have food to eat and eat well, which is my mother’s lifelong obsession. Materials were scarce in the 1960s, but as long as she was at home, every meal in our family would be delicious, with both meat and vegetables. Even the presentation was unambiguous. When the dishes were put into the bowl, there would be soup splashing on the edge of the bowl. She Be sure to wipe it clean before serving it. Every New Year&#39;s Day, the house is filled with the aroma of meat and rice dumplings... My mother&#39;s cheeks, red from overwork, show a smile of contentment, enjoying a rare moment of rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After we got married, every weekend when we went there, she would happily take out large and small boxes and bottles filled with vegetables and soups, with &quot;food instructions&quot; written on medicine box paper attached. She said, &quot;If I have a fever one more time, you can eat one more time.&quot; In this way, she stubbornly persisted until she was hospitalized last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At work, my mother is equally serious and hardworking. After a day of housework, she often uses her chair as a table to study by herself, prepare work materials, and write teaching materials. She graduated from a nursing school and later worked as a teacher, gradually becoming a leader in the nursing discipline in Shanghai. In the 1970s, my mother signed up to support the Huaibei Medical Team. In order to travel more points, she sometimes had to walk dozens of kilometers a day on mountain roads. At that time, she was over 40 years old, and she eventually fell ill with pneumonia from exhaustion. My mother worked until she was 70 years old and retired with the title of senior lecturer. She was famous all over the world. The &quot;Nursing&quot; textbook she participated in compiled laid the foundation for the development of today&#39;s nursing field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retirement, my mother was not idle. She learned English, sang, knitted sweaters for relatives and friends, and wrote memoirs... She said, &quot;I have to do something while I&#39;m alive, so I can&#39;t live in vain.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;When I was a child, every evening we would wait for my father’s tall figure to appear at the entrance of our house at the entrance of the alley. My father loved reading. In that spiritually barren era, we were delighted to get a book. After retirement, biographies of famous people became the books my father often read. He is erudite and has a strong memory, and often discusses current affairs with his colleagues and juniors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, my father was sent to a ferroalloy factory to do manual labor. He had to carry dozens of kilograms of sledgehammers every day. This was a great test for him who grew up in a scholarly family. But he comes home happy every day. He sincerely mingled with the workers. At that time, our family often gathered workers and friends to talk and laugh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father was sincere, upright and aboveboard throughout his life, never ambiguous about right or wrong. In his will, he also told us to &quot;be upright and upright.&quot; He never judged people by money and status. Once, a part-time worker who had worked in our family for several years became seriously ill. He was very concerned and asked us to send money to help. This part-time worker would make a special trip to visit his father every time he returned to Shanghai for medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father has always kept his home spotless. In the last three months, he could no longer walk, and he still looked in the mirror to neatly style his hair. In the early summer of 2013, feeling that his life was coming to an end, he made a will: &quot;I am 86 years old, and I have no regrets...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My parents have gone through 53 years of ups and downs together, which is rare in my memory. They blushed, let alone argued. Our parents gave us a warm home with their lifelong efforts and love; they taught us how to face the impermanence of the world with a positive and optimistic attitude towards life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My parents were reunited in heaven. Our golden years as siblings are gone forever. We feel so deeply the loneliness of the soul and the sadness of being homeless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The love between parents is as deep as the ocean, and the son wants to support him but refuses to take care of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博士举报医院套取医保基金：控费与反控费是协同进化的游戏？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261791]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 23:01:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On December 2, 2023, the Anhui Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau issued a notice saying: On July 18, 2023, the A petition report filed by Yang Moumou revealed that Wuhu Second People&#39;s Hospital illegally and illegally used medical insurance funds through fabrication and exchanging diagnosis and treatment services while his father was hospitalized for cerebral hemorrhage. After investigation, the hospital had problems such as over-diagnosis and treatment, over-examination, over-prescription of medicines, repeated charges, fraudulent charges, and excessive charges, involving illegal medical expenses of 218,200 yuan, of which 187,000 yuan was illegally used of medical insurance funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, &quot;Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau first dealt with it in accordance with the agreement&quot;, recovered the medical insurance funds used in violation of regulations in full, deducted a penalty of 56,074.41 yuan at the top rate of 30%, and gave the whistleblower 5,364.04 yuan Yuan reporting reward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, on November 30, the Economic Observer Network published a report &quot;The family of a patient in Anhui discovered that a tertiary hospital overcharged 100,000 yuan in medical expenses. Investigation showed that the medical fee exceeded 210,000 yuan.&quot; Social media also printed &quot;Prestigious School&quot; The doctor used a statistical model to find out that the hospital overcharged 100,000 yuan in medical expenses.&quot; The notification from the Anhui Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau confirmed this report. On December 3, the Economic Observer published a self-report by the patient’s son (a doctor of law), describing how he discovered that there was something fishy in the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, the family members found that: when surgery is excluded and dialysis is not required, the patient needs to pay out of pocket 1,000 yuan per day for maintenance treatment in the ICU; when hemodialysis/continuous blood purification is required, the patient needs to pay out of pocket 2,000 yuan per day. . This model applies to the first two months of hospitalization, but starting from June 14, 2022, the amount of out-of-pocket expenses has skyrocketed. Then comparing the charging items, it was found that the hospital was suspected of fabricating hemodialysis monitoring time, fabricating patients to receive exercise therapy, and fabricating enteral nutrition. Number of perfusions and replacement of drugs, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, the doctor conducted a statistical analysis and concluded that the hospital defrauded and illegally used medical insurance funds of at least 95,861.93 yuan to 103,681.93 yuan. A notice issued by the Anhui Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau showed that the actual amount found was twice that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Observing this incident, the motivation of the patient’s family members to report is a very meaningful perspective, and it is of irreplaceable value in exploring how to reduce the hospital’s use of medical insurance funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The patient suffered from the uremic stage of diabetic nephropathy and required regular dialysis. On March 19, 2022, he was rushed to the above-mentioned hospital due to sudden left limb weakness and confusion. He was diagnosed with thalamic hemorrhage. Breaking into the brain ventricle, the doctor said in his own words: &quot;My father was hospitalized in Wuhu No. 2 Hospital for a total of 117 days. He underwent three craniotomies and was treated in the hospital&#39;s ICU. Most of the time, he was in a deep coma. His family could not accompany him or see him. &quot;. This gives hospitals room to raise their hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report does not specify whether the patient enjoys employee medical insurance or resident medical insurance, but no matter which kind of medical insurance it is, the medical insurance fund pays the majority and self-pay is the small portion. The hospital&#39;s fictitious medical projects and increased medical expenses The main purpose is of course to defraud medical insurance funds (in this case, the amount amounted to 187,000 yuan). However, the direct reason for being reported was obviously that the patient&#39;s family members found something wrong with the &quot;skyrocketing amount of self-payment&quot; (an extra charge of 31,200 yuan in this case). The patient&#39;s family members&#39; motivation to care about their own interests was the decisive factor in triggering the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, maintaining a certain out-of-pocket ratio when using medical insurance has nothing to do with whether the medical insurance fund is sufficient, but whether the medical insurance fund can be used properly. Such an arrangement provides an incentive and linkage mechanism for the patients themselves and their families. People will most likely be concerned about whether their money has been overcharged by the hospital, and will also be concerned about whether the medical insurance fund has been abused by the hospital. In the final analysis, it is a matter of human nature. problems, making good use of self-interest can also help promote the public interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, both employee medical insurance and resident medical insurance are essentially compulsory medical insurance (Security). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For employee medical insurance, employees pay a certain percentage of pre-tax salary (generally 2% for individuals + 8% for units). High-income earners pay more, and low-income earners pay less. But except for individuals, The account accumulation is different, but the medical insurance benefits enjoyed by everyone (the social pooling part, represented by the medical insurance fund) are the same. In essence, there are three &quot;transfer payments&quot;: intergenerational transfer payments from workers, young people and the next generation to retirees, the elderly and the previous generation; intra-generational transfer payments from high-income people to low-income people; healthy people with fewer diseases. Transfer payments from the sick to the frail. For resident medical insurance, premiums are paid annually according to age groups, and then the government provides most of the subsidies. The reimbursement rate is slightly lower than that of employee medical insurance, and everyone enjoys the same medical insurance benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the insured becomes seriously ill and needs to be hospitalized, most of the medical expenses will be paid by the medical insurance fund. Although the medical insurance fund comes from everyone&#39;s contributions, it is mixed into a big pool. &quot;What you eat is yours.&quot; In form, it is paid by a third party, and the patient does not need to pay for it. This is a problem for the patient. Encourage yourself to get more and better examinations and treatments. This resonates with the hospital&#39;s interest appeal: It doesn&#39;t matter who pays, what matters is that someone pays. As long as someone pays the bill, how can the hospital resist making more money? Now that patients are actively demanding more and better examinations and treatments, why wouldn’t hospitals do the same? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, third-party payment itself will push up medical prices and medical expenses. The ultimate form is British-style public medical care, where patients do not have to pay at all. However, since there is no price to reflect the intensity of demand, everyone has the mentality of not using it for free, and they flock to public hospitals for all minor ailments, but medical resources are still limited. This leads to longer and longer waiting times, and those with serious illnesses in urgent need of treatment are not given priority, and many people&#39;s conditions worsen as a result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, the Medical Insurance Bureau has introduced various cost control methods, such as single-disease payment or DRGs (payment based on disease diagnosis-related groups). In fact, many of the methods are learned from abroad. At the end of each year, it becomes difficult to be hospitalized in some places because the hospital&#39;s medical insurance quota has been exhausted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, the hospital fabricating medical items and overcharging medical expenses for patients is a cat-and-mouse game played with the Medical Insurance Bureau: if you control the expenses, I will counter-control the expenses. The medical insurance fund is like Tang Monk Meat. &quot;Whatever falls into your hands is your own.&quot; Information is asymmetric between hospitals and medical insurance bureaus. Doctors are the experts when it comes to medical issues. Experts are involved, and it is not easy for a layman to expose it. I just often walk by the river without getting my feet wet. When I meet the family members of the patients who are serious and knowledgeable, I lose my temper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, cost control and anti-cost control are a co-evolving game. The Tao is one foot high, the devil is one foot high, and there is no end. As long as there is compulsory medical insurance + third-party payment, it is difficult to have a permanent solution. We can only try to find solutions, continue to iterate, and constantly make new patches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[永世难忘的师生际遇：回忆姜亮夫先生与“楚辞班”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261766]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73919&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70709&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/dabd733a49.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;jiangliangfu2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/dabd733a49.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260521&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(153, 153, 153); text-align: center;&quot;>;Thirteen students from the Chu Ci Workshop took a group photo with Jiang Liangfu and his wife when they graduated in 1980. Front row from left to right: Li Huang, Mrs. Tao Qiuying, Mr. Jiang, Yao Yixin; middle row from left to right: Lu Peicheng, Niu Guoping, Li Anhuai, Jiang Zonglun, Lin Weichun, Zhang Chongchen; back row from left to right: Hao Zhida, Ding Bing , Wang Yanhai, Yin Guangxi, Zhao Haoru. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; ended, colleges and universities resumed enrollment. However, at that time, university teachers were faced with a severe problem of “lack of employment”. The professional skills of some young and middle-aged teachers also need to be improved urgently. After investigation, the Ministry of Education proposed to let some veteran experts teach young and middle-aged teachers, and entrusted relevant universities to organize refresher courses. This kind of refresher course highlights the business expertise of veteran experts, is divided into detailed subjects, and is highly targeted. For example, Mr. Hong Cheng of Nanjing University was commissioned to hold an exegetical teacher workshop, and Mr. Wang Jisi of Sun Yat-sen University was commissioned to hold an opera workshop, which took place roughly between 1979 and 1980. It was also during this period that Mr. Jiang Liangfu of Hangzhou University was commissioned to hold a Chu Ci workshop. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 1979, Mr. Jiang was already 78 years old. But he was still very happy after receiving the task. He &quot;felt that this was a very important academic research task&quot; and &quot;perhaps my biggest effort&quot;, so he &quot;stood up, made plans, prepared reference books, and drafted a teaching syllabus. Use all your strength to complete this task&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (see &quot;Preface to the Modern Interpretation of Chu Ci&quot;)&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before September 20, 1979, all thirteen students had arrived. They are: Lin Weichun&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Jinan University)&lt;/span>;, Hao Zhida&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Nankai University)&lt;/span>;, Zhang Chongchen&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Lanzhou University)&lt;/span>;, Ding Bing&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Northeast Normal University)&lt;/span>;, Wang Yanhai&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot; >;(Liaoning University)&lt;/span>;, Yao Yixin (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;East China Normal University)&lt;/span>;, Zhao Haoru&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Yunnan University）&lt;/span>;, Yin Guangxi&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Yunnan University）&lt; /span>;, Jiang Zonglun&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Kunming Normal University)&lt;/span>;, Lu Peicheng&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_ GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Shaanxi Normal University)&lt;/span>;, Li Huang , Li Anhuai&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Guizhou Normal University)&lt;/span>;, Niu Guoping&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Gansu Normal University)&lt;/span>;. Since Niu Guoping did not join the program when he resumed school in 1980, academic circles called us Mr. Jiang’s “Twelve Disciples,” and Mr. Jiang often said that we were his “big melon” in his later years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony was held on the afternoon of September 24, 1979. A vice president of Hangzhou University, Hu Zhongying, director of the Academic Affairs Office, and Lu Moye, deputy director of the Chinese Department, attended. Mr. Jiang delivered a brief speech at the ceremony and clearly stated that &quot;we must comprehensively study Chu Ci.&quot; It also pointed out that such research requires “not only knowledge from social sciences, but also knowledge from natural sciences.” Taking the word &quot;lan&quot; in Chu Ci as an example, I urge everyone to conduct comprehensive research. Taking the auspicious day &quot;Gengyin&quot; of Chu State as an example, it shows that the study of Chu Ci also requires an understanding of folklore. Although he didn&#39;t say much, he was concise and concise, which inspired the students as soon as they started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the teaching plan, Mr. will give lectures twice a week. One time was a big lecture in the classroom, and some young teachers from Hangzhou University also came to listen; one time was sitting around and talking at my husband&#39;s house, and we were able to chime in, so the atmosphere was lively. In addition, some auxiliary handouts will be distributed before each class, mainly related articles by the teacher. For some topics that cannot be discussed in class, I will go and read the handouts. As for individual counseling, it can be done at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teacher also designated required reading and optional reading for us. Among the must-read books, Hong Xingzu&#39;s &quot;Supplementary Commentary on the Songs of Chu&quot; must be read by everyone; the other five are Jiang Ji&#39;s &quot;Shandaige Commentary on Chu Songs&quot;, Wang Fuzhi&#39;s &quot;General Commentary on Chu Songs&quot;, and Dai Zhen&#39;s &quot;Commentary on Qu Yuan&#39;s Fu&quot;. &quot;, Liu Mengpeng&#39;s &quot;Qu Zi Zhang Ju&quot;, Jiang Liangfu&#39;s &quot;Qu Yuan Fu Annotation&quot;, and then choose to read two to three of them. There are fifteen kinds of books to choose from, namely Zhu Xi&#39;s &quot;Annotations to the Songs of Chu&quot;, Lin Yunming&#39;s &quot;Deng of Chu Songs&quot;, Hu Wenying&#39;s &quot;Qu Sao Zhi Zhang&quot;, Ding Yan&#39;s &quot;Chu Ci Tian Wen Jian&quot;, &quot;Bamboo Chronicles&quot;, &quot;Historical Records·Chu Family&quot; &quot;Mandarin·Chu Language&quot;, &quot;Warring States Policy·Chu Ce&quot;, Engels &quot;The Origin of Family, Private Ownership and the State&quot;, Ai Siqi &quot;Chinese Social History&quot;, Deng Yongling &quot;Chinese Folklore&quot;, Wang Guowei &quot;Guantang Jilin&quot; , Ma Qichang&#39;s &quot;Qu Fuwei&quot;, Jiang Liangfu&#39;s &quot;Five Kinds of Chu Ci Bibliography&quot;, Zhou Shengkai&#39;s &quot;Chu Bao&quot;, you can choose and read a few more according to your ability. After reading each book, you can write a reading report. &quot;Each one should focus on his or her experience. If you don&#39;t have any experience, you don&#39;t have to write. If you have some experience, you can write more. You can submit a collection of manuscripts at any time as a result&quot; (see &quot;Training Plan&quot;). The reading report I wrote was &quot;An Annotated Version of &quot;Chu Ci&quot; Worth Attention - Reading Liu Mengpeng&#39;s &quot;Quzi Chapters&quot;&quot;, which was praised by Mr. Jiang. This article was later published in the &quot;Literature&quot; magazine (Volume 12), and after being compressed, it became an entry in the &quot;Chinese Encyclopedia: Pre-Qin Literature Volume&quot;. I heard from Brother Jiang Linchang that Mr. Jiang later used this article as a model essay when he guided doctoral students to write reading reports. Of course this is a story for later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lecture started going very smoothly. Although Mr. Jiang did not bring a lecture note, he quoted literature and compared the similarities and differences of various views. He uses clear ideas and fluent language to reveal profound academic issues in simple and easy-to-understand terms. This kind and natural teaching style benefits the listeners a lot. We were like rain after a long drought, reluctant to let go of every detail, and listened attentively to every word of the teacher. And every time before get out of class ended, our teacher always asked us if we understood. When we said we understood, our teacher stood up with a smile, and two students immediately helped him go home. Later, we felt that walking back and forth was very tiring for our husband. After negotiating with the school, the school sent a car to pick him up every time he went to class (usually on Thursdays). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73921&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70711&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/03/acba5617dc.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;WeChat picture_20230715215113.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1657&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/acba5617dc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260522&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Mr. Jiang Liangfu’s reading picture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the seventh week of the lecture, something unexpected happened. On the night of October 27, 1979, a petty thief broke into Mr. Jiang’s house through the wind window. First, he stabbed his wife &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (it was later found to be a skin injury)&lt;/span>;. When the husband saw this, he hugged the robber and was killed. He was pushed to the ground, causing a concussion and a fractured tailbone. The next day, the two elders were sent to the hospital for treatment. At this point, the school had no choice but to suspend the Chuci class. We had to take turns to be on duty to accompany our husband, but he refused, saying that our task was to study, not to accompany patients. So we had to go back to our original unit and wait for the notice of resumption of classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late March 1980, I finally received a notice from Hangzhou University to resume school, requiring me to register on April 5th and start school on April 7th. I arrived at Hangzhou University on April 5 as scheduled, and on the same day I went to visit my husband with my brother Wang Yanhai. My husband recovered well and was very happy to see us. He kept saying, &quot;It&#39;s not easy for you to return to Hangzhou. I&#39;m very happy!&quot; It turns out that my husband already knew that at that time, colleges and universities were evaluating professional titles, raising salaries, and adjusting housing; you If people are not in school &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (even if they are just going out to study)&lt;/span>;, all of this will be in vain. In order to keep up with Mr. Jiang, we completely ignored this. No wonder Mr. Jiang was moved by it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to improve our knowledge structure and expand our knowledge, Hangzhou University also arranged a study tour for us for half a month at the suggestion of my husband. To this end, my husband wrote us twelve more letters of introduction, introducing us to twelve famous experts who were famous teachers in Jiangsu and Zhejiang (also his old friends), namely Chen Zhongfan and Cheng Qianfan from Nanjing University, and Wang Shanye from Yangzhou Normal University. , Bian Xiaoxuan, Zhu Jihai from Suzhou, Zhu Dongrun, Jiang Tianshu, Guo Shaoyu, Chen Zizhan from Fudan University, Xu Zhenyan and Dai Jiaxiang from East China Normal University, Gu Tinglong from Shanghai Library. When I went to get the letter of introduction, my husband earnestly warned me: &quot;You must seriously consult the experts. Master Zhuan Yiduo is your teacher.&quot; My husband&#39;s academic ambition is really admirable. Regarding the specific circumstances of this study visit, I have written an article &quot;Remembering a Study Visit Forty Years Ago&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (published in 2023 July 3 (Southern Weekend)&lt;/span>;, I won’t go into details here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning from the study tour, classes will continue on May 8, twice a week, once in the classroom and once at my husband’s home. The distribution of handouts and individual tutoring will continue as usual. From May 8 to June 29, the teacher gave six more lectures, plus the six lectures in the second half of 1979, for a total of twelve lectures. We record each of these classes and organize them after class. After Kunwu added annotations and Mr. Jiang reviewed it, it became &quot;Lectures on the Modern Interpretation of Chu Ci&quot;. After this book was officially published by Beijing Publishing House in 1981, it immediately caused a sensation in the academic circle of Chu Ci, and Jiang Liangfu became known as the &quot;Twelve Disciples&quot; in the academic circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73922&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70712&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/03/ff1b130855.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;01017a5772bfe4e49e_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1566&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/ff1b130855.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260523&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Mr. Jiang Liangfu&#39;s classroom recordings of the Chu Ci workshop were later compiled into the book &quot;Lectures on the Modern Interpretation of Chu Ci&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to learning Chuci in the Chu Ci class, Mr. Jiang also provided supplementary lessons on our ancient Chinese language, especially philology and phonology. I also gave this big class five or six times. The teacher expressed the profound and difficult phonology knowledge &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (such as &quot;waiting for a call&quot;, etc.)&lt;/span>; in very simple language, It gave us a sudden enlightenment. The teacher also introduced us to the most exquisite &quot;Chengjun Map&quot; by Mr. Taiyan, and said that &quot;Mr. Zhang Taiyan&#39;s &quot;Chengjun Map&quot; is scientific and tells us how to master the laws of circulation&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(see &quot;Chinese Dictionary&quot; compiled by the Zhejiang Provincial Writing Office)&lt;/span>;. Thirty years later, I studied the pronunciation of 28 characters in &quot;Cangjie Book&quot;, which was precisely due to Mr. Taiyan&#39;s &quot;Chengjun Map&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, during the period of studying in the Chu Ci Class, to use a popular saying, it was full of gains. The most important thing is that he taught us an advanced and effective academic method. Specifically, it includes the following three points:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the comprehensive research method, that is, a multi-angle and multi-level research method. &quot;Chu Ci&quot; is an encyclopedia, which not only contains rich historical materials of Chu culture, but also contains many important information about Asian and even Pacific Rim cultures. Therefore, the study of &quot;Chu Ci&quot; cannot just stay at the literary level, but should be carried out in an all-round way. In this regard, Mr. &quot;Chu Ci Tong Zhu&quot; has set a shining example for us. My subsequent analysis of the word &quot;lan&quot; in &quot;The Songs of Chu&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The word &quot;lan&quot; is found 42 times in &quot;The Songs of Chu&quot;. It includes five categories: Peilan, Zeelan, Mulan, Malan, and Orchid)&lt;/span>;, as well as an exploration of the cultural connotation of &quot;Orchid&quot; in Chu Sao&#39;s chant (i.e., the suitable soil of Chu land, the good medicine for fitness, the king&#39;s herb, and poetry Si Zhi Yuan Sou) were all inspired by his teacher and followed his path. My book &quot;Research on Chu Ci Culture&quot; is a study of &quot;Chu Ci&quot; from the perspectives of philosophy, politics, education, aesthetics, literature, history, geography, folk customs, dialects and even botany. It is actually a comprehensive study of Mr. Jiang A practice in research methods. After reading it, Mr. Cui Fuzhang said that &quot;it has the style of an old master&quot;. This not only encouraged me, but also showed that he saw my inheritance of Mr. Jiang&#39;s comprehensive research method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the &quot;triple evidence method&quot;. Since Mr. Wang Jing&#39;an proposed the &quot;double evidence method&quot; of using &quot;materials underground&quot; to &quot;correct materials on paper&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (see His &quot;New Evidence from Ancient History&quot; was praised by all academic circles. Mr. Jiang added &quot;folk custom&quot; to this basis. Not only did he often emphasize the importance of studying the Chu Ci from a folklore perspective in his lectures, and assigned us several folklore reference books, he also cited a large number of folklore materials in the study of &quot;Nine Songs&quot;. For example, when he talked about &quot;National Sorrow&quot;, he cited the &quot;beating and adding officials&quot; in later opera customs to explain that the poem was &quot;used to inspire soldiers.&quot; Folk customs are living historical materials spread among the people. Although they have not been formed into documents, they often contain the shadow of ancient people&#39;s lives. Although Mr. Wang did not explicitly juxtapose the folk customs and &quot;double evidence&quot; he focused on, privately we have combined &quot;folk customs&quot; and &quot;double evidence&quot; into the &quot;triple evidence method.&quot; I later wrote several articles such as &quot;A Study of Chu People&#39;s Divination&quot; and &quot;Speaking of &quot;Girls&quot;&quot;, and I deliberately used this method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is the comparative memory method. I was surprised by his extraordinary memory, so I asked him how he could remember so many Chu Ci documents. The teacher said that it relies on comparative memory, that is, comparing the similarities and differences of different schools of thought on a certain issue. In this way, the document comes alive and is no longer a rigid dogma. I tried this and it had good results. For example, regarding &quot;Qiu Nu&quot; and &quot;Two Ascensions to Kunlun&quot; in &quot;Li Sao&quot;, I will sort out the sayings of Wang Yi, Tang Dynasty, Song Dynasty, Ming and Qing Dynasties, and even Wen Yiduo, You Guoen and Jiang Liangfu. , understand the similarities and differences, not only the problem is clarified, but also the key points of the various versions are memorized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be said that Mr. Jiang’s academic methods can be applied not only to Chu Ci, but also to other ancient literary works. This is fully proved by my comprehensive research on &quot;Strange Stories from a Chinese Studio&quot; from the perspective of Chinese and Western communication as well as from the perspectives of religion, folklore, journalism, etc. ;&quot;>;(See my work &quot;Liao Zhai Cong Kao&quot;)&lt;/span>;. The &quot;research of ancient literature from a macro-cultural perspective&quot; that I later advocated when I was doing research and supervising graduate students was also proposed on the basis of Mr. Jiang&#39;s &quot;comprehensive research method&quot; and I will keep it in mind throughout my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chu Ci Class has gone through two stages of learning, and it is finally coming to an end. On the morning of June 28, 1980, Hangzhou University held a graduation ceremony for the advanced training course on Chu Ci. The school department leaders, Mr. Jiang and all the students attended. Mr. Jiang delivered an affectionate speech at the ceremony. He said: &quot;I was hospitalized because I was injured by a robber. The school decided to suspend classes and let students return to school to wait for the notice of resumption of classes. After the notice of resumption of classes came out, were our classmates interested in coming back? As a result, all the students came, and some even stayed in school. I have classes, and I am in the &quot;work transfer&quot;, involving professional titles, wages, houses... I don&#39;t care about anything, just throw it away... and then continue it after the interruption, without any trace. You can report to the Ministry of Education, is this happening across the country? Class? Everyone has more or less seen the future and interests of the country and the nation, so they came here to study. It goes without saying that you studied hard during your studies at Hangzhou University... I am eighty years old, and I am the best in the world to have made so many friends like you. This is a rare thing, I am deeply grateful!&quot; Finally, Mr. encouraged the students and said: &quot;You keep walking, I will follow you!&quot; &quot;>;(Mr. Jiang&#39;s speech is based on the records of Brother Yin Guangxi)&lt;/span>; It not only reveals Mr. Jiang&#39;s consistent humility and sincerity, but also is full of love and fervent hope for students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the graduation ceremony, following Mr. Jiang’s speech, I couldn’t help but make a speech, mainly talking about the teachings I received from Mr. Jiang and what I gained from participating in the Chu Ci class. Although I was completely unprepared, I had never given such a heartfelt speech before. When I spoke, my husband kept nodding and smiling. I know that Mr. Xi is very satisfied with the hard work and concentration of our students. After the ceremony, I sent my husband home. On the way back, my husband told me that he had read the book report I wrote on Liu Mengpeng&#39;s &quot;Quzi Chapters&quot; and it was well written. The main things had been captured. He also asked me to condense it a little more and write it as &quot;Chinese Poetry&quot;. An entry in the Encyclopedia. Sir, sir, you really care about your disciples&#39; studies all the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the graduation ceremony, the day of separation is coming. Just as several of our class committee members &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Hao Zhida, Lin Weichun, Yin Guangxi, Zhao Haoru, Zhang Chongchen)&lt;/span>; were discussing how to express our gratitude to our teacher, Jiang However, Mr. Jiang sent his son-in-law, Mr. Xu, to inform us that Mr. Jiang was going to host a banquet for all the students of our Chuci class at the &quot;Lou Wai Lou&quot; restaurant. This really surprised us. Since ancient times, when students graduate, only students have invited teachers. How can teachers hire students? I think this exceptional approach by Mr. not only reflects the great importance he attaches to the friendship between teachers and students, but also implies his excellent impression of our class of students. At the banquet, we frequently raised glasses to express our gratitude to our husband and wish our teacher good health and longevity. Mr. Jiang was also very happy and looked at every student kindly. My husband once again told us earnestly and earnestly to study and work hard after returning to the unit. If we have any problems in our studies in the future, we can write to him at any time to continue discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to spend more time with my husband, we invited him to Huanglong Cave for tea on June 30, and he went happily. While drinking tea, my husband was still discussing studies with us. He asked us to each write an article about Chuci when we return and hand it in next year for him to publish a collection. He also told us that everyone’s graduation appraisals have been written and can be picked up in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the afternoon, I came to my husband’s house as scheduled and took back the completion appraisals of the twelve students. I circulated them to everyone first, and then submitted them to the Hangzhou University for approval and sent them back to the original unit. It can be seen that although the time we spend with our husband is not very long, he is well aware of everyone&#39;s temperament and academic characteristics, and he is very encouraging. One of them about me is:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Comrade Zhang Chongchen is a middle-aged teacher who is well-versed in books. This is the most important method of reading. If you only specialize in one or two subjects, it will naturally be easy to achieve success, but your achievements will inevitably be limited. Returning from the major to the appointment, and then being able to truly master what you want to master, this is the basic element of the comprehensive research method that has been popular in recent years. He is also very careful and honest in his reading. He recently wrote a book report on &quot;Reading Liu Mengpeng&#39;s &quot;Quzi Chapters&quot;&quot;. It seems that his deep understanding of Liu Shu&#39;s strengths is inseparable from his extensive knowledge and carefulness. . He is a rising star in our team. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Jiang Liangfu June 30, 1980&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: sans-serif;&quot;>;On the evening of July 4, 1980, I went to Mr. Jiang’s place to say goodbye. My husband told me solemnly that he hoped I could come to Hangzhou University and be his assistant. Of course I was very happy to hear that. But I knew that the transfer had to be approved by Lanzhou University, so I told my husband that I would work hard for it. Unexpectedly, after going back to school and putting in a lot of effort, Lanzhou University still refused to let him go. I wrote to my husband and he told me to go first and he would pay me my salary. I know that your husband is following the example of Gu Jiegang, Tong Shuye and Tan Qixiang back then, but times have changed, and all college teachers must be included in the system; moreover, how can I bear to take up my husband&#39;s salary! So the thing didn&#39;t work out in the end, and I can only regret it for the rest of my life. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: sans-serif;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73920&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70710&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/03/6bcde815f5.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;WeChat picture_20230715162921.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;879&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/6bcde815f5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260524&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: sans-serif;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Jiang Liangfu and the author of this article ( Figure right). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, although the assistant was not regarded as such, the correspondence between our teachers and students continued. And every time I write a letter, my husband always responds, even when my eyesight has deteriorated and I can no longer distinguish my fingers. In recent years, I have taken out more than a dozen of my husband’s letters and re-read them, and every time I read them, I couldn’t help but shed tears. I am deeply grateful to my husband for his teaching and care for me, and I am always grateful for this unforgettable teacher-student encounter between me and my husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨樊纲：进入中等收入阶段后，真正重要的是后发优势]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261770]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic , Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;PhD profile:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Fan Gang, the first doctorate in the history of Western economic thought in New China (tied with Zuo Dapei). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in Beijing in September 1953 city. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1969, he went to Heilongjiang Production and Construction Corps Farming, in 1975, transferred to Weichang County, Hebei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1982, Hebei University Bachelor&#39;s degree in Economics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1982-1985, Chinese society Graduate student in Western Economics at the Academy of Sciences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985-1988, Chinese society PhD candidate in Western Economics at the Academy of Sciences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985-1987, went to the United States Studied at the National Bureau of Economic Research and Harvard University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1988, he entered China with a Ph.D. Work at the Institute of Economics, Academy of Social Sciences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1992, he was promoted to the Chinese Society of A researcher at the Academy of Sciences, he was rated as a national-level young and middle-aged expert with outstanding contributions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1994-1995, served as China Deputy Director of the Institute of Economics, Academy of Social Sciences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1995-2015, served as China Chairman and legal representative of the Economic Reform Research Foundation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since 1996, he has served as the head of China’s economic system Vice president of the Reform Research Association and concurrently director of the Beijing Institute of National Economic Research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;2006-2010, 2015 -In 2018, he served as a member of the Central Monetary Policy Committee twice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since 2012, he has served as a national high-end think tank Vice Chairman and President of the Board of Directors of China (Shenzhen) Comprehensive Development Research Institute. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On August 26, 2020, Fan Gang delivered a keynote speech at the World Ocean City Qingdao Forum. (Provided by People&#39;s Vision Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/15c14a9ac8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/15c14a9ac8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260526&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: justify;&quot;>;On August 26, 2020, Fan Gang gave a keynote speech at the World Ocean City Qingdao Forum. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 18, 1968, China’s northernmost black land entered the best season of the year. A unit with the main task of “reclamation and border defense”-Heilongjiang Production Construction Corps - established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In pursuit of the goal of &quot;reclaiming the Great Northern Wilderness&quot;, millions of urban educated youths have gone to a foreign country that is covered in frost all year round. In the vigorous tide of the times, young Fan Gang is no exception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Fan Gang was born in 1953 in an intellectual family. His parents left Shanghai after graduating from church school and went to work in Beijing. There, after Fan Gang finished primary school, the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; began and he was assigned to attend a nearby middle school. But in just the past year and a half, the general environment has changed. In 1969, Fan Gang, who had just learned a few English letters, was assigned to work in the Heilongjiang Corps as an educated youth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Logging, clearing up wasteland, and farming, it took six years in a flash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Despite being separated from the school environment, Fan Gang is still learning and thinking. Around 1974, the Heilongjiang Production and Construction Corps discussed trialling the work point system and reforming the original fixed wage system, and Fan Gang&#39;s company was selected as one of the pilots. Relying on the &quot;Dialectical Materialism and Historical Materialism&quot; and &quot;Political Economics Textbooks&quot; he had read, Fan Gang put forward his own opinions on the pilot plan and was invited to attend a meeting at the Corps headquarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 1975, Fan Gang was transferred to the countryside of Weichang County, Hebei Province, where his cousin lived, because he was visiting relatives and friends. There, there are only two meals a day in winter. After finishing millet porridge at 5 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, people are starving by seven or eight o&#39;clock. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But soon, a turning point came. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Less than a year after leaving the village, Fan Gang was seconded to the county cultural center to engage in mass literary and artistic creation. In 1977, Fan Gang was experiencing life in the commune iron foundry when he heard the news on the radio about the resumption of the college entrance examination. Relying on the knowledge accumulated through years of reading miscellaneous books, he stood out from more than 5.7 million candidates across the country and was admitted to the Department of Economics of Hebei University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Four years later, Fan Gang was admitted to the Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, which had absolute authority in the field of economics at the time, and studied under Professor Zhu Shaowen, continuing to study his favorite field. Western Economics. There, Fan Gang&#39;s talent in economics was recognized again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 1985, upon the recommendation of Dong Fucheng, then director of the Institute of Economics of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, Fan Gang was given the opportunity to study abroad, studying at the National Bureau of Economic Research and Harvard University in the United States. economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As important as talent is Fan Gang&#39;s diligence. Mentor Zhu Shaowen once mentioned that Fan Gang worked very hard when he was studying in the United States. He often couldn&#39;t get home because he left too late, so he slept under the table in the research bureau. In 1988, Fan Gang, who returned to China after completing his studies, successfully completed his doctoral thesis, and together with his fellow student Zuo Dapei, became the first two Western economics Ph.D.s independently trained in China after the reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After receiving his degree, Fan Gang continued to stay at the Institute of Economics of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;His academic achievements and social influence extend far beyond the ivory tower. In the 1990s and early 21st century when China&#39;s reform and opening up set off huge waves, Fan Gang was a representative of young scholars in the economics community. At the age of 38, he won the Sun Yefang Economic Science Award, the highest award in domestic economics research; at the age of 39, he was promoted to the Academy of Social Sciences. Researcher; at the age of 40, he became one of the youngest doctoral supervisors in the Chinese social science community; in addition to academic work, he was twice appointed by the State Council as a member of the Central Bank&#39;s Monetary Policy Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For his contributions and achievements in the field of transition economics, Fan Gang won the highest award in the domestic economic theory circle, the &quot;China Economic Theory Innovation Award.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, along with the honor and cheers, there are also doubts from the outside world. In 2018, during an interview with the media, Fan Gang was pushed into the limelight because of his view of &quot;emptying 6 wallets to buy a house.&quot; When asked about this view again two years later, Fan Gang responded that it was intended to express that houses were too expensive for young people to afford, rather than to encourage young people to &quot;gnaw at their old age.&quot; However, if he hadn&#39;t been asked again, he &quot;couldn&#39;t remember it&quot; himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On November 2, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters met this 70-year-old scholar who is still energetic. Perhaps as a result of studying economics for many years, Fan Gang has a consistent determination, as if all the great changes of the times are just pebbles thrown into the lake to him, and all he wants is to &quot;hope that China will do well.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Only debate is exciting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;Southern Weekend&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; When the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977, you were admitted to the Department of Economics of Hebei University. Why did you choose this major? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;I went to the countryside in Heilongjiang Production and Construction Corps in 1969. The books I read at that time were all related to Marxism-Leninism, philosophy, political economics, and scientific socialism. After a lot of study, I found that I was more interested in political economics. &lt;br>;At that time, we also faced practical problems, which made people think. At that time, a company of the Construction Corps could still make a profit by farming with just 20 people. However, when more than 100 of us educated youths left, the cost increased and we actually lost money. It is said that labor creates value, how should we understand it now? At the same time, everyone is trying to change the status quo, which makes me more interested in economic issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition to reading theoretical books, I was also interested in literature. At that time, everyone wanted to be a literary and artistic young man, so I also worked hard on writing. Later, I also engaged in creation at the county cultural center and wrote some folk art programs. But literary creation relies on perceptual thinking. At that time, I thought that this aspect was not my real interest, because I was not good at telling stories and I was not motivated to tell them. What&#39;s the excitement, the theoretical debate, I get excited as soon as the debate starts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The college entrance examination was resumed in 1977, and everyone could apply for three choices. I applied for economics in all of them, but not literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;You once mentioned that you are still When you went to the countryside in Heilongjiang, you once made suggestions for the reform of the work-point system, but they were not adopted. Did this experience dampen your enthusiasm for economics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;I don’t feel frustrated or unhappy. At that time, the Corps headquarters was discussing whether to change fixed wages to a work-point system, and our company was selected as the pilot. Because I had learned a little bit about political economics, I wrote a paper with my ideas, and the company instructor handed it to me. Later, the Corps invited the two of us to attend a seminar at the Corps headquarters in Jiamusi. It could be said to be my first seminar on economic issues. It was a pleasure for me to participate in the discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At that time, I was indeed very interested in theoretical research. Although I was not a professional and had no education, my interest was still very important. In the evening, everyone We all went to bed, and I was reading and writing alone under the oil lamp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;When the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977, you Is the economics major you want to take the exam highly competitive? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>; At that time, there were very few subjects and very few enrollments. For the political economics major, Peking University has one enrollment quota in Hebei Province, Jilin University has only one in Hebei, and the others are Hebei University. &lt;br>;Before I went to the countryside, I was only a primary school graduate and never went to middle school. When I knew that I was going to take the college entrance examination, I only had a little over two months of review time left. Fortunately, I never stopped reading in those years, and I could find all the books I could find. I read them all, so I relied on the &quot;foundation&quot; of reading miscellaneous books in literature, history and philosophy at that time, and I learned mathematics in those two months. There were a total of 8 textbooks in middle school. I studied a little more than 7, and finally scored more than 60 points in the test. Attended Hebei University. Now that I think about it, the whole review process was not easy, and I grasped the last straw. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; You once mentioned that most of the university courses during your studies were classical economics. When did you first come into contact with modern economics? &lt;br>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;I always say that we are a relatively lucky generation. When we first went to college in 1978, China’s economy was at its lowest point, with per capita income and economic growth rate very low. The Third Plenary Session of the First Central Committee was held, and the concept of reform gradually took shape. But in fact, what everyone was more familiar with at that time was the Soviet-style political economics. The modern economic theoretical system was not systematically taught in various universities. Only Professor Jiang Guangyuan, the department chair of Hebei University, did this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Professor Jiang graduated from Peking University with a master&#39;s degree in economics in the 1950s. He studied Western economics in his early years. During the ten years of turmoil, a group of them were decentralized and later transferred to support Hebei University. When I was a senior in college, when other schools were still teaching the &quot;school&quot; of Western economics, he gave us a textbook on the principles of modern economics in a systematic way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It is also because this course allows us to master modern economics more systematically, so that we can realize that in those years when we were isolated from the world, modern economic theory It has become very complicated and needs to be remedied quickly. Only in this way can we talk to the world and know in which direction the theory should develop. So later I went to the Academy of Social Sciences for graduate school, and chose the history of Western economic thought as a major, and continued along this path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fan Gang&#39;s doctoral degree certificate. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/03/a8924b415f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/03/a8924b415f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260527&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Fan Gang’s doctoral degree certificate. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;We must not forget those who sit on the bench&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Professor Zhu Shaowen was your supervisor when you were studying for your master&#39;s degree and doctoral degree. What influence did he have on you when you were studying? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;Professor Zhu’s guidance mainly focused on learning and thinking methods. He emphasized the need to read the original works and lay down a solid foundation in basic theory. , forcing us to read many original English works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; What is your relationship with Professor Zhu over the years? Master and apprentice are like father and son. What kind of person do you think he is? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Professor Zhu is a very persistent person. In a certain sense, it can be said to be a bit stubborn, very persistent, Very stubborn. He sticks to his point of view, no matter what others say. After the reform and opening up, when everyone stopped talking about Marxist economic theory, Mr. Zhu still talked about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Decades ago, he admired the views of List, the originator of German development economics. At that time, List believed that Germany was relatively backward and could not Economic measures adopted by developed countries must be adopted immediately, and there must be protection and certain government controls. Later, Japan learned from Germany, and Professor Zhu introduced these theories to China when he was studying at the University of Tokyo. But Professor Zhu&#39;s views were not recognized at that time, but now facts have proven that thanks to some unique industrial policies, our economy can develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; Development economics advocated by Professor Zhu The point of view has also been inherited by you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>; Some. To be honest, when the country was first opened, we paid more attention to the market economy itself. We were preoccupied with studying why other countries were so efficient and developed so advancedly, and we wanted to learn from Western systems to develop ourselves. At that time, before Western countries and we had reached the stage of competition, we were developing labor-intensive industries, and academic research was mainly concentrated in the field of institutional economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It was not until the new century that we began to have some development competition with developed countries that we began to think more about development economics. After 2010, I started teaching development economics to graduate students at Peking University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Except for Professor Zhu, the past twenty During your years of study and research, are there any teachers whose teachings have had a greater impact on you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;This is a long story. One was Dong Fucheng, the director of the institute at the time. I once said in a commemorative article that I was able to study abroad because Director Dong gave me the only indicator. He felt that I had a foundation in foreign languages ​​​​and Western economics and could make good use of this opportunity, even though I was still young at the time. Not from the place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The second person who had a great influence on me was Liu Guoguang, the then vice president of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. He advocated reform. In the late 1980s and early 1990s, with his approval, we were able to set up a research group and write the book &quot;Outline of Macroeconomic Theory of Public Ownership&quot;. Although some of the views in this book were unclear at the time. Not entirely consistent with his views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;There is also Professor Zhang Shuguang, who is now 84 years old. He is both my collaborator and my predecessor. He was the deputy chief author of the &quot;Outline of Macroeconomic Theory of Public Ownership&quot;. Compared to me, the main writer, he has personally experienced the era of planned economy and many early research experiences, and is more familiar with the reality of China. When writing the book, I had many in-depth exchanges with him, and the theoretical system of the book was also constructed by us together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;There are also some old gentlemen who, although I have not had much contact with them, left a deep impression on me, such as Wu Baosan. He returned from studying economics at Harvard and advocated using more scientific methods to analyze China&#39;s economic history. When he studied history, he not only saw the historical facts, but also saw the economic logic within it. In order to do research, he spent a lot of effort. Even during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, he still wrote a lot of things in his study, which was not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From today&#39;s perspective, they have been sitting on the bench for many years and have contributed to the basic project of Chinese economics. Don&#39;t forget them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Consensus is &quot;balance&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;During your PhD studies, you went to study in the United States and came up with the idea of ​​using modern economics theory to explain China’s problems. How could you come up with such an idea if you are not at the center of the reform trend? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;After all, I had been studying economics for nearly ten years before going abroad, and at the same time, I was studying China&#39;s economic issues. In addition, after graduating from elementary school, I first stayed in the Heilongjiang Corps for six years, and then stayed in rural Hebei for two years. I had a real sense of poverty in rural areas, and also a real sense of China&#39;s economic problems. I have personally seen people in a state where they don’t have enough to eat. I still remember one time when I went to a house in the village. A middle-aged man was lying on the kang. I asked him why he didn&#39;t go to work. He said that there was some food for my son to eat at noon. If he went to the fields, I couldn&#39;t go there. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After I went abroad and learned more things, I felt that I began to &quot;integrate&quot; theoretical and practical issues. The knowledge accumulated in the first 10 years of studying economics, Coupled with constant thinking about practical problems, I feel that I can better explain China&#39;s economic problems. I feel that I can do a lot of things, and these things are not what I can do abroad. I must do it with everyone at home. I did it, so I insisted on returning to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; Regarding the Chinese economic theory at that time, Do you have any clear ideas or plans for renovation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>; There is no systematic plan, I just feel that there is a need for systematic understanding and change. For example, at that time, there was an endless debate in China about which was the truth, Marxist political economics or modern economics. When I was writing my doctoral thesis, I gradually realized that any theory is a process of continuous innovation and synthesis. Different theories The theories will gradually integrate and learn from each other&#39;s strengths, so I wrote my doctoral thesis &quot;Comparison and Synthesis of the Three Major Modern Economic Theoretical Systems&quot;. The purpose at that time was that no matter what others said, I figured it out myself. From now on, if I encounter this kind of problem again, I won’t be entangled or come back to it again and again. My point of view is in this book. I don’t have to discuss it over and over again, so I can be free to study real economic issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;So in the first ten years after I came back, I wrote several big books with millions of words, as well as some papers and essays. After finishing them, I felt It&#39;s easier. Not only do you no longer need to worry about some issues, but your theoretical views will also be more consistent, and you won&#39;t have to do this now, then that, and always have to revise and correct yourself later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;When I graduated with my Ph.D., the school had Are you saying that you are the first doctorate majoring in the history of Western economic thought? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;Everyone may know that I am the first doctorate in this major, but in fact, Mr. Zhu led a total of I have obtained three master&#39;s degrees and two doctorates. I graduated with Zuo Dapei. You can say that I am the first, and you can also say that Zuo Dapei is the first. When we graduated, we didn’t have doctoral hats or gowns, so there was no sense of ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;During his doctoral studies, Professor Zhu did not You were allowed to participate in social discussions too early, so you only embarked on the path of &quot;managing the world for practical use&quot; after graduating from your Ph.D. What goals did you have at that time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>;I got the associate senior professional title two years after I graduated with a Ph.D., and passed French and English in the third year. After passing the foreign language exam and publishing works on a certain scale, I was promoted to full professor under the exception, and all the professional title matters were completed around the age of 40. For me personally, I don’t want to be an official or do business. I really don’t have any specific goals. All I want to do is write something that can have an impact on others and contribute to the development of a discipline. However, I have also done some administrative work in recent years, including being responsible for two or three research institutions and fulfilling some social responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;In 2006, you became the central bank currency Member of the Policy Committee and served two terms thereafter. During this period, a series of problems such as the 2008 global economic crisis occurred one after another. Do you have any special observations during this tenure? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang&lt;/strong>;: It is very beneficial to participate in some discussions at this level. You can observe closely how various ministries and commissions consider issues. From different angles, we can enhance our understanding of the so-called interest subjects. Different ministries and commissions are responsible for different things. They not only represent the overall interests of the country, but also represent different interest groups and have different perspectives. During the discussion, the people sitting in the room, that is, representatives of various ministries and commissions, will bring their own issues and perspectives to the decision-making circle. Everyone will speak out and explain these issues clearly. The consensus reached in this way will be To a certain extent, it is what is called &quot;equilibrium&quot; in economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Goals should not be specific to things like position and money&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; Judging from the papers you published, you have many academic opinions that directly point to institutional issues. It seems that you are not a &quot;pacified&quot; scholar-official in the traditional Confucian concept. Image, is this a common trait among economists or is it just your personality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fan Gang:&lt;/strong>; There are also people who are more radical than me. One reason is that after the reform and opening up, there was a better environment, everyone spoke more openly, and the problems we faced at that time were more realistic and acute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But I don’t want to do anything to impress people. If I talk about a certain problem, the premise is that in my opinion, the problem really exists, and I I don’t want to turn a 3-point question into a 5-point or 10-point question. Although sometimes what I say is sharp, the purpose is to mention some constructive ideas. The ultimate goal is to solve the problem. This is the bottom line I have always adhered to. I hope China is good, and I hope that China can continue to develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; Do you have conflicts with others during the discussion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Fan Gang: &lt;/strong>; There will always be some differences in views, and there are even some deeper differences, but in most cases in these years If you do n’t go to argue with others, I always feel that it is good to explain my own point of view. It is a matter of others who do not accept it. You do n’t have to want to convince anyone. This will consume a lot of energy and it does n’t make sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; But in early February this year, I published an article in &quot;Manage the World&quot;, which put forward my difference in the views of Professor Lin Yifu&#39;s comparative advantages, view. The so -called comparative advantage is to say that a backward country must make good use of the advantages of low cost of certain production factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; My basic point is that the comparative advantage is only important in the early stages of our economic development, that is, the stage before and after the WTO, the salary of the migrant workers before the soaring salary of the migrant workers . When we enter the middle income stage, the comparative advantage is gradually decreased. At this time, what is really important is the &quot;post -issuing advantage&quot;, that is, through opening, learning, introduction, digestion, and absorption. Knowledge and technology allows these knowledge to play a role in our country and realize the spillover of intellectual elements. Our development not only introduced advanced technology and equipment at the beginning, but has exerted the advantages of the post -development. In recent years, the growth of more than 20 years has mainly relied on the various knowledge and technologies learned after opening up, and gradually learned the ability of innovation . Now Americans try to curb our development, various methods of curbing, decoupling, disconnecting, stopping academic exchanges, restricting international students, etc., all are all to curb us to play the advantage. They don&#39;t care about your comparative advantage at all, because your comparative advantage is only the cost advantage of some &quot;primary elements&quot;. You can only engage in the labor dense type that they do not care about, and what they really jealous is how we pass the post -posting advantage and fast fast. Growth knowledge and technology &quot;high -quality elements&quot; have made them lose their comparative advantages in this regard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; You mentioned in autobiography, During his visit to Harvard University, he was very touched by their graduate training methods. After returning to China, I tried at the Graduate School. What adjustments did you make at that time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Fan Gang: &lt;/strong>; Harvard&#39;s graduate student will take two years of lessons and pass the Qualify test to start writing papers. Graduate students are not textbooks, but they are directly lectured. Even if they just published it yesterday, as long as everyone thinks it is valuable, textbooks are only used for reference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; When I returned to China, I felt that Chinese graduate education needs to be improved. For example, Haiwen, Zhang Weiying and others gave lectures to the graduate students of the Academy of Sciences. I also gave two semesters myself to improve the knowledge level of the graduate school of the Department of Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; Is there any advice for college students and graduate groups? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Fan Gang: &lt;/strong>; I have never allowed myself to do &quot;young mentor&quot;, so there is no suggestion in life. My &quot;suggestion&quot; is that the goal should not be similar to things such as positions and money, but I should think about how to make something decent and provide my own contribution to obtain social recognition. From the perspective of life, this is a true satisfaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方回应“五月天被质疑假唱”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261781]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 20:09:02 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recent The audio was identified and believed that there were fake singing in many songs, which caused widespread attention. This year&#39;s &quot;May Day&quot; also performed many performances in Beijing Bird&#39;s Nest. On December 3, Nandu reporters called the Beijing Cultural Market Comprehensive Law Enforcement Corps. Staff said that it was known that discussions on the Internet would be highly concerned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/cddc8251f7dd3a37935FB455F398d2.jpeg&quot; width = &quot;800&quot; height = &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/cddc8251f7dd3a37935d8FB455F398D2.JPEG&quot; Data-Key = &quot;260545&quot; Data-MCE-Wi dth = &quot;0&quot; data- MCE-Height = &quot;0&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Blog lead has a wide range of discussions on the &quot;true and false singing&quot; identification of the &quot;Mayday&quot; concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the end of November to the beginning of December, the blogger &quot;Mai Tian Farmers&quot; &quot;analyzed&quot; the &quot;Mayday&quot; two concert audio audio of &quot;Mayday&quot; in Shanghai and London. Or part of the paragraph is a fake singing, which has attracted widespread attention. In this regard, the &quot;Mayday&quot; and the territorial management departments of related concerts have not responded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This year, &quot;Mayday&quot; also held a number of large -scale concerts in the National Gymnasium (Bird&#39;s Nest). On December 3, a reporter from Nandu contacted the Beijing Cultural Market Comprehensive Law Enforcement Team. It is not possible to determine whether the performance of the &quot;Mayday&quot; Beijing field is a fake singing, but it will maintain great attention in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above -mentioned staff introduced to Nandu reporters that Article 28 of the &quot;Regulations on the Management Management of Business Performances&quot; stipulates that &quot;actors must not deceive the audience by fake singing, and the performance organizer shall not organize actors to sing. Any unit of all units. Or individuals must not provide conditions for fake singing. &quot;The Implementation Rules for the Management of Business Performances clearly states that&quot; fake singing refers to the actor&#39;s use of pre -recorded songs instead of live singing during the performance. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt; P>; For the basic situation of the actor&#39;s singing process, the &quot;Rules&quot; also stipulates that the performance organizer shall send a special person to supervise the singing behavior and make a record for investigation. The record must be signed and confirmed by the person in charge of the performance organizer and the supervisor. If netizens have relevant information and evidence, they can report to the government management department corresponding to the concert. Beijing&#39;s report call is 010-12345. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[野猪再闹南京城，救护人员称不应投喂野生动物]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261774]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 18:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img img-id = &quot;73946&quot; group-id = &quot;0&quot; asset-id = &quot;70737&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/a0d227fcf1.jpg&quot; IMG- Title = &quot;February 2022, the foothills of the Wild pig police signs Federation. Visual China Map. Jpg &quot;ALT =&quot; In February 2022, the foothills of Zijin Mountain in the Zhongshan Scenic Area in Nanjing, the wild boar police sign is noticeable. Visual Chinese map &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height = &quot;810&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/a0d227fcf1.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;260528&quot; style = &quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In February 2022, the foothills of Zijin Mountain in the Zhongshan Scenic Area in Nanjing, the signs of the wild boar police are noticeable. Visual China Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wild pig was finally trapped in a river channel with more than 3 meters wide and about two hundred meters long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At noon on November 29, 2023, this wild boar that only appeared in Jianye District, Nanjing, Nanjing, has caused a lot of commotion. Finally, the police were driven to this little small named South Hubei. In the ditch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The riverside on the left is the low lawn, and the palm cluster is about one meter up, and the wild boar hides under the palm bush and avoids it. Dozens of special police and auxiliary policemen took the shield, and explosion -proof steel forks were waiting. Two staff members from the Hongshan Zoo Wildlife Rescue Center came from about 2 meters away from it to emergency formula for anesthesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the road on the right bank of the river, many residents have stood. In the video shot by netizens, a takeaway brother in the crowd rang the notice of assigning orders, and the voice was kicked off, and no one left; another uncle was carrying a bag of persimmons in his hand and standing onlookers; a lady walked the dog to walk the dog. After, I couldn&#39;t stop looking at the river and began to stop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We have never seen such new things, and we have never seen it.&quot; Wei Zhennan, deputy director of the Yiyuan Community Neighborhood Committee of Jianye District, Nanjing, told reporters from the Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Nanjing, the wild boar is the most frequent wildlife. The Nanjing Municipal Government has stated that it will formulate and improve the emergency plan for the disposal of wild boar police. Work. But for Wei Zhennan, such a big movement of hunting wild boars has never been seen before. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Water pigs &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Earlier media reports that the wild boar appeared on a campus in Jian&#39;ou District, Nanjing. After the security guard was found to be worried about the wild pig hurt, he called the police for help. After receiving the police, Nanjing Jianye went to the scene to search, and the wild boar began to rush out of the school and fled around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A staff member of the Beilei community in Nanhu Street told the southern weekend reporter that when the wild boar came to the community, it was six or seven in the morning. They had not yet went to work. . According to media reports, a security guard in the Beilei community was knocked down and bitten by a wild boar, and was sent to the hospital for six stitches. The above -mentioned staff said that they had to condolences to the injured security guards, but did not disclose the injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Yiyuan community, Wei Zhennan was already more than nine in the morning when he received a property phone call. The other party informed the residents to find that there was a wild boar activity in the jurisdiction. &quot;I thought it was a small wild boar at that time.&quot; Wei Zhennan also felt novel. After checking the monitoring with the community police, he found that at seven o&#39;clock in the morning, the wild boar had strolled in the community. In the monitoring, the wild boar was strong and there were more than two hundred pounds. &quot;So the police quickly requested support.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When Wei Zhennan rushed to the hiding place of the wild boar, the police of Jianye District had begun to take a warning and prepare to be arrested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Near 11 o&#39;clock, Li Feng (a pseudonym) of the Dynamic Institute of Wildlife Rescue Center of Hongshan Zoo received a call from the 110 Police Center and hurried to the scene. For Li Feng, this is part of his daily work. Every day he receives five or six wild animals for help, involving birds, snakes, wild boars and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is dangerous to shoot anesthesia for wild boars. Generally, Li Feng will work with colleagues to work with colleagues. The distance between blowing is 3-5 meters. Li Feng explained that it is far away. The injection cannot be pierced through the pig skin, and the anesthesia drugs are slow. If it is too close, the risk of the staff increases. The wild boar reaction was much faster than people. One time after the wild boar injected anesthesia, the staff chased for nearly two kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This time on the banks of the South Hubei, Li Feng held anesthesia and blowing the pipe, squatted below the palm bush, and slowly poked his head to aim at the wild boar. The first anesthesia needle was shot to the head and neck of the wild boar, and the wild boar drilled out of the palm bush, bumped the police on the side, and soared along the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The crowds of the onlookers immediately surged. Police and community staff quickly increased their volume and evacuated the residents of the onlookers. It&#39;s okay. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the video shot by the media, after the wild boar ran hundreds of meters, it returned from the river. Li Feng took advantage of the wild boar to go ashore, and then shot three anesthesia. Li Feng estimated that the anesthesia was effective after about half an hour, and the wild boar was blocked under the bridge hole and took it ashore. However, because the wild boar anesthesia water, it was dying when she went ashore, and died on the way to Hongshan Zoo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the local media released a live video of catching wild boars, netizens suspected that it was the previous &quot;crossing Jiang Meng pig&quot; -the 12 minutes on November 27 crossed the Yangtze River and went to Nanjing. When crossing the river, Yao Chengyu, the head of the Ship Transportation Management Center of the Nanjing Maritime Safety Administration, found it in the monitoring, watching it flexibly escape many large ships and traffic at high speeds on the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tang Xiaofan, director of the Party and Mass Work Department of the Nanjing Maritime Safety Administration, said that although there were many vessels connected by the channel at that time, the wild pigs would not cause the ship to be damaged, but the wild boar was not damaged. It is easy to die. For the staff of the Maritime Bureau, large wild animals like wild boars appear rarely in the river surface, and more common are wildlife such as porpoons and birds. In terms of wildlife protection, they mainly cooperate with the Nanjing Municipal Government departments to delineate the ecological protection zone, forbidden navigation in the ecological reserve, and reduce water quality pollution in the Yangtze River. They do not need to deal with wild boar traffic accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; After the rescue &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend found that in November 2023, there were many wild pigs in Nanjing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 1st, a woman in Jiangning District, Nanjing sat at the door of the restaurant and met wild boars and quickly fled into the store. The restaurant owner said that the aunt in the restaurant was not bitten, and the wild boar left quickly, and they did not call the police. On November 10, the media reported that Mr. Zhou, a citizen of Nanjing, collided with a wild boar while driving, and his vehicle was damaged. Mr. Zhou told the southern weekend that the wild boar was injured after being hit, and passers -by called the Hongshan Zoo Wildlife Acceptance Rescue Center to drag it away. The subsequent friends of Mr. Zhou asked the wild boar treatment and learned that the wild boar could not be saved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Southern Weekend reporters repeatedly called the Nanjing Public Security Bureau to ask the wild boar police situation on December 1 and failed to get a reply. On the website of the Nanjing Municipal Government, a reporter from the southern weekend found that a report was published on July 5, 2022. The Nanjing Garden Greening Bureau&#39;s response to the Nanjing People&#39;s Congress on the proposal of wild boars in rural areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The answer mentioned that in recent years, due to the improvement of the ecological environment, the number of wild pig species in Nanjing has grown rapidly, and the scope of activities has continued to expand. Wild pigs are not. The news of wild boars out of the mountain forests, frequently entered the news of tourist attractions, parks, transportation roads, residential communities, shopping malls, campuses, etc., which has been reported to destroy crops, destroy facilities, and even cause personal injury. One of the hidden dangers of safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From January to May 2022, the Nanjing Public Security Bureau reported a total of 201 parts involving wild boar police conditions, covering many administrative districts in the city, mainly for the traffic accidents caused by the accident caused by the accident, and the invasion of wild boars invaded the wild pig wait. Faced with such alarm situation, the territorial public security organs all sent members to the scene for the first time to deal with it. If the situation is critical and possibly threatened the public&#39;s personal safety, after the on -site evaluation and other standardized processes Work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Feng remembers that in 2022, the number of wild boars in Hongshan Zoo was 32, and it was reduced by ten in 2023. He believes that it is about to be removed from the wild boar from the &quot;three&quot; protective animals. In July 2023, the State Forestry and Grassland Bureau officially released the adjustment of the &quot;Land Wild Animal List with important ecology, science, and social value&quot;, and the wild boar is not in this list. This means that wild boars are no longer protecting animals, and further simplify the procedures for wild boar hunting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Feng suggested that if the citizens encounter wild boars on the streets and parks, they don&#39;t have to panic. They can be far away from it without being hurt. If there is already an emergency that hurts people and invades the lives of residents, citizens can call the police or call the wildlife rescue center call. After the Redshan Zoo rescue wild animals, it will make an evaluation. Foreign species will stay in the park to raise, and the local species will be about 40%of the fields of home species. &quot;This success rate is quite high.&quot; The rescue process of wild animals is prone to various accidents, such as accidentally drowning after anesthesia in the South Hubei River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Feng deliberately mentioned a wild boar rescued from Bazi Mountain Park in 2022. The wild boar has become very docile because of being raised for a long time, and people can even touch it. Hongshan Zoo is worried that it has no survivability in the wild and has been raising in the zoo. &quot;Some tourists are unclear. He thinks that feeding these animals is to protect it, and it actually hurts it.&quot; Li Feng and the team also rescued two wild boars that were fed near the Zhongshan Mausoleum in 2023, and eventually failed to release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Faced with the increase in the number of wild boars, Nanjing adopted the methods of strengthening the survey of population groups, strengthening the prevention and publicity guidance of wild boar activities. In addition, the Nanjing Garden Greening Bureau has also adopted the method of regulating wild pig species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above -mentioned Nanjing Garden Greening Bureau responded that Nanjing City has launched a pilot of wild boar hazards prevention and control work in the Zijinshan area since October 2021. After the expert evaluation and demonstration, the density of the wild pig species in the Zijinshan Monitoring Area has exceeded the control standard. The Nanjing Greening Garden Bureau applied to the Provincial Forestry Bureau for 60 wild pig hunting and hunting limits, and issued an administrative license to the huntering wild boar to the Zhongshan Cemetery Administration. From March 22, 2022 to March 15, 2023, it was launched in the Zijin Mountain area. Wild pig population regulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Feng believes that in recent years, the public has improved the awareness of wildlife protection. Citizens will take the initiative to call for help when they encounter wildlife trapped and wild animals. In 2022, Hongshan Zoo rescued about 1,200 animals, &quot;a wild boar is just a small wave.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 18:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[信用卡质效榜：股份行霸榜前四 城商行高度分化]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261776]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 17:34:12 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Heming Three years later, three years later, the domestic credit card market will be opened to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 19, 2023, the International Credit Card Organization Giant MasterCard obtained a bank card liquidation business license at the China Holdings Company Monthly, and said it was called Within 6 months, they will expand member institutions in China to authorize the issuance and acceptance of the bank card of the MasterCard brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At this time, the Chinese credit card market has shifted from the horsesy circle of the horse-rail-ups to refinement. At the same time, the Chinese credit card market is facing the challenge of rising loan rates and contraction of new card volume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As the second largest personal credit market after housing mortgage loans, how can commercial banks respond to a new situation of high-quality assets of credit cards? Which of the risk management system and risk control effect of card issuance is better? Which card is more effective to retain customers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has specially evaluated a multi-dimensional evaluation of the credit card business of 20 systemic banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>; Five dimensions, 12 sub-indicators &lt;/h3>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center The foundation has established an evaluation system for the 2023 credit card efficiency list. It is consistent with the wealth management list, the green finance list, the digital finance list, the data security list and the life insurance efficiency list. Media factor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Among them, quantitative qualitative indicators include business scale and growth, risk management, customer service and product innovation. The indicators are given differential weights for their importance. The total weight of quantitative qualitative indicators is 70%. In quantitative qualitative indicators, the business scale accounts for 35%of the weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also invited 7 external authoritative experts to score an independent real-name review based on the overall cognition of the bank&#39;s credit card business, with a weight of 15%. At the same time, in order to encourage commercial banks to increase the transparency of information disclosure in the field of credit card, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center forms media factors based on the feedback of the special survey of 20 bank credit card business, and the weight is 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img img-id = &quot;73942&quot; group-id = &quot;0&quot; asset-id = &quot;70734&quot; &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/dc5c17a121.png&quot; IMG- TITLE = &quot;Index system .png&quot; Alt = &quot;Credit Card Quality Effect List System&quot; BORDER = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;1799&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/dc5c5c17a121.png&quot; data- &quot;260532&quot; style = &quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Credit card quality list indicator system (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;/p >; &lt;h3>; Paying in the innovation of scale risk control &lt;/h3>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Now the dimensions of the credit card quality list and the quantitative qualitative indicators set under it are as follows: &lt;/p>; &lt; P Syle = &quot;Text-Align: left;&quot;>; (1) The business scale is an important manifestation of the strength of the credit card of major banks. There are 6 sub -indicators at this dimension, which are credit card issuance and their changes, credit card loan balances and their proportion, the number of credit card users, and credit card transaction volume. The 6 sub -indicator rights coincide 35%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; (2) Risk management is a necessary dimension to examine the comprehensive strength of each bank&#39;s credit card. There are three sub -indicators in this dimension, which are non -performing loan balances, non -performing loans and changes in credit cards. The total right of three sub -indicators coincides with a total of 18%. Among them, in order to highlight the efforts and effects of banks to control loan adverse rates, on the basis of credit card loan adverse rate indicators, the change rate indicators of credit card loan adverse rates directly reflect the effectiveness of various banks&#39; measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; (3) Customer service and product innovation is an inevitable choice for major banks to respond to the increasingly fierce market competition in credit cards. There are three sub -indicators in this dimension, which are bank card handling fees income, credit card complaints and their changes. The total weight of the three sub -indicators is 17%. Among them, the number of credit card business complaints and their changes can counter the customer&#39;s recognition of the bank&#39;s credit card business, which is a negative indicator. Credit card product innovation and customer service level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>; Shareholdership and Sanjia &lt;/h3>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Comprehensive quantitative qualitative indicators, expert review and media factors for 20 banks, southern weekend New Financial Research The center built the 2023 credit card quality list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img img-id = &quot;73941&quot; group-id = &quot;0&quot; asset-id = &quot;70733&quot; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; &quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/fa546FF341.png&quot; IMG- TITLE = &quot;List .png&quot; ALT = &quot;Credit Card Quality Effect List&quot; Border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 2237 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/fa546FF341.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 260533 &quot;style = &quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Credit card qualitative list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p stylele = &quot;Text-Align: left;&quot;>; Credit card quality list shows that China Merchants Bank, CITIC Bank and Guangfa Bank have scored the top three in comprehensive scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; China Merchants Bank ranked first in quantitative qualitative indicators, expert review scores, and media factors. It is the only way to get expert review and media factors &quot;double full scores&quot;. Bank of. The bank won the championship with a 12 -point leading advantage, reflecting the competitiveness of the bank&#39;s credit card in various aspects such as business, finance and word of mouth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; CITIC Bank won the Guangfa Bank with a weak advantage of 0.24 points, and the two joint-stock banks ranked the credit card quality list runner-up and the third place. Coupled with the fourth -ranking Ping An Bank, in the 2023 new financial competitiveness list released this time, the credit card quality list is also the only sub -list with the top four of the list of dominations by the joint -stock bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Although external review scoring and media factors have weakened the influence of scale indicators on the list, it is only performed from quantitative qualitative indicators. The score is still the top three. Among them, the balance of credit card loans in Guangfa Bank accounted for 48%of the bank&#39;s personal loan balance, far exceeding the industry, which proves that the credit card business has a huge influence on the bank that has beyond the industry. At the same time, in the case of the overall contraction of credit card card issuance, CITIC Bank and Guangfa Bank&#39;s issuing card volume remains positive, which also shows the good strength of the two joint -stock banks in the credit card business. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; The five major lines are among the top ten &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Although the three major banks have not been shortlisted, all the five major banks in the construction of diplomatic relations between the workers and peasants are among the top ten There is a big bank&#39;s overall strength in the credit card business. The state -owned bank credit card business started earlier, and the customer foundation was huge, and the scale of credit card business has been significantly ahead. However, in recent years, with the fluctuation of credit card assets and the strict supervision of the new rules of credit cards, the invalid and inefficient credit card issued in the early stage has withdrawn from the market. In this long, the scale of large banks in various countries has gradually been ironed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The importance of credit card business to a state-owned bank is not as good as a joint-stock bank. From the perspective of credit card loans in personal loans, the average proportion of credit card loans of the five major banks is 9%, while this indicator of 9 joint -stock banks is as high as 27%. In this sense, under the circumstances that the entry time, the scale of assets, and the customer base are in the overall disadvantage, the joint -stock bank can occupy half of the country in the credit card market, and the comprehensive competitiveness of the opponent is obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Therefore, the ranking of the five major banks in the credit card quality list is just right. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Head City Commercial Bank is catching up &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 5 city commercial bank credit card scores are highly differentiated. Among them, Ningbo Bank&#39;s comprehensive score is second only to ICBC, ranking 6th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the first half of 2023, the bank&#39;s credit card issuance volume increased by 40%year-on-year, ranking first in 20 banks; The non -performing rate of credit cards is only 1.19%, which performs the best in the industry. While maintaining an ultra -low credit card adverse rate, the bank&#39;s credit card adverse rate is still on the downward channel, which is even more difficult. This reflects that the head city commercial bank is trying to catch up in the credit card business, and has made great progress on some indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Compared to Bank of Ningbo, the other four city commercial bank scores rank at the tail, showing that they still have a significant gap with large and medium-sized banks in terms of credit card comprehensive strength. Affected by factors such as the short time of the credit card market, the smaller business scale, and the weaker customer foundation, the four city commercial banks overall have lagged more on indicators such as credit card issuance and credit card loan balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鸟兽、巫气与万物：一位北方作家来到大陆最南端]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261772]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 17:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/da1pphxcp4g16ci6bvenqh1zaktptpt80myy4jim.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 640 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.CMS/medias/im/im/im Age/23/11/29/DA1PPHXCP4G16CI6bvenQH1ZAKTPT80MYY4JIM. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260003 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;H4>; Half of the ocean, half of the land &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Leizhou Peninsula, at the southernmost tip of mainland China, each other across Hainan Island. Writer Sun Bin came here for two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When he arrived on the island, Sun Frequent kept walking and kept looking at each plant, every animal. She talked to locals of different ages and learned some Leizhou dialect. &quot;Eating&quot; is &quot;exemption&quot;, &quot;fault&quot; is &quot;top dwelling&quot;, and he is the most likely to be a northerner to perceive the temperament and character of this soil and soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;witch&quot; temperament is filled with the Leizhou Peninsula. Tianhou Palace and Mazu Temple are everywhere, and each village has all kinds of gods. &quot;Faced with the huge things like the ocean, humans must not be in awe, and they must ask for its blessing.&quot; The worship of the many gods derived from the ocean and its derived has penetrated into many details in the daily life of the beach. &quot;The folk customs here are The folk customs are particularly strange. I am curious about these, so I had this idea at the time. I wanted to write a place at the junction of the sea and land. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In the novel&quot; Seaside Magician &quot;published in 2023, the novel&quot; Seaside Magician &quot;,, the Season Magician, the Sea Magician,, Sun Ban fictional constructed a seaside village at the southernmost town of Leizhou Peninsula: Papaya Town. The first collection of novels, &quot;Seaside Magician&quot;, tells a northerner who came here to find her brother who disappeared for many years. For Sun Bin, searching is a very charming process. &quot;You keep going on the road, I don&#39;t know what kind of people will encounter in front of you and what kind of story.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; So, the northerner met an old lady who made her not to scare the jackfruit. &quot;Jackfruit is very attached to people, and I like to touch and praise them.&quot; Holding the leaf cake to the grave in the woods, I believe that the dead soul of her family is living on the black cat; she also encounters a person who looks like a carp essence. In order to let her believe in her words, the carp essence is facing The Mazu worshiped in the house is like burning incense and worshiping God. &quot;I tell you in front of Mazu, there will be no false words.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;In this town, many borders are blurred, Between people and plants, animals, between living and dead people, between the ground and the ground, they can shuttle with each other. >; &quot;There is a deserted temperament here so far. On the one hand, it is a knife to cut people, and the blood splashes five feet. In the same way, the gods celebrate the grand festival of the villagers on their birthdays. They are collectively called the annual calendar. They must sing a thunderic drama on the stage, to worship the wine to the gods, prepare fresh white -cut chicken, and put a whole day of firecrackers. To dance the lion, there must be a very solemn swimming ceremony, and God just sat in his own temple and quietly watching people wish them life for it. &quot; , Stkaiti; &quot;>;&quot; Seaside Magician &quot;&lt;/span>;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Naturally, life is fruit. Accompanied by the sea all day, the folk life of the Leizhou Peninsula stacks a layer of dreamy and mysterious atmosphere, and it is hidden behind this is the huge weakness and loneliness of humans when facing the ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When I first met the sea, there was no difference between Sun Zhan and many inland people. &quot;It&#39;s too big, so that you don&#39;t know what it is hidden inside.&quot; For living in land In terms of people, land means a stable life. Walking and living on land, living ancestral halls, build ancestral temples, generations of generations. And what exactly does sea life look like? Facing the huge, mysterious and unknown sea, how should people settle their own sea life that is destined to wander &quot;rootless&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Running back and forth, from Xu Wengang to Haikou, Sun Bar has more than a dozen ships in total to try to chat with the crew. Crews are often silent, especially ocean crews. The sea sailing at sea for a year or two makes them lose contact with friends on the land, and people on the land have gradually forgot their existence. &quot;This kind of life on board is split with land. They become a world and one on the world.&quot; When talking to Sun Bin, a captain claimed to be &quot;sea people&quot;. She noticed the particularity of this word. &quot;Not the crew, nor the seafarers, but the sea people.&quot; &quot;This distinction is no longer professional, but the split from the fundamental standpoint of people.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; This loneliness is ultimately the end of What do you go? Sun Duan found that after catching the expensive fish, some fishermen will take the money selling fish to the city center, find a hotel to open a house, eat some delicious food, and then go back to fish after spending the money. She heard that many ocean crew members would also do this. When the ocean ship was supplied by the offshore, they would go out of the ship to buy things desperately. Sun Duan tried to explain the source of this kind of compensation psychology. &quot;For example, a fisherman may be dead to drive a boat out of the sea. Under such impermanence, once you have the opportunity to get rid of or relax, you will desperately want to compensate themselves. &quot;&quot; Or is it very simple, you can spend money quickly, in case I will be dead tomorrow. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The sea is silent, and the sea people are silent. The boat is like a natural prison. &quot;Because of the narrow space and the departure of its land, it is likely to become a prison, and the crew will become a prisoner to endure the torture.&quot; &quot;But, can we change to another? To understand it from an angle? This closed and isolated space can actually become a Thorro -style hut, a unique space suitable for philosophical mysteries? &quot;In the second&quot; Seagull Knight &quot;in the novel collection, Sun Zu fictional Captain, wearing a suit, combing back, burning incense, drinking tea, and playing the piano every day. &quot;He is still elegant in the place where no one is, just like a ghost dormant in the old castle ... He is sometimes easy -going, sometimes very again Occasionally a little fierce, when I feel good, I will talk elegantly in literature and art, and there is a kind of things between noble and gloom. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; She wants to ask How can we find a wider and richer spiritual space for yourself in such a closed and lonely environment? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/itb5uciqfpil5adf64gmrgujvfqr2x1szlqjpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;820&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/itb5uciqfpil5adf64gmrgujvfqr2x1szlqjpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259999999999 6 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; At the seam of civilization &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Two years ago, Sun Zone&#39;s novel &quot;In the name of birds and beasts&quot; was published, and Fan Xiaoshe&#39;s editor of the People&#39;s Literature Publishing House first edited Sun Zone&#39;s book for the first time. &quot;Whether she writes the grand and dense plants in the south, the rich aquatic products in the ocean, or the unmanned dense forest in the north, these things are just the material of Sun Zan&#39;s novels,&quot; Fan Xiaoshe said. &quot;And in the end all novels are directed by modern times, all of them are modern times. Civilization (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; modernization, urbanization &lt;/span>;) gives people&#39;s inner impact, and find or ask at the same time. &quot;&lt;/P >; &lt;p>; In &quot;The Name of Birds and Beasts&quot;, Sun Fan set his gaze to the people in Luliang Mountain, his hometown. There, the modern urban civilization is constantly entering this &quot;wild&quot; land. Sun Zhan shaped a mountain tour, and he walked out of the mountain and had a decent civil servant job in the town. But this profession has not provided him with a source of identity, &quot;his roots are still in the mountains.&quot; In Sun Zu&#39;s view, what You Xiaolong represented was the suffering of some people in the process of urbanization, &quot;they The soul is nowhere to be placed, the hometown can no longer go back, and the city does not belong to itself. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; Don&#39;t you think this is the epitome of a large part of China? &quot; Coming, &quot;Of course, urbanization is a must -have stage for the development of human society. But in fact, every step of the era requires hundreds of millions of life blood and tears.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The attention of urbanization also continues To the third episode of the new novel, &quot;Falling Sun Coral&quot;. In the novel, Sun Ban carefully recorded the urbanization process of Papaya Town: In the 1980s, 100,000 talents went to Hainan, and the nation of Papaya Town became a hawker. In the 1990s, Wenzhou speculation groups allowed smuggling cars to invade and devour the entire town ; When Hainan Island scratched the trend of travel and vacation, Papaya Town scrambled to run coral homestays ... between cities and towns, Sun Bin once again chose the seam of civilization as the perspective of her thinking. The protagonist of the novel &quot;I&quot; once moved from Papaya Town to the city. &quot;It was pursuing modern civilization, but he couldn&#39;t really enter the city.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Under the change of migration, Sun Zhan always watched the spiritual situation that was not limited by the region, and it had some kind of universal &quot;loneliness&quot; -the personal spirit that was difficult to place in modern civilization and turbulence. As a result, Fan Xiaoshe said that &quot;looking back&quot; not only constituted the fundamental questioning of modern civilization, but also the inherent inherently inherently inherent in Sun Zan&#39;s self -life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the &quot;post -80s&quot; generation of Sun Byn, she feels that every change in the times has an impact on her and her generation. She witnessed the laid -off workers in her childhood, and became a &quot;hard -working town as a questioner&quot; in her childhood. &quot;When I graduated, the sense of superiority of college students who still existed in the 1990s had gone, and college students turned into a dust.&quot; When she was in college, she would still think, &quot;This has entered the 21st century. Why is it? What preparation and non -compilation work exist. &quot;After working for a short time, her thoughts changed, and the cruel reality of society seemed to teach her what life was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;All I experienced, and every step of the society, must have impact on me. And in the process, I kept thinking about it, thinking about each tide of the era. The individual&#39;s threat, &quot;When these thoughts slowly accumulated,&quot; you want to express it. &quot;Sun Bin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After graduating from college, Sun Zone successively published a collection of novels &quot;Pain&quot;, &quot;Salt&quot; and &quot;Crack&quot;. Many readers and critics noticed the pain of the mind and spirit in the work. &quot;Because I really feel that pain, I can write it out, so I invested in high concentrations of emotions in the early novels.&quot; Sun Duan said. Like the name of the novel, these creations revealed the confrontation between a young man, the society, the world, and the spiritual situation that he could not reconcile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking back at his creation in his twenties, Sun Zhan feels normal, which is in line with the mood of a young man at that time and her understanding of the world. &quot;Society&quot;, followed by the weak helplessness of the individual, and the sudden break and impact when facing the ivory tower built from literary education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;It&#39;s just that I can&#39;t be desperately burning my emotions like 20 years old. My novel at the age of 20 pays attention to the deep and struggling hearts of young women. As I get older, I will try to understand more people and pay attention to the wider world, so that it is interesting. The writer is burning himself throughout his life, but later, what I have burned is no longer just emotion. Instead, when I understand this broad world. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; When editing&quot; The name of birds and beasts &quot;, Fan Xiaoshe felt that Sun Zone&quot; began to become open. &quot; She believes that when &quot;Pain&quot;, &quot;Salt&quot; and &quot;Crack&quot;, she pays more attention to the pain of individuals. Starting from &quot;The Name of Birds and Beasts&quot;, she has made some museums, plants, mountains and rivers, including behind them. The history of history has been brought out. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The writing of anthropology inspired her. In anthropology, Sun Bin saw a deeper and more perspective of human beings. She wrote &quot;The Name of Birds and Beasts&quot;, using anthropology to handle the changes in mountains, the history of grass and trees, and mountains and rivers, and deeply describe the evolution of the lives of mountain people between cities and mountains and forests. The long -lasting sight of this world of human and human beings is full of patience and full of &quot;the greatest respect for different people.&quot; And when she looked at these mountains, fishermen, and sea people with the same patience, and these &quot;wild&quot; people in the eyes of urban civilization, she practically appreciated her unique vitality. She wrote all kinds of strange strange mountain people in &quot;Riding the White Horse&quot;, and brought the younger bachelor brothers with a big bachelor to run a short man in the farmers&#39; university in the mountains ... &quot;You see their living conditions are actually very difficult, You can also describe them with a barren, &quot;Sun Fan said.&quot; But, their language and their ideas are full of vitality. That kind of vitality does not belong to cities and civilization, but it is also sincere and moving. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG SRC = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/m1e2goklujsxdouwgx9k0tdrgcw43m.png&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; width = &quot; 321 &quot;Height =&quot; 428 &quot;Data -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/m1e2goklClujsxuWGXUWEBVLGV9K0TDRGCW43M.PNG&quot; Data-key = &quot;260004&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p stylele = &quot;color: #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Sun Zan&#39;s style at the seaside of the Port of Xuwen &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (provided by the interviewee/picture) A broader world &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; At the scene of the new book sharing session of &quot;Seaside Magic&quot;, the writer Li Jingze said: &quot;Although Sun Zone&#39;s creation has changed a lot, I think her direction has really not changed. There has always been an intention to establish a connection between people and all things. This is particularly important. One of the usual situations in Sun Zhan&#39;s novels is that when walking, there are fewer and few people, there are fewer people, and everything is born. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the age of age, Sun Fan found that his interest in people was not so great. &quot;When there is a lot of disappointment with human or human nature, or not deep comfort in the crowd, the complex relationship between people is gradually becoming a forceful space, which will restrain people.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; She goes to know plants, animals, those rivers she passes by, and people who can&#39;t talk to those who can&#39;t talk to their calls and try to understand them. &quot;This is a very interesting process in itself,&quot; said Sun Duan, &quot;Because you are gradually understanding the world, which is actually very healed for people living in high -rise buildings.&quot; When she came from the city to the mountains and forests from the city forest The changes in the ocean and the region affect the mood of the person in it. &quot;You will become more and more tolerant.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The turning of this life mood eventually changed her creation. &quot;My early novels were entangled in the relationship between people, and later I was a little tired of this writing,&quot; Sun Duan said. &quot;I don&#39;t mean to write down like this. I think there is a premise that each writer&#39;s attempt is to make him feel stretching and pleasant, and to have the function of healing and nourishing the author. What you don&#39;t want to write, even if this can bring more reputation to the writer himself. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Sun Zhan imagined that he became a fictional captain in&quot; Seagull Knight &quot;, trying to create a better one , A greater spiritual space- &quot;Because writing itself is a healing and placement for yourself.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;At that moment, I think, if all things are spiritual, that person After dying, I just left human society, but entered a broader world. In that world, plants, animals, mountains, rivers, sun and moon, ocean, hurricanes, gods, dead souls, monsters, elves are all all are all are all are all all You can communicate with each other. This kind of communication cannot be seen by people who are alive, but in those lonely, trauma people, there are some traces of somewhat traces ... &quot; _GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>;&quot; Seaside Magician &quot;&lt;/span>;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; Escape and settled at the same time, &quot;Sun Fan said,&quot; You can understand this evasion as a reason for people right people right. The escape from the sense of weakness of the real and material world, but at the same time, in the process of escape, you also constructed a new world for yourself. &quot;Back. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Questions still exist.樊晓哲认为，孙频的创作始终在处理她内心的困惑，“首先她觉得现代文明下人与人之间的沟通是有困难的，于是她产生了困惑”，“在《疼》《盐》《 In the crack &quot;, she sets out from individual feelings and constantly writes puzzles.&quot; &quot;In the back, she further questioned the source of confusion. Is this a person&#39;s problem or a social problem?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot; At this stage, she did not look for answers in the crowd, but went to all things to find. &quot;In the edge of the modern civilization, no one knows the depths of the mountains and islands, those ships, sailors, mountain people, birds and beasts , They are all self -consistent. &quot;Among all things, her confusion was diluted and relieved, or healing.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Sun Zhan likes &quot;Elf -style temperament&quot; in the poems of Emily Dukinson, and also likes Shen Congwen&#39;s Writing, such a text atmosphere is her longing, &quot;In him, there is no trace fusion between people and nature, very comfortable, natural sutures and connections.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 17:25:12 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[尼泊尔爆发抗议：君主与共和之争？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261760]]><description> &lt;DIV>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 16:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &quot;The outlet sounds frequently on the scene, and a large number of police officers gathered together. The sound of the car has been loud, and many people watch it. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Thinking of a few days ago, the Nepalese Mata still remembers it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 23, 2023, thousands of people came to Nepal Kandamu to carry out large -scale demonstrations. &quot;Restore the monarchy and abolish the Republic.&quot; Nepalgander&#39;s protests shouted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to local police estimates, about 9,000 people participated in the protests of the former members of the Communist Party (United Marxist -Lenin) and medical entrepreneur Durga Prase. Although the police claimed that the demonstration event was &quot;basically peaceful&quot;, the activity still caused minor injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the evening of the afternoon of the day, when Pilate gave a speech to the masses, he urged his supporters to break through the security warning line and marching towards Mittica. Subsequently, the police used water cannons and tear gas to dispel the crowd. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Recently, the current political competition between the current republic and support the monarchy has increased. The Nepalese government has deployed about 10,000 security personnel from the Nepalese police, the armed police force and investigators to prevent the two groups from preventing the two groups. There may be conflicts between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The capital &quot;Confidentiality&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Zhu Ming opened a restaurant in Nepal. He told the Southern Weekend that Nepal is an overall peaceful country, but in some political needs, Nepal Ri riots occur from time to time. Now every major streets have local police to maintain order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Youth Carry remembered that the protest conflict took place at a intersection of the capital of the capital. The people at the scene gathered and ran. Smoke trajectory &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the same day, the local police fired 146 tear bullets and 5 rubber bullets to dispel Balcu&#39;s Prase supporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Polarus, who has been claiming to be a maverick, recently adhered to the anti -government and anti -corruption position. In a speech at the rally, the Prime Minister Prachangda failed to rule the country. &quot;He surrendered to the people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Prase also claims that his supporters will continue to hold protests elsewhere and will ignore Kathmandu&#39;s ban. Earlier, the government announced that the Mittabaneshwar road section was the restricted area of ​​the protests. He said that his campaign would not stop before restoring the monarchy, Hindu countries and the 1990 constitution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Plasizer has always been considered a &quot;controversial&quot; businessman. He attempted to overthrow the current government of Nepal and call the protests the &quot;saving national action&quot;. He said the protest was to oppose the government&#39;s failure to curb the state of anarchy, corruption, and rising inflation. Prase hopes to restore the monarchy and Hindu countries by abolishing the current Federal, Republican and secular systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also protested the support of the merchants at the scene and asked them to suspend business from November 24. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Youth Branch of the Communist Party of the Communist Party (United Marxism -Leninism) Lastia Youth Party and their student branches in Nepal National Freedom Student Union also participated in the demonstration parade in Tingku. There are also many protesters who came from the plain in southern Nepal to Kathmandu, and they are also the &quot;victims&quot; of bank micro -credit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Prase said that the bank tried to exploit the money of the lender and called on the masses to give up the loan in the bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, demonstrators who support the current republican government have also taken the street. They believe that only the republic can ensure the fairness and peace of society, and &quot;can everyone have the opportunity to realize their dreams and pursuits.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the scene of the conflict, the protesters and protesters who supported the monarchy had a conflict. The anger of the protesters spread from Balcu, a designated protest area to various regions such as Tingku, Galigama, Santala, Tapatali, Fodong and other key points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Subsequently, the Kathmandu police arrested a total of 261 protesters, set up roadblocks and water guns on the streets, and installed CCTV supporters all -clock to monitor Pracey. The police also added sniffing dogs around the conflict location and the roof to ensure safety and prevent possible events. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, in order to prevent the conflict of hostile groups, the police have set up two different protest areas. However, crowds that support the monarchy and the republican system are huge, and their opposition will also lead to intensification of tensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Zhu Ming said that protests have not had much impact on local life. Because protesters march in the designated area, except for the traffic shutdown during the parade, other regions include major commercial areas and world tourist concentration centers that are not affected, and shops are open normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The political system under the conflict &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Nepal, located in the Himalayas, has a colorful culture, natural landscape and political history. However, its political system has gone through the evolution of many centuries, from the feudal monarch to the Federal Democratic Republic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu, an associate researcher at the South Asian Research Institute of Sichuan University, said that after the establishment of the current republic, it has indeed achieved certain positive results, including the expansion of the people&#39;s democratic rights and obtaining more guarantees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As early as the early 21st century, Nepal&#39;s politics had undergone major changes. In 2006, the Civil War in Nepal ended, and the government signed a peace agreement with the rebels. Two years later, in 2008, Nepal officially announced that it would become the Federal Democratic Republic, abolished the monarchy, the head of state became the president, and the regime was scattered between the central government, the federal state government and the local government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, the Nepalese government has set up a new constitution and established a federal system. Nepal is divided into 7 federal states, and each state has a certain degree of autonomy and is responsible for managing the state affairs. This constitutional formulation process has experienced many political crises and protests, but eventually passed in 2015 and became the current constitution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The main dissatisfaction with the Republican system is two parts of people.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu said that some people are young people. They have grown up by modern education and have more expectations for the country. Another person is a group who has gone through the era of monarchy. They believe that although the monarchy has many problems, politicians can at least compete in a limited range to achieve general stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu said that in the process of Nepal&#39;s modern politics is still cultivating, the current chaos is more not due to the problem of the political system itself, but due to the problems of the political family class, the operation of the current system is operating. There are many problems, which also causes more dissatisfaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the end of the monarchy, political instability has troubled Nepal, and more than ten government changes have occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu said that although Nepal has not been similar to the previous civil war, the political scene has been in a political party for a long time, and the political situation has been turbulent for a long time. The continuous division of political parties and the continuous changes in policies have disappointed voters. Voters want to establish a stable government through elections and let the country go on track, but politicians often use votes as chips for political negotiations of political parties, causing strong dissatisfaction among voters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The political situation is unstable, and economic development has also slowed. Millions of young people go out to find jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiangyu told the southern weekend reporter that Nepal&#39;s economic development has always been unable to come up, and the public is in a state of extremely confused and extremely sleepy state. Many people who study abroad or are working abroad are unwilling to come back. Some young people are more willing to go to the bay or India to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The recent outbreak of protests also shows the controversy and differences of the political system within Nepal society. Obviously, Nepal&#39;s politics still faces some challenges and problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhu Ming sometimes &quot;chat&quot; with protesters. He said that the real appeal of the protesters was to return to the era of king&#39;s power. &quot;Because only the king will think about the people.&quot; He said that the protesters believed that no matter which party, they represent their respective interests, and they would be bought by different international forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There are multiple political forces in Nepal, and behind the scenes of the interests of various political parties.&quot; Zeng Xiangyu believes that although this is the disadvantage of the current republic, it has a fierce confrontation or in the era of civil war. Compared to &quot;it is better.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Is the &quot;curry flavor&quot; protest valid? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; conflict and violent protests are not the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kathmandu Police said that on the afternoon of September 7, 2023, the 47 -year -old Hiammum Sapokta attacked the Nepalese National Party&#39;s co -General Secretary of the National University of Kathmandu.其脖子后部被深深地割伤，随后被警方送往医院接受治疗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件发生后，一段流传在社交媒体上的视频显示，萨普科塔高呼要求恢复该国的君主制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年12月，支持君主制、支持印度教的活动人士在加德满都街头游行，要求恢复君主制和尼泊尔作为印度教国家，并废除联邦制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“关于宪政体制的争议始终存在，拖了很多年，到现在还没有完全解决。”曾祥裕说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，尼泊尔是一个多民族国家，不同的民族和社会群体之间存在紧张关系和分歧。一些地方民众对联邦划分和自治权的分配感到不满，这导致了抗议和政治动荡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾祥裕分析，尼泊尔作为联邦制的国家，中央和各省的关系怎么处，以及各省怎么命名、首府设在哪儿，这些都是引起巨大争议的问题，“在国王时代有争议的问题延续到现在，争议就更大了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，尼泊尔的政治现状仍然动荡不安。君主制和共和制支持者在政治理念上存在严重分歧，这种对立不仅局限于意识形态，更牵涉到民众对国家未来的看法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“尼泊尔的政党，特别是主流政党，分化组合的速度特别快，且完全以政治利益为考虑重点。”曾祥裕点评说，各个政党没有把利于国家的具体政策作为工作重心，反而热衷于政党斗争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游行前，朱明询问参加抗议活动的人“会不会成功”，得到的答案是“能”。但就目前结果来看，“大概率没有达到目的吧”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾祥裕表示，尼泊尔的政局不会因为此次抗议发生大的波动，还是会延续原来的轨道，几个政党分化组合，为了政治利益不停地“你方唱罢我登场”，经济社会发展也暂时不会有大的突破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“民主和共和不可能出错。”对于这次抗议，尼共（联合马列）主席奥利表示，个别掌权者可能会犯错误，但这并不意味着整个制度有缺陷. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥利说，恢复君主制是不可想象的。就像人类不能回到石器时代一样，我们也不能回到君主制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“抗议者的目标不可能实现。”曾祥裕分析，君主制已经是过去式，不符合时代的潮流，它更多地是情绪化的一种表达，是对现状的protest. “要实现恢复君主制这个目标，几乎没有什么可能。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这种抗议情绪，对尼泊尔来说，也许是一种机遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是对尼泊尔政治家阶层的一个提醒。”曾祥裕说，“十多年过去了，民众会倒过来怀念君主制，宣泄对现状的不满，这本身就很值得反思。在尼泊尔，现在也有一些新兴政党代表年轻人的声音，并取得了不错的成绩。但是他们如果想取代传统政党，还有很长的路要走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:55:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王贤才丨两次焚稿，九译其书：我翻译《希氏内科学》的历程]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261714]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/e8b0f8c820.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1611&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/e8b0f8c820.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;本世纪初，王贤才与老伴曾汉英重访出生地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我祖籍江西九江县永安乡。上世纪20年代，祖父把家迁到上海，民国22年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1933年）&lt;/span>;阴历九月十六，我出生在上海法租界福履里路&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今建国西路）&lt;/span>;“建业里”。 2023年10月30日是我的90周岁生日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本世纪初我和老伴曾汉英重访故居时，建业里已成危房，即将拆除重建，居民都已迁出。门卫问清来意，允许我这个老居民进去走了一圈，在里弄门口留下这张相片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年秋，我随父母回到九江，住在都天巷祖父置下的祖屋，是座前后两重的老宅。 When Jiujiang was liberated in Jiujiang in May 1949, I was a high school student in the same language. 1951年春即将升入高三下时，奉命去武汉中南团校学习&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（江西当时属于中南区）&lt;/span>;。 7月结业回来，团市委要我留在学生部，正式参加工作。生活节奏一下慢下来。我不习惯机关干部的生活，这时全国高校首次统考已过，忽然发现山东大学医学院还要单独招生，就要求辞职升学。学生部长同意，组织部长认为这是资产阶级个人主义思想作祟，不服从组织决定，强令“退团”。这是我在政治上遭遇的第一次打击，成为我的“原罪”。有识之士认为，我前半生的坎坷遭遇，都与这有关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被迫“退团”后，辞别父母，黯然离家，到青岛顺利考入山大医学院。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f4d1658ee.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f4d1658ee.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;报考山大的报名照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;虽然我从未想过学医，但也只能如此了，否则就要再等一年。后来发现，这个被动接受的专业，也在很大程度上保护了我。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为我是付出了惨重代价才得到升学机会的，所以我痛定思痛，焕发出从未有过的勤奋努力。那时大学没有教科书，主要靠上课时记笔记。我是专心听讲，要求自己不但要听懂，还要当堂记住，下课后凭回忆整理出笔记，再把从图书馆看到的中外资料补充进去，所以学到的东西总比课堂听到的更多。大学期间所有课程的每次考试成绩，我都是全班第一。生理科教授吕运明先生在百分试卷上曾破例给了我110分，因为我的回答已超出了他在课堂的讲授内容。 Thirty years later, I returned to Qingdao to participate in the school celebration. Mr. Lu was also pleased to mention it with me. The important thing is that my medical translation is also starting in the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/729c561658.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/729c561658.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;就读山大期间，在青岛海滨留影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入临床课程后，我就知道美国有部享誉世界的医学名著《希氏内科学》， 老师们戏称它是临床医学的《资本论》。 I went to the school library to register and queue up, and I borrowed this heavy masterpiece.阅读学习中，深感它的博大精深，论述系统、严谨，尤其侧重于临床和基础理论方面的联系，就有了把它译成中文的念头。 I think this is a very meaningful thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千里之行，始于足下。我想分两步来做：先译一部较小的书，取得经验后，再去动那个大部头。后来我挑了英国HC奥文司教授为实习医生和低年资住院医生们写的《临床外科须知》（&lt;em>;An Approach to Clinical Surgery&lt;/em>;）试笔，觉得这部书的内容是我能把握得住的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过无论是想译《希氏内科学》还是试译这本小册子，当时都还是我的机密，只有一位同班密友&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（刘丕仁）&lt;/span>;知道这事，他是一直看好我、鼓励我的，还为我找到一个“秘密”译书地点，就是外科三病房楼顶的小attic.那是个蛛网尘封、低矮逼仄的斗室，我要弓身弯腰才能进去。 “桌子”是叠加的肥皂箱，坐在用报纸包起的砖上。我每天凌晨即起，躲到这里来译书。阁楼没有电，只能用蜡烛照明。我的视力不好，凑近看时，常常闻到一股焦味，那就是头发烧着了。干到六七点钟悄悄回宿舍，跟上同学们的生活节奏，一起洗漱、吃饭、上病房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/e53a0d5f09.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1662&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/e53a0d5f09.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在阁楼偷偷译书时期的相片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的低调加上保密工作又做得不错，直到我译完这本二十多万字的小书，“地下活动”也没被人发现。 1993年我回青岛参加母校校庆活动，当年住我下铺的同学刘镜如&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(时为青岛市卫生局局长)&lt;/span>;承认，他当年对我的这些活动毫无所知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/400851e4cb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/400851e4cb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1993年回青医参加校庆活动，与时任青岛卫生局局长的老同学刘镜如（中）合影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1957年《临床外科须知》在上海卫生出版社出版时，我已毕业在北京工作了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cf8354f25c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1078&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cf8354f25c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这本小书出版后，我就屡经坎坷，几乎失去一切，这是从网上买到的旧书，在旧书网上意外发现，至少还有过上海科技出版社（1960、1961) 和香港商务印书馆(1970)三种翻印本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;进军《希氏》&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《临床外科须知》的出版，给了我很大的鼓励，我买回第9版《希氏内科学》，开始向它进军。这次翻译不是“地下活动”，同事们都知道我在做这事。但是我的时运不佳，不久就来了反右运动。我虽平安度过大鸣大放的1957年，但因医院反右指标未完成，到1958年6月，仍因“妄议”苏联医学被补划为右派分子。这时反右高潮已经过去，我和另两位增补的右派未被发配出去，留在医院监督劳动，每月生活费32元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个月后，医院忽然奉命迁往内蒙古呼和浩特，支援当地的大跃进。我感受的压力也越来越大。终于在一个月明风清的夜晚，把译成的第9版《希氏》约四十万字手稿，在医院旁的一块荒地里烧了。心里虽很苦难过，但还能勉强说服自己：现在不是译书的时候，得先努力摘掉头上这顶“帽子”。科学总在不断发展，到时还会有新的版本出来，我再重新开始。 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从1960年起奉命“代理主治医生”。每天早晨带领住院医生、实习医生们查房，这时我是他们的上级，查房后，他们回到办公室，我去给病人扫地、擦桌子、倒便器。凡是病人需要我做、我能做的，我都积极主动地去做。因为我和他们不一样，我是被监管的右派分子。在当时，就是人民的敌人，就是“反动派”。所以我昼思夜想、心心念念的就是“摘帽”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;盼星星，盼月亮，总算盼来了这一天。 1961年11月，院党委宣布给我“摘帽”。这时候形势也有了很大变化：苏联成了“苏修”，成了我们批判的对象，不是什么“老大哥”了。我又重操旧业，买了第11版《希氏》，再次向《希氏》进军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但命乖运蹇，又来了“四清”运动。领导运动的工作组长警告我：不要旧病复发，“右派”帽子摘了还能给你再戴上的！这话击中了我的“要害”。我得悬崖勒马！终于把再次译下的第11版《希氏》手稿&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（也是四十多万字）&lt;/span>;，在医院旁的荒地里，点火烧了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有位名人说过，人生最痛苦的事是梦醒了无路可走。在我戴着“帽子”的时候，可以做摘了“帽子”以后再干的梦。现在我还能走什么路，做什么梦呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生活有时真是严酷而又不失风趣：二十多年后，我应邀重回呼和浩特，在内蒙古科技大楼和科技人员座谈时，我发现这楼就在我原先工作的医院旁、我曾两次焚稿的荒地上建起的，忍不住和他们说起了这段往事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;再次升级&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“四清”运动还未完全结束，就进入了十年浩劫。我以“摘帽右派”的待罪之身，升级为“现行反革命”，判刑12年，剥夺政治权利4年，进入劳改。所幸当局用我的一技之长，让我在劳改队的卫生部门服刑改造，避开了一般性的劳动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1971年，刑满获释的难友程大路给我送来一份包扎严实的“厚礼”，打开一看，竟是第13版《希氏内科学》！程大路是上海下放到山西的知青，以“反革命”罪被判刑5年，因患胸膜炎在我这里住院治疗过较长时间。我们相处不错。他知道我立志翻译《希氏内科学》的事情，记在心里。当时规定，家在大城市和沿海沿边的人，释放后不能回家，都要留厂&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（场）&lt;/span>;就业。所以他能利用每天犯人出工后，监房暂无门卫的机会，给我送书。程大路每月只有29元“工资”，还要接济下放到安徽的妹妹。但他在外文书店发现新出的《希氏内科学》（影印本）后，竟想方设法，变卖衣物替我买来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b574c980bd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b574c980bd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1984年在九江和程大路（图左）劫后重见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;忽然看到久违的《希氏》，物是人非，心里的感觉真是难以言喻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天犯人出工后，午饭是在工地吃的，要到下午六点才收工回来。所以上午我处理完病房的事，就能看书，晚上处理完各队送来会诊的病人，到八九点钟，也能消停下来。我翻看13版《希氏》，发现随着时代的进步，内容与以往版本又有很大不同。希氏本人早已退休了，这部书的作者有177位，总主编是牛津大学（后来调到美国华盛顿大学）的毕森（Paul B. Beeson）教授。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c79b574a0b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1437&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c79b574a0b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《希氏内科学》13、14、15版总主编毕森送给我的签名照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;狱中译书&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我不禁蠢蠢欲动，想利用现在的时机译书。我不是一时冲动，异想天开，而是经过深思熟虑，认真考虑的。我到劳改队以来，工作上一直是兢兢业业，小心谨慎的，如临深渊，如履薄冰，没犯过错误，没出过医疗事故，特别是利用闲置多时的显微镜，和从总厂大库里找到的分析天平、光电比色计，建立了检验室，能做当时一般医院开展的临床和生化检验&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（由此得到减刑一年的奖励）&lt;/span>;，因此领导对我是很信任的。我想我能争取到领导的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按规定，干部们是不能到我这里来看病的，但从厂领导李恒文政委起，都常到我这里来看病，我当然无权拒绝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这天李政委又来我这里看病。他当时年约半百，是位抗日老干部，当过公安局长。他常苦于心率过慢，病因不明。我经过周密检查和检验，认为是冠心病表现。在那物资短缺，人们普遍营养不良的年代，冠心病在中国还很罕见，大医院偶尔见到几例冠心病、心肌梗塞，写成的论文，可以发表在国家级学术期刊上。医生们对此经验不足，又难以接触到国外医学资料。后来外面医院也认可了我的诊断，这也增加了李政委对我的信任，问我是怎么从心率慢想到冠心病的。我趁机搬出那部大书，说是它告诉我的，我想把它翻译过来，让更多中国医生能看到它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李政委翻动那部大书，没有回答我。有好长一段时间没有说话。我觉得有些不安，不该冒昧提出这个要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他把书合起，对我说：“既然是部这么好的书，你就在这里把它翻译过来。我们支持你。译完了不能出版，我们给你印出来！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他就是这么说的，我至今记忆深刻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;学“哑巴日语”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;就这样，我在劳改队第三次翻译《希氏内科学》，想要实现学生时期的心愿。在这样的封闭环境译书，困难自然不少。虽说那个时期里，劳改犯中能人不少，但是专业性较强的问题，还是难以找人商榷。记得译到一段有关CT的内容时，一下卡住了。现在CT已是家喻户晓，可是那时CT才刚问世，我无法从“computerized tomography”两个英语单词，猜度这简称CT的检查“神器”为何物&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（字面意思是“计算机处置的体层摄影”）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过本市犯人带话出去，请家属帮找一下有关CT的解说资料。总算找到一份送进来，却是日文的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;病房里正好有位日语专家：山西大学历史系教授罗元贞先生。罗老早年留学日本早稻田大学，娶过日本夫人&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（被疑为“日本特务”）&lt;/span>;，他是“未决犯”，看守所人满为患，也送来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是隔行如隔山，精通日语的罗老，也看不了那份有关CT的日文资料，说只有你自己看；不懂日语可以学。我还有点犹豫：为看一点日文资料而要学门外语，是否太过？罗老说，可以速成：学个“哑巴日语”，只求看书，不求说话写文章，个把月就行。在那种环境下，别无选择，也只有这样了。于是翻译暂停，先跟罗老学日语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/0f3bf689c9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1467&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/0f3bf689c9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;我在狱中的日语老师，山西大学教授罗元贞（1906-1993）先生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天查房后，把罗老请到我房间&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应该说“监舍”）&lt;/span>;来学日语。不到一个月，“哑巴日语”粗通，看懂了那份有关CT的日文资料，再回到《希氏》的翻译上来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1975年9月下旬的一个晚上，《希氏》第13版全书&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（340万字）&lt;/span>;中译稿终于杀青。我把最后写下的译稿，放进译成的手稿里。每页300字的稿纸，页码编到一万一千多页，码起来像个小山头，颤颤巍巍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学生时期的心愿终于完成了，只是韶华不再，我已不再年青，还是在这样的境况下译书，令人唏嘘！虽说宿愿终偿，也能感到一点欣慰，但是几乎与此同时，又一种难以言喻的悲怆之情也已渗透我的身心：我会不会又一次被迫把它们烧掉呢……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这时夜深人静，监房一片沉寂。我这里离大墙很近，可以看见高墙上被风吹得哗哗作响的高压线和岗楼上荷枪实弹的哨兵……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;改判释放&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;译完《希氏内科学》第13版不到十天，我的生活又迎来一次重大改变：内蒙古高院决定对我撤销原判，改判八年！这是小平同志二次复出，提出以毛泽东的“三项指示为纲”，各行各业都要进行整顿的结果。我是1967年被捕判刑的。据此推算，我已服刑8年，所以决定改判8年。但是他们不了解，我已减刑1年，要是改判9年就更“合适”、更“准确”了。改判书下达的这天是1975年9月27日。多坐就多坐了吧。那时候也没有国家赔偿一说，我更没什么好说的。劳改队决定放人，并容许我把第13版《希氏内科学》全部译稿带走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/bed71ffd4f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/bed71ffd4f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;狱中译出的《希氏内科学》第13版全书340万字手稿，现藏九江市博物馆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到故土九江，和老母相依为命。不久我被雇到一家工厂医院当临时工&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（做医生）&lt;/span>;，每月34.5元。这时候，又有了第14版《希氏》，我买回来，用它对照和增订、补充第13版译稿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1978年12月，党中央举行了具有历史意义的十一届三中全会，从“阶级斗争为纲”转变到以经济建设为中心。中央发出55号文件，给全国右派分子“摘帽”，属于错划的都予改正，失去工作的安排工作。我被安排在九江市第二人民医院。但是改正和平反的事，还得由原单位来做。所以1980年，我又回到内蒙古的原工作单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;签约出版&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;右派改正，冤狱平反，都很顺利，还有意外之喜：因为我的冤狱都在浩劫时期，按规定，当时扣罚的工资都可补发，所以我一下子成了“万元户”！这在当时是笔巨款，等待逐级批复期间，我到内蒙人民出版社为朋友的一部书稿探询出版事宜。接待我的编辑徐诚，是科技编辑室主持工作的副主任。徐诚对朋友那部书稿没有兴趣，随口问了句：还有什么书稿吗？我也随口回了句：“大书稿有兴趣吗？《希氏内科学》。”不想徐诚眼睛一亮，劲头一下来了。他仔细问了书稿和我的情况，要我给他一点时间。二十多天后，徐诚跑来找我签约，说他们决定分10册陆续出版，三年出齐！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐诚的话把我吓了一跳：一部这么大的书，就这么决定了？我们从不相识，素昧平生，他怎么就能信得过我呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来这些天里，围绕这部书，他已做了很多工作：他知道我是医生，打听到我当年在内蒙古小有名气；从图书馆检索到我早年译的那部《临床外科须知》，认真看过了；还开了两个座谈会，有一个是专程到北京去开的，征求与会专家们对出版《希氏内科学》的意见，获得一致肯定和支持，这才向领导汇报，找我签约的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想更重要的原因应该是：改革开放，百废待兴，人们渴望了解外部世界，可是经过这些年的折腾，英语人才已是凤毛麟角，所剩无几了，我总算活了过来，又有这部现成的译稿。这是我的幸运，其实也是我的侥幸。尽管如此，我对徐诚的敬业精神还是非常敬佩的。他比我年轻12岁，1966年毕业于内蒙古大学生物系。以后我和他成为终生之交。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1499da72df.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;871&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1499da72df.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;徐诚（图右）和我商谈《希氏内科学》发稿事宜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到九江，我立即将首先发排的《第五分册》心血管疾病译稿寄给徐诚。那时印刷还是铅字年代。选择先出这个分册，不是因为我是这个专业的医生，而是徐诚的营销考虑：心血管病患病人多，好卖&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（后来果然如此，初印1万册两月后脱销，随即加印）&lt;/span>;。可是就在排版期间，我又收到第15版《希氏》，内容也有了很大改变！作者已增至277人，全书篇幅也扩大到约500万字，甚至编排风格都很不同了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这对我来说又是一次严峻考验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我可以走一条比较轻松的路：按合同要求，把已完成的译稿陆续发去，用3年时间把书出完。这在国际上也不算落后。但我毕竟不是为出书而出书，而是把它作为一份事业来追求的。要是我不能把最新最好的版本奉献给读者，这书即使出来了，也会留下深深的遗憾。夜里经历了激烈的内心斗争，黎明即起，写信给徐诚，信刚发出，忍不住又到电信局给他打长途电话，说明原委，请他立即通知印刷厂停止排印，追回译稿，我决定从头开始，重译第15版全书，保证三个月内交出首先发排的第5分册约50万字译稿。全书10个分册仍将在3年左右时间出齐！ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;重译第15版&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这是我第五次翻译《希氏》，争取圆满实现早年那个心愿。我知道重译全书的难度和工作量，但我想再难也比在劳改队里译书方便得多吧。为了抢时间，从此我再未休过任何一个节假日，多年来养成的午休习惯也戒除了。每天凌晨即起，夙兴夜寐，伏案工作。 1982年2月，首先发排的第5分册如期出版。 1984年12月底，终于完成第15版《希氏内科学》全书译稿共470万字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f1b522794.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1441&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/6f1b522794.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;重译第15版《希氏内科学》的日日夜夜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1985年6月，十个分册全部出齐。虽然经历了一些曲折，但我们还是世界上最早推出《希氏内科学》第15版译本的国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c0f4b042c0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c0f4b042c0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1985年分10册出版的《希氏内科学》第15版中译本全书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾这些年来，我一共接触了五种不同的版本，两次焚稿，五译其书，总共译下了约1070万字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卫生部对《希氏内科学》中译本组织评审，专家们对译文质量表示满意。卫生部决定设立“医学翻译特别奖”。 1987年2月，崔月犁部长在卫生部为我授奖，老伴曾汉英由于在译书和出版过程中的辛劳，也被请去参加授奖仪式。迄今此奖是仅有的一次。一年后，徐诚也在内蒙古荣获出版战线的重要奖项“伯乐奖”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cef17b4f83.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;746&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cef17b4f83.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1987年春，在卫生部接受“医学翻译特别奖”，前排左起：卫生部副部长顾英奇，部长崔月犁，王贤才夫妇，卫生部科技司司长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不是中国第一个翻译《希氏内科学》的人。民国时期，中华医学会曾组织国内一批专家集体翻译、出版过第7版《希氏》，但只限于内科相关内容，不是全书，故用了《希氏内科学》的书名。原书内容广博，除临床内科各系统外，还包括外科、妇产科、儿科、皮肤性病、眼耳鼻喉以及公共卫生、医学统计、临床检验和放射线诊断、医学遗传与伦理学等相关内容。所以原书书名是“&lt;em>;Cecil Textbook of Medicine&lt;/em>;”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(《&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;希氏医学教科书》）&lt;/span>;。我译的是全书，也是我国第一个全译本，但还沿用了前辈们翻译时留下的书名：《希氏内科学》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《希氏内科学》中译本问世，受到广泛关注，这不是我真的做了什么了不起的事，而是那个时代的特色：改革开放，人心振奋，一台戏，一个电影，一部小说，往往都能引起哄动效应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/09ffc11e53.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/09ffc11e53.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;应邀在北京参加《希氏》第15版中译本首发式,左为责任编辑徐诚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《希氏内科学》在北京首发时，不能分册选购&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（往常可以）&lt;/span >;.购者还是纷至沓来，络绎不绝。有位老人早早地骑车从郊区赶来买书。他是工程师，家里也没有学医的人。我为他签名时提醒他这不是科普的书，但他还是坚持要买。以后我做《希氏》第17、18版补译工作时，领导居然决定，译稿先在一个综合性医学期刊上连载，随译随发&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为此增加了刊物篇幅）&lt;/span>;，一年发完，再交出版社汇编出书。这个决定见报后，那年该刊的邮发量竟因此而增长了近三倍！这些都是现在无法想象也很难理解的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为世界医学名著，《希氏内科学》已有意、日、西、葡等多种文字译本，各国翻译该书，都是上百人的专家班子集体翻译，从来没有一个人完成《希氏》全书翻译的。卫生部顾问、著名麻风病专家马海德&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（美裔华籍）&lt;/span>;说，海外媒体称王贤才是“中共十一届三中全会后冒出的&#39;出土文物&#39;（unearthed relics）”，问我有何观感。我说他们看到三中全会、改革开放的决定性作用是对的，但也不是我特别能干，是我的境况和经历决定了只能孤身拼搏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;后记&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;以后一些年里，我还译下了：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《简明希氏内科学》第2版&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（141万字&lt;/span>;）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《希氏内科学》第17、18版补译本&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（150万字）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《西氏内科学》第21版全书&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（600万字，因与西安世界图书出版公司合作，他们建议改“希氏”为“西氏”）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《西氏内科学》第22版全书&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（815万字）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/60a8a893fe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/60a8a893fe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;陆续译出的不同版本的《希氏内科学》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;连同最先出版的第15版《希氏》，我先后接触过9个不同版本，共计译成和出版2106万字。在迄今我的全部译著中，《希氏》系列约近其半；结缘可谓深厚了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是2003年11月70岁时退休的。 《希氏》第22版&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（815万字）&lt;/span>;是退休后的译作。回顾我这一生，出版的主要译著15种37部约5000万字，可能是中国，也是世界上译著字数最多的人，因为发达国家是无需大量科技翻译的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b95d5cc5b9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1375&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/b95d5cc5b9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;我和我的主要译著。前下是1957年最先出版的稚嫩的小书《临床外科须知》。它是丑小鸭，微不足道，但它引领了后来的那些译著，也开启了漫长的坎坷之路，所以我对它始终有着更多的感情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>