<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[毕业生求职，“我全都要”容易实现吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258810]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Affected by the economic environment and the number of graduates, the employment situation of college students graduating this year is severe. Although my friend Xiaoyan, a recent graduate student, received several offers (job opportunities), he was not happy at all, but became even more anxious. After some inquiries, he found out that none of these jobs seemed to meet the standards of his ideal job. How to choose a suitable job is a question that every graduate needs to think about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of economics, there is a famous &quot;Mundell&#39;s Impossible Triangle&quot;. This theory is that the country cannot simultaneously satisfy the independence of monetary policy, the stability of exchange rates, and the free flow of capital, and can only choose two of them at most. Similarly, in the job market, I think there is a similar &quot;impossible triangle&quot; law. It involves three conditions: salary level, work platform and relative stability of a job. It is difficult to achieve at the same time, and only two of them can be met at most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let me briefly introduce the basic information of this friend: Xiaoyan comes from a rural family in a provincial capital in the northwest. He graduated from a 211 university with a bachelor&#39;s degree and a doctorate from a well-known 985 university in Beijing, with excellent grades; he published many publications during his studies. He has written SCI papers, participated in many national-level projects, and won many high-level competition awards. The three offers he got each have clear characteristics. His first job was as an official in the national ministries and commissions. He had a household registration, a good job platform, and a relatively high social status. However, his income level was in a first-tier city like Beijing, and there might not be much left after excluding expenses. Faced with the high housing prices, he was more than satisfied. The second job belongs to a monopoly institution in the industry, with a staff and a guaranteed income, but the platform is average, and there are more restrictions on job-hopping in the future; the third job is in a 211 university in my hometown, with a high level of scientific research platform and strong academic strength. The job is rich and the working hours are relatively free. The only drawback is that with the reform of universities and institutions, this job has no establishment and the employment period assessment pressure is high. He is worried that in the future he will face the outcome of promotion or resignation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Xiaoyan’s final choice has not yet been determined, I suggest that when he is looking for a job, his first priority is to learn to lower his expectations for a specific factor, rather than falling into a &quot;I want it all&quot; situation. As far as these three jobs are concerned, if he prefers a stable working environment within the system, he should probably lower his salary expectations. The first job may be the best choice; if he pursues better salary and treatment, he needs Compromise on the requirements of the work platform, so that the second job may be more suitable; if you yearn for a better scientific research platform and are interested in academic development, Xiaoyan can try to be less optimistic about the establishment of this indicator and challenge the third university teaching position. The job is not bad either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the moon waxes and wanes, and work also has its flaws. For most graduating college students, the jobs they find basically conform to the &quot;impossible triangle&quot; law. Therefore, when necessary, we need to identify the needs and learn to make trade-offs, so that we can feel less anxious and face the severe employment environment calmly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a doctoral graduate in 2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email :nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[歌枕之巅——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（四）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/gAXZuPLXeiaWEXiOOMVw0is3TGpubj7FJLgSx4Ep.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gAXZuPLXeiaWEXiOOMVw0is3TGpubj7FJLgS x4Ep. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254353&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho once lived facing the sea when he traveled to Matsushima. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue to walk further north, passing through Akita and entering Aomori. Along the railway line are apple orchards in the harvest season. In some areas, branches and leaves covered with red fruits are brushing against your hands, separated by the glass windows of the train. That kind of surprise is really quite strong. To really touch an apple, you have to go to the station supermarket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aomori’s apple production accounts for half of Japan’s national production. It is the birthplace of the world-famous Fuji apple, as well as twenty or thirty other varieties of apples. The &quot;world&#39;s best&quot; apples grown in Aomori weigh more than 500 grams each, and some can reach 1,000 or even 1,500 grams. When we were shopping in the supermarket, we saw that those Aomori apples were also huge. They were sold one by one for about 500 yen each, which is equivalent to about 30 yuan in RMB. It&#39;s a little more expensive, but it&#39;s juicy and tastes sweet. The three of us bought a shared meal while changing trains at a small station, and we were all full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While in Aomori, of course I had a destination - go to Kaneki to see Dazai Osamu&#39;s former residence &quot;Seiyangkan&quot;, and also went to Towada to visit the famous Towada Museum of Art. As for Basho&#39;s whereabouts, it has to reach a climax after this cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We turned around from north to south, took the bus from Aomori to Sendai, and then transferred to the main route to Matsushima Kaigan Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bajiao chants: &quot;On a summer moonlit night in Songdao, the clear water is my clothes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho and Zeng Liang’s trip to Oshu, he said, was purely a whim, so he didn’t care about Wu Tianbai’s hatred. This whim was mentioned in his preface, because the Moon of Songdao appeared in his heart, tempting him to go on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Tian&#39;s white hair is a reference to Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;I arrived in Dongluo on the 9th last year, and I came to Wuxiang on the 9th this year. The hair on both sides was white for a while, and the chrysanthemums in three places were the same color.&quot; , &quot;Shoes fragrant with Chu ground flowers&quot; all mean that the journey is long and difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/jZeCav7eKr5CrSenYdxKPRvuuJUexS5tydhfHScY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/jZeCav7eKr5CrSenYdxKPRvuuJUexS5tydhfHScY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254354&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsushima is located in Miyagi-gun, Miyagi Prefecture, northeastern Japan. It is a scenic spot in Matsuo Basho&#39;s &quot;Song Pillow&quot; and is named after the pine trees planted all over the islands. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Songdao is named after the pine trees planted all over it. The ancient Japanese traditional color name is pine leaf color. As the name suggests, the color of pine leaves is a dark green that is evergreen all year round. Among the traditional Japanese colors, there are several colors related to pine leaves, including sea pine color, which is a green that is close to black; and sea pine brown, which is a dark green mixed with brown and yellow, which is a calm and pretty green. Then there are sea pine blue, yellow sea pine tea, blue sea pine tea, etc., which in my opinion are various derivatives of pine leaf color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot;, Basho would occasionally note that he had reached a certain &quot;singing pillow&quot;. The word &quot;Utabu&quot; means a place of interest that has appeared in Japanese Waka since ancient times. At the top of Japan&#39;s singing pillow, there are three scenic spots: Amanohashidate, Matsushima and Itsukushima (also called Miyajima). These three major attractions have been famous since the early Edo period. For me, Matsushima feels more literary because of Basho&#39;s description in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. Basho&#39;s &quot;aphasia&quot; was particularly interesting. He shouted, &quot;Matsushima! Ah! Ah! Matsushima! Matsushima!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7ApEi9HKrHnqZ1Pl4VExcQcLavIICeH0KLTKSTjH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/18/7ApEi9HKrHnqZ1Pl4VExcQcLavIICeH0KLTKSTjH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The dry landscape garden of Zuiam Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matsushima is a group of islands in the bay, Miyagi-gun, Miyagi Prefecture, northeastern Japan. It is composed of 260 small islands, large and small. They are named because they are covered with black pine and red pine. The four colors here are blue waves, white sand, limestone, and green pine. The colors are quite bright and harmonious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2019, Wei Dong, Yan Ning and I set off from Hachinohe in Aomori to Matsushima. Take the bus from Hachinohe Station to Sendai, then transfer to the main line to Matsushima Kaigan Station. A very small station platform stands in the middle of the railway. When we arrive at night, the biting cold wind blows from all sides of the platform. After all, it is already autumn. The sun is warm during the day, but disappears at night. We quickly got on the shuttle bus between the hotel and the station, turned a hill, and arrived at the hotel &quot;Daguanzhuang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large rectangular building lying on its back, with a huge lobby extending to both ends of the building. This large-scale resort hotel is almost identical and can be found in Hakone and Hokkaido. I highly doubt it was done by a designer. When you see a hotel of this size, you know how popular Songdo is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you enter Songdo at night, you can’t see much. When you wake up in the morning and open the curtains, you will be greeted by a 180-degree sea view. Beautiful indeed. Her pure and simple beauty is suitable for people like Basho who are in a light and lonely state of mind. Basho also lives in Songdao facing the sea, on the second floor (we live higher than him on the third floor). He said, “Opening the window and facing the sea, the so-called traveling and sleeping in the wind and clouds, the wonderful feeling is indescribable. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I carry &quot;The Secret Path of the Oku&quot; with me. When I arrived at Songdao, I read the chapter about &quot;Songdao&quot; in the book carefully. Basho sighed, &quot;According to old legend, Fusang ranks first in the scenery of Songdao, and its coverage is not inferior to that of Dongting and West Lake. From the southeast, the sea enters the bay, and within three miles of the bay, it surges like the tide of Zhejiang. There are countless big and small islands, and the towering ones point directly to the sea. Outside the sky, prostrate ones are crawling on the waves. Either two layers overlap, or three layers are piled up; the islands on the left and right are either separated or connected; those with burdens and those with hugs are like loving children and grandchildren. The pines are lush, the tide is blowing, the wind is blowing, the branches and leaves The curves are natural, but appear to be the result of manipulation. The scenery is natural, with the appearance of a beautiful woman condensing her makeup. Could it be that the mountains were only made by the gods in ancient times? Who can use the colorful brushes of the heavens to achieve their beauty? Really?&quot; (Translated by Zheng Qingmao)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bajiao has never been to China, but he is not reluctant to borrow the scenery of China. Through reading Chinese classics and paintings, ancient Japanese literati became quite familiar with and intimate with Chinese scenic spots such as the West Lake, Dongting Lake, and Qianjiang Tide. A matter of course. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of 2018, my friends and I visited the Sumio Goto Museum of Art in Furano. I vaguely remember that he seemed to have a painting of Songdao, and it was a very long painting. I remember that I took a photo (Special note, many art museums in Japan are not allowed to take photos of exhibits, or can only take photos of some of the exhibits. I strictly abide by this rule. Photography is allowed for all exhibits in the Goto Juno Museum of Art) ). In November 2019, after returning home from a trip to Oshu, I turned on my computer to check, and I found this painting. I was very surprised. Isn’t this the view we saw from our room in Daikanso? I think Goto Juno stayed at Daikanso when he visited Matsushima, and it was one of the rooms on the third floor of our row facing the sea. This painting by Juno Goto was painted in 1987 and is called &quot;Morning on Matsushima&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ud8QPlbfKJzhSCfAI3lRj04aLAniveD7G2jmoqTK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ud8QPlbfKJzhSCfAI3lRj04aLAniveD7G2jmoqTK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Autumn leaves at Entsu-in Temple, an affiliated temple of Zuigan-ji Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I stood in front of the window in the early morning and looked at the Matsushima sea view in front of me, and I thought of the Japanese cultural essayist In a passage from Hakushu Masako, she said, &quot;Japan is an isolated island in the East, and the good and the bad are all in the word &#39;iso&#39;. This isolated island is like a wind-swept corner of world culture. No matter what it is, as long as it passes through the hands of the Japanese, it will It will transform into something more indescribable, delicate, and dense.” I agree with this statement. There is no clear distinction between cultural forms, but there are completely different differences in rhythm, speed, and texture. Japanese culture is a condensed representation of world culture. Strong winds and waves transported various cultures to this island country in the Far East, and that&#39;s where it ended. Then, after being eliminated and transformed, they were condensed into a crystallized cultural form. Its static and density are completely different from mainland culture and corridor culture. The wind and waves stop here, but they are condensed in it, like a drop of amber between heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the scenery of Songdao in front of the window, I suddenly remembered these. During the trip, generally, abstract words will continue to stimulate my thinking, while visual beauty will make me quite distracted. Songdo is an exception. It seems that this is indeed an unusual Songdo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Small Path of the Oku&quot;, Basho&#39;s disciple Zeng Liang recited a haiku, &quot;On the pine island, the cuckoo should use the crane&#39;s body to sing throughout the bay.&quot; This haiku was engraved. The stele was erected at the entrance of Zuiyan Temple, juxtaposed with the &quot;Bajiao stele&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core of Songdo is Zuiam Temple. Basho and Zeng Liang visited Ruiyan Temple in the summer, and they thought it was peaceful and peaceful. We arrived in mid-autumn, and the tranquility was still there, with the subtle yellow and red colors of autumn mixed in with it. The smell of the sky must be completely different. The sky in all four seasons is really wonderful, equally clear and high, but the autumn sky is more profound and vague, like a pair of eyes with deeper sockets, which is different from the other three seasons. Starting from Sendai Station, I saw Matsushima red foliage tourism promotion posters posted all the way. They were overwhelmingly popular. The poster selects the red leaves of Zuigan Temple, or to be precise, the red leaves of Entsuin Temple, an affiliated temple of Zuigan Temple. The courtyard of Yuantongyuan is winding and graceful. It is a courtyard specially prepared for autumn. It is planted with maple trees, which will be full of red in late autumn. What was it like when we arrived? Take the marathon as an analogy. The starting gun of Hongfeng has already sounded. Some runners have already rushed out, but the huge team is still at the starting point. Imagine that as soon as we walked away, the red leaves in Yuantongyuan would start running wildly on a large scale until the whole garden was burning. It would be impossible not to feel a little sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zuigan Temple is an important temple of the Rinzai Sect. It was built in 828 AD. There is a room in the temple where Emperor Meiji once stayed, which is specially marked. After walking around the main hall and cloisters along the tour route, my attention was focused on the garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once the autumn light settles, it is gray-blue. Especially in the morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning from Songdo, I often looked at the photos of the dry landscape garden at Zuiganji Temple. A wonderful scene separated by light. In the shadows, the white sand turns into a clear gray-blue. There are tiny wind and thunder in the wrinkles of the sand. The dark and light moss has a wonderful sense of exquisiteness. Beyond the shadows, in the strong light, the white walls and rocks, and the pine trees rolling down the cliff outside the temple, with the cluster of red leaves as the boundary, have lost their tension here and calmed down. But this stillness seems to be broken at any time, if the light changes slightly. As a result, those watching couldn&#39;t help but hold their breath. Therefore, it is right to freeze it into a photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Art philosopher Professor Arthur Danto has studied Basho very well and believes that the texture of Basho haiku is &quot;quiet, concise, as crystal clear and cool as a diamond&quot;. He once said that he wanted to be like Basho. Basho&#39;s journey is a pilgrimage to art, nature and the heart. He is humorous, self-deprecating, proud and lonely, but has a strong sense of humility. He regards his ancestors, nature and the very act of tapping the ground with his feet. They all have very pious thoughts. His practice has been successfully completed in the process of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Danto once said it well. He said, &quot;...Bashō, as an individual, exists in such a reality where the expression of personality and the disappearance of personality are unified. It is neither worldly nor independent. So out of the world; as he mocked himself, he was like a bat, neither a mouse nor a bird, but a hybrid shape-shifting creature between two animal states of existence. I was always moved by his travel notes . These travel notes are a symbol of the restlessness in his body. He always starts from a feeling or a hope for the end, with no intention of returning, in order to seek some ultimate escape. In the end, he discovers that escape itself is an achievement.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;As for Basho, I once said that I regard him as a literary lover. In other words, I want to be like him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国草”与“东方神药”的丝路之旅]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the arrival of the rainy season, the incidence of malaria on the African island of Sao Tome has begun to rise. Guangzhou University of Traditional Chinese Medicine went to Sao Tome Huang Xinan, leader of the Dome-Príncipe Artemisia annua anti-malarial expert team, is increasingly busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 16, 2023, shortly after it rained, he and his colleagues set off from downtown Sao Tome in a pickup truck and walked on the dirt road to Diogo Nunez (Diogo Nunez). Nunes) village. There, expert team teachers guided center employees to collect samples door-to-door to screen for potential cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/VtYO8mMHyaXbgJDWiTy90yXEXlacasevoPowyJj2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/VtYO8mMHyaXbgJDWiTy90yXEXlacasevoPowyJj2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Under the guidance of Chinese anti-malarial experts, staff went door-to-door to collect samples and screen for potential cases. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the outskirts of Nadi, Fiji, 85-year-old farmer Kumar is still in good spirits. On the 16th, he drove a small truck and brought back a load of Juncao oyster mushroom waste from the China-aided Juncao Technology Demonstration Center in Fiji. This waste mushroom material can be used as organic fertilizer for fruits and vegetables on the farm. Two months ago, under the guidance of Chinese Juncao technical experts, Kumar was still planting Juncao on the landslide on the farm&#39;s river bank to control the worsening water and soil erosion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative was proposed, one after another &quot;small but beautiful&quot; projects that benefit people&#39;s livelihood have been implemented in countries along the initiative. Combining its own development experience and technological advantages, it provides Chinese solutions for local poverty alleviation, public health and environmental governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/ybXmglmJkHiHYtescPrMyUKXKnuyv5ar7SbtErGS.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/ybXmglmJkHiHYtescPrMyUKXKnuyv5ar7SbtErGS.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kuma, an 85-year-old farmer in Nadi, Fiji, uses waste mushroom material as organic fertilizer for fruits and vegetables on the farm. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Juncao&quot; and &quot;Artemisia annua&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For many For Fijians, Juncao is the &quot;magic grass&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Juncao planting base of the Juncao Technology Demonstration Center in Fiji, you can see these &quot;guests&quot; who have traveled across the ocean. These giant grasses are several meters long, with thick stems, wide leaves and well-developed root systems. Even the tallest people in the crowd feel as if they are walking into a reed marsh as soon as they enter the grassland, and they are instantly overwhelmed by the green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local people often pronounce Juncao as Junkao according to their English pronunciation habits. In fact, Juncao technology is an original technology that China has completely independent intellectual property rights. Until now, the international English name of Juncao is &quot;Juncao&quot; in Chinese pinyin. In 2001, China&#39;s first foreign aid Juncao technology demonstration base was built in Papua New Guinea. So far, this technology has been promoted to more than 100 countries and regions around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 22, 2023, the China-Pacific Island Countries Juncao Technology Demonstration Center was unveiled and launched in Fiji. Lin Xingsheng, an expert at the National Juncao Engineering Technology Research Center of Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University, came to Fiji in January this year. Since then, his tasks have become even heavier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In Fiji, Juncao can be used as high-quality feed for livestock and poultry, and can also be used to cultivate edible fungi—traditionally, it is a high-quality culture material for growing mushrooms.” He told Southern Weekend reporters that their Work includes production, scientific research, demonstration, training, promotion, etc. Since the implementation of Juncao technology in Fiji in 2014, more than 2,300 local Juncao technical talents have been trained, more than 700 farmers have grown Juncao mushrooms, and more than 1,000 farmers have developed Juncao farming, ending Fiji’s inability to The history of mushroom production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Juncao is full of treasures and can be used for many purposes.&quot; Lin Xingsheng said that in addition to &quot;replacing wood with grass&quot; as a culture substrate for edible and medicinal fungi, Juncao can also be used as a culture medium for cattle and sheep. and other livestock feed, effectively alleviating the dry season feed shortage problem in the arid western Fiji area and promoting the development of local animal husbandry. In addition, Juncao grows quickly and has a well-developed root system. It can also be used to prevent local soil erosion and improve saline-alkali land. Planting one hectare of giant fungus in Fiji can absorb more than 100 tons of carbon dioxide, which is an effective way to combat climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, with the help of Lin Xingsheng and other experts, Juncao was planted on the river bank of the farm of Kumar’s family, a local in Nadi. Just over a month has passed, and clumps of green grass have grown on the originally bare steep slopes. After entering the tillering stage and jointing stage, Juncao will grow faster and faster. Lin Xingsheng is &quot;confident&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Soil and water loss was very serious on the landslide before. When it rained, the sediment would rush into the river. Planting Juncao can effectively solidify the soil and store water. This is why we carry out Juncao slope protection and bank protection in Fiji to prevent soil and water loss. One of the demonstration sites of ecological governance.&quot; Lin Xingsheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the tall Juncao, Artemisia annua looks particularly &quot;weak&quot;. The ancient name of Artemisia annua is &quot;裣&quot;, which means &quot;grass that treats malaria&quot; and was first recorded in &quot;Shen Nong&#39;s Materia Medica&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 1,700 years ago, Ge Hong, a Taoist priest and medical scientist in the Eastern Jin Dynasty, left a record of artemisia annua against malaria in &quot;Emergency Prescriptions&quot; - &quot;A handful of artemisia annua, soak it with two liters of water, and wring it out. Just take it.&quot; This 15-character ancient prescription has inspired generations of Chinese medicine practitioners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tu Youyou, a researcher at the China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences, was also inspired by this, changing the extraction method from high temperature to low temperature, and finally successfully discovered artemisinin, which has benefited millions of malaria patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 30, 2021, the World Health Organization announced that China had passed the malaria elimination certification. According to disclosed data, the number of local primary cases of malaria in China has dropped from 30 million per year before the founding of New China to &quot;zero for four consecutive years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the advancement of the Belt and Road Initiative, China’s anti-malarial experience with Artemisia annua has also been introduced to other countries in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sao Tome and Principe (referred to as &quot;Sao Tome and Principe&quot;) is an island country in the west of the African continent with a population of about 220,000. The year here is divided into dry season and rainy season. Among them, during the rainy season from October to May of the following year, the humid and high temperature weather is very conducive to the breeding of mosquitoes. Mosquitoes are an important vector for the spread of malaria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, Huang Xinan, an associate researcher at the Artemisia Research Center of Guangzhou University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, who is carrying out anti-malarial assistance in Sao Tome and Principe, told Southern Weekend reporters that while the rainy season has just begun, they must speed up monitoring and control. pace. Currently in Sao Tome, a village can be classified as an epidemic source village if there are more than 3 cases of malaria patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, a hospital in Água Grande, São Tomé City, reported three malaria cases. On October 16, they deployed manpower to carry out a large-scale malaria epidemic prevention and control operation in key epidemic source villages. Screening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Generally, we will determine the source village through feedback data from hospitals, epidemic control centers and other channels, and then work with malaria prevention team members to carry out case screening, drug distribution, mosquito disinfecting and other tasks.&quot; Huang Xinan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, in Liberdade, Dashui District, São Tomé City, the China Artemisia annua anti-malarial project team adopted a &quot;source elimination and malaria&quot; program that prioritized removing the source of infection to conduct an anti-malarial pilot . Prior to this, this village with a population of more than 600 had 300 to 400 malaria cases every year. After three rounds of medication, the team continued to carry out measures such as monitoring the floating population and investigating the infection rate. During the long rainy season that followed for eight months, there were no local cases of malaria infection in Liberty Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The success of the Free Village pilot has given the Sao Tome and Principe government and local WHO officials greater confidence in defeating malaria. Because of its immediate therapeutic effect, the Artemisia annua compound medicine distributed by the expert team was also called the &quot;Oriental Miracle Medicine&quot; by the villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/geojCBVSi5UwUXjMZ5rz4X4lMnNTkoO2NsMuWGgN.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/geojCBVSi5UwUXjMZ5rz4X4lMnNTkoO2NsMuWGgN.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254646&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;With the help of Chinese Juncao technical experts, Juncao was planted on the river bank of Kumar&#39;s farm. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Business opportunities&quot; and connections&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Juncao mushroom cultivation project is It brings business opportunities to local farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Xingsheng, leader of the expert team of the China-aided Fiji Juncao Technology Demonstration Center, gave an example. The Fiji Juncao Center provides technical training to local farmers and provides fungus bags full of mycelium. After farmers receive the mushroom bags from the center, they can cultivate the mushrooms under the forest or in the shade of the shed by covering the soil with soil. They only need simple management measures such as simple watering and maintenance, lifting the film for ventilation, and the first crop of oyster mushrooms can be harvested in about 7-10 days. , you can have income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Fiji, ordinary farmers only need to plant 10 square meters of Juncao oyster mushrooms in front of and behind their houses. If they plant 4 times a year, they can harvest 1,200 kilograms of fresh oyster mushrooms and earn 20,000 Fijian dollars. The equivalent of RMB is almost over 60,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is much higher than the annual income of ordinary local farmers, so the locals call the Juncao project ‘quick money, easy money’ (money is easy and fast).” Lin Xingsheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rwanda, a country in central and eastern Africa, the economic benefits of growing mushrooms also attract ordinary farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Xiaobin, leader of the expert team of China’s Juncao Technology Demonstration Center in Rwanda, told Southern Weekend reporters that Rwanda has a large population but little land and underdeveloped industry. Local workers have low incomes, with an average daily income of only 9 yuan. Through the simple and easy-to-operate Juncao technology, ordinary people only need a small piece of open land and basic care to grow cash crops that make money quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with previous local mushroom growing technologies, China’s Juncao mushroom growing technology has low cost, high yield and easy operation, and is welcomed by many mushroom growers. In neighboring countries adjacent to Rwanda, such as Uganda and the Democratic Republic of the Congo, mushroom merchants also go to border trading points to purchase fresh mushrooms. The ever-expanding domestic and foreign market demand has also stimulated the enthusiasm of mushroom growers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to growing mushrooms in mushroom bags, some people are also studying mushroom bag production technology to achieve &quot;technical localization.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Nadi, Fiji, farmer Ashniel is an expert at growing mushrooms. Not only did he fully master the management technology of Juncao mushrooms, he also learned to produce mushroom bags independently. At the same time, he also modified a humidifier to adjust the humidity in the mushroom-producing place. The oyster mushrooms he grows have thick flesh and good quality, which not only attracts many people to visit and study, but is also favored by customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rwanda, many locals who come for training are college students with higher education. After completing their studies, they started their own business and sold fungus bags to local farmers for a fee. According to preliminary statistics, there are about 50 local companies and cooperatives that independently produce mushroom bags. According to Chen Xiaobin, in Rwanda, Chinese Juncao technology is a symbol of high-quality mushrooms. Mushroom growers or mushroom bag manufacturers will rush to put the &quot;Juncao Technology&quot; label on their products when promoting their products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the introduction of Juncao mushroom cultivation technology, Chinese mushrooms have also quietly integrated into the local food culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Xiaobin of the Rwanda Juncao Technology Demonstration Center said that every time when training students, teachers will arrange cooking classes to demonstrate various ways of eating mushrooms. &quot;Such as deep-frying, stir-frying, mushroom soup, etc.&quot; After students read it, they will also make innovations based on local eating habits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Fiji, mushroom growers process the mushrooms and add cassava flour and other materials to turn them into mushroom drinks. In Rwanda, Sambusa (the Chinese call it Triangle) is a traditional pasta made of dough and stuffing. Bao), in addition to regular fillings such as potatoes, beef, and onions, recently the hot-selling mushrooms have also been added. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Eastern Highlands Province of Papua New Guinea (referred to as &quot;PNG&quot;), the first stop for &quot;Juncao going overseas&quot;, the Juncao and upland rice industries have become the second and third largest industries in the region after coffee. three major agricultural industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2000, China&#39;s Fujian Province and Papua New Guinea&#39;s Eastern Highlands Province signed a sister province agreement, listing Juncao and upland rice technology as Fujian Province&#39;s assistance projects to Eastern Highlands Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Yingxing, leader of the expert team of China’s Juncao Technology Demonstration Base in Papua New Guinea, told Southern Weekend reporters that over the years, the Juncao project’s promotion area in Papua New Guinea, the number of participating farmers, training personnel, and experts have increased significantly. improve. Currently, subdivided projects such as Juncao mushroom cultivation, Juncao livestock husbandry, and upland rice cultivation have been promoted to many provinces in the country, benefiting more than 10,000 farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by the &quot;PNG Courier&quot; on October 4, 2023, this project has become a model for the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; cooperation between China and Papua New Guinea. The friendly relations between the new Eastern Highlands provinces played an important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/DcAQuuhEf58ZJEm5CWhquZSmUTKwD0tQyhU0KgGe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/DcAQuuhEf58ZJEm5CWhquZSmUTKwD0tQyhU0KgGe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Nadi, Fiji, the oyster mushrooms grown by farmer Ashniel have thick flesh and good quality. They not only attract many people to visit and learn, but are also favored by customers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Prescribe the right medicine to the case&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to WHO data in 2020, Among the six major regions in the world, Africa is the most severely affected by malaria. In 2020, the region accounted for 95% of the global total of malaria cases and 96% of the global malaria deaths. An estimated 80% of malaria deaths in the region occur among children under 5 years of age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2006, Deng Changsheng, an associate researcher at the Artemisia annua Research Center of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, provided anti-malarial assistance in the African island nation of Comoros. He saw from preliminary survey data that at that time, about 60% of outpatient cases in medical institutions in Comoros were malaria. More than half of the hospitalized cases were malaria patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be said that malaria was the most troublesome health problem in this country at that time.” He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Comoros at that time, many residents were accustomed to collecting rainwater in cellars during the rainy season for use in the dry season. During field research, Deng Changsheng saw mosquito larvae crawling densely in the water cellars of many residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Poor drinking water environment is undoubtedly one of the reasons for the spread of malaria. Even in recent years, the malaria situation in Africa is still not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Song Jianping, director of the Artemisia annua Research Center of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2017, the team conducted random checks among about 150,000 people in the Est-Mono region of Togo, Africa. Among more than 2,000 people randomly checked, the infection rate among the sample population was as high as 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to extremely high infection rates, many African countries have very weak anti-malarial medical systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many African countries have a common problem, that is, there is no primary medical care, or there is an urgent shortage of emergency doctors.” According to Song Jianping, people with malaria are unable to seek medical treatment for various reasons after they develop symptoms. Some residents need to spend their own money for tests and high-priced drugs; some residents have inconvenient transportation and cannot reach regular hospitals. If it cannot be detected in time, it will be impossible to achieve the effect of early treatment and early prevention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many years, Chinese artemisia annua anti-malarial experts, including Song Jianping’s team, have launched artemisia annua anti-malarial campaigns in African countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Comoros, his team implemented a campaign of universal administration of artemisinin compound to eliminate the source of infection, curbing the country&#39;s malaria epidemic and achieving zero malaria deaths. In Papua New Guinea, only one year after the project was implemented, the average population infection rate was 0.07%, a decrease of more than 99%, and zero malaria deaths were achieved. In Sao Tome, the project team has gradually established a three-level anti-malaria system of &quot;Ministry of Health - County - Village&quot; in São Tomé and Principe. According to the malaria incidence rate and the number of outbreaks, targeted early intervention is carried out in high-incidence villages to suppress malaria outbreaks. Popularity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Over the years, these programs have been verified by millions of people in many countries, and there is very rich clinical data. The data proves that the Chinese programs are effective and immediate. For compound artemisia annua anti- We are very confident in our plan to combat malaria,&quot; Deng Changsheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Jianping believes that malaria prevention and control is a complex and huge task. In terms of the drug itself, the compound artemisia annua antimalarial regimen has its own advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that the team is constantly optimizing the drug ratio in anti-malarial drugs so that it can maintain the advantages of artemisinin’s high cure rate while reducing adverse reactions and taking rounds as much as possible. Suitable for large-scale drug administration sites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有些药物的不良反应发生率高达百分之二三十，这会让病人产生恐惧心理。参与度低意味着覆盖率低，无法达到防治效果。”宋健平说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在非洲大陆，尼日利亚和刚果金两个国家占了全世界疟疾发病的70%。相较岛屿国家，这里发病率更高、感染程度更重、人口更多、人口流动性更强。方案实施起来，可能需要更大的资金量以及更大范围的协同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接下来，宋健平希望一方面持续开发更有效的抗疟药物，另一方面把抗疟经验推广到更多地区。 “将来我们希望在非洲大陆有所作为。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生翟桓、包婧玥对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[个人养老金保险名单增加18款税延养老产品 总名单扩容至69款]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，据中国银行保险信息技术管理有限公司（以下简称“中国银信保”）官网显示，个人养老金保险产品名单扩容至69款产品，涉及22家保险公司。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，此次扩容不仅在7月末48款产品种类基础之上增加了3款，并且还将18款个人税收递延型养老年金保险（以下简称“税延养老产品”） 纳入了个人养老金产品体系。扩容后个人养老金保险产品种类包括专属商业养老保险、两全保险、年金保险和税延养老产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254620&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（图片来源：&amp;nbsp;中国银信保）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述18款纳入个人养老金的税延养老产品分别由中国太平洋人寿保险股份有限公司、太平养老保险股份有限公司、平安养老保险股份有限公司、泰康养老保险股份有限公司、太平人寿保险有限公司和中意人寿保险有限公司提供。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开源证券研报显示，税延型商业养老险并入个人养老金主要为税延型养老保险投保人完成第三支柱税优政策协调统一，并降低领取时个人所得税率，利于个人养老金体系的进一步完善。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，8月31日，国家金融监督管理总局发布《关于个人税收递延型商业养老保险试点与个人养老金衔接有关事项的通知》。 《通知》主要内容包括对税延养老保险试点与个人养老金衔接过程中的工作要求、业务调整、产品管理、保单转移等进行明确，并且对中国银信保统筹做好客户信息确认、加强系统建设，以及税延养老保险试点保险公司业务操作、公告通知、信息报送等提出要求，原则上应于2023年底前完成各项工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;业内人士表示，个人税收递延养老保险凸显“减负”效应，退休后税收负担较轻。而此次名单的扩容意味着税延养老保险业务与个人养老金制度衔接工作正在有序推进，符合工作预期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2018年，财政部等部门联合印发《关于开展个人税收递延型商业养老保险试点的通知》，启动了在国内的试点业务运行。试点区域为上海、福建及苏州工业园区，税前可扣除额度最高为个人应税收入的6%或12000元/年孰低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平安证券表示，该试点政策对低收入人群缺乏吸引力，对可享受税收优惠的人群来说，税优力度有限。而个人养老金制度下产品选择更多、税收抵扣手续更简便，两类产品属性相似、共享税优额度，税延型商业养老险并入个人养老金将理顺税优型养老保险关系，简化相关手续，便于投资者理解，同时将进一步丰富个人养老金产品选择，提升投资者投保意愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2022年11月个人养老金制度正式实施以来，个人养老金保险产品持续扩容，据中国银保信官网披露，2023年7月末，个人养老金保险产品数量已由试点之初的7款扩容至48款，当前已扩容至69款产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平安证券表示，人口老龄化背景下居民养老储蓄需求持续扩张，而今年以来长端利率保持低位震荡、多家商业银行下调存款利率、权益市场波动较大，竞品收益率下滑，而保险产品遵循定价利率、产品具备保底收益率，同时可提供身故、全残、失能等风险保障，差异化优势进一步凸显。商业养老保险作为养老第三支柱的重要组成部分，有望在个人养老金制度下获得长足发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[社会学家刘汶蓉：年轻人的很多选择无法成为“现实选择”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258959]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相关报道详见：《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/258684&quot; title=&quot;纪录片《巢》：互相折磨的两代人，为什么还要住在一起&quot;>;纪录片《巢》：互相折磨的两代人，为什么还要住在一起&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纪录片《巢》把镜头对准了上海一个三口之家，85后男青年毕业多年，与父母蜗居于30平米的老公房。上海社会科学院研究员刘汶蓉关注到这个纪录片，她对这样的家庭十分熟悉。 2016年是纪录片开始拍摄的年份，她当时正在做代际关系研究的课题，发现了“啃老”家庭这个群体：“在2016年的时候已经有很多这样的案例，只是现在青年人就业形势更严峻，还有他们的期待不一样了，所以越来越多。最早是2005年还是2006年，上海这边就开始&#39;啃&#39;了，因为房价开始贵了，老年人感受到支持子女的压力越来越大，对&#39;啃老&#39;这件事情当时有一波讨论。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘汶蓉读博时便开始关注、研究中国社会的代际关系问题。 21世纪前十年，从事质性研究的学者以大量篇幅谈论孝道衰落、养老危机、代际失衡等问题。她当年的博士论文也源于想要验证“孝道衰落”的说法，结果却把她引向另一个方向。 2008年，她在分析兰州和上海的调查数据时，发现代际关系反而呈现紧密化趋势，并且越年轻的人越认同孝道观念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年至2019年，她与课题组走访上海、兰州、大连等地，搜集137个家庭个案，在美国搜集11个家庭个案，结合抽样调查资料，最终得出结论：社会转型强化了中国家庭“亲子一体”的情感结构，代际互助传统表现出强大的韧性，代际纽带仍然发挥着安顿个体生命和激励日常生活的共同体功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在实地调研过程中，刘汶蓉见过许多受家庭兜底、托举的中国年轻人，而在美国调研时，与当地学者交流，东西方家庭两相对照，令她触动。加之自己拥有了母亲的身份与体验，她的心态有了变化。曾经，她一度反感中国的家庭文化，认为“道德绑架”过重，如今她认为这是种温暖的制度设计，中国城市家庭承担了青年人失业和结婚生子的“兜底”工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/G1B26cwWmFMgurABuZhU54FAwqVtFsddRwNjeouX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2160&quot; height=&quot;1215&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/G1B26cwWmFMgurABuZhU54FAwqVtFsddRwNjeouX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;纪录片《巢》中，85后主人公（左）与年过七旬的父母共同生活。片方供图&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;）&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“虽然我们之前的文化理想是自由平等，破除封建主义的孝道和代际父权等等，但是现实中的社会，离开这些，目前没有建立起其他的可以支持人安身立命的文化心灵基础，所以（家庭文化）反而变成了一种价值示范。我们要尊重文化的传承，又要改造。这不是说改造就能改造的，需要深刻的思想上的转型，它是一个比较长的过程。”刘汶蓉对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，刘汶蓉将研究重心转移至青年婚恋上，正在操作课题“大城市青年人的婚恋趋势、困境与社会过程研究”。在与南方周末记者的访谈中，她谈及转型期家庭代际冲突、全职儿女现象、信息社会中的青年困境等话题。以下为其自述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;子女一旦不再结婚生子，很难与父母真正和解&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们70后，往上的时代更加是，在青年时期，我们有非常强烈的离家的动力。为什么呢？父母的管控是非常痛苦的，而我们感受到的爱是非常少的，因为多子女的时候，父母分配给你的时间和精力，包括经济资源，都非常少。这种状态下，孩子不需要评估，几乎是一个自然形成的动力，就是必须要在很早的时候读书远离他们，必须挣到钱养活自己，这种动力非常强。还有必须要结婚，因为结了婚就可以理直气壮地离开那个家庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种动力下，可以说我们那时都是生存的问题。我们也想要自我实现，从小想过画画啊，唱歌啊，写作啊等等，但是大部分人都只是把它当作自己埋在心里的一个理想。首先要满足自己的生存，要就业，要结婚，要在社会上有一个同辈的支持网络。我们的支持主要是依赖于朋友、同学，这个网络是非常重要的，很愿意花时间精力结交这样的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是现在的年轻人，父母给的生存上的压力非常小，他们把很多精力和思想都花在自己的理想为什么不能实现这件事情上，就显得非常无力，因为他们的自我实现标准是比较高的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然我觉得这种话说出来年轻人会不开心，我知道他们的经历不一样，他们没有办法理解。我的研究也发现，代际之间，因为没有相似的经历，也没有相似的社会角色，互相理解是很难的，更多的是要依赖于父辈，因为父辈比他们成熟。比如和谐家庭依赖于父辈的妥协，无论是自然做到还是经过反思后塑造的，但一定是做到了深刻的、思想观念上的慰藉、包容。如果没有这一条是很难的，因为子代没有相似的人生道路和体验，是很难和父辈达成精神上的和解的。就算他们也认同孝道，认同爱的重要性，但是很难生发出这样一个东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以这也是家庭对人的精神的一个困境吧，特别是现在转型之后，人生道路不再标准化、不复制，每个人个体化了。我后来出一本书专门讨论中国家庭代际关系的情感转型，我最后的结论就是在讲生育对两代人的价值认同和情感沟通的作用。很多青年是在自己结婚生孩子之后，才和父母达成精神上的和解。如果他没有做父母，很难真正理解父母，很难放下父母对自己的伤害。只有他自己站在同样的角色上，（拥有）自己对自己孩子的情感经历的时候，真正意识到做父母的苦衷，发现自己再怎么样有好的意愿，也有很多的不如意，会有很多不可控情况，自己没法成为一个完美的父母，这个时候，他对父母对自己养育过程中的一些事情才能够放下，而且能理解到养育过程的不容易。这种和解其实是很微妙的。我的调查中，父母会自然感受到（和子女）之间的默契，心灵上就会得到一种宽慰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国父母为什么特别在意孩子结婚生子？传宗接代这个事，当下的中国父母已经基本不是很强调了，都会认为它是封建思想，特别是受过教育的父母。但是为什么还会追求这个东西，总觉得好像缺点什么，就是自己做父母的这条艰辛道路没有被认可。这是一个他们价值上巨大的失落，这种失落感无法在现代价值体系中被言说。网络上父母不会讲这些东西，甚至在日常生活中，他们也不知道自己为什么这样。其实是自己没有得到认可，就是不知道自己一辈子忙活了些啥的状态。但是当子女生了孩子，他们在心灵上得到了一种理解和宽慰，和一种价值的认可，这个是很重要的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国家庭文化的活力在于传承性，传承是一个循环，不是线性的。但是一旦子女不再结婚生子，其实他很难理解婚姻中的挣扎，养育中的挣扎，他们心理上很难与父母真正和解。所以，我觉得当下青年人中兴起的自愿不婚不育文化，是中国家庭目前在社会转型中面临的非常大的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们都经历了经济快速发展期，而且青春期没有那么强的信息传播，我们也没有经过很刻意的反思，就是自然而然地享受了这个时代发展的红利。但是当下的青年人成长于完全不同的社会发展阶段，他们面临非常大的精神挑战。我们需要更多的代际之间的理解，我们不能说现在的青少年都很矫情，都很虚无，说他们躺平、没有志向，或者懒惰。每个时代都有因为心理上或者个性上有一些问题，无法走向社会的人。但这个人群如果特别大，就是一个社会问题。我们需要的是代际之间的理解和沟通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如说青年人的婚恋问题，我们也着急，主流社会非常着急，国家也非常着急，为什么不愿意结婚？为什么不愿意生孩子？我觉得更重要的还是要理解，重要的是要让年轻人从内心认可结婚生子这条道路，还需要告诉他们亲密关系对人的心理健康和长远发展的意义。因为不婚不育，大多是青年人处于风险感知之下的一种自我保护，如果缺乏支持，他们只能顾当下了。所以，我们在文化上，对家庭生活的精神性、心理性，都需要全方位地思考。或者，需要更多的全社会讨论，让大家对婚姻制度、亲密关系有更多的理解，对个人的道路选择创造更多的可能性和空间。我们政府一直说支持婚育，就是给钱，给时间，我觉得还有就是价值层面需要更多地引领，或者说让年轻人更多地认同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我们担心的是青年永远无法走出家庭”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在城市中产阶级家庭里，95后子女更加回归父母。我的文章《转型期城市家庭亲权回归与孝道再造》，就是回应“妈宝”越来越多，孩子很多东西都愿意听父母的，和父母关系紧密、情感亲密这一现象。日常生活中，他们是小叛逆，但是大问题上面与父母没有什么冲突，不管是择偶的观念，就业的观念，还是入学的观念，好像都很相近。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于中产阶层父母来说，他们已经完全改变了过去“家长式”的亲职模式。我在文章中称之为自反性的亲职实践，就是父母反思自己成长经历中的伤痛，形成了一种以爱和情感为基础的养育方式，对子女成长道路进行全方位的规划和协助，期待孩子幸福又成功。另一方面，就是中产父母的资源也不一样。 80后的父母，50后，他们自己的财富积累没有那么多，经济压力还很大。但是到了95后就不太一样，整个社会的经济状况都有了很大发展，特别是中产以上、受过大学教育的父母，他们一般自己职业也比较好，经济积累、知识积累也比较好，社会资本、经济资本各方面都比较好，所以能全方位地投入孩子的养育，而且从小是一种亲密亲职和密集养育。这种亲密亲职用的是情感感化和引导的方式，粗暴的强制管控行为变少了。所以孩子在成长过程中与父母没有那么大的紧张和冲突，以至到了青年期依然表现出对父母的高度依赖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得到了00后、10后，心理健康问题特别严重，这当然与学业有关，另一方面也是与长期的家庭结构，就是代际之间的共生有很大关联。孩子被照顾和被安排得满满当当，这种爱让他无法呼吸。孩子在学校也好，在家里也好，都是这种完全被监控的状态。这样的话，孩子的心理是很难健康的，无力感会很强，所以青少年抑郁症现在也日渐增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们中国的家庭主义，就是亲子一体的状态，在生活支持方面有很强的工具性功能。比如，在我国的经济转型过程中，没有出现大批的青年贫困人口，都是父母在支撑，也没有那种大批的无法结婚、落入贫困，甚至流浪的青年人，这都是因为中国家庭父母在托底，所以这是一个工具意义上的好处。但是现在已经到了21世纪的第二个十年，我们看到的更多是精神上的压力，给青年发展上的压力，我们担心的是青年人永远无法走出家庭，困在里面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本也有相似的情况，当经济条件发展放缓甚至停滞以后，青年人获得稳定的好工作、好婚姻的机会减少，父母就保护子女，他们叫“寄居单身”现象，就寄居在父母那里，不婚，有的人也不工作。我看一些资料介绍，这些单身到老的子女，在父母去世后，很可能陷入单身无缘的状态，也是一个非常大的社会问题。我们是不是也会到这一步呢？当人的生存已经不是问题了，发展面临瓶颈怎么办？父母把子女保护起来是一个出路吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于全职儿女，我并不反对，但是父母要做聪明的父母，子女也要做聪明的子女。阶段性的gap没有问题，因为现在你有条件追求更好的事业，追求更高的学历，追求更好的结婚对象，中间成年的时间就必然变得越来越长，但是一定要意识到不能一直这样。子女身份是无期限的，但是做了全职儿女，有一个契约的概念，我可以解约，我可以换工作。它是个职业，是临时的，不是终身的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母和子女都要为跳槽或者为转变职业身份，做自己的准备，不能够“我这样也挺好的”，就接纳这样一个状态，就一直这样。除非你在从事一种创造性的工作，（比如）在家里写东西，但是你还要有办法养活自己，因为你的价值来源不独立的话，自我效能感一定很低，从心理健康上看也绝对不是一个长久之计。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西方人把中国的家庭概括为corporation model——认为中国的家庭是一个合作社，其实corporation也是一个以理性架构为基础的组织，是一个事业。组织和事业需要发展，发展需要不断壮大。但是我觉得这些年轻人并没有继承这个家庭主义观点，他是因为外界的风险太大，缩小了自己建立更大亲密圈的努力。其实对他们的家庭来说，是没有发展、没有未来的，也就是说，在他们这两代人之间，结束了就结束了。这不是我们中国的家庭主义传统，他只是满足于自己最朴素的孝道思想，就是我是一个好人，我孝敬父母，父母爱我，我也爱他们，我努力让父母过得好，就完成了我人生的道德上的价值。所以这种“孝道回归”，确实是现在年轻人的真实思想状态，但也绝不是简单的向传统回归。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;这个潮流让人活得非常抽象&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;现在年轻人的需求是比较高的，包括婚恋的标准，非常复杂。我支持年轻人精神上的追求、爱情的追求，但是这些追求又加上现实考量就很难。我做婚恋研究发现，所有的调查者都没有办法回避，择偶到最后都是一个经济指标，但是只有经济又不能完全说服他们，所以就非常纠结。心理的复杂性非常强，不像我们70后有非常强的离家的驱动，真的是没有考虑那么多。因为当时的多子女家庭资源有限、父母对孩子也普遍缺乏耐心，年轻人必须去外地上学、就业、结婚、建立起自己的生活网络，这背后是一种更接近生存需求的动力，所以对工作、伴侣的理想化、完美化追求就比较弱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现在整个社会的信息、参照标准不一样，现在的网络、信息传播太发达，给人的无力感太强了。你总觉得有无限的可能，但现实并非如此。他参照的对象永远是最好的那一批人，没有办法对自己身边的人和事，包括对自己满意，活得非常不快乐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的话，就让年轻人很难活在自己眼前具体的生活当中，导致他们陷入了非常大的无力感。 “我不将就，我努力”既是一种个性宣言，也是一种风险规避。他们其实没有努力，因为没办法有努力的途径。人的能量、力量是有限的，只能在自己附近去努力，就像一句老话说得好，要一步一步来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们那时候很容易做到，现在为什么年轻人很难做到，不是说年轻人不好，是因为整个社会的变化，导致人的心理环境的变化。所以要做一些反向的自我训练，必须要通过刻意的、有意识的、深刻的自我规训才能做到，如果你顺着这个潮流就做不到。因为这个潮流下，好像就是有一种文化环境，让人活得非常抽象、不实在。而我们那个时候，即使是随便找一个工作，我们好像也没有觉得不行、不舒服，因为大家都这样，不是不能接受的，大部分人是这样一个状态。这也是一个社会的进步，生存已经不是问题了，现在年轻人才会想“我不要将就，我要追求我自己最理想的那个状态”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一个是风险社会的背景，就是恐惧心理造成的，这个也很重要。我们要看年轻人的注意力放在了哪里，他放得越高远就会越恐惧，他的无力感就会越强。但是这个时代是注意力经济，吸引人的永远是那些高远的东西。消费主义啊，网络文化啊，都是这样的，大多数是满足人生理上的刺激，激发了人的欲望，这种欲望暂时会让你兴奋或者满足，或者产生一种美好的想象，但是它不长久地支持你一步一步地生活。所以我说年轻人活得很抽象，我不愿意用别的词，比如浮躁这类贬义词。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在“成人”变得非常困难，自我认同、稳定下来非常困难。当然人一辈子都要处在这样一个认识自己的过程中，但是年轻人的成长很难进入下一个阶段，因为他无法分清，无法抉择，一直处在这种纠结的状态。而现在的网络文化也好，消费文化也好，游戏也好，都让年轻人更多地沉溺在这个阶段，一直不成年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们一直在欲望和理想中分不清：其实是在满足他们的一种短暂的欲望，不是走在理想的道路上，因为没有在现实中去落地。我们的文化营造的这些氛围，让他们感觉自己在这条路上，造成了好像自己很有追求、很有理想、在奋斗的幻想，这样就错过了生命周期的最佳状态，慢慢地自然而然地滑落。其实有很多研究已经注意到，包括日本对青年的研究调查也是，并不是年轻人计划不婚不育，一开始就坚定地树立“我是一个不婚不育者”，有，但并不是大多数人。只是他们在寻找伴侣的过程中，在探寻自己理想的道路上，滑落到了最后单身的结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得对年轻人还是要更理解，确实是整个环境的影响，社会文化、心理、经济各个方面，其实是整个现代性对人精神的一个压迫。如果再往上走就是到这个（层面），在青年这里非常明显。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;现在年轻人没有机会日久生情&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;你在二十来岁的时候看起来有无限可能，到了四十岁，似乎也还有很多可能。但事实上你在现实中，看看你的周围又好像没有什么机会，这就让人很抓狂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我做婚恋研究，发现年轻人觉得有很多机会，互联网上有很多平台。选择似乎非常多，但其实最后都不是选择，就是都没有办法成为现实选择，这就是青年的困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种选择和我们那时候不太一样。我就讲一个点，很有趣的是，现在大学生不谈恋爱，高中生好像还谈谈，但是大学为什么不谈呢？而且他们工作以后也不找自己单位的，因为会觉得如果不成很尴尬！这个理由初听很不可思议，但仔细想我觉得也挺对的，这是非常理性的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恋爱这个东西是需要时间、情感培养的，需要长期地互相接触。我调查发现，他们每个周末都很辛苦地要去相亲，一周就相亲一次，要绞尽自己的脑汁去跟人谈，甚至参加各种相亲活动。但活动结束以后，那个人就不会出现在你身边了。就算你当时觉得这个人还行，但他在这一周之内不出现在你身边，最多周末再见，很多人都是坚持个两三次就索然无味了。而且关键是条件不会好到让你不顾一切，也许条件还行，但是再一想，还有很多你不满意的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是一种理性衡量了，你按条件来衡量永远有不满意的地方，不可能一个人什么都好，什么条件都完全达到。日久生情不是看条件，即使条件一般但是有感情了，也就在一起了，很多时候是这样的。但是现在年轻人没有这个机会，他没有生出感情的机会，因为他们根本就没有日常接触，甚至是发生一些事件触动你。这样的话，没有感情你就完全看条件，看条件又总是不满意，所以就很难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个社会看起来好像选择非常多，但事实上因为你没有现实的接触，附近没有什么机会，也没有什么可选的。而且他们害怕进入现实生活中具体的关系，他们很怕关系破裂或不愉快的风险，担心受伤和关系的缠绕，对人际关系的投入有一种非常大的担忧和警惕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不知道这是不是独生子女普遍的问题，就是他们的人际边界感很强，担心、害怕关系复杂，与人自然形成一种远离，到哪里都很想把自己择出来。而在我们那个多子女时代，从小就在各种关系里面摸爬滚打，伤害肯定也很多，但是好像自然而然就形成了不怕，觉得这是一个正常的状态，或是生出了应对的生理反应也好，技能也好。现在被家长保护的年轻人，或者独生子女，他们没有这个能力，也不愿意去掺和人际关系，他们觉得那样很low，喜欢独来独往，需要自己的空间比较大。所以我觉得这都是时代的变化，也是时代进步的一个负向后果吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我有一个学生就说，她只要和她父母在一起就可以了。确实有这样的孩子，这样的想法：我在这个世界上也不需要再和谁建立那么强的紧密的关系。因为建立紧密关系需要很多磨合，有很多不适应，挑战非常大。人和人之间的忍让，各种各样的妥协，总之他们不太愿意，觉得这个太复杂了，偶尔一两次，就玩一下，但是很难深入交往。所以我觉得他们宁愿相亲。甚至有学生说，老师，如果国家给我们发一个配偶就好了。他们愿意追剧，磕CP，那种爱情的甜，这样就用完了，不需要在现实生活中找爱的感受了。因为没有那么完美的一个人，让他有那种情感，想到两个人那么甜那么相爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看别人谈恋爱，如果要组建家庭，“国家发我一个”。所以他们很接受父母介绍。当然父母也跟他们价值观念比较接近，在择偶上意见也能够协调，所以他们挺接受父母安排的，这个和我们当时预见的也完全不一样。我们原来想的都是，随着现代化的发展，教育程度提高，婚姻一定是自由恋爱模式。但是现在看起来也不全是，恋爱是恋爱，但是婚姻的话父母安排挺好的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，这都不是大型调查，大型调查里面可能还很难反映出来。但是我之前看到过一个全国调查数据，就是和1990年代比，21世纪以后父母在子女婚恋决策中的作用在上升。这个我觉得很自然，主要是经济上的原因。现在年轻人结婚，买房、彩礼、看娃哪一个环节都要依靠父母，再加上年轻人心理上对父母的依赖也有所上升，所以父母的话语权肯定上升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改什么？怎么改？难在哪？超大特大城市城中村改造政策解读]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今年以来，城中村改造按下“加速键”。住房和城乡建设部近日表示，超大特大城市正积极稳步推进城中村改造，分三类推进实施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一个关乎多方利益的系统性民生工程和发展工程，当前在超大特大城市推进城中村改造的背景是什么？怎么改？难点在哪儿？ “新华视点”记者就此采访了业内专家学者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;为什么改？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;今年以来，城中村改造备受关注。 4月28日召开的中共中央政治局会议提出“在超大特大城市积极稳步推进城中村改造”的要求；7月，国务院办公厅印发《关于在超大特大城市积极稳步推进城中村改造的指导意见》，并召开电视电话会议进行了专门部署。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，住房和城乡建设部对城中村改造提出了具体政策落实措施，分三类推进实施：一类是符合条件的实施拆除新建，另一类是开展经常性整治提升，第三类是介于两者之间的实施拆整结合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城中村被称为“都市里的村庄”，兼具农村和城市的双重特征，是城市化发展过程中的历史产物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上海市中心城区最大的城中村——普陀区红旗村为例，586亩的土地上，曾聚集着90家印刷厂、207个冷库、9个大型初级集贸市场、1000多个摊位，这里人口复杂、群租遍地、违建密布，流动人口多达6万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照相关标准划分，城区常住人口1000万以上的城市为超大城市，如北京、上海、广州、深圳、成都、重庆、天津、武汉等；城区常住人口500万以上1000万以下的城市为特大城市，如青岛、合肥、杭州、长沙、南京、东莞等。全国总计有20余个城市属于超大特大城市范畴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我国超大特大城市吸纳了大量外来人口，这些群体有相当一部分租住在城中村。尽管城中村租房成本较低，但是普遍缺乏必要的基础设施、公共服务，尤其是在卫生安全、社会治理等方面存在诸多隐患。”浙江工业大学中国住房和房地产研究院院长虞晓芬说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市房地产科学研究院院长严荣表示，推进城中村改造，一方面可对经济稳增长发挥积极作用，成为扩大内需的重要拉动点，产生超过十万亿元的直接投资，并拉动家具家电、餐饮服务、纺织品等多方面的消费；另一方面可优化城市空间布局，进一步提升城市治理水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;怎么改？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“城中村产权结构、人员构成、空间分布、历史遗存等具有高度复杂性，这次改造提出拆除新建、整治提升、拆整结合三类改造模式。”广东省住房政策研究中心副主任李宇嘉说，具备条件的，即资金能平衡、群众改造意愿强烈、土地及物业权属清晰的城中村将实施拆除新建；不具备条件的，不硬上，以守住安全底线为原则，常态化开展整治提升，逐步解决问题的基础上再实施改造。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在改造方式上，当前城中村改造特别强调要将村民合法权益保障与先谋后动相结合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虞晓芬说，新政着重强调在大部分村民同意的情况下方可实施改造。改造前，地方政府要先做好产业先行搬迁、人员妥善安置、历史文化风貌保护和落实资金等前期谋划工作。改造时，应先行安排安置房项目供地和建设，确保安置房在合理工期内建成，品质不低于商品住房水平，配套基础设施和公共服务设施与安置房规划、设计、报批、建设、交付使用“五同步”，切实保障好村民利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“城中村是高度复杂的社会综合体，改造后应该保持多样化的业态。”中国城市规划学会副理事长赵燕菁说，城中村本身是一个产业空间，其业态不是预先规划，而是随市场需求变化而不断变化。城中村改造要注重产业导入和培育孵化，努力发展各种业态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/42989bb71d383982a62565612bc4cc29.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1254&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/42989bb71d383982a62565612bc4cc29.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254585&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;拼版照片：上图为2023年8月3日拍摄的改造后的安徽省合肥市瑶海区安拖东村及新庄城中村改造项目（无人机照片）；下图为2015年3月拍摄的改造前的安拖东村及新庄城中村旧貌。新华社发（解琛摄）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李宇嘉说，过去的城中村改造由市场化主导，挑肥拣瘦，经济价值高的被纳入改造计划，而历史遗留问题多、安全风险隐患大的却被留置。 “这一次，全部城中村都要纳入改造范围，征拆时不能只算经济账，只征收经济价值高、问题少的地块，而是要不分好坏全部征收，彻底解决城中村问题，并防止出现新的城中村。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次城中村改造，要求原则上应当按一定比例建设保障性住房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，赵燕菁表示，目前城中村在城市中承担的一个重要功能，就是给流动人口提供租赁性保障房，城中村事实上成为保障房体系中的有机组成部分。 “如果改造后这部分保障房供给减少了，流动人口的居住环境恶化，租金更高，那就没有实现城中村改造的初衷。因此，必须在改造方案中按一定比例建设保障房作为补偿。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;改造要注意哪些问题？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在采访中，专家普遍认为，推进城中村改造要特别注意三个问题：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是拆迁安置问题。虞晓芬说，超大特大城市遗留的城中村，违章建筑多、人口密集、产权关系复杂，是改造难度大的“硬骨头”，其拆迁、补偿等问题十分复杂，矛盾和不确定性因素较多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者在各地采访了解到，在超大特大城市的城中村里，各种经济活动几乎应有尽有。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现实中，城中村在与城市其他功能长期互动中，形成了功能的互补。简单&#39;切除&#39;城中村，城市其他部分也会随之失能。对此要特别慎重。”赵燕菁说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵燕菁认为，改造伊始，就要对城中村承担的城市功能进行认真调研和分析。如果没有找到对这些功能的替代途径，就不要贸然采取“切除”手术，此时应采用“微创”的保守疗法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是资金平衡与筹措问题。虞晓芬说，遗留的城中村建筑密度大、安置成本高，特别是在目前超大特大城市外围房地产市场仍然较为低迷的环境中，相较过去，城中村改造后出让土地的价值下降，必然会增加社会化资本的筹措难度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“城中村改造如何啃&#39;硬骨头&#39;，关键还是改造资金怎么平衡。”李宇嘉说，国务院办公厅印发的指导意见提出，鼓励实施区域统筹和成片开发，改造项目土地四至范围可扩大至周边少量低效用地，允许集体土地和国有土地整合、置换。 “也就是说，各地政府可以将过去单一城中村改造的&#39;小平衡&#39;变为片区综合改造的&#39;大平衡&#39;，以丰补歉、以肥补瘦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵燕菁说，城中村改造必须创新改造模式，寻求多样的融资渠道，鼓励和支持民间资本参与，其中特别重要的是原物业所有者的参与。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是标准和规范约束。一些不具备拆迁条件的城中村，实施局部拆建和综合整治，要求按照文明城市标准整治提升和实施管理，这对于一些住房质量较差、标准较低、整治成本高，且部分住房产权模糊、手续不全的城中村，具有挑战性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“城中村改造需要先谋后动、统筹兼顾、整体谋划、积极稳步推进，以新思路新方式破解城中村改造中账怎么算、钱怎么用、地怎么征、人和产业怎么安置等难题，探索出一条新形势下城中村改造的新路子。”中国房地产估价师与房地产经纪人学会会长柴强说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[城市排名，看看就行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258754]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the consulting company Resonance Consultancy released the &quot;Ranking of the World&#39;s Best Cities in 2024&quot;. 2024 has not arrived yet, but the ranking is so forward-looking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this ranking, the top ones are: London, Paris, New York, Tokyo, Singapore, Dubai, San Francisco, Barcelona, ​​Amsterdam, Seoul, Rome, Prague, Madrid, Berlin, Los Angeles, and Washington. Then there is Beijing, ranked 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens sarcastically asked, did this list take into account the rarity of drug dealing, shootings, explosions, robberies, thefts, etc.? Nowadays, I increasingly don’t believe in the various rankings selected by foreigners. In some cities, local friends told me not to go out at night before I even went there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sarcasm of netizens has some truth to it. It is actually difficult to define what is the best city. In 2018, a research institution ranked 338 cities above the prefecture level in China and ranked 15 new first-tier cities. Some cities are convinced by this ranking, while others are dissatisfied. In fact, not to mention that the concept of &quot;best&quot; is too big to be defined, even the smaller &quot;urban livability&quot; is difficult to explain clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary people, whether a city is livable is nothing more than commuting to and from work, making money and development, and basic necessities, food, housing and transportation, that is, income, consumption, and public services. In terms of work, the more developed the city&#39;s economy and the higher the income, the more livable it is. In terms of life, the more convenient, higher comfort and lower the cost of living, the more livable it is. These two aspects are related to the market. Outside the market are the public services provided by the government. Among the public services provided by the government, education and medical care can be provided by the market, but public security can only be provided by the government. Public security is the foundation for a livable city. Otherwise, no matter how much money you make, you can&#39;t save your life, so what&#39;s the point? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, these indicators are contradictory. The most typical example is that big cities have higher incomes and more development opportunities, but at the same time, housing prices and consumption in big cities are also more expensive, and the cost of living is very high. So, are big cities livable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there are more opportunities in big cities. Big cities have economies of scale. Under the economies of scale, there will be many services and jobs that cannot be maintained in small places. This is what many people say, they cannot find a job when they return to their hometown in a small town. Therefore, large cities with higher economic indicators can often provide more jobs and higher wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a consumption perspective, due to scale effects, big cities have richer ecosystems and many services will be cheaper. For example, if you want to see an expert account, living in a big city is just a matter of registration fee. You can find corresponding experts for all kinds of difficult and complicated diseases. But living in a small town also involves extra costs such as travel, accommodation and time off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although houses in big cities are expensive, houses are also an asset. Even if you spend millions to buy a house, the money can still be recovered and liquidated. What&#39;s more, the prices of industrial products such as mobile phones, TVs, and automobiles are almost the same. This means that as long as a person&#39;s income can offset, or partially offset, the rent in a big city, his living standard in a big city will be higher and richer, his children will have more opportunities, and he will be able to spend more in emergencies. money. This is roughly what the word livable refers to. More and more people are flocking to big cities, which also proves that big cities are more livable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, people&#39;s needs are complex and diverse. Some people want to live in a 200-square-meter house and play mahjong, but have no interest in opera or luxury goods. Some people are willing to live in a small house of 60 square meters in order for their children to receive a better education. Therefore, livability ultimately depends on the individual. Whether this is an abstract evaluation of the livability of large cities or small cities, we can only give one judgment principle. If we want to evaluate the livability comparison between specific cities, it is even more confusing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anyone with statistical knowledge and research experience knows that data can lie. Not to mention the authenticity of the data, even if the data is real, there are too many ways to control the final conclusion in terms of indicator settings, sampling methods, data processing, and data interpretation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, set up a consumption indicator, consisting of online shopping activity, overseas shopping activity, takeout activity, and movie viewing frequency. Movie watching seems to reflect cultural consumption, but movies have a lipstick effect, which means that when the economy is bad, people will still entertain themselves, and even use entertainment more to comfort themselves, but they will turn to relatively cheap ones. It is possible that tourism consumption has gone down while movie consumption has increased. Therefore, the movie viewing indicator may not be objective. At least, it is not as authoritative and direct as the indicator of total social consumer goods per capita. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many other indicators selection techniques. If public security is to be regarded as the most important indicator and a number of small indicators are set, then the world ranking of Chinese cities will definitely improve a lot, because Chinese people are kind-hearted and have omnipresent eyes. If you regard fireworks as an indicator and set 10 small indicators, then New York&#39;s score may be improved a lot. After all, even Times Square is a mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, urban livability indicators are often not independent. If one indicator improves, other indicators will also improve. For example, if a city has more universities, its medical conditions will also improve. Because universities often have medical schools, there are naturally more experts in medical schools. But it seems impossible to exclude this independence. Because going to a better university and seeking medical treatment from experts are essentially citizens’ educational needs and medical needs. These are indeed two aspects of needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, by setting indicators, the livability evaluation of a city can indeed be greatly affected. The same is true for other cities&#39; economic activity, urban development, best cities and other rankings. They can be used as a reference, but they do not need to be regarded as authoritative. Generally speaking, which city you decide to work and live in will be the most livable city for you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中职学校数量十年间大减，但“这不是坏事”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258931]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766tPBtXF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1263&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766 tPBtXF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 16, 2023, Hohhot, a vocational and technical school teacher introduced the professional situation to students . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A set of data on secondary vocational education once attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media reported that in the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 3,039. Southern Weekend reporters combined data from the websites of the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools continued to decrease, with a cumulative decrease of 2,911. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the websites of the two ministries and commissions, the number of secondary vocational schools in China will be 9,752 in 2022, less than half of the peak in the 1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the country’s adjustment of vocational education policies is the main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools. In addition, the practical difficulties encountered in the development process of secondary vocational schools are also one of the reasons why various places have taken the initiative to merge and reduce schools. However, in recent years, with the changes in the layout of vocational education, secondary vocational schools have also ushered in new changes such as a substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that, combined with the predictions of scholars, in the next few years, the gradual reduction, dissolution, merger and optimization of secondary vocational schools will continue to be a trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Anhui Province has the largest decrease&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;An easily confused concept is that in China, secondary vocational education is divided into four categories, including general technical secondary schools, vocational High schools, adult secondary schools and technical schools. In accordance with the Vocational Education Law and the current &quot;three determinations&quot; (functional configuration, internal organization and staffing) plan of the State Council, vocational high schools, general technical secondary schools and adult technical secondary schools are under the management of the education department, and technical schools are under the management of the human resources and social security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be pointed out that the academic qualifications obtained after graduation from general technical secondary schools, vocational high schools, adult technical secondary schools and technical schools are all secondary education qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the Ministry of Education website shows that in 2013, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide was 12,300. By 2022, this number dropped to 7,201. In the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 5,100 overall. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A closer look at the year-by-year data on the Ministry of Education’s website will reveal that from 2013 to 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased each year by between 151 and 676. In 2021, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased by 2,602 compared with 2020, and there were obvious abnormalities in the range of data changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, a note on the official website of the Ministry of Education shows that the statistics of secondary vocational colleges in 2021 and 2022 do not include technical schools managed by the human resources and social security departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that including data from 2021 and 2022, the number of technical schools increased by 69 and 59 respectively. Combined with the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools in the country from 2013 to 2022 compared with the previous year, the data shows that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide decreased by 2,911 in ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the official data released by the education departments and statistics departments of 31 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) across the country from 2012 to 2022. Whether each province (autonomous region and municipality) plans to collect data The standards for entering technical schools are not uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, looking at the overall situation, nationwide, except for the Tibet Autonomous Region, which has a slight increase in the number of secondary vocational colleges (an increase of 7) on the original basis, the remaining provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) are all. downward trend. The number of secondary vocational schools in Anhui Province has decreased the most, with a decrease of 216 in ten years, a decrease of approximately 44%. Henan Province followed, with a decrease of 198. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, the number of universities has decreased by more than 100 in 10 provinces. Except for Heilongjiang, Shandong, Guangdong, and Zhejiang, the rest are all in the central and western regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Qinghai, Ningxia and other places have experienced single-digit declines over the past ten years due to factors such as insufficient construction of secondary vocational schools, and the change is not significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 25, 2022, in a clothing production company in Tongren, Guizhou, students majoring in clothing design at the Yuping Dong Autonomous County Secondary Vocational School were processing clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Policy adjustment is the main reason&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Secondary vocational school It once played an important role in China&#39;s economic development. Its number experienced explosive growth in the late 1980s, from 2,760 in 1978 to more than 20,000 in 1990, an increase of nearly eight times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by the end of the 20th century, with the combined effects of multiple factors such as industrial restructuring, tightening of the employment environment, and expansion of college enrollment, the development of secondary vocational education gradually declined because it was difficult to adapt to the needs of the market and employers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Official data shows that since 1999, the number of secondary vocational schools has been declining year by year, with only a slight increase between 2004 and 2008. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, in 2007, the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Further Improving the Enrollment Management of Various Types of Colleges and Universities&quot;, which stipulated that the corresponding enrollment plan for colleges and universities to recruit secondary vocational graduates should not exceed the number of fresh graduates of secondary vocational schools that year. 5% of students. This proportion limit actually clarifies the employment orientation of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools is the adjustment of national policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014 and 2019, the State Council issued the &quot;Decision on Accelerating the Development of Modern Vocational Education&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;) and the &quot;Notice on Issuing the National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; respectively. It is proposed to “encourage high-quality schools to integrate school resources and optimize the layout and structure of secondary vocational education through mergers, trusteeships, cooperative education, etc.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Decision&quot; was promulgated, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission announced the corresponding implementation opinions of Beijing, requiring the number of secondary vocational schools in the city to be adjusted from 116 to about 60, a reduction of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan started optimizing the layout of secondary vocational schools in 2015, and integrated a number of &quot;weak, small and scattered&quot; schools in the form of cancellation, merger, and transfer. Jiangxi also introduced a new policy for secondary vocational education in 2015, proposing to merge more than 200 secondary vocational schools within three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in 2015, Guangxi proposed that &quot;by 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools in the region will be adjusted from the current 333 to about 240.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, nine departments including the Ministry of Education jointly issued the &quot;Action Plan for Improving the Quality of Vocational Education (2020-2023)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Plan&quot;). Based on the original policy It is further proposed to &quot;comprehensively verify the basic conditions for running secondary vocational schools, integrate &#39;empty, small, scattered and weak&#39; schools, and optimize the layout of secondary vocational schools.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the adjustment of national policies, the difficulties encountered by secondary vocational schools in their own development are also one of the reasons for the reduction in the number of schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, before the state promulgated relevant policies, local governments had already taken measures to reduce the number of secondary vocational schools, which directly pointed to practical problems in the development of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the beginning of the 21st century, in order to meet the needs of Beijing’s urban function adjustment and industrial structure upgrading, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission merged a number of small-scale, low-efficiency schools with unclear professional characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not a bad thing. Only by merging schools with poor quality and low enrollment can we improve the quality and attractiveness of secondary vocational colleges.” Vice Chairman of China Development Research Foundation Fang Jin, the secretary-general, once said publicly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The transformation of secondary vocational schools pays more attention to quality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The decrease in the number of secondary vocational colleges has a certain relationship with the transformation of secondary vocational education, because the government may China pays more attention to quality rather than quantity.&quot; Xu Hui, a doctoral candidate in sociology at the University of Jena in Germany and a researcher at the Sino-German Research Center for Skills and Social Development, told Southern Weekend reporters that this reduction in quantity may help concentrate resources and improve the quality of education. , to meet today’s ever-changing professional needs. According to Xu Hui’s observation, under the transformation, secondary vocational education has greatly improved in terms of curriculum diversity, technology upgrading, and career guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ensuing increase in attractiveness is also the result of policy changes. One of the key points is the substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PhD candidate Jiang Beijia and scientific research assistant Fan Yilin of the National Education Macro Policy Research Institute of East China Normal University published a paper &quot;Policy Changes in Vocational Education for Higher Education: Context, Logic and &quot;Mirror&quot;, sorted out relevant policy documents and found that since the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Education Reform and Development Plan (2010-2020)&quot; issued in 2010, it was first proposed to separate the enrollment of higher vocational examinations from the general college entrance examination. The &quot;National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; clearly states for the first time that &quot;the establishment of a vocational education college entrance examination system&quot; will be completely liberated from the previously restricted enrollment rate in secondary vocational schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the main channels for secondary vocational school graduates to obtain undergraduate degrees include consistent training, vocational education college entrance examination, junior college to bachelor&#39;s degree, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smooth flow of channels for further education has led to an increase in the admission rate of secondary vocational schools. Data released by education departments in many places show that the enrollment rate of secondary vocational schools in recent years has generally exceeded 80%. Taking Shenzhen, which has developed secondary vocational education, as an example, the &quot;Shenzhen Secondary Vocational Education Quality Report 2023&quot; shows that in 2022, the number of graduates from Shenzhen&#39;s secondary vocational schools will be 12,485, and the number of students entering higher education will be 11,173, with the enrollment rate reaching 89.49%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xu Hui also pointed out that a high secondary vocational education promotion rate can provide students with more opportunities, but a careful balance is also needed to ensure that the quality and resources of secondary vocational education are not ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2022, at a press conference held by the Ministry of Education to introduce the work related to promoting the high-quality development of modern vocational education, Chen Ziji, Director of the Department of Vocational Education and Adult Education of the Ministry of Education, further explained that optimizing the quality of secondary vocational education The layout structure is mainly achieved through measures such as cancellation, merger, transformation, trusteeship, land replacement, and group school running. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that in the future, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide may continue to decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女童被狗咬伤事件中，伤人的罗威纳是种什么犬？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258939]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[普通人上播客讲故事：声波起伏间，听见人生一段]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258802]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;46-year-old excavator Wang Chunyan told her life story through a podcast. This time, her voice arrived In the ears of tens of thousands of people. On the construction site where the machines are roaring, she is silent most of the time. When faced with the foreman&#39;s scolding, she just pretends not to hear it and sometimes has to smile. With only one square meter in the cab, she would listen to her favorite music and sing loudly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DNEXw9iOruxL22YwlzaDlFPOCgz64j52FhUkjWP6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DNEXw9iOruxL22YwlzaDlFPOCgz64j52FhUkjWP6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254358&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Women are in the minority among those who operate excavators. As one of them, Wang Chunyan’s experience is special. The picture shows the scene of drying chili peppers in Jiuquan, Gansu Province in September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the collection of stories on the theme of &quot;My achievements have nothing to do with gender&quot; was issued, Kou Aizhe received a large number of submissions , he was first attracted by Wang Chunyan’s message, although she only briefly expressed that as a woman, “the excavator makes me very proud.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye, who is studying for graduate school in France, entered the podcast process as a narrator, which was full of drama. She learned that her father, whom she had not seen for many years, passed away in Cambodia. She wanted to go there, but she did not dare to leave rashly. She happened to find a podcast episode in which a Chinese man in Cambodia, Santiao, told his story about a foreign country. She finally contacted him through a message. With care, Xiaoye completed the &quot;journey to find his father&quot; with peace of mind, and later accepted the invitation to participate in the podcast recording with this story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Xiaoyushu App, Xiaoye’s story has become one of the three most popular programs among all podcasts. This kind of spread effect was expected by the host Da Meng. What he didn’t expect was that as a Content workers can help some people solve real-life problems while making programs. This is the biggest healing and encouragement Xiaoye&#39;s story brings to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Xinran listened to his podcast outside the massage parlor where he worked. He was embarrassed to listen in front of his colleagues and felt that his voice was unpleasant. When he told his story, there was something &quot;very hard to explain&quot;. He is a blind marathon runner. In the show, he said: &quot;As long as you run, you can create the wind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe and Dameng are the owners of two podcasts - Story FM and Genius respectively. Founder and anchor of Catcher FM. Story FM passed its seventh birthday, and Genius Catcher FM was born at the end of 2019. The former&#39;s guest self-narration format has become a signature, while the latter uses interviews to capture the inspiration of all kinds of life. The content narrators of podcasts are often industry experts, scholars, and media people, and these two podcasts provide a stage for lay people to talk and express themselves, and amplify their voices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djz1BWwVeyn3H4uCHyx0M6YiDijOez8Jk340CNkQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djz1BWwVeyn3H4uCHyx0M6YiDijOez8Jk340CNkQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are currently relatively few Chinese podcasts where amateurs tell stories. The picture is a creative picture. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They host almost the only large-scale witness story podcast in China. Dameng saw that the podcast platform classified the two into the story category, which is not a problem in itself. What is strange is that other podcasts in the same category tell ghost stories and historical stories. &quot;They are not the same &#39;storytelling&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;From listener to narrator&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan had been listening to Story FM for five years before she opened her mouth to tell the story. At first, she was attracted by the eye-catching title of Story FM, but gradually she felt that it suited her very well, as it was an &quot;unconcealed, spiritual communication program that directly faces people&#39;s hearts.&quot; She is particularly interested in stories involving life, death and human emotions, and is keenly aware that the program &quot;focuses on more vulnerable groups.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she saw Story FM’s call for submissions to collect stories about women in gender-imbalanced industries, Wang Chunyan had a lot to say. &quot;As a female excavator master, I don&#39;t know if I have a firm foothold, but I have persisted for more than ten years and I feel quite proud.&quot; She left a message, &quot;I didn&#39;t expect Ai Zhe to really see it.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When the epidemic broke out, Xiaoye developed the habit of listening to podcasts. She described that she had some obsessive-compulsive disorder at the time. After discovering Genius Catcher FM, she listened to every program from the beginning. Xiaoye, who already likes to listen to different life stories, is like finding a treasure. He keeps listening to it until now. The program invited many people from all walks of life to tell their career stories. She was deeply impressed by the psychiatrist Chen Baiyou among them, because what she told was very touching and different from the public perception. &quot;She said that only kind people will suffer from mental illness, which touched me very much.&quot; Xiaoye told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye’s parents went to Cambodia to work together. She was also born in Cambodia. After her parents divorced, her mother took Xiaoye back to China to develop, while her father stayed in Cambodia. In June 2022, Xiaoye learned about her father&#39;s death through relatives. On Father&#39;s Day a week later, she sent her blessings to her father&#39;s WeChat, but she did not expect a response from the other party. A strange Cambodian woman contacted Xiaoye and claimed to be her father&#39;s partner. Later, she invited Xiaoye to Phnom Penh to participate in her father&#39;s 100-day festival. When she was hesitating whether to go there, she happened to see Genius Catcher FM&#39;s push &quot;I collected corpses for Chinese people in Cambodia, but I didn&#39;t dare to show the faces of the corpses to their families.&quot; She left messages for Dameng on various platforms, hoping to get to know the narrator, Santiao, and Dameng set up a connection between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sanjou said to Xiaoye: &quot;Just come, I will pick you up at the airport.&quot; As soon as she left the airport gate, Xiaoye saw the woman holding a photo of her father, but she always felt that she would just go with this stranger , feeling panicked. At this time, Sanjou appeared. He grabbed Xiaoye&#39;s suitcase and protected her from behind. On the first day of Xiaoye&#39;s arrival, Sanjou drove with him all the way, and even called his girlfriend, who could speak English and Cambodian, to act as a translator for Xiaoye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye bought an urn at the local market and took away part of his father&#39;s ashes. Among his father&#39;s belongings, there was a small box containing several photos with Xiaoye. Xiaoye also discovered that although he had not seen his father since his second year in junior high school, his passport still had records of entering China several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Xiaoye returned to daily life, Dameng chatted with her for an hour or two and recorded this life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His father was absent when Xiaoye was growing up. Whether it was on the phone or via WeChat, Xiaoye felt that he could not truly communicate with each other. But within just two or three days of staying in a foreign land, Xiaoye realized that his father had been thinking about him. From a group of strange Cambodian people, she heard her relatives call her: baby, with an exaggerated pronunciation and mouth shape, which was unique to her father. She thought about how many times her father had to say it before everyone around him remembered it. Some listeners shed tears after hearing this detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/N6yoBn0rYEuKFsOCqtCknUHP4Y8clT3ww87UIy03.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/N6yoBn0rYEuKFsOCqtCknUHP4Y8clT3ww87UIy03.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254359&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The stories of the Chinese in Cambodia have been made into a series of podcasts, including the story of Xiaoye going to participate in his father&#39;s 100-day festival. The picture shows the Day of the Dead in Phnom Penh, Cambodia in October 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan has been driving excavators for more than ten years. When she talked about taking hormones to gain weight in order to collect bills more easily and avoid being sexually harassed, Kou Aizhe was shocked and confirmed again, did you really take hormones to gain weight? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many inconveniences for women working as excavators, such as the lack of toilets at the construction site. For this reason, Wang Chunyan would leave home at around 5 a.m. and get off work at around 8 p.m. without taking a sip of water. Sometimes she couldn&#39;t hold it in any longer, so she would dig a hole for emergencies. Not many people can persist. Wang Chunyan has built a &quot;National Queen Group&quot;, which has 99 female excavator operators, roughly 1/3 of which have mature skills. She has accepted three female apprentices, and they either changed careers or started working on their own. When you are the boss, you no longer do it yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan persisted mainly to make money. Doing other jobs cannot support this family. When she was 16 years old, her abducted sister returned home nine months pregnant. Both her mother and sister suffer from mental illness, and her father-in-law is careless. The family&#39;s livelihood depends entirely on Wang Chunyan. Later, her husband was in a car accident and became a vegetative state. After he woke up and was discharged from the hospital paralyzed, he owed a large amount of medical expenses, which Wang Chunyan has been paying over the years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two months after the podcast was released, many listeners left messages and were moved by her tenacity, courage, and optimism. Wang Chunyan didn&#39;t pay much attention to this feedback. She was working every day in the past few days and &quot;didn&#39;t stop to review those things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Speak out your worries and hear new knowledge&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan has never told her family about the hardships she experienced outside. Her sister, mother, and husband are all patients. Her parents-in-law have never wanted to see her because of her family background. She, there was almost no emotional communication between the two parties. &quot;I don&#39;t have an outlet to vent. Sometimes I feel very depressed and want a space to talk.&quot; Talking about her life in the podcast fulfilled her wish to talk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe understands this mentality very well, “Everyone needs to tell something that has been buried in his heart for a long time, or some obstacles that he cannot get over, or he is confused about this matter and wants to hear some people’s opinions. Feedback, but he may not want people around him to hear it, for example, he cannot accept these people judging him.&quot; Some of the more secretive stories are basically from the narrator&#39;s initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, if the narrator states that he does not want certain details to be disclosed, such as name, city, and industry, they will be blurred. This protection of anonymity also gives the narrator more courage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s anonymous anyway, no one knows who I am, so I can say whatever I want.&quot; Xiaoye received Da Meng&#39;s recording invitation and readily agreed. She was very happy to be on the podcast she often listens to. , at the same time, she felt that this story was &quot;quite bizarre, outrageous, and worth telling&quot; and wanted to share it with more people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dameng’s view, recording a podcast is a process in which the narrator and the producer complement each other. &quot;Sometimes people experience some legendary things and want to record them. Some people are willing to write and some are willing to talk about it. It is also important for the guests to record their own experiences on our program. Let me help them complete it. Content editor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because everyone&#39;s life is boring and they are curious about what other people live, so they especially like to listen to such stories. For me, this is a way to see the world. The window is mainly for fun.&quot; Xiaoye explained why people love to listen to stories told by another ordinary person so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For producers, the fun of doing programs is largely due to the ability to gain new knowledge and broaden their cognitive boundaries. When I first started doing a series of stories about Cambodian characters, almost every issue would refresh Da Meng’s understanding. The narrators all live in Phnom Penh and Sihanoukville, Cambodia, helping Chinese people in trouble in foreign lands. Santiao was the first one to share on the show. He volunteered to help Chinese people who died accidentally in Cambodia, process and cremate their bodies, and transport them back to China. Later, Dameng interviewed Jie Ge and Aaron one after another. They used their own methods to protect the Chinese wandering in Cambodia or guide them on their way home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Long Distance Running Festival in April 2023 made Dameng pay attention to He Yajun’s Blind Assistance Group. After contacting several blind runners in the group, he chose Song Xinran as the subject of his story. The theme of the program is about &quot;wind&quot;. Every Wednesday and Saturday morning, Song Xinran runs with nearly a hundred teammates in the Beijing Olympic Forest Park, passing through flowers, bamboo forests, and ponds. The blind friend and the running aid volunteer are connected by a running aid rope for the blind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v5xWL54vReWbjIi8ol9nJ4E7jtFpQz3b2eNNqLOk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v5xWL54vReWbjIi8ol9nJ4E7jtFpQz3b2eNNqLOk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Song Xinran, a blind man, talked about his experience in long-distance running. The picture shows a blind running rope connecting a blind marathon runner (left) and a volunteer guiding him (right) in Tai&#39;an, Shandong in 2017. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The competition that Song Xinran is most proud of is the 2019 Beijing Long Distance Running Festival. He ran hard and ran within the prescribed time. He crossed the finish line and won the qualification for his runner to pass through to the &quot;Northern Marathon&quot; competition. Running has become an indispensable part of Song Xinran&#39;s life. The customers who come for massage are also infected by him and start practicing running. Sometimes when talking about pace, they praise it, it’s so fast. You have bad eyesight and you can run faster than us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Story FM has also invited some blind narrators. Although everyone has their own interests and hobbies, when it comes to employment, most of them can only go for massages. In a later episode, a group of blind employees from Xiaomi in Shanghai were invited to talk about how they worked as markers and trained the AI ​​Xiao Ai classmates. A blind listener in Xi&#39;an listened to the program and kept sending messages to Kou Aizhe, telling him how the program inspired him. Kou Aizhe witnessed his changes little by little. The latest news was that he came to report good news: Xiaomi was recruiting blind people to do similar work in Xi&#39;an, and he successfully applied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listening to strangers’ stories sometimes has such a direct impact on the audience that they respond in their own lives. As the popularity of the program increased, Dameng discovered that many listeners regarded Genius Catcher FM as a career guide. A program by a space organizer inspired several listeners to start engaging in related work. A person passed the police civil service examination and sent a private message saying that he was not a police major. After listening to the program, he yearned for the honor and experience of this profession and had a belief. I was so moved and frightened that I turned on the program and listened to it again, &quot;Don&#39;t say anything nonsense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let different people &quot;penetrate each other&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye likes to listen to podcasts in the shower and while commuting. Chatting podcasts rank first in her mind. “They are the kind where the host is chatting, and you listen and feel like you can join in, so you can’t help but join in the discussion.” One time while commuting, she heard something funny, stopped and stamped her feet on the street, laughing loudly. Life seemed to have a different color because her ears were plugged and she couldn&#39;t hear the sounds outside. At that moment, she felt happy and contented, &quot;This is my world.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When operating an excavator, if the construction site is large enough, has a good view, and the work is not too tight, Wang Chunyan will turn on the stereo and listen to something. Only in the one-square-meter cab of the excavator can she have some time of her own. The rest of the time belongs to others. &quot;Coming home is like fighting a war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan also plays Douyin. Among the bloggers she follows, there are many ideological bloggers, but she believes that &quot;Douyin is just a kind of fast food, and the real nutritious meal is podcasts.&quot; Podcasts arouse her deep understanding. There is more to think about than short videos. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A podcast episode is usually tens of minutes long, or even as long as two or three hours. Unlike short videos and other content, Dameng pointed out that the main value that podcasts, long-form content that focuses on reality, can bring to listeners is &quot;companionship and recognition.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He interviewed the founders of transgender groups, social workers who helped female domestic workers, and niche professional or hobby groups, trying to reflect the situation of a group of people through their narration of their fate and experiences, and make many people who originally felt People who are very lonely are no longer so lonely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In podcasts where amateurs tell stories, the narrator’s expressive ability is not that important. Dameng believes that the value of stories to people, the scarcity of information, and the desire of guests to share are all more important than the ability to express themselves. Kou Aizhe bluntly said that the so-called ability to express well is actually a privilege. What Story FM wants to do is to break it rather than strengthen it. &quot;Those who are not so eloquent in expression have very good stories and very good experiences, but It is a pity to remain silent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寇爱哲采访过一个投稿人，是流水线上的女工，多年来，她尝试把孩子带在身边，与自己一同在城市里生活，结果处处碰壁，后来，她也试图回家乡找份工作，但家乡没有好工作，无法养活家庭，给孩子更好的生活。虽然她的受教育水平不高，表达也质朴无华，却令许多一线城市中产家庭父母产生共鸣，父母对子女的爱与付出、养育孩子过程中的纠结，是共通的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不希望大家非常单一地、用某个标签去评价一个人，这可能是我的故事想要表现出来的东西。”寇爱哲想通过播客，让不同阶级或者阶层的人“彼此穿透”，了解各自的生活是什么样的，多一分理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪春艳曾怀揣着好奇听完了“5000万相亲局的背后，亿万富豪还相信爱情吗”这期节目。她得出结论，“本身我们作为一个人基本的特征，追求的也就是真心和真诚，不管他是千万富翁也好，平民老百姓也好。&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“短视频也好，或者是短的一些帖子、图文内容，我们很快就会收获一个结论，但是在播客里面，就可以跟着亲历者，重新回溯这个人的成长、这个人的经历，就会发现每件事、每个人的背后都是复杂的。”大猛对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“你只看见我这一面就好”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;宋新然的播客被队长转发到了跑团群里，队友们夸赞他，讲的故事特别真实，希望以后还能听到他亲口讲述的故事。他在播客里还提到自己和女友相识相爱的过程，两人在跑团共同训练，逐渐产生感情。表白那天，他拥抱了女友，群里有人听见后揶揄，“现在的年轻人，胆子可真大，我们那时候可不敢那样。”女友听了节目，也嗔怪宋新然把他俩的事“说得那么直白”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小叶给身边友人听自己那期节目，有几个半生不熟的朋友，在微信上向她发送很长的小作文，中心思想是安慰与夸奖，“给我整得特别不好意思”。小叶最爱问听过的朋友，你听哭了吗&lt;span>;？ &lt;/span>;对方说哭了，小叶便觉得“可以，有一种赚到了的感觉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪春艳对于录播客这件事很低调，女儿是她唯一的分享对象。汪春艳陪同丈夫在浙江住院那三年，女儿被送回湖北老家，读小学的她遭到校园霸凌，得了抑郁症，一直比较叛逆，很少与父母交流。汪春艳不知道女儿听后的具体感受，因为她没说什么，隔了一天才和自己联系。只是从那之后，女儿开始愿意和汪春艳聊天，关心也变多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;柬埔寨之行，小叶对包括母亲在内的亲人只字未提，自然也没有让他们知晓自己录的播客。父亲，本就是小叶和母亲心照不宣避开谈论的话题，小叶也不希望让母亲知道自己去了柬埔寨：“一方面因为她有点控制欲，我大部分时间还是在演着一个比较听话的女儿，对于这种大的事我都会尽量倾听她的意见。她之前很严肃地跟我说不希望我去，但是我出于自己的倔强，还是去了。还有我也不是很想她知道在柬埔寨还有一位女士跟我爸生活，不想让她离开我爸这么久，还要因为我爸的事情思来想去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，小叶又有些期待母亲能发现这件事，说不定两人会因此更敞开去谈。小叶决意不主动告诉她，而录播客就像埋下了一个线索，也许她会寻到，也许成为永远的秘密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故事FM2022年请制作人们进行“年终总结”。其中一位制作人提到自己在制作一期节目时，本来被受访者的一段自白打动不已，都想到要把这段话作为节目结尾了，受访者却接着问：“怎么样，我这么说还挺能调动听众情绪的吧？”制作人忽然意识到，就算是如此追求纪实的采访，也往往只是将某个人生命中的片段放大，所以想提醒听众：别那么在意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;节目刚播出的几天，小叶留意了评论。看见有人说好想关注小叶微博，她心想，千万别关注。 “你听我的故事，这是我的一面，但是如果你真的关注我的生活，就是另一面。人本身就是多面的，你只看见我这一面就好，我不想全方位无死角地展现在大众面前，我不喜欢这样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;播客凝结了他们的一小部分人生记忆，而真实的生活仍在继续，远比被讲述的故事复杂得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪春艳在节目里说，自己当时在菩萨面前许愿，如果丈夫醒过来，自己愿意给他一半的寿命，只活到50岁。还有几年就到这个岁数了，她希望能去旅行，为自己活一把。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实里的汪春艳，在热情、勇敢之外，另有一层被境遇打磨出的清醒与冷峻。她认为，“世上的事情看多了，活那么多也没有什么用，活50岁就够了。”去精神病院看望姐姐，对方已经不认得她了，需要别人递水递饭才会进食，她想，那种状态下，维持姐姐的寿命又起到什么作用呢，只是让自己这个亲人心安而已。她将《红楼梦》读了不知多少遍，对人生空幻之感，毫不陌生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采访最后，她忽然询问南方周末记者，骨髓捐赠（即造血干细胞捐赠的俗称）对于捐赠者的健康会否有影响，她申请过志愿捐献造血干细胞，最近与一个病人初配型成功，但女儿不同意。如果不会影响她干活，她还是希望出一份力：“一个生命等着，不去挽救，也太残忍了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中小叶、三条为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高法发布国家公园司法保护典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258840]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;国家公园是我国最重要的自然生态空间，是自然生态系统中最重要、自然景观最独特、自然遗产最精华、生物多样性最富集的部分。建立国家公园体制，是习近平总书记亲自谋划、亲自部署、亲自推动的“国之大者”。党的十八大以来，以习近平同志为核心的党中央站在实现中华民族永续发展的战略高度，作出一系列重大战略部署，推进建立国家公园体制，加快建设以国家公园为主体的自然保护地体系，切实加大自然生态保护力度。2021年10月12日，习近平主席在《生物多样性公约》第十五次缔约方大会领导人峰会上宣布，我国正式设立三江源、大熊猫、东北虎豹、海南热带雨林、武夷山等第一批国家公园，标志着国家公园这项重大创新制度落地生根，国家公园建设迈入新台阶。2022年11月，我国出台《国家公园空间布局方案》，明确了国家公园创建设立工作流程、主要建设任务和实施保障措施，遴选出49个国家公园候选区，擘画了构建全世界最大国家公园体系的宏伟蓝图。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;高质量建设国家公园，是我国生态文明制度建设的重要内容，对于推进自然资源科学保护和合理利用，促进人与自然和谐共生，推进美丽中国建设，具有极其重要的意义。近年来，人民法院始终坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，深入践行习近平法治思想、习近平生态文明思想，深入贯彻落实能动司法理念，坚持为大局服务、为人民司法，依法妥善审理涉及国家公园的环境污染防治、生态保护修复、&lt;/span>;资源开发利用等各类环境资源案件，努力推动我国国家公园高水平保护高质量发展。为加强国家公园法治宣传，培养国家公园文化，传播国家公园理念，彰显人民法院保护国家公园取得的成效，最高人民法院发布系列国家公园司法保护典型案例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次发布十件典型案例，具有以下亮点。一是涉及诉讼种类多、保护范围广。本批典型案例包括环境资源刑事、民事及公益诉讼等不同诉讼类型，涵盖了环境资源审判领域的主要范围；涉及的国家公园既有三江源、大&lt;span>;熊猫、东北虎豹、海南热带雨林、武夷山等五个首批设立的国家公园，还有列入《国家公园空间布局方案》遴选的国家公园候选区的钱江源-&lt;/span>;百山祖国家公园，体现了人民法院审理涉国家公园保护的案件诉讼种类多、保护国家公园范围广的特点。二是坚持能动司法。案例五王某民等六人滥伐林木、危害国家重点保护植物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，及案例九张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案，人民法院对于审判中发现的国家公园管理方面的漏洞短板，没有机械司法、一判了之，而是积极延伸环境资源审判职能，主动融入生态文明建设进程，向行政主管部门发出司法建议，督促有关部门查漏补缺，是能动司法的生动实践。三是坚持一体化保护、系统治理理念。案例三杨某等三人污染环境案，体现了人民法院加强对大熊猫国家公园毗邻区域环境污染行为的治理；案例四李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，人民法院对危害珍贵、濒危野生动物犯罪的“猎捕-收购-运输-销售”环节进行全链条打击，是一体化保护、系统治理的生动实践。四是坚持最严法治原则。案例一&lt;span>;郑某成、高某进、叶某东非法采矿案，对于非法开采国家战略性资源的行为，在法定刑幅度范围内从严处罚，并严格控制缓刑的适用，用司法利剑保障国家战略性资源的开发利用。案例七海南省人民检察院第一分院诉李某清、叶某青生态破坏民事公益诉讼案，在行为人已被另案判处刑事责任的同时，严肃追究其民事赔偿责任，体现了损害担责、最严法治的原则。案例八浙江省开化县人民检察院诉陆某燕等四人生态破坏民事公益诉讼案，对于通过录制宰杀视频验货、网络支付、邮寄交货等方式非法收购、出售野生动物行为，依法严肃惩处，彰&lt;/span>;显了以最严格制度最严密法治保护国家公园生态环境的态度。五是坚持预防性司法。案例四李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，对于动物园经营者的犯罪人，为预防其利用从事野生动物收购、饲养、出售、运输等便利条件再实施此类犯罪，人民法院对其判处“禁止令”，体现了预防性司法理念。六是妥善处理民生、发展和保护的关系。案例二张某强非法制造枪支、非法狩猎案，对于刚刚脱贫的当地村民适用缓刑，避免刚&lt;span>;脱贫的家庭因刑返贫，较好平衡了生态环境保护和民生保障之间的关系。案例六李某良、羊某理失火、羊某理非法狩猎刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，考虑到被告经济困难，准许其通过劳务代偿的方式履行异地生态修复义务，体现了司法对民生保障的关切。案例九张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案，依照野生动物保护法有关规定，对野生动物造成伤亡人员的家属请求有关部门给付补偿金的诉讼请求予以支持，体现了兼顾野生动物保护与维护人民生命财产安全的双重目标。案例十青海某水电开发公司破产重整案，充分发挥审判职能作用，加强与政府相关部门的协调，促成案涉水电站全面复工，有效化解了企业破产纠纷，妥善处理了社会经济发展和生态环境保护的关系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这十件国家公园司法保护典型案件的依法妥善审理，充分展现了人民法院发挥生态环境资源审判职能、依法保护国家公园自然生态系统的完整性和原真性、给子孙后代留下珍贵自然资产的责任担当，对维护国家生态安全，保护生物多样性，推动国家公园高水平保护高质量发展具有积极意义。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;国家公园司法保护典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一、郑某成、高某进、叶某东非法采矿案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;二、张某强非法制造枪支、非法狩猎案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;三、杨某等三人污染环境案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四、李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;五、王某民等六人滥伐林木、危害国家重点保护植物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;六、李某良、羊某理失火，羊某理非法狩猎刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;七、海南省人民检察院第一分院诉李某清、叶某青生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;八、浙江省开化县人民检察院诉陆某燕等四人生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;九、张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;十、青海某水电开发公司破产重整案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;一、郑某成、高某进、叶某东非法采矿案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被告人郑某成与他人共同承包位于福建省光泽县鸾凤乡某山场的林地，该山场位于武夷山国家公园范围内。郑某成与被告人高某进系朋友关系，二人预谋在该山场合伙开采稀土牟利。2016年9月至2017年5月期间，郑某成、高某进组织冯某安、钟某明（均另案处理）和被告人叶某东等人在无采矿许可证的情况下，到该山场采用在山体打溶洞注入硫酸铵等，再对析出液体进行沉淀的方式开采稀土矿，现场查获疑似稀土半成品9300千克。经鉴定，案涉稀土矿均属离子吸附型稀土，属国家规定实行保护性开采的特定矿种，郑某成等人非法开采行为还造成稀土矿点矿产资源破坏。此外，另查明叶某东于2018年3月与他人因琐事争执并打斗，犯有故意伤害致人轻伤的犯罪事实。福建省光泽县以郑某成、高某进、叶某东犯非法采矿罪，叶某东犯故意伤害罪提起公诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;福建省光泽县人民法院经审理认为，被告人郑某成、高某进、叶某东等人违反矿产资源法的规定，无采矿许可证擅自开采国家实行保护性开采的特定矿种离子吸附型稀土矿，情节特别严重，已构成非法采矿罪。郑某成、高某进是主犯，叶某东是从犯。遂以非法采矿罪分别判处郑某成、高某进有期徒刑四年九个月，并处罚金15万元；以非法采矿罪、故意伤害罪，数罪并罚，判处叶某东有期徒刑三年，并处罚金10万元；扣押在案的稀土半成品予以没收。宣判后，被告人高某进不服，提出上诉。福建省南平市中级人民法院二审裁定：驳回上诉，维持原判。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;武夷山国家公园是我国目前唯一一个既是世界人与生物圈保护区，又是世界文化与自然双遗产的国家公园，储有众多不可再生的宝贵矿产资源。其中的稀土是我国的重要战略资源，是新兴产业、高端制造业、现代国防科技工业的关键元素。近年来，武夷山国家公园周边地区出现了非法开采稀土的犯罪行为，损害国家稀土资源储备，严重威胁国家公园环境资源安全。本案被告人以原地浸矿法开采稀土矿，危害到武夷山国家公园的生态服务功能和生态系统稳定性，容易导致植被破坏、山体裸露、水源污染、水土流失、山体滑坡、地面裂缝和沉降等严重后果发生。人民法院在开采的矿产品价值和造成矿产资源破坏的价值均已查明的情况下，以造成矿产资源破坏的价值认定被告人非法采矿行为情节特别严重，依法严厉惩处非法开采稀土犯罪，在法定刑幅度范围内从严处罚，并严格控制缓刑的适用，有利于保障国家战略性资源的开发利用，守护国家公园生态安全。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;二、张某强非法制造枪支、非法狩猎案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2017年期间，被告人张某强到海南省海口市某五金店购买一把射钉枪、一根枪管及铁砂、射钉弹后，使用其自有工具组装枪型物1支。经鉴定，张某强制造的枪型物为利用火药为发射动力的枪支。2022年3月21日凌晨，张某强在未经野生动物行政主管部门许可，且无狩猎证和持枪证的情况下，擅自进入被划为禁猎区的海南热带雨林国家公园霸王岭分局洪水管护站内狩猎，使用枪支共猎捕赤腹松鼠3只、椰子猫1只、鼬獾1只，使用头照灯照射猎捕大绿臭蛙30只。张某强于次日下山途中被公安民警当场抓获。经鉴定，案涉椰子猫属国家二级保护野生动物，鼬獾、赤腹松鼠均被列入《国家保护的有益的或者有重要经济、科学研究价值的陆生野生动物名录》，臭蛙属于海南省重点保护陆生野生动物。海南省人民检察院第二分院以张某强犯非法制造枪支、非法狩猎罪提起公诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海南省第二中级人民法院经审理认为，张某强行为已构成非法制造枪支罪、非法狩猎罪，应当数罪并罚。张某强作为生活在国家公园范围区刚脱贫的村民，改变当地的传统生产生活方式，走绿色发展改善民生之路，尚需探索时间。张某强是家中主要劳动力，对其羁押既不符合刑法谦抑性原则，也可能使其家庭重返贫困。法律的权威在于刑罚的不可避免性，而非严苛，在能使用较轻刑罚达到制裁目的时，无需使用严厉的制裁方式。鉴于张某强系初犯，案发后如实供述其罪行，认罪认罚且有悔罪表现，其居住地愿意配合进行社区矫正，宣告缓刑对所居住社区没有重大不良影响。遂判决：张某强数罪并罚，决定执行有期徒刑三年，缓刑五年，没收犯罪工具等。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年4月，习近平总书记在海南考察调研时明确指出热带雨林国家公园是国宝，是水库、粮库、钱库，更是碳库，要求对热带雨林实行严格保护，实现生态保护、绿色发展、民生改善相统一。尽管海南热带雨林国家公园建设过程中对环境资源保护的力度不断加大，国家公园附近的原住村民对热带雨林及生物多样性资源的损害性利用仍时有发生。本案中，被告人违反狩猎法规，在禁猎区使用改造的枪支及其它工具狩猎，破坏野生动物资源的价值较大，应当受到刑事制裁。同时，人民法院充分考虑被告人的个体因素，给予其改过自新的机会，对其适用缓刑，避免刚脱贫的家庭因刑返贫，彰显司法的人文关怀，实现了惩罚和预防犯罪相结合的目的，也较好平衡了生态环境保护和民生保障之间的关系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;三、杨某等三人污染环境案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2020年6月至9月，被告人杨某、屈某敏、高某虎在未取得危险废物经营许可证、未采取地面防护措施的情况下，在毗邻大熊猫国家公园保护区域的四川省绵阳市安州区花荄镇某村的山林中，利用破碎机等设备对14.53吨废机油格进行破碎处置，分离出废铁和废发动机油并销售。三被告人销售废铁非法获利26450元、销售废发动机油非法获利6000余元。经绵阳市生态环境局认定，案涉废机油格为含有或沾染废发动机油的过滤吸附介质，被列入《国家危险废物名录》，废物类别HW49，废物代码900-041-49，属于危险废物。经评估，案涉地块土壤中石油烃的最高浓度为3080mg/Kg，超过《土壤环境质量建设用地土壤污染风险管控标准（试行）》（GB36600-2018）表1中第一类用地筛选值，确定该地块存在石油烃污染，此次违法生产行为对该地块的土壤生态环境造成了损害。三被告人均投案自首，自愿认罪认罚且签字具结，并主动退缴违法所得3.3万元。四川省绵阳市安州区人民检察院以污染环境罪对杨某、屈某敏、高某虎提起公诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省绵阳市安州区人民法院经审理认为，杨某、屈某敏、高某虎违反国家规定，非法处置危险废物，严重污染环境，构成污染环境罪。三被告人系共同犯罪，犯罪作用相当，不区分主从犯；三被告人主动投案并如实供述自己的罪行，系自首，依法可以从轻或减轻处罚；三被告人自愿认罪认罚，可从宽处理；三被告人主动退缴全部违法所得，可酌情从轻处罚。遂判决：杨某、屈某敏、高某虎有期徒刑各九个月、缓刑各一年，并分别处以罚金1.5万元，没收三人违法所得3.3万元（已追缴）。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;森林土壤是发展林业生产的物质基础。近年来，部分不法分子受利益驱使，侵占山场林地，非法回收废机油、倾倒有毒有害物质，对林地土壤及其附作物造成严重破坏，打破森林的生态平衡，损害公共利益。本案案发地毗邻大熊猫国家公园保护区域，由于废机油污染介质具有流动性、迁移性，因此针对废机油导致的环境污染事件，不应仅以国家公园边界为准，而需要对国家公园毗邻区域全方位一体化保护。本案中，人民法院依法惩处污染环境的犯罪行为，全面加强环境资源保护力度，坚守人与自然和谐共生，践行绿水青山就是金山银山理念，为加快形成绿色发展方式，促进经济发展和环境保护双赢提供法治保障。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;四、李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2019年以来，被告人李某华多次联系被告人龙某军猎捕野生小熊猫活体。2019年至2020年4月期间，龙某军将其自己捕获的野生小熊猫活体15只出售给李某华及被告人李某秋（李某华之子）；李某华父子将其中14只运至山东莱州、江苏南京等地，向被告人刘某甲出售2只，向其他三名动物园经营者（另案处理）共出售10只，非法获利29万元。2020年11月至12月期间，龙某军从被告人高某林处收购4只野生小熊猫活体后，将其中1只耳朵有缺陷的野生小熊猫放生，将3只小熊猫驾车运至四川省泸定县，李某华父子及被告人刘某乙驾车从泸定购得该3只小熊猫后返回途中被公安机关查获。2020年4月以来，李某华父子到四川省平武县锁江羌族乡从被告人马某曹处收购金丝猴活体18只；其中13只，由李某华父子二人雇佣被告人张某华、刘某乙运输至安徽铜陵出售给经营动物园的被告人徐某珍、沈某等人，非法获利56万元。经鉴定，案涉小熊猫均为国家二级保护野生动物，单只价值为4万元；金丝猴均为川金丝猴，系国家一级保护野生动物，单只价值为50万元。雅安市人民检察院以危害珍贵、濒危野生动物罪对李某华等十一人提起公诉，并提起附带民事公益诉讼，诉请李某华、李某秋、刘某甲、龙某军赔偿死亡的野生小熊猫11只公益赔偿金共计44万元，李某华、李某秋、马某曹赔偿死亡的野生金丝猴1只公益赔偿金50万元，李某华等十一名被告共同在媒体公开赔礼道歉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省雅安市中级人民法院经审理认为，李某华等人非法猎捕、出售、收购、运输国家重点保护的珍贵、濒危野生动物的行为，均构成危害珍贵、濒危野生动物罪。其中李某华、李某秋非法收购、运输、出售国家一级保护野生动物川金丝猴18只，国家二级保护野生动物小熊猫18只，野生动物价值共计972万元，属情节特别严重，综合考虑李某华具有累犯、坦白等情形，李某秋具有立功等情节，判处李某华有期徒刑十四年并处罚金50万元、李某秋有期徒刑八年并处罚金30万元。马某曹非法猎捕、出售国家一级保护野生动物川金丝猴18只，野生动物价值900万元，属情节特别严重；综合考虑其系自首等情节，判处马某曹有期徒刑十一年并处罚金30万元。判处其余被告人有期徒刑三年至六年不等，并处罚金5万元至25万元不等。对于动物园经营者刘某甲、徐某珍，并处自刑罚执行完毕之日或者假释之日起五年内禁止从事与野生动物有关的一切经营性活动。判令民事公益诉讼被告李某华、李某秋、刘某甲、龙某军共同赔偿公益赔偿金44万元，李某华、李某秋、马某曹共同赔偿公益赔偿金50万元，李某华等十一人在媒体公开赔礼道歉。宣判后，马某曹等部分被告人不服提起上诉，四川省高级人民法院审理后裁定驳回上诉，维持原判。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案案发地之一的四川省绵阳市平武县，是大熊猫国家公园的核心区，素有“天下大熊猫第一县”的美誉。大熊猫国家公园对于加强大熊猫及其伞护的其他物种和典型生态脆弱区整体保护，打造国家重要生态屏障具有重要意义。本案中，被告人在大熊猫国家公园内猎捕国家重点保护野生动物用于销售，已经形成了危害珍贵、濒危野生动物犯罪的“猎捕-收购-运输-销售”完整产业链，且以民营动物园为链条终端，通过动物园收购和再次交易将野生动物“洗白”，严重破坏大熊猫国家公园内自然生态系统的原真性、完整性和系统性。本案部分被告人身为动物园经营者，具有从事野生动物收购、饲养、出售、运输等便利，其明知收购、运输珍贵、濒危野生动物必须按照法定程序审批，却为追求经济利益而利用其职业便利实施非法收购、运输野生动物犯罪，已严重违背职业道德和从业义务，为预防其再实施此类犯罪，人民法院对其判处“禁止令”，禁止犯罪人再次从事野生动物经营，体现了打击和预防犯罪并重，以最严法治守护国家公园生态安全的决心。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;五、王某民等六人滥伐林木、危害国家重点保护植物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年2月，被告人王某民以其妻名义与案外人乔某某签订《林权林地转让合同书》，受让位于吉林省图们市凉水镇某村林地3785亩的林地使用权、林木所有权。同年4月，王某民使用案外人王某的身份证申请办理了林木采伐许可证，采伐地点为凉水林场的三个伐区，批准采伐总蓄积456 立方米，树种为柞树。同年4月至5月期间，王某民雇佣被告人张某奎组织多人进场作业，被告人沙某、刘某军、徐某仁等负责采伐，被告人杨某负责归楞、装车。王某民等人实际伐木区域除了上述经批准的三个伐区外，还包括未经批准的楞场东侧伐区等三个伐区，性质为集体林区或国有林区；砍伐树木包括柞树、杨树、紫椴等。经鉴定，王某民等人违反林木采伐许可的树种、数量和采伐方式，非法采伐柞树、杨树等林木立木蓄积1438立方米价值131万余元；采伐国家二级保护植物紫椴485株，立木蓄积257立方米，价值23万余元。吉林省珲春林区人民检察院以滥伐林木罪、危害国家重点保护植物罪就上述行为提起公诉；并对王某民等六被告提起附带民事公益诉讼，诉请：王某民承担修复生态环境综合费用156万余元，沙某、张某奎、杨某对此承担连带责任，刘某军、徐某仁对其中14万元承担连带责任，六被告共同承担鉴定费用5千元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;吉林省珲春林区基层法院经审理认为，王某民、沙某等六人违反林木采伐许可证规定数量、树种和采伐方式，任意采伐林木，数量巨大，其行为构成滥伐林木罪。王某民、沙某违反国家规定，故意采伐国家重点保护植物紫椴，情节严重，构成危害国家重点保护植物罪。对王某民、沙某应当以滥伐林木罪和危害国家重点保护植物罪实行数罪并罚。王某民等六人犯罪行为严重破坏生态环境、危及生物多样性保护，使社会公共利益受到严重损害，应承担民事侵权责任。遂判处：王某民等六人二年至七年不等的有期徒刑，并处1万元至120万元不等的罚金；王某民承担修复生态环境综合费用156万余元，沙某、张某奎、杨某对此承担连带责任，刘某军、徐某仁对其中14万元承担连带责任，鉴定费用5千元由六被告共同承担。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案系发生在东北虎豹国家公园范围内滥伐林木及危害国家重点保护植物的案件。东北虎豹国家公园内优质的森林资源和完整的生物链为东北虎、豹等珍稀野生动物提供了良好的生态家园。随着国家公园保护力度的加大，近年来，几十年不见的东北虎、豹重回故里繁衍生息。紫椴有“象牙板”和“世界四大行道树”的美称，具有较大的药用、欣赏和经济价值，属于国家濒危保护物种以及国家二级保护野生植物。本案中，人民法院依法对滥伐林木行为和故意采伐国家重点保护植物行为予以数罪并罚，加大对破坏森林资源犯罪的惩治和震慑力度；同时判令行为人赔偿生态环境修复费用，对保护东北虎豹栖息地生物多样性和生态系统安全具有积极作用。本案裁判后，人民法院践行能动司法理念，立足东北虎豹国家公园生态资源管护实际，向有关部门发出司法建议，推动形成国家公园保护的强大合力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;六、李某良、羊某理失火、羊某理非法狩猎刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被告人李某良与羊某理相约到山林内熏蜂采摘野生蜂蜜，并将该过程录制视频用于蜂蜜出售。2021年4月1日，李某良、羊某理到海南热带雨林国家公园管护站内汇合，并携带打火机、铁桶、摄像机等工具步行上山寻找蜂蜜。后李某良在点燃火把熏蜂过程中，不慎将蜂窝周围的茅草引燃。李某良一边扑火，一边喊羊某理帮忙救火。羊某理发现火势正在向其所在位置燃烧便逃离现场，李某良见状也逃离现场。经鉴定，本次森林火灾过火面积为90亩（均为有林地），系一级保护林地（重点公益林），火烧林木的树种为松树和天然阔叶树。羊某理、李某良被抓获归案后，羊某理如实供述了公安机关尚未掌握的本人非法狩猎罪的犯罪行为。海南省人民检察院第二分院以李某良、羊某理犯失火罪，以羊某理另犯非法狩猎罪提起公诉；并对二人提起附带民事公益诉讼，诉请：羊某理、李某良按照生态环境修复方案共同对被毁损的90亩林地进行异地修复，或者连带承担修复费用26.7万元（通过支付费用或劳务代偿等方式履行），连带赔偿被毁林地生态环境受到损害至修复完成期间服务功能丧失造成的损失698736元、本案鉴定及修复方案编制费用3万元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海南省第二中级人民法院经审理认为，李某良、羊某理违反森林保护及森林防火法规，熏蜂采蜜造成森林火灾，使公私财产遭受重大损失，构成失火罪。羊某理违反狩猎法规，在禁猎区内使用禁用工具、方法进行狩猎，破坏野生动物资源，情节严重，构成非法狩猎罪。李某良、羊某理失火行为大量烧毁林木，对当地林业资源及生态环境造成严重损害，应承担相应的民事责任。遂判处羊某理数罪并罚，决定执行有期徒刑一年六个月，李某良有期徒刑一年二个月；判令李某良、羊某理连带承担异地修复费用26.7万元（通过支付费用或劳务代偿等方式履行）、生态服务功能损失鉴定及修复方案编制费用3万元，连带赔偿被毁林地生态环境受到损害至修复完成期间服务功能丧失造成的损失698736元。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案系发生在海南热带雨林国家公园范围内的一起刑事附带民事公益诉讼案件。海南热带雨林国家公园面积占全国国土面积的比例不足0.046%，但拥有全国约20%的两栖类、33%的爬行类、38.6%的鸟类和20%的兽类野生动物资源，其中属于国家重点保护野生动物的有145种，属于海南省特有野生动物的有23种，有着极其重要的生物多样性价值。保护好海南热带雨林国家公园的良好生态环境，是人民法院环境资源审判工作的重要使命。本案中，人民法院依法严肃打击对热带雨林生态平衡有严重影响的失火、非法狩猎犯罪行为的同时，判令侵权人依法承担生态赔偿责任，践行了生态环境保护领域的最严法治原则。此外，考虑到被告经济困难，准许其通过劳务代偿的方式履行异地生态修复义务，既体现了司法对民生保障的关切，也有助于判决内容的实际履行，帮助被告改变其固有的“靠山吃山、靠海吃海”思想，有利于带动周边亲友转变生产生活方式，实现人与自然的和谐共生。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;七、海南省人民检察院第一分院诉李某清、叶某青生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2020年1月起，被告李某清、叶某青未经行政许可，陆续雇人砍伐位于海南热带雨林国家公园范围内的海南省黎母山林场鹦哥傲分站内一条土路两旁的马占树，砍伐过程中还毁坏了两株桫椤树。后两人把砍伐的马占树拉走出售得款18450元。经鉴定，被伐林木地块为二级保护林地，森林类别为省级公益林，林种为防护林；被伐林木立木蓄积量171立方米；被毁坏的两株桫椤树为国家二级保护植物大桫椤；被伐林木造成生态服务功能损失总价值74902.95元/年，案涉造林修复投资经概算为49501.8元。上述鉴定评估费用3万元。李某清因犯盗伐林木罪被另案判处有期徒刑四年六个月。海南省人民检察院第一分院就李某清、叶某青的盗伐林木行为提起生态破坏民事公益诉讼，诉请：李某清、叶某青连带承担因盗伐林木造成的生态服务功能损失费用149805.9元、生态环境损害修复费用49501.8元、鉴定评估费用3万元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海南省第一中级人民法院经审理认为，李某清、叶某青的侵权行为对林场生态环境造成了损害，应对造成的生态环境损害承担相应民事责任。遂判决：李某清、叶某青连带赔偿因盗伐林木造成的生态服务功能损失费用149805.9元、生态环境损害修复费用49501.8元，连带承担本案生态环境损害鉴定评估费用3万元。宣判后，各方均未上诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;涉案黎母山林区位于海南岛中部，为海南热带雨林国家公园的重要组成部分。本案被告在国家公园范围内的重点保护区砍伐毁坏林木的数量大，致使天然林生态系统的完整性、生物多样性、水土保持等生态功能和价值减损，破坏热带雨林的生态环境，损害社会公共利益。人民法院判令侵权人对生态资源损失进行赔偿，加大行为人的违法成本，有力震慑潜在违法行为的发生，有利于营造全民保护热带雨林资源、维护美好生态环境的社会氛围，也向社会公众传递了人民法院打击破坏生态环境行为、高质量护航国家公园建设的态度。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;八、浙江省开化县人民检察院诉陆某燕等四人生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被告陆某燕、徐某系夫妻，二人在浙江省开化县某农贸市场经营一家野味店。2018年11月，开化县森林公安局接到公益志愿者举报后，在二人仓库内当场查获并扣押疑似白鹇3只、野猪11只、野兔42只、黄麂23只。经查，2017年12月底，被告王某经由被告程某俊通过微信联系徐某购买猫头鹰1只，并通过录制宰杀视频验货、邮寄交付等方式完成交货，后由王某送给朋友食用。经鉴定，案涉3只疑似白鹇为白鹇，属国家二级保护动物；猫头鹰为雕鸮，属国家二级保护动物。经评估，陆某燕非法收购、销售珍贵、濒危野生动物和非法收购其他野生动物的行为对生态环境资源造成损害价值107860元，其中徐某共同参与的非法收购、销售珍贵、濒危野生动物和非法收购其他野生动物的行为造成损害价值97860元；程某俊、王某的非法收购珍贵、濒危野生动物行为对生态环境资源造成损害价值为1.5万元。陆某燕、徐某、王某、程某俊四人被另案追究刑事责任。浙江省开化县人民检察院以徐某等四人为被告提起民事公益诉讼，诉请：陆某燕支付生态环境和资源损害赔偿款107860元，徐某对其中97860元承担连带赔偿责任，程某俊、王某各自分别对其中的1.5万元承担连带赔偿责任；四被告在媒体上赔礼道歉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;浙江省衢州市中级人民法院经审理认为，陆某燕、徐某共同经营野味店的过程中非法收购、出售国家重点保护野生动物和没有合法来源证明的非国家重点保护野生动物，王某、程某俊为食用目的非法收购国家重点保护野生动物，四被告行为对生态环境和资源造成损害，应当承担侵权责任。其中，陆某燕就案涉全部事实承担责任，应支付生态环境和资源损害赔偿款107860元；徐某对其中97860元与陆某燕承担连带赔偿责任；王某、程某俊对其中1.5万元与陆某燕、徐某承担连带赔偿责任。遂判决支持了公益诉讼起诉人的全部诉讼请求。该判决已经发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案发生在钱江源-百山祖国家公园钱江源园区，系由非法收购、出售国家重点保护野生动物引发的生态破坏民事公益诉讼案件。钱江源-百山祖国家公园于2016年被纳入国家公园体制试点，是《国家公园空间布局方案》遴选出的49个候选国家公园之一。钱江源-百山祖国家公园钱江源园区完整地保存着全球稀有的、大面积的中亚热带低海拔原生常绿阔叶林，被誉为“长江三角洲的最后一块生态处女地”，也是诸多珍贵、濒危野生动物的最后“基因保护地”。本案中被侵害野生动物中白鹇和雕鸮均为珍稀鸟类，属国家二级保护动物。白鹇作为明清时期五品官服的图案，是清廉、正直的象征，具有极佳的观赏性和文化蕴意。四被告非法收购、出售野生动物，通过录制宰杀视频验货、网络支付、邮寄交货等方式，企图逃避监管和追责，是为牟取一己私利对大自然的过度攫取。人民法院依法判令四被告支付生态环境和资源损害赔偿款并赔礼道歉，在刑事追责之外挽回生态损失，彰显了以最严格制度最严密法治保护国家公园生态环境的决心，警示国家公园区域内人员依法依规开展经营活动，促进现代文明与原始生态和谐交融，共建共享人与自然和谐共生的国家公园。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;九、张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2017年3月18日，巡山人员发现，陕西省汉中市洋县茅坪镇朝阳村十二组村民郑某海死于朝阳村十二组小河沟路边。经洋县公安局勘查检验、洋县林业局调查确认，郑某海系被国家一级保护动物羚牛致伤身亡。后洋县林业局、财政局联合向汉中市林业局、财政局上报，请求按照《陕西省重点保护陆生野生动物造成人身财产损害补偿办法》（以下简称《补偿办法》）及其实施细则规定，对郑某海的死亡予以补偿资金187820元（全省2016年度农民人均纯收入9396元×20倍），其中省级财政分担150336元，市、县级财政各分担18792元。2018年12月12日，汉中市财政局对郑某海被羚牛致伤身亡的省级财政负担资金150336元划拨到位。因郑某海亲属对补偿金的分配未达成一致意见，补偿金未予兑付。郑某海的父母已亡故，郑某海生前与前妻育有两个女儿即张某彦、张某怡。张某彦、张某怡遂以生命权纠纷为由提起诉讼，诉请洋县林业局赔偿损失216933元。审理中，双方对补偿金额187820元均无异议，洋县林业局亦认可二原告系死者郑某海的第一顺序法定继承人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;陕西省汉中市洋县人民法院经审理认为，《补偿办法》第二、八、九条规定，经县级以上人民政府林业行政主管部门确认，在本省行政区域内，国家和省重点保护陆生野生动物造成人身伤害或财产损失符合规定情形的，受害人有依照本办法取得政府补偿的权利；造成死亡的，给予一次性损害补偿（含丧葬补助费），标准为全省上年度农民人均纯收入的20倍；人身财产损害补偿费由省级财政负担80%，设区市、县级财政各负担10%。据此，二原告作为郑某海之女，有权利依法向政府申请补偿。洋县林业局作为洋县人民政府的林业行政主管单位，应按照《补偿办法》规定履行法定义务。遂判决：洋县林业局向张某彦、张某怡支付省级财政已划拨到位的150336元补偿金；市、县级财政各分担的18792元补偿金，由洋县林业局向财政主管部门申报后支付；驳回原告其他诉讼请求。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案系一起发生在大熊猫国家公园区域内的国家保护野生动物致人死亡引发的纠纷案件。羚牛是国家一级保护动物，与大熊猫、朱鹮、金丝猴一并被称为“秦岭四宝”，均是生活在大熊猫国家公园的珍稀物种。随着我国生态文明建设的深入推进，野生动物栖息地和生存空间不断扩大，野生动物伤人事件时有发生。《中华人民共和国野生动物保护法》第十九条规定，因保护本法规定保护的野生动物，造成人员伤亡、农作物或者其他财产损失的，由当地人民政府给予补偿，具体办法由省级人民政府制定。本案中，人民法院参照该省补偿规定，判决被告支付相应的补偿金，较好地兼顾野生动物保护与维护人民生命财产安全的双重目标，对于构建人与自然和谐共生的良好生态环境具有积极意义。同时，人民法院及时向林业主管部门发出司法建议，督促其通过在野生动物保护区设立警示标志、在动物活跃期增强巡逻等方式，切实提高周边群众防范意识，确保周边群众的人身财产安全，也是能动司法理念在环境资源审判工作中的具体体现。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;十、青海某水电开发公司破产重整案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;青海某水电开发公司承建的黄河玛尔挡水电站是首批列入国家基础设施领域鼓励社会投资的项目，是实现西电东送的重要节点工程。该项目于2010年10月开始前期工程的建设施工，先后完成导流洞、上下游围堰等施工内容，后期由于青海某水电开发公司资金链断裂，建设资金不能按期足额到位，导致玛尔挡水电站停工，国家重点项目难以落地，移民安置陷入停滞，防汛隐患日趋严峻，庭外重组引入投资人失败后向人民法院申请破产重整。2020年6月，青海省西宁市中级人民法院依法受理青海某水电开发公司破产重整案。同年11月，某能源投资集团公司作为青海某水电开发公司破产重整战略投资人，与破产管理人签署破产重整协议。2021年4月，西宁市中级人民法院组织召开第二次债权人会议，通过了重整计划草案等文件。根据重整计划，重整投资方将继续静态投资上千亿元，打造玛尔挡“水光风一体化”综合能源基地，带动抽水蓄能、光伏、风力发电及化学储能等新能源的开发利用。青海某水电开发公司管理人申请法院批准重整计划。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;西宁市中级人民法院经审查认为，青海某水电开发公司不能清偿到期债务，且有明显丧失清偿能力的可能，对青海某水电开发公司实施破产重整，将更有利于保护债权人、债务人及企业职工的整体利益，也有利于解决项目停工造成的黄河上游干流度汛安全以及生态环境修复治理难题。本案重整计划的制作、表决程序及内容均符合法律规定，且具有可行性。遂裁定：批准青海某水电开发公司重整计划，终止重整程序。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案水电站位于青海省海南州同德县和果洛州玛沁县交界处的黄河干流，地处三江源国家公园范围内，是国家“十二五”规划建设的重点水电项目。案涉项目停工不但对经济发展和移民安置等造成负面影响，也对黄河上游干流安全度汛以及生态修复、环境治理造成极大影响。人民法院受理并开展破产重整后，充分发挥审判职能作用，妥善处理保护和发展的关系，加强与政府相关部门的协调，促成案涉水电站全面复工，有效化解了企业破产纠纷，也使三江源国家公园内黄河上游防汛工作得到加强，因项目停工可能带来的生态环境治理困境也迎刃而解。同时，玛尔挡“水光风一体化”综合能源基地的建设，也将带动三江源国家公园周边区域能源结构优化，有利于推动当地经济社会绿色高质量发展再上新台阶。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>