<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[湖南衡阳政务数据经营权出让被叫停：公共数据不应“资本化”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261010]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;nation&#39;s first&quot; public data franchise transfer transaction was halted. Well parked! Public data should be used with caution and should not be used as a &quot;franchise&quot; and become a tool for a few people to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Securities Daily&quot; report, on November 10, Hunan Hengyang City Public Resources Trading Center issued the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Resources and Smart City Franchise Transfer Project Transaction Announcement&quot; to transfer the city&#39;s political data Resources and smart city franchise rights are listed at a base price of 1.802 billion yuan, with a price increase of 10 million yuan. But a few days later, the transaction was requested to be suspended by the Hengyang Administrative Approval Service Bureau, the transferor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data is considered by some to be another &quot;factor of production&quot; in addition to land, labor, capital, and technology. Many organizations that own data want to get a piece of it. This &quot;first in the country&quot; government data auction announcement attracted great attention, and some people in the industry spoke highly of it, believing that it was the first of its kind to capitalize on government data elements. Some even believed that government data might replace land and become the basis for local government An important asset and source of income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the prerequisite for the transaction is clear ownership. Who does the data belong to? A piece of data contains information that usually involves different parties. For example, a person purchases a piece of clothing from an online store. This message involves consumers and online stores. So, who owns the rights to this information? If it belongs to consumers, theoretically, online stores cannot sell this information. If the ownership of the information belongs to the online store operator, do consumers have the right to withdraw and request the operator to delete this information? Even if only a subset of consumers ask for information to be deleted, the integrity of the entire data set is greatly weakened. How valuable is such data? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The issue of data ownership is even more important when it comes to public data. The so-called public data refers to data generated by administrative agencies, public institutions, public institutions, state-owned enterprises and other public institutions in the process of performing their duties or providing public services. For example, case data from public hospitals, subway passenger flow data, census data from the Bureau of Statistics, marriage and divorce data from the Civil Affairs Bureau, etc. It is questionable whether these public authorities have the rights to this data. Under intellectual property law, official documents and other content produced by government agencies in performing their duties are not copyrightable. The reason is that using copyright to protect these official documents is not conducive to the disclosure of government information and is not conducive to social and public interests. In the field of public data, should this principle also be followed? Public agencies cannot own data obtained and formed in the course of performing their duties? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, data from public institutions usually contain sensitive information such as citizens’ names and ID numbers. In theory, public data should be desensitized before being made available to outsiders. However, hasty operations may result in incomplete desensitization and leave behind some personal information. Even if there is no problem with the desensitization process, if the granularity of the data provided is too fine, it is still possible to deduce already desensitized personal information through cross-analysis with other data. In a situation where data leakage is very serious and almost everyone has nowhere to hide in the face of big data, this possibility cannot but be considered. Once the data is desensitized, it may be used by telecommunications network fraud, causing heavy losses to the parties concerned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the &quot;20 Data Articles&quot; issued by the central government (&quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Building a Data Basic System to Better Play the Role of Data Elements&quot;) pointed out that the use of data must be in order to safeguard the national Data security, protection of personal information and business secrets are the premise. Especially for public data, it must be utilized on the premise of protecting personal privacy and ensuring public safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The information in public data is all information produced or obtained by relevant agencies in the process of performing administrative management or other public duties. According to relevant regulations on government information disclosure, information produced or obtained by administrative agencies in the course of performing their duties, except for information involving confidentiality or personal privacy, should be disclosed in a timely and accurate manner. According to the same principle, information generated by other public agencies in the course of providing public services should also be disclosed as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data is a collection of pieces of information. Every piece of information in the public data set should be made public, so naturally the entire data set should also be made public, and cannot be given or received privately, becoming an &quot;asset&quot; that the government can sell. From this perspective, even those public data that can be used should not be auctioned or &quot;franchised&quot; and become a tool for some people to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;20 Data Articles&quot; emphasize the need to protect the public interest in the supply and use of public data. To protect public interests, the best way is to make it public, not &quot;auction&quot;. Unlike land and other exclusive production factors, data is not exclusive. If a piece of land is given to A, B can no longer use it. Therefore, in order to maximize public interests, the land can be auctioned and awarded to the highest bidder, with the proceeds used by the government for public utilities. The data is different. If A is used, B can still be used. The reusable nature of data determines that only disclosure can achieve greater utilization, create greater value, and is more in line with the public interest. If the use of public data is handed over to a &quot;third party&quot; in the form of a &quot;franchise&quot;, it is actually giving this third party the power to monopolize public data with administrative power. This third party then charges other users, which increases the costs for other users and harms the interests of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, public data occupies a very large proportion and status in data. Currently, more than 80% of China’s data is in the hands of the government. As the pressure on government revenue and expenditure continues to increase, it is understandable that local governments are eager to find ways to generate income that can replace land finance. But if you want to monetize the public data you hold, you must be cautious. How to use public data must go through extensive discussions and reach social consensus. Until then, it’s better to rest on the “capitalization” of public data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[第三轮中央生态环境保护督察全面启动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261029]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 18:03:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the &quot;Central Ecological Environmental Protection Inspection Work Regulations&quot; and approved by the Party Central Committee and the State Council, the third round of central ecological Environmental protection inspection will be fully launched on November 21. The first batch of five central ecological and environmental protection inspection teams was formed to conduct inspections in five provinces: Fujian, Henan, Hainan, Gansu, and Qinghai for about one month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reporter learned from the Ministry of Ecology and Environment that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, the inspection team always adheres to the people-centered approach, adheres to serving the overall situation, adheres to the system concept, adheres to the problem-oriented and strict tone, and adheres to precise scientific and legal compliance. Focus on supervising the implementation of Xi Jinping’s Thoughts on Ecological Civilization by provincial party committees and governments and the major decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council on the construction of ecological civilization, the implementation and responsibilities of ecological and environmental protection responsibilities of relevant provincial departments, and the ecological and environmental protection of prefectural and municipal party committees and governments. Work progress and implementation status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the inspection, the inspection team will focus on the implementation of Xi Jinping Thought on Ecological Civilization and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions and instructions; the implementation of relevant major decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council; accelerating the green transformation of development methods and promoting high-tech development. Quality development, resolutely curb the blind launch of &quot;two high and one low&quot; projects and the elimination of backward production capacity; prominent ecological and environmental problems in the implementation of major regional strategies; major ecological damage, environmental pollution, ecological and environmental risks and their treatment; environmental infrastructure construction and operation status; the rectification of problems discovered by previous inspections; the prominent ecological and environmental problems reported by the people; the implementation of &quot;equal responsibilities of the party and government&quot; and &quot;double responsibilities for one post&quot; for ecological and environmental protection, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the period of stationing, each inspection team set up contact numbers and postal mailboxes respectively to accept letters, calls and reports on the ecological and environmental protection of the inspected objects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[占卜算卦蟑螂走没走，年轻人“玄”起来有多野？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260577]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏省委原副书记张敬华一审获刑14年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261020]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 17:04:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/bc56d0a46a822b120fc0756ccb399cc9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bc56d0a46a822b120fc0756ccb399cc9 . jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259032&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;720&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, 2023, the Wuhan Intermediate People’s Court of Hubei Province made public The former deputy secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee Zhang Jinghua was sentenced in the case of accepting bribes. The defendant Zhang Jinghua was sentenced to 14 years in prison and fined RMB 4 million for accepting bribes. Zhang Jinghua&#39;s proceeds and interest from the crime of accepting bribes were recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/6c7936a86101eeceb982aed9800e15f8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/6c7936a86101eeceb982aed9800e15f8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259031&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;720&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After trial, it was found that from 2008 to 2021, the defendant Zhang Jinghua used his position as director of the Environmental Protection Department of Jiangsu Province, deputy secretary and mayor of the Xuzhou Municipal Party Committee, and secretary of the Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee , Secretary-General of the Jiangsu Provincial Government, Deputy Governor of the Jiangsu Provincial Government, Member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, Secretary of the Nanjing Municipal Party Committee and Secretary of the Party Working Committee of Jiangbei New District of Nanjing City, Deputy Secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee and other positions, as well as the convenience in the formation of powers and status. Conditions, providing assistance to relevant units and individuals in engineering contracting, project development, job promotion, etc., illegally receiving property directly or through others, totaling more than 49.84 million yuan, of which more than 16.76 million yuan was not actually obtained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wuhan Intermediate People&#39;s Court held that the defendant Zhang Jinghua&#39;s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes. The amount of bribes accepted was extremely huge and should be punished in accordance with the law. In view of the fact that Zhang Jinghua truthfully confessed the criminal facts of bribery that the supervisory authorities have mastered after arriving at the case, and took the initiative to explain the criminal facts of bribery that the supervisory agencies have not yet mastered. Some of the bribery was attempted crimes. He pleaded guilty and repented. All the stolen money and property involved in the case have been recovered and brought to the case. He can be punished according to law. Light punishment. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日本作家铃木凉美：我不认为夜生活出身的人写书有什么稀奇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260978]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/J1df1hgCGaZhUHvm6xw2wqPEDmdfcHZDhjKBS9ZA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/J1df1hgCGaZhUHvm6xw2wqPED mdfcHZDhjKBS9ZA. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Suzuki Ryomi’s mother is Haijima Kari, a researcher of Japanese children’s literature. , she wrote a collection of essays &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot; before and after taking care of her sick mother, unfolding this complex mother-daughter relationship that is both alienated and full of love. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suzuki Ryomi is a &quot;hot girl who grew up in Tokyo&quot;, who is in love with Cinderella-style misfortune. Will consider themselves a victim. Her speeches and works reveal lightness, some humor, and inherent heaviness and pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the collection of essays &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot;, she devoted a lot of space to writing about her rebellion against her original family. Her family must be the envy of most people. Her mother is the translator Kari Haijima, and her father is Suzuki Akira, an honorary professor at Hosei University. Happiness is hard-won, and the pieces of life gradually accumulate tension between mother and daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are not free. Although we are not expecting a big reversal of fortune, we are still shackles. We can always feel the mother’s curse hidden between our spine and skin, and we can’t help but feel chills in our bones. .&quot; The book writes about the mother&#39;s overly ardent hopes for her daughter. She wanted to get rid of the regrets she had in her original family and married life, but she changed her mind and injected specific trivialities into her daughter&#39;s life, always in the name of love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If she follows the established path, Suzuki Ryomi can easily become the stereotype of a &quot;decent person&quot;. That was not the case. She knew a part of the world that many people knew and experienced, but few could express. After entering the night world by mistake, she discovered many familiar stories among the women around her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;As long as you walk into the night, you will temporarily forget everything else. The longer you sink into the dazzling and crazy world, and the longer you stay in a world that worships emptiness as nobility, the less you can touch it. That thing.&quot; Suzuki Ryomi sold underwear to middle-aged men in high school. After graduation, she &quot;couldn&#39;t wait to go to nightclubs and work many odd jobs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nightlife compared to the daytime is indeed paradoxical, &quot;there are as many girls as Cinderella-like as you want.&quot; Women pay for the cowherd, who is often more domineering; female escorts need to endure the domineering male guests. A large number of details more or less reflect the essence of gender issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The men and women there occasionally share the cruel joys and sorrows. As time goes by, the fragile &quot;equality&quot; will inevitably disappear, and the people in the night world have overdrawn their youth early. Many female practitioners in custom shops have decent family backgrounds and education, and college students often work part-time jobs at night; while the cowherds are often in a difficult situation, with average education levels and lack of ability to make a living. All these people will age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suzuki Ryomi went to graduate school and wrote a master&#39;s thesis on pornographic film actresses. She worked as a journalist and later resigned. In 2014, &quot;Weekly Bunshun&quot; reported on her past as an actress in pornographic films. She is now a well-known author and considered a sociologist, although she denies the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she started writing &quot;Flowers for Love and the Womb,&quot; her mother had her first cancer surgery. Some time later, my mother&#39;s cancer recurred, and she died half a year before finishing the book. Her mother repeatedly said: &quot;I&#39;m sorry, I still have many things to tell you, but I don&#39;t have time.&quot; Through writing and recalling, Suzuki Ryomi discovered the similarities between herself and her mother, and also understood more about her mother&#39;s various ways of doing things. . She once said: &quot;It is very lonely to lose such an enemy and a friend.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later than &quot;Flowers for Love and the Womb&quot;, Suzuki Ryomi&#39;s correspondence with the scholar Chizuru Ueno The collection &quot;Starting from the Limit&quot; was published. She was born in 1983, more than thirty years younger than Chizuru Ueno. The age gap between the two is about the same as that of mother and daughter. It is no surprise that there is a huge difference in the perspective of understanding the world. In the correspondence, she mentioned that a man who had had sexual relations several times said to his friend in a serious manner in front of her: &quot;Which man is willing to date a woman who has acted in AV.&quot; Those men who bought underwear had already The impression that it was impossible for me to understand this creature seemed to be happening again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suzuki Ryomi&#39;s mother always said: &quot;If you are caught for fraud or terrorist activities, I will do my best to stand with you. If you become an AV actress, forget it.&quot; &quot;Such words are like the swan song that Ms. Haijima Kari sang for part of her life. At the same time, she also said: &quot;I am very happy. I have raised a good daughter.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/kdZnRltNFpZnTR2Q8EwLTLu9FNTwg2EEangNog4Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1044&quot; height=&quot;1568&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/kdZnRltNFpZnTR2Q8EwLTLu9FNTwg2EEangNog4Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;UTF-8&#39;&#39; Japanese writer Suzuki Ryomi was born in an intellectual family in Tokyo in 1983. She once worked as a bartender and a pornographic film actress. After retiring, she was admitted to the University of Tokyo for a master&#39;s degree and became a journalist. He was shortlisted for the Akutagawa Prize, Japan&#39;s highest literary award, for two years. He is well-known to Chinese readers for his collection of dialogues with Chizuru Ueno, &quot;Starting at the Limit.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;At least my mother is not the kind of person who doesn&#39;t care about the world&quot;&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is an impressive description of mother in the book: &quot;They are performing another kind of mysterious and unspeakable magic, never stopping, spreading the powder called love to us.&quot; You then recorded some suffocating past events. So, can you go back to that statement? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The relationship with the mother has an immeasurable impact on the child&#39;s future life. This is not a simple dichotomy of love and dislike, likes and dislikes, respect and contempt, but a complex interaction between the mother&#39;s expectations, preferences, personality and habits and the child&#39;s personality and life. Although there are exceptions, it is generally believed that mothers love their children, and I can indeed feel that my mother loves me. However, I feel that the so-called &quot;love&quot; is not always warm and soft, there is also a lot of mud and roughness in it. Many young people will more or less rebel against their parents&#39; overbearing and overly strong love and achieve independence by having a world unknown to their mothers. But even so, the relationship and influence with the mother is more or less undeniable. I use the word &quot;magic&quot; to describe this feeling: I had been a part of my mother&#39;s life, and once I became independent, I would be separated from her, but never completely separated, as if by magic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After several years, your feelings for your mother have changed. What changes? Has the “magic” faded? Will you understand her better because of some memories? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Basically, I think as we grow older, we will slowly have our own world that our parents don’t know about. The &quot;magic&quot; with our mother fades because we will have faces that we can share with others but have never shown our parents, and things we have never told them. During my bad teenage years, I managed to develop a relationship with my parents: I was connected to them but didn&#39;t necessarily share everything with them. It is not so much that a certain memory has deepened my understanding of my mother, but that now that my mother has passed away and time has passed, when I am the same age as the mother who once raised me, I recall every bit of our childhood. I sometimes imagine that maybe that was the mood. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are in &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot; &quot;&quot; writes about the subtle emotions between mother and daughter. They both think that the other is in a better position, which seems to be a kind of competition between mother and daughter. Is this phenomenon common between mothers and daughters? Or is it unique to your family? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mother and daughter are the two closest and most similar people in the world. Dependent on mother&#39;s relationship. When they grow up, they are in an environment where they can conform to the same gender, and naturally a very complex and primitive competitive relationship will arise. I think many people have had this experience. During adolescence, they are unwilling to accept the female side of their mother, but sometimes mothers are also unwilling to accept the female side of their daughters. I think there is a subtle psychology in it. Both of them obviously love each other very much, but they don&#39;t want her to be like themselves. I think the meaning of parents in life is different for everyone, and for me, they are the ones who keep asking me questions. Even now that they have passed away, I feel like I am still being questioned by my mother. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In China, parents often want their children to have a partner. , or urging marriage due to family reproduction issues. Is this phenomenon common in Japan? If so, does it have anything to do with the gender of the child? Is the reason due to child care issues, or is it just a stubborn point of view? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In recent years, it is said that more and more parents value their children&#39;s wishes or feel lonely when their children finally get married. But I often heard in the past that if you are still single at the age of thirty, your parents will nag you to get married. This situation still exists in some areas of Japan and elsewhere. Marriage in Japan used to be a family affair. Marriage is a necessary means to maintain the survival of the family, so the pressure on the eldest son is particularly great. Women, for their part, want to marry themselves off, even though it has nothing to do with the survival of their own families. But Japan is a country with a lot of peer pressure. Everyone else gets married at about this age. Only my family doesn’t get married. People will talk about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, I have recently begun to think that in real life, there may be a more real desire, and that is the happiness of children. Of course, there are forms of single happiness. But I think parents still hope that their daughters can experience the happiness of starting a family, and do not want their daughters to live alone in this world one day after they die. At least my mother is not the kind of person who doesn&#39;t care about the world, so when she said she hoped I could have a companion one day, I felt she was doing it for my own good and hoped I could experience the happiness she experienced. Of course, some people may feel stressed or nosy about this. And in Japan, some sexual orientations are not recognized and can be married, so I can&#39;t say that this is completely well-intentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, I think it&#39;s best not to take your parents&#39; words too seriously, just listen to their opinions from time to time, but don&#39;t take them too seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Now that I am really 40 years old, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;but &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;not much has changed&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As expressed in the Chinese word &quot;forty without confusion&quot;, it seems that people of this age will understand There are many principles, such as how to treat others and how to fight for rights and interests. You mentioned in &quot;Flowers for Love and the Womb&quot; that when you were about thirty years old, you discovered that the few people who stayed in Tokyo were not only friends, but also survivors. When you were forty, did you have a similar realization? A certain idea that seems natural actually changes quietly with age. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was a teenager or 20 years old, I imagined that I would know clearly when I was 40 years old. No matter what you want to do or what you don’t want to do, your relationship with others will be stable. But now that I&#39;m actually forty, I feel like I haven&#39;t changed much. I still wanted a lot of things, still lacked confidence in myself, and still worried about what others thought of me. I didn’t grow much. At least work-wise, though, I have more experience than I had in my twenties, so I have more concrete ideas about what I want to do in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;So, when communicating with younger girls , do you feel the generational difference obviously? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes I feel there is no difference, and sometimes I feel it is completely different. Overall, young girls today are much more docile, kind, classy and mature than they were when we were young. But at the same time, they don’t have that much energy to do stupid things when they are young. Perhaps it is because Japan&#39;s economy has been in recession for a long time and people are full of uncertainty about the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said in &quot;Starting from the Limit&quot;, &quot;Standing at the limit, I look at things from where I am.&quot; Are there any recent changes or shifts in the “limits” of how you view the world? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I may be a pessimist, a realist at best, a cynic at worst, so I had a habit from the beginning of limiting my expectations, assuming that things were never going to change no matter what. Society won&#39;t change anyway, so let&#39;s enjoy freedom as much as possible in this society, etc. However, for example, the issue of sexual assault has recently begun to be widely reported in Japan, which was unimaginable twenty years ago. In this sense, I think I should be more idealistic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you because of communicating with Ms. Chiheko No? , and lead to some new thinking? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think I have changed drastically since we ended the correspondence. It&#39;s just that when I think about something, I ask myself, &quot;Is this really the case?&quot; &quot;Isn&#39;t there anyone else who has such an idea?&quot; I think the main thing is that now I have another channel to think about problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;When a woman has several categories of attributes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;it often scares men&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What literature and social science books have had a great influence on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ryomi Suzuki:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For example, Mieko Kanai&#39;s &quot;Yeye Shengge&quot; and Inoue Yasu&#39;s &quot;Japanese Grammar&quot;. When I was young, I didn&#39;t really realize that thinking about problems was an exciting thing. I thought it was more exciting to give up thinking, such as nightlife and consumption. But after encountering a good book, I realized that the opposite was actually true. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What does the night world currently occupy in your life? What proportion? Would you talk about your identity as a writer and sociologist with your friends in the night world? Do they understand this part of your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the current life, the participation rate in the night world is now almost 0%, up to 10%, but my brain I still spend 50% of my time thinking about the people living in the night world. I don’t consider myself a sociologist, but not many of my former Night World friends know that I’m a writer. Whether it is current acquaintances or new friends, everyone knows that I also write books. In fact, I don’t think it’s unusual for someone with a nightlife background to write a book. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will the temporary equality of the sexes in the night world be possible? Will it become more and more unstable as we age? For example, if an elderly cowherd no longer engages in this job, he may become a grumpy uncle. Will the equality brought about by sharing the joys and sorrows with the women around him easily disappear? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ryomi Suzuki:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;York World is basically divided into male and female characters, and I feel like gender equality is not well recognized there. Because many people sell their looks, youth has great commercial value, and this trend is more obvious among women. Rather, this &quot;world&quot; in the sense that young women here have more power than middle-aged men can create a different gender balance than the normal daylight world. Yet it is also a sad world, as young capital is dwindling every year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Read &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot; When reading, I feel through words that men and women in the night world are somewhat insecure. What kind of protection should they get? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Even those who once had no problem surviving in the night world will later encounter problems in life due to the loss of youth. difficulty. I think there should be social security for people who have problems after leaving the night world. Indeed, some people enter the night world at an early age and have no choice. The best social security is to give them the opportunity to receive a proper education, regardless of the circumstances of their birth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can you imagine an ideal relationship between the sexes? Way? What is your understanding of the “male gaze”? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I still don’t know what an ideal relationship should be like, where we use each other’s fantasies without hurting each other. Change slowly and flexibly? When you want to use one word to describe the male gaze, you can actually imagine a lot of things. For example, when dividing the roles that women play for men into different categories, I think it is masculine: mother, wife, coworker, mistress , prostitutes, students, etc. When a woman has several attributes at the same time, many people will be very angry. For example, when a colleague is a mistress or his wife is a prostitute, it often scares men. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Finally, could you introduce your current work progress? ? For example, your novel &quot;Backstroke&quot; tells the story of a forty-year-old woman looking back on her life. Is this a summary for you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Backstroke&quot;, I only reviewed what happened in a certain month when I was nineteen, so I can&#39;t say It is completely autobiographical, but it reflects strongly on my experiences. When I turned thirty-nine, I realized that twenty years had passed. When writing a novel, I often draw from past experiences or memories and weave them into a text. This is nothing special. But I have a soft spot for it because it is closer to my own experience than anything else I have ever written. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武大靖：期待新生活]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/FDFQyeVtbLaS66HB2YDLtYGRHf5iLyLDfFzH827s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;572&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/FDFQyeVtbLaS66HB2YDLtYGRHf5iLyLDfF zH827s. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258961&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 22, 2018, men&#39;s short track speed skating at the Pyeongchang Winter Olympics in South Korea In the 500-meter final, Wu Dajing won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The &quot;new journey&quot; of the speed skating veteran&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On a windy winter day in Beijing, Wu Dajing appeared in the studio to record an exclusive interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shooting plane required a change of thin clothes. In order to relax him and quickly complete the shooting, the photographer joked: &quot;It is summer at 30℃!&quot; Wu Dajing showed a big boy&#39;s smile and cooperated patiently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This day is November 12, 2023. What a coincidence is that on November 12, 2018, five years ago, Wu Dajing won the Men’s Short Track Speed ​​Skating World Cup Salt Lake City Station in the 2018-2019 season. In the 500-meter final, he won the championship with a time of 39.505 seconds, breaking his own world record set at the PyeongChang Winter Olympics in February 2018. As of now, Wu Dajing is still the holder of both the Olympic record and the world record in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past five years, Wu Dajing has experienced the glory brought by his fame-at his peak in 2018, he broke the world record three times in a year and set a new Olympic record; he has also experienced the trough-injury. Under heavy pressure, he finally stood on the highest podium at the Beijing Winter Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Beijing Winter Olympics, for 28-year-old Wu Dajing, it was the best time to retire after success. Age and injuries will only bring greater uncertainty to the future. Retiring at this time can be regarded as a perfect ending. But Wu Dajing chose to continue standing on the ice rink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Recently, I have been carrying out rehabilitation and restorative training step by step.&quot; Wu Dajing said. In 2023, he participated in some domestic competitions and will continue to participate in other competitions next year and beyond. What he is most worried about is the recurrence of old injuries, like an elusive bomb. He doesn’t know when it will explode next. “So now I try to extend my cycle as much as possible and make a sufficient long-term plan. It must be very scientific. Be careful and you may not make it to the end if you are not careful at all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ S9aj6ar7tSsUFdbTKqDeVvt1OQirCsFfBxBOri95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/S9aj6ar7tSsUFdbTKqDeVvt1OQirCsFfBxBOri9 5.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;258960&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Dajing feels relaxed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has been preparing for the Beijing Winter Olympics for 4 years. Before the game, he injured his right knee, and then the waist injury recurred. &quot;It was a particularly hard blow at that time, because you didn&#39;t know if you could play. All the athletes had gone to train, and I was the only one lying there. It was quite uncomfortable. One thing, I was very helpless. At that time, I felt like a child, knowing nothing and unable to do anything.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, he withstood the pressure, worked with the team, and won the short track speed He won a gold medal in the men&#39;s and women&#39;s 2000-meter mixed skating relay, which was also China&#39;s first gold medal at the Beijing Winter Olympics. After the game, he and Fan Kexin hugged each other tightly. As the oldest athletes in the men&#39;s and women&#39;s teams, they have both experienced three Olympic Games. &quot;At that moment, we really understood each other with just one look. It was like watching a movie in my mind, and all the details of the preparations for the war in the past few years emerged.&quot; Wu Dajing recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many people once said to him, &quot;Otherwise, you will retreat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There will also be tangled, and some time I think it will not work. The physical condition or age is not the best state, so I also measured to compare it by myself. In the end, I still feel that I can&#39;t bear it. I can&#39;t bear it. The skating has always been loved by me. It&#39;s not that you can let go. Now, in my concerns, it is easy to persist, and it is not easy to let go. &quot;Wu Dajing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Dajing has created a number of history of Chinese short track speed skating. It is called &quot;the king of sprints&quot; by the International Slide. He is the first person in the Olympic gold medal of the Chinese men&#39;s ice. In the Pingchang Winter Olympics, he won the championship with a score of 39 seconds 584, breaking the world records and Olympic records. He won the first and only gold medal for the Chinese team to get the first Winter Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the women&#39;s team to the world champion, he described &quot;every time he is breaking through himself and challenging himself.&quot; Today, in the face of this new journey, different from the past, he needs to challenge his mentality. Well, the results are not the only important thing for me. The moment the athletes were on the court, in fact, it was to prove that I got good results, but now I love it more, so I use a better mentality to come. Ready, maybe it will be better. I can still be athletes, I can continue to stand on the ice rink, I think this is enough. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; http: // images .infzm.com/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/21/6mjg4y6VSJ6FNQ8MCBIQAR6OKGMA3uk60fph.jpg &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;664&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;/// /IMAGES.INFZM.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/21/6mjg4run4y6vsj6fnq8mcbiqar6OKGMA3UK60FPH.JPG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 258963 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; COLOR: #999; Text-Align: Cen: CEN Ter; &quot;>; Wu Dajing relaxation &lt; /P>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Childhood &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Training field and new identity &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In August 2023, Wu Dajing became the Coach of the short track speed skating project of the Bing Sports Management Center of Jilin Provincial Sports Bureau. It is both an athlete and a coach, which is a brand new beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, before the identity of the coach, Wu Dajing began to play the role of the bond in the team. In September 2018, Wu Dajing was selected as the new captain of the Chinese short -track speed skating team. In addition to improving his skills, he also began to cultivate the ability to collaborate between teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This reminds him of his childhood, and young athletes are afraid of coaches. When Wu Dajing first entered the national team, because the coach&#39;s energy was limited, he would give more time to the main athletes. &quot;So when I entered the national team in the first year and the second year, the coach could tell me the last sentence one day, and I could help me a move. I feel very happy. Well; when I didn&#39;t talk to me, when I didn&#39;t point me, it was a day that was difficult and difficult. &quot;Wu Dajing recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;At this time, a person in the team requires a person who is both a teacher and a teammate to stand up. You can tell us what the most authentic physical condition or what problems you encounter. He changed, or helped him take less detours. We have been doing this in the past few years. &quot;Wu Dajing pointed out that the coach&#39;s attention may affect the mentality of the team members. He hopes that he can play such a role- - Help the coach to share attention and help the younger generations, and become a bond between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/dfb1y8MRU3CKDLFCFA4JVDKLBUHCHQ2G.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;widt =&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;664&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/dfb1y8mru3d3CKDLFCFA4JVDKLBUHCHQ2G.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; &lt;258965&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Wu Dajing relaxation &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From personal responsibility to collective glory, Wu Dajing fully felt the power and value brought by a team. &quot;Skating has left me a beautiful and fearful experience for my childhood. From this collective life I experienced when I was a kid, to growing up with my teammates, I can participate in the competition on behalf of the motherland and show on the stage of the world. Yourself. This experience is beautiful and worthy of memories. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In childhood, he usually needs to get up at more than 4 am. The winter in the northeast is particularly cold. There is no street light in the small city. The mother rode a bicycle and sent him to the ice rink. The road was all snow. The sky was not yet on, and they took a light on the ice rink. &quot;We are training there. Parents take big brooms on the ice rink to scan the ice, and the division of labor is clear -there are ice sweeping and ice. Then these parents. A simple shed was spontaneously setting fire inside, in order to warm up. &quot;Such training venues, there are no board walls outside, parents use snow to pile a protective wall to prevent children from falling out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the price of ice shoes is relatively expensive, it usually buys a bigger, and the feet are painful. They often bleed and crust, and repeatedly. &quot;But when I was young, I didn&#39;t feel bitter. (Even) I felt that it was particularly comfortable on the ice rink, and I could put on the ice knife. I didn&#39;t feel cold at that time, but now I think it is really cold. I am particularly cold now. It&#39;s more frozen. &quot;Wu Dajing laughed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Dajing once said that he had a pair of &quot;ugly feet&quot;. He accumulated a &quot;bun&quot; because of the unsuccessful ice shoes and accumulated training, and even some places to deform in some places. &quot;I said that I must wear shoes in the future, and I must buy good shoes. The most sorry for my life in my life is my feet. I have been witnessing my journey for more than ten years. I am still eating with me. I often joke and say that I will have better to my feet in the future. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In 2019, Wu Dajing built a public welfare ice rink in Jiamusi, Heilongjiang, Heilongjiang, to support my hometown. The short track career, the &quot;wild ice rink&quot; trained when he was a child, hopes to give children more training venues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Today, when this charity ice rink is in winter, there are particularly many people, children, and skating enthusiasts, and they spontaneously organize to maintain the ice rink. &quot;I don&#39;t think I don&#39;t have Bai Jian. Many people use it. Children, elderly people, and young people can skate here. I think it is a very meaningful thing to help more people.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Sutling in public welfare also makes Wu Dajing happy. After he won the first gold in the Beijing Winter Olympics, he got a golden pier and hugged it to sleep. However, on the day of closing, he decided to auction this Jintun and donated the good money to the &quot;Hope Project · Dajing Ice and Snow Public Welfare Program&quot; to create the conditions for ice and snow sports for the rural youth. He felt, &quot;We can see the effect to help others. This is its significance to maximize it.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms//cms/ Medias/Image/23/11/21/MWJ2D93PXUCO5QS2C5BFLHYQCGSU4RKODSURFTEA.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;head =&quot; 657 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzmm .com/cms/Medias/Image/23/// 11/21/MWJ2d93PXuCo5qs2C5bFLHyQCGSu4rKoDSURFtea.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258964&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年2月5日，在北京2022年冬In the Olympic short track speed skating project&#39;s hybrid group relay final, the Chinese team won the championship. Wu Dajing celebrated &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; You can afford you to engage in &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; This project is enough &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly : &lt;/Strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; As a short-track speed skating veteran, what new life stage do you think you have entered? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Now there is an extra coach status to help the team to improve together. This is a brand new beginning. It is enough to continue to glow in this project. Although now in a confused period, I feel that I still want to prove myself, my mentality will change from before, but I can also stand on the training ground and can exert all my strength. This is enough to be enough . &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Competitive sports not only test the results, but also test the mentality. I used to practice well. Now it ’s different. You need to think about the entire team. You need to consider young athletes that the responsibility on your shoulders is heavier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; You can&#39;t joke with his teammates as unscrupulous as it is, this team needs to move forward. I also slowly explored in this process, not only incorporating the feelings between our athlete teammates, and at the same time, it was better to make the coach&#39;s identity better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_Gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; If you use three keywords to describe yourself, you will you Which three do you choose? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; lucky, happy, looking forward to. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lucky is because I have a beautiful childhood that I have done other children without challenging, and also achieved ideal results. When being athletes, there is a strong motherland to support us behind it. It is lucky to have such a glorious moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Happiness is what I can still do now, and maybe a few years later, I can still go to this career, which is the current happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I look forward to the choice of transformation in the future. Whether being an athlete, a coach, or other things in the industry, it is a new test for me. I look forward to the arrival of a new life, especially yearning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; I just thought about many moments, there is no moment of instantaneous one Zhang photos impressed you particularly? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In fact, there are very few photos in our family, and almost five or six can be added in total. In the summer of 2022, the three people came to Beijing together and brought the medals. Then, then I wore a lot of clothes and took a group photo in the middle. For many years, I haven&#39;t accompanied their parents to spend the Spring Festival and have not accompanied them to live a good time for a while. Next, they will bear the responsibility of their families more. I washed this photo and placed at home. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How will you overcome anxiety, bold pursuit The life of &quot;full score&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I will be anxious when my results are not improved. I am an old athlete in this industry. Facing the transformation of new identity. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As the age is older, this anxiety will be obvious every day in my body. I think it is normal to have anxiety at different times. A good mentality is not to say that you ca n’t be anxious, but how to solve it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For myself, I find my own direction -I really want to do what I want to do, and whether to prepare in that direction. After doing this well, I feel that anxiety will be less. There will be more sense of responsibility towards the goal, and the rest is just to fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Is there a veteran you admire very much, he has insisted on the field on the field Idol? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Athletes are actually admired by each other, because only enough concentration can become the best in a certain field, such as Malone, such as Malone, Gong Lizhen, Su Bingtian, etc., and those who silently paid for the Chinese sports industry are all people I admire from the heart. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They are examples of the entire sports industry worth learning. They have chosen to continue to persist and impact their dreams. Although the results will decline and face doubts, as long as you feel that you are worthy of yourself, you can afford the project you are engaged in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高人民检察院依法对李再勇决定逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261016]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-21 14:34:16 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;pan>; Reporter learned from the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate on November 21 that the original party group and vice chairman Li Zaiyong&#39;s case of bribery and abuse of power was investigated by the State Supervision Commission for investigation and transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution. A few days ago, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate made a decision to arrest Li Zaiyong on suspicion of bribery and abuse of power in accordance with the law. The case is under further processing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[虎扑“高校评分”爆火：哪些才是一流大学的硬指标？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260986]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-21 14:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recently, the &quot;Tiger Flutter College Score&quot; has caused widespread attention and enthusiastic discussions, especially among the college student groups. Many &quot;witty comments&quot; have become new &quot;network stalks&quot;. For example, the comments of the Chinese People&#39;s Public Security University &quot;Gathering is a fire, and it is a police station.&quot; &quot;, Changsha University of Technology&quot; E -sports 985, Rap 211 &quot;, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The public opinion field is more reported by the &quot;college score&quot;. There is no reason for him. This &quot;college score&quot; is an evaluation from the perspective of a student. &quot;University Rankings&quot;. On the occasion of public opinion and carnival, there are also some problems worthy of analysis: What kind of &quot;college evaluation&quot; is credible? What kind of &quot;college evaluation&quot; do we need? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are always many outside universities Zang Yuedan, and the evaluation forms are also diverse: from the various universities of independent institutions, to the peers to the professional list, and then to the business community or formal or official or official or formal or formal Private evaluation is not enough. However, there are few evaluations that can satisfy everyone, and there is no set of &quot;ranking&quot; or &quot;list&quot; that can destroy the controversy. The reason is naturally the difference between the evaluation subject and the evaluation standard, and the right and wrong of the selection procedure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In order to cater to various &quot;university rankings&quot;, Chinese and foreign universities have also tried their best. For example, in order to improve the rating of domestic universities, international students are recruited regardless of the quality of students; many of European and American pheasant colleges have also carried out many marketing operations to attract international students. The result is that the criteria for evaluation of these rankings are not only one -sided, but some of them can&#39;t stand on their own, but the credibility of the damage institution itself. For colleges and universities, the swollen face is insufficient, and the appropriate performance is not enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Even the &quot;look fair&quot; statistics such as teachers and scientific research quality are not always fair and reasonable in reality. &quot;One -foot&quot; response strategy. For example, in the ranking of mathematical disciplines announced by USNews in 2021, Qufu Normal University surpassed the ranking of Peking University, which surprised the industry. However, its output process is &quot;reasonable and well -founded&quot;, and it is exactly the method of &quot;thesis irrigation&quot; and &quot;self -introduction in the school&quot;. However, it is self -evident how much such an evaluation standard is in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In recent years, Chinese and foreign universities have all have various dissatisfaction sounds, and the &quot;exit ranking&quot; action has risen. In 2022, the National People&#39;s Congress, NTU, and Lan University withdrew the rankings of the World University, announcing that they would no longer provide data and were not led by the &quot;foreign indicators&quot; with their noses. In November 2022, Yale University School of Law publicly announced the withdrawal from the &quot;US NEWS American University Ranking&quot;, on the grounds that it ranked &quot;serious defects&quot; and the institution itself was &quot;profit&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Back to the &quot;college score&quot;. On the surface, &quot;college scores&quot; are like &quot;Public Comment&quot;, &quot;Taobao Rating&quot; and &quot;Douban Rating&quot;. They belong to the &quot;quality assessment&quot; of consumers for merchants, but college students have a little more subjective random random rating of colleges and universities. In essence, this &quot;university score&quot; activity can be called &quot;pulling stepping on each other&quot;, &quot;anti -string black&quot;, &quot;high -level black&quot; and &quot;self -black&quot; extension, which can be regarded as an alternative &quot;college evaluation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Because of this, students in this mountain will be affected by the &quot;observer effect&quot; after all, after all, it is impossible to be completely objective and fair. In this &quot;Tiger Flutter University Rating&quot;, there are comments such as &quot;the alma mater is not good, and you have to give a full score&quot;. There are also many comments and scores that are realized &quot;just like music&quot;. For example, Tsinghua University&#39;s score is only 5 There are many points, and the hot review is also the entertainment discourse of &quot;feeling school -like&quot;, so &quot;voicing&quot; is obviously not too serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, the &quot;tiger flutter college score&quot; that triggered public opinion carnival is destined to be only a kind of &quot;college evaluation&quot;. : The evaluation subject is diversified, the evaluation standards are changing, and the evaluation procedures are different. Let any form of college evaluation can only have a reference value within a certain range, rather than the golden family jade law that everyone wants to follow. Digging the mind matching some specific &quot;ranking&quot; and &quot;list&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; So what is good college evaluation? In short, what can be considered a good school? The assessment of colleges and universities has long been evaluated for thousands of faces, and good schools do not rely on one or two good rankings to become good schools. Except for the indicators that are often used in the evaluation, the quality of student sources, alumni achievements, interbank certification, and employment market recognition are difficult to shake. The true indicator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The so -called &quot;teacher -solid apprenticeship, and apprentice also choose a teacher&quot;, as well as the relationship between universities and students. The school and the students are two -way choices. The school rankings are essentially the ranking of students. Most of the evaluations of the enterprise community also stem from the evaluation of graduates, which only derives the level difference between colleges and universities. After all, major colleges and universities are not selected by any of them on the shelves, nor is it a music/movie/game that everyone can buy experience. The student groups of colleges and universities are often selected by colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the writer Fang Long, a scholar said that he invented a great truth and had to teach his knowledge to others. As a result, a group of young people gathered around him, and the university was born. It was originally a consortium of professors and students. &quot;Learning Solidarity&quot; is the background of the university, and it is also the starting point of all evaluations. The &quot;college score&quot; this time has not lost to pay tribute to the ancient tradition. At least, compared to the ranking of the university, colleges and universities should first listen to the voices of students and alumni. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海实业集团总裁周军被查，曾三度任600亿医药龙头董事长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261012]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-21 14:14:03 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On the evening of November 20, the official WeChat public account of the Shanghai Discipline Inspection Commission &quot;Integrity Shanghai&quot; posted a message saying that Shanghai Industrial (Group) President Zhou Jun is suspected of serious disciplinary violations and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervision investigation by the Shanghai Discipline Inspection Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/e12e777726fd064b3561b927b9.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;opac it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1552 &quot;height =&quot; 610 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/E73A810EA77726B3561B927B9.PNG &quot;Data-key = &quot;258989&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; On the same day, Shanghai Pharmaceutical (601607.SH) also issued an announcement. On November 18, the company&#39;s board of directors received a written resignation report from Zhou Jun. Due to personal affairs, Zhou Jun could not invest enough time to perform the company&#39;s position. All positions such as the chairman of the company, the non -executive director, the convener of the strategic committee of the board of directors, and the members of the strategic committee of the company, and the resignation report came into effect from the date of delivery from the board of directors of the company. In addition, Shanghai Industrial Holdings (00363.HK) and Shanghai Industrial Environment (00807.HK) also announced that Zhou Jun applied to resign all his positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company stated in the announcement that Zhou Jun has confirmed that he has no disagreement with the board of directors. As well as internal control mechanisms, the above matters have no significant impact on the company&#39;s daily operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that Zhou Jun, a bachelor&#39;s degree in literature from Nanjing University, a master&#39;s degree in international financial majors in Fudan University, Ph.D. Zhou Jun has nearly 30 years of professional work experience in securities, acquisitions, financial investment, real estate, project planning and corporate management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In April 1996, Zhou Jun joined Shanghai Industrial Group. Independent non -executive director, vice president of Shanghai Industrial (Group) Co., Ltd., general manager of investment planning department, deputy general manager of Shanghai Real Estate Group (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. and Shanghai United Industry Co., Ltd., Deputy CEO of Shanghai Industrial Holding Co., Ltd., Directors of Shanghai Xinghe Digital Investment Co., Ltd. and other positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From October 20, 2016, Zhou Jun began to serve as chairman of Shanghai Pharmaceutical. According to the Shanghai Pharmaceutical Announcement, on June 29 this year, at the first meeting of the eighth board of directors of the company, Zhou Jun was re -elected as chairman of the company and should end his term in 2026. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from Nandu · Bay Finance noticed that Shanghai Pharmaceutical is a member of the Shanghai Industrial Group. In terms of performance, in the first three quarters of this year, Shanghai&#39;s pharmaceutical revenue was 197.508 billion yuan, an increase of 13.11%year -on -year; the net profit attributable to mothers was 3.797 billion yuan, a year -on -year decrease of 21.13%. Among them, in the third quarter, operating income was 64.916 billion yuan, an increase of 3.2%year -on -year; net profit attributable to mother was 1.187 billion yuan, an increase of 6.14%year -on -year. As of the close of November 20, Shanghai Pharmaceutical&#39;s stock price closed at 17.92 yuan/share, with a total market value of 66.36 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, Zhou Jun also served as representatives of the 16th People&#39;s Congress of Shanghai, President of the Shanghai Medical Industry Association, President of the Shanghai Environmental Protection Industry Association, and President of the Shanghai Youth Entrepreneurs Association, And the director of the Shanghai Institute of Immunotherapy Innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the beginning of this year, Shanghai&#39;s pharmaceutical industry has set off a storm of anti -corruption, and many high -level high -level companies have been investigated. On September 2nd, the Shanghai Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection issued news that four cadres of Shanghai Pharmaceuticals and subordinate companies received disciplinary review and supervision investigations, including Pan Deqing, former vice president of Shanghai Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd. Li Ping, general manager of Shanghai Shangke Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Chen Binhua, former general manager of Shanghai Shang Pharmaceutical Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Huang Zhenhui, former deputy general manager of Shanghai Shang Pharmaceutical Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Anti -corruption in the medical field that has been deepened recently. At the 2023 Jinan Biomedical and Big Health Industry Symposium held on August 10, Zhou Jun said that Shanghai Pharmaceutical will be fully cooperated and resolutely implemented. &quot;This industry wants to make huge profits. Its public welfare, importance, and special nature determines that&quot; serving the people and serving the country &#39;is always the most advanced values ​​in the industry. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[水庆霞下课：中国女足没落，不仅是教练不行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261006]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-21 12:45:06 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/21/7m9lighl8vbknrtwzhklier5CSBEOCSK0ODM9gk.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 741 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.CMS/medias/im/im Age/23/11/21/7m9lighl8qvbknrtwzhklier5CSBEOCSKODM9GK. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258986 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; August 1, 2023, the Chinese team coach Shui Qingxia in Ade, Australia, Australia After the 2023 FIFA Women&#39;s World Cup D in the 2023 FIFA Group D against England, he raised his hand to the fans. The Chinese team lost to the English team &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the afternoon of November 20, 2023, the official Chinese Football Association official It is announced that Shui Qingxia will no longer be the head coach of the Chinese women&#39;s football team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shui Qingxia, born in 1966, is a famous Chinese football and the main player of the most brilliant period of Chinese women&#39;s football team. After retiring in 2001, Shui Qingxia took up the coaching position. In the women&#39;s football match at the Olympic Games in July 2021, the Chinese women&#39;s football team suffered a 2-8 defeat to the Dutch team. Shui Qingxia was appointed at a critical moment and officially served as the head coach of the Chinese women&#39;s football team in November 2021. In two years, she has brought victory and hope, as well as defeat and even despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In early 2022, Shui Qingxia led the Chinese women&#39;s football team to defeat Japan and South Korea in a row, and won the Asian Cup championship after 16 years. But by 2023, the women&#39;s football team has failed to meet people&#39;s expectations in the three major events of the World Cup, Asian Games and Olympic preliminaries. In the World Cup, the Chinese women&#39;s football team failed to qualify in the group stage and was defeated by England 1-6. They lost to Japan in the Asian Games and missed the finals. The same group failed to qualify in the Olympic preliminaries and bid farewell to the 2024 Paris Olympics in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the Asian Cup won the championship in 2022, Shui Qingxia received overwhelming praise. It is generally believed that she is the best coach candidate because she comes from the women&#39;s football team, has a brilliant resume, is well versed in the laws of women&#39;s football and athlete psychology, and has been the coach of the local team for a long time. But after consecutive losses this year, what awaits Shui Qingxia is a flood of criticism. Some good people dug up netizen comments and media comments from different periods and found that the overlap rate between those who praised Shui Qingxia at the beginning and those who are now endlessly belittling her is quite high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is the manifestation of the impetuous side of Chinese football, and managers, practitioners and fans are all. After Shui Qingxia&#39;s dismissal, many people believe that some players who have not been reused before will get more opportunities. But if you know a little bit about football, you will know that the plight of the Chinese women&#39;s football team is by no means a problem that can be solved by changing the coach or a few players. Its backwardness is all-round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/muzslvksauzg35gdbf6w1fvev56zqk.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/muzslvksauzg35gdbf6w1fvev56VMYT2C6ZQK.JPG&quot; data-key = &quot;258982&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On September 22, 2023, after the competition in the Hangzhou Asian Games Football Project women&#39;s group group A, the Chinese team played the head coach Shui Qingxia (first from the right). The Chinese team defeated the Mongolian team 16-0 &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; The departure of Shui Qingxia, is The metaphor of the decline of the &quot;old women&#39;s football model&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In all fairness, although there are many problems in Shui Qingxia in the selection of people, employment and on -the -spot conductor, it can be described as due to the diligence of the head coach of the Chinese women&#39;s football team. Responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shui Qingxia of that year was a multi -faceted stadium. She initially practiced track and field, and did not receive professional football training until she was 17 years old. However, due to her hard training day and night, she was drafted into the national team more than a year later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shui Qingxia once recalled that the training conditions in the 1980s were very bad. The training ground was only muddy, and there were stones on it. This is not an isolated case. Most of the Sonorous Roses of that year stood out under such difficult conditions and competed in various world competitions under difficult conditions. However, the development of women&#39;s football in the world has long passed the era when &quot;only relying on fighting spirit can lead to victory.&quot; Shui Qingxia&#39;s dismissal is itself a metaphor for the complete decline of the &quot;old women&#39;s football model&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the World Cup in 2023 was defeated by the England team, the player Wang Shuang choked and asked: &quot;I dare to say that we have worked hard than those players in Europe, and we have to pay much. Gets? &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In the face of absolute strength and in the face of competitive laws, it is useless to rely on hard work. Moreover, compared with the hard-working Chinese women&#39;s football model, &quot;enjoying the joy of football&quot; is the basis of competitive rules. Just as the England player Laurun James said after that game: &quot;The game is like playing football on the street when I was a kid. We are fully enjoying the fun of football.&quot; In the era of women&#39;s football, Chinese women&#39;s football can earn their glory through hard training and hard work. However, as the professionalization of women&#39;s football is advancing rapidly, major football powers are injecting men&#39;s football and market-oriented models into women&#39;s football, and operating women&#39;s football leagues based on the mature operating experience of men&#39;s football professional leagues and professional clubs, causing the Chinese women&#39;s football team to completely lose its past advantages. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/uaioo4pjesvwedta8ha0cqzjim2edqxvwyfbt&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/uaioo4pjesvwedta8ha0cqzjim2edqxvwyfbt.jpg&quot; data- &quot;&lt;258983&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On July 11, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s football team members trained in Adelaide, Australia, preparing for the Women&#39;s Football World Cup &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/ Figure) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The concept also needs to be adjusted. Many people&#39;s judgment of women&#39;s football is still stuck in the Rose Rose era. This concept not only refers to performance, but also to the environment. For example, when talking about the plight of the women&#39;s football team, many people immediately said that the women&#39;s football team is too poor. It would be great if the unsatisfactory men&#39;s football team could allocate part of the money to the women&#39;s football team to solve their worries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This statement does not understand the embodiment of football. The rapid development of women&#39;s football in the world in recent years often benefits from highly professional and market-oriented football leagues. What the men&#39;s football team provides to the women&#39;s football team is not only the club&#39;s operating model and advanced management, but also a steady stream of financial support. &quot;Raising women&#39;s football teams with men&#39;s football teams&quot; has long been the norm in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Chinese men&#39;s football team is indeed not angry, and the golden Yuan football in previous years is also criticized. But anyone familiar with the history of women’s football knows that after the retirement of the Sonorous Rose generation, the Chinese women’s football team fell into a long-term trough. The “Little Indian Spring” in recent years also benefited to some extent from the abundant funds of the Jinyuan Football Era. Although the level of the Chinese men&#39;s football professional league is not high, it is still more professional than the women&#39;s football league and can provide a relatively complete structure and system, as well as financial support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is also supported by this. The income of Chinese women&#39;s football players is not low, and the training conditions have been greatly improved. The &quot;Global Women&#39;s Football League Research Report&quot; released by FIFA in 2021 shows that the average annual operating costs of Chinese Women&#39;s Super League clubs rank first in the world, close to US$2 million. At present, the income of players in the Chinese Women&#39;s Super League is not lower than that of their foreign counterparts, and overseas players even face the problem that the salary for playing abroad is not as good as at home. Therefore, it is no longer appropriate to use the word &quot;hardship&quot; to describe their living conditions. The real gap in women&#39;s football is not in economic conditions, but in the backward understanding of the laws of football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ytProwyelstpuo5e8VN1DB5ZEOD3QC10RPG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;663&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ytprowyelstpuo5e8vn1db5zeod3qwqc10rp8nso.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258984&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On February 6, 2022, the Chinese women&#39;s football team defeated the South Korean team in the 2022 Women&#39;s Asian Cup finals and won the Asian Cup in the ninth time. The top of &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; China &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Women&#39;s football &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Nirvana is difficult &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of the world competition in 2023, the backwardness of the Chinese women&#39;s football team is comprehensive. Shui Qingxia once concluded that European players generally run and sprint at a high intensity of more than 700 meters in a game, and some good players can reach more than 1,000 meters, while the average Chinese women&#39;s football team member only reaches 300 meters. When faced with the opponent&#39;s pressing, it is difficult for the Chinese women&#39;s football team members to even look up and watch the ball being passed, and their past technical advantages have long since disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The development of Chinese women&#39;s football team has always had many inherent problems, including limited grass -roots football popularization, inadequate youth training system, and low professional league levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The current female Super League is still very irregular, and the schedule often changes, and it is impossible to cultivate fans. Data shows that the average number of spectators per game in the first 16 rounds of the Women&#39;s Super League this season is basically around 1,500, and many spectators are family members and friends of players, or employees of sponsors, and there are very few real fans. In comparison, the women&#39;s Premier League averaged 5,099 attendances per game last season, and the &quot;North London Derby&quot; between Arsenal and Tottenham attracted 47,367 people. Last season’s Women’s Champions League quarter-final match between Barcelona and Real Madrid attracted 91,553 spectators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In order to achieve results, the national team often adopts the long -term long -term training mode, which in turn affects the league schedule and quality, which makes players more unable to get the influence of high -level competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/mkvrzijkzugfse5nnw7whrpzz1v0etf8jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;661&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/mkvrzijkzh9ugfse5nnnnnnnnwhrpzz1v0ETF8j8cn.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; &lt;258985&quot;>; &lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On November 1, 2023, in the second stage of the second stage of the Asian District (B) of the Paris Olympic Games Women&#39;s Football Eling for the Paris Olympic Games in Xiamen, the Chinese team coach Shui Qingxia (Left) Guide player Wang Linlin. The Chinese team tied the South Korean team with 1-1, and missed the way to advance to the Paris Olympic Games. It is not enough to provide enough &quot;employment positions&quot;, so there will only be fewer and fewer girls who are willing to take the professional football road. The situation of campus football is well known to everyone. Some time ago, there was a hot topic of &quot;giving ten minutes between classes to the children.&quot; If they can&#39;t even have ten minutes between classes, how many children can get the right to play football? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past women&#39;s football mode, the light league focuses on the world competition, which is a kind of thinking inertia. Its backwardness is not only because it has lost the soil of the league, but also because even if it is limited to the World Series, it is vulnerable because it despises the laws of modern football and sports science. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the Women&#39;s Football World Cup, Chen Wanting, coach of the technical research team, once sighed that it is difficult to see the required video materials in the Chinese Women&#39;s Super League. Because the video materials provided to her were only shots from the perspective of the television broadcast, not the entire scene. As we all know, fans watch the game from different perspectives than coaches watch the game. What the coach needs is full-field analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Coaches cannot keep up with the development trend of women&#39;s football, and it is difficult for players to improve their technical and tactical capabilities. The old training model can no longer adapt to the needs of modern football. It involves running circles and practicing without thinking. On the field, facing the opponent&#39;s rapid transition of offense and defense, you will be at a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For a long time, the Chinese women&#39;s football team has always faced the situation of hot and cold alternatives. Every time there is a World Series, people call for concern and development of women&#39;s football. After the competition, there is silence again. Many people use women&#39;s football as a tool to crowd out and ridicule men&#39;s football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Whether it is the killing and murder of Shui Qingxia, or using the Chinese women&#39;s football to extract the men&#39;s football, it is actually meaningless. What the Chinese women&#39;s football team urgently needs to do is to calm down and truly understand and learn the development laws of world football. There is no other way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部：缅北共向我方移交电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人3.1万名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260984]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-21 11:23:02 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/21/7DA4B29319035F4DF2CD598D3CAC1F3C.JPEG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 7008 &quot;Height =&quot; 4672 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com.com /CMS/Medias/Image/ 23/11/21/7DA4B29319035F4DF2CD598D3CAC1F3C.JPEG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 258936 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The severe situation of crimes involving telecommunications network fraud in northern Myanmar, the Ministry of Public Security and other places in Yunnan and other places have continued to promote border police police officers and other places. Effective law enforcement cooperation has been carried out for multiple rounds of crackdown. As of now, the relevant local law enforcement departments in northern Myanmar have transferred 31,000 suspects for telecommunications network fraud criminals, including behind the scenes, 63 organizational leaders and backbones, online online, online, online, online, online, online, online, online, online, online, online, online There were 1,531 fugitives and achieved significant results in the crackdown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since September this year, under the command and deployment of the Ministry of Public Security and the Yunnan Provincial Public Security Department, the public security organs of Xishuangbanna, Pu&#39;er, Lincang and other places have carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant law enforcement departments in Myanmar to carry out a series of series A large number of telecommunications network fraud criminal suspects were transferred to us to achieve remarkable results. Since November, in order to advance the crackdown in depth, our public security organs have further deepened police law enforcement cooperation between China and Myanmar and launched a fierce offensive against telecom network fraud crimes in northern Myanmar. The results have been remarkable and good news has been reported frequently. Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen, the important leaders of the Kokang telecom network fraud criminal group in northern Myanmar who were publicly wanted by our public security organs, were successfully arrested and brought to justice. The first criminal Ming Xuechang committed suicide in fear of crime. A large number of overseas fraud dens were successfully eradicated, which dealt a severe blow. The arrogance of overseas fraud groups. On November 18, the Dehong Public Security Bureau made an important breakthrough in border police law enforcement cooperation. The law enforcement department in the Muse region in northern Myanmar handed over 571 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us one after another, forming a strong deterrent to fraudsters. So far, with the strong cooperation of all parties in Myanmar, a total of 31,000 telecommunications network fraud suspects have been handed over to us and have been successively taken back by the public security organs of the places involved. The public security organs will thoroughly investigate all illegal and criminal facts and resolutely punish them severely in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ee443362355a261326cc529713496eg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ee443362355A2613713496E08.jpeg &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;258935&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; The relevant person in charge of the public security organs said that they will always maintain high pressure on the high pressure of the criminal group of telecommunications network fraud crimes in northern Myanmar, continuously deepen the China -Myanmar border police law enforcement cooperation, continue to organize special blow operations, fully clear the fraud dens, arrest according to law, arrest according to law Crusher personnel are resolutely safeguarded the safety and legitimate rights and interests of the people of the people, and effectively maintain the security and stability of the border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>