<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[关注 | 2023诺贝尔奖揭晓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258135]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 18:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>; Starting from October 2, the list of 2023 Nobel Prize winners will be announced one after another. This year’s prize will be increased to 11 million Swedish kronor, approximately A total of RMB 7.23 million. The scientific highlight of the year, when human stars shine, from mRNA vaccines to attosecond pulsed light to the discovery and development of quantum dots... Behind some esoteric terms, the next future of the world may be hidden.</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公务员招录：“35周岁以下”的门槛可否放开？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258050]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years, a hot topic regarding the civil service examination is: relaxing the age limit and replacing the current &quot;35-year-old&quot; The threshold for &quot;under the age of 40 or 45&quot; has been relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of discussion is a reflection of the mid-life crisis in the workplace. Many people have worked for more than ten years and are in the prime of life, facing workplace pressure and even unemployment crises. There are many job opportunities in the market for fresh graduates, and civil service positions are also fully open to them, with preferential admissions. Even in the civil service examination itself, fresh graduates have an advantage. A large number of young people are pouring into the public service system, and middle-aged people are under pressure from the workplace, which they think is unreasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Middle-aged people are just a little older, but when it comes to being energetic and hard-working, they are not inferior to young people in any of them. When it comes to work experience and communication and coordination, the abilities of middle-aged people in their thirties are far beyond that of fresh graduates who have just left school. It has to be said that this complaint is justified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The civil service system has always favored fresh graduates, roughly because college students are highly educated, learn new things quickly, and have strong plasticity. This is true in an era when college students are scarce. But nowadays, most middle-aged people are college students, and their education level and work ability are fully qualified. The reason in the past is no longer tenable. In fact, the most important reason is: to relieve employment pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every year during the college graduation season, college students rush into the market and the short-term employment pressure is very high. Recruit civil servants and &quot;leave&quot; jobs to them. In years of economic downturn, we even hesitate to expand recruitment to relieve employment pressure. This seems to be an impeccable arrangement that kills two birds with one stone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, recruiting college students for civil servants does not really solve the employment problem, because civil servants rely on taxes to support them. To create wealth and tax revenue, we have to rely on enterprise production and operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of actual needs, it seems more reasonable to select people with certain social experience as civil servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Civil service positions in China are generally divided into general management, professional and technical, and administrative law enforcement categories. Professional and technical positions have a small number of people and high requirements, and young people usually have no opportunity; administrative law enforcement positions perform punishment, supervision, inspection and other responsibilities, involve major matters, and have tense interpersonal interactions, making it often difficult for newcomers to the job to be competent. There is a tradition of “mentoring and apprenticeship” in frontline law enforcement work, and here’s why. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comprehensive management position, which has the largest number of people and handles the widest range of affairs, it is necessary to interact with people and involve the basic rights of citizens. Even a simple window clerk&#39;s ability, efficiency and sense of responsibility will have a significant impact. More comprehensive management positions will inherit the leadership&#39;s will and come down to merchants and individuals. While they work within the legal framework, they have a lot of room for personal judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A young man who has just stepped out of school and entered the public sector, lacking social experience and no work experience, can be said to be ignorant of the sufferings of the world to a certain extent. Its services and management are closely related to the interests of citizens. Especially in administrative law enforcement positions, the overturned palms of law enforcement officers often affect the joys and sorrows of other people&#39;s families. Is this appropriate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, middle-aged people who have long-term work experience and have dealt with complex relationships may be more suitable for civil servants. It’s not that they are more compassionate than young people, but they are better able to understand complex things, appreciate the hardships of the world, and make appropriate decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, we have seen from the media that individual civil servants are rigid in enforcing the law. To give a few examples, for example, in March this year, a snack bar in Fuzhou newly opened and placed several opening flower baskets at the door. It was deemed to be &quot;operating on the road&quot; and was fined a sum of money before it opened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July this year, a man who sells vegetables on a tricycle in Henan received a &quot;sky-high price ticket&quot; for selling substandard vegetables. He made a profit of 21.05 yuan from selling vegetables and was fined 110,000 yuan. Outsiders find it unbelievable, but law enforcers have plausible arguments and can find evidence for them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being fined for selling vegetables, there is a very controversial fine item in rural areas. If farmers kill their own pigs, it is not a big problem if they only eat the meat. If you sell a few kilograms of meat to your neighbors, you will face a fine of tens of thousands of yuan. This kind of thing was unimaginable in the past, but now it has become a common fine item in rural society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision-makers of these policies and penalties are all middle-aged cadres and above, and they seem to have nothing to do with young people - in fact, they were also young civil servants in the past. As soon as I graduated from university, I entered officialdom. Interpersonal interactions are simple, mainly about obeying or giving instructions; I have little financial experience, mainly spending money, and I never have to look for money when I am short of money. Professional civil servants are good at paperwork and conference affairs and have limited contact with people. There is a gap with real society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, I agree with the call of contemporary middle-aged people to open the age limit for civil service examinations. Not only should the upper limit be relaxed, it would be better to set a lower limit. For example, we can discuss banning fresh graduates from taking civil service exams - they need to enter society and gain experience before they can manage and serve the public. Except for a small number of simple technical and internal civil servants, most civil servant positions should set age requirements and examine work ability to ensure that they are competent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Given that work history and abilities are relatively subjective, age is particularly important. Recruitment companies in the market will set requirements for job seekers&#39; working years and experience. The more important the position, the higher the requirements. Once incompetence is found, the job will be quickly demoted or even fired. In comparison, the recruitment criteria for civil servants are much simpler - almost only based on test scores, and there is no risk of unemployment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a lot of room for reform in the current civil servant recruitment and assessment model. The goal of the reform is to make civil servants more down-to-earth and less bureaucratic. Increasing the age requirement, examining professional resumes, and increasing the proportion of the contract appointment system are all directions that can be tried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访《少年的你》导演曾国祥：“我不希望把责任推到谁的身上”丨影视大咖谈⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257485]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/19/ 11/08/BHybgYSlr2zOIrNdKdL0mDhAAo7VfIRzcBt5eWhU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/19/11/08/BHybgYSlr2zOIrNdKdL0mDh AAo7VfIRzcBt5eWhU. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;38825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Zeng Guoxiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some eyes are only for teenagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie &quot;Young You&quot;, Chen Nian and Xiao Bei, two low-income teenagers whose parents have neglected their duties, are like two helpless little animals who need to hug each other for warmth and lick each other&#39;s wounds. When one party accidentally did something wrong and faced jail time, the other party decided to stand up and &quot;take the blame&quot;, completing an agreement that could change their fate almost instantly. There is no verbal communication, the eyes are enough to show the firm trust, and he will not hesitate to be broken into pieces. Director Tsang Kwok-hsiang is well aware of the value of a young man&#39;s eyes, so he shot a large number of close-ups, hoping to show the fire in the young man&#39;s eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eyes were exchanged again, and the location shifted to the visiting room of the detention center. A glass wall separates them from two worlds. The young man&#39;s face overlaps on the glass. You are in me, and I am in you. There should have been a thousand words, but once again, there were no words, just looking at each other, tears streaming down their faces. Soon, their fate will be reversed again. This is also a scene that makes Zeng Guoxiang proud. He insisted on not having any dialogue and what he wanted to say was expressed clearly in his eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of November 6, 2019, the 13th day of release, this movie focusing on college entrance examinations, tutoring and campus bullying has grossed more than 1.2 billion yuan at the box office and has a Douban score of 8.4. Yi Yang Qianxi, who plays Xiaobei, gave an impressive performance, which made him far away from the label of &quot;traffic star&quot;. The discussion also went beyond the movie itself, with many viewers recalling the joys and sorrows of their own growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Young You&quot; tells an alternative story about the college entrance examination. In the college entrance examination re-reading class, Chen Nian, a good student played by Zhou Dongyu, witnessed his friends being bullied on campus and chose to shut up. Unfortunately, he himself became a victim of bullying. She is focused on completing more important things, that is, relying on the college entrance examination to change the fate of herself and her mother who ran away to avoid debts. Xiaobei is a &quot;little gangster&quot; who was abandoned by his parents since he was a child and grew up on the streets. They came together by an accident, and Xiaobei soon appeared silently like a shadow on Chen Nian&#39;s way to and from school, protecting her from bullying. How could life be normal? One &quot;derailment&quot; and the dominoes fell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Dongyu has always been quirky and casual, which is often the case in movies. In her first film &quot;July and Ansheng&quot;, which she collaborated with Zeng Guoxiang, she just acted according to her personality, and the director just captured the moments that felt useful. But in &quot;Young You&quot;, Zeng Guoxiang repeatedly told her: &quot;I don&#39;t want Zhou Dongyu.&quot; Many times, Zhou Dongyu almost collapsed. She especially couldn&#39;t understand that if Chen Nian was beaten, he could just beat him back. Why endure it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I kept explaining to her, because you are not only carrying your own destiny, but also your mother&#39;s future.&quot; Zeng Guoxiang recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Guoxiang also needs to know more things. At first, he could not appreciate the great significance of the college entrance examination to the individual. His father is the famous actor Eric Tsang. He completed his studies in Canada, and his background is very different from that of mainland candidates. He watched a lot of documentaries about the college entrance examination and read related books. During the two days of the college entrance examination, he and his team stayed outside a middle school in Chongqing to capture photos. They stayed there from six or seven in the morning until the students left the examination room, and then they stopped working. Those two days meant a lot to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film was shot in Chongqing, and there are many scenes worth pondering. There is a spiral bridge next to the school, which looks like the Colosseum in ancient Rome, reminiscent of the atmosphere of the college entrance examination; at the same time, it spirals upward, like a metaphor for youth growth, and a turning point in the story is also placed here. In real life, this is just a pedestrian bridge at Tongyuanju Subway Station on Chongqing Metro Line 3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s like a maze. These young children can’t seem to get out of this world. We chose Chongqing because the city has many ups and downs, highs and lows, and many winding alleys. It feels like it takes forever to walk. You can&#39;t leave this place. There are viaducts and buildings everywhere you go, which gives you a feeling of pressure. We hope to present this sense of oppression and the feeling of being trapped in a place in the movie.&quot; Zeng Guoxiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2019, Zeng Guoxiang accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;To make a good movie, you must consider things from each character&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Young You&quot; has aroused a very enthusiastic response. What do you think triggered the audience&#39;s enthusiasm? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;At least in Chinese-language movies, the pain of growing up and school bullying are rarely discussed in this way. I didn&#39;t expect the response to be so big. Of course, when I wanted to make this movie, I also hoped to have such an effect. Let everyone reflect and show a little care and love to the people around them, which can have a positive impact. I have always felt that adolescence is a period that particularly needs protection and protection. Teenagers feel that the world is not good enough. The idea that they can change the world is particularly valuable and requires the protection and protection of adults. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But in &quot;Young You&quot;, parents are collectively missing of. Chen Nian kept asking where the adults were when she was bullied. What are your thoughts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;I don’t want to put the responsibility on anyone. Everyone has the responsibility. This matter is extremely complicated and is not just a problem for parents. Of course, the biggest influence on a child is the parents, but we explained the state of her family in the movie. Everyone is a little powerless, and they don’t treat others like this on purpose. Sometimes the environment is like this, and people like this are formed, and things like this happen. The same goes for schools, teachers, and other students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before filming the movie, did you have any interviews with mainland campuses and senior high school students? Do some homework? Have you combined your own experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;We knew at the script stage that the college entrance examination would be a very important element. In fact, it is the timeline and backbone of the entire story. As the coming-of-age ceremony for this group of teenagers, the college entrance examination is a very, very important step. We did a lot of homework before filming. As a Hong Kong director who &quot;went north&quot;, I felt a lot of pressure to shoot such realistic subjects. I want to make sure that the things I shoot are down to earth. After watching it, everyone will feel that this is how they came here. This is the atmosphere during the college entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I read a lot of documentaries and books about the college entrance examination, talked to some teachers and students about their state during the college entrance examination, and talked to the staff or friends around me about how they passed the college entrance examination. The filming of this film started in Chongqing in mid-July 2018. During the two days of the college entrance examination in June, we went to the examination room to capture photos. We stayed there from 6 or 7 in the morning until the students left the examination room after taking the exam before calling it a day and returning. Those two days were particularly meaningful to me. We observed many details and restored them in the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the details? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;We took pictures of the entire college entrance examination, what clothes parents wore, what they brought students to the examination room, the students’ state and eyes before entering the examination room, What to talk about. We tried our best to faithfully restore what we saw in the movie. Apart from the school uniforms, it does take into account the art of the movie, so it will be made a little neater and more beautiful, but not excessive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I didn’t put too much of my own experience into the movie. After all, my growing up experience was so different from that of the students in the movie. I just tried to refer to a lot of information and materials and tried to restore what I found interesting. It&#39;s hard for me to say how I feel about it. I can only say that I sympathize with them very much and understand their pressure. Before making this movie, I had been paying attention to the news about the college entrance examination. There were many characters and stories in it, which were very interesting. Every student is burdened with heavy pressure, which is unfamiliar to me and particularly touches me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I also experienced the college entrance examination, in Canada at that time, we were quite relaxed. Although it is also a very important exam, I don’t take it that seriously. I think it is an exam that will change our future destiny. When I started working in the Mainland, I came across news reports about the college entrance examination one after another. I was particularly distressed by how much sweat some students put into preparing for the college entrance examination and how much pressure they had to bear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You majored in sociology at university. Did your professional background help? There are richer sociological issues implicit in &quot;Young You&quot;, such as class and upward mobility. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;Sociology taught me how to have empathy; after leaving school, sociology taught me how to approach the perspective of different classes, countries, and races. , see things from their perspective. During this filming on campus or before, I worked as a screenwriter and wrote the script. What is the background of each character, what will happen, how to make him have his current values, and his attitude towards things. This is a very big help. . As a director, to make a good movie, you must consider things from each character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;Use close-up to show the fire in their eyes&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;You and Zhou Dongyu collaborated in &quot;July and Ansheng&quot;. At that time, you asked her to &quot;spare her acting&quot; and capture her suitable moments. Did you take the same approach this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;No. After &quot;July and Ansheng&quot;, there will actually be pressure for us to work together again, because no one wants to repeat what we have done. When I photographed her before, I tried to capture her normal feeling, always going with her more naughty and casual feeling. But this time I suppressed all her past and told her very clearly that I don’t want the Zhou Dongyu of the past, and I hope that everyone can see a very different Zhou Dongyu. She understands very well and wants to find a breakthrough. During this collaboration, what I told her the most was &quot;I don&#39;t want Zhou Dongyu.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In &quot;Young You&quot;, the audience saw the big Zhou Dongyu Sometimes she is extremely tolerant. For example, she was always bullied by a group of girls in school. It is said that she was very dissatisfied during the filming. According to her character, it would be fine if she was bullied and beaten back. Why should she endure it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;She was very entangled when she first started filming. She couldn&#39;t believe it: Why do you have to endure it like this? I kept explaining to her that because you are not only burdened with your own destiny, but also your mother&#39;s future, if you resist and speak out, the result will be that you will not be able to study, review, and take the college entrance examination properly. The latter is more important to you than anything else. important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I choose to close my eyes. I feel dissatisfied when others are bullied and cannot bear to see them, but don’t speak out. Later, she became the target of bullying, but she still chose to endure it, because she felt that everything would be fine after this year, and she would be able to leave this place and get into a good university. Her fate was different from that of her mother. So she has been under so much pressure and struggling. I kept explaining to Zhou Dongyu, and after the scene with her mother was finished, she gradually understood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a scene in the movie that is very impressive. Two teenagers are visiting a prison. faces overlapped on the glass. You also used many close-ups of characters&#39; faces in the film. Is this an aesthetic consideration? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;The method of overlapping faces is not my innovation. It has been done in many movies, but I think it is very suitable here. I have been analyzing this with the actors, and later on in the interrogation scene, the two people have become one. In the close-up of each person, there is a reflection of another person, that is, I am in you, and you are in me. I like to use a lot of close-ups in my previous films, but this time there are a lot more. Not only the close-ups of the main actors, but also the close-ups of many students, I wanted to capture the eyes and expressions of these teenagers. The young you and the young me have to show the innocence and straightforwardness of their youth. I hope to use close-ups to show the fire in their eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to Zhou Dongyu, Yi Yang Qianxi’s performance in the movie is also good That’s interesting. What specific “training” did you do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;It’s not that I changed him. Maybe people were biased against him before, labeling him an “idol” and a top traffic person. &quot;Little fresh meat&quot;, I immediately felt that he couldn&#39;t act. Everyone has not seen him act fairly, but he is actually a very serious boy. From the first day we chatted, to the time he joined the cast, he was really attentive and determined to be a good actor and play the role of Xiaobei well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the scene where Xiaobei and Chen Nian were chatting about Xiaobei’s mother on the bed, I actually didn’t tell him that I wanted to cry at all. I just talked to him and explained his relationship with his mother. He brewed it by himself and acted it out. When the emotion arrived, tears naturally flowed down his face. This shows that Qian Xi himself is a very sensitive boy, and the mother-son relationship allows him to find the fulcrum to enter the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“I hope to give the actors a sense of security on the set”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yi Yang Qianxi and Zhou Dongyu had a rivalry scene. When the two first came into contact, he pushed Zhou Dongyu into the corner. This scene was very tense and the scale was right. How did you explain the scene to him at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;This is a very good point. He was a little nervous at first. He had never had the experience of pressing a girl against the wall, so he was very embarrassed and shy and didn&#39;t know how to act. I also took a lot of shots during that scene, and I kept guiding and demonstrating to him how to do it. He also needed some time to adjust slowly. Patting and patting, he slowly let go, and we were able to reach the degree we needed. He is a very good actor, but he doesn’t have that much experience. We need to talk to him more and give him more time to meet our requirements for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wei Lai, the perpetrator of campus bullying in the movie, happens to be a A very good-looking girl with a good family background. What are your considerations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;We met the actors and wrote the script at the same time. I have always been confused about what kind of person to choose to play the role. I don’t want her to become so superficial. In many movies, one look at the person&#39;s appearance and you know that they are definitely the head of the bully, which we want to avoid as much as possible. I met many actors and kept an open attitude to see what kind of people I could meet that would inspire me. Later we met Zhou Ye, and it was actually she who inspired us to think this way. The day she came, we had a strong feeling that she was very confident, and then she was so beautiful and cute. At that time, we felt that if we cast such a person, with such a high starting point, and bullying others, the cruelty would be even stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, the people who have the least empathy do not necessarily have poor families or bad backgrounds. Instead, those with good family backgrounds but distorted family views are the most terrifying. They think that others can do whatever they want. I&#39;m at my mercy. So we set it from the beginning that Wei Lai has a good family environment and is good at studying, but her family view is very distorted and she has no empathy. She doesn&#39;t feel that she is doing anything wrong to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;To sum up, do you have any unique experience in &quot;training&quot; actors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;I have no secret, I am still very honest with actors. I hope to give the actors a sense of security on set, which is very important. Actors often bare their hearts to the audience. If they don&#39;t trust the director and the team, they will often protect themselves and their performance will not be that good. What the director can do is to invest more, shoot this point well, and consider their feelings more. Small things like this allow the actors to slowly build trust in you as the director, and then they will trust your opinions and tips. I often let the actors play the version they think is most correct, and I make adjustments based on that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 17:55:10 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的家乡重庆丨月是故乡明⑤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257350]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 12/02/nszAcS51cXSdJFRcz6yYfmyY5xfdkskn6p7vDzSc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/nszAcS51cXSdJFRcz6yYfmyY5xfdkskn6p7v DzSc. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 1, 2012, in Ciqikou, Chongqing, citizens raised the Drinking tea and chatting on the rocks &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown, Chongqing, is located in the southwest of China&#39;s inland area and the upper reaches of the Yangtze River. It is a municipality directly under the Central Government of China, an important strategic fulcrum for the development of the western region, an important connection point between the “One Belt and One Road” and the Yangtze River Economic Belt, and an inland open highland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chongqing is a mountain city, because it is mainly a mountain road with many uphill and downhill slopes. There are beautiful night views of the mountain city, majestic cross-river bridges, unique urban traffic, and magical overpasses that even experienced drivers can get lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the special geographical environment and climate, Chongqing has many nicknames, such as &quot;Stove&quot; named for the extremely hot summer; &quot;Mountain City&quot; named for the city&#39;s buildings on the mountains; The clouds are light and the fog is heavy, so it is also known as the &quot;fog city&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a city with unique terrain, mountains, rivers and culture. As a &quot;Chongqing kid&quot; who grew up in Jiefangbei and climbed hills and mountains eating spicy hot pot, I have a deep affection for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/dESuJydDdo45qO7g4ofhWqGEq2QxuGez6UDIdkK4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/dESuJydDdo45qO7g4ofhWqGEq2QxuGez6UDIdkK4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174015&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 16, 2018, Chongqing Jiefangbei. As a city landmark, the Liberation Monument has witnessed the changes in Chongqing over the past 40 years of reform and opening up &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/P8dxXnb3vmLdSWqZKDXIYfWKsJOUq8saK4JKKEka.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/P8dxXnb3vmLdSWqZKDXIYfWKsJOUq8saK4JKKEka.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174016&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On June 9, 2018, citizens chatted leisurely in a teahouse on Huangjueping Main Street in Jiulongpo. This teahouse is the only teahouse in Chongqing that maintains the style of the 1980s &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/zdEN79mBMW2cYkXFAXQzbylpflysTYLvr0HYmb3m.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/zdEN79mBMW2cYkXFAXQzbylpflysTYLvr0HYmb3m.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017 On June 22, 2019, people danced the baba dance in the riverside square at night &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/qBVYUk6OxoBO1tmuRhZsENZmGeYicPw75zRT2Q7e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/qBVYUk6OxoBO1tmuRhZsENZmGeYicPw75zRT2Q7e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On July 15, 2018, people watched the night view of the city at Yikeshu Scenic Area in Nanshan &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/wrmOfmfwdIgoArJpoH6JJyGCS3fTcwCAioYNgHmY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/wrmOfmfwdIgoArJpoH6JJyGCS3fTcwCAioYNgHmY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On June 26, 2020, citizens jumped from the high platform into the Jialing River at Shimen Bridge. The high platform is a remnant of the former pier and is now a diving platform for diving enthusiasts &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/lNOJdGlHG95lcfUwhqqNdCOLXzHsjn9OJwhVBy1l.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/lNOJdGlHG95lcfUwhqqNdCOLXzHsjn9OJwhVBy1l.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On August 23, 2010, people watched the floods passing by the Chaotianmen River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/H5RlxtlMUYPa4P5L6flO94Udr3pU7k9IH7T4TgQl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;488&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/H5RlxtlMUYPa4P5L6flO94Udr3pU7k9IH7T4TgQl.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On July 7, 2013, in Shizhuhuangshui Town, an old couple from Yubei District sat huddled on a hanging chair, looking peaceful. The uncle said that they come to Huangshui to escape the heat every summer, and go to Hainan to spend the winter &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/SjKdI7WsFq5GCaZYX5nWhrw0UKvhURtgWAX2ZbNw.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/SjKdI7WsFq5GCaZYX5nWhrw0UKvhURtgWAX2ZbNw.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017 On May 16, 2019, citizens returning home walked on the pedestrian bridge on Zuoying Street in Yuzhong District. This overpass is about 40 meters above the ground, with a deck width of about 2 meters and a length of about 30 meters &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/kpnRG6oQWBDTGzt2Tjvxa9cOjTAHH2SPEvLNYRBt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/kpnRG6oQWBDTGzt2Tjvxa9cOjTAHH2SPEvLNYRBt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At 16:00 on August 30, 2012, the old landmarks of the Chaotianmen area, the Chongqing Port Passenger Terminal and the Three Gorges Hotel came to a close - successfully blasted. The future Chaotianmen will be an urban complex integrating residences, hotels, shopping malls, office buildings, service apartments, and restaurants and clubs &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/Bi38Ogp9m6PGFM2B054KuiWymePnrlrTAz7haMx6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;490 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/Bi38Ogp9m6PGFM2B054KuiWymePnrlrTAz7haMx6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On April 19, 2020, people were relaxing on the rocks by the Jialing River, and the city lights were reflected in the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/1ntLJ5pISRrv9dMm5i4Z6CYHPO6UHO80nWPjl4zT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 734&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/1ntLJ5pISRrv9dMm5i4Z6CYHPO6UHO80nWPjl4zT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 25, 2018, the Yangtze River Cableway is a large-scale cross-river passenger cableway designed and manufactured by China. It has a total length of 1,166 meters and connects Yuzhong District and Nan&#39;an District. 6 meters, running time is about 4 minutes &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/gmahmon9COvTteK99FKkXNswKi50YsoXV1RrmJsG.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/21/12/02/gmahmon9COvTteK99FKkXNswKi50YsoXV1RrmJsG.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174013&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;March 2, 2012, Beibei Tutuo Chedu Wharf, with more and more cross-river bridges put into use, fewer and fewer people cross the river by boat. This pier has only one ferry, and very few cars cross the river every day. This is the last car ferry in the main city of Chongqing&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/E3hHK9vwZEXClYALI2xNvjUYJQIAqv2xhXBOMXKD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/E3hHK9vwZEXClYALI2xNvjUYJQIAqv2xhXBOMXKD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174014&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;August 7, 2018. Air-raid shelters were used to avoid enemy air raids during the Anti-Japanese War. Since 2003, Chongqing began to try to open up civil air-raid projects as a cooling spot for residents in summer&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一个肉贩的十四宗罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258124]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/05/Zk3WQLdcl9B5xPVH4QAJXVuXousw1CA2eHTg9ud7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Zk3WQLdcl9B5xPVH4QAJXVuXousw1CA2eHT g9ud7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nanmen Vegetable Market in Yu&#39;an District, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Minyu/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bian Xiamian was arrested, and the notice offering a reward for reporting was posted all over the Internet. On the short video platform, fellow villagers who knew him mentioned that when Bian Xiu was killing pigs in the town more than 30 years ago, his family often went to him to buy meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After many years, the identity of the former butcher suddenly changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When questioned by the public security organs in October 2021, Bian Xiuxiu was already the vice president of the Anhui Pig Slaughter Association and a member of the CPPCC Yu&#39;an District, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province. Three of the five companies under his name were engaged in There is a designated slaughtering business for pigs and cattle, but in Yu&#39;an District, there are only four companies with relevant business qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In less than two years, the former entrepreneur became a prisoner. On June 28, 2023, the People&#39;s Court of Shucheng County, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province announced in the first instance that Bian Xiu was guilty of 14 crimes including organizing, leading, and participating in a mafia-type organization, robbery, provoking trouble, and forced transactions. 25 years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 31 defendants in this case, 14 were former public officials of the Commercial Circulation Association, the Pig Office, the Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, and even the Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan, who once served as the director of the Real Estate Management Service Center of Yu&#39;an District, Lu&#39;an City, was also identified as one of the principal criminals in the case. He was convicted of organizing, leading, and participating in a mafia-type organization, robbery, and picking quarrels and provoking trouble. , misappropriation of public funds and other 11 charges, and was sentenced to 23 years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verdict shows that when the pork business was just starting, Bian met Sun Changquan, then president of the Yuan District Commerce and Circulation Association of Lu&#39;an City, and relied on him to rise to prominence. However, more case materials show that during the 20 to 30 years of business activities, Bian Xiuxiu, who was a hawker, also met several leaders of Yu&#39;an District, and with their help, he monopolized the Yu&#39;an District pork market and continued to suppress it. Competitors and general merchants in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the secret investigation of the State Council Supervision Team discovered the problem, the underworld gang composed of Bian Xiuxiu, Sun Changquan and others was quickly punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bian Xiu and Sun Changquan refused to accept the first-instance judgment and appealed to the Lu&#39;an Intermediate People&#39;s Court. The second trial of the case has not yet begun. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From stall hawker to monopoly market&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1968, Bian Xiuxiang was born in Shouxian County, Huainan City, Anhui Province, a village bordering Lu&#39;an City. Bian Moxi dropped out of elementary school and learned to butcher pigs from his second uncle when he was 14, becoming a butcher. In 1991, Bian Xiu began to rent a stall at the Nanmen Farmers Market in Lu&#39;an City, and brought pigs killed in his hometown to the vegetable market for sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case record shows that between 1991 and 2003, Bian Xiuxiu successively met Yan Guang, the coordinator of the Fenlukou Township government who collected the pig slaughter tax, and the two directors of the Pig Office. The former later became the director of his company Deputy General Manager, the latter two provided new opportunities for his pig slaughtering business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Guang is also one of the defendants in this case. The Shucheng County People&#39;s Court sentenced Yan Guang to 20 years in prison for eight crimes including participating in a gangland organization, robbery, picking quarrels and provoking trouble, forced transactions, and extortion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2002, Bian modified the contract for the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan’s younger brother recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that after contracting the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse, Bian Xiangxi and Sun Changquan met after being introduced by a then leader of the Matoji Police Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shucheng County Procuratorate alleged that while contracting the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse to engage in the fixed-point slaughtering business of pork, Bian Xiu met Sun Changquan, then president of the Yuan District Commerce and Circulation Association of Lu&#39;an City, who took advantage of his power , arranged for the state-owned Yu&#39;an District Food Company (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Food Company&quot;) and the Yu&#39;an District Commercial Administrative Law Enforcement Brigade to suppress Bian Xiu&#39;s business competitors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just when Bian Xiu was developing his pig business through his network and everything was going smoothly, his biggest competitor since he started business appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 5, 2005, the Lu&#39;an Municipal People&#39;s Government signed an investment agreement with Hong Kong Xishang Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Xisshang Group&quot;). The Lu&#39;an Municipal Government promised to close other pig slaughterhouses in the city after the project is put into operation, and determined Xishang Group to be the only designated pig slaughtering plant in the city. At the same time, the office of the city&#39;s designated pig slaughtering management department will be located in Xishang Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2006, the Lu&#39;an Municipal Government Office issued Document No. 80, announcing the closure of three slaughterhouses in the city, including the Sanli Street slaughterhouse contracted by Bian Modi. In early 2007, the Sanli Street Slaughterhouse was officially closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Case materials show that Bian Xiuxiu and Xishang Group had constant conflicts, and both parties reported to each other. In December 2006, Bian Xiangxiu led dozens of people to forcibly prevent Xishang Company&#39;s pork products from entering the Nanmen Farmers Market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 18, 2007, the Lu&#39;an Municipal Economic Development and Environmental Protection Committee Office submitted an investigation report to the municipal government, recommending that the public security organs launch an investigation into Bian Xiu and his associates who are suspected of being evil forces. , and at the same time, the Discipline Inspection Commission launched an investigation into Sun Changquan, then deputy director of the Commerce Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the storm did not have a substantial impact on Bian and Sun. The transcript shows that after being reported by the Xishang Group, Bian Xiu went out to Hefei briefly and then returned to Lu&#39;an. Sun Changquan&#39;s position remained unchanged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 1, 2008, under the witness of the Lu&#39;an City Livestock and Poultry Slaughter Management Office, the Industrial and Commercial Bureau and other units, Xishang Company and Bian Modified reached an agreement that &quot;pork from urban areas will not be sent to the countryside, and pork from rural areas will not be sent to the countryside.&quot; &quot;Not entering the city&quot; agreement, the former occupies the urban market, the latter occupies the rural market, and the two parties do not interfere with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, Bian Xiuqiu successfully obtained the qualification to carry out designated pig slaughtering in urban areas through the acquisition of Lu&#39;an Tianan Food Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tianan Company). So far, Bian Xiu has a certain monopoly position in Lu&#39;an&#39;s pork market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan&#39;s official career has also been smooth, and he has served as deputy director of the Yu&#39;an District Commerce Bureau, director of the Yu&#39;an District Key Project Construction Management Bureau, director of the Yu&#39;an District Real Estate Bureau, and director of the Real Estate Management Service Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan did not deny his special relationship with Bian Xiu, admitting that the two had been in contact and understanding each other for many years, and confessed that Bian had bribed others for the pork business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Sun Changquan confessed that in the process of acquiring the qualification to carry out pig slaughtering in urban areas through the acquisition of Tianan Company, a leader in Yu&#39;an District who was in charge of the pilot work of building a &quot;safe meat&quot; system summoned the pig office , the District Discipline Inspection Commission, the District State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, the District Audit Bureau, the District Government Office and other units held several meetings and proposed that Tianan Company be handed over to Bian Xiu for exclusive management. In return, Bian Xiu paid for the leader&#39;s facade house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 27, 2023, the Anhui Discipline Inspection and Supervision website issued a notice stating that the leader had repeatedly violated regulations from 2013 to 2022 by accepting high-end liquor, gift cards, banquets and travel from management and service objects. Arrangement, he was dismissed from his post by the government and demoted to a fourth-level chief clerk. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The supervision team made an unannounced visit&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bian Momo, whose career is getting bigger and bigger, deliberately spends money to protect himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case record shows that at the end of 2015, on the recommendation of a leader of the Yu&#39;an District CPPCC, Bian Xiu, who had not graduated from elementary school, fabricated his undergraduate degree and was successfully elected as a member of the district CPPCC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2017, with the help of this leader, Bian modified and joined a certain democratic party. Afterwards, Bian Xiamian purchased a facade house worth more than 1.1 million yuan for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rewards are also huge. Three of the five companies under Bian&#39;s name are engaged in the fixed-point slaughtering business of pigs and cattle, while in Yu&#39;an District, there are only four companies with relevant business qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Bian Modi, who has obtained a monopoly position, is not satisfied with this. In addition to requiring the Pig Office to supervise the pork flowing into the rural market from Xishang Company, and to inspect the &quot;outside meat&quot; slaughtered outside Yu&#39;an District and sold into the rural market, Bian also forced the butchers who came to slaughter to use pig offal. Deduct slaughtering fees to monopolize and crack down on the meat slaughtering market in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verdict records that in early 2013, because he was dissatisfied with a butcher who wanted to take back the internal organs of the slaughtered pigs, Yan Guang publicly insulted and beat him, and finally choked him and pushed him out of the slaughterhouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why don’t you charge a slaughtering fee but forcefully take the pigs away? An operator who purchased pig offal from Tianan Company in 2017 said that over the years, the price of a pair of pig offal has been as low as 90 yuan and as high as 150 yuan. When African swine fever is prevalent, the price is even higher. , and the slaughtering fee is generally tens of yuan, and the value is much lower than that of pig offal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the audit by Shucheng Antai Accounting Firm, from March 2013 to September 2021, Bian Modified’s two companies slaughtered more than 1.13 million pigs and used pig offal to deduct pig slaughtering fees. In this way, he obtained illegal income of 71.756167 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, more than 80 pork vendors jointly submitted a letter of complaint, reporting that Bian Xiu and others were involved in gangs and evil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 4, 2021, the eighth supervision team of the eighth major inspection of the State Council came to Yu&#39;an District to conduct an unannounced inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A situation report written by the Yu&#39;an District People&#39;s Government Office in the same month showed that the inspection mainly focused on three specific people&#39;s livelihood issues: the issue of demolition and resettlement costs in a community, the issue of water meter replacement charges in a community, and pig products in the district Difficulty in circulation and sales. Issues such as law enforcement officers&#39; crackdowns on interfering merchants and the monopolistic behavior of a Shunxin slaughterhouse owned by Bian Hao were also included in the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For three consecutive days starting from September 4, 2021, the then Secretary of the Yu&#39;an District Party Committee held 4 meetings on the issue of pig slaughter and sales. On September 5, the Yu&#39;an District Government established a special investigation team on pig circulation issues, with seven units taking the lead in conducting investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, 2021, the Yu&#39;an District Government announced that the previously implemented registration of livestock products from other places entering Yu&#39;an did not comply with relevant legal regulations and had decided to cancel it. On the same day, the original livestock and poultry slaughtering joint law enforcement team was cancelled, and the relevant responsible persons were also held accountable by the Discipline Inspection Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspection incident was officially settled one month later. On October 11, 2021, the Yu&#39;an District Committee issued a completion report document, which mentioned that since 2013, the Yu&#39;an District Government Office has issued pig slaughter management working documents seven times in succession, but the legality of the Yu&#39;an District Justice Bureau has been verified After review, the relevant documents were annulled, and the legal representative of Tianan Company, Bian Xixiang, was also criminally detained by the public security organs and put on file for investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Deeply intertwined&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 21, 2021, January 18, 2022, and July 22, 2022, Lu&#39;an City Public Security Bureau The bureau has collected clues from the public three times about Bian Modification&#39;s criminal gangs involving gangs and evil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan’s defender introduced that the case was initially filed for investigation by the Yu’an Branch, and was later upgraded to the jurisdiction of the Lu’an City Public Security Bureau for investigation, and the Shucheng County Public Security Bureau was designated for further investigation. September 27, 2022 , the case was transferred to the Shucheng County People&#39;s Procuratorate for review and prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that the underworld gang headed by Bian Xiu and Sun Changquan was in its initial formation stage from 2001 to 2007. From 2012 to 2021, the gang &quot;through the deep interweaving of public power and organizational power, form an inseparable and unified whole.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that the criminal gangs of Bian Xiu and Sun Changquan carried out two robberies in total and suppressed other meat product operators in the name of law enforcement since 2007, which constituted the crime of provoking trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, the State Council implemented the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Pig Slaughter&quot; and implemented a system of designated slaughter and centralized quarantine of pigs across the country. The following year, the Lu&#39;an City Pig Slaughter Management Office was established, with a pig market inspection team responsible for the management, coordination, supervision, and inspection of pig slaughter in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Documents issued by the Yu&#39;an District Commerce Bureau show that in order to implement the &quot;Pig Slaughter Management Regulations&quot; of the State Council, the Yu&#39;an District Commerce Bureau established a commercial law enforcement and inspection squadron in 2000, headed by the deputy director of the Commerce Bureau. He also serves as the squadron leader and is responsible for inspecting non-fixed slaughtering and sales of pigs in the region, as well as the transportation of live pigs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 9, 2013, the &quot;Summary of the Construction of the &quot;Safe Meat&quot; System in Yu&#39;an District&quot; mentioned that in accordance with the document &quot;Strengthening the Management of Cold Fresh Meat from Other Areas&quot;, Yu&#39;an District conducts full supervision of external pork. , set up inspection points to maintain the order of the meat food market in Yu&#39;an District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Statistics from Southern Weekend reporters found that among the criminal facts related to the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, a total of 103 were related to the criminal gang confiscating meat products from other business owners or preventing their transportation and sale, and another 7 The incident was caused by the Tianan Company forcing the butchers to pay for the slaughtering fee by using pig meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Changquan’s defender believes that among the more than 100 illegal and criminal acts of picking quarrels and provoking troubles charged by the public prosecution, except for a few cases where the victims were lawfully enforced for selling substandard meat, the rest were all due to the Pig Office’s It is caused by the inspection of meat. When the local pig office clearly stipulates that the pig office can implement market access to meat from other places, deviations caused by the implementation or understanding of the policy should not be considered as provocation and troublemaking behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, regarding the crime of robbery, a crime occurred at 6 a.m. on October 10, 2013. At that time, the deputy general manager of Tianan Company led a team to impose regulations on the &quot;Yurun Pork Monopoly&quot; on the grounds that Lu&#39;an City&#39;s urban pig product circulation management regulations require that urban pig products must be registered and filed with the Municipal Commerce Bureau and require &quot;secondary inspection.&quot; Pork from other places sold in &quot;shops&quot; will be inspected and seized. During this period, the boss Zhan Xian tried to stop him with a knife and called the police. Later, Bian Xiamian and Sun Bangsheng rushed to the scene. Several people had a physical conflict, and 600 kilograms of pork stored in the cold storage of the store was finally confiscated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Bangsheng is also one of the defendants in this case. The Shucheng County People&#39;s Court sentenced Sun Bangsheng to 12 years and 6 months in prison for the crimes of underworld organization, robbery, and picking quarrels and provoking trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to ask Zhan Xian for more information about that year, but he said it had been too long and he did not want to mention it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the criminal facts related to the sale of live pigs, the first-instance judgment also mentioned that at the same time as Bian Xixiang’s pork business started, starting in 2010, Bian Xiuxiang also entered the real estate field with Sun Changquan and developed many properties. A real estate project, but the first start-up capital came from embezzled public funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这一天，七位中国选手得到了他们迟到的奖牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258110]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the replacement Olympic medal ceremony for Chinese track and field athletes was held at the Hangzhou Olympics Held at the Sports Center Stadium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1caa387610.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1caa387610.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the supplementary Olympic medal ceremony for Chinese track and field athletes was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Stadium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, after the track and field competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese Olympic Committee held a replacement Olympic medal award ceremony at the competition site. The Chinese men&#39;s 4×100-meter relay team, composed of Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, Wu Zhiqiang and Tang Xingqiang, won the bronze medal in this event at the Tokyo Olympics as replacements; Qie Yangshi, Liu Hong, and Lu Xiuzhi won the women&#39;s 20-kilometer race walking gold, silver, and bronze medals at the London Olympics respectively. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Wu Zhiqiang, Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, and Tang Xingqiang (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1874077748.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/05/1874077748.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Wu Zhiqiang , Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, Tang Xingqiang (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the men&#39;s 4x100m relay final of the Tokyo Olympics in 2021, the Chinese team ranked fourth with a time of 37.79 seconds, and the Italian team, the British team and the Canadian team won the top three. According to the International Court of Arbitration for Sport&#39;s finding in February 2022, British athlete Gizindu Ujah was found to have violated anti-doping regulations during the Tokyo Olympics. Therefore, the British team&#39;s results in the men&#39;s 4X100m relay final were canceled and stripped of their silver medal. . On May 19, 2022, the International Olympic Committee announced that the Chinese team rose from fourth to third place and won the Tokyo Olympics men&#39;s 4X100 meter relay bronze medal. This is the first medal won by the Chinese men&#39;s 4x100m relay team at the Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Xie Zhenye said, &quot;This medal is a milestone for our Chinese track and field, allowing China&#39;s track and field to leave its mark on the world. ”” src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/5d36f1b4c8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/5d36f1b4c8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;Xie Zhenye said, &quot;This medal is a milestone for our Chinese track and field, allowing China&#39;s track and field to leave its own mark on the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 2023 On the evening of the 4th, Wu Zhiqiang, Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, and Tang Xingqiang waved to the media present.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/e1f0ba96b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/e1f0ba96b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253034&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Wu Zhiqiang, Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye, and Tang Xingqiang waved to the media present. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Liu Hong, Sister Qie Yangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b6ff6478ba.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/05/b6ff6478ba.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The evening of October 4, 2023 , Liu Hong, Sister Qie Yangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi (from left to right) came on stage to receive the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the national flag was raised and the national anthem was played. The dedication of Chinese athletes has finally paid off.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dbe33ccd2e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dbe33ccd2e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the national flag was raised and the national anthem was played. The hard work of Chinese athletes has finally paid off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Russian athlete Kashnikina, who won the runner-up in the women&#39;s 20-kilometer race walk at the London Olympics, was disqualified by the International Olympic Committee for doping violations. Sister Qieyangshi, who originally won the bronze medal, , and won the silver medal. Another seven years later, in March 2023, the International Olympic Committee announced on its official website that Russian athlete Yelena Rashmanova, the gold medal winner in the women&#39;s 20-kilometer race walk at the 2012 London Olympics, was also disqualified due to illegal doping. and championship qualifications, Sister Qieyangshi eventually became the gold medalist, and the silver and bronze medals were redistributed to Chinese players Liu Hong and Lu Xiuzhi. The top eight spots in the event have also been adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, after receiving her Olympic gold medal, the famous race walker Qie Yangshi cried with excitement.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/12d1dce893.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/05/12d1dce893.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 4, 2023 In the evening, after receiving her Olympic gold medal, the famous race walker Qie Yangshi burst into tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tibetan, Sister Cheyangshi’s name represents luck and happiness. When she learned the news, she expressed on Weibo that she was both happy and sad: happy because she became a champion in her heart and could have an Olympic gold medal; sad because she had never felt what it was like to be a champion and had not won an Olympic championship. aura. At the end of the article, she wrote down her expectations: Let the past be in the past, and still work hard to get what you want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, Liu Hong, Sister Qieyangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi walked down the podium and accepted photos from the media.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/0b1c1c2a4e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/05/0b1c1c2a4e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The evening of October 4, 2023 , Liu Hong, Sister Qie Yangshi, and Lu Xiuzhi walked off the podium and accepted photos from the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 4, Sister Qieyangshi won the championship in the mixed 35-kilometer race walk between men and women at the Hangzhou Asian Games. She won the Asian Games gold medal and the Olympic gold medal in one day. She said that honors belong to the past. When she steps off the podium, everything starts from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 4, 2023, the audience raised their mobile phones to take pictures. This supplementary Olympic medal award ceremony focused everyone&#39;s attention.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/c521617812.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/05/c521617812.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The evening of October 4, 2023 , the audience raised their mobile phones to take pictures. This replacement Olympic medal awarding ceremony focused everyone&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[用最“快”的光照亮幽微世界——透视2023年诺贝尔物理学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258128]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 3, 2023, Beijing time, the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences announced that the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physics will be awarded to Pierre Pierre Agostini, Ferenc Krausz and Anne L&#39;Huillier &quot;for their contributions to the study of electron dynamics in matter&quot; Experimental method to generate attosecond light pulses.&quot; The three people each received 1/3 of the total prize money of 11 million Swedish krona (approximately 7.23 million yuan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Usy1cgehlyOdXJA6isO3Ca5Mv9MaY1vpRmSxOY6V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1582&quot; height= &quot;760&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Usy1cgehlyOdXJA6isO3Ca5Mv9MaY1vpRmSxOY6V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253044&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Winners of the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physics, from left to right, are Pierre Agostini, Ferenc Kraus and Anne Leweli Er&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nobel Prize official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Agostini received his PhD from the University of Aix-Marseille in France in 1968 degree and is currently a professor at The Ohio State University in the United States. Krautz was born in Hungary in 1962. He received his PhD from the Technical University of Vienna in Austria in 1991. He is currently the director of the Max Planck Institute for Quantum Optics in Germany and a professor at the Ludwig-Maximilians University of Munich in Germany. Le Huillier was born in Paris, France, in 1958. He received his PhD from Pierre and Marie Curie University in Paris in 1986 and is currently a professor at Lund University in Sweden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this award, Lehulier also became the fifth woman to win the Nobel Prize in Physics. The previous four winners were Marie Curie in 1903 and Marie Curie in 1963. Maria Goppert-Mayer in 2018, Donna Strickland in 2018 and Andrea Gates in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These three physicists were awarded this year&#39;s Nobel Prize in Physics because their experiments provided humans with new tools to explore the electronic world inside atoms and molecules. They demonstrated a method of creating extremely short light pulses that can be used to measure the rapid processes by which electrons move, or change energy. In 2022, Lehuillier and Kraus also won the Wolf Prize in Physics for &quot;pioneering contributions to ultrafast laser science and attosecond physics.&quot; At that time, another co-winner was a Canadian physicist. Paul Corkum, a professor at the University of Ottawa. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Finding the fastest &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &quot;shutter&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Events of short duration cannot be observed by the human eye. For example, a hummingbird can beat its wings 80 times per minute, but we can only see the blurry motion of the hummingbird while hearing the humming sound. Thanks to high-speed photography, we can see events that seem fleeting to us, like the beating of a hummingbird&#39;s wings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The faster events happen, the faster you have to take photos to capture those moments. If we want to explore truly ephemeral events, we need very special techniques. At the scale of molecules and atoms, events occur at extremely fast speeds. For example, within a molecule, the time it takes for atoms to move or change is on the order of femtoseconds. Femtosecond is a very short time, 1 femtosecond is equal to 10&lt;sup>;-15&lt;/sup>; seconds. At this point, the motion of the atoms can be studied using very short pulses generated by the laser. However, when electrons move inside atoms or molecules, changes in the femtosecond time scale become very blurry because they move too fast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in the world of electrons, changes occur in tens of attoseconds. Attosecond is a unit of time, and 1 attosecond is equal to 10&lt;sup>;-18&lt;/sup>; seconds, which is a very small time scale. One attosecond relative to one second is equivalent to one second relative to the age of the universe. Therefore, if physicists want to explore the electronic world inside molecules and atoms, they need to find a fast enough &quot;shutter&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dCHhgjLb11KQemJoZt6qZLFqlEBnkQCIRJFPMJ8F.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;636&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dCHhgjLb11KQemJoZt6qZLFqlEBnkQCIRJFPMJ8F.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253043&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Attosecond physics gives physicists the opportunity to observe the motion of electrons. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nobel Prize official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Femtoseconds have long been considered the limit of the shortest possible light pulses. Improving existing techniques is not enough to see processes taking place on the extremely short time scales of electron movement; doing so requires completely new techniques. Experiments by three of this year&#39;s laureates produced extremely short pulses of light, measured in attoseconds, demonstrating that these pulses can be used to provide images of processes inside atoms and molecules. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Birth of Attosecond Physics&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Light is a wave produced by changes in electric and magnetic fields. Different lights have different wavelengths and appear in different colors. For example, red light has a wavelength of about 700 nanometers, one-hundredth the width of a human hair, and it fluctuates about 430 trillion times per second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shortest light pulse is the length of a single period in the light wave. If traditional methods are used to create ultrashort light pulses, the duration of each light pulse will never be less than femtoseconds, making it impossible to observe the movement of electrons. In the 1980s, physicists thought this was a very difficult limit to overcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the mathematics of describing waves shows that any waveform can be constructed using waves of the right size, wavelength, and amplitude (the distance between crests and troughs). The secret to building attosecond pulses is to create shorter pulses by combining more light with shorter wavelengths. To obtain these shorter wavelength light, we need to use a phenomenon called &quot;gas harmonics&quot; produced when the laser passes through the gas. The harmonics here are like the overtones produced when plucking guitar strings. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1987, Lehuillier discovered that when she passed an infrared laser through a rare gas, it produced more and stronger &quot;overtones&quot; than in previous experiments. When the laser passes through the gas, the laser interacts with the atoms in the gas. The extra energy gained by the electrons in the interaction is released in the form of light pulses, and these light pulses from the electrons are the &quot;overtones&quot; in the experiment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once these &quot;overtones&quot; appear, they interact with each other. When the peaks of light waves coincide, the light becomes stronger, but when the peaks in one cycle coincide with the troughs of another cycle, the light becomes weaker. Under the right circumstances, the &quot;overtones&quot; coincide and a series of light pulses appear, each lasting a few hundred attoseconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Physicists understood the theory in the 1990s, but it wasn&#39;t until 2001 that they made a breakthrough in actually identifying and testing light pulses. Agostini and his collaborators in France succeeded that year in generating and studying a series of successive light pulses. Using a special trick, they combined these light pulses with delayed portions of the original laser pulse to see how the overtones synchronized with each other. This process allowed them to measure that each pulse lasted only 250 attoseconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, Kraus and his collaborators in Austria developed a technique to select individual pulses. The pulse they successfully isolated lasted 650 attoseconds, which the team used to track and the study of processes that pull electrons out of atoms. These experiments show that scientists can observe and measure attosecond pulses, and that these attosecond pulses can also be used in new experiments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The future of attosecond physics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the attosecond world is within our reach. These short pulses of light can be used to study the movement of electrons. Physicists can already obtain pulses as low as tens of attoseconds, and the technology continues to evolve. Eva Olsson, chair of the Nobel Prize Committee in Physics, said: &quot;We can now open the door to the world of electrons. Attosecond physics gives us the opportunity to understand the mechanisms governed by electrons. The next step is to exploit These mechanisms.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Chinese physicists are also conducting research on attosecond physics and are collaborating closely with international colleagues, including the winners of this Nobel Prize in Physics. For example, the Institute of Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Songshan Lake Materials Laboratory jointly established the Attosecond Science Center in Dongguan, Guangdong. The Institute of Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences built a comprehensive extreme conditions experimental facility in Huairou Science City, Beijing, which can provide ultrafast data of about 100 attoseconds. For light fields, the Xi&#39;an Institute of Optics and Precision Mechanics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences established the Attosecond Science and Technology Research Center in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attosecond physics has potential applications in many fields. For example, in electronics research, it is important to understand and control the behavior of electrons in a material. Attosecond pulses can also be used to identify different molecules, which could have applications in medical diagnosis. In the future, we are expected to see attosecond physics play a more important role in basic and applied research, helping us deepen our understanding of the physical world while bringing more benefits to human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:25:20 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不止于新冠疫苗，有可能引发疫苗革命 ——透视2023年诺贝尔生理学或医学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258126]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 13:46:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 2, 2023, Beijing time, the Swedish Nobel Prize Committee announced that for the invention of nucleotide base modification , thus developing an effective messenger RNA (mRNA) vaccine, American scientists Katalin Karikó and Drew Weissman won the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, and they will share 1100 SEK 10,000 bonus. Due to the great success of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccine, Carrico and Weisman have won many major awards including the Breakthrough Prize in Life Sciences, the Lasker Prize and so on. The Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine this time is truly well-deserved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/fAsK0dPttYF2W8soIvVJrdEUBDYF79H9JgXcOZRc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;982&quot; height= &quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/fAsK0dPttYF2W8soIvVJrdEUBDYF79H9JgXcOZRc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253045&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Drew Weissman and Katalin Karikó, the main pioneers of mRNA vaccines. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Cell website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Pioneer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Carico 1955 Born in Szolnok, Hungary, after receiving his PhD in Hungary, he moved to the United States in 1985 and entered into postdoctoral research at Temple University in Philadelphia and Bethesda University of Health Sciences, focusing on research on the medical application of mRNA. After experiencing a series of setbacks such as frustrated funding applications, demotions and salary cuts, and suffering from cancer, Carrico met her long-term research partner Professor Drew Weisman. The two met dramatically because of their fight for a copy machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Professor Weismann was already a moderately accomplished immunologist. Weisman, two years younger than Carrico, was born in Lexington, Massachusetts, USA. He received a doctorate in medicine from Boston University in 1987. When he met Carrico, Weissman had just established his own research group at the Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, working on research in areas such as AIDS vaccines. After learning about Carrico&#39;s research interests, Weisman suggested that Carrico switch to the field of mRNA vaccines and decided to collaborate with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But mRNA vaccine research is not easy because mRNA is an extremely unstable small nucleotide molecule. The mRNA molecule is widely present in living organisms. It is the &quot;messenger&quot; for DNA to guide cell cooperation proteins. It is responsible for transmitting the genetic information of the gene to the ribosome, which &quot;installs according to the diagram&quot; and assembles the amino acid &quot;parts&quot; into various proteins. Therefore, mRNA is called messenger RNA. After completing its mission, the mRNA is quickly broken down by enzymes in the cell and its existence time is very short. If mRNA is injected into the body as a vaccine, these mRNA molecules will be broken down quickly before they can instruct cells to synthesize proteins. What&#39;s even more deadly is that animal experiments show that injecting unmodified mRNA into the body can trigger an immune response in the body, leading to serious adverse reactions to the vaccine. mRNA vaccines have also been ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to these problems, Carrico and Weisman conducted a series of studies. Although funds were limited, they still persisted in this direction and made some major breakthroughs. In 2005, Carrico and Weisman discovered that some natural nucleotides in messenger RNA were important factors in causing adverse immune responses in the body. They found the nucleotides in messenger RNA that triggered adverse immune responses, and then used artificially synthesized Nucleotide replacement significantly weakened adverse immune responses. This study laid a key foundation for the subsequent development of mRNA vaccines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Carrico, Weisman and others improved the messenger RNA vaccine to increase the stability of the mRNA vaccine in the body. For example, they used a liposome &quot;coat&quot; to coat the messenger RNA vaccine. Wrap it up so that it cannot be broken down by nucleases before entering the cell. With the continuous improvement of technology, there is increasing hope for the industrialization of mRNA vaccines. Compared with traditional vaccines, mRNA vaccines have some obvious advantages, such as good safety, short design and development cycle, low production cost, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;New Opportunities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, before the outbreak of the new crown epidemic, mRNA vaccines had been tepid. At that time, dozens of mRNA-based vaccines were being developed around the world, and a few vaccines such as influenza vaccine, Zika virus vaccine, and rabies vaccine had entered clinical trials, but none had yet been approved for human disease prevention. This situation quickly changed due to the global pandemic of the new coronavirus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to long-term accumulation, BioNTech, a German biotechnology company where Carrico serves as vice president and head of RNA therapy development, quickly launched new crown vaccine research and development after the outbreak of the new crown epidemic. The mRNA COVID-19 vaccine BNT162b2, which targets the spike protein of COVID-19, was developed. Due to the emergency of the epidemic, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has also given the green light to clinical trials of COVID-19 vaccines such as mRNA vaccines, greatly shortening the pre-clinical animal testing and clinical trial time of COVID-19 vaccines, which originally took several years or even more than ten years. The clinical trial was completed in just 7 months. Fortunately, BNT162b2 not only shows good safety, but the effectiveness of the vaccine has also reached an astonishing over 90%, which is significantly better than traditional vaccines. Since the end of 2020, most countries and regions around the world, including the United Kingdom and the United States, have successively approved the emergency use of BNT162b2 vaccine. At the same time, the new coronavirus RNA vaccine mRNA-1273 developed by the American company Moderna also achieved similar results, and this vaccine is also based on the patented mRNA vaccine technology of Carrico and Weissman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In less than a year from vaccine design, clinical trials to approval for marketing, BNT162b2 and other mRNA COVID-19 vaccines have created a miracle in the history of vaccine research and development. This is of course related to the global pandemic of the new crown epidemic, but it is mainly due to the good safety and excellent effectiveness of the mRNA new crown vaccine. Judging from the real application data of subsequent large-scale immunization and the preventive effect against new coronavirus variants, mRNA new coronavirus vaccines such as BNT162b2 also performed well. According to the Nobel Prize website, more than 13 billion doses of COVID-19 vaccines have been administered around the world, saving millions of lives. BNT162b2 and other mRNA COVID-19 vaccines are among the most outstanding vaccines. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Vaccine revolution? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If the mRNA vaccine can only work in the new coronavirus epidemic, its charm will be greatly reduced. In fact, greatly encouraged by the success of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccine, dozens of clinical studies based on mRNA vaccines around the world are accelerating. If its application scope can be expanded, the mRNA vaccine technology pioneered by Carrico and Weismann is expected to start a vaccine revolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are currently two main application directions for mRNA vaccines. The first major application direction is to prevent infectious diseases. In addition to COVID-19, the current mRNA vaccines against human infectious diseases caused by pathogens such as epidemic viruses, Zika virus, cytomegalovirus, and respiratory syncytial virus have also entered Phase II or III. Clinical Trials. According to a press release issued by Moderna on September 13, 2023, the company has submitted marketing authorization applications for the respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) mRNA vaccine globally, and the seasonal influenza mRNA vaccine has been approved in three clinical trials. All trials also demonstrated acceptable safety and tolerability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second main application direction is the treatment of cancer. According to the US clinical trial website, there are currently nearly 50 mRNA vaccines related to cancer treatment in the world that have entered or completed phase II clinical trials, including Bion. A number of mRNA vaccines for cancer treatment developed by companies such as Tektronix and Moderna have entered Phase II clinical trials. These vaccines mainly target cancers such as melanoma, colorectal cancer, non-small cell lung cancer, and head and neck squamous carcinoma. Among them, there are high hopes that mRNA vaccines can be used in combination with other anti-tumor drugs to improve the effectiveness of cancer treatment. According to the results of a phase II clinical trial jointly released by Moderna and the US pharmaceutical giant Merck at the end of 2022, an mRNA vaccine developed by Moderna performed well when used in combination with Merck&#39;s checkpoint inhibitor Keytruda. Good, over 1 year, the mRNA vaccine combined with Keytruda led to a more than 40% reduction in the risk of cancer recurrence or death in patients with stage 3/4 melanoma compared with Keytruda alone. Moderna and Merck plan to launch phase III clinical trials of this treatment in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, apart from the multiple COVID-19 vaccines that have been approved for marketing, no mRNA vaccine has yet been approved for marketing. It remains to be seen whether the mRNA vaccine can show promising results in the prevention of other infectious diseases and cancer treatment. However, judging from the current progress of clinical trials, it is only a matter of time before a new mRNA vaccine is approved for marketing. The vaccine revolution initiated by mRNA technology may come soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[兰州一高中两老师深夜围殴学生：“突击查寝”制值得反思丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258086]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a school violence incident has attracted attention. According to a report by China Morning Post, based on the statements of parents and dormitory administrator Ma, the timeline of the incident is as follows: At 11:40 pm on September 26, four persons, the principal Wu and the admissions office director Hao, entered the They searched the dormitory and violently kicked in the door before entering. Suspecting the students to smoke, Wu and another teacher worked together to beat two students in the dormitory. The beating lasted for more than an hour, and the four did not leave until 1:20 a.m. the next day. During this period, Hao kept shouting, &quot;Beat him to death. If he is beaten to death, send him to the hospital.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, a student suffered from syncope and nosebleeds. The dormitory manager, Ma, fed the child candy and stayed with him to comfort him for more than two hours. Afterwards, &quot;the school confiscated the phone and watch and asked the students to write a guarantee not to tell their parents.&quot; Three days later, both parents &quot;discovered&quot; that the child had symptoms such as facial bruising, lethargy, nightmares and convulsions, which brought the matter into the public eye. The parents first contacted the dormitory manager, Teacher Ma. After hearing about this, Teacher Ma was &quot;filled with indignation and resigned.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recorded conversation between Teacher Ma and the principal Wu, Wu apologized and admitted that &quot;the action was a bit too big and a bit extreme&quot; and &quot;has already apologized to the students and parents.&quot; Afterwards, Teacher Ma also told the media that students on the entire floor witnessed the atrocities that night and &quot;I have no intention of doing it anymore.&quot; After the media called the principal Wu, Wu simply said, &quot;We are dealing with this matter.&quot; At present, the Lanzhou Municipal Government has established an investigation team on this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The timeline of this incident is not complicated, but there are still many questions that are worth analyzing one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the details of the incident are still quite ambiguous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the origin of the incident, the dormitory manager surnamed Ma said that he was &quot;inspecting the student dormitories on behalf of the school, but he did not expect to be so ruthless.&quot; It seems that the reason why the principal and his party entered the dormitory to check the dormitory and violently beat them was because they &quot;suspected the students of smoking.&quot; So, did the two students smoke? Why did the principal and his team violently kick in the door during the bed check? These are two key issues in this assault. There should be a logical chain between the student closing the door, the principal kicking the door and the student suspected of smoking to explain the cause of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The facts presented in the current media reports and interviews with the parties can only be interpreted as &quot;the students did smoke and locked the door for fear of being punished. The principal failed to open the door and then violently kicked it in, and finally surrounded him.&quot; . Even if two students do smoke, the principal and others can only punish the students, not corporal punishment, which is prohibited by the Teachers Law and the Compulsory Education Law. If the two students were not smoking at all, the behavior of the principal and others would be tantamount to violent madness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 7, paragraph 3, of the &quot;Penalty Rules for Primary and Secondary School Education&quot; (Trial) stipulates that if &quot;smoking, drinking, or behaving inappropriately and violating the student code&quot;, the school and its teachers should stop it and provide criticism and education , education and punishment can be implemented if necessary. However, any kind of disciplinary action does not include the violent beatings in this incident, which is &quot;corporal punishment that directly causes physical pain by hitting, stabbing, etc.&quot; which is expressly prohibited in Article 12. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the accusations made by the boarding manager and parents are true, then the principal Wu and others are also suspected of illegal and criminal acts. Judging from the descriptions of &quot;facial bruises&quot; and &quot;nosebleeds,&quot; the two victims may have met the criteria for &quot;minor injuries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this incident also shows a major problem in the current teaching management of primary and secondary schools, that is, there is an almost absolute &quot;management and obedience&quot; relationship between schools and students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a power relationship between teachers and students, and the principal and director of the admissions office are higher &quot;superiors&quot; than teachers. They come out to &quot;check the bed&quot; to discipline students, and they are also unconsciously or consciously expanding this power, which includes the power to unconditionally discipline students with corporal punishment. At the same time, students must obey the principal and other superiors unconditionally, otherwise they will face an escalation of corporal punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current law, once a violation of the student code such as &quot;student smoking&quot; occurs, on the one hand, the school can only punish and educate the students instead of corporally punishing and beating the students. On the other hand, the main responsible person they should hold accountable should be It is merchants who sell cigarettes to minors, parents or guardians who instigate or allow minors to smoke, rather than violently punishing minors who smoke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this incident also makes people rethink the management system of student dormitories and the so-called &quot;surprise dormitory inspection&quot; system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original intention of the student dormitory management system is to improve dormitory management, protect student safety, and ensure learning and living conditions. However, schools at all levels are now using the banner of &quot;benefiting students&quot;, which naturally takes over the private space of students&#39; study and life. In this incident, the principal and his team came to check the dormitory room at 23:40 in the evening and violently kicked the door. From every angle, they were eroding or even violating the students&#39; private space. As adults, college students will naturally complain about regulations such as &quot;forced self-study&quot;, &quot;locking the computer&quot;, and &quot;checking the bed every night&quot;; and judging from this incident, even if the high school students are minors, such &quot;surprise bed checks&quot; are not allowed. It was too harsh, and the subsequent &quot;confiscation of phones and watches&quot; further demonstrated the willfulness of those in power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High school students, mostly between the ages of 15 and 18, have the right to start taking over their own lives, manage their own personal space, and be responsible for their own actions. Whether high school boarding schools still need to treat older children like little ones is debatable, at least in terms of the dormitory management system. Schools should give students more private space to cultivate students&#39; self-management skills and better prepare them for adult life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the problem exposed in this incident is not just a simple issue of school violence, but also reveals problems in the teaching management of primary and secondary schools. As quasi-adults, high school students cannot just be subordinates who accept management and punishment unconditionally, but are future masters who should be cared for and cared for in the adult world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[“文坛祖母”冰心 用爱温暖世纪丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257697]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[提升软环境，善待游客始]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258090]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 11:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mid-Autumn Festival and the National Day are on consecutive holidays, and travel is popular. Experts estimate that more than 100 million people will travel during this long holiday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-driving has become the mainstream during long vacation travel. For those car owners who drive to Xi&#39;an, Shaanxi, Mianyang, Sichuan, Xinxiang, Henan and other places, this year&#39;s journey will have a lot less worries: the traffic police departments in these places recently announced that minor violations of foreign tourists&#39; vehicles will not be punished during the holidays. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such &quot;flexible law enforcement&quot; measures are generally welcomed by car owners. The car is in a different place and the road in life is unfamiliar. Even if you have a navigation system, various situations will inevitably happen. If you are slapped with a ticket and fined for this, you may not be in a good mood for the whole day. There are no penalties for minor violations of laws by foreign vehicles. This will allow foreign tourists to relax and have fun without having to worry about getting into trouble or losing money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actions of the traffic police in these places are not illegal, but based on evidence. The Administrative Penalty Law clearly stipulates that if the violation is minor and is corrected in a timely manner without causing harmful consequences, no administrative penalty will be imposed; if the violation is for the first time and the harmful consequences are minor and the harmful consequences are corrected in a timely manner, administrative penalties may not be imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the fundamental purpose of punishing traffic violations is to ensure safe and smooth traffic and improve traffic efficiency. If some minor violations do not cause traffic congestion or affect traffic safety and traffic efficiency, they do not need to be punished. If you use a high-power magnifying glass to see defects and you are punished for minor violations, it becomes a fine for the sake of fines, which is putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, tourism has become an important economic driving force in many cities. To attract tourists, in addition to unique attractions, the soft environment is also an important aspect of attraction. For example, this year&#39;s Zibo barbecue fire caused many tourists from out of town to come by car. There was no room in the parking lot, so some people parked their cars on the roadside. Faced with these illegally parked out-of-town vehicles, the Zibo traffic police did not come up and issue a punishment note. Instead, they called each one to notify them to move the vehicles. This practice was praised and attracted more people to Zibo to eat barbecue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, there were some places that had &quot;extremely strict law enforcement&quot; on foreign car owners. I drive this road, and when foreign car owners come, they have to find faults and fines. Some places even deliberately set up law enforcement traps to punish outsiders. In this way, foreign car owners are treated as &quot;water fish&quot;, and they will not come next time. Not only will they not come, they will also post online to appeal to others not to come. When such word-of-mouth evaluation spreads, there will naturally be fewer and fewer tourists, and the tourism economy will be out of the question. On the contrary, if foreign tourists are &quot;softly enforced&quot; and try not to be punished, so that tourists feel comfortable, they may stay here for a few more days. Next time they come, they will take the initiative to do voluntary publicity online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, foreign car owners who enjoy flexible law enforcement treatment must also consciously abide by traffic rules, try not to violate the rules, do not create congestion in the local area, and be decent in both directions. After all, only good traffic order can bring a relaxing and pleasant travel experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tourism environment is part of the business environment and a reflection of the overall business environment. There used to be some places that specifically targeted foreign investment merchants. In the early stage, they used various &quot;preferential policies&quot; to attract foreign merchants to invest in and build factories. After that, they started to &quot;harvest the wool&quot;. Not only were the original promises unable to be fulfilled, but they also had to eat all kinds of food. To get the card, &quot;beat the foreign businessmen to internal injuries and strip the domestic businessmen naked.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What kind of business environment there is, there will be what kind of investment enthusiasm. From the tourism environment to the business environment, they are essentially a reflection of the level of local public governance. Paying attention to one&#39;s own reputation and reputation is the basic prerequisite for local public governance to become good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>