<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[奶茶按公斤炫！新疆人豪横起来连东北人都害怕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260575]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, milk tea in Xinjiang has become a hot topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some netizens posted pictures showing that when buying milk tea in Xinjiang, a cup starts at 1kg, triggering heated discussions among the public about the &quot;bigness&quot; of Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The air in Xinjiang seems to be filled with baking powder, and food will &quot;expand&quot; several times once it arrives in Xinjiang. For example, 10 kinds of Xinjiang delicacies, including Xinjiang’s No. 1 Nang, Big Plate of Chicken, Noodle Soup for Ten Thousands of People, Largest Oil Cake Tower, and Rice Pilaf for Ten Thousand People, have all set Guinness World Records for their “bigness”. Compared with milk tea that starts at 2 pounds, It can be regarded as a &quot;baby meal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xinjiang&#39;s largest &quot;Aimai&quot; naan has a diameter of 40 to 50 centimeters. It requires 1 kilogram of flour to make. There are patterns stamped in the middle of the naan, and there are chopped onions or sesame seeds. . Nang with meat in a vat, pitted meat with naan, Xinjiang fried rice noodles with naan... Thousands of ways to eat naan, brewing the nostalgic memory of Xinjiang people when they were children waiting for their mother to break off a piece by the naan pit and feed it to their mouths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason why Xinjiang cuisine is so heavy is that Xinjiang people don’t have the concept of kilograms and liangs. What they call “one kilogram” is actually one kilogram. Because of the &quot;bigness&quot; of Xinjiang, they created their own weights and measures - there are 22 airports in one province of Xinjiang. In their eyes, distances within 1,000 kilometers are very close, and 1,000 kilometers is enough to travel from Beijing to Taiyuan and back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the large portions, the prices of Xinjiang dishes are also shocking in Northeast China, which is always known for its affordable prices. According to data from Dianping, the top ten restaurants in Urumqi, the capital of Xinjiang, only cost 74 yuan per person, which is lower than the average price in the capitals of the three eastern provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is large in area and heavy in weight, and the &quot;imagination&quot; of Xinjiang people is also very big. Many Xinjiang people&#39;s store names reveal a kind of simple humor. A series of store names such as &quot;Sexy Mommy&#39;s Postpartum Recovery Mother and Baby Center&quot; and &quot;Drag and Drive Over&quot; make people laugh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As an inland province, Xinjiang gives people the impression that it has nothing to do with water. Also because of its &quot;large&quot; territory, Xinjiang has almost all the country&#39;s specialties, such as Salmon production accounts for 15% of inland production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xinjiang also has great charm. In the first three quarters of this year, Xinjiang received 213.86 million tourists, a year-on-year increase of 77.73%. Tourists rushed to this western land, came with expectations, and left reluctantly as if they were heartbroken. Xinjiang’s specialty paper-skinned walnuts and Hotan jujubes are also on sale on Taobao. Even if they stay at home, they want to taste the taste of Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;know&quot; will talk to you about the &quot;bigness&quot; of Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73461&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70268&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3fbf9d25ee.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3fbf9d25ee.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258185&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73462&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70269&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/14/5dc309c9d1.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5dc309c9d1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258186&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73463&quot; group-id= &quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70270&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/22777928eb.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/22777928eb.png&quot; data- key=&quot;258187&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73464&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70271&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b673748357.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b673748357.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258188&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img -id=&quot;73465&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70272&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3de07e6f6c.png&quot; img -title=&quot;custom – 5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/14/3de07e6f6c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258189&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73466&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70273&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f437541a92.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom –6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f437541a92.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258190&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“永恒”的敌人：未了案横跨八十年，谁的“王洛宾”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260885]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 11, 2023, Zhuozhou, Hebei, Wang Haicheng&#39;s &quot;In That Faraway Land&quot; &quot;Place&quot; manuscript. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/1c70971ed9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/1c70971ed9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 11, 2023, Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, Wang Haicheng&#39;s manuscript of &quot;In That Distant Place&quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A stage play&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Only a few people realize that everything they enjoy at the moment is facing unprecedented challenges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A quarter of an hour before 7:30, outside the West Second Ring Road in Beijing, a group of children and parents gathered in front of the Erqi Theater. It was a cool evening in early September, and the new version of the red children&#39;s drama &quot;The Ballad of Soybean&quot; began its national tour here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some Chinese people are familiar with this story. In 1940, the Gansu Provincial Working Committee of the Communist Party of China was destroyed. Luo Lili, who was 8 months old, was arrested at the same time as his parents. After several twists and turns, he was imprisoned in Lanzhou Dashagou Prison, where he spent 6 years. Wang Luobin, who was also in prison, asked Luo Lili what the most delicious food in the world was. Luo Lili, who had never been exposed to the outside world, thought it was broad beans that he had eaten by chance. Wang Luobin composed the song &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot; from this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A while after leaving the venue, the crowd suddenly surrounded an old man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The old man has appeared on CCTV 13 times. On TV, he is smart, wise, and tall. He is proud that he &quot;didn&#39;t make a single mistake&quot; when talking. &quot;, and sometimes, I even have to play and sing &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; on the stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the old man in front of him has droopy eye bags and a lot of white hair on his sparse head. He kept taking out performance tickets from the small shoulder bag on his chest, a total of 40 tickets, which belonged to &quot;old friends&quot; he had met through cooperation in the name of his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of these &quot;old friends&quot; reached the peak of their careers in the 1990s. They had their own programs in top media and were able to open solo concerts in the most central concert hall in Beijing. Concert, organize a commemorative concert for Wang Luobin in the most famous building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also officials from Zhuozhou, Hebei. This county-level city with a population of 650,000 has a 30-square-meter former residence of Wang Luobin and a Wang Luobin Choir. The director of Zhuozhou Culture and Tourism Bureau and the director of the cultural center drove 60 kilometers to come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is the youngest son of Wang Luobin, the &quot;King of Western Singers&quot;. Wang Luobin&#39;s ancestral home is in Zhuozhou, and a new Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is about to be renovated in an old factory in the north of the city as a local cultural landmark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin, who will appear on the stage in a quarter of an hour, is a &quot;prisoner&quot; who has to go through several political movements before he can be called the King of Singers in the future. , Prison Years, and Social Change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin&#39;s 83-year ups and downs often give playwrights a headache. He once participated in the Northwest Anti-Japanese War Theater Troupe with Xiao Jun, Seke and others. He was also highly appreciated by the warlord Ma Bufang and formed a children&#39;s theater troupe in Qinghai. During China&#39;s darkest period, he captured a hint of romanticism, and some of the songs he was most proud of in his life were born here, including &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; and &quot;Youth Dance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At half past seven, &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot; started. I got a chance to film Wang Haicheng, a documentary director who has been following him for more than ten years. The film is called &quot;Looking for Wang Luobin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the &quot;old friends&quot; in the audience, some people want to promote this drama to a bigger stage, and some people want to make a movie related to Wang Luobin. , two people respectively proposed to build a music school named after the king of singers in Hebei and Hainan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They all need to obtain authorization from Wang Haicheng. Only a few people realize that everything the son of the King of Songs enjoys at the moment is facing unprecedented challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 11, 2023, in Zhuozhou, Hebei, Wang Haicheng showed his published biography of Wang Luobin and audio and video products. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ae52930ca3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/19/ae52930ca3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258760&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 11, 2023 On the same day, in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, Wang Haicheng displayed his published biography of Wang Luobin and audio-visual products. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;SON OF THE SINGER&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Family has never been a place where the singer is willing to devote his attention&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng has spent half his life defending his father&#39;s honor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin has two marriages, three sons and several loves. Among the three sons, the eldest went to Australia in the 1980s. The second child was a truck driver and died of illness. After surviving a period of history, the four fathers and sons now only have the third child left. Therefore, interviews, authorizations, rights protection, concerts, commemorations, and publications all fell on Wang Haicheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, for a long time, the identity of &quot;Wang Luobin&#39;s son&quot; made Wang Haicheng breathless. When he was 8 months old, Wang Luobin was arrested, followed by a search of his home. A month later, his mother passed away in the hospital bed. Relatives in Beijing did not dare to have contact with the Wang family. After hearing about it, the fifth uncle in Zhuozhou drove a carriage all day and night from Beijing in the early winter in the north to bring the body back from Beijing and bury it in a wheat field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A few years ago, Wang Haicheng tried to find his mother&#39;s tomb, but he could no longer find it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Studying stopped in the second grade of junior high school. When it was time to go to the mountains and countryside, Wang Haicheng stayed on the farm for nine years because of Wang Luobin. When groups of educated young people returned to the city one after another, he also got a nickname: &quot;Cushionzi&quot;. This dialect refers to the last puppy out of a litter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Family is never a place where the singer is willing to devote his attention. Wang Haicheng wrote that the union between his father and his mother was due to the breakup of his father&#39;s previous relationship, so he wanted to take revenge on his life. Wang Luobin was born free. He went to the grassland, to the market, and even in prison, collecting folk songs. A producer who visited the singer&#39;s deeds mentioned a detail. In his later years, Wang Luobin rode a bicycle everywhere. When it got dark, he would lie on the road and fall asleep, and then go home the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin passed away in 1996. Wang Haicheng immediately joined the China Music Copyright Association and registered 207 musical works recorded, organized and created by Wang Luobin with the association. He became increasingly aware that his father had left a shining legacy. Since 2000, Wang Haicheng has successively published two biographies of Wang Luobin, a song sheet of Wang Luobin, invested in TV films, and a long narrative poem. Four exhibition halls have been created in Turpan, Xinjiang, Haibei, Qinghai, Baishui Ancient Town, Dabancheng, Xinjiang, and Liupan Mountain, Ningxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is difficult to say how father&#39;s love plays a subtle role in Wang Haicheng&#39;s life. In order to guard this heritage, he was like an ascetic, stationed in the Grape Valley of the Flame Mountain for 16 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first few years of the 21st century, the Turpan Wang Luobin Music and Art Museum in Grape Valley was the only temple to commemorate the king of singers. This building has an Ottoman-style white circular dome and 80 panels displaying the singer&#39;s life. Visitors came in the 40℃ high temperature. When they opened the door, they saw the sweaty son of the singer wearing a shirt with Wang Luobin&#39;s logo in front of him. There were biographies, song collections, tapes and records on the counter. When the operation of the art museum was most difficult, Wang Haicheng went to bring in strange stones from the Gobi Desert that looked like pork belly and English letters. This is the most popular commodity in Xinjiang’s tourism market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also set up an incense burner in front of his father&#39;s portrait - Wang Luobin converted to Buddhism in his later years. There was once a man who claimed to be a physicist and kowtowed three times directly to the portrait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng honed his speaking skills, pondered the details of his father&#39;s life, paid attention to his image, and never refused any opportunity to appear in the national media. The comment that moved him most came from an old man from Shandong: &quot;Wang Haicheng, you are the biggest filial son in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On July 24, 2022, Wang Luobin Music was located in Putaogou, Turpan, Xinjiang Art Museum. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dc0cd8871e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dc0cd8871e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 24, 2022, Wang Luobin Music Art Museum is located in Grape Valley, Turpan, Xinjiang. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Salvage and Debate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changing one note, two notes, or a chorus counts as &quot;adaptation&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the 1990s, a modern storm swept through Urumqi: the most cutting-edge local popular music came from further west. Ethnic minorities hold weekly house music gatherings. Seven days and nights after the song &quot;Forgetting Love Water&quot; reached Urumqi, the shops in the Grand Bazaar would use rough-sounding speakers to play versions in other languages. The bars all over the street are full of singing bands. On the radio, the male host can talk endlessly about the Beatles, Tchaikovsky and Rachmaninoff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yibo, the director of &quot;Looking for Wang Luobin&quot;, was the popular host of the Urumqi Economic Radio program &quot;Music Leisure Island&quot; at the time. After more than 20 years, she believes that Urumqi at that time showed tolerance for all kinds of music and was the &quot;center of Asian music.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But there is no local singer&#39;s name in popular music. His limelight comes from outside Urumqi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin was rediscovered in the context of an era where order was brought to order. In May 1981, on an afternoon when the temperature suddenly soared to 33°C and the snow suddenly melted, in a five- to six-square-meter concierge at the Qianjin Theater, Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhao Quanzhang met Wang Luobin, who had just been released from prison. In Zhao Quanzhang&#39;s reminiscence article, this person who looked like Quasimodo in &quot;The Hunchback of Notre Dame&quot; was unemployed, had no household registration, and did not even have &quot;food and oil connections.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Quanzhang wrote the internal reference for Wang Luobin, and soon received instructions from Song Renqiong, then head of the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. Zhao Quanzhang once recalled that the work of bringing order to the country was not completely smooth at that time. The resolution of Wang Luobin&#39;s problem had an impact on Xinjiang and the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Openness was the theme of the 1980s. And for a musician who has experienced the war of resistance, prison, and rehabilitation, is there any symbol more suitable to glimpse a country&#39;s path of exploration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 1988, &quot;Eight Thousand Miles to the Clouds and the Moon&quot; hosted by Taiwanese artist Ling Feng went to Xinjiang to interview Wang Luobin. This was the first program from the other side to introduce China. TV programs about mainland China’s customs and customs. Then, Xia Jie, a female writer from Hong Kong, China, also came to visit and wrote three articles. Soon, Singapore, Australia, North America, and overseas Chinese had someone to pay attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The media calls him the King of Western Singers and enjoys special government subsidies. China Record Corporation awarded him the Golden Record Special Creation Award, and UNESCO awarded him the &quot;Promote &quot;Special Contribution Award for Cultural Exchange between East and West&quot;. But all the medals are inferior to the gifts given by the people. In the era when the word &quot;fan&quot; only refers to fans, Wang Luobin&#39;s most proud example is, &quot;Chinese friends said that at least half of the two million Chinese in the United States can sing. &quot;In that distant place&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A more well-known story is that Sanmao, a female writer from Taiwan, China, moved directly into the home of the singer, and scandals abounded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Trouble is coming quietly. One day in 1993, Luo Dayou&#39;s agent called. Not long ago, Rolling Stone Records released the tape &quot;Love Song Anniversary - Luo Dayou and Wang Luobin&#39;s Great Collaboration of the Century&quot; without Wang Luobin&#39;s consent. The King of Songs was very angry and took Luo Dayou to court for infringement of his copyright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Greater controversy ensued. Someone revealed that Ling Feng paid 20,000 yuan to buy out ten of Wang Luobin&#39;s songs, including &quot;In That Faraway Place&quot;, &quot;The Girl from Dabancheng&quot;, &quot;Mayila&quot; and &quot;Youth Dance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The music issue soon turned into a political issue. Someone asked, can Wang Luobin sell folk songs that belong to the people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A major discussion that lasted for more than a year began. In June 1994, &quot;People&#39;s Music&quot; magazine began to discuss the copyright issue of Wang Luobin&#39;s folk songs. Dai Penghai, an associate researcher at the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, published two articles criticizing the news media for hyping up Wang Luobin, and also accused Wang Luobin of &quot;selling out the people&#39;s sovereignty and interests in national music culture.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also people who support Wang Luobin. Liu Zaisheng, a professor at the Music Department of Shandong Normal University, pointed out that “collecting brotherly ethnic songs in different languages ​​is a more complex and difficult task, and the translation and dubbing of lyrics often plays a key role in success or failure.” And “if we combine the When the lyrics are analyzed together, it is not difficult to find that they have formed Wang Luobin&#39;s unique creative style that is lyrical, colloquial, and popular.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another background to the great discussion is that during China&#39;s &quot;resumption of customs&quot; negotiations, the Copyright Law was promulgated in 1991, which stipulates that &quot;adaptation, translation, The copyright of works resulting from the annotation and arrangement of existing works shall be enjoyed by the person who adapted, translated, annotated and arranged them.&quot; In other words, if Wang Luobin &quot;adapts, translates, annotates, and organizes&quot; folk songs, the copyright of the new songs belongs to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But, does changing one note, two notes, or a chorus count as &quot;adaptation&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 5 of that year, a symposium attended by more than thirty people was held in Beijing, including musicologists, composers, and legal professionals. people and journalists. The person presiding over the meeting was Qiao Jianzhong, then director of the Music Research Institute of the China Academy of Arts. He later recalled in an article that this symposium was actually an &quot;absent criticism&quot; against Wang Luobin, which was very explosive. However, the meeting finally reached a consensus that Wang Luobin had worked hard in recording, translating, editing, and adapting folk songs, but the rights he enjoyed needed to be quantitatively analyzed before the rights could be determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The eighty-year-old singer was very hurt and left the stage to participate in the debate in person several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the death of Wang Luobin in 1996, the big discussion did not continue. But this discussion could have clarified some fundamental issues, such as the quantitative standards for adaptation and the copyright of folk songs. In that era, Wang Luobin was not the only one who encountered similar problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Shanghai, a young man who was writing &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; was also troubled by this problem. In the process of sorting out Xian Xinghai&#39;s works, Wu Yuebei, a top student in the composition department of the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, checked and filled in the original scores. Some melodies that he thought were not harmonious even needed to be changed. When Xian Xinghai&#39;s descendants heard about Wang Luobin&#39;s dispute, they worriedly asked, if the original score was adjusted, would the copyright belong to him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After consulting the leaders of the Ministry of Culture at the time, &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; was finally processed as follows: the works with major changes were also included in the revised original works. version, as well as a more substantial adapted version. For revised or revised editions, the name of the reviser will be marked as a footnote at the end of the work, but no copyright will be generated. The edited version will have a copyright page marked with the name of the organizer, who owns the rights to the content compiled by him in the new version, but not the rights to the original work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This young man majoring in composition has no way of knowing that after more than 20 years, he may end the discussion about the copyright of the singer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wang Luobin and Luo Dayou. Reproduced from the photo album saved by Wang Haicheng on September 11, 2023. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/19/449cb5c56b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/19/449cb5c56b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Luobin and Luo Dayou. Reproduced from the photo album saved by Wang Haicheng on September 11, 2023. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Carpet rights protection&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;His opponents include video city vendors, publishing houses, university professors, as well as Li Yuchun, Tan Weiwei and Wang Sulong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new century is coming, and the law has become a modern weapon to protect rights and interests. Wang Haicheng suddenly discovered that everything his father left behind could be easily taken away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, China was in the midst of a heat wave to achieve modernization through a market economy. The &quot;resumption of customs&quot; turned into &quot;joining the WTO&quot;, a stable and international The integrated legal system is gradually improving. Intellectual property rights are a focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2002, Wang Luobin&#39;s adaptation of &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; was sued by the family of a deceased musician for copyright infringement. The family members believe that &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; is not a folk song, but a song composed by the late musician, originally titled &quot;How Beautiful My Garden is.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The family did not sue Wang Haicheng directly, but first sued an audio-visual company in Guangzhou. The CD published by the company labeled &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; as a folk song. The court found that the song was composed by the late musician. Afterwards, the family took this judgment and sued Wang Haicheng, claiming 230,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng said that &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; was written by his father in 1969 while serving a sentence. At that time, a young man was unjustly imprisoned, and his new wife died. The young man stopped cutting his hair and shaving. Wang Luobin felt inspired and adapted &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; based on an Ili folk song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A friend in Yili told Wang Haicheng that the original version of this ancient folk song can be found in the local archives. But before he was about to leave, the friend said that the information was missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2004, the court of first instance sentenced Wang Haicheng to pay compensation of 237,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the appeal, Wang Haicheng and his lawyer began to think about how to collect evidence. In October 2005, he and his lawyer pretended to be collectors from Beijing and spent 4,600 yuan to buy a small video camera. After arriving in Yili, they arranged to grab mutton and invited local music teachers and old people who could sing folk songs for interviews. At first, they did not reveal their interest in &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; and started talking about Ili folk songs. The cameras are always working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the conversation was almost over, Wang Haicheng turned to &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; and asked if there was an original folk song version of this song. Everyone said yes, and everyone hummed a line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But when they reveal their identities, very few people are willing to testify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After hitting a wall one after another, they finally found three old people willing to testify. I also met an &quot;Avanti&quot; (meaning &quot;teacher&quot;) named Ishamuddin, who said that the original song had probably been circulated for two hundred years, and he also knew that a lawsuit was ongoing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, Wang Haicheng thought that if he lost the lawsuit, &quot;things would develop like dominoes.&quot; Dozens of publishers had published this song Society will also be in crisis. Even if he travels to Hainan, he will pray with Mazu, hoping that Mazu can help him, the son of the king of singers, who is in trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On May 8, 2006, the Xinjiang High Court made a judgment that the two songs each enjoyed property rights in copyright. In Wang Haicheng&#39;s words, &quot;Both songs come from folk songs, and they are in a parallel relationship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At almost the same time, Wang Haicheng launched a blanket rights protection campaign that lasted for several years. For the sake of copyright, he fought against pirated CDs, KTV bosses, and singers who randomly covered his father&#39;s works. His opponents include audio-visual city vendors, publishers, university professors, as well as Li Yuchun, Tan Weiwei and Wang Sulong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was in 2004 when he was ordered to pay 237,000 yuan in compensation that Wang Haicheng received an unfamiliar phone call. The other party introduced himself like this: Ju Yonghe, a native of Jiangsu, a lawyer in Beijing, and a loyal fan of Wang Luobin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When they finally met a year later, Wang Haicheng was deeply impressed by his &quot;uprightness and non-joking&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He said that he was concerned that there were many publications infringing Wang Luobin&#39;s rights on the market, and he especially wanted to help protect his rights.&quot; Wang Haicheng was &quot;a little nervous financially at the time, and he was also weighing Should I file a lawsuit?&quot; Lawyer Ju dispelled his concerns: He would bear the cost of the lawsuit. If he lost the lawsuit, he would not ask Wang Haicheng for money. If he won, he would pay half of it after deducting travel expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This may be a more subtle way, and it also uses legal weapons to confirm again and again that Wang Luobin owns the copyright to a certain song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2005, Lawyer Ju has continued to make efforts. He went to the audio and video market and Xinhua Bookstore, walked around, saw the allegedly infringing publications, bought them, issued invoices, and sued. &quot;All those audio and video publishers came to me to ask for authorization. They can also use high-definition pictures of Wang Luobin on the covers of their publications. I also provided the introduction of Wang Luobin on the inside pages. It is more accurate and the text is smoother.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin became an inviolable icon. Around 2010, Lawyer Ju moved to KTV. In the words of the time, it was a &quot;mopping up&quot; operation. KTV&#39;s infringement made Wang Haicheng even more intolerable. The scenes in &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; were of Hainan beaches and bikini beauties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on the Yangtze River Delta, Lawyer Ju gradually expanded the scope of his operations. In his eyes, &quot;the judicial environment in the Yangtze River Delta was relatively good at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Victory is like a snowball getting bigger and bigger. In the eyes of some people in the music industry, even what didn&#39;t belong to him before, now belongs to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Wang Haicheng, the economic benefits in this round were not as much as people imagined. The compensation involved in the case that he received was &quot;about 120,000 yuan.&quot; &quot;. But he is very happy and feels that this battle is going smoothly and &quot;the pirated KTVs have been beaten into silence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this battle, he gave himself an indestructible meaning: to maintain his father&#39;s eternal status in the history of Chinese music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But this blanket rights protection came to an abrupt end in 2013, and Wang Haicheng was put in a tight ring. After mediation by the Supreme People&#39;s Court, Wang Luobin&#39;s descendants reached an agreement: some of the previous lawsuits should be withdrawn. &quot;If the lawsuit cannot be withdrawn, the accepting authority should proactively notify the accepting agency to add Wang Haiyan (eldest brother) and Wang Haixing (second brother) as co-litigants. Everything involving Mr. Wang Luobin&#39;s intellectual property rights All litigation actions should be jointly made by three persons (Wang Haiyan, Wang Haixing and Wang Haicheng) to make substantive decisions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It will be 6 years before Lawyer Ju appears again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 10, 2023, Wang Haicheng came to an old factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei, where the Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is being planned. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7f942b41f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7f942b41f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 10, Wang Haicheng came to an old factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, where the Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is being planned. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Xunge&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;On nights like this in the 1970s, Wang Haicheng asked his silent father again and again: I heard that there is a song that is also yours? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin left behind a world of lush water and grass, where there were young birds, rivers, long-braided Dabancheng girls, and most of all, It is important to praise the courage of love at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the world left behind by his father, Wang Haicheng spent more than twenty years marking the birth and origin of each symbol, the youthful bird and the long-braided Da. Bancheng Girl was born in 1938, while Alam Khan did not appear until May 1944. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​reason is that Wang Luobin rarely signs his name. He compiled a book called &quot;Song of the Northwest&quot; related to the Anti-Japanese War. The back cover said &quot;Compiled and printed by the Gansu People&#39;s Anti-Enemy Support Association.&quot; Wang Luobin said in his autobiography, &quot;I think this work is a citizen&#39;s duty.&quot; In this special era, many of his songs were not signed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Hai wrote three biographies of his father, a large part of which is about tracing his father&#39;s creative story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But it was 1974 when he first heard his father talk about his creative motivations. One day, the father and son went to a friend&#39;s house to celebrate their child&#39;s full moon. With the wine mixed with alcohol, everyone booed and asked Wang Haicheng to sing. He took over the guitar, finished singing &quot;Manli&quot;, and vividly talked about the origin of the song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There was a pair of lovers on the Mongolian grasslands. During the Anti-Japanese War, the man signed up to join the army to fight. The woman heard from the rear that the man had died. She was very sad and died of illness. &quot;The man came back from the war and heard that his fiancée was dead, so he ran to the cemetery and sang this song in front of her grave. Suddenly, this woman stood up from behind the grave again.&quot; Wang Haicheng recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin, who was no longer very talkative, took a sip of wine and said: &quot;Today is so interesting. My son sang a song by Lao Tzu. I didn&#39;t know that the song was from Lao Tzu.&quot; &quot;Written.&quot; It was a pornographic song, and criticism of it reached its peak in the 1950s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More stories were collected during the period when I temporarily lived with my father at my second brother’s house. Father and son sleep in a small room together, with two beds on the left and right and a window in the middle. During the day, Wang Luobin opened the bed and used the bed board as a table to copy music scores. &quot;He did not forget to revise the songs while copying them, and he sang them while writing.&quot; At night, the mosquitoes kept the two awake. On nights like this in the 1970s, Wang Haicheng asked his silent father again and again: I heard that there is a song that is also yours? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But this experience will not be helpful until Wang Haicheng writes his father&#39;s biography 30 years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After his father passed away, it became more difficult to find songs. The problem of songs was sometimes a legal issue, and sometimes even a political issue. There is only one song whose origin does not need to be searched by Wang Haicheng, and that is &quot;In That Distant Place&quot;, the &quot;Crown Pearl&quot; of the King of Western Songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1939, Wang Luobin followed director Zheng Junli to Qinghai to shoot the movie &quot;Long Live the Nation&quot;. Dolma, the daughter of a Tibetan head of thousands of households, was chosen to be the shepherdess. Wang Luobin Become a helper. When catching the sheep, Wang Luobin accidentally pumped a whip on the horse&#39;s buttocks, Zhuima on the horse shook the whip and gently hit Wang Luobin&#39;s body. So, there was the plot in the lyrics: &quot;I would like to make a lamb/I followed her/I would like to hit me with a leather whip every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The king himself told the media too many times. But maybe it is too much, so that one day in the future, some people who are interested start to compare the time, place and characters of each story, and find that it is difficult to fulfill the flaws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin also told the actor Ma Yue. In his early years, the actor won the second prize of the Blogo Singing Fa in the Qing Ge Charity. After holding a personal concert at the Beijing Opera House, after singing &quot;In the Far Far&quot;, a goat Hu Hu found him and said, &quot;Ma Yue, you look like when you are young.&quot; Second The saying is, &quot;You sing my singing accurately.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; That was a big discussion in 1994. The King of Song pointed out his two errors, one of which was the wrong tune. &quot;I am in prison, you sing my song outside. Now I sing back the song back, everyone said that I sang the wrong, I I can&#39;t change it anymore. &quot;Many people don&#39;t know, the&quot; In the Far Far &quot;, which is widely sung, is indeed not a version of Wang Luobin. His version, the score is now engraved on his tombstone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the two met twice, the song king added the process of spreading this song. He said, &quot;There are a lot of people who sung in the front of the front line. Why? Because each Anti -Japanese soldiers have a good girl.&quot; The young man who was rising in his career realized that Wang Luobin &quot;all the works grew from the soil of the nation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Wang Haicheng and his father Wang Luobin (right). (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /19/32F0379936.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1516 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/32F0379936.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258764 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Wang Haicheng and his father Wang Luobin (right). (Interviewee/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Okay, let&#39;s play to the end&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; The courier in the community to send the court courier every day, very wondering. What did this family commit? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The second day after the performance of &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot;, a student of Wang Luobin invited Wang Haicheng. The dishes were overwhelmed, and she asked carefully whether she needed help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The worry of the old friend is not without any reason. Wang Haicheng&#39;s second round of rights launched in 2019 has just encountered a defeat. In June 2023, the final judgment of the Beijing Intellectual Property Court determined that Wang Luobin and his descendants no longer enjoyed the copyright of &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, &quot;Four Seasons&quot; and &quot;Under Silver Moonlight&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 9 months ago, the Yangzhou Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Jiangsu Province had identified Wang Luobin as the copyright owner of &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unlike the abnormual rights protection ten years ago, most of the defendants are professional musicians and publishers. In the list, the national first -class composer Gong Yaonian, Hu Tingjiang, deputy director of the composition department of the Chinese Conservatory of Music, and the People&#39;s Music Publishing House were listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The issues of arguments are mainly concentrated. Is the song presented in the publications of these composers copy or adapted from Wang Luobin&#39;s version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For example, the reason why Gong Yaonian was sued was that he had previously compiled a batch of folk song piano songs from circulating folk songs, named &quot;Somson&#39;s folk songs&quot; &quot;Gong Yaonian &quot;Arrangement&quot;. This has aroused the dissatisfaction of Wang Haicheng. In his opinion, the nine capitals including &quot;The Far Far&quot; belong to Wang Luobin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;A inappropriate metaphor proposed by the other party is the relationship between grandpa and grandson. &quot;Li Yan, deputy director of the editor -in -chief of the People&#39;s Music Publishing House, said,&quot; But in the words of the other party in court, &#39;Wang Luobin is grandfather, all of you are grandson&#39;. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text -rign: left; &quot;>; The defendants also questioned accordingly, thinking that some of Wang Luobin&#39;s songs did not go through&quot; adaptation &quot;at all, or even&quot; copied &quot;the creation of others directly. The family of one of the defendants also found that the authenticity of the creative stories written by Wang Haicheng and the creative story of the King of Songs is yet to be questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The defendant&#39;s family is Wu Yuebei, who participated in the &quot;Complete Works of Xinghai&quot; more than 20 years ago. He is now a professor at the School of Music and a doctoral tutor in the composition direction. The defendant Gong Yaonian was his father -in -law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The second round of rights are turbulent. At the beginning, the defendants each fought. Hu Tingjiang, the earliest prosecution, adapted a &quot;Marrayam&quot;. In just this song, the lawyer of the residence sued him nearly a hundred times in many courts across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Hu Tingjiang recalled that he had been prosecuted, and there were still many puzzles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Around 2017, Wang Haicheng suddenly added Hu Tingjiang WeChat to inform him of the adaptation of &quot;May&quot; from Wang Luobin&#39;s &quot;May&quot;, and he needs to get his own. Authorization. Hu Tingjiang replied to respect Mr. Wang Luobin, but &quot;Marra&quot; was not created by Wang Luobin, but a well -known Kazakh folk song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Once, Wang Haicheng sent a message and praised Hu Tingjiang&#39;s adaptation very successful. He hoped that he would continue to work hard and adapt a few more Wang Luobin&#39;s works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In June 2017, Wang Haicheng sent another solo concert list of Changji College, which was printed with the words &quot;Young Dance&quot; Hu Tingjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It didn&#39;t take long for him to be prosecuted. The subpoena was sent from all over the country, and Hu Tingjiang remembered that the courier in the community was sent to the court courier every day, and he was very puzzled, &quot;What did this family commit?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Until a trial live broadcast, Hu Tingjiang, who was fighting alone, learned that Gong Yaonian was also prosecuted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Soon, these prosecution professors, musicians, and publishers formed an alliance of interoperability information. There are 43 people in the &quot;Wang Luobin Copywriter Case, and there are more than a dozen publishing houses in the&quot; Music Publishing Unite &quot;. Different from those KTV and audiovisual companies that have been sued by the son of the king of the song, the people in the &quot;alliance&quot; uphold such beliefs: even if they are only claimed with 10,000 yuan, they must make the reason clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the afternoon of April 20, 2023, 29 years after the discussion was launched, another symposium was held at the People&#39;s Music Publishing House called &quot;National Folk Music Work Protection -Wang Luobin&#39;s descendants of the Western Folk Song Copyright Dispute Case &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On this day, Li Yan once doubted that some publishers far away from Shanghai and Hunan would send representatives to this meeting with only half a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On that day, she was surprised to find that more than thirty publishing houses, many of them were present in person. At the meeting, some people admitted that they did hesitate to the court&#39;s subpoena before: (Wang Haicheng) It costs 10,000 yuan a song to bargain with him, and 5,000 can be reconciled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Someone later proposed that it was not money. Finally, everyone formed a consistent opinion, okay, let&#39;s go to the end.&quot; Li Yan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another consensus reached by the conference is that &quot;the legislative level should be introduced as soon as possible&quot; to &quot;realize the law can be rely on, avoid the same case in the judicial practice, &quot;Different judgment&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, the original provisions of the copyright law introduced in 1991 that &quot;the copyright protection measures of folk literature and art works are separately stipulated by the State Council.&quot; But there is no following. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The most active Hu Tingjiang, northern Wu Yue, etc., turned the libraries of the Central Conservatory of Music, the Chinese Academy of Music and the China Institute of Music, and even Also find original information from the Moscow Library of Kazakhstan and the Moscow Library in Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After more than three years of searching and research, Wu Yue north now believes that he can complete the tasks that the teachers have not completed many years ago and put Wang Luobin down the altar . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At the end of September 2023, I met Wu Yue in a community near Wanshou Park, Beijing. He has a majestic national face, and he has a tired elegance when he walks. Beside a piano, he prepared a chair and a laptop for me, which contained evidence he collected. Earlier, he had to bring two things, a Bluetooth speaker, and a luggage full of physical evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This composer made me stare at the computer screen carefully. Then, he closed his eyes and repeated everything he had investigated in the past 4 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 15, 2023, Beijing, Wu Yue north shows the evidence he collected in the computer. Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/c8081ce523.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com// CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/19/C8081ce523.jpg &quot;Data-key =&quot; 258765 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; September 2023 On the 15th, Beijing, Wu Yue north showed the evidence he collected in the computer. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body style _GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Speaking of&quot; In the Far Place &quot;, the person they think of is Chen Tianhe. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On March 31, 1946, a student society named Shan Ge Club was announced at the National Music Institute of Qingmuguan in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Shange is the product of the student movement. Earlier, the authorities planned to cancel the subsidies of the student&#39;s consumption of coal and were opposed by the students. After the &quot;Coal Incident&quot;, students began to seek autonomy in a school in the subtropical canyon. At the same time, they couldn&#39;t wait to find some deeper things from the soil of folk songs from the soil of folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At that time, the situation was unknown, but this group of music students began to worry more eternal issues. In the first series of &quot;Chinese Folk Songs&quot; they printed, there is such a wish: &quot;After analyzing these folk songs, the problems that have not been paid attention to in Western composition can be produced. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; There was no way to pick the style at the time. According to a memories article by Xie Gongcheng, the first series of&quot; Chinese Folk Song &quot;was from&quot; New Music &quot; Magazine, Yan&#39;an&#39;s small singing book, Wang Luobin&#39;s &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; and private relationships, more than a hundred national songs collected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; was published in Chongqing in 1942. At the end of 1939, Wang Luobin gave the manuscript to the reporter Zhang Xiluo, a reporter from Chongqing in Xining to publish it, and Zhang Xiluo found the opportunity until he opened the Dagong Bookstore. The collection of the Capital Library shows that the song collection contains 17 songs, and there is no &quot;in the distant place&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; During the collection of &quot;Chinese Folk Songs&quot;, the students of the piano group were responsible for the accompaniment, and the vocal group was responsible for the singing. There are two teachers joining, namely the professor of the composer and the director of the teaching affairs, Chen Tianhe, and the professor and director of the composition department, Jiang Dingxian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; History has a bifurcation here. Although Volkswagen regards Wang Luobin as the benchmark of the western folk songs, the college faction has also paid attention to Wang Luobin, but in the music education of professional colleges, the history of the folk song system has begun to start with the &quot;folk song movement&quot; of the Shan Song Club. When it comes to &quot;Alamu Khan&quot;, they will think of Xie Gongcheng&#39;s four chorus adapted in 1945; when it comes to &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, he will think of Jiang Dingxian; and when it comes to the &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; of the Song King, The person they think of is Chen Tianhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There is only one reason. The accompaniment of this song popular version is equipped with Chen Tianhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Yuebei looks for clues from Wang Luobin&#39;s own words. &quot;People&#39;s Music&quot; magazine published an article &quot;History is fair&quot; written by Wang Luobin in 1994, which mentioned that &quot;in the distant place&quot; can allow his colleagues, a lady named Ug Huiying to testify as a testimony. &quot;It can not only prove that this song was written by me, but also proved that this song should have copyright.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Ugly Huiying at the time was the chairman of the Taipei Music Copyright Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Yuebei found the &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; compiled by Ugly Huiying in 1967. A total of 88 songs, 84 of which are edited by Ugly Huiying, and &quot;in the distant place&quot; is marked as Chen Tianhe arranged. Interestingly, the version of Chen Tianhe is currently a small version, and it is engraved with the tombstone of Wang Luobin, which is a big version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1994, Ugly Huiying presented a &quot;Selection of the Chinese National Ballad&quot; by her in 1982 by her in 1982. Nothing was marked with her name. As for &quot;In the Far&quot;, only &quot;Qinghai Folk Songs&quot; are written. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; These two versions seem to contradict each other. From the north of Wu Yue, two key issues are explained. First of all, there is no version of Wang Luobin published by Ug Huiying. Secondly, according to the analysis of Wu Yuebei, the reason why the second version has the names of ugly Huiying and Chen Tianhe, it is that the version of the &quot;removed &#39;part&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This is actually an old topic in the 1990s discussion. What exactly is the difference between &quot;adaptation, sorting&quot; and &quot;notes&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the north of Wu Yue, the arrangement is on the basis of the original work. It simplifies the complicated works by increasing or decreased and deleted. The work, plus his own play, becomes a readable vernacular work. The adaptation must be incremental, for example, a folk song is changed to a symphony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; And, folk songs have its particularity. The folk song is a song created by the public. The words and songs have been continuously polished and deformed by countless people. According to different times and place, different versions will be generated. Wu Yuebei also gives an example, &quot;You change the&quot; In front of the bed, the moonlight &quot;to the&quot; In front of the window, the moonlight &quot;, are you going to replace Li Bai?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He found a &quot;Selection of Chinese People&#39;s Songs&quot; published by Shan Ge Society in 1946, which selected a small version of &quot;In the Far Far&quot;, which stated that &quot;Chen Tianhe is accompanied by accompaniment&quot;. According to the survey of Wu Yue, a female student in Qinghai sang to Chen Tianhe in 1945, and the latter spent the piano song for this. Wang Luobin&#39;s version was officially published in 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;. Wang Luobin knew that the existence of a small version was also attached to the book, but he explained that this was the result of the female student who went to school in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In some circulating statements, the female student was Ugly Huiying, who graduated from Chongqing National Music Institute in 1947. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The memoir called &quot;Walking through the Memory Star&quot; also inadvertently mentioned Ugly Huiying and Wang Luobin. This book was written by Luo Wenzhi, the vice president of the former Ningxia Huangpu Military Academy Association, and wrote his son Luo Jiyuan in 2010. It is mentioned that in August 1993, Luo Wenzhi met with Tang Ying Ugly Huiying in Beijing. During the chat, Ug Huiying said that in 1993, Wang Luobin reunited with her in Taipei, and learned that she had spread her &quot;The Far Far&quot;, &quot;Youth Dance&quot; and &quot;Daban City Girl in Dazya City&quot; in Qinghai for many years. Folk songs are very emotional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Pearl on the crown&quot;. According to Liang Maochun, a professor at the Central Conservatory of Music, in 1940, a musical named &quot;Flower of the Desert&quot; was staged in Xining. The &quot;New Music&quot; magazine published in November 1942 reported the matter. The &quot;Songlin&quot; magazine published in December of the following year records the complete script and music of the play. In the preface of &quot;The Song of Desert&quot;, Wang Luobin mentioned that the episodes used in the play are all Kazakh people&#39;s songs, with new words. &quot;I Want to Be a Shepherd&quot;, which is the predecessor of &quot;The Far Far&quot;, appeared in the first act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; History meets the narrow road here, but as the parties leave the world one by one, some statements have been difficult to verify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2023, the opinion of the lawyer is that the signature on any or several &quot;earliest publications&quot; cannot prove that the signature is 80 80 Author of a certain song a year ago. He also made an example: &quot;A watch on a person&#39;s wrist, and life experience tells us that the person wearing a watch is the owner of the watch, and the person who does not need to wear a watch provides any other evidence to prove it. And their descendants have claimed their rights, exercise their rights, and defend their rights for songs such as &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, &quot;Four Seasons&quot;, &quot;Mayera&quot;. No one else has proposed rights proposal in the past 40 years. Anti-evidence. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; north of Wu Yue, why did the students of the music department that year become the main force of the altar of the king of La Ge more than 20 years later? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The reason is that his understanding of Wang Luobin has begun since the 1980s. In the 1990s, many friends and teachers, including Dai Penghai and Xie Gong, had participated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; One more important reason may be that Wu Yuebei is responsible for a national folk song inheritance project. Wang Haicheng&#39;s prosecution will make him unusual difficult. Do you want to include folk songs related to Wang Luobin? Will there be legal risks after inclusion? What should I do if similar people come out? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Not long ago, some editors asked Li Yan and wanted to use western folk songs to deal with it? &quot;I suggest him that the case has not been finalized yet, so you don&#39;t need it.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;The 1947&quot; Chinese Song Selected &quot;by Hu Tingjiang, of which&quot; Kangding Love Song &quot;signed&quot; Jiang Dingxian &quot;(Jiang Dingxian&quot;. Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/34df94a31a.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/34df94a31a.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 258766 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The 1947 version of&quot; Selected Chinese Songs &quot;found by Hu Tingjiang, of which&quot; Kangding Love Song &quot;signed&quot; Jiang Dingxian &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Smoke disappear &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Initially, it was their fall, and then the fans were old. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At least one thing, Wu Yuebei and Wang Haicheng have a rare consensus. They all found that society pays attention to new series of lawsuits. Not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Until today, there are still Wang Luobin&#39;s memorials in Pakistan, Hubei, Baishui Ancient Town, and Urumqi. Member of the CPPCC also hopes that all children in Puzhou will sing Wang Luobin&#39;s song. In early September 2023, at a lecture at the Three Gorges University, Wu Yuebei mentioned this protracted copyright dispute, but the audience at the scene did not know who Wang Luobin was except the teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Today, the person who knows the western song king most lives in a 26-storey commercial house in the north of Lazhou. This is a residence purchased after Wang Haicheng was moved by the enthusiasm of Lizhou officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Most of the time, Wang Haicheng is a long-awaited and strictly restricted old man. Once, he took me to the old factory in Puzhou to check the construction progress of the Wang Luobin Music Art Museum. He indirectly reached a call, and the other party wanted to buy Wang Luobin&#39;s manuscript. He was full of &quot;good&quot;, hung up the phone, and made a look at me. &quot;I asked others to know that Wang Luobin&#39;s son sells manuscripts, which is incredible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is easy to be excited, especially when it comes to these difficult and from the academic opponent, he will doubt the motivation of the opponent and admire their cunning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is difficult to confirm whether Wang Haicheng understands these complaints from the professional music circle. In this commercial house, he continued to move out of his published Wang Luobin&#39;s work and several thick Xinjiang folk songs, and repeatedly emphasized that the change of a note and a word is the result of his father&#39;s exhaustion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Uyghur is a multi-syllable, Chinese is a single syllable, and the Han people say that good is &#39;good&#39;, Uyghur said that a good one is&quot; To sing the Chinese folk songs in Chinese, it must be a big surgery for it. &quot;Wang Haicheng can also give more examples. For example,&quot; Alamu Khan &quot;is adapted to the Children&#39;s Troupe of Qinghai, so it has been added for half a rest, which is convenient for convenience Children breathe when singing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The 72-year-old man still needs to answer the &quot;love&quot; between his father and Sanmao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;I have seen it, eating at my house, my wife gave Sanmao noodles, eaten two meals, and told me to talk to me when I have come, I have been here for several days. Today this day is the most comfortable &#39;. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>;&quot; I understand her, there is a kind of &quot; Feeling, she wants to integrate into her home, and she wants to live with my father. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Once valid. His &quot;My Father Wang Luobin&quot; Douban score is 7.9, and many people have burst into tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the Library of Laizhou, the photos of Sanmao were placed on a desk that was used by Wang Luobin, which was moved from Xinjiang. Wrapped wrapped, Wang Haicheng said that all of this was arranged according to Wang Luobin&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But in the photos of Wang Luobin and desk he showed afterwards, there were no three-hairy photo on the table. He also explained that the photo was actually placed on the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Now, some stories are invalid. The Tianjin High Court determined that the &quot;Mayera&quot; adapted from Hu Tingjiang was not infringed; during the trial of Hu Tingjiang&#39;s version of &quot;Youth Dance&quot; case, the Hubei High Court directly stated in a 34 -page judgment: If Wang Haicheng and others have the demands of rights, then then It is tantamount to &quot;belonging to the right of primitive folk songs.&quot; The Hubei High Court also ordered a series of &quot;risks&quot; after litigation: Once supported rights protection, Wang Haicheng and others can be based on Wang Luobin&#39;s first work, and arbitrarily initiate lawsuits in other homologous works in the subsequent subsequent. This is undoubtedly &quot;harmful to the right to the original folk song.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another reason is that the world left by his father, Wang Haicheng spent half a lifetime and continued to construct. Those who accused Wang Luobin of no copyright may disappear all this smoke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is the child who has won Wang Luobin from the three brothers. So far, he will play the piano every day and play with the guitar. If anyone says he and Wang Luobin are very Like, he will show a sincere smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin did have a dream to let his songs sing for 500 years. So far, the longest Chinese songs are said to be &quot;Jasmine&quot;, which has been circulating for nearly 400 years. In 1794, I finally met the Macanloni Mission of the Emperor Qianlong, ready to return to Britain from Guangzhou. Here, the group secretary John Baro heard the Guangzhou dialect version of &quot;Jasmine&quot;. He was in &quot;China Travel&quot; The song was recorded with Roman Pinyin and translated lyrics, becoming the earliest record in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, who is pushing the eternal universe of the western song king and let it slide into the abyss of forgotten? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Perhaps, all this has nothing to do with the law. All cultural idols will disappear in time. At first, it was their fall, and then the fans were old. Idols may be mentioned briefly at a certain moment and a certain period -but this is only accidental. In the end, they will sink into the long fog again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; How many people remember, this year is the 80th anniversary of the birthday of Sanmao? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 10, 2023, Hebei Library Library, Sanmao&#39;s photos are placed on the right desk, Wang Haicheng is playing&quot; Youth Dance &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/ Figure) &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dbb29400.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dbb29400.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258767&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style: #999999; text- Align: Center; &quot;>; September 10, 2023, Hebei Library Library, Sanmao&#39;s photos are placed on the right desk, Wang Haicheng is playing&quot; Youth Dance &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; What is it if it is not a folk song? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; After many inquiries, he finally found &quot;Dada and He The author of Maria and &quot;Marray&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A sunny and kind Beijing autumn afternoon in the afternoon, I saw Du Yaxiong, who edited 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;. He is now Chinese music. Professor of the Department of Music of the College. He just discharged from the hospital, his face was rosy, his hair was silver, and he often made a strong laughter. In the afternoon of the same day, a male tweeter came to visit and heard about Wang Luobin. He talked: &quot;Wang Luobin&#39;s songs dare not touch, and we (units) have also defended.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left ; &quot;>; In the summer of 1982, Du Yaxiong was still a young man. He lived in Wang Luobin&#39;s house to help him organize the score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Recalling the summer of forty years ago, Du Yaxiong has a feeling of vagueness. Wang Luobin did not understand the origin of his song. &quot;After all, he is not engaged in us. This major (ethnic music), we know whether a song belongs to a folk song or a song, which is very clear. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; National music began in 1959. Dutch musicians, who have been dispatched by Java for 15 years, renamed the 3rd edition of his book &quot;Music&quot; to &quot;National Music Science&quot;, which created this discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin told Du Yaxiong that the song &quot;Dadal and Maria&quot; was sang by a Kazakh old lady in Xining, Qinghai around 1940. Including &quot;Maura&quot;, Wang Luobin believes that these are folk songs, but Du Yaxiong does not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;People who have studied Kazakhson folk songs can be seen that these are not folk songs. Why? Kazakh folk songs have specific rhythm, a song divides the main song and chorus song In the two parts, the lyrics of the main song must be 11 syllables, their combinations can be 344, 443, 434. Each combination is a sound step. &quot;Du Yaxiong said,&quot; There is still a rule, that is, the combination The lyrics and songs are consistent, and a phrase of the Kazakh folk song has ended, but the word has not been sang, and the last voice of the first sentence should be placed in the second music. The first sound of the last lyrics in the last music festival. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Du Yaxiong speculates that this way of presenting this music is likely to come from the daily life of the Kazakh people. Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There is a swap mechanism for nomadic peoples. Young people will not stay in the tent and go sheep. , Riding the horse, 200 meters away from the tent, first &#39;ah 呺 —&#39; shouting, someone in the tent, he will come out to tie the dog, and use &quot;Ah 呺 —&quot; to respond to you. &quot;This Scholars who studied the history of music have added a naughty supplement, &quot;but I am not necessarily right.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; What if it is not a folk song? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Du Yaxiong understands Kazakh. After inquiring from many parties, he finally found the author of &quot;Da Dar and Maria&quot; and &quot;May&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The author of the first song is Mary Jagel (1887-1950), born in Acko Mora, Kazakhstan, is Kazakhstan. Stan people artist. Du Yaxiong inferred that she created the song around 1903. This song has been widely circulated in Kazakhstan, once the theme of many music works. Judging from Wang Luobin&#39;s record, at the latest in the early 1930s, this song was introduced to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The author of the second song is Marrara Shammustinovova (1890-1927), Professor Ah Hedi, Aramutu Conservatory of Music McDIS Jubanov introduced this person in the book &quot;The Nightingale of the Times&quot; and said that the song was the author&#39;s &quot;self -portrait&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Du Yaxiong also verified &quot;Girl in Daban City&quot;. Cut the rhythm. He was curious why Wang Luobin&#39;s version was not like this. Wang Luobin&#39;s saying was that the driver he heard was singing -not Wang Haicheng said, but the active version of the version suitable for the Han people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Regarding &quot;Youth Dance&quot;, Wang Luobin told Du Yaxiong: &quot;It was recorded in Jiuquan Dongguan in 1939. The lyrics were original, not me. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; As for the&quot; pearl on the crown &quot;, Du Yaxiong does not think that the popular version is the result of&quot; tuning &quot;, but a version of the male cavity, using&quot; Anti -tuning &quot;method creates a female cavity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Therefore, in the 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;, Du Yaxiong divided the songs into two parts, the first part was the folk song, the second part was Wang Luobin&#39;s of Creation, and these songs are in the first part. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, Du Yaxiong also affirmed the contribution of Wang Luobin&#39;s translation of ethnic minorities. Translated into Chinese, it is too difficult, translation is to see Yada. Of course, some things are not right with the original, he is a half -compiled and half translation. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, Wang Haicheng still won part of the victory in the final judgment of the Beijing Intellectual Property Court. The court determined that Wang Luobin and his descendants continued to enjoy the copyright of &quot;Daban City Girl&quot;, &quot;Da Dar and Maria&quot;, &quot;Mayra&quot;, and &quot;in that distant place&quot;; for &quot;Youth Dance&quot;, he enjoys lyrics copyright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But Wang Haicheng still determined that someone is accelerating the disappearance. Not long ago, when Beijing Normal University produced the musical &quot;The Ballad of the Past&quot;, some people proposed that &quot;in the distant place&quot; may be controversial. The school conveyed was reported by a lawyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The lawyer&#39;s name is Dong Xiaoyue, the granddaughter of Chen Tianhe. She also has a persistent life. When holding a chorus competition in high school, some students mentioned that &quot;in the distant place&quot; belongs to Wang Luobin, and she will scratch others. Chen Tianhe died in 1955. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Dong Xiaoyue after the 80s became a reporter and book editor, but from time to time, she held her. Around 2010, she began to find the &quot;Selection of Chinese Songs&quot; from the major libraries in Beijing. The earliest version of this book has only two volumes in China. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is like the result of a period of life, Dong Xiaoyue became a lawyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Someone once asked her to charge the copyright fee. She replied in a letter: &quot;It should not be entangled in the copyright dispute, let everything follow the wind. The problem of music does not need to be given to the law. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; The young Wang Luobin more than 80 years ago would not expect that the copyright and origin of a song will be far away. It will become so important in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1935, at the age of 22, he worked as a music teacher at a middle school outside Beijing&#39;s Xizhimen. There is a river nearby. At noon in the summer, he ran to the river to swim, and there were many college students who moved after the fall of the Northeast.一天，光着屁股、一身泥的众人在听同学念《八月的乡村》，这本小说描写的是“九一八”事变后，东北军民同日本侵略者奋战的故事。当念到一首名叫《我要恋爱，我也要祖国的自由》的诗时，满怀激情的王洛宾穿起衣服，把诗抄下来，回家谱曲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来，一位青年找来，说他歌写得好，唱得也好，但知不知道小说作者是谁。王洛宾窘了，回答不知道。青年大笑，说，“作者是萧军，我就是萧军”。王洛宾回忆道：“我大吃一惊，于是我们两人拥抱，开怀大笑，就这样做了朋友了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生黄晓颖对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月10日，河北涿州，王洛宾故居纪念馆。（南方周末记者苏有鹏/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/fcb1a38e23.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/fcb1a38e23.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258768&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月10日，河北涿州，王洛宾故居纪念馆。 （南方周末记者苏有鹏/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;王洛宾年谱&lt;/h5>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1913年，出生于北京。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1931年，进入国立北平师范大学音乐系学习。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1937年，抗日战争全面爆发，前往山西参加八路军西北战地服务团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1940年，在青海西宁担任音乐教育工作，负责组建青海儿童抗战剧团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1949年，参加中国人民解放军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1952年-1976年，多次入狱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1981年，平反恢复名誉和军籍，任新疆军区文工团艺术顾问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1991年，享受政府特殊津贴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1994年，被联合国教科文组织授予东西方文化交流特别贡献奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1996年，因患胆囊腺癌医治无效去世，享年83岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“4个月挣250元”，去横店当“童漂”值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260937]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 12:25:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/26999ccfcca7220487e539964eb758de.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/26999ccfcca7220487e539964eb758de. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, many parents are now taking their children to work as &quot;child slaves&quot; in Hengdian, looking for opportunities to star in film and television dramas. The life of &quot;child drifters&quot; is also very bitter. &quot;100 people fight for one seat&quot;, &quot;earn 250 yuan in 4 months&quot;, and &quot;pay a large amount of money to join the group&quot; are the norm for many &quot;child drifters&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media statistics, among the films, online dramas, TV series and other film and television cultural works filmed in Hengdian in 2022, 230 will have underage entertainers participating, with more than 6,000 people participating. This number is not small, and it is also the reason why &quot;child drifting&quot; exists - Hengdian does provide opportunities to act and become famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，随着各路怀抱梦想的儿童及其家庭的涌入，“童漂”迅速变得内卷。 The &quot;child drifting&quot; industry can no longer be said to be a pure dream-chasing story, but has evolved into a bizarre capital game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;With 20,000 yuan in 1 year, you are guaranteed to be in at least 3 plays within 1 year, and you can appear as special actors, etc.. With 50,000 in 3 years, you are guaranteed to be in at least 8 plays in 3 years, and you can be in special actors and roles, etc.&quot; , this is the charging model of several children&#39;s agency companies in Hengdian reported in the media. According to the payment amount, they are divided into various levels of &quot;members&quot; and then equipped with corresponding resources. Obviously, for families who lack economic foundation, &quot;child drifting&quot; is already very cruel, and the return rate is extremely low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another problem with &quot;child drifting&quot; is that the main subjects of pursuing dreams are children. If they are in an unstable situation, what about education? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Compulsory Education Law stipulates that parents or other legal guardians of school-age children and teenagers shall ensure that they enter school on time, accept and complete compulsory education in accordance with the law. If parents let their children leave school early for the dream of being a child star, it is already suspected of breaking the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if a child successfully completes compulsory education, the basic education is too weak, and the impact may be lifelong. The cost of &quot;child drift&quot; is too huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, parents should have a more rational and comprehensive assessment of the risks of child abuse. After all, there is huge uncertainty in &quot;what you do is what you want&quot;. Is it wise for a family to risk everything for an opportunity with a very low probability? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, children do not yet have full capacity for civil conduct, and they do not actually have a complete and clear understanding of the nature of their own behavior. Many children do like acting, but they lack awareness of &quot;sunk costs&quot; - once their acting career is blocked, how can children return to their regular growth path? Children are ignorant of this, and parents who lack prudence are undoubtedly irresponsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is no need for public opinion to make excessive criticism of &quot;child drifters&quot; and their families. Some common criticisms on the Internet, such as &quot;using children as money-making tools&quot; and &quot;parents have dreams of getting rich&quot;, are not necessarily accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the interviews that many parents just want to try their best to help their children realize their dreams because their children want to act. They are not necessarily profit-driven parents. This is essentially the same as asking their children to &quot;attend a prestigious school&quot;. They have both chosen a very involutive path with uncertain prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在规劝家长保持审慎的同时，社会也应当有所干预。 For example, whether those entertainment agencies are formal or not should actually attract the attention of relevant departments. Some parents reported that &quot;bringing money to join the group&quot; was suspected of being defrauded. After paying the money, not only did they have nothing to do, but they were also &quot;blacklisted&quot; by the person involved. For these, the market supervision department should follow relevant clues to investigate whether there are any violations of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A red line that cannot be blurred is: no matter what growth path a family chooses for their children, education must be compulsorily implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In any case, the bitterness of Hengdian&#39;s &quot;child drifting&quot; is, after all, an unspeakable involution. The journey of chasing dreams is of course full of hardships, but this path does not seem to fit in with a simple narrative of children’s growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of this, parents still need to carefully consider whether &quot;child drifting&quot; is suitable for their family situations; and society should obviously work hard to eliminate the risks and hazards involved, protect the rights of minors, and at least allow them to There are fewer pitfalls on the road to &quot;Tongpiao&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[假如我变成了“熊孩子”丨世界儿童日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260935]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉罪的“豆芽”：网售体彩242亿元被控非法经营]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260927]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On August 3, 2022, Hohhot, passengers on the China Sports Lottery &quot;Lucky Train&quot; Photos taken on the theme train. (People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d59a5b48fe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d59a5b48fe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258819&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 3, 2022, Hohhot, passengers took photos on the China Sports Lottery &quot;Lucky Train&quot; themed train. (People’s Vision/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The online platform is no longer available?&quot; On November 15, 2023, Wu Yong, the owner of a sports lottery shop in Changxing County, Zhejiang Province, Another inquiry from a regular customer popped up on WeChat. He receives similar messages almost every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yong operates 5 sports betting shops in the county. He was once the owner of the national outstanding sports betting outlets selected by the Sports Lottery Management Center of the State Sports General Administration. But now, he is planning to transfer three of the stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On February 16, 2023, Wu Yong was detained by the Public Security Bureau of Jishui County, Jiangxi Province on suspicion of illegal business operations. He was released on bail after &quot;returning the stolen goods&quot; of 1.2 million yuan. Awaiting trial. The Jishui County Procuratorate determined that from 2019 to 2023, Wu Yong sold 127 million yuan in sports betting through the &quot;Douya&quot; App, making illegal profits of more than 8.1 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“豆芽”App的运营模式是，彩民线上下单，店主收到通知后，在线下彩票实体店出票。 App operators make money by collecting a 1% handling fee from store owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the indictment, there are nearly 14,000 lottery agency stores registered in Douya, with more than 2.71 million lottery players. From 2019 to 2023, the total number of lottery tickets sold through &quot;Douzhao&quot; was approximately 24.2 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从时间上看，吴勇等人被指控的行为主要发生在2015年国家对网售彩票清理整顿之后，8年来，财政部没再Open authorization for online lottery sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the criminal law, one condition that constitutes the crime of illegal business is violation of &quot;national regulations.&quot; However, the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; formulated by the State Council in 2009 do not provide for the sale of lottery tickets through the Internet. Relevant regulations are formulated by the Ministry of Finance and other relevant ministries and commissions. During the trial of this case, the focus of dispute between the prosecution and the defense was whether Wu Yong and others violated &quot;national regulations&quot; by selling lottery tickets through the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Ban&quot; brings dividends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yong&#39;s lottery The store business started ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2013, the year before the World Cup in Brazil, Wu Yong, a fan, rented a storefront in the business district of Changxing County and ran his first sports betting shop. Open. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, many leading Internet companies launched online lottery sales businesses on their respective platforms, and the business of offline lottery stores was not booming. According to Wu Yong, online lottery sales services have attracted a large number of young people. Before the start of the World Cup, the business of his lottery shop &quot;basically only returned the money&quot;, and most of the customers were acquaintances who watched the football with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After reviewing relevant public information, the Ministry of Finance has not publicly disclosed the size of the Internet lottery market. One data for reference is the &quot;2014 Internet Lottery Market Analysis Report&quot; released by Pantone Consulting, an organization that has long tracked the lottery market. It shows that in that year, China&#39;s Internet lottery sales reached 85 billion, doubling the sales volume in 2013. The market share exceeded 20% for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the hot Internet lottery market was quickly cooled by policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On January 15, 2015, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the State Sports General Administration jointly issued the &quot;Self-examination and self-correction work on unauthorized use of the Internet to sell lottery tickets&quot; Notice on Problems&quot;. At the end of February, several Internet platforms including Alibaba, Tencent, NetEase, Sina, and People&#39;s Daily announced they would stop selling lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unexpectedly and unexpectedly, Wu Yong enjoyed multiple dividends brought by the &quot;ban&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lottery players who were originally attracted by the Internet platform began to patronize his lottery shop. From time to time, people ask him that buying lottery tickets offline is too troublesome. Is there any way to buy lottery tickets online? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While communicating with colleagues, Wu Yong learned about the application &quot;87 Caidian&quot; (the predecessor of &quot;Douzha&quot;). He found the company&#39;s phone number online and called to inquire. Afterwards, the company&#39;s sales staff contacted him and asked him to provide store photos, sales certificates, bank cards, ID cards and other qualifications for verification. After passing the approval, Wu Yong&#39;s online lottery business started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After lottery players download the App through the lottery store promotion code shared by Wu Yong, the purchased lottery tickets can only be issued from Wu Yong’s store. Since 2015, online sales have accounted for nearly half of Wu Yong’s total store sales. The subsequent COVID-19 outbreak has further accelerated the development of Wu Yong’s online business. “Almost 70% to 80% of lottery tickets sold through the App will be sold,” he estimated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021 is Wu Yong’s best year, with online lottery sales reaching more than 40 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Football matches are mostly concentrated in the evening, and lottery players buy tickets half an hour before the game starts. An offline sports lottery store generally only has one terminal ticket issuing machine. When business is booming, the ticket issuing speed cannot keep up. Starting in 2018, Wu Yong successively applied for four sports lottery agency stores as a clerk or relative to absorb more orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While using &quot;Bean Sprout&quot;, Wu Yong noticed that some store owners were notified by the local sports lottery management center because of their use of this app, and their store sales permissions were suspended. In his store, there are also posters issued by the county sports lottery center prohibiting online lottery sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But he &quot;didn&#39;t take it seriously.&quot; After all, it would be difficult to even recoup the capital by relying on scattered customers in physical stores. “To survive, it is impossible not to use online channels.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the case that at least 62 lottery shop owners who have used &quot;bean sprouts&quot; are currently under investigation by the Jishui County Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to two shop owners who have been sued to court by the procuratorate, Southern Weekend reporters confirmed with the other six shop owners involved in the case that they were involved in the case between February and June 2023. He was successively released on bail by the Jishui County Public Security Bureau on suspicion of illegal business crimes, and is still under investigation by the public security organs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;These six people expressed similar thoughts to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Everyone is doing this. If you don&#39;t do it, won&#39;t you lose money?&quot; said a shop owner. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fluctuating policies&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He and Wu Yong were prosecuted by the Procuratorate There is also another lottery shop owner, as well as Wang Lingfeng, the actual controller of Beijing Chun Xinya Technology Co., Ltd., the operating company of &quot;Bean Sprout&quot;, and 6 employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Lingfeng entered the Internet lottery industry at the end of 2014. According to what he told Southern Weekend reporters, he entered the industry at the suggestion of the leader of a sports lottery management center in a certain province in East China. Since then, he has been invited by sports lottery centers in many places to provide training to shop owners, &quot;How to use &#39;Internet +&#39; thinking.&quot; Selling lottery tickets&#39;&quot;. However, Southern Weekend reporters were unable to verify this with the sports betting agency he mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2016, Wang Lingfeng mentioned in an interview with &quot;Sina Pantone&quot; that before the policy banning the sale of Internet lottery tickets was introduced in early 2015, the company had begun to cooperate with many places. The sports lottery center discussed cooperation. The center recognized their model and was willing to promote it to shop owners. After the ban was issued, all negotiations stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To his surprise, many lottery shop owners took the initiative to find the company. &quot;At that time, I really felt that they were almost finished, but they actually survived.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那次采访中，王岭峰谈到，创业中面临的最大困难，“还是政策”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Internet lottery system has experienced a process from tightening to relaxing and then tightening. In China, the only legal lotteries are sports lotteries and welfare lotteries licensed by the State Council. The Ministry of Civil Affairs and the State Sports General Administration are responsible for the management of national welfare lottery and sports lottery respectively, while the Ministry of Finance is responsible for the supervision and management of lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In December 2007, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Issues Concerning the Use of the Internet to Sell Lottery Lottery by Lottery Agencies&quot;, mentioning We must stop using the Internet to sell lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in 2010, the Ministry of Finance issued the &quot;Interim Measures for the Administration of Lottery Sales on the Internet&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Interim Measures&quot;), pointing out that it is necessary to promptly select companies with Interim Measures Units with specified conditions and good management foundation shall submit to the Ministry of Finance for approval before launching pilot projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;暂行办法中还强调，未经批准，任何单位不得利用互联网销售彩票。 However, this document is still interpreted by the industry as a positive signal, which means that the online lottery sales model, which was previously in a gray area, is expected to be legalized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With no organization approved by the Ministry of Finance, the Internet lottery industry has developed rapidly. Portals such as Sina and NetEase and e-commerce platforms such as Taobao, JD.com and Dangdang have all launched lottery services. According to Pantone Consulting statistics, in 2011, China’s Internet lottery sales exceeded the 10 billion yuan mark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2012, the pilot online lottery sale was launched. The Ministry of Finance agreed with the Sports Lottery Management Center of the State Sports General Administration to entrust China Sports Lottery Network and 500 Lottery Network to carry out online sports betting business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2015, the policy gradually tightened, and relevant departments issued the aforementioned ban on online lottery sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On April 28, 2016, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Public Security, the former State Administration for Industry and Commerce, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration jointly issued a document pointing out that since 2015, The clean-up and rectification of online lottery sales has achieved initial results, but in some areas there are still problems with orders and prohibitions. The document once again emphasizes that lottery issuance and sales agencies and their agents are strictly prohibited from selling lottery tickets online without authorization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, a survey released by CCTV in April 2018 showed that there are still more than 300 lottery websites in operation, with the annual lottery sales amount not less than 1,000 billion. During the start of the World Cup in Russia that year, multiple lottery apps appeared at the top of the download rankings of mobile application malls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Four months later, on August 21, 2018, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration jointly organized 12 ministries and commissions including the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, and the Ministry of Public Security. An announcement was issued to resolutely prohibit unauthorized online lottery sales, and pointed out that the Ministry of Finance has not approved any lottery agency to open this business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;13 days later, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration issued another decision on amending the &quot;Implementation Rules of the Lottery Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Unauthorized use of the benefits of Internet sales Lottery and sports lottery&quot; are included in the list of &quot;illegal lotteries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 3, 2023, the sports lottery exhibition in the sports service exhibition area of ​​the Beijing Service Trade Fair. (People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/19/774ebd3c4a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/19/774ebd3c4a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258820&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 3, 2023, Beijing Service Trade Sports Lottery Exhibition in the Sports Services Exhibition Area. (People’s Vision/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;National Regulations&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;After the policy was tightened in 2015, the Ministry of Finance no longer authorized the sale of lottery tickets on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration can only supervise provincial and municipal lottery distribution centers and agents. Su Guojing, founder of the China Lottery Industry Salon, believes that if online sales of lottery tickets are allowed, once &quot;ticket stealing&quot; and various disputes arise on the online platforms of non-lottery institutions, how and who will supervise them will become a big problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;ticket eating&quot; means that lottery players buy lottery tickets online, but the platform or agent does not actually issue the tickets, but directly pockets the ticket money. If a lottery player wins a small prize, they can cash it in directly. If a lottery player wins a large prize, the platform or the agent cannot pay the fee, and the site may be closed or run away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Procuratorial Daily&quot; reported a case of &quot;ticket eating&quot;. Sun, the owner of a lottery shop in Shanghai, used the Internet to sell lottery tickets 508 from February to April 2019. Ten thousand yuan, the actual ticket issued was 4.43 million yuan, and the ticket consumption was more than 600,000 yuan. In 2020, the Shanghai Qingpu District Court sentenced Sun to 6 years and 6 months in prison for illegal business operations and fined him 600,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On Douya, every few months, Wu Yong will be asked by customer service to randomly check the actual ticket issuance status. Customer service randomly selects 10 orders. Wu Yong needs to find the corresponding physical tickets, take photos and send them to customer service for review. Wu Yong said that for lottery players’ online orders, he actually issues all tickets offline. The indictment also did not mention his behavior of &quot;eating votes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, there will still be &quot;fish that slip through the net&quot; on the platform. A Hunan sports lottery shop owner who was prosecuted by the Jishui County Procuratorate along with Wu Yong was accused of &quot;eating tickets.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the indictment, from January 2019 to the end of 2021, he used the &quot;Yuncaidian&quot; App (also the predecessor of &quot;Douzha&quot;) to sell 148 million lottery tickets. Yuan, the amount of &quot;ticket eating&quot; was more than 64 million yuan, and the illegal profit was more than 3.27 million yuan. In an interview with Southern Weekend, the shop owner said that he had indeed engaged in the behavior of &quot;eating tickets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unlike those who &quot;eat tickets&quot;, lottery shop owners such as Wu Yong sell lottery tickets through apps, but issue tickets offline. Are they also suspected of illegal operations? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In January 2022, the Xiushui County Court in Jiangxi Province issued a judgment on a similar case (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Xiushui Case&quot;). Southern Weekend reporters learned from the defense lawyer of one of the defendants in the case that in this case, neither the lottery app nor the owner of the lottery shop withheld money from the tickets but did not issue them or &quot;eat the tickets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Xiushui County Court finally determined that the person in charge of the lottery selling app and several lottery shop owners who cooperated with the app were guilty of illegal business operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The basis of the court&#39;s decision is that the &quot;Implementation Rules of the Lottery Management Regulations&quot; stipulate that lottery tickets sold on the Internet without authorization belong to the category of illegal lottery tickets. In addition, the App also set up copying and syndicated buying programs with a gambling nature, etc., which changed the rules for lottery sales and prize redemption. &quot;The sales amount was extremely huge and the circumstances were extremely serious, disrupting the order of the lottery market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 225 of the Criminal Law defines the crime of illegal business as violating national regulations, operating specialty items stipulated in laws and regulations without permission, or otherwise disrupting market order. illegal business practices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the defendant appealed, the court of second instance upheld the original verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The lawyer in the Xiushui case told Southern Weekend reporters that during the court session, one of the key points in the confrontation between the prosecution and the defense was, what are &quot;national regulations&quot;? As well as the relevant documents prohibiting online lottery sales without approval, are they considered &quot;national regulations&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 9 and 10, 2023, the first instance of the illegal business case involving Wang Lingfeng, Wu Yong and other nine people was held in the Jishui County Court of Jiangxi Province. The above issues were also heard in court. in focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 96 of the Criminal Law explains &quot;violating state regulations&quot; as violating the laws and decisions formulated by the National People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee, and the administrative regulations formulated by the State Council. Regulations, prescribed administrative measures, issued decisions and orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yong’s defense lawyer and associate professor at the University of International Business and Economics Zheng Haiping pointed out in court that the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; were formulated by the State Council and fell into the category of &quot;national regulations.&quot; However, the &quot;Regulations&quot; only prohibit the &quot;unauthorized issuance and sale of lottery tickets&quot; and do not explicitly prohibit the use of the Internet to sell lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prohibitive regulations on the use of the Internet to sell lottery tickets mainly appear in the &quot;Implementation Rules of the Lottery Management Regulations&quot; and the &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Internet Lottery&quot;. However, the former is formulated by the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration, while the latter is issued by the Ministry of Finance. From a legal perspective, they are only departmental regulations and shall not be deemed as &quot;violating national regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At present, the Jishui County Court has not made a first-instance judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The distribution pattern may be broken&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Bean Sprout Case&quot; The other six shop owners who have not yet been charged are also waiting for the verdict. They opened offline lottery shops in Fujian, Shandong, Jiangsu and other places. They all claimed that they did not &quot;eat tickets&quot;. After paying &quot;illegal gains&quot; ranging from hundreds of thousands to millions, they were released on bail pending trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;代理了修水县法院审理的非法经营案后，前述代理修水案的律师又陆续接到了近十件类似案件当事人的咨询， &quot;More than 80% of cases are filed and investigated by the public security organs of Jiangxi Province.&quot; This means that lottery shop owners who use online sales are facing the risk of criminal offenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Despite the risks, it is not uncommon for stores to sell lottery tickets through online channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters randomly called 10 sports lottery stores in Beijing and asked as lottery players whether they could buy lottery tickets online. Eight lottery stores stated that they can add WeChat and purchase online, and two of them sent App download links for online sports lottery purchases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As far as the attitude of the regulatory authorities is concerned, the characterization of purchasing lottery tickets through the App is different from that of letting store owners purchase lottery tickets through WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the sports lottery management centers in Beijing, Zhejiang, Hunan and other places that purchasing lottery tickets through Apps is explicitly prohibited, but purchasing lottery tickets by adding the store owner’s WeChat account Whether it is a violation or not has not yet been clearly defined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Huzhou Sports Lottery Center in Zhejiang Province, where Wu Yong is located, believes that buying lottery tickets on WeChat is an online lottery behavior and &quot;is not as serious as illegal, but we do not advocate it.&quot; The Changsha Sports Lottery Center stated that if any lottery shop owners are found to be selling lottery tickets through WeChat channels, they “may be punished by withdrawing their tickets.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Why is it so difficult for online lottery sales to be loosened? Su Guojing told Southern Weekend reporters that in China, the public welfare nature of lottery is emphasized while its gambling attribute is weakened. Internet platforms provide more convenient sales channels and payment methods than offline purchases, but they may cause lottery players to become addicted and make it more difficult to control minors’ lottery purchases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Haiping, associate professor at the School of Psychology at Beijing Normal University and former deputy director of the China Lottery Research Center, said that another problem caused by Internet lottery sales is that the original The distribution pattern of public welfare funds has been broken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lottery funds are divided into three parts: bonuses, issuance fees and public welfare funds. According to regulations of the Ministry of Finance, half of the lottery public welfare funds in each province are turned over to the central finance, and the other half is retained in the provincial finance. The Internet sales of lottery tickets break geographical restrictions. In provinces with developed Internet economies, sales will increase and more public welfare funds will be retained in local finances. Provinces dominated by offline sales will inevitably lead to a decrease in public welfare funds. This can easily lead to unhealthy competition in lottery sales among provinces, which will not only break the original pattern of raising and distributing public welfare funds and create new inequality between rich and poor, but also lead to various market chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Su Guojing&#39;s view, if the lottery industry does not introduce higher-level laws and &quot;if the responsibilities and rights in Internet sales are not clarified, the problem cannot be completely solved.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[去扬州看东坡：到心仪之地，施仁爱之方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There are many thoughts and memories in Pingshan Hall&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Yangzhou once had a dense population of outstanding figures from all dynasties, and its winding flower paths are layer upon layer filled with cultural gold dust. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Overlooking the Slender West Lake from the Qiling Pagoda of Daming Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Exiting the North Gate of Slender West Lake, across the road is the Daming Temple. Entering the slope of the scenic spot, the &quot;Qiling Ruins&quot; archway appears in front of you, with four pillars and three couplets, and double eaves and tile ridges. There is a stone plaque embedded in the wall on the east side of the courtyard. The big red characters &quot;The No. 1 View in Huaidong&quot; are very eye-catching. They come from Qin Guan&#39;s &quot;Pingshan Hall&quot; written by Ci Yunzi: &quot;If a tourist talks about the beauty of climbing, he must write &quot;The No. 1 View in Huaidong&quot;. Take a look.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After passing the Tianwang Hall of Daming Temple, there is an octagonal doorway on the west side, passing through it is Pingshan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In front of Pingshan Hall is a wooden flower gallery. The old wisteria planted on both sides are circling and twining. The dense branches and leaves and blooming wisteria flowers sprinkle the ground with coolness. I suddenly remembered the &quot;weeping willow in front of the hall&quot; and exited the flower gallery first. There are wintersweet, viburnum, boxwood, crape myrtle, etc. planted around. The leaves of magnolia are lush and moist. The tree is seven or eight meters high. It should be very gorgeous when in full bloom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a milky white stone on the grass on the south side of the vestibule, with the word &quot;European Willow&quot; written in big green characters on it. It is indeed there. Below is Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;Chaozhongcuo&quot;: &quot;The sill of the flat mountain leans against the clear sky, and the mountain scenery is blurred. Weeping willows are planted in front of the hall, and there are few spring breezes...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first year of Renzong Jiayou&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1056)&lt;/span>;, my friend Liu Chang was going to be appointed as the magistrate of Yangzhou. Ouyang Xiuwei gave this poem as a farewell farewell. It has been several years since he was transferred from Yangzhou, and he still misses the Pingshan Hall where he once visited. There is a hint of melancholy about the passage of time in the words, but the tone is broad-minded and clear, without any sense of decadence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四处张望，却不见柳树踪影，有点奇怪，继续搜寻。 It turned out that it was right next to the stone, low, young, and leaning as if it was about to lie down. It was a tamarisk tree. The leaves are short and stubborn, not graceful at all. If you imagine the weeping willows planted by hand in Central Europe, they should be the delicate and slender ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pingshan Hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingshan Hall is very crowded. Tour groups are coming and going. The couplet below the plaque of &quot;Pingshan Hall&quot; incorporates the vastness of time and space, the boundless wind and moon, and there are knowledgeable and knowledgeable scholars in the scenery: &quot;When you lean on the railing at dawn, you can see the green mountains of six generations; when you come to drink wine at night, the bright moon is right above your head. On the east and west sides of the plaque, there are plaques &quot;Sitting on Flowers and Carrying the Moon&quot; and &quot;Feng Liu Wan Zai&quot; hanging high. The latter was inscribed by Liu Kunyi, the governor of Liangjiang in the late Qing Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the windows of the east and west wings of Pingshan Hall, Sikuquanshu&#39;s &quot;Six One Poetry&quot;, &quot;Ouyang Wencui&quot;, &quot;Wen Zhongji&quot;, etc. are placed; four wooden poetry plaques occupy half of the wall, recording He wrote poems by Su Zhe and others about Pingshan Hall. Mei Yaochen&#39;s &quot;Thousands of Mountains Flying Shadows Across the River&quot; and Su Che&#39;s &quot;Looking down at the river and the mountains from the hall&quot; both have a silhouette. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eighth year of Renzong Qingli&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1048)&lt;/span>;, when Ouyang Xiu moved from Chuzhou to Yangzhou, he was still in the &quot; The political low period after the failure of the Qingli New Deal. He cared about people&#39;s livelihood, and maintained a lenient and simple administration without slacking off. People in Chuzhou and Yangzhou felt his virtue and government, and built shrines to Ou Gong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After official duties, Ou Gong spent time in poetry and wine. He built a Pingshan Hall in the southwest of Daming Temple, where he could not only meet friends and relatives, climb high and look far away, but also enjoy the tranquility alone. He was very happy in the letter he wrote to Han Qi, his former magistrate: &quot;Dupingshan Hall dominates Shugang, and the mountains south of the Yangtze River can be seen thousands of miles away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at Ouyang Xiu&#39;s description, I thought Pingshan Hall was located. The Shugang is majestic and tall. Today, I was standing outside the hall. Under the stone railing directly south of the tamarisk tree, there was a piece of happy and beautiful red leaves. I tried to look into the distance again, but my sight was blocked by trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, we took the elevator to the 70-meter-high Qiling Pagoda of Daming Temple, which was really good for the distant view. Pingchuan and vast fields stretch as far as the eye can see, with no peaks in sight. The gray buildings in the distance are as small as building blocks. The Slender West Lake at your feet is like a long scroll of scenery. The water bank is curved and lingering, as if randomly embedded in thick or light green trees, with a few pavilions scattered among it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daming Temple Qiling Pagoda (right) and Hongfo Pavilion&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Among the many stone carvings displayed in Pingshan Hall and Ouyang Temple, Dongpo&#39;s &quot;Moon on the Xijiang River&quot; and Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;The Drunkard&#39;s Pavilion&quot; attract people&#39;s attention. The latter was written by Dongpo in Yingzhou. Shen Xiong&#39;s flexible regular script has always been favored by calligraphers. The lyrics of &quot;Xijiang Moon&quot; were written in Pingshan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Shi’s feelings for Mr. Ou are unusual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧阳修一向举贤好士，他隆重奖掖苏轼，更是天下尽知。 The prevailing Taixue style of writing at that time was tortuous, profound, difficult and eccentric, and Ouyang Xiu and others were determined to correct it. In the spring of the second year of Renzong Jiayou&#39;s reign (1057), Ou Gong, as the examiner of the provincial examination of the Ministry of Rites, wrote &quot;the words are very simple and have no meaning&quot;. Su Shi, who was decorated by &quot;Zhaozao&quot;, was promoted to the second place in the &quot;Lun&quot; examination. There are many famous people among this year&#39;s Jinshi, and the Jiayou Gongju Examination is regarded as &quot;the first in the millennium imperial examination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After some well-known candidates who were determined to win the exam failed, they were angry and dissatisfied. Someone wrote a memorial letter as a prank and sent it to Ou Gong&#39;s house. There were also frivolous scholars who surrounded Ouyang Xiu and made noises in front of his horse. &quot;Thousands of people gathered to laugh and curse.&quot; It was difficult for the patrolling soldiers to stop him. But since then, the sick writing style has gradually been reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ouyang Xiu spoke highly of the three Sus, and Su Shi&#39;s rich and fluent writing impressed him even more. In his letter to Mei Yaochen, he happily said: &quot;Reading Shi&#39;s book makes me sweat, so good, so good! I should avoid the road and let him go out of his way. What a joy, a joy!&quot; This is the discovery of outstanding young people by senior writers. I can&#39;t help but feel happy, and it&#39;s the sympathy of genius for genius. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Gong’s support and expectations made Dongpo grateful for his whole life. He said that he was &quot;the most deeply influenced by it&quot;. In the seventh year of Yuanfeng (1084), Dongpo traveled from Huangzhou to Ruzhou. When he passed through Yangzhou in October, he set foot on Pingshan again. Hall. He &quot;remembers the drunkard every time he goes to Pingshan&quot;, and this time is no exception. The ink on the wall is still there, but my mentor has passed away. It has been more than ten years since we last met. Dongpo deeply missed Ou Gong with a piece of &quot;Moon over the Xijiang River&quot;, and also lamented that time flies and things are illusory:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;em>; After passing the Pingshan Hall three times, I heard the sound of a snap of my fingers&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I haven’t seen the old immortal in ten years, and dragons and snakes are flying on the wall. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt; em>;If you want to express your gratitude to the governor, you still sing the spring breeze of the willows. Don&#39;t say that everything will be empty when you turn around. When you don&#39;t turn around, it&#39;s all a dream. &lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou and Su, two literary loyal dukes, leaders of the two generations of literary circles, both set an example for the world with their moral articles. Both of their terms were short, but they made Yangzhou people miss them and made Pingshan Hall full of magnetism. Descendants came to worship in an endless stream, leaving many poems and essays, continuing a romantic tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shizhen&#39;s &quot;Flowers and Grasses&quot; said: Pingshan Hall is not high in terrain and has an ordinary environment. &quot;However, the European and Su poems make the place heavy.&quot; Once the pavilions and pavilions are stained with the luster of a wise man, or Blessed by Li Cihongpian, it will be more charming. Even if the eaves and corners of the corridor columns have been worn away by time, they are still immortal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingshan Hall was abandoned and rebuilt several times. The existing buildings were rebuilt during the Tongzhi period and were subsequently overhauled many times. It made Yixingya feel beautiful and condensed a touching teacher-student friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What can be done in half a year&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;By the time Dongpo came to Yangzhou as a prefect, it was more than 40 years after Pingshan Hall was built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhezong Yuanyou&#39;s seventh year&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1092)&lt;/span>; In February, Dongpo received his appointment in Yingzhou , he was very happy to move to Yangzhou. He took office in March and stayed in Yangzhou for less than half a year. It is difficult to achieve anything in such a short time, but he impressed the people with his good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongpo loves flowers. He plants flowers, appreciates them, gives them hairpins, sighs at them, and interacts with them in various ways. The plum blossoms, orchids, chrysanthemums, peonies, crabapples, camellias, and rhododendrons in his paintings are either beautiful or quiet, some stand alone, or the trees are full of beauty. He was also able to appreciate the charm of peony. He wrote a poem &quot;Zhao Chang Peony&quot; and said: &quot;Yangzhou has been red with thousands of leaves recently, which is the beauty of the fashionable times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Dongpo took office, he did A decision that ruined the scenery: the Wanhua Festival was cancelled. He wrote to his friend Wang Gong: The Wanhua Hui has become a big harm to Yangzhou, and the suspension of the Wanhua Hui &quot;will ruin the scenery, but it will not cause karma.&quot; His article &quot;Harming the People with Joy&quot; said: Yangzhou peony is the best in the world, and Wanhua Hui uses flowers. More than 100,000 branches not only destroyed the gardens of various houses, but also disturbed the people and harmed the people. Yangzhou people were very dissatisfied. , causing harm to the poor people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Mozhuang Manlu&quot; written by Zhang Bangji, a scholar of the Northern Song Dynasty, records: The Wanhua Hui began when Cai Jing learned about Yangzhou, and continued every year thereafter. The flower party was held, &quot;everyone was excited and happy.&quot; Zhang Bangji commented: Su Gong’s administration was basically like this, benefiting the people, so he was praised by them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On his way from Yingzhou to Yangzhou, Dongpo witnessed the tragic situation of the people struggling to survive and being displaced: there were many refugees in the cities along the way, unable to pay their accumulated debts&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style, italic style _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(owing taxes to the government)&lt;/span>; and dare not return home. When traveling to the countryside, Dongpo often screened officials and visited villages. The elders all cried with sorrow: Although the summer wheat is ripe this year, the demand for payment of accumulated debts in the good years will be more stringent. &quot;If the apprentice is at the door and the yoke is on the body, no one will be able to die.&quot; Dongpo couldn&#39;t help crying. He wrote two memorials: I once knew Hangzhou and Yingzhou, and now I went to Yangzhou. &quot;I personally saw that the people in Zhejiang, Jingxi, and Huainan were all burdened by accumulated debts.&quot; They were increasingly in distress, and more than half of them were exiled or died. Huai and Zhejiang had the most accumulated debts and suffered from disasters year after year. The officials, under the supervision of their superiors, pressed for collection and threatened and flogged the civilians every day. How do people live in peace and contentment? How is the benevolent government of the imperial court reflected? Dongpo &quot;said nothing&quot; and asked the court to suspend collection for one year, &quot;so that the people who have been trapped for a long time can know the joy of having a full meal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Su Shi&#39;s request, the imperial court issued an edict on June 1 that the debts accumulated on Huainan East and West Road and Liangzhe Road were suspended for one year. He couldn&#39;t help being happy: &quot;The edict is generous and the debts are owed, and the father is of good looks. Congratulate me again, I won&#39;t be greedy for this treasure. I smiled slumped at Ruan Ji, and drank a few books to thank me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Dongpo found out about Taxation, warehouse law, water transportation, etc. also put forward suggestions for improvement to promote the advantages and eliminate the disadvantages. Disciple Li Zhuo&#39;s &quot;Teachers and Friends&quot; records: In the past, the government allowed Gangyun&#39;s boatmen to carry goods privately to supplement their income. They often regard official ships as their home, repair them at any time, and sail them quickly. In recent years, private transport has been strictly prohibited. As a result, the bad people on the boats have become poor, and the amount of water and rice has been lost several times more than before. Both public and private companies have suffered losses. Some boatmen have stolen goods due to hunger and cold, and have broken down and sold the cars and boats. In Yangzhou, Chuzhou, Sizhou and other prefectures, many boatmen were whipped and sent away, and some became beggars and thieves. The memorial on Dongpo suggested restoring the old practice, which was approved by the court. The disadvantages are eliminated, both public and private parties benefit, and no one is punished for it. Li Lao quoted the words of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; and lamented: &quot;The words of a benevolent person are extremely beneficial.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gulin Hall to the north of Pingshan Hall was built by Dongpo, and the existing buildings were rebuilt in the late Qing Dynasty. It is connected to Pingshan Hall by a corridor with red beams. Separated by a wall to the east of Gulin Hall is the Main Hall of Daming Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three characters &quot;Gulintang&quot; on the forehead of the hall are derived from Dongpo&#39;s Dharma stickers. The couplet &quot;Under the deep valley is graceful; in the high forest there are tall trees and trees&quot; comes from his poem &quot;Gu Lin Tang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall feeling of Gulin Hall seems to be less solemn than that of Pingshan Hall. From the perspective of etiquette, it is in line with the order of seniority and youth. Of course, the decoration is also very rich. On the walls of the lobby and the east and west wings, there are portraits of Ouyang Xiu, Mei Yaochen, and the Su brothers, &quot;Jiayou Gongju Picture&quot; and &quot;Red Cliff Night Tour Picture&quot;, etc., and calligraphy of East and West. Poe Linyan Zhenqing&#39;s &quot;Tie for a Seat&quot; and his &quot;Tie for Seeing&quot;, &quot;Tie for One Night&quot;, etc. Displayed in the window are the yellow-covered &quot;Song Dynasty Dongpo Collection&quot; and the Siku Quanshu&#39;s &quot;Dongpo Shu Biography&quot;. The walls are neatly arranged with poem plaques written by the &quot;Four Scholars of Su Sect&quot;. Among them, Chao Buzhi&#39;s seven-line poem &quot;Zhao Jinyun Guards Guan Yanyuan, Professor Zeng Yan and Ji Pingshan Hall&quot; was written when he invited Zeng Yanhe and others to gather at Pingshan Hall: &quot; &quot;Shu Gang is connected to Shu Mountain, and dragons and tigers reach up to the purple sky... There are no traces of Shaoshi Yangliu.&quot; From the latter sentence, it seems that Ougong Liu no longer existed when Chao wrote the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Jiayou Gongju Picture&quot; on the wall of Gulin Hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In the fifth year of Yuanyou of Chao Buzhi &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1090)&lt;/span>; served as the general magistrate of Yangzhou. Dongpo knew about Yangzhou, and he served as his deputy, and the teacher and student got along well with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the seventh year of Yuanyou&#39;s reign&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1092)&lt;/span>; In August, Dongpo received the imperial edict and served as Minister of War and concurrently In the southern suburbs, the envoy Lu Bo was enshrined. After repeated urging from the imperial court, Dongpo arrived in Beijing in September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chao Buzhi was the son-in-law of Du Chun, the minister of the Ministry of War. When Dongpo took over, he happened to be Du Chun&#39;s immediate boss. Considering that his father-in-law and his teacher had never been close together before, and he was worried that they would not get along so well, Chao Buzhi introduced to Dongpo Du Chunli&#39;s style of life and the advantages of being an official and benefiting all things. Later, his father-in-law wrote a letter saying that he had a good time working with Dongpo, but he felt that he was &quot;arrogant and argumentative.&quot; Chao Buzhi replied with a long letter, detailing Su Gong&#39;s high integrity in governing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have nothing to praise for the fact that Su Gong is a corporal. However, he is upright, pure and has few desires. He has become extremely frugal, but he takes on official responsibilities. He is jealous of evil and loves things. He does everything he knows, especially if he does not neglect the details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chao Buzhi bluntly refuted his father-in-law - he did not think that Mr. Su had this problem: &quot;The letter came from him because he was so arrogant and argumentative. This is beyond Bu&#39;s knowledge.&quot; He also reminded his father-in-law: People Not sages, everyone has his shortcomings and strengths. He gave the example of Ji An and Zheng, the famous officials of the Western Han Dynasty: they had different temperaments and had different brilliance and flaws, but Sima Qian praised them as virtuous. Therefore, &quot;Gentlemen use the same to differentiate, if that is possible.&quot; Chao Buzhi believed that if all the sages were harmonious in the court, then the local good deeds would be consistent with the court, and then nothing would be impossible. This son-in-law is really serious about arguing with his father-in-law and defending his master. Chao Buzhi was the earliest known among the four scholars of Su family, and his admiration for Su Gong can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Walking to the small garden on the north side of Gulin Hall, this corner is relatively quiet. A group of rockeries, several old osmanthus trees, the slanting branches of the osmanthus cover the ridge of the green tile roof, and the tall maple poplars and bamboos sway in the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Small garden on the north side of Gulintang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongpo After arriving in Yangzhou, he was in poor health and rarely received guests. After receiving the tea as a gift from Mao Zhengzhong, he organized a dinner party on the Dragon Boat Festival and entertained guests with sumptuous dishes and rice dumplings in accordance with the solar terms. He especially used the clear water from Shujing to cook tea. Dongpo confessed: &quot;Repaying the favor to the king is not in vain. You know that I am not sipping lightly.&quot; Mr. Mao&#39;s good tea was not given to the wrong person. Now you know how solemnly I drank it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Gulin Hall was built, Dongpo also drank tea in the woods beside the hall, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Writing poetry almost got into trouble again&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Very different from the hustle and bustle of Slender West Lake, Zhuxi Park is sparsely populated and quiet. It is located on the bank of the ancient canal and was built in 1989 near the ruins of Zhuxi Temple. The scenery inside is good, it seems like the back garden of a Yangzhou person&#39;s home. There are not many outsiders to disturb it, and it is quietly beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the rain, the air is cool and moist, and the patches of ginkgo, osmanthus, pine, bamboo, red maple, etc. become cleaner and fresher. The camellias are in full bloom, and the dense, finely chopped off-white flowers of pittosporum exude a light fragrance. There are shallow mountains, thatched pavilions, stone bridges, bonsai, and several old ruins of former sites, all of which are impressive. On the left side of Zhuxi Jingshe stands a portrait of Wu Daozi, a praise inscribed by Li Bai, and a copy of the Three Jue Stele written by Yan Zhenqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Three Jue Monuments&quot; in Zhuxi Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The water area in Zhuxi Park is not small, with streams and lakes, and the water is introduced from canals. The semicircular bridge hole of Yueming Bridge connects with the reflection in the water, just like a full moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the pond deep in the park, there are two vertical corridors of inscriptions, displaying poems by Du Mu, Wang Anshi, Qin Guan, Jiang Kui and others in praise of Yangzhou. Dongpo&#39;s poem stele &quot;Ci rhymes with Su Bogu&#39;s visit to Shugang and sending Li Xiaobo as envoy to Lingbiao&quot;, which was once a treasure of Zhuxi Temple. Later, the poem stele disappeared. Wang Shizhen went to the temple to search carefully and found the ruins of the stele. He brushed away the cobwebs and dust, and &quot;sighed three times, as if he were talking to the public and singing in reciprocity that day.&quot; Then Ci Yun wrote &quot;The Stone Engraving Poems of Visiting Mr. Dongpo in Shangfang Temple&quot;, &quot;I remember the Emei people, their literary talent is truly immortal.&quot; The stele. On display in the gallery are copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhuxi Park Stele Corridor&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Dongpo&#39;s &quot;Return&quot; In front of the stele of poems &quot;Yixing, &quot;Three Poems inscribed on Zhuxi Temple&quot;, there is a large rosy red rhododendron, full of flowers and brilliant colors, which perfectly matches his cheerful and joyful poems. The third one wrote:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I feel that nothing has happened in this life, and I am still having a great year this year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am happy to hear the good words after returning from the mountain temple, and the wild flowers and birds are singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring of the eighth year of Yuanfeng (1085), Dongpo received Shenzong’s edict. Allowed to live in Changzhou. He happily returned south from Nandu &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Shangqiu, Henan)&lt;/span>; and arrived in Yangzhou in late April. The pastoral dream has come true, and I feel good. On the first day of May, I visited Zhuxi Temple with my friends. I was entertained and enjoyed everything I saw and heard. I couldn&#39;t help but write poems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Su Dongpo&#39;s Poetry Monument in Zhuxi Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A quilt in the park In a corner hidden by bamboo branches and holly, there is an old well. The wall of the small gray stone well is more than a foot above the ground, and there are several deep marks on the inside that have been made by the well ropes over the years. The word &quot;Shujing&quot; is engraved on the stone tablet about one meter high next to it, which was inscribed by Professor Qin Ziqing, a descendant of Qin Guan. Shujing, also known as the &quot;First Spring&quot;, is one of the eight scenic spots in Zhuxi Temple. Ancient people said that the water from the well tastes sweet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Temple is located at the end of Sichuan Hill, where the hills tend to become gentle. It is said that the ground veins of Shugang are connected with Shu, and the spring veins are also connected with Shujiang River. Therefore, Dongpo called the water from Zhuxi Temple the flavor of his hometown, and he wanted to carry the well water with the flavor of his hometown to his new home in the south of the Yangtze River. It&#39;s so pleasant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, he almost got into trouble again with poetry. In the sixth year of Yuanyou&#39;s reign &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1091)&lt;/span>; when Dongpo was appointed as a Hanlin scholar and knew how to make imperial edicts, his political enemies went so far as to check the records for Luo Zhi. It was said that Emperor Shenzong died in March of the eighth year of Yuanfeng. Su Shi regarded this as a &quot;good word&quot; when he wrote a poem, and he was overjoyed. Dongpo quickly wrote a letter to defend himself, saying that he returned to Changzhou after mourning the late emperor in Nandu in early March. When I went to Zhuxi Temple in early May, &quot;I saw a dozen people, elders of the common people, talking and laughing to each other. One of them put his hands on his forehead and said, &#39;See, what a young official!&#39;&quot; I was pleased to hear that the common people were praising the young emperor. Sincerely; in addition, his request to return to Changzhou to farm was approved; when passing through Huaihe and Zhejiang, he saw a good harvest in sight, so he wrote a poem and inscribed it on the wall of the temple. If I have any bad intentions, how dare I openly show them to others? Moreover, it had already been two months since the death of the late emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally no danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhuxi Park is very quiet&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangxiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Park Located on Zhuxi Road, there are also streets named after Zenzhi, Shangfang, etc. in the surrounding area. Go east out of the south gate of the park, go to the intersection, and turn north onto Jiangdu North Road. The small high-rise residential building on the right side of the road is called Zhonghai Shixi. I feel that the quality of the community is good. It must be a pleasant sight for residents to overlook the garden path of the park from their balconies. Three to four hundred meters ahead is Zenzhi Road, a slightly narrower branch road. On one side of the road is a construction site, surrounded by beige walls with slogans such as &quot;Yangzhou is my home, take good care of it.&quot; Continue north along Jiangdu North Road, and the next intersection is Shangfangsi Road. There is less traffic, the road is smooth, and occasionally three or two pedestrians walk leisurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Temple, also known as Zenzhi Temple and Shangfang Temple, was originally the palace of Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty. Later it became a famous temple and hosted many emperors, famous ministers and literary figures. It was destroyed by war in 1853. From palaces and gardens where emperors enjoyed themselves, to famous temples where eminent monks resided, to historical sites where poets lingered, they transformed into parks, communities, and streets where citizens walked... This corner of the soil has lost so much prosperity and joy that it has melted away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Tang Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty, countless poems were written about Zhuxi Temple, and many brilliant figures in the history of literature left their traces here. It&#39;s romantic and arouses people&#39;s imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If their figures were reproduced on film, it would look like this: Du Mu came with the sound of cicadas after the autumn rain, the surrounding moss covered the steps, and the sweet-scented osmanthus fluttered; Zhang Hu walked through the bustling ten-mile street , went to Zhuxi Temple, stood on the Yueming Bridge, watched the beauties parading around, and sighed that if he wanted to die, he would die in Yangzhou; Dongpo was particularly active. After entering the temple, he drank Jisu water first, then Yingsu soup, and borrowed vines. The bed was made of tile pillows, so I lay down and enjoyed the cool bamboo breeze. Before I left, I didn&#39;t forget to draw a jar of well water and dip it in ink to write a poem on the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His &quot;image&quot; materials are the most abundant and vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[抢课大战后，年轻人在夜校找到了生活的盼头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260905]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the countdown reached zero, the system crashed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prepare for this battle to grab classes, Jim, a girl born in the 1990s, specially made a form and arranged the volunteers in order of priority, including African drum lessons, hand disc lessons, silver jewelry making classes and tie-dye craft classes. . The plan could not keep up with the changes, and on August 11, the system crashed as soon as it was started. She was lucky enough to get a spot in an African drum class. &quot;It&#39;s like grabbing tickets for a concert,&quot; she said. &quot;I have to have a sense of belief. I have to get it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;500 yuan, 12 lessons, Each class is one and a half hours long. In the fall of 2023, night school, a mass life with a sense of the times, suddenly became popular on social platforms. According to data from Meituan and Dianping, searches for “night school” on the platform increased by 980% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市民夜校的“资深学员”任轶切身体会到此前从未有过的火热。 Around 2018, she accidentally learned about the existence of citizen night schools. Her mother originally wanted to learn mobile phone photography, but when she signed up for the night school, she found out that the age limit was between 18 and 55 years old. There is a special &quot;senior college&quot; for seniors over 55 years old. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi has since &quot;entered the pit&quot;. In the past five years, she has tried leather goods classes, crochet classes, and buttoning classes one by one. She said that at that time, citizen night schools were not as popular as they are today, and “you could basically get them by sticking to the spots (open places).” Most of the night school courses at that time were common subjects such as calligraphy and painting, yoga, and vocal music. Five years later, the registration page is confusing. There are many courses on the list that can arouse interest just by looking at the names, such as &quot;Pet-Friendly Social Courses&quot;, &quot;Shanghai-style Drinking Tea&quot;, &quot;December Flower Goddess Series Courses&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of young people joining night classes is very simple. A girl explained her intention to Southern Weekend reporter: &quot;Socialize, meet more like-minded people, or you just want to learn a new skill, or just go and see Look, if you can learn, just learn, if you don’t, forget it. It doesn’t matter.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the fierce situation, Ren Yi encountered the waterloo of rushing to class, but in the end he got good luck. In a dynamic system where people drop out of classes at any time, she missed one class. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Flock into night schools to “learn art”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi prefers handicraft courses and has previously taken leather goods and crochet classes at night schools. In the leather goods class, they use a complete piece of vegetable-tanned leather as a starting point. After cutting, punching, and stitching, they learn to sew card holders, key bags, or gold bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the buckle class in the fall of 2023, the new object she fiddled with was the buckle, a button used to fix the placket of traditional clothing. The course starts at 7pm on a weekday and lasts for one and a half hours. She coiled long soft buckle strips into various kinds of buttons, such as gourd-shaped and swallow-shaped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time flies by. &quot;Every time, we may not be able to finish the work at the end, but the cleaning lady is so anxious that she has to get off work, so she rushes us.&quot; Ren Yi considers herself to be a relatively clumsy student in the class, &quot;but I just never tire of it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the buttoning class, students learned to make the buttons that fasten the placket of traditional clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Eryu is a freelance illustrator. His daily routine is &quot;sleep early in the morning and get up at noon.&quot; &quot;The night class at seven o&#39;clock every night happened to be a relatively sober moment of her day. She signed up for tea art classes, flower art classes and Yue opera classes, which were held from 7 to 8:30 pm every Wednesday, Thursday and Friday respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Eryu said that the tea art class and the flower art class are &quot;leisure and leisurely&quot;. If you spend thousands of dollars to learn it outside, it is not worth it. It is better to use the money to learn a language, which will look better. Practical knowledge. The low price of night school lowered the threshold for her to get involved in such hobbies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Eryu’s tea class notes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, if I wanted to learn this kind of course, I could only search it online. Being able to identify the level of a teacher “may lead to being deceived”. Before signing up, Lu Eryu paid attention to the background of the tea art teacher. He was a &quot;first-class tea art technician&quot; and &quot;an inheritor of tea ordering in the Song Dynasty&quot;, with reliable qualifications. The teachers at Citizen Night School have been screened, and the course introductions are clearly listed, which saves you a lot of trouble. “You may have something you want to learn, but when you think of complicated things to understand, keep asking these questions. That home, maybe the enthusiasm has worn off after the consultation.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She likes the atmosphere of the tea art class very much. There are more than ten people in groups of four or five. A group of people listened to the teacher talk about the origin of tea and the brewing method of black tea. The teacher taught the formula for memorizing the six types of tea, &quot;&#39;traffic light (black tea, green tea, yellow tea)&#39;, plus &#39;black, white, and green&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tea art classes at night schools are cheaper than training courses on the market, and the teacher qualifications have been specially screened, making it convenient and reliable for young people. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the tea art class, the teacher brought different brands of mineral water or purified water and poured it on透明杯子里，让大家蒙眼品尝不同水泡茶时的口感。 Tools that measure pH value can measure &quot;some water is 7.37, some is 8.08, and some is 6.26.&quot; Lu Eryu observed that the pH value of water usually has little impact on the taste, while the hardness and mineral content of water will bring about polarizing evaluations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the handicraft class that Ren Yi took, the last class was usually a results report, where everyone displayed the results of the semester. &quot;The long table in the entire classroom is filled with various works of everyone. If there is a night market today, our entire class can come out to practice stalls.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Achievements of the handicraft class. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is not something that needs to be persisted&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; &quot;I signed up for night school simply because of several considerations. First, it is very economical. Courses of the same quality and content may cost two or three times the price on the market. Second, it is very secure and the risk is relatively low. It is a project run by the Shanghai Mass Art Museum. It is not like many hobby training institutions outside, which have been affected by the economic downturn. I ran away before finishing the course, and my money was wasted. .&quot; Jim told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has only been officially employed for a few years. She works in a government agency, and her profession requires her to maintain a &quot;serious and rigorous image.&quot; She has certain standards for both her professional image and her own behavior. But during African drum lessons, she doesn&#39;t have to be so tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every day, Jim commutes by bicycle, carrying a backpack with an African drum behind him. From a distance, he looks like a backpacker. A solid wood African drum weighs five or six pounds. When her colleagues asked her if she was going out to play, she never explained, &quot;I said I was just going out to play.&quot; After get off work, she took off her professional clothes, changed into casual clothes, rode 20 minutes to the night school, and then rode home for half an hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teacher who teaches African drum lessons knows a variety of instruments, such as ukulele, ruan, guitar, and keyboard. There are 12 lessons. The first half starts with basic quarter notes and eighth notes, and is interspersed with rhythmic teaching in the middle. Now that the course is halfway through, she is struggling with the latest assignment - the teacher requires everyone to compose a song of their own. She observed that African drum teachers pay great attention to cultivating their arrangement skills, so that after they learn it, they can convey their life insights through the instrument instead of just typing out a melody written by others according to the score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Djembe drumming) is not something that I need to insist on. I don&#39;t find it burdensome. It is something that I can relax after work.&quot; Jim said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After weighing the distance of the class location, the time cost and the urgency of learning, Sun Yiran finally chose the bridge class. This is a very mental chess and card game. While listening to the teacher, she wrote down the card types and rules in her notebook. The bridge class is only one subway stop away from her home. &quot;It&#39;s like when I go to night school, I just get off the subway one stop earlier to go to class. After class, I take the same subway and get home in one stop.&quot; Some of my classmates in the night school class live in Pudong and rush to night schools farther away from home after work just because they are interested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yiran feels that taking night classes once a week will not put too much pressure on him. &quot;There are really other more important things, and I have other time to deal with them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is usually engaged in data analysis work. According to her, it is to organize, analyze and output information into facts that &quot;anyone can see is like this&quot;. &quot;Work is not a purely rational state. Bridge has complete rules and obvious logic, which can actually be calculated. You can completely make an AI robot that can calculate probabilities and what cards the other party may play.&quot; Sun Yiran said, &quot;I Although my work sounds like sorting and analysis, it is not purely rational. There are many human factors involved in decision-making. I will feel a little restricted at work, but bridge does not.&quot; She said that this is the fun that bridge can bring her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A multiplayer chess and card game, it can also be fun to observe the different styles of players on the bridge table. Sun Yiran observed that some people have bright minds and can deal with various types of cards easily on the card court, but they have a &quot;very strong desire to win&quot;; some people, like her, need to constantly look through their notes during the game, thus dragging the game out. It is very long; and the game is just treated as a game, tending to let the opponent directly tell the cards, and everyone thinks about what to do together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7mHrDYb4en1fFAVYlAQsX7bt7b8LYpiqGJ9uoXbe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7mHrDYb4en1fFAVYlAQsX7bt7b8LYpiqGJ9uoXbe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bridge lesson notes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yiran described the weeknights before going to night school as boring and time-killing. &quot;Eating dinner, working out, and watching variety shows are all over. There is no end to watching variety shows or movies. If you have time, you can keep watching and never finish them. But if I have other things to do, it won&#39;t be because I haven&#39;t watched less. It’s a two-hour variety show and I’m sad.” Sun Yiran said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Evening classes have attendance assessment. If you are absent for more than three times, you will lose your registration qualification for the next season of night classes. Many interviewees said that the evening classes are now halfway through, and most people have persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nowadays, young people are under greater work pressure than before, and they need more release and some fun. Everyone has different ways of having fun.&quot; Sun Yiran said, &quot;Because the Internet is developed, everyone is more accustomed to it. Instead of communicating online, there is less offline communication. The extra time will give you more time, so everyone may want to go out and play more, including going to night school.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Every I am looking forward to it every week.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After incorporating night school into their weekly schedule, these young people also feel the changes that their seemingly useless spare time has brought to their daily lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the results of the MBTI personality test, Lu Eryu is an &quot;I person&quot;. In the &quot;Liberating Nature&quot; Yue Opera class, everyone has to stand up to sing, press their legs, and run in circles. The students in the class were paired up, one sang Hua Dan and the other sang Niu Sheng. The Yue Opera class is all girls, regardless of age, ranging from those born in the 1970s to the 1990s. In the first few classes, they were learning &quot;Sister Lin Falls from the Sky&quot;, and Lu Eryu chose to play the role of a heroine who &quot;can be more introverted&quot;. &quot;Jia Baoyu has some eye-catching scenes. He said that Miss Lin fell from the sky, and she had to show &#39;Wow, so beautiful&#39;, and she was surprised to see Hua Dan. Some students will show particularly exaggerated expressions, and the teacher will also be amused. , you will also be infected in this environment.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, Lu Eryu, who considered herself a &quot;home girl&quot;, would not go out for more than 20 days except to go downstairs to throw away garbage. She said, &quot;Night classes are actually equivalent to forcing yourself a time to go out, so as not to be completely disconnected from society. Because you don&#39;t go to work, and you don&#39;t go to offline (social activities), you are getting further and further away from the crowd, so it is a bit forced on yourself. It feels like being away for three days.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing African drums with his classmates gave Jim an unforgettable experience. When playing drums, because you are not familiar with the music score and are worried about not being able to keep up with the rhythm, the rhythm will often become faster and faster. At this time, as long as one person realizes the problem and can slow down, more and more people will find that the rhythm is faster and work together to bring it back to normal. track, &quot;Maybe the overall rhythm will be pulled back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jim said that this is the opposite of the &quot;involution&quot; that everyone is keen to talk about now. There is a classic figurative metaphor of &quot;involution&quot;: in a movie theater, a person in the front row stood up, blocking the view of the back row, so more and more people stood up, and eventually everyone could only stand and watch the movie. The slowed-down pace in the African drum was just the opposite. &quot;At that time, I realized that it could still be like this. It felt amazing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back in the classroom again, Sun still felt that the atmosphere in night school was much better than that in college or middle school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Before high school, you were basically forced to learn these things, whether you like it or not. Although you choose your own major in college, there are basically a large proportion of people in every class. In fact, I don’t want to listen at all.” She observed that in bridge classes at night schools, there was rarely silence, and the teacher’s questions always received enthusiastic responses from the students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as the bridge knowledge deepened, Sun Yiran, who came to class with the mentality of learning new things, also felt the pressure of knowledge accumulation. &quot;Now I feel a critical point. The joy that doing this thing brings me is almost equal to the effort I have to put in to do it well.&quot; She worries that as the difficulty increases, bridge will become a little stressful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This spot is relatively difficult to grab. You signed up, paid money and time, and if you don&#39;t practice well, you might as well not go.&quot; Sun Yiran said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yiyi, who enrolled in a leather goods class, occasionally felt anxious. Once, due to a business trip, I had to miss a lesson in my leather goods class. &quot;I wonder if I will learn less than others if I miss a class?&quot; The teacher in turn comforted her and would help her make up for this class when she comes back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Yiyi generally feels that &quot;there is hope every week.&quot; &quot;It allows you to break away from work and find a new sustenance. You are already tired from work during the day. If there is a new content at night, you can adjust your life. It will make your life focus not always on work, but can be divided a little bit.&quot; Give your mind to other things,” she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Ren Yi and Lu Eryu, the other interviewees are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[近十年来最具话题度的日本动画完结，如何盖棺定论？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260933]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 4, 2023, &quot;Attack on Titan Final Season Finale Part 2&quot; will be broadcast. This episode with a tough-to-pronounce name announced the complete end of the ten-year &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that everything has settled, we can fully evaluate &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;), the most popular and topical Japanese animation work in the past decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/EAtAXg52wGhYOn1Rm5NNB1ZyHtWjuUIZa3PD9LtB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/EAtAXg52wGhYOn1Rm5NNB1ZyHtWjuUIZa3PD9LtB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic scene of the giant staring in &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is &quot;Giant&quot; so popular? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To evaluate the work &quot;Giant&quot;, the first question that must be answered is: Why is &quot;Giant&quot; so popular and discussed globally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypYjeefyRY4CiYEcGnOjEDEECvEE7Ztn1J09SPeZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;342&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypYjeefyRY4CiYEcGnOjEDEECvEE7Ztn1J09SPeZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic gesture of the protagonist of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, television is still the main broadcast channel for animation. The vast majority of Japanese animations in the Chinese context are classified as late-night programs. They usually air after midnight. This broadcast schedule shows that these animations were not considered to be produced for the public from the beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is because Japanese cultural products have formed an industry with extremely mature market segmentation. Almost every work that appears in such a market is specialized for its main audience group, and the same is true for Japanese animation as a late-night TV show. Popular works during the same period when the first season of &quot;Giant&quot; was aired included &quot;There&#39;s Something Really Wrong with My Youth Love Story&quot;, &quot;How Can My Sister Be So Cute&quot;, &quot;Date A Live&quot;, &quot;The Perverted Prince and the Laughing Cat&quot;, &quot;Let&#39;s Work&quot; ! &quot;Demon Lord&quot;, &quot;A Certain Scientific Railgun S&quot;, etc. These animations, from background settings, characters, to story directions, are all customized for Japanese animation lovers in the traditional sense and can appeal to these core target groups. Good, but it also limits the dissemination of these works to a wider public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the conventional production concept of Japanese animation has always been low cost and small output. In the Japanese animation industry, which has long relied on DVD and Blu-ray discs as its main profit channels, an animation can be considered a best-seller if it can sell 10,000 discs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Giant&quot; is an &quot;alien&quot; in Japanese animation. The average sales volume of the nine-volume animated disc of &quot;Giant&quot; in the first season was 52,067 copies, and as of August 2016, the total sales volume was 468,603 copies. It was also the number one selling TV animation in Japan in 2013. In mainland China, iQiyi, which exclusively introduced the copyright, received a total of 320 million online views by the end of the first season. In North America, the work has sold 200,000 copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the Japanese animation works, the production level of &quot;Giant&quot; is far higher than the industry average (regardless of the graphics, actions, and soundtrack). This is the production company of the previous seasons of &quot;Giant&quot; Wit Studio has earned the nickname &quot;Hegemonic Society&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production cycle of the &quot;Giant&quot; animation is also different - such a popular work did not continue to work while the iron was hot. The second animated season of &quot;Giant&quot; airs, four years after the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This long pause comes from the decision of &quot;Hegemony Society&quot;. The company believes that the success of &quot;Giant&quot; is mainly due to its own production level, and thinks that instead of producing &quot;Giant&quot; animation whose copyright does not belong to itself, To earn some hard-earned money, it is better to use production resources like &quot;Giant&quot; to produce your own original animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This animation is &quot;Kabaneri of the Iron Fortress&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;The Iron Fortress&quot;), and Wit Studio has devoted considerable resources to it. Judging only from the animation quality outside of the plot, &quot;Iron Castle&quot; is better than the first season of &quot;Giant&quot;. However, &quot;Iron Castle&quot; is far from meeting Wit Studio&#39;s expectations in terms of reputation and popularity. The shortcoming lies in the story of &quot;Iron Castle&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;detour&quot; of Wit Studio just provides a control group, allowing us to clearly see the root cause of the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; through the control variable method-its own story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from those stories with &quot;otaku&quot; attributes that are generally targeted at two-dimensional enthusiasts in the Japanese industry, &quot;Giant&quot; is an extremely rare work that is truly created according to the model of popular works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMa5Hcv5KLsY818h8abDian5L1jDBT82RpJW9Vp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMa5Hcv5KLsY818h8abDian5L1jDBT82RpJW9Vp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;, humans and titans fight. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The popular pop culture works have some very basic characteristics, that is, they do a good job of showing the world view, On the basis of suspense creation, rhythm control, characterization, etc., use good production level to tell a story well. The original comic book &quot;Giant&quot; followed this rule until the final ending - good-looking stories are liked by people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to evaluate &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; mainly comes from the original comic, the evaluation of &quot;Giant&quot; should also be based on the original comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the &quot;Giant&quot; comic, readers at the time had this to say: When the final chapter of the &quot;Giant&quot; comic was released, the fans of &quot;Fullmetal Alchemist&quot; were the happiest because there would be more comics in the new century. The status of the ceiling is preserved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems almost a joke, but it is actually fair. Before the end, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic was expected to become the strongest shounen comic since 2000, but in the end it failed to reach the top due to problems with the ending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The qualifiers such as &quot;new century&quot;, &quot;monthly updates&quot; and &quot;shounen comics&quot; are not like the increasingly subdivided statistics in sports competitions. &quot;As long as you add enough qualifiers, everyone can win.&quot; It is possible to become the first in history in some aspects.&quot; It&#39;s because, in a place like Japan that emphasizes market segmentation, there are great differences between different types of Japanese comics. Not only youth comics, shounen comics, and girls&#39; comics have completely different creative models and concepts. Even if they are both shounen comics, monthly comics and weekly comics are almost two completely different ecologies due to the difference in publication frequency and length of each issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, trying to simply and crudely bring together works from different creation eras in &quot;Guan Gong vs. Qin Qiong&quot; will not lead to valuable conclusions. Japanese comics, which are highly commercialized, are largely driven by readers’ preferences. Therefore, the story direction and themes expressed in a comic largely reflect the acceptance of the mainstream audience at that period, and are not solely determined by the author. Moreover, the comics created later are more likely to be more perfect in terms of plot and plot than the previous works. Putting aside these talks about the degree of completion and the level of narration, it is unavoidable that the book &quot;focuses on the present and ignores the past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the most important indicators to measure the success of a commercial work - popularity and sales - cannot be used as a basis for comparing the quality of works across eras. The current Internet environment, coupled with the increasingly saturated marketing of producers, and the continuous development of markets outside Japan, have resulted in current works generally having higher popularity and sales than in the past. For example, when &quot;Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba the Movie: Mugen Train&quot; was released, it broke the Japanese movie box office record of &quot;Spirited Away&quot; which had been held for more than 20 years, and now ranks first in the box office history of Japanese movies. But I&#39;m afraid not many people would think that the quality of &quot;Demon Slayer&quot; really surpasses &quot;Spirited Away&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how do you evaluate what kind of work &quot;Giant&quot; is in the history of Japanese comics? You might as well change your thinking and think about this question: When will the next highly topical Japanese comic work like &quot;Giant&quot; appear, and can it avoid the unfinished ending of &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For current and future Japanese comics, works like &quot;Giant&quot; with a complete world structure and description of social organization are rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world constructed in comic works actually comes from the author&#39;s own worldview and values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the history of Japanese comics, you will find that the eras in which cartoonists in previous periods provided them with rich life experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest cartoonists, such as Osamu Tezuka and Fujiko F. Fujio, personally experienced World War II and the reconstruction of postwar Japan. They can grasp the grand propositions such as war and human fate in their works. For example, Osamu Tezuka&#39;s &quot;Firebird&quot; is a grand work on the theme of the universe and life that cannot be surpassed in the history of Japanese comics. Fujiko Fujio&#39;s &quot;Doraemon&quot;, even though it is a funny comic for children, does not forget to make Doraemon and Nobi Nobita laugh and cheer in the work: &quot;Japan is defeated!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The subsequent generation of Japanese cartoonists personally experienced the Japanese left-wing movement in the 1960s and 1970s, which affected the depth and value of exploring social propositions in their works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, as Japan’s economy took off in the 1980s, cartoonists who grew up in this era had an international vision that surpassed their predecessors. Their works also began to really focus on the real world outside Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today’s young manga authors are living in Japan during the “lost thirty years” after the economic bubble burst. Corresponding to the economic stagnation is the slow development of Japanese society and the isolation of popular culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comic writers who grew up in this environment not only have difficulty understanding the real relationship between countries, but also have difficulty understanding the logic of social operations. This has led to a large number of Japanese comics now. When they were still within the scope of campus in the early stage, the plots and characters looked pretty good. Once the plot develops beyond the scope of the school in the later period, various flaws will appear in the character logic and world setting, eventually leading to a bad ending. The same is true for popular works in recent years, such as &quot;Kaguya-sama Wants Me to Confess ~ Geniuses&#39; Battle of Love Minds ~&quot;, &quot;The Promised Neverland&quot;, and &quot;BEASTARS&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, works like &quot;Giant&quot; are rare in the current Japanese comic industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty of world building is only one aspect. &quot;Giant&quot; has the current popularity mainly because of its control of the story rhythm before the end. Before Chapter 90, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic achieved the charm that &quot;information asymmetry&quot; should have. Various hidden clues are revealed bit by bit, gradually piecing together a complete world. In this process, the foreshadowing and echoes before and after the comics can be said to be like a gray line and a thousand miles of hidden connections. This joy of exploration is the most attractive part of &quot;Giant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what if we don’t demand the authenticity of the world view, but instead ask, &quot;Can there be another Japanese comic with a story as exciting as &quot;Giant&quot; that is not unfinished at the same time?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It doesn’t seem easy either. This is because for a comic work released in a serial form, the fascinating of the previous plot is actually highly positively correlated with the final end of the end. This form of serialization determines that Japanese comics are a matter of &quot;killing the king and taking the road&quot;. If you want to catch the attention of readers in the highly involved Japanese comics industry, you must make various abnormal plots in the early stages of comics that are &quot;not shocking but endless&quot;. The more these plots violate the logic of daily behavior, the easier it is to arouse readers&#39; interest. However, in order for the story to proceed normally, the author must give a reasonable explanation to these abnormal passages in the subsequent plot. This in itself is an almost impossible task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost all Japanese comics have this problem. For example, one of the flaws of &quot;One Piece&quot;: the ceiling of the entire comic&#39;s combat power, why the red-haired one of the four emperors had his arm bitten off by a sea monster at the beginning of the comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes this situation worse is the high update frequency of Japanese comics. As a weekly Japanese comic, comics authors are generally required to update more than ten pages of content every week, while monthly magazines generally require thirty to forty pages of content per issue. During this period, the author has to complete story and line conception and storyboard design, as well as comic drawing from draft to final product. Although most cartoonists hire more than one assistant, the work intensity of cartoonists is still far beyond what most people imagine. Under such a continuous and high-intensity working state, it is difficult to expect comic writers to maintain the exquisite conception of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Giant&quot;&#39;s clever handling of various early foreshadowings and clues seems so unusual among Japanese comics. It is also the continuous increase of previous characters and story lines that increases the difficulty of ending the entire story and also raises readers&#39; expectations. All this has become an unsolvable problem before the author Isayama Hajime. In the end, he chose an ending that puzzled most readers. This kind of regret is unavoidable when you think about it carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第十一届茅盾文学奖颁奖，专访茅奖新晋得主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260851]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of November 19, the 11th Mao Dun Literature Award Awards Ceremony was held in Tongxiang, Zhejiang Province, the hometown of Mr. Mao Dun. Five novels won awards: Yang Zhijun&#39;s &quot;Snow Mountain Land&quot;, Qiao Ye&#39;s &quot;Bao Shui&quot;, Liu Liangcheng&#39;s &quot;Bemba&quot;, Sun Ganlu&#39;s &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, and Dongxi&#39;s &quot;Echo&quot;. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎不只小孩得，大人也要当心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260909]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 22:05:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Mycoplasma pneumonia is not limited to children, adults should also be careful. Recently, a 30-year-old Ms. Zhu from Guangzhou developed fever, chills, weakness in her limbs, and coughed up yellow sputum. She originally thought it was a common cold, but she didn&#39;t get better. After a bronchoscopy, it was discovered that it was &quot;mycoplasma pneumonia.&quot; After targeted anti-infection He was discharged after improvement after treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;She has an inexplicable high fever that persists and cannot be relieved by ordinary treatments&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;30-year-old Ms. Zhu is usually in good health, but she suddenly developed a fever recently. The maximum body temperature was 39.8°C, accompanied by chills, chills, and weakness in the limbs. She went to the hospital for treatment. After the doctor gave her ibuprofen to reduce fever and cephalosporins to fight infections, her symptoms were not significantly relieved. She then coughed up yellow and white sticky sputum that was difficult to cough up, especially at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Ms. Zhu came to the outpatient department of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital to seek treatment. Dr. He Yaowei discovered through chest CT examination that she had an infectious lesion in the lower lobe of her right lung, so she was admitted to the hospital to further improve the examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The doctor found through bronchoscopy that there was a large amount of yellow-white sticky sputum in Ms. Zhu&#39;s right lower lung bronchus. Through rapid etiology testing, &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae&quot; was discovered. In other words, Ms. Zhu suffered from the recently popular &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of her situation, the doctor gave her levofloxacin for targeted anti-infection and symptomatic support treatment such as cough and phlegm reduction. Ms. Zhu quickly improved and was discharged. &lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916de7086c6ad38f2062.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916de7086c6ad38f2062.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;258779&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chest CT before treatment: Multiple small flakes and patchy increased density can be seen in the lower lobe of the right lung , the density is uneven, the boundary is blurred, patchy consolidation shadows can be seen, and air bronchial shadows can be seen within them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2a7c361a222986c53f627af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2a7c361a222986c53f627af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258778&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Thorax CT after treatment: Multiple small flakes and patches of increased density in the lower lobe of the original right lung were significantly less dense than before. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is also an important causative agent of adult pneumonia&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital, explained that mycoplasma pneumonia is Acute pulmonary infection mainly caused by interstitial lesions caused by Mycoplasma pneumoniae is significantly different from pneumonia caused by common bacteria such as Streptococcus pneumoniae in clinical manifestations. Therefore, it is clinically distinguished from Legionella pneumophila, Chlamydia pneumoniae and acute pneumonia. Pneumonia caused by other atypical pathogens such as grammaticis is collectively referred to as &quot;primary atypical pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current epidemiological survey results of multiple adult community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) in China show that Mycoplasma pneumoniae and Streptococcus pneumoniae are important pathogens of adult CAP in my country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, the incubation period of mycoplasma pneumonia is 1 to 3 weeks, and the onset is diverse. Most patients only have low fever and fatigue, and some patients may have sudden high fever accompanied by obvious headache and myalgia. and nausea and other systemic symptoms of poisoning. The most prominent respiratory symptoms are dry cough, which often lasts for more than 4 weeks, is often accompanied by obvious sore throat, occasionally chest pain, and blood in sputum. In a few severe cases, respiratory failure may occur, manifesting as respiratory distress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the non-respiratory symptoms, earache, measles-like or scarlet fever-like rash are more common, and a few patients may be accompanied by gastroenteritis, pericarditis, myocarditis, meningoencephalitis, myelitis, and hemolysis. anemia, disseminated intravascular coagulation, arthritis and hepatitis, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having few positive signs in the lungs and obvious imaging manifestations are important features of mycoplasma pneumonia. The lesions are mostly cloud-like patchy infiltrates with blurred edges and low density, radiating from the hilum to the peripheral lung fields. When the lung parenchyma is involved, large consolidation shadows may also appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quinols and tetracyclines are the drugs of choice for adults with mycoplasma pneumonia&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, commonly used drugs for the treatment of mycoplasma pneumonia include macrolides, fluoroquinolones and Tetracyclines and macrolide antibiotics (such as azithromycin and clarithromycin) are currently the drugs of choice for the treatment of mycoplasma pneumonia in children. Quinolones and tetracyclines are the drugs of choice for adults with mycoplasma pneumonia. However, there are also mycoplasma pneumoniae and macrolide antibiotics. Lactone antibiotics are resistant, so the clinical selection should be based on the individual situation of the patient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will mycoplasma pneumonia cause &quot;white lung&quot;? A small number of mycoplasma pneumonias invade a wide range of lesions or have poor mucus drainage, involving the bronchi, alveoli, and interstitium of the lungs, causing &quot;atelectasis&quot; and even &quot;white lungs&quot; on imaging. Through effective anti-infection, expectoration, and shooting, Back and bronchoscopy treatment and other methods can cure the disease in a short time, and most patients have a good prognosis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doctors remind that Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year, especially in late summer, autumn and winter, when the incidence is high. The main sources of infection are patients and carriers, which are mainly spread through air droplets, such as coughing and sneezing. Preschool and school-age children and adolescents over 5 years old are at high risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The preventive measures for mycoplasma pneumonia mainly include: ① Stay away from the source of infection, regularly open windows indoors for ventilation, and it is recommended to wear a mask when going to crowded and closed places. ② Perform good hand hygiene, wash hands frequently with soap (hand sanitizer) and running water, or use alcohol-based hand sanitizer to wipe your hands. ③Eat more fresh vegetables and fruits, drink enough water, get enough sleep, and exercise moderately to enhance immunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital, reminded that during the period of high incidence of respiratory infectious diseases, if you have upper respiratory tract infection symptoms such as cough and fever, it is recommended to seek medical treatment as soon as possible to find out the cause. Treat in a targeted manner and do not take medicine on your own to delay the condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[体验“人生的旷野”后，两位985大学生选择回归国企和考研]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg6VvrzP.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2449&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg 6VvrzP. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;234068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Every year during the school recruitment season, we can hear different employment stories of college students. In many narratives of 2023, the word &quot;wilderness of life&quot; appears frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although more and more college students are joining the difficult job search path of civil servants, central enterprises, state-owned enterprises, large Internet companies, etc., there are still some people who choose to find the wilderness of life on the so-called non-mainstream path. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two guests on this podcast, one of whom is a graduate with a double 985 master&#39;s degree, chose to take 3 months out of the busy school recruitment season to study cooking at New Oriental School and graduate. It has been on the hot searches on Weibo and Xiaohongshu twice. Another guest is also from 985 University. After graduating from undergraduate degree in 2021, he has experienced 100 different lives through various unique part-time experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after experiencing the wilderness of life, they eventually returned to the traditional path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly has higher education brought us? Do we have to return to the mainstream path eventually? Does the wilderness of life really exist? Let’s find the answer in this podcast conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;Guests for this issue: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qianyu&amp;nbsp;2022 Master&#39;s Degree from Renmin University of China Graduate, currently working in a state-owned enterprise in Shanghai&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;KAMA (pseudonym) 2021 undergraduate graduate of Nanjing University, currently preparing to take exams in the art field&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000 ;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Listening tips:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 03:25 Before and after graduation, I was on two hot searches&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:52 at In college, you will feel that everyone has the same goals&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 13:48 Life is a process of constantly collecting plastic bags&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 25:57 Leaving the step-by-step study life , I chose a stamp collecting part-time job&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 36:25 Young people always have to do a reverse weaning from their parents&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 38:43 When I was working part-time, I concealed my academic qualifications &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 50:11 Learning to cook at New Oriental made me feel that people can live no matter what&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 52:20 After leaving college, I realized my shameful sense of superiority&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;► 60:44 Does higher education constrain our choices? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: right;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #808080;&quot;>; Editing: Zheng Yuchun &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: right ;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Promotion and operation: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>